this kid made over one million dollars in one year with a business idea that nobody's talking about AI generated books he invited us into his apartment in Toronto to show us where he found
this idea how he started on a budget and how he built it in a few hours a day while attending College full-time before the money Joe popplus was just a uni student stocking shelves for 11 bucks an
hour now he's making a living selling thousands of ebooks using an unconventional method with chat gbt initially this wasn't the way I did it but this is the best way to do it now but the craziest part about his business
is actually not how he creates the books it's how he advertises them the majority of my money has been made off of dads the AI Revolution is here and Joe is
living proof I'm Pat walls and this is starter story you built an amazing business tell me about who you are and what you build I'm
Joe I'm a 20 year old computer science student I've built a book brand that is now valued at 930 000 I generate all books with AI and then I Market them on
Pinterest to middle-aged moms how did you come up with this business idea 2020 was the year when I graduated high school I started working on a use case
for gpt3 I got a really good idea of how AI could be integrated into different business models in 2022 I was like why don't I just utilize my pre-existing
skill sets AI gpt3 is now out a few businesses know about it maybe I could help provide some value to like some small mid-sized businesses who want to learn more about AI around that time
that I got that idea people actually started reaching out to me asking about my experience at openai I had a kind of like tab on my LinkedIn that showed that I had worked on use cases for openai for
the gpt3 beta they started asking me certain things it got to the point point where I started charging for the advice
that I was giving in July of 2022 I met with the Publishing Company where I got the idea they showed me their stats and
how much money they were making off of selling books that was a complete eye-opener for me I didn't realize how many people bought books per month their revenue was about two million dollars
which was absolutely insane to me I thought why can't I just start up something similar because what they were doing was so insanely simple that they were not doing anything AI book related
and when I met with them I told them nothing about my idea that I had kind of formulated while we were on the call in the month of August I generated 10 20
books I generated a few more in September by the end of September I was at 40 bucks I generated 40 books with AI then on October 3rd I hit my first profitable day and I was like 20 October
4th I was like at forty dollars and then from there it almost grew X-Men actually on December 28th I'll never forget this day that's when I hit my first 1K day profit and that was crazy that was just
after Christmas and my whole family knew about it I told all my friends we built this business from money that you made for your minimum wage job did you do it all yourself yeah it was completely self-funded and if I did it properly the
first time with the stuff that I know now I could have started it up in under 500 but I just made a bunch of mistakes yeah it's just a new Venture for me how did you manage building this business while you're in school and you had a
part-time job that was probably the hardest part for me I was fitting in time for me to work on the book brand when I was studying for a huge test it was coming up in school I dropped two
courses to work on my book Brands but I spent most of the day working on school and then I would spend five six hours in the nights working on my book print how can someone who's watching right now get
into AI generative books the best way to start off learning is taking an interest in these gender of AI models and learning how they work how you can get the best output out of them with the
correct settings with the correct prompts then you need to find a niche a niche that has traffic a niche that has a lot of ambitious people in it when you
have people like that you can tug on their emotions more and you can present the outcome to them that they want to achieve and the only way to get to that
outcome is through your product your first AI ebook that you created tell me about how you did it I literally knew nothing about books so I was researching how to actually build a book I knew I could write it with AI like I knew the
output would be good enough but I had no knowledge on how I should structure it what should be included all of that when I created my first book it was probably the worst book anybody could ever read
like there was no congruency nothing as I actually started purchasing my competitors books and reading through them I knew exactly what I needed to include it's not as easy as just putting
into Chachi BT write me a book on whatever initially this wasn't the way I did it but this is the best way to do it now you get Chachi PT to create the book outline let's say for example you have
five chapters and then per each chapter there are five topics you are going to go through each Topic in each chapter
and generate that topic even though I wasn't super experienced with writing books people still like them the first few ebooks that I put out they they enjoyed what they were reading hey real
quick that business you want to start let me show you how you can make your first dollar ten times faster by using case studies imagine you could read the exact steps to how someone built a million dollar business and the mistakes
they made so you can avoid them when you launch well at starter store we have a library of over 4 000 case studies and business idea breakdowns where you can do this all backed by real data for example Loop joint starter story and
dove into our case study about a newsletter that makes 25 million dollars a year just one month later he launched his own newsletter that did five thousand eight hundred dollars in Revenue in the first 30 days
simple he studied what works implemented it and avoided the mistakes of people that were just a few steps ahead of him if you're serious about building something check out starterstory.com or running a special deal this week and you can click the link below in the
description to get it much love and I hope you guys enjoy the rest of the video peace can you break down how much profit you made and what the business is valued at today two dates I've made 390k
dollars profit and my current valuation is nine hundred and thirty thousand dollars what's the typical profit margin in a business like this my profit margin
is about 70 to 80 percent the only real expense that takes away from my profit is the ads I have my premium extension
subscriptions which is about 200 a month creating books to create a full book it's about three dollars with GPT three and then I have my proofreader just go through everything I have them on a retainer but you can just do the
pre-freed ink yourself at the starting when you started out you proofreaded everything I did yeah I spent a lot of time I would basically basically generate a full book do a rough draft and then I would meticulously go through
each chapter each subtopic just going through the book and I just do one revision of that and then I'd have a good ready to go book tell me more about the marketing side of things as I understand uh you make money with ads
how specifically does that work majority of my money has been made off of Pinterest ads when you land on Pinterest and you start with Pinterest ads you're going to start off with consideration campaigns and then you're gonna move
into conversion campaigns consideration campaigns are going to give you a general idea of which Niche you should be selling your product in you're going to test out different niches with consideration campaigns then you're
going to go way more granular you're going to set up your Pinterest tag and then move into conversion campaigns where you're really going to dial in every single stat take a look at everything your landing page copy whether people are converting above the
full below the fold all of that tell me a little bit about how the landing pages work how do people find the landing pages and and what's the purpose of them the landing page is going to give you
room to show the lead value Stacks what's provided chapter previews everything it gives you so much more real estate to sell them on the product it's almost impossible to sell if you
don't do a landing page a landing page is also the first touch point where the lead is going to get a really good idea of your overall brand image so if your
landing page is really really bad it doesn't look professional they're gonna bounce they're gonna bounce right away and you're going to get a bounce rate of over 80 percent over 70 percent that's when you know that you know your landing page just doesn't look professional with
AI books there's a low barrier to entry right anybody can write an AI book and sell it how do you approach competition and things getting saturated I'm at a
point right now where my brand has so much momentum when I see new competitors coming to the space it doesn't scare me it hasn't affected my profit and I don't
expect it I don't see it affecting my profit in the future either because I have such a loyal customer base there is such a huge Market as as well I'm only advertising on Pinterest when you take
Google ads Facebook into account there's so much room for growth I'm sure there's going to be many many like hundreds of book Brands popping up but the market is
so huge by the point that I predict or expect it to get saturated all be well on my way I think that'll be years down the line though and saturation just means more competition it means you need
to be better at what you do provide more value in your product and I think it's good for people to stride towards providing more value how sellable is a business like this initially I didn't
think it would be super sellable and I wanted to test the waters and what I did is actually posted a bunch of the details just on a few marketplaces I just wanted to see what investors would
offer for my business the very first offer I got for the entire business was nine hundred and thirty thousand dollars when I saw that number and I got the email notification that I got an offer I
was like I'm really on to something here now I'm actually working with an investor who is purchasing 40 of my book
Brands and I'm able to continue building up another book rant to then maybe sell another 40 so it's a completely repeatable process where you can build a
book brand sell it build another sell it and it doesn't mean you have to sell this whole Corporation you can sell just parts of the corporation like what I'm doing right now you made all this money
selling AI books uh what does a typical day look like for you what's your typical routine all of my mornings are usually spent on making sure the ads are running correctly making sure my proofreader is doing what he needs to do
I'm just checking in with the business now I'm working a lot and this is mostly the afternoon I'm working on teaching people how to build their own book brand that's been extremely rewarding I've had
some really successful students they've been absolutely killing it and then in the night I actually make house music as a hobby and I actually have a few songs posted to my Spotify so AI music is that
the next thing yeah it could be it could be yeah that's amazing what's your DJ name it's just my name Joe popolis nice yeah you made a lot of money as a 20 year old uh have you bought anything
cool with the profits I really haven't bought a lot of things the only thing I bought is just this Rolex and I know it's going to keep its value I want to stay away from depreciating assets as
much as I can for now I just want to make a huge bag and then in the future in the near future I'll invest and you know get a nice car all that kind of stuff but for now I'm just solely focused on building businesses I'm very
lean and I want to stay that way for a while if you could sit on Joe Pablo's shoulder when you were just starting out you you had a couple failed business ventures what would you tell him I would
tell him to prioritize learning over earning be more focused on learning the skills building up a huge skill set instead of being focused on how much I'm earning it was almost impossible for me
to fail with the book brand because I had built up so many skills beforehand thank you Joe yeah follow us advice and you will make millions with AI books
so yeah did you make house music I do like house music do you want to hear the latest songs