what's your story [Music] I mean we bootstrapped this thing from day one and we need it to be profitable we didn't have any money to put in we couldn't afford to lose this is Aaron
Spivak and he nearly lost everything launching a business at first he thought he was a Founder genius we were doing 30k a month 60k a
month 90k a month but then realized it was just beginner's luck you know our first summer we went to zero it was a moment of like are you guys actually going to do this or not so what happens
when you're staring in the face of failure and your bank account is losing money every day my co-founder leor called me and he's like hey we gotta we gotta shut this business down do you give up we need to prove that there was
something here or do you jump even further into the abyss and go to the ends of the Earth just to find a way to make it work we broke the internet we went viral on Netflix for doing that for
the first time ever in that moment I was like that's why we storytelling this is the story of how two guys from Toronto turned four thousand dollars into 48
million dollars in four years I'm Pat walls and this is starter story growing up Aaron was your typical young entrepreneur hustling and starting just
about everything lemonade stands party buses and even starting his own Juice Shop in Toronto but everything changed when he met leor his eventual business partner he realized there was a bigger
opportunity starting an online business I always wanted to really start a business with lior I thought he was just super smart he was like in that online world I was opening up two shops and
making smoothie recipes and I actually wanted to sell Cricket protein that grinded up crickets and I brought it to leor and he's like that's disgusting but
have you seen this rise in weighted blankets and then we went on Google and we saw that there was 300 000 people searching for weighted blankets in the coming months with enough proof of concept and validation Aaron and lior
started developing a sample of what they thought to be the perfect weighted blanket and the wild thing is that they were doing all of this while they were working their current full-time jobs like I was opening my juice shop at 6am
until like 2 3 clock and then I'd probably work out or eat dinner lior was running a software company the same time frame we'd meet up every day at like seven o'clock at his apartment and then
we'd work till like one two a.m after grinding it out for months the plan started to fall in place Aaron and lior found a new audience to Market these weighted blankets to and started running
ads on Google so we literally with basic images in one sample put up a pre-order site and then we bought ads for the most expensive keyword which was weighted
blankets first sale came in we made I think like 20 bucks the next day we made three sales I remember Leo and I took those three sales extrapolated over the year I'm like oh my God we're gonna buy
Ferraris like we're rich like this is it we were doing 30k a month 60k a month 90k a month with a little bit of beginner's luck they were really successful out of the gate we launched
in January we went from one three five sales 20 sales a day but they were not ready for what was about to happen and our first July in Toronto it's 30 degrees outside which is the hottest
month month of the year we went from all those sales to literally zero sales most days and some days one our best day of the month we maybe had two sales Aaron and lior had made a huge mistake they
didn't forecast their inventory for the summer months and this was threatening their entire business they were running out of cash and sitting on hundreds of unsellable inventory lior even came to
Aaron to shut the business down you know our first summer we went to zero my co-founder Leo called me he's like hey we gotta we gotta shut this business down because I'm not interested in a seasonal business we have a seasonal product we're stuck with all this
inventory let's get rid of it as fast as possible and you know you've got juice shops he had a software business let's move on in those moments it was like looking yourself in the mirror from being like
am I actually the real deal do I wait do I actually know what the hell I'm doing like do people actually like my like was this all an accident the fast success started to collapse for Aaron in
lior and the dark thoughts came pouring in as their bank accounts came closer to zero so because we were broke it was one of the most challenging years of our
lives and there was doubt and there was uncertainty I mean we bootstrapped this thing from day one and we need it to be profitable we didn't want to we didn't have any money to put in we couldn't
afford to lose it was a moment of like are you guys actually going to do this or not if even though things were tough the boys were determined to figure it out but with money running out they had
to do something quickly and this is when Aaron had a brilliant idea we needed to prove that there was something here that someone wanted to buy this product and once they got the product that they were
happy with it we weren't just good marketers with shitty product it got to the point where I was like hey why don't we just call everyone because clearly they were buying it they're not buying it now why are they not buying well just
ask and that's exactly what they do in August of 2018 they sent out an email to all of their customers with a calendly link their goal to talk to every single
one of their customers and ask them why they stopped buying the blankets every single person said the exact same thing Aaron we love the blanket it's so amazing it's it's incredible but I'm
sweating in places I've never sweat before it's disgusting so I'm putting it in my closet and in the winter I'll pull it back out and this is when Aaron and Leora have the biggest breakthrough in
their Journey instead of launching a product and hoping for the best they realized the secret to building a business is talking to customers and it was like a light bulb moment where we're like wait a second
why don't we just make a cooling weighted blanket because if it was cooling you would use it all year round like of course we would of course we would so we spent all of September flying around talking to suppliers and
sourcing the coolest fabric ever we ended up having to create our own fabric which is called the ice fabric which is the coolest Fabric in the world it literally keeps you cold without any
water or fans going through your bed but it was so expensive it was a hundred thousand dollars to get the first roll of that fabric and we couldn't afford it Aaron and leor are faced with their
biggest challenge yet they need a boatload of cash to make more blankets but they're down to their last four thousand dollars because they wanted to stay bootstrapped and keep 100 of the
business investors were off the table so they decide to throw a Hail Mary and try raising a few thousand bucks on Kickstarter they set a very low goal of
25 000 in hopes it will be enough to keep the business alive and make their next order when the kickstarter goes live something amazing happens the boys
raised over one million dollars in the first 30 days so in 2019 we launched the 1.0 the hush ice the world's coolest weighted blanket it was a top 10 Canadian Kickstarter of all time and
when people ask us like what was the hack how did you reverse engineer Kickstarter like what it was what was it a specific agency or a video style and it's like no I mean I had 3 000 people
that literally told me on the phone that they would buy it if I made it Aaron and Leora realized they need to take the momentum from their Kickstarter and push it into something even bigger they sit
down and ask themselves this question how can we get these weighted blankets in front of a massive audience they come up with a plan they're gonna weasel their way into one of the biggest shows
on television that year we then went on Canadian hit TV show Dragon's Den and we went on the show told our story and had in 14 Seasons so 14 years of the show
there's never been a pitch that came on and increased their evaluation on live TV through debate amongst the dragons and we were the first we broke the internet we went viral on Netflix for
doing that for the first time ever it catapulted the brand as 2020 comes around the boys continue to double down on their success reinvesting every dollar they earn they pick up the phone
again and continue talking to customers and this gives them a new idea to create a new product a pillow they call thousands of customers and get feedback
on what would make the perfect pillow then they launch it on their email list and sell 3 000 pillows in 72 hours and I remember I post about it on LinkedIn I'm like hey we just sold out 3000 pills in
72 hours and everyone's initial reaction is like what was the marketing what was the email what was the hype what was the flow and it's like well no actually retired last year we were talking to our customers literally asking them what
pillow you want let me build it for you they realize they have a formula talk to customers understand their problems and then create more products to sell them so they do the same thing and launch the
hush ice blanket 0.0 and then do the same thing again and launch the hush ice bed sheets that year they do 20 million in sales we over doubled the business
again heading into 21 where we just said it's time to shine we want big goals we wanted to do 40 million bucks we really wanted to sell the business at that time with big plans to sell the business
Aaron and leor need to find a final product to create that will increase their valuation so they decide to do something that nobody expects in an industry where it's nearly impossible to
make a profit we have the stupidest idea in the world which was to launch a mattress in a box no one makes money selling mattresses in a box but for whatever reason we thought we could and
we spent three months calling customers because we were so nervous so expensive the inventory was so expensive so for the next few months they of course spend all of their time calling up their customers and asking them what would
make the perfect mattress and to their surprise the biggest pain point was that their current mattresses were super uncomfortable when it came to making love so we went out we created a
specific Zone technology that has specific Springs and specific areas that keep you flat no matter how you're positioned or how you're leaning up against something we did a million and a half dollars on launch which nobody
believed that we can do then in October of 2021 the biggest sleep company in Canada gives them a call they want to acquire hush blankets we sold the business to the largest sleep company in
the country we went from zero to 48 million and 48 months and it's been a really fun ride along their Journey Aaron and Leora learned hundreds of lessons but there's one lesson that
stands out and it's something they didn't realize until they sat down and really looked back all of these phone calls and customer conversations created a community of super fans customers that
would buy from them forever and it's actually what makes hush stand out from the thousands of other companies selling the same products we opened our first pop-up store the highest grossing Mall
in the country fourth in all of North America and aloe also decided to come to Canada open the same time as us and they had 700 people come through their door on opening day we had 1500 and who came
our people there's a blanket behind you someone's had a sign their blanket and they gave it back to us as a souvenir one of the executives from the company that purchased us was there watched it happen in real time and came up to me
after he's like I've never in my 25 years in this industry would think that someone would ask a guy that sells blankets to sign the blanket in that
moment I was like that's why we storytelled today customers care more about the people behind a brand than they do about the product itself Aaron and Leora documented their journey and
got customers involved from the start they weren't just selling blankets and pillows they were bringing their customers along for the ride being vulnerable and sharing all the ups and the downs I think storytelling is the
most important thing you can have when you're marketing a brand and storytelling is the emotions and it's the magic that people want to feel before they go out and purchase something like if you think about
Abercrombie walking into a mall there's two shirtless teenagers with six packs labs and cologne that's like oozing out
and we're all like yeah that's us you know and like now that story doesn't resonate but that's who we wanted to be we wanted to be that guys with the cool hair and the six-pack ads that the girl
loves and that we smell good and we we walked into the store we bought those jeans and we put them on and we felt like those guys that Essence that emotion that magic is everything when
building a brand people can have that feeling with small Brands and small businesses and I don't know why I don't know why Founders are are not leaning into that perhaps they think it's beneath them but that's how you build
community from four thousand dollars in the bank to 48 million dollars Aaron and Leora have proved that thanks to the internet anyone can build something huge as long as you're willing to pick up the
phone and tell your story anything is possible what the internet afforded us was guys like me are able to go and compete with the big guys because the internet
previously you needed to go and knock doors of these retailers and beg for them to take your product they'd put you in a shitty Corner no one would try to have no sales you have returned and like it was the barrier to entry was so big
but now there's a story for the underdog there's a story for the guys shooting on their cell phone that gets to be that way I do that to me
[Music]