300 is all Sherman shares made in his first year on YouTube now he makes a full-time income as a YouTuber living in the most expensive city in the world New York City boy in this video he tells us
why he quit his six-figure job just to make Pennies on YouTube I was just like this is the end turns out it was a little motivation I watched the garyvee video and he's like this is exactly when
you can live with four roommates in a basement and eat fast food do you understand paired with a humbling move back into his parents house moving back from my parents we'll show you
exactly how he was able to go from miserable office job to YouTuber with thousands of subscribers and six figures in Revenue I'm Pat walls and this is starter story thank you
[Music] all right we're headed up to the content closet right now let's check it out how's it going welcome back good to see you good to have you welcome to the contact closet
foreign before you became a YouTuber you were a software engineer and you had like a pretty big six figure job but you left it all so yeah tell me tell me why you
did that you know I did everything my parents had told me to do which was you know study hard go to college get a good job and then I came to the realization that like all right now I have 50 years
of my life left is this what I really want to be doing but it was just the desire to chase something that kind of like internally this internal voice is telling me hey you got to go chase after something that just doesn't make logical
sense right now did anyone help you or how did you come to the decision to finally quit how did that look so funny stories I quit my job twice technically once was the software engineering job and then I kind of like did YouTube and
kind of explored and I became a product manager and then I quit that job too there was no one else like I think all my friends were working regular jobs they're enjoying it they're doing well financially and I watched the garyvee
video and he's like if you just graduated college like you need to chase your dreams this is dreams we're talking about we're talking about dreams hey this is the time to be high risk and I was like
he's so right like in five years if I'm married and have kids [Laughter] because like in five years if I'm married and have kids I won't be able to take a massive risk like you can't just
quit your job because you have to pay for your mortgage or whatever else like you're supporting other people so I was like Now's the Time just take the risk what's the worst thing that can happen I can always go back into a
software engineering job and that's when I kind of like decided and then I just became like okay how do we go about it and journaling journaling journaling journaling and then finally one day I was just like this is the end quitting
your job for YouTube is a crazy move how much you have saved up do you have a backup plan at the time so I had a lot of Investments um from software engineering luckily that I had put like in retirement
account and then like other assets and I was fortunate enough that those assets had grown immensely so I had kind of like a asset I could pull from if I really needed an emergency but in my
bank account I think I had like five or ten thousand dollars but I felt comfortable because I had like those assets backing me and I was like if I really need more money I'll sell stuff and I'll use that money but I didn't really want to sell anything at the time
but you're able to make it off of five ten thousand at least in the beginning yes uh so luckily YouTube was already making some money I was making I think two to three thousand a month and I was
like as long as I can increase that Revenue by focusing more on that then I should be fine so I really just focused on increasing that revenue and I cut my personal costs as low as possible
and that's kind of how I lived and for the most part that was helping me and I recently just started paying myself through the business you said that you brought your personal expenses down to basically nothing what did that look
like uh that was kind of like moving back into my parents so no rents they paid for food um I didn't have to pay for a car so I had the lucky opportunity that I
could lean on them so that was kind of the big thing I was like all right how can I go about using this as as a as a way to kind of not have to spend too much money being a YouTuber for anyone
else who wants to do YouTube full-time how much you used to have to spend as a YouTuber you don't have to spend any money and you have to spend all the money I think it's all hard work and dedication like one thing I've really prided myself is trying to meet as many
other creators as possible and the big thing you learn from that is a lot of people don't want it they say they want it they're like yeah I want to do this I want to do that or I have this dream but no one wants it if you're hungry enough
you could do it that's that's the part that I've realized like so many people just say things but they don't actually put in the work if you put in the work day in day out there's nothing stopping you how can you tell if someone really
wants it it's not about how they talk it's about what they publish like are they publishing consistently are they adapting and learning and growing and are they asking questions like one thing
I struggle with is asking for help but I've realized that even people who like I'm not a big Creator but people who might be like one step behind me if they ask me for feedback like okay that person is hungry and then I'm like okay maybe I should be asking other people
for feedback too so that like shows that you want to learn and you want to get better when you first got started how much time were you spending creating videos and like how many subscribers did
you have in the early days I was doing like I think daily Vlogs were were the thing back then so I was like oh I need to publish every single day so I would record during the day edit at night and then publish the next morning and I did
a couple like 30 day 90 day challenges um and I think I had like 100 maybe 200 subscribers at the time how many videos were you putting out what was your what was your output look uh I think it was
once a week twice a week I still switch between that I'm trying to do like I did three months where I was like we're doing twice a week and then I scaled it back to once a week but for the most
part I think twice a week once a week or twice a month are probably like the three best cadences for YouTube is what I've learned and noticed from most people so how long did it take you to
get to a thousand subscribers was that a big Mark for you I've heard this great quote 100 subscribers is the hardest a thousand is the next hardest ten thousand is a little bit harder 100 000 is a little
easier and then a million is even easier and I think it's because the Snowball Effect right I I don't remember how long it took me to get to like a thousand but I remember it was like years like two
years maybe uh just posting content and I wasn't really analyzing what was bringing in subscribers I was just posting out of like oh this is fun I like this let's just keep doing it
um but it took like two maybe three years and how long did it take to make your first dollar through your videos so before the one thousand four thousand hours limit that YouTube had I was
monetized and I was making like ten dollars a month within the first year that I started YouTube and then they created that cap and I was under the 1000 subscribers so they cut off my
money and I think I made like 300 over a year but that was the first like couple dollars that came in and you couldn't get the money until you hit 100 threshold so I was like I would see it right
we need 20 more to get the cash and how did you make that money was it just through YouTube AdSense that first it was all YouTube AdSense I know you make money through lots of different ways now uh how did you find those and what does
that look like for you I started to make videos that were kind of search based um and like we were product reviews like one of them was like a fitness tracker band and I was like oh they gave me like a referral link you know sometimes they
say oh put your link in the app like oh you get one month three if you refer someone so it's like all right let's do it so I put that link in there and the video got some views and then all of a
sudden I had three years of membership and I was like what do I do with this and then I became 10 years of membership and I was like what do I do with this so then the company reached out to me and they're like hey we have an affiliate
program um it's invite only do you want to be in it and I think of course like what am I going to do with 10 years of membership so that was the first time they're like okay here's your link instead of getting a free month which was like I don't know
30 bucks or something we'll give you 50 dollars and I was like all right that sounds better like a cash over like this thing that is not really like attainable and that was the first time that I
started to get like some amount of cash and I was like all right let's replace that link and then I was like okay so it looks like if I make a product review and people are searching the review and I provide value
um and some people will decide not to buy it because of my video and some people will and if I tell them to use my link then I can make some money so that helps support making more videos could you break down all the different ways that you make that you make money as
YouTuber I know affiliate marketing YouTube AdSense maybe do you have any brand deals could you break it all down for us yeah um right now it's just affiliate marketing and YouTube AdSense I'm starting to get into sponsorships but I
don't really want to yet because I want to like optimize for watch time and I don't know it's like a fear that maybe if I put a sponsorship in like views are gonna drop I think it's probably like 80
20 20 is YouTube AdSense 80 is uh affiliate marketing and then Within like there's two major companies that cover most of the AdSense
probably around 50 of that and then the rest is like a whole bunch of other small um companies this is my bedroom very tiny New York City boy
yeah so living in New York City is obviously really expensive how are you able to live in New York as a Creator um you just have to give out an arm and
a leg I think part of it I was lucky and fortunate enough to meet two other creators who were also chasing the same thing and we're like we figured out what we wanted to prioritize and for me it was like location I want to be surrounded by
other creators and we know a lot of other creators who kind of live near this area and then the second aspect was save as much plenty as possible so we try to find the cheapest place where all three of us could live in and this was
it like it provided bedrooms for all of us it has a nice big living room so that way we can like have our desks and create content it kind of got our basic needs met so it's just cut costs as low
as possible and get like your high priority items yeah and that's it and how much does this place cost for rent in the whole place and in this room we pay 4 500 for three of us so me and my
roommate changes we pay 1600 and then uh Colt our third roommate pays the rest and do you eat out a lot or what how do you saving money I'm trying to cut that down so actually
one video I'm working on is how to make homemade meals in less than two minutes and save money that way as well as like optimize time so I have like a little Smart Oven thing that I use and that
helps me like cook most of my meals nice and what are the other big expenses as a new NYC Creator what is it other than rent and food what do you spending coffee this place is so small like it's nice to
just change your environment and go outside somewhere so I like to go work at a coffee shop or meet people at a coffee shop that's probably my biggest expense and then gym I love working out so there was a time where I had two gym
memberships but now I don't um but like going to the gym or a sauna and and cold plunge Studio like that's another cost so I would say health and
wellness costs are pretty high anything you really want to do in New York City it's like almost double the price sometimes yeah I think that's a good segue to go check out a coffee shop and
right say coffee coffee shop cut the coffee shop [Music]
all right so what's been your most like successful or viral video on YouTube it was definitely the I replaced my iPhone with an Apple Watch Ultra I think it's around 1.56 million
views right now and what's the story behind it so that's like been a video I've done a couple times before and the intention behind it was like can I survive with just my Apple watch like I'm always consuming social media on my
phone and I want to just like get rid of my phone so I was like can I do 24 hours just Apple watch and I've done it before and it did pretty well I was like all right the new Apple watch is coming out
let's launch this video at the same time that all the Apple watch Ultra hype is happening so as soon as I got the watch I did the video literally the next day and I tried to release it as fast as I
could like I I don't think the editing was great it was just like get it out now why do you think it went viral timing uh topic uh and just having previous data that like this style could
potentially work so I think there's a factor of those three things like I know this video has worked for me in the past timing of Apple watch Ultra and then the topic people love Apple watches yeah yeah and how did it feel like you're
getting like all this views Was it crazy I think I was like oh I really don't care I was like it's not about the views like yeah having one viral video is is
cool I guess but like I want to have an Engaged audience and engaged community and all those 1.5 million people watch the video and never come back like what's the point I want people to come
back I gotta I'd rather have consistently a hundred thousand views than one video that gets like 10 million views so that's kind of my goal
[Music] you got a team working with you now how do you find good editors and good filmers and good people to work with um I think it's Network either through
other Creator friends to ask them hey do you know anyone who has is available for work uh going to different events and meeting people and then asking them that's probably the biggest one and and then online like upwork is a good spot
it's hard to find good people you really have to like go through like hundreds of people to finally find a good editor that's kind of how I found my first one it was cheap I think they were like seven to ten dollars an hour yeah and if
you Outsource it to other countries then you can save a ton of money that way yeah all right so sure what would be your advice for anyone that maybe is in a full-time job right now and wants to create content for a living or be a
Creator or just to get start creating start creating I think uh take a day one day a week like your Sundays and dedicate that day to creating content and just start building momentum because that's the most important thing if
you're not consistently creating then it's not worth quitting your job you have to first build the momentum build the habits of actually doing it and you have to sacrifice like some of your social life you have to sacrifice other
things in your life but I think it's important to just get the ball rolling
you're doing videos on Tech and gadgets and fitness how do you find ideas for videos yeah it's just a lot of searching on YouTube like I'll search the topic like right now I'm
doing a testosterone supplements video um and one thing is like I can search like the supplements called Tomcat alley so it's like I could search that it's like okay these videos aren't doing that well but if I do testosterone
supplements maybe that is doing well but if I do a video about gaining muscle like oh that's going to do extremely well so yeah the video might be about the same thing but it's like how do I frame it and it's about researching and
then all right what's kind of related to this and then looking at other videos kind of related to that and then just kind of going down a rabbit hole of a whole bunch of YouTube videos to finally figure out what's the best way to kind of frame this video uh and
then just chasing my Curiosities like I'm a very curious person I like to think so if I'm like I want to learn about this I must know like what happens if you do this then that kind of becomes an idea and then it becomes how do I
package that idea yeah do you believe it's important to to surround yourself with creators I think anything you're trying to achieve you must surround yourself with people who are also doing the same thing you know the five chimps Theory you become
like the people you're surrounded by um so I'm a big believer in that and that's why I destroyed myself with other creators and then how did I go about finding them it was just I went to Creator events so like I think I looked
on Meetup or random things like that once you move to a new city it's just like you're just searching online to find whatever you can and then as soon as you meet one then they start to invite you to other events and it becomes like The Snowball Effect where
once you have at least like five Creator friends like they know about other events and it becomes this kind of word of mouth thing um and it's just like going to these dinners going to any kind of event
that's based around creating content you get to meet other people who are also doing the same thing and it's kind of lonely I would say a lot of creators like it's there's not that many creators in the world right people who are
actually serious about it so when you do meet other people who are also in the space like it's just like an instant bond because you know the challenges that they've been through um and you know like this person is also hungry like they're not just like here
to like lollygag I heard that you're trying to run a five minute mile how's that going I got injured but I'm gonna do it um I am I want to do it uh if you know a
guy named Dr Andrew huberman I recently learned that he his fastest time is a 457 so that's my new goal is I want to beat his time in the mile um I think it's like one thing as I'm
getting older is like my body is I've hit the age room my body's deteriorating every year so I just want to see like what am I physically capable of doing and I also want to use that as a goal to
build these long-term habits for longevity of just staying healthy with my cardiovascular system but I did get injured but I'm slowly getting back into running and I'm like I need to take a safe approach I'm not a 21 year old
Invincible man uh just about you know maybe this is not going to take longer than two months like it's gonna take a year two years but chase after that goal
yeah and how close did you get uh 526 is my fastest time so far it's pretty good yeah pretty good almost there almost there okay make sure to like And subscribe turn on your notifications don't ever put that
in a YouTube video