this guy turned $1,000 into a $60 million investment fund through a loophole that nobody's talking about The Syndicate he invited us out to New York
to show us exactly how it works and how anyone can be a venture capitalist without being a member of the ultra Rich Alex has invested in over 270 private
startups and the crazy part is he still hasn't quit his full-time job it's probably a 70 30% split of 70 job 30%
kind of the side hustle VC World a Syndicate is like a special club for investing and now it's popping up everywhere why because it allows regular people like Alex to invest in unicorn
startups with as little as $1,000 but how does someone raise over $60 million from a bunch of random investors by using a strategy called
deal scouting most PES that I meet aren't going to give a [ __ ] about me right my check is small I'm insignificant to that but if you're able to share high quality deals or you actually Source a deal that they end up
doing you'll see the relationship change quite a bit in this video Alex breaks down everything how he'd start over from scratch how he found his first deal and how to evaluate startups that could
return over 20x when I say big winner I mean 50 100 250X are in your investment I'm Pat
walls and this is starter story all right man thanks for having me appreciate it tell me about who you are
and what you're doing my name is Alex ptis and I run what's called a Syndicate a Syndicate is an alternative approach to venture capital where you would invest in the fund and then the manager
would Deploy on your behalf what we do is we provide direct access to a specific deal and allow our limited partners to participate in as little as
$1,000 so I was able to invest in $27 75 companies deploy about 60 million in in total Capital all as a side hustle while I was kind of operating as an early
stage employee at a startup and as I understand it you can technically invest in a startup that you wouldn't be able to invest in previously because you're putting just a little bit of money in and then you are working with a network
of people to put the rest of the money in yeah so I'm not high net worth I don't have a ton of money to deploy right for me this is an Avenue to meet a typical minimum threshold to get
directly on that cap table so if we are to invest 100K in a company and you invest $11,000 into my SPV you're going
to own 1% of this entity that goes on the cap table and then at some point in the future when the company might IPO or exit you will then make a return if we
have a positive outcome something changed in the last few years where now this opportunity is possible can you tell me a little bit more about that yeah you've now seen a number of companies that help individuals set up these spvs so you've got players like
like angelist like sidecar like ca enabling individuals like me who have zero AUM nobody's invested in my fund to go out there and identify a great
founder or great company to invest in I can set up this SPV I can reach out to friends friends of friends those who are accredited investors to participate in that deal and invest through my vehicle
backing syndicates is kind of a unique way for these everyday investors to access this Venture Capital asset class where you need to actually have a relationship with the founder the CEO the company and at the right time of
when they're actually raising around so most of these folks while interested in Venture Capital they don't know the founders they don't know the timing to be talking to the founders we take care of all of that by securing these
allocations knowing the timing knowing the right companies and provide them an Avenue to participate in these deals unlike the public markets where you can simply research buy and trade as you see fit so it's a really nice way to bundle
these checks democratize access to a lot of these startups and I think yeah over the past 5 years we've seen significant growth there and and aot lot of these platforms have played a kind of meaningful role in that as well tell me
about your backstory uh how do you get here out of college I got a sales job at J&J selling medical devices that job took me to Sacramento California decided I need to make the move to New York so
uh did that and that was my kind of intro point to the world of operating and early stage startups so I ended up joining the company called Market access transformation joined as the first
employee pre-launch kind of the stage of it's myself and the founder and kind of a concept that we were looking to bring to life the company went on to have a really great outcome and exit but before we got there and I was on the journey I
kind of felt that my net worth was heavily tied up in one single company so in the process of trying to diversify some of my future net worth I identified kind of syndicates and special purpose
vehicles I started out by backing Jason cis's Syndicate and that was like a great opportunity for me to see some of the deals he was doing and get the
opportunity to participate over you know a one-year period I invested in a handful of startups I started to ramp up deal flow I started to meet other Founders that was kind of the the point and inspiration to launch my own
Syndicate at this time I really invested a lot of time networking with other Venture capitalists right and I branded myself as kind of this deal flow hustle guy who would essentially get the
opportunity to learn from them right what deals do they want to see what deals do they want to participate in how do they think about investing so after like grinding this out for a couple years I ended up co- syndicating deals
meaning I would team up with another Syndicate lead to kind of put both our deal flow together and our LP or our investor base together to get more deals done and that was when things really started to take off so this was probably
end of 2020 so the past 3 and a half years is really where we've been able to lean in now back 275 different companies deploy about 60 million in in total capital and uh pick up a lot of key
learnings back a lot of awesome Founders and companies along the way so what's crazy about all this you've invested in over 270 companies while part-time how the hell did you do this it's navigating
what are the times that I can spend talking to the right Founders scheduling the right intro calls with them for me I'm a morning person I get up very early and that's kind of my opportunity to get in a couple hours of work before kind of
the day job hits so a lot of times it's the early morning meetings it's the late evening meetings I meet Founders for coffee all the time on the weekend it's
probably a 70 30% split of 7 full-time job 30% kind of the side hustle VC world I also believe in kind of the long-term
Vision here I think there's a bigger opportunity this is a growing category I want to be known as you know The Syndicate lead there a lot of that thinking and attitude I think has enabled me to go the extra mile whether
it's taking an hour out of the the evening or the weekend or whatever to meet the founders build a relationship make sure that if they are indeed the right company in the right time for us to invest I'm going to be there to get
that allocation quick break this is me 5 years ago desperate to start my own business but plagued with shiny object syndrome I tried building SAS tools freelancing affiliate marketing but none
of these business ideas ever panned out to anything but everything changed one day when I looked inside and wondered what if instead I built a business around what I'm good at and what I'm
passionate about well that decision led me to building a business that now makes over a million dollar a year and that's what starter story is All About it's a community of thousands of Founders who
changed their life by building an online business around their skills and their passions our 4,000 plus case studies and business idea breakdowns will show you how regular people just like you found
the right idea and turned it into millions for example Luke joined starter story and Dove Andor case study about a newsletter business that makes over $25 million a year just one month later he launched his own newsletter business
that did $5,800 in Revenue in 30 days so if you're serious about finding that right idea click the first link in the description we're running a special for the YouTube family all right enjoy the
video I'll see you around peace let's talk about your first deal uh you invested as I understand only $1,000 into your first deal can you tell me about how that manifested and how it worked I ended up finding this
particular deal through another very early stage Venture Capital fund that I had build a relationship with in this particular company they were raising $2 million at a $6 million valuation we had
the opportunity to invest 150,000 as the final trunch and that company today has recently raised at a $500 million valuation wow so that's
like a 2,000 3,000% return it's a bigger return than you're going to see in the public markets it looks extremely well for all those folks who got involved at that $6 million valuation you've done a
ton of deals what exactly is the selling point and how are you able to round up so much Capital so easily as a part-time job I think for each deal there's a bunch of selling points but there's
really two that stick out one is who is this tier one institutional fund that's leading the round has done the diligence most of these investors will leave the
round and set the terms and folks would not typically have access so part of my role is gaining that access getting the allocation to participate in that round alongside these tier one these
institutional Venture Capital funds for as little as $1,000 um per deal and the second piece is the founders right for early stage investors we don't really know if this product is right or if
they're going to Pivot later on we're betting on people to navigate the probably soon to be choppy Waters and figure out a great solution to the to the problem that they're trying to solve identifying Founders who have a really
good background or Market fit or have shown success in a previous company as a founder or CEO those are the people that we're really looking to identify so yeah if I had to sum it up I'd say we really focus on backing the right people and
investing alongside the right investors 270 companies invested in how do you find all these deals really there's five different ways that we typically Source deals and and access Founders the first
is co- syndicating with other Syndicate leads like myself right A lot of times there will be other syndicates that maybe have a larger allocation than they
can fill and they'll reach out to us um to kind of co- Syndicate the deal team up and put the deal together a second way is relationships with other Venture
Capital funds early on in my day I spent a lot of time building this steel flow hustle guy brand for myself and I shared a bunch of deals with a lot of different VCS today I've been able to access some
deals alongside them when they might be leading the round or they might be setting the terms another way that we access deals is through our portfolio Founders so as we've built relationships with the founders that we've invested in
and been helpful or been easy to work with and become friendly or whatever it may be they're now referring a lot of their founder friends to us which has been a great way to access Founders early on and really in a positive light
from an existing uh portfolio founder another way that we access deals is through other Angel Investors invest very early stage and you know they're
not going to be competitive with us or bigger Venture Capital fund they always take a small sliver of the round itself and so when I can build good relationships with these angels and
Source deals their way they also will share a lot of the deals that they are participating in or have participated in and then the last piece is leveraging our investor base the folks that invest
in our deals a lot of those times they are founders CEOs heads of product engineering a head of sales or run a small business that might sell into these startups so those are kind of the
five different ways that have built a flywheel I'd say over the past four or five years and see a lot of the uh most competitive deals and when you get a deal how do you evaluate how do you know it's something that you should or should
not invest in so the founder CEO and their relevance to the business is always going to be the most important are they in this for the long run do they understand this Market based on their previous role and problems they
may have solved companies they may have worked at are they a multi-time Founder have they shown success in a previous co-founder CEO role then we're also looking at things like how big is this market right and is it a growing Market
is there an opportunity for this to be a really big company or even have multiple big companies in that market are there early signs of product Market fit a lot of times we invest when there's very limited traction and you know the
business is just getting off the ground we want to see those early signs that they are building a product that customers want and will pay for and have the opportunity to scale and then some of the other things we'll look at is who
is co-investing in the route I am not built like an Institutional fund with management fees to work 9 to5 on this and do the diligence that a traditional institutional fund would do so
piggybacking or leaning on these funds that are set up to lead round set terms and sign off or underwrite the deal is also quite important when we think about what's the right fit for us or not for someone watching who wants to start
their own Syndicate how do you get started and how do you start sourcing deals I I think it's really about leaning into building a network of individuals or funds that have access to Deals and figuring out how they can
share them with you and I think in order to build that you really have to have a Pay It Forward mentality with some of these relationships most VCS that I meet aren't going to give a [ __ ] about me right they like my check is small I'm
insignificant to them but if you're able to share high quality deals or you actually Source a deal that they end up doing you'll see the relationship change quite a bit where they actually want to
lean into keeping you happy keeping you top of mind you know I've got examples of VCS that I probably sent 10 20 deals to and it wasn't until the 20th or so that they actually ended up
participating in that round and now like some of these folks who I spent you know couple years sharing deals with I'm just now getting the Unique Look of deals that they are leading and now sharing
with me so once you find the deal what are all the steps that happen until this deal is finalized and all the investors have put their money in the the first part is securing our allocation so
typically we'll be talking to the founder they may have already had a lead VC lead the round and set terms in that case we're ready to secure our allocation and start sharing with our
investors what I would do from there is put together both my deal memo on why we're excited about the opportunity and want to invest and set up the SPV in parallel this is typically about a
two-day process of putting the materials together getting the SPV set up once that's complete I will then send the deal materials to our investor base
typically give them about 1 to 2 weeks to make their decisions in terms of capital um to the particular deal in between that one to two weeks will allow
for you know any follow-up questions investors might want to know more about the founders background or their business model you know 5 years out from now and then from there once we've got
the capital committed which again may be a 1 to 2 week period we would then close out the PV and wire Capital to the company just explain to me how the business model works here how does this
make money for you we make money off of what's called carried interest that we refer to as carry what this means is if you and an investor invest in an SPV
that we run after an outcome an IPO uh an exit years later everything that gets returned on top of the principle that you originally invested we're going to
take a 20% carry of those returns so you would get 80% of the profits so in short I only make money if I return Capital to my limited partners the investment world
has some big numbers for what you're investing in what's the typical Roi for these Investments The Venture Capital asset class is highrisk high reward right this is quite different from public markets when you're investing in
early stage startups you're really trying to identify one or maybe a couple big Winners and when I say big winner I mean you know 50 100 250X Roi in your
investment and that company is going to make up for the other other 10 20 30 5050 losers that you may have invested in in order to be a good early stage investor you have to do a lot of deals
you have to diversify it is really about finding that that big winner that U story that Airbnb story so last question we ask to all of our Founders or investors what would be your advice if
you go sit on Alex's shoulder 5 years ago and what would you say first and foremost start building a network of folks who have unique access to deal
right an awesome startup in a competitive round alongside these Tier 1 VCS if you're able to access that there will be investors out there that want to participate in that deal right there's
multiple ways to find them being able to continue that going forward enables you to build a portfolio which is kind of a track record and a growing resume which will enable you for multiple different
directions right it could be continuing The Syndicate investing in more of the best companies it could be raising your own Venture Capital fund it could be joining a venture Capital fund there's a lot of different routes that you can take and the the earlier and the faster
you can do that and build a network the the quicker you'll show success and this Venture Capital ecosystem all right thank you so much Alex appreciate it this was a blast
thank you follow these steps and you will invest in 270 companies in two
weeks