what if I told you you could turn this blank Google doc into millions of dollars well that's what thousands of people are doing right now on the internet but nobody's talking about it
so I found someone who would Alex Garcia a kid from Austin Texas who makes eight hundred thousand dollars a year writing five different email newsletters he invited me into his house and broke down
everything including a step-by-step blueprint anyone can use to build a six-figured newsletter from scratch if you have those four things you have just about everything you need to run a successful newsletter we also broke down
how to find the right Niche how to get advertisers to pay you thousands of dollars and the fastest way to get your first 10 000 subscribers and from that time frame I went from 2000 Subs to like
eight or nine thousand Subs I think you could build a nine figure company with newsletters thank you hey welcome to Texas thank you good
to see you yeah welcome in thank you all right Alex here we've got one of the coolest jobs on the internet can you tell me a little bit about yourself and what you do um lucky enough that I get to honestly research a bunch of dope content about you know a bunch of marketing campaigns
and get to write newsletters about it so we have marketing exam which is the biggest one we have content examine social examine landing page examine and now DTC examine all in all it's like 150
160 000 total subscribers driving right now roughly in the range of like 65k to 70k a monthly Revenue all from ad sponsors and then on the other end it's like the products that I'm telling you I'm testing right now it's going to be
spun into a product that's bringing in 15 to 20K but my whole life my whole career revolves around content how did you come up with the idea to build newsletters I was a huge fan of the hustle and I saw that they actually had a job opening so I applied for it
because I knew I wanted to be in that space I wanted to understand how to grow a newsletter how to scale a media company and so I applied for a position at the hospital and I got in and when I got to the hustle I gave myself one year
two months probably before I left I really started going you could say like hard on Twitter like making that my primary channel of distribution and started building up the the newsletter kind of tweaking messing with different
ideas of what the content is what the content isn't once I kind of got that then the idea was okay I love hbr I love Harvard Business Review how do I take that idea and that concept and bring it
to marketing and then scale that into marketing and examine let's talk about the opportunity of newsletters some people might see a newsletter and think oh that's a small business what are the numbers here in terms of what you can
really build with the newsletter to me it's how creative you want to get with it morning Brew expanded into 15 20 different Publications and sold for a part of the company for 75 million cash they're now doing over 100 million in
Revenue the hustle I was even there and I don't know the final number but I'm guessing in the range of 20 to 30 million off of one newsletter in a paid product I think you could build it in a nine figure company with newsletters especially in the B2B space the part
that nobody talks about with newsletters is top of funnel for anything else you want to build if you want to launch an agency it is top of funnel for you agency if it works in congruency with your newsletter the potential is endless there's so many different things you can
write about yeah foreign [Music] newsletter how did you go about finding your Niche and what would you recommend others to look for what topic to write
about yeah so I think there's two ways to skin the cat there right like the first one I think about is if you want to write about something that you love that's one way to find the niche right like what on your downtime find yourself reading and wanting to do research about
or already writing about it I think the second is if you are more money driven you're just like want to start a business and sell it what is the topic that's exploding right now what is the thing that people are talking about right now that you can start a business
in for me it was what did I love reading about what did I love talking about what did I love researching about those three things and it all came down to marketing and content and Building Things right that's how I found what I wanted to
write about hey real quick that business you want to start let me show you how you can make your first dollar online 10 times faster by using case studies and as you could read the exact steps to how someone built a million dollar business
and the mistakes they made so you can avoid them when you launch well at starter store we have a library of over 4 000 case studies and business idea breakdowns where you can do this all backed by real data for example Loop
joint starter story and dove into our case study about a newsletter that makes 25 million dollars a year just one month later he launched his own newsletter and did 5 800 in Revenue in 30 days it's
simple he studied what works implemented it and avoided the mistakes of people that were just a few steps ahead of him if you're serious about building a business head to starterstory.com Alex it's only one dollar for seven days and
I'll leave a link in the top of the description much love hope you guys enjoy the rest of the video peace let's talk about how you get your first few subscribers how do you get your first 100 or 1 000 subscribers on a newsletter
yeah so this is something I learned from Noah Kagan and it's this idea of like Hanahan combat when you're trying to get your first 100 subscribers your first thousand subscribers you do the things that aren't you can't really scale and so you're reaching out to people telling
that you that you have a newsletter right you're dming people on LinkedIn you're dming people on Twitter Instagram you're getting friends to push it you're doing little giveaways like you're finding this small things that adds 10
subscribers 15 subscribers right second thing I would do is what we call is like Buffet marketing the idea of like you walk into Golden Corral and you see all this food you're like man I got 20 bucks and I got all this food right now I'm
about to get all these plates and I'm gonna try all this and then what I like I'm gonna go back for and it's like what has the potential to 10x finding those things that have the 10x potential and then honing in on like the one or
two things that always are driving growth if I was trying to start from scratch again I would start first with Hannah hand combat then Buffet marketing then I would optimize scale and continue
refining it yeah this hand-to-hand combat what specifically does that look like that's going on your Facebook page right you have 500 to 800 friends on Facebook that you never go on there that would actually click a link and subscribe something and support you
right for me you know one of the things that I did at the beginning was I wrote 50 marketing threads over 50 days so every day I was publishing a marketing content specifically a Twitter thread and from that time frame I went from it
was like 500 followers on Twitter to 40 000.
in between that I grew my newsletter from I think it was like 2 000 Subs to like eight or nine thousand Subs all right let's talk about how to find good content to write about and content that will keep people subscribed
and coming back for more one way you can do it is you can use a tool where you can put in a certain topic and it will give you the most shared articles on the internet about a certain topic Twitter
advanced search is another great way if you could understand how to use the filters and use advanced search just to find like hidden gems that nobody talks about right like you could put different
keywords in Twitter and find like in my case like that marketing campaigns no one known as ever covered let's talk about monetizing a newsletter how do newsletters make money and how are your newsletters making money right now the
simplest way to monetize a newsletter is via sponsorships that is going out and finding somebody that wants to to get in front of your audience you've built distribution you've created trust with
your audience people want a piece of that so think of your newsletter as Facebook ads as Instagram has as Tick Tock ads where you have the reach you have the potential for a return on ad
spend so now how do I get people to want to pay money to get in front of that group the other way is a paid newsletter I don't know if you're familiar with Lenny's newsletter that is another great way of monetizing your newsletter where
he has the free newsletter that works as top of funnel for his paid newsletter that he charges I think like 8.99 or like 10.99 for or it's more exclusive content I mean specifically right now we
monetizing in two ways the the first way is through sponsorships the second way is through Services which is the testing grounds for a product that we're going to be launching in Q3
foreign what tools do you use to run a newsletter business all right so there's four primary tools that I use and like this is the core of the of the company
it's zapier it is notion it is slack and is an ESP if you have those four things you have just about everything you need to run a successful newsletter you have zapier which connects everything you
have notion which controls everything you have slack to communicate with everyone and you have your ESP which sends the emails out to everybody so you have five newsletters do you write all the content yourself so I hired writers
now for marketing the exam and there's a writer for each Niche tell you kind of a tip for finding a good writer search a very Niche topic on Google and then go on to like Pages two three four like
just deep into the archive of Google read some of these people's content that is such a place to find great writers it is a difficult thing to find good writers but you can find a good writer
do everything you can to keep them and entertain them have you grown your newsletter first one is content marketing and it has been using my Twitter to really grow the newsletter and being able to find like what are the growth pieces of content what are the
pieces of content that the algorithm favors and will push and then the last year and a half that has been Twitter thread so being able to use Twitter threads and segue people to the newsletter the second one has been paid acquisition so that's running Facebook
ads Instagram ads Tick Tock ads Reddit like all you know testing all the different acquisition channels I'll try all sorts of different ctas on my Twitter threads whatever works there is then the basis for a lot of things I'll
do on Pace and then the third is this is newer it's a lot of platforms like spark Loop a lot of platforms like beehive are now in convertkit they give you a scalable way of having cross promotions
so where you can set a budget of ten thousand dollars a month and then piggybacking off somebody else's content yeah or somebody else's newsletter and grow so those have been the three main acquisition channels we talked about the
growth side of how you find readers how do you find advertisers who will pay you money to sponsor your newsletters there's two ways you want to develop how can you get people to want to sponsor you that are readers and then the other
way is outbound the way I want to do it with with inbound traffic or with inbound sponsors is having the newsletter and having a very easy way for people that want to sponsor the newsletter to be able to sponsor the newsletter the second way is the
outbound process all the newsletters in your Niche that already have advertisers and find those advertisers and reach out to those advertisers right like these are already people spending money on newsletters primarily comes down to
courtly mailing say newsletter has 10 000 subscribers how much could you sell an ad stop for if you have 10 000 Subs you could sell anything for over a thousand dollars and people will pay for it to get in front of 10 000 people that
is your direct audience I mean I'd pay a thousand dollars for that [Music] all right you're a world-class marketer you run a business about marketing what's your advice on how to become a
better marketer one you want to find somebody that is where you want to go and you want to learn from them the second thing is build things like Tinker build actual products launch things try
to figure out how you can get your product to a thousand dollars or drive a thousand dollars in sales or whatever the third thing is you have to be not so data driven and like intuition driven and I know you're super into fitness
tell me about your daily routine and what you do outside of marketing exams there's three things that I basically do I work I work out and I hang with my fiance and dogs like that is that is my
routine and so right now that I'm you know I am trading for what's called Austin fit Fest in August 19th so we're about 12 weeks out I'm up by by six by 6 30 I'm training either in the garage at
the collective or at another gym over here called Los campeones but as soon as I finish that session that's usually around 8 or 8 30 shower and the next four hours five hours is deep work or
just work in the office then I'm hitting my second training session usually around 2PM I'll do more work again in the in the office and then I hit my third session and then at night if I'm not
hanging out with Vanessa I'm back in in my little office like I told you and trying to create that that Vibe of like nighttime creativity and just being uh in the office but I mean that's
essentially my routine all right our final question that we ask all entrepreneurs if you could go back to when you were just starting your business or just starting getting into marketing and sit on Alex's shoulder what would you tell them I would build
more things and I would test more things and just try to to continuously build little things that I could ship and I could learn what's good what's not what do people like and I would take very
intentional jobs that are Stepping Stones to where I want to be what I would advise is be very intentional in the things that you give your time and energy to because they're gonna those
are gonna be the things that then Propel you to where you want to be so yeah those that's that's what I would tell somebody thank you Alex awesome dude I appreciate you have amazing and yeah follow us in advice and you'll build a
multi-million dollar newsletter business
foreign