this guy made 11 million dollars in two years with just one product how by capitalizing on one of the biggest marketing opportunities in years user
generated content Oliver brocato started tabs chocolate in his college apartment just two years later he was a millionaire by age 21.
I pretty much drained my entire bank account to go all in on this business we met up with Oliver and he broke down exactly how he's built an 11 million dollar brand how he runs it with zero employees and
why he created a product the world has never seen before so I saw sex chocolate on the internet the secret behind this business lies within a loophole in The Tick Tock algorithm and Oliver breaks down exactly how he's leveraged
user-generated content to take advantage of that loophole I've created my own content machine where every day hundreds of videos are going out and reaching millions of people which in turn is
responsible for the 11 million dollars plus we're going to do this year Oliver is proof that anyone can turn a one product brand into millions with one marketing strategy I'm Pat walls and
this is darker story all right Albert tell us what business you built and how much money you make yeah man um so I sell sex chocolate on the internet in essence we created an
edible for sex we took the most popular and effective natural supplements that typically come in a pill or powder format and we transformed it into a very luxurious high-end experience this year
we're gonna do about 11 million dollars in Revenue so it's pretty incredible how far we've come no outside Investments I've just been constantly reinvesting every dollar back in to fuel the growth
sex chocolate is a wild product idea it really it really stands out and starts a conversation how did you come up with the idea for this my body was scrolling Tick Tock one day he was taking and he saw this video posted by some like
teenage girl uh reviewing a sex chocolate and he sent me the video and eight million views two million likes and I go to look up the product online and they don't even have a website didn't have a social media page didn't
have an Instagram enough Tick Tock and I was like yup this concept is absolutely brilliant clearly they've already validated that it can go viral if I were to take my AI prior experience and
background in this space I can make this into a multi-million dollar brand I then ended up spending a year you know like building this out the right way agonizing over every single little detail in order to create the best
customer experience there's a million products you can pick why sex chocolate yeah we knew from the start that we were going to be able to take this from zero to 100 super fast we had the experience
we had the skill set we had the knowledge and the marketing sauce it was just now about finding a product that would you know intrinsically go viral and that's exactly what tabs is you're scrolling you know through Tick Tock all
day you see sex chocolate what like it's it's super novel people have never seen it before right and so it invokes some sort of reaction which is the key to going battle is you know something what
they call emotional arousal making the viewer feel something and it doesn't matter what you're making them feel it just you need to make them feel like a super intense emotion and that's what invokes people to eight watch the entire
thing and then B like share with their friends which creates intern Vitality let's talk manufacturing and working with suppliers how do you get something that's in your head an idea and turn it
into this yeah absolutely you know there's first the Box itself we had to like design that kind of raw files I was designing them myself on canva and figma and then we sent it over to a professional designer to really clean it
up then we have to get 3D renders made and then we sent it over to our manufacturer in China the boxes are made in China the chocolate and anything that touches the chocolate is made in the United States that's super super
important to me uh you know in terms of the Box itself once we have the design file once we had the 3D render we sent it over to them and they made their first prototype and then there's the chocolate itself in order to create the
chocolate they're like four or five different Niche supplement manufacturers you know each supplement has its own independent manufacturer because we Source the best of the best and then each chocolate is wrapped in a plastic
that has its own you know manufacturer and then you know the chocolate doesn't just spawn in this format there's our logo the two T's over here and then there's a clean brick so that you know you can break it and split it right I
mean I don't know get away from you oh but yeah I mean that's kind of what the whole entire um you know supply chain looks like and tell me about some of those mistakes
that you made in the moving pieces what are like the top three Melodies uh Inventory management yeah yeah so I could tell you like right off the bat um
when we sold out we decided to ship our next order of Boxes by but the reason being is that when you ship it by boat it's a lot a lot cheaper than shipping it airfry but it also takes four times
as long so we ordered you know like I think it was like 60 or 70 000 boxes and it was a disaster the container got delayed and so you know as a result we basically just put everything on pause we moved to pre-orders but you know
sales just decline decline decline almost went to zero so you know there have been many many times where we've run out of chocolate or we weren't able to forecast demand properly so what we've been trying to do is just order as much inventory as we possibly can and
it's which is why we've been reinvesting every dollar back into buying as many boxes and chocolates so that we can hopefully be prepared but it's been a Perpetual problem in fact in our first year of business we we were out of stock
for more months than we had stock and we still put up like four million dollars so yeah pretty proud about that hey real quick that business you want to start let me show you how you can make your
first dollar 10 times faster by using case studies imagine you could read the exact steps to how someone built a million dollar business and the mistakes they made so you can avoid them when you launch well at starter store we have a
library of over 4 000 case studies and business idea breakdowns where you can do this all backed by real data for example Luke joined starter story and dove into our case study about a newsletter that makes 25 million dollars
a year just one month later he launched his own newsletter that did five thousand eight hundred dollars in Revenue in the first 30 days it's simple you studied what works implemented it and avoided the mistakes of people that
were just a few steps ahead of them if you're serious about building something check out starstory.com or running a special deal this week and you can click the link below in the description to get it much love and I hope you guys enjoy the rest of the video peace
[Music] let's talk about the power of a brand there's a lot of people on YouTube that talk about Drop Shipping and how it's easy to get started what's the difference between what you're doing and
Drop Shipping everybody that you see on YouTube like perpetuates like this Drop Shipping story like oh like you want to get rich overnight like make money Drop Shipping the only people making money through this Drop Shipping thing are the
people that are selling the courses like secret for you it's the YouTuber that's behind the camera that's like get into jobs you're getting into jobs like not like they're the only ones profiting on that Drop Shipping sucks you're selling
a trendy product in an incredibly saturated market and you have no competitive Advantage why is the consumer going to buy it from you versus buying it from Amazon why are they going to buy it from you versus you know
buying it from the other 150 sellers that are Drop Shipping the Sim exact the answer is that they're not the power of the brand is dropping a product on your website and in 30 seconds it's sold out
the power of the brand is creating a community and like an identity uh you know between you and your consumer where they live and breathe and die for your [ __ ] when you unlock something like that
you made it because it doesn't matter what you sell it doesn't matter what you drop you got a cult like following and on a business sense what that means is that you have Evergreen customers
forever so like when you have new product drops when you introduce new skus like you know that people are coming back and you're going to be able to make money off of this customer cohort time and time again on top of
that you know with the brand You're Building equity the people that make money I'm talking real money they don't make it off the cash flow they don't make it off the yearly sales they're making it off the
exit with Drop Shipping there is no brand equity which puts you in this really difficult spot to ever build any sort of thing that's concrete or build anything that's of real value because
every two months you're you're closing down shop opening a new shop closing down shop opening a new shop so at the end of the day people that are thinking long term and people that are focused on building brands are always going to win
all right man you're a young guy only 21 years old with massive success made Millions take me through your minds at the time where you really did decide okay I'm gonna start something what was
really kind of like the impetus was Christmas break when I was a freshman in college you know it was at the time and so there was like this two-month break between first semester and second semester and so you know during that
break I'm back at home I'm like sitting around my house and I was like this is like the perfect time and opportunity to build something and so I did just that and it took it took a year to go from
idea to bring it into reality you know it was super slow like I'm not going to sugarcoat it like there were weeks where I wasn't even working on the business because I was waiting on this person or I was waiting on this to get done I was waiting on this thing for this thing
like you know it didn't just like kind of like materialize overnight it was a long long long process but once we had product in hand and we had an incredible product that you know I poured my Blood
Sweat and Tears into over that year we hit the ground running and in our first three weeks we sold out of all of our inventory and in our first month we had to move to pre-order and we did over 280
000 in Revenue at like 50 net margins because we were just going viral left and right it was absolutely Bonkers and so you know from that point on like I knew that I had something and I knew
that I had to like see it through in order to take it to the next level all right let's talk startup costs how much did it cost to start tabs and how much does it cost to start an e-commerce business so I started tabs with thirty thousand dollars total I pretty much
drained my entire bank account which came from like all my previous Ventures from when I was younger to go all in on this business so like I don't know if that would be like the average business I think that like honestly you could
probably start anything like any sort of econ brand at least with an MVP with like 10 grand I think like the the biggest cost the r d side of things right like the research and development
of the the product itself eh and then B like in terms of like developing that sample like that first initial sample once you have that down it's then about finding a manufacturer that's willing to
work with you because here's the deal a lot of Manufacturers don't give you the time of day because you're too small so if you could find a manufacturer like a small guy that's like willing to kind of take you under their wing and like that on you you can you can for sure make
something happen for sub 10 grand yeah how do you find a small manufacturer that will take a bet on you yeah Google man everything everything is at our fingertips I literally typed in on
Google chocolate contract manufacturer I went through all the pages on Google like the first 20 or 25 pages I made a spreadsheet you know collecting their information their name their website
link I was just ringing them up I would just literally like make phone calls and dial them up send out emails um and go from there
[Music] let's talk about marketing I know you've done hundreds of millions of views on Tick Tock and you make most of your business through short form social media
yeah can you tell me more about how that works yeah I basically had like hundreds of people that are on my payroll and they're pushing out content every single day they're putting up videos on tick
tock on Instagram on YouTube any short form platform you can imagine I'm on it and so through that I've created my own content machine where every day hundreds of videos are going out and reaching
millions of people which in turn drives tens hundreds of thousands of dollars in sales a day and you know on a macro level is responsible for the 11 million dollars plus we're going to do this year
and so you actually have a bunch of people that just make content for you yeah dude I have like over like 60 people that make content out of thousands of people that like post the content across a web of accounts what
kind of videos are they yeah so I try to make them seem as native as possible consumers are smart if they think it's an app they're not going to watch it so
I make the videos like super on par with whatever's trending in the moment whatever sound is popping whatever like movement is happening like whatever it is like my creators are making content
around that and then of course we have some like validated Concepts that like push really hard but yeah that's pretty much it so you don't do a lot of like paid ads not really it's like mostly organic it's most like all the content
creators and the reposters I do double and paid where like I take my most model creatives and play these meme pages that have tens of millions of followers to post my content and then I also run a little bit of Google ads I do email and
text message marketing which is more like kind of bottom of the funnel but yeah I mean for the most part it's a pretty uh crazy organic system that I pioneered all right to close this interview out some people will be watching this that want to start their
own brand they want to start their own e-commerce brand potentially what's one thing they can do today to get started the best advice that I can give anybody that's like watching this today is that like I'm not smarter than you I don't have a higher IQ there's a lot of
something like special like sauce and I'm gatekeeping literally just go out there and make some [ __ ] happen and uh never look back and in three or five or ten years from now
they're not going to recognize like how much progress you've made because it doesn't just all happen at once it's like every day you're compounding compounding compounding and then one day you wake up and you know you're worth millions of dollars and that's kind of
how it is thank you sir foreign