this is Karthik he turned 500 bucks into 10 million dollars by building four different e-commerce companies what's even crazier is that he built these companies with no funding and he had a
full-time job I'd go in at you know 8 AM and I'd get off around 5 36 and then I'll be working till midnight I do it all over again this guy is a hustler one of the hardest working people I've ever
met we were actually starting a bunch of other businesses so we had a promotions company a discount card storage company and then we had this apparel business in this episode he invited me into his New
York City Apartment to show me exactly how he's made Millions he also told me the secret to why his newest company has become one of the biggest brands in college sports and it's got something to
do with changes to the NCAA Karthik also told me how he's made millions in sales without spending a dime on ads get into these marketplaces right that's free marketing you guys are gonna love this
interview it's a master class of what it takes to build a 10 million online business I'm Pat walls and this is starter story iPod that you're running multiple businesses right now can you give us a
breakdown of everything that you've built yeah so we actually started off doing custom fraternity and sorority merchandise custom is the key word right at the end of the day we we went after
one niche market which was serving fraternities sororities on campus but we were doing custom stuff for their events which then led into doing custom stuff for the colleges and departments on campus we went ahead and got essentially
300 College licenses to do all that merchandise for the campus organizations departments on campus and then naturally as we started growing out our sales team we started getting ancillary business to
do custom merchandise for businesses so then we launched threadly which is our custom apparel business for businesses you know fundraisers non-profits and
then in the last year with us kind of building out these other businesses we built Tech along the way to kind of manage these different brands and all the back-end processes and us being in
the license space for so long we actually saw an opportunity when the name image likeness Supreme Court ruling came out where student athletes can monetize on their name image and likeness so with that we actually got
into making merchandise co-branded with the college and the athlete which is the brand is athlete's thread and so really focused on custom branded merchandise and licensed merchandise is the two
buckets that I would put it in as far as what we do as a whole but it is kind of Nest within four Brands so you got Greek house for fraternities and sororities College thread for all the Departments
and organizations threadly for corporate companies and then now athletes thread for athletes and colleges yeah so essentially you know different niches within the apparel industry and these
are all websites where people can buy merchandise like Shopify websites or exactly so one is custom right you would come to us and say hey we want this custom design or product made we would
design it and produce it for you on a kind of like a bulk basis or bulk order basis so that's a little bit less on the direct to Consumer side it's more business to business but then yes for
athlete's threat you're coming on and you're buying one item for for that athlete in college and just use yeah through Shopify tell us a little bit about your life before athletes threaten your business that you're running what's the journey that brought you to building
this business yeah so one of my fraternity brothers and I we just saw a need to fill the market with just a better vendor on the custom apparel side
and this was back in 2013 when you know technology was really really kind of coming to the Forefront of every business we really rode that train hard and we started building out an order
management platform as well as a customer portal but as we were figuring out this business Luke and I my co-founder we were actually starting a bunch of other businesses so we had a
promotions company where we threw concerts we had a discount card that we would sell to uh students student organizations to raise money and then we had this apparel business and you know
uh Luke also started a storage company a storage and retrieval company for College college students so we had multiple tries at entrepreneurship in college but this one it happened you
know the first year we did 50 000 second version a hundred thousand and this was us kind of working on it part time in between school doing all the stuff that a student would do and then also um our other businesses we were trying to stand
up and get running as well and then upon graduation I actually got a full-time job at Amazon you had a full-time job and you're working on this on the side uh yeah I mean it was uh you know what
was crazy about Amazon was I had to work from Wednesday night to Sunday morning so I'd come in Wednesday night at literally 11 pm and I would get off
between 11 A.M to 12 p.m go home sleep and then I'd wake up in the evening start working on Greek house then go into Amazon do it all over again
um and in Salesforce same cycle but I had a little bit of a more normal schedule I'd go in at you know 8 A.M and I'd get off around 5 36 and then I'd be working till midnight and do it all over
again and then week guns you know typically got maybe one weekend day off uh Saturday but yeah it was it was pretty much Six Days on um and one day off kind of deal for a
good good two two and a half years we'll give you the motivation to do all that for so long yeah so um my family's an immigrant you know have really humble
beginnings since we moved here um you know I we immigrated to from India to here I was born in Bangalore when I was seven years old so I think one we've you know I've always seen my
parents work hard and I think that's always hard work has always been instilled in me um but two you know my parents gave up everything from a family perspective to to move my brother and I
over here and now my sister is here as well um but you know we we just you know we're very fortunate to have the opportunity to live in a country where the opportunities you know you can go
out and get it and so uh you know I think just wanting to make my parents proud it would be like number two and just like really I think that's supersedes almost everything but three
you know I think ultimately uh you know every time I go back to India or you know we have employees all over the world I just like realize how fortunate I am and we are to live in a country
like the US to be able to build startups without barriers so um yeah you know I think it's just it's just what I've always known um you know I have entrepreneurship all throughout my family we have you know
over 24 restaurants in India so it runs all throughout our family as well so I'd say It's a combination of all that and I'm just very fortunate that I get to do this every day all right so you started
Greek House in your dorm room or your college basement with only 500 bucks what did that look like at the time yeah so um we were basically in our
fraternity house and so we would literally meet in the common areas and and basically get a sales plan going and um you know a lot of what we did to
start our business was there's Savvy college kids and this is before you know we had in Instagram and different ways to reach the you know different folks there we would just go out start texting
our friends and in different sororities and fraternities try and figure out who's making the decision to buy T-shirts and just we're out there hustling and kind of working through our networks meeting people on campus going
to different you know the student organization meetings going and pitching to them there on hey you should use us to buy your shirts and that was kind of our Edge was we were these young Hustlers that could go out and just you
know we were we were sharp we really liked sales and really just going out and pitching people and you know we probably sucked at sales in the beginning but you know over time you get better and better your pitch gets refined but you know putting yourself
out there and just going for it it's the best thing you can do as a college student so I always tell students to just go for it if you're in college you know there's no reason you can't be
starting a side hustle or a business while you're in school [Music]
I know building a licensing business can be complicated are there any really scary moments while building this business or any big obstacles that you had to get through to get where you are today yeah actually
um when I went first went full time with the business in 2016 you know moved all my stuff down to Los Angeles where my two other business partners were one of my co-founders were there uh you know
we're we're three months in and uh things are going great you know sales are picking up we're seeing a lot of growth working a lot of hours but having a lot of fun working our living room at
this one middle desk in a really small apartment in La just really working and grinding away but you know about a month about four months in in April we get a notice from one of the licensing
organizations saying hey you're not paying royalties and we're finding out that there's all these sales that you're basically not reporting on and we're like what are you talking about and so we started looking into it and ended up
finding out a way licensing's a whole thing we have to get approved rude we have to pay royalties and so we basically got audited and long long
story short we had a forty thousand dollar bill four months into it which you know at the time you know we were doing just under a million in sales and that was really scary right that's like
four percent of our costs and we didn't even have 40K in the bank to roll with and so you know we went back to the licensing agency and said hey you know we want to be in this industry for the
long term you know we will make it right give us some time to make these payments we'll give you one lump sum now and the rest over the course of you know 12 14 months and so um it was a very valuable
lesson but you know at the time you know I thought I was gonna have to go back to work full time working in in Corporate America I know you probably have a million skus
how do you ship out all this take orders and and manage this whole operation yeah so we've uh we've built out a supply chain um so we don't manufacture anything in-house but we work with amazing print
and production Partners all throughout the US and so that's been accumulation of just us building relationships over the last 10 years but in most Industries
right on a distributor level like us it's easy to find manufacturers it's hard to find good manufacturers or great manufacturing partners and so these are relationships
we've had to develop over the years but in managing that right one is we've built out a Vendor Portal so that they can manage all their orders effectively so in some cases you know we've come
into that shop that we work with the the printer production partner and said hey you know we want to work with you these are our prices but we are also going to provide you Tech so that when you
service our account it takes one tenth of time to service than it does for your other customers because we're going to keep everything so organized and so clean for you so that you know you don't
have to to to manage 100 other aspects of the admin side of the workload and so um that's what's really kind of led us to having great Partners is being able
to build out you know systems and processes for them that makes their job easy so that you know there's no question when an order comes through on what needs to be printed who it needs to go to we give that to them in an
organized fashion and we've helped automate and streamline their workflows on the production line all right let's talk about competition in the e-commerce space anyone can start a Shopify store and I know that 90 of Shopify stores
fail so how do you differentiate yourself as a brand and how do you look at competition one from a like just a company and Landscape perspective what's
great about being in the licensed industry right there is a lot of hurdles to get to where we are first and foremost you need to have licenses for the call colleges and then you need to
get rights for from each athlete so that hurdle alone 99.99 of companies will not get through that hurdle so that really Slims down
you know the vendors and the competition in the first place the second area that we've really been focusing on is building a true brand so you know we went from doing custom merchandise to
now doing our own brand with athletes thread right and how we've been differentiating from building a brand I mean one is amazing customer service and turnaround time right when we ship
product out you know that is the first kind of like way that we differentiate is making sure that each customer when they reach out to us they're getting a response in less than four hours time
they are also you know products are not shipping out in the two to three business days we guarantee we harp on our vendors to really get those out and making sure that we meet our slas and so
that's the first area where our brand is really strong is good product and good product delivery the next area I would say is that we've been doing a lot of things around our brand so we're doing neck
labels we're doing custom packaging so really starting to build a brand there and then the third is from a social media perspective right we have a fairly young team who loves sports so we're
really trying to lean into that and so really put out really engaging and cool content that not just the students Vibe with but the athletes survive with and also the sports teams the individual
teams right they all Vibe with marketing is the hardest thing to do as a business it's easy to start a business hard to grow it what is your marketing strategy look like and what's all the
ways that you get sales and reach customers yeah so when we first started we went deep into a few different channels we originally started with outbound email marketing which is
one-to-one emails called outreaches and then that turned into outbound sales so we were going much more of a direct response route and that's what really worked for us it was cost effective
scalable we were able to find a lot of emails and contacts online the second approach that's really worked for us is building out an affiliate or an ambassador program right what's great about those kinds of programs is that
you're not just spreading your word about the product you're finding Advocates that are selling your brand on your behalf right whether they're you know posting content they're sending it
to their friends they're posting their discount codes you know what's great about that is you know if you do send them free product yes that's some initial investment up front but they can also give you content on the back end
right so that you're able to reuse it repurpose it and start building your brand further and then it's kind of like you know kill two versions one stone they're also going out and promoting it so you get content and you get promotion
of your product um and then third right is paid marketing um you know we love paid search because when somebody's searching for Google for
a Bryce young t-shirt right they are really looking for that specific item so um there's there's very high level of intent right people are looking for
these items whereas social media you're trying to just get more products in front of them based on interest or based on different demographics and so we found that page search on Google has
been highly effective and then lastly get into these marketplaces right that's free marketing meaning if you can get your product on Etsy get it on Etsy if you can get it on Google shopping get it
on Google shopping right these marketplaces go a long way because you know I found that a lot of people now out they just go to they click on shopping when they Google something and
they're looking for products to purchase they're literally clicking on that shopping tab so that it Aggregates all the sites that Google might be connected to on the shopping side
hi Karthik what would you say are the most important skills to building a business like yours yeah so I think uh first being remote right communication
is so key that's the speed of communication the quality communication the clarity I think communication is just a huge undertaking and there's different forms of communication right
written verbal uh even recording videos and sharing it with your team creating that kind of asynchronous Harmony within the company where you don't have to meet to you know figure out these issues
right I think is what has really led us to be successful on the internal side and then externally right how you're communicating with customers and clients that's really really key so I'd say communication is very top there written
verbal and just even yeah recording videos I would say is its own form um then number two is like the ability to learn anything or teach yourself something right there's so many
resources online you know everything is a Google search away from you learning it on your own and oftentimes you know I think even I see it in our employees where they'll get stuck on a problem and
I'll they'll come to me and I I don't know the answer to the problem what do I do I go to Google and I search it right so trying to get in that mindset where there is always an answer out there for your problems and then third I think
surrounding yourself with either a good co-founder and or advisor right or mentors that have done it before and have been in your position right but
also they can be very blunt with you and very critique it so I don't know if it's necessarily as much of a skill or as a tactic right is getting and hiring good
people around you whether it be advisors co-founders employees I think really getting that skill down is really really important um and just kind of getting getting it getting a good team under under you or
behind you is is really really important what advice would you have for someone who's just starting a Shopify or e-commerce or anything in the retail and Merchandising space yeah so I think the
first is like just get started I think like a lot of people overthink how and when or what to do do to get started whether it's writing up a business planning strategy right and I'm not
saying go right at 50 page business plan but develop parts of a business plan and then start implementing some of that right away you're going to learn more on the job than you will uh just kind of reading stuff and articles online and
then lastly I'd say humility right and just making sure like you don't know everything and kind of having that learning mindset and that just really wanting to engulf yourself in the
industry or market and learning from the ground up I think that's a really key aspect of Entrepreneurship is just having that intellectual or that that genuine curiosity I think is really key
to success as an entrepreneur