this is David he built an AI app that is now valued at over a million dollar and the crazy part is he built it all with no code he invit us into his house to
show us exactly how he built this thing with a family a full-time job and just working a couple hours a day really took me just a couple weeks came down to learning all of this content mostly
through YouTube David launched his product using a viral marketing strategy that got him thousands of users in just a few days but what goes up must come down I blew
through like $5,000 in days I had a decision to make right it's either shut it down or keep going in this video he breaks down how he bounced back how he
made his first dollar and how he plans to build a business that won't be replaced by chat gbt my vision moving forward is to build something that cannot be replicated both in chat gbt as
well as Microsoft this is the breakdown on how a normal guy turned one idea into a a million-- dooll business on just a few hours a day I'm Pat walls and this is starter story
David thanks for having me thanks for coming on ever I love your story tell me a little about who you are and what you built sure daveid brusser built what was called XL for real bot now it's
just called for real bot Microsoft gave me a uh season doist a few months ago or so and so it's a software that really helps people work faster and smarter with data there's really three main
products Ai and spreadsheets it's col like chat GPT inside both Excel and Google Sheets for whe generators that translates text into formulas with the help of AI and then the last product
where a lot of my time and resources have g into is called the data analyzer where it's kind of like zappier you can upload your data and then through natural language get answers analysis
charts modeling all done by just typing in some words the application has been around for about a year and a half and during that time there's now roughly
about 750,000 users and of those 750k there's about 5,000 people that pay for unlimited access to Tool and during that
time it's has reached about $226,000 a monthly recr as I understand you started formula bot while you had a full-time job tell me a little bit more about that
story it was July of uh 2022 I had this opportunity and the opportunity was my youngest one was about to be born and so I knew I was going to have about 6 weeks
to to do something and I've been working a full-time job since I graduated college 2011 and I've always kind of had that entrepreneurial neck basically said okay I've got 6 weeks let's build something people always say scratch your
own itch right solve your own problem and my problem was I I was getting so bogg down with all of these Junior adal they come knocking on my office door like hey can you help me with this for
me can you help me with that I kind of thought okay my itch is helping people with Excel while chat gbt wasn't around then the actual technology was I
actually asked the open AI uh application I said hey I'm thinking about building this app what's a good name for it and uh one of the names I
suggested uh was Excel formula do thing you do of course is you go to go daddy it was available and then I was like let me just see if someone's built this yet
and I scour the internet for hours couldn't find it I'm like this is it I'm on the something special it was tough try to find that balance between personal life you know I I can't help
but to a certain extent stay on the grid for my full-time job especially in the senior position that I was in and so while I wasn't working I still had access to my phone people were still
asking me questions here and there but then in the back of my mind I'm like I've got this idea that I have to execute out I tried to spend as much time with the family especially early on but I couldn't have book time myself
kind of stepping away for a little bit go to coffee shops wh it might be and just kind of put my head down and execute and uh there were definitely a lot of nights where I only got a couple hours of sleep my wife at that time
thought I was crazy uh especially because I I didn't really have a clear path I just know wanted to build this thing so from what I understand you have no experience coding how did you build
and launch something like this I'm not a coder by any means if I see it I kind of know okay that's JavaScript that's HTML and I knew for what I wanted to build as an MVP it would take a pretty
significant time to build it with code and I at that time wasn't making any money I didn't want to hire anyone because I just had an idea and so that's for where I was really exposed to uh the
the no code industry I was exposed to bubble.io that was really the only application that I really dove into to to build cuz it was the most well-known and based on the research that I had
done that the easiest of all the not code Solutions the first place I went was the bubble official website for just kind of reading some documentation but there's so much documentation out
there which is a good thing kind of where I got hung up was very isolated issues that I was TR Sol but that's really where YouTube University came in there are some awesome bubble developers
out there that produce such high quality content on YouTube and it's all free at that time the whole app was in bubble it was 100% no code probably up until maybe
four or 5 months ago it went from 100% no Cove to now it's about I would say like 5 or 10% as you get more experience with no code you start to understand
some of the limitations there's not a lot but there are some limitations David is the perfect example of how someone with zero experience turned one idea into hundreds of thousands of dollars
but that comes with knowing the right information and finding the right problems to solve now imagine there's a place that gave you all this the problems to solve the blueprints to solve them and the strategies that turn
simple ideas into million-dollar businesses well at start story we have a library of over 4,000 case studies and business idea breakdowns where you can access this all backed by data from real
entrepreneurs so if you're serious about building a profitable side project and joining a tight-knit community of Founders head to the first link in the description and we're going to give you
52 micro SAS ideas just like David's so you can get started on your journey much love enjoy the rest of the video peace all right so you have this MVP that you built from scratch how do you get your
first customer and how do you get a ton of people to use it the first people I told were the people that were at my full-time job at that time and they're like oh my God this is amazing they thought it took me months to build this
thing really took me just a couple weeks and then that really kind of speaks to the power of no code um because if you were to code it it would take much longer and so my next step was I need to
tell more people about this tool and so naturally the next place I want was Reddit went to the XL subreddit where there's probably several hundred people
that follow it RIT title was AI XL formula generator and I think I mentioned it was free and it was just a title and the description was just the link minutes later it was like the top
post of the day turned into the top post of the week it blew up as much as like something can blow up within the Excel Community a couple of days after that someone in the CET section said you
should post this on the Internet is beautiful subreddit and so I posted it there that was like the thing that put the app over for the edge and made it go viral for months and so I had posted
there it got some 10,000 up votes thousands of comments yeah I got thousands and thousands of people visiting the site using the app all
right so you have thousands of users how do you start making actual money from this the next thing I did was want's the open AI website what's the billing
section it just like oh God I I blew through like $5,000 and
open AI API costs in days I had a decision to make right it's either shut it down or keep going and so I acre this
huge bill over that time I recouped some of it back I put up a link like a stripe link where it's just like hey my name's David I built this app it went viral
give me Z feel free to donate so I made a few,000 back I was super Scrappy of like trying to make something back at that time it was pretty poetic
especially probably at its peak of virality the host from the um esorts ESPN XL competition I didn't say it
correct for good something like that but it's basically like extreme sports but it's for Excel the host reached out to me and said hey we have our competition on on ESPN in a couple of weeks can we
run a beta ad I'm like sure I'm like and at that time I was like maybe that's how I before even thought about subscriptions I'm like maybe that's how I can make money at least in the interim
is just running ads so I ran some Google ads made a few bucks here and there it just it definitely wasn't worth the hassle but I I ran an ad for ESPN for
like a week and it drove a ton of clicks and it was actually pretty funny because the guy asked me to design the creative I'm like look dude like you've seen the website especially at that time it was a
single page piece of crap it wasn't crave at all but I I locked something up for he said okay works for me and so some of the donations that came in a
couple of sponsorships it it gave me the motivation to kind of keep going and not just completely shut this thing down and so then a few months later launch with a
pay wall logins and the whole nine yards let's talk about product talking to customers how you figured out what features to build early on just kind of scratch my own itch and what would bring
me value and what started off as just a XL formula generator turned into different generators that was really just the first product it was actually interesting because at that time my site
was blowing up and I I I took a few phone calls with VCS they would ask me you know what's your vision what's your broader vision and I would just say more generators and they're like okay I never
got called back I didn't have a broader Vision that's where I started talking to people that I work with who it's required to work with data in spreadsheets started asking asking them
and see what they liked what they didn't like but occasionally and and this is where I think I would get the most value talking with customers a lot of them
email me basic Excel questions that couldn't necessarily be answered through an Excel formula generator they would literally email me their Excel files they're like hey your Excel formula
generator couldn't do this can you help me with this and it wasn't even to like build a formula it was to like build a report where I have no domain knowledge of of of what they're trying to accomplish I would probably get one
email a week of someone just sending me a file and so I thought okay you know what even if they're not a paying customer I'm going to take this but guess what I'm going to do it with you
on a phone call and I'll do your work for you but every time I do it they have to hop on a call at me and they have to ask questions about what they like and what they don't like about the product as well as some ideas that they have and
so the culmination of kind of scratching my own itch leading on my network and having these kind of impromptu phone calls kind of revolutionized the product away from just being an XL formula
generator to just kind of being this all-in platform for anything that you do with data analytics building a SAS product software product there's probably going to be a lot of competitors coming in tell me about how
that works product took me a few weeks to build this app and a few weeks after that I think there was probably 10 other EXL formula generator sites and the
frustrating part was they all sounded the same right at that time Excel formula bot Excel formula generator another one was called Excel formulator they all sounded the same and when you'd
go to Google and you'd search mine you'd see the other couple ones right there so at that point it was really a Ras to the bottom and my prices especially early on it was $3 I was getting pretty
frustrated just all of the competition that was coming in and literally like carbon copying my exact application not only like what it does but also the
front end the name and then I just kind of reached the point where I knew I was going to have to build something that isn't just a simple input output box few
months later EXL for bot was was getting more and more popularity Microsoft actually reached out to me they reached out to me twice one for a Seas business and the other one it was someone that
was on their add-ons team Excel has you know thousands and thousands of partners that they work with to build an add-on that supplements what you can do with Excel they reached out to me and said
hey we want to take your XL formula bot and add it within our add-on store let us build it for you I was like sure how much does it cost they're like we'll do
it for free I'm like this is awesome and then as they were building it I was like wait a second they're just going to hijack this idea and build it as one of
the many features in their in their Suite couple weeks after that they had announced their partnership with open AI everyone's so excited for AI being integrated in the office suite and I'm
like I am so crude and so that's where kind of went back to me being my own competition where I had to really take a
step back and think through what is this product going to be once Microsoft embeds this product within their Suite have even talked about chat GPT chat GPT
especially at this time as well it was free and it it still is free for unlimited usage at that time you had to paid $299 now you got to pay $9 it's got
to work its way up $299 to $699 to $9 and you have to pay for unlimited usage whereas chat GPT has always been free
and so I have about 5% CH 10% of the reason why people CH is because of chat GPT and so early on before a lot of the
newer products especially the the data analyzer where you can upload your data and to with it the competitive Advantage I had over chat GPT was really convenience generate formulas within
Excel you don't have to leave your spreadsheets you don't have to open up your browser you don't have to open up chat gbt and write list long prompt you can do it all there convenience and
customization when you sign up you can put in your language your speaking language you can put in your language for what you prefer for Excel because there's a lot of people out there that speak in in Spanish but they prefer the
Spanish version of Excel and then also vice versa again Excel it's used by a billion people in the world Excel for laot is used by every single country and thousands of languishes so early on it
really was convenience and customization but that can only take you so far and so more so recently with the addition of the new features and new products it's
moved from that to you can no longer do that in chat GPT and eventually when Microsoft really just this past week builds AI into their own tool right now
my vision moving for Bo is to build something that cannot be replicated both in chat gbt as well as Microsoft hey Pat from starter story here thank you guys so much for watching I really hope
David's story inspires and motivates some of you to get started on your own thing if you're curious about doing something similar but you're still looking for an idea well right now you can download our Deep dive SAS report
for free it breaks down 52 different micro SAS ideas and tons of other stuff you'd want to know just click the first link in the description and if you're serious about building it then consider
joining starter story and we'll help you do that much love and I'll see you guys in the next one [Music] peace