what if I just went for it this was the question I asked myself one summer for probably the 39th time it was a Sunday and I was about to get on a
flight across the country I just spent the weekend drinking into Oblivion with my friends the whole week felt like a blur I was so hung over and like with every other hangover I began to ponder
my life I couldn't stop thinking about how much I didn't want this living for the weekends dreading Mondays a life full of comfort yet devoid of any freedom I was nearly 30 years old
already many years into my so-called career Successful by Society standards but something just didn't feel right you see as a kid I always had
dreams I'd be different but as life went on those dreams they faded away and I found myself stuck behind a desk all thanks to a series of decisions I thought were in my best interest College
the fancy job the big city these decisions did I make them for me or did I make them for everyone but me and whenever I found myself alone in the airport hung over like this these dreams
would come back it was at this moment I found myself wondering what if I just went for it one year that's all I need what would happen if I chased my dreams for 365 days
and that's when it all [Music]
started in that moment I reached into my suitcase and pulled out the book I've been struggling to get through a book called Think and Grow Rich this book would eventually rewire my brain for
success but for now I flip to my bookmark and read this whatever the mind can conceive and believe it can achieve a simple quote but I read it over and
over and over if you want to change you must believe in that change you must visualize that change but what change did I want I wanted to be free of my
student loan in credit card debt I wanted to work on things I was passionate about I wanted to be free but Dreams they're not enough you must create a detailed plan of action to
achieve your goal so what would be my plan of action I will stop spending money on I'll dedicate nights and weekends to building my future I will start building a business I wrote
all this down on a tiny little note card this was my Manifesto exactly what I want and exactly how I'll get there when I got home I nailed this little note
card right above my bed and I read it over and over every night night and every evening until it was etched in my
memory what should I even work on what am I actually passionate about and how can I actually make money from it these questions they paralyzed me they
prevented me from ever actually getting started and that's when I realized I was obsessed with control I was obsessed with the idea of having it all figured
out and this made me scared of committing to anything but really I was scared of failure but this Manifesto this little piece of paper right here it
did one thing it forced me to get started and getting started even in the tiniest way taught me something that would change everything failure is
success when I finally gave myself permission to fail it unlocked the
answer I knew I wanted to build a business but what do I work on getting started was the first part but I quickly found myself trying to build things I had no business doing my first business
idea lasted about 3 weeks until I realized I was building something because someone told me it could make money online I had no passion for the idea and no skills that would help me build it and that's when I went back to
the drawing board and looked for an idea that only I could build something that aligned perfectly with my skills my passions and of course something that
could actually make money within days I came up with the idea for starter story a platform where you could see how regular people like you and me built businesses that changed their lives
exactly how they found their ideas exactly how they launched and exactly how they got customers this was the product that I knew and this was the product that only I
could build so why not create it for the world I purchased the domain name I put together a plan I started building and everything started to click I realized that this idea it had been living in my
head all along but my obsession with control my fear of failure prevented me from ever getting started on it but once I let go of that I was free I believe
that everybody has a business idea just like this something that aligns perfectly with your skills your passions and of course something that can actually make money to prove it to you
I'm running a free Workshop to show you exactly how you can do this too we'll hang out and talk about how to overcome that self-doubt how to find your million-dollar business idea and exactly
how to execute on that idea on Just 2 hours a day just head to the first link in the description to save your seat
spots are limited I'll see you in there
ever heard the phrase people never change well I believe this is mostly true with one exception people do change when they changed their environment it's
the reason people change when they leave their Hometown for the big city a new start I needed a new start I was trying to become this new person trying to
actually build something but the problem was I was stuck in my old apartment in my old ways no execution no Focus no consistency and that's when I realized
that was my problem it was my environment that's what I needed to change so I went looking for a new place a new environment where I could have a new start and I know it sounds so simple
but that place was the Starbucks down the street this was the place where I transformed from someone who never did anything to someone who actually got done I started waking up every day
at 6:00 a.m.
and every day I walked into that Starbucks I became a new person this new environment this new me and this is when things really started to change I basically stopped drinking and
spending all my money on the weekends I stopped spending every Sunday watching 12 hours of football and I started building this new future things started
to happen really fast two months in I found my distribution Channel I went viral on Reddit and all a sudden I had an audience and an actual validated
business model four months in I made my first dollar and landed the first sponsor of my newsletter 5 months in I started making internet founder friends and building a following on Twitter and
meeting people from all across the world 8 months in I landed my first really big sponsorship deal for $112,000 I had never seen this amount of
money hit my bank account at one time this is when I knew that I really had something people were willing to pay me money for something that I built from a
Starbucks and a laptop and this blew my mind and 365 days later I had built a business to $3,500 a month from a laptop and a
Starbucks while I had a full-time job I had made it I walked into work handed my resignation and quit my full-time job I
was going to go all in on starter [Music]
story this journey it didn't come without sacrifice yes I built this business but in the process I had to change into a different person I became
so focused on actually making this thing work that I felt like I had to leave a part of my past behind I became more and more detached from my old friends and
even my family I had to move from the city that I loved I even had to miss a good Friend's Wedding All For What and
that was probably the hardest part in my darkest moments I laid awake wondering if this was all worth it am I being selfish to sacrifice everything in the
name of chasing my dreams I knew I had to go on this journey but what would happen when I came back and I'm a new person my old friends my family would they
accept the new me as I look back on the journey I can't stop thinking about that question what if I was never alone in that airport on that fateful day what if I never had
that book in my suitcase yes the journey was full of sacrifice if I didn't push through those 365 days of change to change my habits to change my environment to change my identity what
would have happened and even though I had to change as a person my friends my family they welcomed me back with open arms they were so happy for me I didn't realize it but they were actually along
for the ride the whole time and that makes me so happy in those 365 days I built a business that changed my life I achieved that freedom that I had set out
to get no boss no Mondays nobody can tell me what to do that doesn't mean that life is easier now because there's a whole new set of problems when you're in control but now I'm in the driver's
seat and even more important I get to wake up every day and work on something that I'm so passionate about starter story so were those 365 days worth it
who knows but I know one thing for sure I'll never have to ask myself the question what if I never went for it