all right gam what's your story I come from a background with like literally zero money going like from shitty job to shitty job and I had only
like $1,000 left it was like all my savings at that time I just felt okay like I need to be my own bus this is gam mubes a guy who set out on a mission to
become an entrepreneur and make millions online I've been at it for now like if you combine all experiences close to 10 years and in the beginning things were
tough after launching the project creating the whole website and putting it online it was a a massive fail but I didn't give up I think deep inside I had
a voice that wanted to prove everyone wrong after years of failure gam finally came across an idea that would make his dreams come true there is no way to
describe how it feels when you have a true product Market fit it's like poetry it's like magic everything you do works you're in a state of bliss you feel like
a superhero and you feel like nothing can destroy you until Al of our customers were just saying like what the [ __ ] they were like
public messages on the community like yesterday I love lemlist today I [ __ ] hate it it was the month where we went from 40% month over month grow rate to
0% so that was really hard and it was very intense for me like uh I pushed myself close to the limits this is the story of how Guam mubes went from his
last $11,000 to a company valued at over $150 million in Just 4 years welcome to the [Music]
underdog I grew up in Paris two of my parents are not entrepreneur like they grew up on a farm in in the southwest of France they never had like a lot of
money so they sacrificed quite a lot so we could get a good education After High School I went to like a university I needed to work on the side so I could
pay for for life I was going like from shitty job to shitty job and I applied like to the MacDonald where all my friends you know like got accepted and
they declined and at that time I really really like felt like [ __ ] [ __ ] you know like everyone can work at mag Donald's and not you you're really like the worst
sheit ever you're doing like a uni where you don't even know if you're going to get a job afterwards so you start like questioning everything after struggling to land basic jobs during University gam
realized that the usual path from school to a 9 to-5 job wasn't for him so he starts looking for something better at that time I just felt okay like I need
to be my own boss I need to live following the the rules I want to establish I don't want to have someone you know who tells me what to do working in a like normal company I feel like
your creativity is often very like limited and I've always been someone creative I've always felt like I don't belong in a specific category so I just felt like launching a company was the
coolest thing to do and I've also loved money to be honest I've always loved money I've seen how people you know have been treated my dad because he didn't have enough money and I think it's like a great tool that can be used you know
to uh to also do like good thing with it I just decided to grind hard and uh make this thing
work so I switched to do a a master in marketing during that Master I just thought that I could give back to my dad by launching a a business with him cuz I
felt like okay now that I know marketing I'm going to be super rich and make money online I was just thinking let's do like t-shirt business it doesn't require a lot of money and we don't have money so it's perfect you know how to
print on fabric and I know how to sell with his Masters in marketing Gom is convinced that his t-shirt business is how he's going to give back to his dad and make it big he's finally ready to
leave the minimum wage jobs behind and become a successful entrepreneur and after months of Blood Sweat and Tears everything was ready after launching the
project creating the whole website and putting it online uh it was a a massive fail uh we only sold like six- shirts um and my plan which seemed to be perfect
which was build a community create a website sell the T-shirt to the community have tons of word of mouth and become super famous was totally crushed
my dad was uh disappointed because the business was not going you know as as planned and I feel like I was ashamed I couldn't really like help him out you
know I was also mad at first at my dad because we couldn't invest more money but in reality it was my own fault I was mad at him but the version of me that was mad at him was a version that was
also mad at myself and I didn't really realize it after that you know like we didn't talk for almost like a year and a half so that was really hard especially because um my parents you know like they
love you a lot H you need to do like family stuff like on Sunday it's very important and the fact that we didn't really talk it meant also that I kind of like put my hand down and I was saying
like I'm busy with work busy with work and that became kind of like my uh my go two excuses gam realizes that making millions online isn't as easy as it
seems his dream of becoming an entrepreneur led to a ruined relationship with his family but he isn't the one to give up this easily so
he starts looking for his next venture one of my friend who was launching a lead generation agency he asked me like hey I saw you were grinding on your project so maybe you want to join forces
and uh and help me out at that time I did not know what the lead generation agency was so I was like okay what it is and he's like okay basically I'm helping like businesses find their dream
customers so I was like okay that's intriging let me know like how you do it so this is when I really started getting into like gross hacking marketing and sales prospecting so I did that for
about a year I Clos customers uh all over the world and I really became like a an expert at sales prospecting cuz I was booking meetings for tens of different companies in different
Industries I was kind of a math scientist testing like tons of different approaches after some times I was like okay I don't want to do like a legion agency like I'd rather have like my own
software cuz I think as an engineer I love to have like something that was scalable gam was craving more than just an agency business his Ambitions were
much larger he wanted to build the next billion doll startup and make a bunch of money doing it so he left the agency and after long nights of searching
he found his next idea I saw that whenever someone visits your LinkedIn profile you can see who that person is so at that time I was like okay that's
crazy because it means that you can basically do the same on any website I really thought it was going to change the internet to be honest my my ambition was to uh
personalize the internet I went to Russia where I had hired like a few developers I didn't have a lot of money so the developer I had hired they were
kind of like Junior I think in total I have paid maybe like four or 5,000 back in the days it was like all my savings uh but eventually like uh LinkedIn
changed uh one line of code so the entire project uh yeah went to trash and then I was like oh [ __ ] it after moving to Russia spending all of his savings
and having his dream idea crushed by one line of code gam went back home to France to look for another idea but this
time with no money in his bank account I had only like $1,000 left and I didn't want to go work on like shitty jobs like I did for I don't know six or seven
years to pay like for everything else my girlfriend I remember she was paying the rent she didn't believe in me anymore like she was asking me like uh to take a
job my friends you know like they would uh ask me you know like to go to to the restaurant and I would lie I would say like that I was busy that I already had plans the plans was basically like me
cooking pasta for myself cuz it's cheap you know everyone is thinking like why are you doing this you have degrees just take a job and you'll see later if you can become an entrepreneur but I don't
know why I think deep inside I had a voice that wanted to prove everyone [Music] wrong you know we talk a lot about blue ocean and red ocean so I started with
like this blue ocean idea because no one W on it I thought I had like an incredible teex that was going to change the world in the end it was like too complex and it didn't work out we got
blocked Etc so now I was like okay red ocean we have tons of competitors but if we have competitors it means that there is always a product Market fit these guys are making [ __ ] tons of money so
all you have to do is to be better so instead of doing the same as all the platforms I started focusing you know with lemlist with a key differentiator that was how to make sales more human
and how to add extra layers on personalization that no other platform could offer so even though at first I knew all the features that our competitors had were a 100 times better
than ours I focused on something that was really tied to a key problem from our ideal customer profile but also that was tied to a real return on investment
for them which is how many meetings can they booked if you can tie any of your software or product or service to the revenue people are going to make your
product becomes associated with success this is Guam's aha moment he realizes that a good business idea is simply taking a proven idea and just making it
better if you're looking for a similar idea then just do what guom did research proven businesses that are making money right now and you can start doing that
by checking out our 52 micro SAS ideas Deep dive in this database you'll get 52 proven micras businesses how much money they make how they found their idea how
they got customers and tons of other details you'd want to know just click the first link in the description and we'll send it to you over for free now back to the story with $1,000 to his
name and the right idea in mind Guam got down to building and this time he was doing it fast our first MVP was just two weeks of work I closed basically the
first 100 customers doing uh live demos and outbound I did only this on top of it the first customers I was onboarding I would tell them you know what like buy the software subscription and I will
myself write the campaigns for you and in exchange I would also ask them if they want to be part of the content I create as success stories and unfair Advantage I would say that you can have
when you launch a company is if you're among the target audience of what you're building because if you're using your product daily and you're using it so much that it drives you crazy to see all these bugs and the [ __ ] up things
happening because this is software and that happens a lot in the beginning then I can guarantee that the pace at which you improve the product is 100 times better and the gross Loop for me was
simple it's like I use my own products I help people with their campaigns I create like the best content ever I push the content into a community from there I get insights from people who complain
about specific things I improve the product I restart using the product but with the improvements making success stories about it with new templates Etc and so on and so forth and this is a
gross group we've used to really like Skyrocket the gross lless made $600 in its first month and was growing 40% month over month gam thought he finally
cracked the code to building a successful business until he looked closer and noticed something was off I was like we can't have such a low
activation rate so the activation rate for me was uh when someone signed up whether or not do they launch a camp p and that conversion rate I think it was like at 15% so I decided to change
entirely the product I redone like all the wireframes we restarted from scratch when we put it live half of our customers were just saying like what the [ __ ] they were like public messages on
the community like yesterday I love LM list today I [ __ ] hate it and at the time I was like holy [ __ ] like what do you do do you revert or do you wait and see whether or not it's going to give
you like a higher activation rate was starting to have doubts about his decision to change the business overnight and with his inbox flooded with angry customers he was starting to
get scared but instead of backing down he decides to handle the problem head on I took all the users you know were like unhappy I asked them to come directly
like on Zoom calls I started working until like 4:00 a.m.
so I had chat with everyone to understand what they were liking I saw that we had removed stuff that we shouldn't have been removed so we fixed like a lot the product during that time it was the month where we went
from 40% month over month growth rate to 0% but at the end of the month our activation rate was at like 35% instead
of 15 so the next month we grew I think this time by like 60% cuz all the unhappy people wanted to turn turns but eventually like the new one converted at a much higher PA after winning a risky
bet to change the business completely gam and the team were starting to see the results pay off big time I think it took us one year to go from zero to
$250,000 AR annual recuring revenue year two it was uh we reached 1 million year three we were like uh at 8ish and then three and a half years we were at 10
when you go from 1 to 10 in uh let's say a year and a half it means that you're growing anywhere between 15 to 25% month over month every month you're like it's not possible that it's going to happen
but after like Seven 8 months of happening all the time it becomes like the norm for you there is no way to describe how it feels when you have a
true product Market fit it's like poetry it's like magic everything you do Works you're in a state of flow where everything is so easy that you feel like
you've understood everything about life that it was a game all along and you know you're in a state of bliss you feel like a superhero and you feel like
nothing can destroy you until you reach a plateau and this is where you realize or at least this is where I realized
that uh I I hadn't been a great
entrepreneur I learned like the biggest lesson I think of uh of growing a company growing a company is never an exponential curve It's Always A S curve
that can look like an exponential curve but there is always a plateau and the only companies that have like a proper exponential curve are the one we planning for the next S curve after a
rapid growth period lless plateaued at around $10 million ARR on top of that gam was now on his own after two of his
co-founders exited the company when your your co-founder lives it's definitely weird because you know you trusted people for a long time and now I had to handle like all the technical side of things which is definitely like not my
job I started having like a tech support product sales marketing having to manage basically like all of it so that was really hard and it was very intense for
me like uh I pushed myself close to the limits it's it's hard you know when you have like uh this thing happening and you feel really like on your own gam was
Now by himself and faced with an overwhelming amount of new challenges but he still believed lless could be more and he wasn't going to abandon it
after getting this far with his back against the wall he was left with one choice to make things work rebuild the company from scratch so we had coded the
product really quickly to ship a lot of features and then you realize that the way it's been developed doesn't match the amount of users you have and the scale so we had to rebuild entirely our
architecture and I think it took me like a year and a half to deal with all the technical shits and then be sure that uh I would become irrelevant to the growth
of the business that was intense gam spent a year and a half rebuilding the company and trying to get through that Plateau then he finally
came across a strategy that would change the business forever when you're doing like a software as a service business the name of the game is your retention meaning how long do people stay when
they start paying your service so we spent a lot of time I looking at okay who are the people when they join lamb list they never turn I called it like
the magnet Persona the magnet Persona is the Persona that's going to attract a lot more customers and if you take for example Apple their only focus for years
was designers and why designers are a great Persona because designers are cool so if you have a product that makes people feel like they are amongst this
magnet Persona then it's awesome and for us in our space the magnet persona it's really the sales rep it's the sales reps because we're a tool that drives more revenue and who drives Revenue in a
company sales so for us to have like this magnet Persona was just like Game Changer because in people's mind we became like the sales tools for sales teams so anyone who has a company who
wants to drive more sales know that they use they should use list the magnet Persona strategy allowed lless to break through the plateau but more importantly it turned Guam into the successful
entrepreneur he had always dreamed of becoming yeah so right now we're at $30
million AR and $10 million in ebda we're about like 100 people we have customers in more than 100 countries for me when I
reached that state it was uh it was weird because I don't like fancy watch is I'm a terrible driver my holiday it's like going in the mountain and put my tent being the nature I just felt like
money would open so many new doors it would be different Etc and then you realize like you should focus more on the substance like who you become who you help uh your values and that's I
think when the relationship also changed with my parents because even though I didn't grow up with uh with money like they taught me like things that are so much more important they taught me about
hard work respect being a good person in uh in this world I owe them a lot and when you know like you help them financially and uh they realize that they don't have to work they don't have
to worry and that everything is under control I think this is uh the best feeling in the world to be honest right now you know we we're
discussing it live uh on a video but the reality is like uh it's been I've been at it for now like if we combine all experiences close to 10 years so it's an overnight success story that took 10
years for me it's like you got to be patient with the results but you got to be impatient with your action put yourself out there do as much thing as
possible don't be afraid to document never give up believe in yourself and always invest in yourself whether it's a
new job a new experience a conference you want to go to an event you need to attend a webinar a video or whatever always optimize it for the learning you're going to get because the outcome
you you will never control it and the only thing you can control is how you work on yourself so if you work on yourself harder than you work on
anything else I can guarantee that in this life especially right now with distraction we have with social media Etc I can guarantee that you will have
success think of the journey think of the adventure because uh it's all worth it when you when you tell it 10 years later take action invest in yourself and
enjoy the journey that's Guam's formula for winning as an entrepreneur the truth is your idea will never be perfect your skills will never be perfect and the moment will never be perfect you just
have to start because if you don't start then all the dreams you have in your head will have a 0% chance of coming to life I hope you guys are all inspired after watching Guam's story and I hope
it's enough for you to just take one step of action today and if you're ready to take that first step today then you should definitely do that with the starter story Academy our program to
help you find an idea validate that idea and launch it into the real world but first I'd love to show you some examples of really cool SAS businesses like goms
started by regular people just like you making over $10,000 a month just head to the first link in the description and we're going to send over our free deep dive of 52 different micro SAS business
ideas that are making money today this is the type of stuff that gets built in the academy and I want to see you do something similar thanks for watching and I'll see you in the next one
peace [Music]