this guy makes over $10 million a year with six different businesses and the best part he started them all with 0 I drove out to Miami Florida to ask
him exactly how he built these businesses and the blueprint he uses to make over $5 million a year in profit instead of charging $1,500 a month we
charge on average $1.5 million a year you see Greg started his journey working at a VC funded multi-billion dollar company
then one day it went bankrupt it was unprofitable and what he learned from that helped him come up with a formula to start his own business that would be
profitable from day one the ACP funnel is the secret sauce that I've used for the last 15 years that I'm only now sharing with the world in this video
Greg shares his exact blueprints on how to make a million dollars from one client exactly how he's found several million dooll business ideas and why
everyone should aim to become a multipreneur I'm Pat walls and this is starter story thank you Greg thanks for having
me tell me about who you are and what businesses you built my name is Greg Eisenberg and today I run a a holding company called late checkout we do eight figures in Revenue mid seven figures of
profit and I've been a part of companies that have raised billions of dollars and I make more money as the CEO of L checkout and work a lot less can you break down the businesses that are
within your holding company currently and what you plan to build totally so we've got six companies that we've started LCA which is an innovation agency you probably need a robot.com
which is one of the biggest AI communities on the internet we have design scientist.com which is a design agency we've got boring Holdings which
is literally another holding company which owns boring marketing.com an AI assisted SEO business and boring ads.com an AI assisted ads agency and we've got
multipreneur decom which is a a community for multipreneur yeah tell me a little bit more about what multipreneur is and why you're so bullish on it multi preneurship just
basically means that you're building multiple products multiple companies multiple revenue streams instead of having one company do $100,000 a month
in Revenue you now have companies maybe they're only doing $25,000 a month in Revenue but if one struggles a little bit or Google makes a change that
affects this business or Instagram does this you now have that built-in insurance and the compounding with these internet businesses are Next Level so not only is it cheaper than ever to
build faster to ever to build with AI the compounding effects are are super real and I love the diversification of the multipreneur model yeah all right so
tell me a little bit about your origin story how do you get here grew up in Montreal Canada always was in an internet nerd started creating different blogs communities online started making
a few bucks as a teenager when I was 17 my first week of school high school I was actually in a school
shooting and 19 people got shot oh and I remember being in the chemistry class my teacher had locked the door I hearing
bullets left and right I realized as a 17-year-old that life is short and I wanted to do big things from that moment I took building on the internet really
really seriously I started a company called Islands which was kind of like a Discord for college students that was sold to wework and I was the head of product strategy and later the head of
product of wework we were worth $47 billion all of a sudden we run out of cash the headlin read 25 billion 20 billion 15 billion 10 billion we were
can't raage cash I vowed to myself that the next thing I start isn't going to be an unprofitable Venture back business it's going to be a profitable machine so
I asked myself what is a model that could marry the freedom that I want with the creativity of building multiple businesses and that's what got me so
interested in this new way of being an entrepreneur being a multipreneur yeah Greg is proof that you don't need VC funding or a big team to build a million-dollar business you can be a
solopreneur and get started today on a business that might just change your life but that requires knowing the right information and finding the right problem to solve now imagine there was a
place that gave you all this the problems to solve the blueprints to solve them and the strategies that turn simple ideas into million dooll online businesses well at starter story we have
a library of over 4,000 case studies and business idea breakdowns where you can access this all backed by data from real entrepreneurs so if you're actually
serious about building that next profitable side project head to the first link in the description and we're going to give you0 solopreneur business ideas so you can get started on your
journey today just like Greg now let's get back to Greg and how he actually launched this thing so you're out of Wei work and you start your first company
what is that company that you start LCA so it's an innovation agency we'll work with a Nike a Dropbox a Shopify a Tik Tok and we'll say we will help you come
up with new ideas to Future prooof your business instead of charging $1,500 a month which most agency owners do we charge on average $1.5 million a year
why because if we come up with a whole new vision for where to take your company often times those products generate 9 to 10 figures of Revenue if you're spending $1.5 million sounds like
a pretty good trade to me so you're making a million per client how did you actually land these clients and build his business ACP funnel baby a stands
for audience you got to start by social media audience Instagram page Tik Tok page Twitter account I had built a Twitter account of over 10,000 people that's not a lot by the way 10,000
people anyone can get to 10,000 followers C stands for Community how do you convert some of those audience members into some place where you own their emails you have their SMS they
have a place to talk and you really understand what are their pain points and I started posting hey come to these orange wine disco parties in these basement in Williamsburg I actually met
some of my first clients at these parties and then P for product what is the product that you can create that they want the most and I and I told them oh I'm actually starting this thing
called LCA we sell Innovation and they were like come into my office first thing Monday because I had already built so much trust with them our first year we did a million and a half in Revenue
we had one big client and then one kind of half client second year all of a sudden we're doing 5 plus million in Revenue sounds like a lot but again a few clients $1 million each and it's
been going up ever since then the ACP funnel is the secret sauce that I've used for the last 15 years that I'm only now sharing with the world so you're technically a solopreneur with this
massive agency but then you become a multipreneur tell me what that transition looked like we started a second business called nice break nice break.
fun we started direct with the product that's no no no that's that's not the way to build a business nowadays the way to build a business nowadays is you start with the community first then
you build the product so we actually closed it down after that I said all right let's go back to the ACP funnel and we started dispatch we started a Twitter account within a few weeks it
got to a couple thousand followers it was all around design inspiration you know we had the audience and we started seeing hey there's there's an opportunity here so within 72 hours we whip up a landing page a brand and a
team and all of a sudden we're selling design subscriptions our first year we did seven figures of Revenue 450,000 in profit then we wanted to try something different so we started a Twitter
account called boring marketer and started just tweeting about ad stuff SEO stuff just boring ways to get customers we build a community
around it and then we built this AI assisted tool to help do keyword research to help create SEO content basically create this SAS tool in its
first year it did 350,000 in profit and it's second year it'll do two to three million in profit all right let's talk about hiring you have these companies within your personal holding company how do you hire people to run these
companies one way I hire is I build communities and then I actively reach out to some of the the most active people we call them nerds and residents someone who's an expert who cares you
know if it's the AI example you need an AI nerd who's thinking about this all the time right we find them through the community the second way I find Talent is I coold DM a lot of people if I find
someone interesting online I won't be shy and I'll try to find their email address I'll DM and even if they have a job I'll say hey let's let's hop on a quick call the best people to hire
actually work a job let's talk about how you find ideas and how you build them really quickly what's your process I use two tools one is called redditlist.com
which tells me how fast a particular subreddit is growing and it gives me a ranking of all the different subreddits and I use a tool called gummy surch.com which basically takes a subreddit and
tells me what are the biggest problems that this subred is having and it's your job as the entrepreneur as the multipreneur to solve them yeah are
there any other tools that you use to run and build your businesses I use framer to create landing pages and websites really quickly I use convert kit for email I love all the automations
they do I use vid IQ which is a Chrome extension that gives you competitive analysis on YouTube and there's this little feature where what are the top questions on a YouTube comments so
imagine going to a starter Story YouTube page and you can sort by top questions and that gives me ideas around what I could be building for the starter Story community I use slack for team communication our
entire team runs on notion we use figma for designs I use Loom like crazy I just like creating quick looms about stuff and people could see my face or I can screen share that runs our a fig
business okay we are out here in your beautiful condo in Miami Florida tell me about multipreneur why is it the future and why is it different than solar
preneurship I'm not advocating for launch Five products on day one become a solopreneur find a niche build an audience build a community build a product for them all I'm saying is at
the end of that once that business is generating at least $100,000 of profit find an operator then that frees you up to find the next thing either buy
another business using some of that cash flow or your own cash flow or incubate something new one of the benefits of being a multipreneur is a lot of the sleepless nights you're giving to the
operator the second thing is if you're creative you're going to love being a multipreneur you get to work on different projects different spaces every day just feels different but you
need to have a lane our lane for example is We Believe community-based products outperform non-c commmunity based products so we build businesses based on the ACP funnel that we've defined tell
me what a day in the life is like for Greg a multipreneur running an 8 figure business what does that look like uh I wake up around 6:00 a.m.
I make a a French press coffee I have it I sit outside I see the sun come up it makes you feel grateful for for being alive and I get to work I plan out what I want to do today what are the two or three
things that if I did these things today I would be happy sometimes in the afternoon I'll go for a 45 minute workout and then after the day is done I try not to think about work so I do
things where I don't have my phone that helps me reset for the next day yeah all right last question that we ask for every founder that we interview is you could stand on Greg's shoulders back in
the Wei work days or even before that what would be your advice I made the mistake of listening to the top entrepreneurs of my day who said go
build a venture Bag company and go scale it and be Mark Zuckerberg I was living someone else's life by doing that and I spent 12 13 years of my life 7:00 a.m.
to 2: a.m.
every single day working 7 days a week and I think everyone deep down knows what's for them and life is about getting to that truth my advice to
everyone is find your truth don't listen to what anyone says and go after it that's great advice thank you Greg thanks Pat yeah follow this advice and
you will have a $10 million multipreneur Empire peace what's up guys I hope you were inspired by Greg's story and how he approaches starting businesses I think
the coolest thing about Greg is how he's able to to find painful problems and then create solutions to those problems really really quickly that's why he's able to run six different businesses at
the same time doing millions in Revenue if you want to do something similar but don't know where to start head to the first link in the description to download6 proven solopreneur business
ideas you won't find this information anywhere else and if you're really serious about building the business that might just change your life come join thousands of Founders inside starter
story all right see you in the next one peace [Music]