best kept secret in business is this product right [Music]
here what's up starter story my name is Pat I'm the founder of starter story and these are the essential tools I use to make over a million dollars a year this might not be as cool as GQ I'm just a
regular guy but I wanted to show you just some of the my little chosis and random things that I use to make money online
the first tool that I use is Loom I use loom for like everything anytime I was going to write an email or give someone feedback on something or delegate some
sort of project or teach someone in my business how to do something or give them feedback I use it instead of writing an email I think the craziest story about Loom is uh my buddy Peter
levels levels io on Twitter if you're not familiar I was telling him about some stuff that I've done with email marketing just recorded a quick 5minute loom video went over all of our clavio flows sent it off to him just think
thinking nothing of it he comes back to me and he's like yo this is like the most valuable thing I've ever watched I think you could actually just like sell this loom video I created the strip payment link we put it online and it
made $220,000 in one day just from pre-orders I didn't have to do anything it was just a 5 minute loom video became $20,000 in a day the most money i'
probably ever seen a day of that P
[Music] all right this is my my latest Obsession
which is tea I'll let you guys know that I have a very addictive personality and a few years ago I found myself addicted to caffeine addicted to coffee I found
myself having like five cups a day and then I found myself having panic attacks and anxiety where my whole body was tingling all the time and I thought that
I had um cerebral paly and but I looked it up and it was just anxiety so a couple years ago uh me and my girlfriend decided to just quit coffee and switch
to tea this is my new favorite thing and my favorite tea I just love the taste of it is Earl gry and it's actually really cheap basically you just get this tea right here and you get hot boiling water
in here and then you just scoop some tea in there and this really isn't going to work because this isn't actually hot water right now but let's pretend that that's going to steep for a little bit and then after about 4 minutes I get my
little cup and check this thing out this is um what is this thing called again a cup no this one oh but basically you take this you put it on top and it
has this little magical little device right here where it just goes right through and then you have your tea right here put the cap back on and enjoy your
tea [Music]
all right what is this yellow thing this is my favorite book this is the book that changed my life it's called Deep work when I first started my business it was a side hustle I had a full-time job
and obviously I had to pay the bills I had to go into work from you know 9:00 a.m.
to 5:00 p.m.
and that left me with only a few hours left in the day to actually make progress and I found myself kind of scattered I had like Twitter open I had all these different things open and I wasn't getting anything done then I found this book and
I learned about this idea of deep work which is basically distraction free work so I actually built my business while I had a full-time job by waking up early going to the Starbucks down the street
locking in putting my headphones on putting my playlist on blocking all Sites blocking all distractions turning my phone off and just doing deep work
actually coding writing delegating and doing like the hardest scariest things that I had to do to actually get a business launched while I had a
full-time job after 365 days I built a business that made money and I was able to quit my job and it was really just that deep work showing up every day and actually making progress in this crazy
distracted world that we live in and Shameless plug I believe in deep work so much that I've created a community around deep work inside the starter story Academy there are hundreds of
people doing deep work right now logging their progress logging their deep workk hours building their idea getting feedback and actually launching their thing and changing their life if it's something that you think that you would
be interested in trying out you can download our deep work checklist it's a full checklist on how to do the most effective deep work if you have a full-time job and how that can tie into actually building a business the link is
in the description I'd love if you guys checked it out [Music]
so this is a 16in MacBook Pro it's the perfect size if you know what I'm saying I think the 16in is perfect because it has like a big enough screen that you
can not need an external Monitor and also it can fit in your backpack I I like it so that this is all that I need so that if I'm working from a coffee
shop or I'm working from the airplane or I'm working from somewhere all the way across the world or if I'm just working in my house that I don't need anything I don't need a mouse I don't need a keyboard I don't need an external
monitor I have my whole setup right here if Apple charged $20,000 for this I would still buy it I think it is the most it just blows my mind that you know
in 2024 now that you can build a billion dooll business from one laptop in one idea do you remember the uh the video with Alex Goldberg I think his name was
it was my laptop we were using for boll and they were talking talking about all the uh crumbs on his laptop in the comments I didn't see that was because when we flew there I ate one of those little you know those little uh
gingerbread things that gave you on the flight and I've got crumbs all over it you've probably heard of this before this is Reddit one of the biggest websites in the world one of the biggest
Platforms in the world one of the best ways to get the first customers for your startup I had created starter story I thought it was going to be this Mass success when I first created the website
and then no one showed up right after a few months of trying to figure out how can I get customers I created one post on Reddit that essentially went viral and it wasn't even that Viral it got
like 400 up votes or something like that but that led to like a thousand people that signed up for my email list and then led to like the first customers and the first audience building that I ever did the hard part about Reddit is
redditors they [ __ ] hate spam they can smell your solicitation from a mile away my advice for anyone who's trying to get their first customer on Reddit or trying to just get their first customer
in general is go to those subreddits sort by the top posts and look for posts that are kind of secretly showing off a startup you'll probably figure something
out and don't give up on the first try either keep trying and eventually you'll get your first customer I know like a bunch of Founders we've interviewed some people here on starter story who through one Reddit post they changed their life
they quit their job and they built a business that changed their lives
[Music]
woo I love that smell all right so what do we got here all right we got my favorite thing probably in the world which is tennis when you're building a business
especially if you're doing something like a solopreneur you get so caught up in the online world and all the results and all the metrics that one of the best things I've done is
found a hobby that can take me away from that for even just an hour or two per day I picked up tennis maybe four years ago when covid was happening you know
before that I was doing a lot of running I was I ran a couple marathons I liked running but I would always kind of dread going for runs a little bit and when I started playing tennis I found myself wanting to get up early in the morning
and go play and looking forward every single time for anybody that's struggling to get to the gym or work out my number one advice is to find something that's actually fun to do that doesn't feel like working out I've heard
rock climbing is pretty good I've heard pickle ball and Tennis is the one for me who's your favorite tennis player jokovic Novak jokovic is my favorite tennis player because he's the black sheep nobody liked him he was the
underdog and as you guys know I love the underdog
[Music] this right
here this is our pride and joy this is our 100,000 YouTube subscriber plaque in 2024 it doesn't matter what product you build it doesn't matter how good your product is it is
about the distribution of your product YouTube is I think one of the best ways to do that because there's real people watching this right now real people behind the screen that actually you
build a relationship with can change your life overnight by just creating a video how crazy is that so I think that's amazing I think that YouTube is the future like you just saw that Tom Brady and Cristiano Ronaldo created
YouTube channels everybody wants to be on YouTube everybody wants to be a YouTuber now and it's definitely not too late so I think that YouTube is probably one of the most it's the most essential thing in starter stories business it has
changed our business and I want to create more great content that you guys love and uh we'll see you at a million subscribers
[Music] so tell me about your addiction this one's going to get dark by the way yeah
good my name is Pat and I'm a nicotin holic this is Zen these are pouches of nicotine that you can put into your
mouth and get high being completely transparent and vulnerable I've been addicted to nicotine on and off my whole life in
high school I had my first cigarette and I love that [ __ ] that [ __ ] was amazing I was chasing that high for a long time I'm not proud of this I'm ashamed of it but the goal of this video is to be
honest with you and show you the actual things that I use on the day-to-day I like it for zoning in for coding pop that in zone in put my headphones on and just do the thing this [ __ ] is super
addicting and actually my family has a history of heart disease so when I told my doctor this they told me that I needed to get off of it immediately so right now put it in the comments and
tell me that I should stop and I hope to be off it by next time billion dooll company [ __ ] legit best kept secret
in business is this product right here tell me about it this is clavo it is email marketing software it's email and SMS marketing software right now we have
a list of 250 to 300,000 people which means we spent about $4,000 a month and send some millions of emails every month this is actually cheap compared to the
revenue that it generates it technically generates somewhere between 80 to $120,000 a month it's different every month but that would be like an average of what that looks like so funny story
is actually clavio they were the very very first sponsor of starter Story the CEO who started it he sent me a check for $12,000 to sponsor the newsletter they're probably a big reason that
starter story exists now but you don't have to use clavio I think the most important thing is that you do Implement some sort of email marketing strategy into your business I think it's is one of the most underrated things that
people don't actually do really simple stuff like having a welcome sequence when someone signs up to your email list you send one two three four five different emails and tell a story in
your emails and then set up basic stuff like when they go to your checkout page and they don't buy something you send them some emails to remind them and potentially even send them a discount these are called either called email
flows or email sequences all businesses that make a lot of money they do this so yeah clavio that [ __ ] works thank you guys for watching I hope you got some inspiration maybe found a
cool thing or two I'll see you guys in the next one peace
[Music]