all right what's your story 6 years ago I started a business today that business makes over a million dollar a year but what nobody knows is that I built it
inside of a Starbucks at the time I was working a full-time job I'm still working my 9 to-5 job right here and that left me with only 2 hours a day to
build the business of my dreams but there was still one problem I was suffocated by self-doubt I didn't believe I could do it then I found
something that would change my life forever today I'm going to tell you that story I'm Pat walls and this is my starter [Music] story
all right this is me in the summer of 2017 I'm 26 years old I've got a great job I'm making six figures in New York City and by all accounts living the
life of my dreams but deep down I know that something isn't right every day I go to work and do the same same clock in a few Zoom meetings eat lunch
write a few lines of code and clock out this work leaves me feeling empty every day I know this isn't what I meant to do I know there's something missing see here's the truth and it might be
something you felt at some point too secretly in the back of my head I dream about the idea of quitting my job and starting my own business in my free time I'm reading business books and romanticizing about being able to wake
up and work on whatever I want but I keep running into the same problem I have no idea where to start how do I find a good idea how do I know it can make money how do I take the first step
I couldn't find this information anywhere online and that's when I had my light bulb moment I can turn these questions into a product I'll just research successful businesses write
about my findings on a Blog and share them with others who also want to learn and I didn't think this was going to be a big thing I was just genuinely interested in this stuff so this is is
the beginning of the idea but it's not all peaches and cream from there this idea it nags at me for months every single day I tell myself I'll get
started on it but I never do and this is where Starbucks comes into play so let me pull up a map and show you this is New York City this is
where I live this is where I work and this is the Starbucks every day I walk home from work and I walk by the Starbucks and every day I tell myself I'll stop in there order a drink sit
down and get started on this idea but every single day I walk by that Starbucks take one hard look at it proceed to not go inside walk home and watch 6 hours of Netflix and then go to
bed and I do this every day for months this Starbucks it represents the unknown and it's too scary for me to confront
it but everything changes when I come across this book it's called deep work by Cal Newport and deep work is a state of focus that you must learn if you want
to do hard things after reading this book I realize that I'm completely lacking Focus so I put together a contract with myself in this contract I
write down and I visualize tomorrow I'm going to walk in that Starbucks I'm going to order a coffee I'm going to sit down I'm going to set a timer for 2
hours and I'm going to just focus that's the contract the next day day one I walk in that Starbucks I sit down I set my timer and I get started all of a sudden
the timer goes off I look up and think holy that was 2 hours that flew by I was in Flow State I was actually doing
deep work day two I walk into Starbucks and do it again and day three I do it again and I don't stop every single day
I get off work walk into that Starbucks and do my 2 hours of deep work I even start waking up at 6:00 in the morning and getting my deepor in before my full-time job even starts I'm doing it
every day and it feels effortless in the progress it starts to happen after 1 month I've come up with a name and concept for my idea I'm going to call it starter story and I land the domain
starterstory.com for $12 a year I launch it with a few stories and a few hundred people visit the website after 2 months I've published dozens of stories and I'm starting to find a routine the business
isn't making any money but I'm starting to build a tiny audience I then start a newsletter and get my first 100 subscribers after 4 months I start working on marketing and I get my first big break one of my stories goes viral
on Reddit and thousands of people crash my site and join the newsletter now I'm starting to feel like my idea is validated after 6 months I start thinking about monetization and how I
can make my first dollar I monetize the newsletter with a sponsorship and I start making some money from affiliate Revenue now I'm starting to feel more confident like I actually kind of get how this stuff works and and I'm having
fun in the process so this whole thing starts out as a project that I didn't really expect would go anywhere but then it gets
traction and now I'm left with a new problem I need to figure out how this thing can make money but everything on the internet is about how VC backed Tech Giants raised $100 million when I just
want to figure out how I can go from $0 a month to5 or $10,000 a month how do I figure this out by reading case studies about businesses that that are just a few steps ahead of me and that's what
starter story is we have over 4,000 case studies and business breakdowns on successful online businesses that were started by people like you and me in these case studies you can see exactly
how much these businesses make and exactly how they got started so if you're curious on what it takes to build a business to5 or $10,000 a month or even a million doll online business
check out starterstory.com or click the first link in the description we're running a special right now for the YouTube family so how does this turn into a business well I'm reading case
studies about businesses similar to mine and I realize that most of them make their money through sponsorships then something amazing happens I get an email it's from the CEO
of a company called clavio they're a huge company now but at the time they were smaller the email says hi Pat I love starter story and what you're doing both the stories and sharing your
progress keep crushing it AB it's a nice email to get but I don't really think too much of it but as the conversation goes on we start to talk about the potential of clavio sponsoring the newsletter and then he comes to me with
a number $112,000 when I see this I don't believe it at the time I was basically living paycheck to paycheck so $122,000 was more money than I'd ever seen in my life
I send in my bank details and sure enough a few days later the money hits my account I get the notification while I'm at Starbucks and my heart starts beating out of my chest I get up leave
the Starbucks and just take a walk around the block my head is swirling with emotions this is crazy I got $112,000 deposited into my bank account
because of something that I built I felt like I had just become a millionaire all those days of waking up at 6:00 in the morning going to Starbucks and putting in those 2 hours of deep work this money
was the direct result of that I felt like I was on top of the world but these emotions of excitement of bliss it quickly turned to fear I thought was this email some sort of accident did I
just get lucky this $122,000 it represented a decision that I had to make in my life should I keep playing it safe and keep my full-time job or was
this $112,000 validation that I should go all in on one side the devil on my shoulder was saying go all in and the angel was saying no keep playing it safe and I sat on the fence for months but
then I remembered why I started this thing in the first place I wanted to build something for myself and not someone else's dream I realized that if I don't make this decision right now I
might never do it I might get old look back and wonder what if and that was the moment that I walked into work and I handed in my resignation I quit my job decided to go all in on starter story
and the rest is [Music] history all right fast forward 5 years and that was the last time I had a
regular job the last time I ever got a paycheck after that I never looked back I never stopped building and I ended up building starter story into a million-dollar business I'm not going to
lie to you and tell you that it was all easy or predictable from there I failed a ton but when I look back the most important thing that I did was just going inside that Starbucks getting to
work and taking action every single day I was giving myself a chance to become lucky and it took me a few months to get there but when it did when that email came through when that $12,000 came
through I decided to go all in after that and that is really what made the difference that's the story of how I built a million our business from inside of Starbucks and I would like to thank
Starbucks for sponsoring this video just kidding
good we're making money through a couple affiliate deals and a few we're making I'm making money through some affiliate
marketing ah bro what the man get the hell out of here I'm taking a DB