this guy built a $10 million business thanks to one simple skill writing what's even crazier is that he started this business while he had a 9 to-5 job
and didn't quit that job until he was making a million dollar a year he invited us into a studio in Miami Florida to tell us exactly how he made his first dollar and his exact routine
to build a million-dollar business while he had a full-time job wake up at 4:30 a.m.
write for 2 hours get back to my desk at 7:00 a.m.
do my black rock work during the day log off as soon as I could and then build in the evenings before the success Dicky was crushing it by all accounts New York City Wall
Street sixf figure job but deep down he was unhappy slaving away at a job that gave him no Freedom then one day he wrote a tweet that changed his life
forever that was how I earned my first $5,000 I didn't have 20,000 100,000 Twitter followers at the time in this video Dicky shares his exact blueprints on how to master the 10 mil
skill of online writing how to scale your writing business to $800,000 a month and the best way to get to $10,000 a month as a beginner the fastest way to
monetize is actually I'm Pat walls and this is starter story thanks for having me P what's going on man welcome to the shipyard appreciate you being here tell me about
who you are and what you built I uh Dicky Bush two years ago I was a Wall Street hedge fund Trader working 60 hour weeks under fluorescent lights trying to make 90k a year that l me to start writing online now two or 3 years later
I am a full-time writer with a portfolio of writing based businesses on Pace to do $10 million in 2024 break down all the businesses that you run so it's a portfolio right now of four businesses
the first is ship 30 for30 which is a community power writing course that helps beginners who've never written anything start writing online that one does about $3 million per year the second is the premium ghost riding
Academy which helps beginner freelance Riders to position themselves as premium Ghost Riders that's a group Evergreen group coaching model that one does about $5 million a year then we have WR with
AI which is a paid newsletter for training AI writing tools to become your personal writing intern that one's on Pace to do 500k this year and then the last one is type share which is a SAS
business with everything you need to start writing online templates analytics hosting all that in one place so all four of those that're in the writing area they all kind of build on one another and 3 years ago I didn't know
how any of this worked tell me a little bit about your back story and how do you get into entrepreneurship so my backstory you could trace back to when I was pretty young I had a handful of obsessions luckily hit an athletic streak which allowed me to play football
in college at Princeton studied math and computer science there and then as a sophomore I got an internship at Black Rock I was like wow this is the coolest thing ever this is a dream job I'm going to go work for a hedge fund that led to
taking that full-time job when I graduated I was checking every single box I got good grades on track to be 22 years old making 180 Grand in New York City I'm like I did everything right
amazing 18 months later I was doing well at the job but if I showed up at 5:00 a.m.
and worked till 8:00 p.m.
I might make 10% more money but if I worked as little as possible I would make the same amount and that kind of messed with me because I couldn't apply the level of effort that I wanted to because my
incentives weren't there if I wanted to work harder if I wanted to bring more intensity nothing would happen and that was a freakout moment where I said time to go find something I could do that with so you're working your dream job on
Wall Street making good money what was your turning point that got you into writing online I witnessed someone I worked with asked for permission to go to their son's little Le game and he was
probably 37 38 years old and his boss said no so if I do everything right for 14 more years I might be sitting here having to ask for permission to go to my
kids little game uhoh I got to get out of here I didn't quit right away which I think is a big mistake a lot of people do because then I would have been operating from a place of scarcity the
entire time instead I said how can I look for ways to passively pursue New Opportunities I started a newsletter inside black rock as a way to get my name out there more after 3 or 4 months
of doing that I said why am I capping myself with people working in this company when I could use social media and the internet do the same thing and unlock millions of new eyeballs and that
is what led me to starting my newsletter in January of 2020 which was kind of my gateway into writing online Dicky is the perfect example of someone who was able to turn a simple idea into a
million-dollar side project while still working a 9 to-5 job but that's because he was working on the right idea and had a solid blueprint on what to execute on every day and that's why I built starter
story a library where you can access over 4,000 business ideas breakdowns and blueprints that real entrepreneurs use to turn a simple idea into a million-dollar online business that way
you can study and get inspired by what's already working instead of trying to reinvent the wheel so if you're serious about building a profitable side project and you're still working a 9 to-5 job then head to the first link in the
description and we're going to give you a free breakdown of 160 solopreneur business ideas to help you get started on your journey much love and hope you guys enjoy the rest of the video all
right so tell me about the early days of writing online getting your start so I'm still working on Wall Street but realized okay a lot of the work that I was doing on a daily basis was kind of made up I went from working 12-hour days
down to 3 or 4 and spend the rest of a 10hour workday learning reading immersing myself into different things and then writing in my newsletter hey here's what I read this week here's what I wrote here's what I listen to here's
what I'm thinking about following everything that I thought was right but I had something like 250 subscribers and so I committed to a 30-day personal writing challenge where I'm going to write and publish something every day
for 30 days and at the end of this challenge if it doesn't work I'm going to go have to find something else day 27 I hit publish zero likes zero comments zero retweets went to bed thought okay
cool this is almost over like what am I going to do and at the time I was working on a different side project which was SAS that's the Better Business model whatever went to bed woke up that post got retweeted by nval bology a
handful of other kind of high-profile people it had four or 5,000 likes I dropped my newsletter at the bottom and went from 250 subscribers to a th000 and the big takeaway that I made at the time was you never know what's going to go
viral you never know what's going to work you just have to keep showing up and hitting publish and that set the fly will that's been ever since so now you got a little bit of popularity on Twitter how do you actually turn this
into something that makes money the viral post was a breakdown apology the result of that was people who wanted me to write a thread on them were now reaching out to me saying hey I really
like these worldview creation threads that you've been putting together would you be willing to do one for me and I had someone reach out to me he approached me said would you do this for me I said sure he goes okay how much
should I pay you and here I am I have no clue I don't want to say something cuz I've been doing this for free I don't want to say something that would get him to say no so I'm like look I don't know what to say I don't know what to charge
how about this I'll go do this for you you just let me know how valuable it is at the end of this and you pay me that much he's like sure great go for it I was going to ask for $250 but again I didn't ever say that so I spent the
weekend Saturday Sunday just immersing myself 15 hours all the way down the rabbit hole and I put together a really great product form emails me back like 2 Days Later he's like dude this is amazing thank you so much I can't wait
to use all this can't wait to tell my friends like hey you could go do this for them putting you in touch with my assistant who will help coordinate payment so his assistant emails me and says hey where can I pay you I spun up at PayPal sent her the link and then
$55,000 hit my account the next day I thought it was a typo and so I sent him a message like dude that was so generous did you mean to send this much and his response was like dude this was amazing
is that enough for you like there's plenty thanks so much like anything else you need I'm happy to help and that was the very first time in many years I felt that I again had something where more
effort more intensity led to more results and that completely broke my brain of wow the attention that I generated from writing led to a business opportunity that paid me five grand
we're clearly on to something here so you make your first $5,000 wor ghost writing what happens next over the next week or two had a couple more people reaching out where I was probably on Pace to make 10 grand a month but to
scale up a ghost riding side hustle Beyond 5 to 10K as a side hustle was is very difficult so I zoomed out and said what was the put that led to this opportunity while it was writing and
Publishing every day for 30 days on my own so I tweeted out hey I just completed a 30-day writing challenge it changed my life would anyone be willing to do this with me because I knew that was intense I'm going to need some
accountability if I want to do it again again I was terrified to charge money cuz it was like literally a slack accountability Channel like how much would someone be willing to pay but there were so many responses that I couldn't just make it free so it was $50
and you got your money back if you completed all 30 days people loved it the slack channel was blowing up and I wanted to figure out if I was going to actually charge money for this what do I need to deliver so I held over 50
one-onone interviews ended up packaging everything that I learned from those interviews into a much better product and charged $99 for it and then that made 30 Grand in December you're starting to make a little bit of money
online you have this product that's working but you're still working your full-time job tell me about that experience I've realized I have a scalable vehicle that I can dump a ton of effort into I partnered with Nicholas
Cole to come on and train transition this from just a slack accountability channel for $99 to a full immersive 30-day digital writing education so that
was all of 2021 wake up at 4:30 a.m.
WR for 2 hours be at my desk ready to log in for my 7:30 a.m.
Black Rock call do that during the day log off as soon as I could and then build ship 30 in the evenings by the end it ended up working so 2021 ship 30 did a million like 90%
margin I had hit my goal of doubling my full-time job income from my side Hustle facetimed him said hey this has been awesome but I really want to take my kind of Life trajectory in in another
Direction thanks for everything and it ended up working out luckily you have this amazing story about how you built this business just from writing online but tell me why is the skill of writing important when you recognize that the
foundation for every single piece of content every product every video every podcast is writing yeah it's the most applicable skill yeah and so if you can learn that plus learn to write in a
persuasive way or in a compelling way you basically write your income ticket for the rest of your life because you can apply to any business you can apply to any Venture you can apply in any company schools do such a horrible job
teaching it people leave in the real world and go what is writing going to do a thesis statement and like a five paragraph essay and a word count but that's totally not what writing is
what's your advice for becoming a good writer and a great writer so I can help with becoming a good writer cuz that's all I consider myself but the best writer I know is Nicholas Cole who my business partner he wrote a book called
The Art and business of online writing which is the first book I read on writing on the internet I think it's the number one book any person should read who's interested in writing on any kind of social platform it's going to give you a full crash course of everything
you need to know so that'd be my first piece of advice it's after this video go on Amazon check that book out and then my second piece of advice would be always zoom out from the lens of it doesn't matter who you are how much time you spend on it the reader does not care
about any of that they care about what the writing can do for them and if you write with that what we call an empathetic lens putting yourself in the reader shoes and say how can I create something that they're going to stumble into with a problem I'm going to solve
their problem and I'm going to solve it as quickly is 2 minutes by the end of this Twitter thread or tweet or long form it's really just solving people's problems and figuring out how you can do
that in the most concise clear compelling way I think when a lot of people think of writers they think of uh not necessarily making a lot of money you've been able to make a lot of money with writing what's your recommendation for writers who want to make a lot of
money the fastest way to monetize is is actually build the skill yourself and then borrow someone else's audience and go strip for them that was how I earned my first $5,000 I didn't have 20,000
100,000 Twitter followers at the time I had a th000 and I had one person reach out to me that I could charge $5,000 for that's by far the most sustainable way too because you can build an income stream that's 5 to 10K a month that
doesn't take 40 hours to do so you have enough to support yourself and then you can go work on building your own audience on the side so that's our advice to anyone who's looking to write as a career it's figureing out first how
to become a ghost writer and then you're operating from abundance of I have enough money I can then pursue my passion project or write about this topic that I know will take longer to monetize than uh starting right away
trying to sell your own thing tell me about the tools you use as a writer any specific tools you recommend for writers so if you're spending time thinking you have to have the perfect note taking
system and Publishing Cadence and content calendar and editing system before you start writing that's the first thing to avoid just HIIT po that's the best tool so I don't really have any
kind of complexed organized system if I need to find something I've written in the past I just search my own Twitter I use type share for all my publishing so that's a Shameless plug for our SAS that helps you write tweets long form
LinkedIn carousels for Instagram things like that and then I just use Apple notes I have Apple notes on my phone syncs to my computer anytime I come up with an idea I just jot it down wake up right for 90 minutes and expand those
ideas so there's a lot of advice of use this tool use that tool it's going to end up being kind of a productive procrastination exer exercise so I try to avoid end up giving too much of a prescription on that all right so we're
here this is where you get your work done here I try to I lock myself away I lock the door behind me and try to eliminate all the distractions I lock into a little bit of a cave but yeah it's good mix it up what's a day in the
life like for you so what I realized is either be in a full build mode which is my monk mode 5:00 a.m.
wake up I have everything scheduled down to the minute working out twice a day every single meals taking care of in advance going to bed at 9:00 p.m.
I know exactly when that's going to start when it's going to end so I can Sprint very hard during it and there's a single outcome we're trying to accomplish that only happens like three or four times a year now so if I'm not in a monk mode I call it
maintenance mode I take it down a notch I try to sleep for like 9 hours I spend more time at the beach and take my foot off the gas because that's where those ideas actually start to percolate for
the next Sprint tell me about some of the struggles that you've had in your journey as an entrepreneur even going back to some of the days when you're starting m if there's anything that's holding someone back from creating on
the internet more than any other factor it's what their high school friends are going to think about them if they see them on Twitter like writing it clicked with me that those people are far too busy thinking about themselves to pay
any attention to you you were not that important I was letting the imaginary opinions of people I didn't even like hold me back from getting started writing when that click for me I go okay
I should probably just hit publish on this and I remember hitting publish for the first time and no one read it now I have a new problem no one cares what I have to say so this big idea that the whole world's going to laugh at you is
actually the opposite problem which is actually harder to solve of well wait no one cares what you have to say how do you actually put something out there that people want to engage with all right last question that we ask to all founders that we interview on starter
story if you could sit on Dicky's shoulder uh when you're just starting out what advice would you give them so the first one we' talked about a ton which is if the current vehicle you're
in is not leading to more income or more skill if you doubled your effort find something else I wish I'd have made that realization right when I started working instead of waiting two years the second
one was once I made that realization I started down the path of productive procrastination where all I was doing was reading business books without a business Reading Writing books without writing reading leadership books without
a team to lead none of that actually helped me do anything until I had something to work on where I could stop learning just in case and start learning just in time where okay I'm starting a
newsletter I need to learn how to write a compelling subject line now I can go read that copyrighting book jump to the single chapter on subject lines surgically read it now I have that skill
now I can move on to the next thing and you end up learning so much quicker when you have a project or something to work on that provides that relative context and then the last one is that the people
you look up to are no more special than you or more talented or smarter they're just more than likely been doing it for longer so just zoom out extend the time Horizon and you'll end up getting there too if you just stick with it and then
I'd say the last one is there's never a perfect time to start anything that's a big fallacy I had that was once I quit my job then I'll start this thing or once my mom gets better then I'll do this thing or once work sl's down or
once I move jobs that never ends and so if you can't get started on something today thinking there'll be a better time in the future that's never going to come so anytime you can just throw all that out and say how can I take one step
forward on it today I call it killing your wantes if you can kill all the ones in your life you'll be in a better spot thank you Dicky dude appreciate you having me awesome this is great follow
this advice and you'll have a $10 million business ghost writing peace all right guys that's it I hope you like this video personally I think the coolest part about Dicky's first business is that you don't need any
employees or insane funding to start all it really requires is a laptop an idea and a couple of hours of work per day so if you're curious about building a profitable side project head to the
first link in the description to get our free breakdown of 160 solopreneur business ideas just like Dickies so you can get started on your own Journey all right everyone I'll see you in the next
one much love and again thank you guys all for watching peace [Music]