this thing made me a millionaire no not the dollar bill I'm talking about this the eyeball or as I like to call it attention nowadays with the click of a
few buttons you can capture millions of eyeballs in minutes and with a few more clicks you can turn those eyeballs into money but there's a catch you need to
know what buttons to click I tried for days months years to crack the code failure after failure then I finally did
it one day I was a nobody and the next day thousands of followers customers users and of course dollars this is the story of how I
hacked Reddit to build a million-dollar
business the story starts a few years back in New York City 9 to5 six figure salary parties profit but numb on the
inside I want something more no I need something more in that moment I vowed to myself to become an entrepreneur someone who would never have to work a 9 to-5
ever again and that's when I came to the idea to start a business the idea was called starter story in my head I really believe that this is the idea that will
set me free so I spend months working on it I want it to be perfect the perfect landing page The Perfect Design the perfect font the perfect launch nights
weekends meticulously making everything perfect I could see the end result in my head thousands of users thousands of
dollars a new life finally it was ready I put it out in the world I press [Music]
publish then I sit there refreshing my analytics I'm waiting for the success to start happening
and sure enough nothing zilch NADA zero users I keep refreshing just waiting for the word of mouth the sharing the
millions of users to show up but they never do and this this is when I realized everything I was told about startups and business was a lie nobody
gives a f about me or the thing that I launched then I thought how do I make them give a [ __ ] that night I got to work I start studying other successful
businesses to see how they got traction after a couple hours it all clicks the smartest companies in the world started by leveraging one thing and one thing only attention and they did it using
free channels YouTube Instagram Tik Tok Reddit they went to their customers created content for them and in return
attracted millions of eyeballs and then they turn those eyeballs into users AKA dollars so I ask myself where do my customers
hang out then I look at my screen that's it Reddit I post a link to my website it starts getting a few upvotes I start
getting traffic 10 users 20 users 100 users holy sh I'm jumping around the room I could see my future quitting my
job traveling the world a new life and then boom oh no your post has been removed
sincerely the mods oh what the f sorry dude your post Breaks the Rules of This subreddit how
stupid deleted gone all my hopes and dreams ruined by some mod on a power trip but I'm not giving up that easy from that moment I had a new goal find a
way to break the rules rule number one no link post only self posts allowed and then it hits me redditors hate the idea of you
spamming your website so what if I made it feel like this wasn't spam at all I won't post a direct link to my site I'll just take all the content and put it in
its own post I'll keep it on platform and then at the end of my post I'll put a small link to my product if they want more stuff like this I spend the next
few hours putting it all together doing it meticulously ly making it perfect so no moderator can say a thing and then finally I press publish I sit there and
I watch it for a few
minutes it didn't work [ __ ] this I'm going to bed
holy sh it worked hundreds of up votes dozens of comments thousands of people reading my content I open up analytics thousands of
people are visiting my website right now I've never felt anything like this before the engagement was like crack to me this is product Market fit before
nobody gave a sh about my website and now people are begging me for more I hacked the system one simple piece of
content and now I have thousands of eyeballs on my product but there was still a problem I need to turn these eyeballs into
dollars I knew one thing for certain this hack was like a ticking Time Bomb the mods were going to catch on to me others would come and copy my strategy
stry I knew this wouldn't last forever I needed to act and I needed to act fast it was time to go all in initiate step
one of the plan more attention I posted again and again and again and to my amazement it kept working my stuff kept
hitting the front page hundreds of thousands were visiting my website and millions were reading my content but attention was only one part of the
formula initiate step two of the plan converting attention into money how would I do it emails I knew I needed to convert this attention into my own email
list an email list would allow me to own my audience I could sell them whatever I wanted whenever I wanted without reddits
so I optimized a signup box on my site to collect emails from the millions of visitors then the email sign ups started flooding in 100 email subscribers 200
email subscribers 500 email subscribers but time was running out then one day it happened petition to ban
starterstory.com posts this was the [Applause]
end well as they say all good things must come to an end the redditors formed a mob against me I was dunzo but actually I was fine by
that point I built an email list to tens of thousands of subscribers the formula worked I captured that attention onto my email list I had my own users and my own
product and my own business now and I just quit my job to go all in on it and as I look back I just remember how crazy that whole thing was to launch something
and completely FL and then one morning wake up to millions of people using my product over the years I've talked to thousands of successful Founders they all have
stories like this they built something nobody gave a and then they had to figure out how to get in front of their customers that's the secret sauce that
nobody talks about if I didn't focus on that then I wouldn't be here today I'd still be building things and hoping that people would magically show up there are thousands of opportunities like this
hacks and cracks in the algorithm that you can build a million-dollar business on top of all you need to do is find them which is why I'm hosting a live Workshop where I'll teach you my
framework for hacking attention in 2024 just like I did on Reddit and how you can find a million-- dooll business idea in the process if you're curious the
link is in the description I hope I got your attention see you in the next one