I build apps and flip them.
I've done this four times and made over $500,000.
This is Lots, a London-based founder who treats apps like real estate.
He builds them fast, grows them to about 20k a month, and then flips them for all cash deals.
My philosophy is to stack cash and achieve financial [music] freedom.
Since 2022, he's done this four times and made over a half a million dollars.
But, here's what makes his approach different.
Most founders get obsessed with their idea, but Lots doesn't.
He builds to sell.
I'd rather take two to three years of profit up front than grind for a decade.
His philosophy, cash out fast and move on to the next one.
I asked Lots to come on the channel to break down his entire build-to-flip playbook,
and in this video, we'll dive into how he builds and grows his apps in just a few weeks,
his exact framework for finding ideas [music] that can sell fast, and why building to sell beats building to scale for most business ideas that are started today.
This one you cannot miss.
Let's get into it.
I'm Pat [music] Walls, and this is Starter Story.
All right, Lots, welcome to the channel.
Tell me about who you are, what you build, and what's your story.
Yeah, my name's Lots.
I'm from London, moved there recently, and I build apps to about 10 to 20k MRR and flipping them.
I've done this four times now and [music] racked up a total sales of over half a million dollars since 2022.
Okay, before we get into this whole strategy around flipping apps, what were the apps that you built and sold?
So, Bible Buddy was my first one.
So, that was a AI therapist for Christians.
Then Magic Music, which was a wrapper around Ceno AI, which is a AI music generator.
Then Toxic Traits, which is basically just screenshot chats that you have with people,
and then you get the personality traits from them.
And then Pray Screen was the last one, which was essentially it blocks your apps and you have to pray for you to be able to unlock them.
You can probably see that there's kind of Christianity thread going through all of them as well.
And we've scaled to over a million users across all the apps that we have.
[music] Revenue-wise, I've done 500k of course as well.
Okay, cool.
Well, thanks for sharing that.
Before we get into the kind of build, flip, and sell strategy, I want to understand how you even get here.
How do you get to this point where you've flipped four apps?
Yeah, it actually comes from a place of pain, actually.
So, I was actually in banking originally, and then I started my own VC-backed startup.
You know, everyone thinks they're going to be Mark Zuckerberg, so I also thought I was going to be from London.
Ran it for about 3 and 1/2 years, ended up failing, and I was kind of like to lick my wounds.
I was like, let me just kind of create apps and see how that goes.
Luckily for myself, this was 2022 when GPT was first commercialized, so I was able to ride like loads of waves and learn a lot super quickly.
So, I want to dive into that first app that you built.
Did you always have this idea that you were going to be building and flipping apps?
How did that first flip go?
What's the story behind it?
How I got the idea originally was this obviously GPT came out.
A lot of people didn't like Bible GPT, but a lot of people didn't like Q&A.
It's going to be ask a question, you get something back about the Bible, and that wasn't really helpful.
So, I kind of flipped it to be more of a AI therapist to be a little bit more emotional,
ask questions after each response.
Then launched it on WhatsApp cuz again, I didn't have the technical skills, right?
So, I used like a third party at the time, and then I didn't realize WhatsApp charges an arm and a leg per conversation window.
Then my costs like ballooned to like 15k a month.
I was like, "Hell no.
I need to move on to my own infra."
Then hired engineer from Upwork, and then moved it to like iOS and Android.
And how I found the person that I sold it to was I actually first originally listed it on MicroAcquire.
Then I was also active in the My First Million podcast as well in the community they have on Facebook,
and someone just happened to be in London [music] at the same time that I also was, and he reached out.
He was like,"Hey, this seems interesting."
And then he ended up acquiring it.
Okay, cool.
So, you sort of sell this business as an accident, but then you go and flip three more.
What did you learn through that process, and why are you so into flipping apps and doing this over and over?
Yeah, I see that there's like two key trends I'm riding here.
There's the whole consumer coming back.
The market is like trending and is highly liquid.
So, what I mean by highly liquid, it means that right now tech isn't a hard thing to build at all,
which means there's a lot more buyers out there who can feel like, "Hey, I can just take this product on and just market it better than you and then get more money and more profit margin."
So, I think that's the first thing.
Number two came from a personal perspective.
So, I raised VC originally for my first startup, but I was still broke, right, at the end of the day.
And with this, it was kind of a much clearer route to be able to get some cash in.
And I think there's a lot of my dream sold to people, which is kind of like, "Hey, raise VC,
you know, raise, raise, raise for the next 10 years, and then, you know, hopefully there's that 0.0001% chance you're going to become a a billionaire through there."
I would rather, you know, build something, and then in the 6 to 12 months exit it for like a cool 250k.
Okay, cool.
A lot of people that watch this channel, they have this one big idea.
They get really, really attached to this idea, and they can't even imagine what it would be like to just build something just to sell it.
How do you approach ideas?
Do you get really attached to your ideas, or how do how do you approach ideas?
Yeah, so for me, before I kind of start working on anything, I always tell myself, "Is this going to be my legacy or is this cash flow?"
And that then dictates all further decisions going down the line.
And a lot of the things so far have been things that have just been cash flow.
So, that actually dictates on how I build things [music] itself.
What people normally get wrong is I'll say two main things.
First one is that they make their apps way too complicated.
And when I say complicated, I don't mean the actual app itself, but more so the operations behind the scenes,
and they don't make it clean enough when you want to then get something acquired itself,
which then normally like kills a lot of deals going forward, especially if like, you know,
a buyer is asking you certain questions and you can't answer it or just too long-winded an answer,
they just think, "Oh, you know what?
This is not for me."
So, I think that's the first thing.
Second of all, when they're also looking for buyers, I would say the issue is that everyone wants to go for the highest price,
and the highest price tends to take the longest and also fall through the most itself.
And the longer it takes, the more likely it could have been a fall through.
So, even when I'm actually selling my app, I don't like to sell to the highest bidder.
I normally like to sell to the third highest bidder and tell them that they have two other bids on top of them,
but if they're able to close in like 3 to 4 days, I'll choose them.
And they normally kind of like feel lucky, and they kind of like,"You know what?
Let's just wire everything now, and then let's get everything else sorted afterwards."
I want to tell you about a new tool that makes it even easier and faster to build.
Rocket.
Rocket lets you go from just a few sentences to a full-stack app.
Just describe your vision, and in a few minutes, you will get a complete functional app.
Back-end integrations and production-ready code, everything.
With rocket.new, you can import designs from Figma, integrate with Stripe and Supabase in just a few clicks.
400,000 users from around the world are building with Rocket because it's the simplest way to turn ideas into apps in minutes and not months.
So, if you're ready to finally build your idea faster than ever, check out Rocket at the first link in the description.
Thank you to Rocket for sponsoring this video.
I love what you guys are building.
All right, let's get back to the video.
Okay, cool.
I want to get a little bit more tactical here.
I want to understand your playbook.
You've done this for over four apps.
What is your actual playbook for finding an idea, building it, marketing it, and selling it?
Can you walk me through this step by step?
Yeah, for sure.
So, I'd say like step one is spotting trends in the App Store.
And how you do that is actually pretty simple.
You just essentially go to the App Store and be able to see, okay, who is currently number one in the different categories.
And then once you do that, you're able to then see are there other apps also, let's say in the top 20,
who are doing exactly the same thing, but maybe for just slightly different niches.
Then I go to Sensor Tower to be able to see, okay, what's actually the revenue numbers of each.
And if I see all of them are doing, you know, over 100k MRR or over 500k MRR, then I know,
okay, cool, there's something here for sure.
And once I've actually spotted the trend that I'm seeing, I then think to myself, okay,
how can I make my app unique?
So, for me specifically, I love the Christian market itself, normally because obviously I'm Christian myself,
but also the edge is most technology gets to faith or religion last, and I want to be the one to kind of like pioneer that on the end.
And then step number three, I would say is make the app a single player.
So, whenever I speak to people, a lot of people try to do this whole kind of socialness for the app,
where it's kind of all you need somebody else to be able to come in for you to be able to get value.
But, I always say like make your app single player, something that someone could do on their own without having to invite anyone else in to get that initial value.
Yes, you can do it afterwards as an added extra later on, but it just makes things too complicated,
and then you kind of have to start marketing to two people at the same time.
And then I'd say number four, a key thing for me is like is either you make it highly shareable or super high retention.
So, [clears throat] no one on this earth shares apps, all right?
No one's going to randomly be like, "Hey, yeah, download this app, right?"
But, what they tend to do is actually share an asset within the app, so they don't even know that they're sharing the app.
A good case of this was Magic Music, and I allowed people to share songs with other people,
and it opened up a web view where they could actually listen to the song without downloading the app.
But, then there was a big green button that said, "Create your own song."
So, what we kept seeing is that people would, you know, make a song about their friend cussing their friend.
Their friend listens to it and is like, "Oh, you know what?
I'm going to create my own one."
And then they then downloaded it themselves, and that actually made like the shareability of it like super high.
And then high retention, I mean, Pray Screen is the best one I've seen this.
So, Pray Screen had a 60% day 30 retention, which is kind of like unheard of.
And what helped with that was two things.
Number one, of course, we literally blocked your apps, so you kind of had to use us for you to unlock your apps.
But, also number two is something religious, so there's also another pull factor to bring people in.
And then number five, I'd say making the tech stack simple and plug-and-play.
When you're trying to sell something to someone else, you need to make it look as simple as possible just so that they don't need to come in with like technical know-how per se to be able to operate this thing.
Cuz step six, I would say now you have kind of like your idea ready.
Now, of course the major part is obviously growing it for it to be attractive to a buyer.
I have a very specific route that I go down and it's normally UGC first.
So, I have multiple UGC accounts and I like to create content that is kind of rage baiting where it's kind of like you show something and people have to maybe scroll back or watch it again to just
make sure that I just see that or they just end up arguing with everyone in the comments as well because all TikTok sees is that oh,
that's engagement.
Let's boost that to other people.
Once I have the right hook, then I then launch on Meta Ads for example and that way I actually get really low CPIs.
CPI being cost per install.
[music] So, for Pray Screen we were getting between 30 to 50 cents cost per install in the US market which is like unheard of.
That's actually how I normally grow things.
Then number seven is around I guess the finale which is how to sell it.
For me, I love to get them to about 10k to 20k MRR before then looking for a buyer.
One thing you want to do is that your last three months you want it to be like an uptick,
right?
You don't want it to be like oh, it's currently failing and now you're trying to sell it because it just like you're trying to empty [music] back to somebody else.
Where I'd list it, MicroAcquire is a great place for you to list this.
Also just posting on Twitter as well.
I've seen does really well.
In terms of valuations, they vary depending on the buyer but I've seen between like two to four X EBITDA I would say.
EBITDA would be just essentially profit.
But again, the kind of app side build aren't something that's like so deeply technological that another company would be like well,
we need this for sure.
It tends to be more of a cash flow thing for the other company that's purchasing.
But normally between two to four X EBITDA for the ARR that you have.
Okay, cool.
Well, thanks for sharing that entire playbook.
That was amazing.
You've already built and sold four apps.
So, I imagine you've seen a lot of ideas that didn't work and obviously you've had some ideas that worked really well.
If you were starting over today and building stuff, what would be some of the ideas you'd be working on right now?
Apps that you think you could build and sell just like you've done.
First one sounds funny whenever I say it but if you've been dating or have a girlfriend,
you don't we have this issue where they kind of like oh, you know, I've got a headache.
I don't really feel well today.
And you just find out they three times a day.
I'd build an app where it just tracks that they've eaten three times a day.
For especially like around let's say the 18 to 30 age group for sure.
And the reason I do kind of this is because there's a specific audience.
So, that means targeting is a lot easier.
And then this is something I've already seen adjacent apps do which is more like you know,
calorie tracking specific women.
So, I'll just do some kind of version of that.
Second idea I'll do would probably be something around Korean skin care thing that the ladies love.
Again, I'll just make this kind of like tracker.
You can take a picture of your face kind of like the looks maxing but just more specifically that the Korean glass skin just because there's already a big trend around it.
People already spending real money on real procedures.
So, you would already know the capacity to spend already is there.
And then I call this Chill Guy AI but probably doesn't really make sense.
So, I always kind of thought yo, there should be like an app uh where I can just type in stuff about my girlfriend for example and then it just reminds me and it just says hey,
you haven't had a date in I don't know, three weeks.
[music] Here's a place.
Just click this button to book.
Or like you haven't sent flowers to her in like three months.
I don't have to think about it.
Just click this button to book straight to her address, right?
And like any little thing she's told me before I can just write it down in the kind of like journal [music] and then it just kind of uses that built to find gifts and I just click a button and it does it for me.
And I just kind of think that would absolutely kill it.
Um especially like revenue model wise, you can have a subscription base on that.
So, I think that's something that'd be super cool.
If you build that, I'll be one of your first customers.
I promise.
So, let me know when you do build that.
To talk about that idea that you were just talking about, I want to know about tech stack.
Let's say you were to just go and build that idea right now.
That was your next big idea.
What would be your tech stack in terms of building the app and then also tracking analytics and and running the business?
Yeah, for sure.
So, I tend to build in React Native.
So, that's what I'll do on the building side of things.
In terms of like the marketing which is what really matters on that end, I use something called Short Term Eyes.
That is basically like you're able to track TikTok views over time for the different accounts.
There's also another product called appstoretracker.com and that's able to be able to see different apps and how quickly they've gone up in the app store.
So, you can also track yours and see if there's any changes in like the bios or the titles etc.
Which can obviously help with ASO.
And then the Creator Check.
So, this is something that me and my girlfriend were actually working on.
Just think of it as like a Gusto but specifically for UGC creators where we do the calculations and payouts.
Okay, and on that same note for if you were to build Chill Guy AI, what do you think some of the costs and margins would look like for that business if you were to get to say 10k a month?
I would say all in all you're looking at at max $1,000 a month.
I think the balloon costs come from the UGC side of things and that depends on the amount of UGC creators that you get on board.
So, you could have 10 UGC creators.
Maybe you're paying 5 to 10k a month for them.
And then what you get is 10 different videos every single day which is super cool.
And then on the margin side of things, you're looking to have something that's at least 70% profit margin I would say for something to be super healthy.
Last question I always ask everyone who comes on Starter Story.
What would be your advice for someone starting over from scratch in 2025 building apps to sell?
What would be your advice to someone watching?
For sure.
Like my thing I say now is only play games [music] you can win and always have an edge.
And what I mean by that is like only play games you can win doesn't mean you always win but at least when you lose,
you know it's your fault.
If I was to build another app, unfortunately it wouldn't be Chill Guy AI.
I just don't think I have an edge in that.
But I would build another Christian [music] app but for maybe a different niche.
Um just because over time I now have an email list of 1.2 million Christians.
Uh and you know, Meta has this beautiful thing called lookalike audiences.
Makes it so [music] much easier for me to get now low cost per install uh whenever I want to build an app there.
And operationally it's just so much easier.
Just kind of create a new app and just put it into the [music] same funnel that you have.
And then you can also cross-sell within your apps.
Well, I can actually sell ad space to another one of your apps for free.
I think that's great advice.
Thanks for coming on Lots sharing your entire playbook.
Hopefully people really enjoyed this video.
If you guys have any questions, put it down in the comments below.
But otherwise, thanks for coming on, man.
You're inspiring.
Thank you so much.
Bye.
I want to thank Lots again for coming on the channel and sharing everything.
I think it's amazing that he's done this over four times and he has plans to do it over and over again.
That's the power of being able to come up with an idea and build it fast.
And this is exactly why we launched Starter Story Build.
[music] It's our program where we will help you take your idea and turn into a real app using only AI tools.
If you're ready to get off the sidelines, build that app and launch into the real world,
then head to the link in the description to check out Starter Story Build.
Our next boot camp is starting this week.
So, get in there and save your spot.
I would love to see you in there building.
All right.
Thank you guys for watching.
That's it for this episode.
I hope you enjoyed it.
I'll see you in the next one.
Peace.