What if I told you that success has nothing to do with coding?
Well, what I'm going to share with you today is the difference between apps that make millions and apps that die with zero downloads.
Don't believe me?
Well, here's proof.
Meet Steven, a founder who took his mobile app from 0 to $40,000 MR and then sold it for a life-changing amount.
Steven's not a famous influencer.
He's an actual founder in the arena who discovered a playbook that changed his life forever.
You might remember him from his last starter story video.
Well, that video got a million views and I asked him if he wanted to come back on the channel.
I said, "Dude, why don't you come on again, but this time share the full story.
Not the surface level stuff, but the actual spreadsheets, the exact viral videos, and everything that took you from zero to exit."
He said yes.
And that's what you're about to see right now.
His 10-minute viral validation method.
exactly how to go from 0 to 50 million views for free from your apartment and his simple strategy to turn $1 into $2 in scale using paid ads.
If you don't want to end up on page 500 of the app store, well, get out your pen and paper and enjoy the million-doll app playbook by Starter Story.
Welcome back to the channel, Stephen.
If you can remind the viewers of what you built and what we're going to be talking about today.
>> Thank you, man.
It's a pleasure to be back on the channel.
I'm Steven.
I have built, scaled, and exited multiple mobile apps for millions of dollars in revenue.
Last time I was on the channel, I talked about how I built Puff Count, my quit vaping app,
scaled it to $44,000 in monthly recurring revenue before exiting the company and selling it to a larger mobile app studio in Europe.
And today, we're going to be talking about the most important part of building mobile apps,
which is marketing.
>> Nice.
Big reason why I wanted to bring you back on the channel is you were going to come on and talk about your three-phase marketing framework.
First, before we dive in and get really into the nitty-gritty details, can you give me like the high level of what we're going to go over today?
>> Yeah, 100%.
Like I said, every mobile app that you build should be approached from a marketing first standpoint because as long as you can market your product,
you will make money.
And if your product is not marketable, you could have the best product in the world,
but if no one knows about it, you're never going to make any money.
It's never going to be a successful business.
Marketing should always come first.
To do that, first we do market research.
we understand what's going viral in our niche, what content is working in our niche and that we can also use that to validate the product in general.
Once we have the product validated and we start building it, then we can go into the market research and start to identify what type of content formats we want to recreate.
This is exactly what I did for PuffCount.
This is the entire reason that I was successful with PuffCount is because I did market research in the quit vaping niche on Tik Tok and I simply took inspiration from those videos.
I posted them organically and then scaled the winners with paid ads.
So, we have market research, post volume, organically, scale the winners with paid ads.
That is the three-step framework in a nutshell.
>> Cool.
All right.
Well, let's dive into phase one, which is market research.
I'd love if you gave me the step-by-step playbook if you were starting over today and you are someone who's looking for the idea.
I always like to start thinking of ideas and validating ideas by solving a problem for a large number of people,
right?
Vaping was a problem that I experienced in my daily life.
When I was in college, all my friends got addicted to vaping.
I got swept up in the habit.
So, you know, I knew it was a painful problem.
And I also saw vaping going mega viral on TikTok.
It's controversial.
It's viral.
And I was solving a problem for people.
Those three points together will make a killer product.
>> Cool.
If you were starting over today and everything you've learned with the apps that you've built,
how do you approach this phase to know that you're building the right thing?
>> Here's what we're going to do.
We're going to pull out our phones.
We're going to go to Tik Tok and type in any keywords related to our niche.
And then what you can do, tap the three dots in the top right and then you can filter by most liked videos of all time.
This is your market research.
We'll take Puff Count, my previous app, as an example.
You type in quit vaping on Tik Tok and then you go to videos and you can see that these videos,
some of these videos have gone insanely viral.
We have 1.3 million likes here.
We have 3.7 million likes here, right?
So, this is our market research.
Let's click into one here and let's see if we can find some similarities between this content and some of the content that I created here in this video.
They're dropping their vapes in a glass of water.
And if we go to the Puff Count profile, you can see that we were doing that.
That was one of our bread and butter.
33,000 views.
It's me dunking a vape into a glass of water.
This is not my original idea.
I was not the first person on TikTok to put a vape in a glass of water.
But I did the market research.
I understood that that content was resonating with my ideal target audience.
And I used that concept and created my own videos.
And then my next part of the process, it's very high-tech here.
So this is my market research strategy.
I take exactly what I found on Tik Tok and I put them all into a spreadsheet.
>> That was great.
So once you identify that this is a problem we're solving, I'd love if you could actually walk me through documenting in that spreadsheet on a specific Tik Tok video.
So let's go through this process together.
Again, step one is going on Tik Tok, typing in your keywords, and finding viral videos.
So we'll take this one for example that got 3.7 million organic likes, right?
So, what we'll do is we will copy and paste this URL into your spreadsheet here.
And then what we really want to do is we want to understand why this video went viral.
And every viral video has three key points.
The hook, the story line, and the call to action.
So, let's go ahead and watch this video today.
>> So, I just quit vaping like an hour ago.
I made the decision.
>> Okay.
So, she starts off holding her phone.
There's a little bit of action, a little bit of movement going.
And she starts off by saying, "I just decided to quit vaping an hour ago."
So, we're going to write that as the hook.
And I think it's always nice to take note of the way she shot the video as well.
So, holding camera, walking, then sets camera down.
These small little details in the video are actually very important.
You want to replicate and take inspiration from these as close as possible.
Right?
There's a reason she started this video while walking and then set it down in front of her,
right?
and it it was part of the hook and this video went viral.
So, we're going to use that.
And as you can see, she sits down in front of six glasses of water.
So, we could even add that onto the hook, right?
And then sets camera down in front of six glasses of water.
We want to take note of all of this stuff.
And now she's going to get into her story.
So, let's continue watching.
>> I have been vaping for 7 years.
And this is very symbolic because I have seven vapes.
>> Okay.
She's talking about how she's been vaping for seven years.
And she has seven different types of vapes.
She has her emergency vape, her walking vape, her car vape, her work vape.
And obviously, she's exaggerating here.
This girl is so good at making content.
Like, every every single shot and every single talking point was clearly calculated here.
>> And I've been wanting to quit for three or four of those.
>> So, she is talking about her quitting journey.
Talking about her quitting journey and history vaping while dropping the vapes into glasses of water.
irritable, unmotivated.
All I did was lay in bed and cry.
>> She's also talking about the pain points here.
She's talking about how all she would do is lay in bed, vape, cry, cough, and feel terrible.
This video is 2 minutes long.
I don't think your Tik Toks need to be 2 minutes long.
But if you can make them that long, great.
>> I did do this 15 minutes ago.
I didn't want to wait for it to deliver, so I got the audio book.
>> Here is the call to action.
Most importantly, she got an audio book.
Okay.
The Easy Way to Quit Vaping by Alan Carr.
There it is.
the call to action of the video.
So, in her call to action or solution, she talks about uh chewing gum, uh eating mints,
and the audio book by some author.
Now, we know that this video in reality was an ad because she is pitching this audio book by Alan Carr,
she said, right?
So, we know that she was promoting this book in her video and she crushed it.
The call to action at the end of the video really quickly, really subtly, makes it feel super organic,
doesn't feel salesy at all.
And those are the best ads.
So again, you know, we could sit here for hours and we could analyze these videos.
And this is what you should do.
Before I posted a single video on the Puff Count Tik Tok, I scrolled for 7 days straight.
I saved all the videos to the market research just like this.
And after 7 days of scrolling, analyzing, and understanding what goes viral in your niche and why it goes viral in your niche,
you will be so much better at creating content.
Cool.
So, we got our first video research row of our spreadsheet here.
We're going to go through and spend some days actually just writing these out.
We're not going to use too much AI.
We're going to write this and really understand the problems in our niche, content ideas,
and that sort of thing.
This is the research side, which I really, really like.
What's next?
How do we go from research to actually creating content?
Okay, now we're going to get into phase two, which is the actual creation of this content and growing your channel.
By following this organic growth framework, I grew the PuffCount account to 120,000 followers,
over 50 million views, and hundreds of thousands of app store installs, all for $0.
So, when you're creating this content, there is a proven framework to follow.
And that framework is hook, problem, solution, or call to action.
Obviously, the hook is the most important part.
You need to capture that attention in the first 3 seconds.
And I can show an example, one of my most viral videos.
This one got 5 million views.
I'm shaking this glass bowl of empty vapes.
There's so many different elements of this hook and we did this intentionally.
Number one, there's a sound hook.
We're shaking the glass with vapes in it.
There's some crazy sounds going on.
And then boom, we hop right into the concept of the video.
And then you want to present the problem or the story line clearly.
So, what are we doing in this video?
We're paying people to ditch their vapes.
Why?
Because vapes are unhealthy.
And then, of course, at the end of the video, we're going to have a quick 2- second call to action.
The 2-C call to action, simply showing the product in your video, works so well because if people miss that,
they have to rewatch your video again and it creates an engagement loop.
People on Tik Tok do not want to be watching ads.
They want to be entertained.
They want to be educated.
They want to be informed.
Your entire app is going to be a funnel, right?
And at the very top of the funnel, we have your Tik Tok video or your Tik Tok views.
You don't need to explain every part in your funnel for your video to be effective.
All you have to do is take the person from your Tik Tok video to the app store.
That's exactly what all these videos do, right?
There's no there's no explanation of the product.
There's no explaining the features.
So, if you can do that with your content and present a sly, organic feeling call to action,
you will crush.
Steven is the perfect example of how someone can turn a simple app idea into a million-doll business.
But that comes with finding the right idea and knowing how to validate it.
Well, you're in luck because I've studied thousands of app ideas, making millions, and spent hours obsessing over what works,
what fails, and what separates the winners from the rest.
And today, I'm going to share the entire database of ideas with you for free.
50 plus validated AI app ideas, what problem they solve, how much money they make, and how they grew.
All backed by reallife case studies.
This is basically a gold mine of profitable, simple AI apps on the internet right now.
So, if you're serious about building an app that can make money like Steven, hit the first link in the description and grab it for free.
Hopefully, this helps you find your next big idea.
All right, let's get back to Steven.
All right.
Well, the next question that I have for you is, you know, once you start posting stuff,
creating stuff, which is a big learning curve for a lot of people, especially putting themselves out on short form video for the first time.
What's the posting strategy of this?
You mentioned you do videos one time a day.
What would you do if you were starting today?
What do you recommend?
Uh is what time to post, how much to post, and when to know when to stop.
The posting strategy.
This is where I see a lot of people fail, right?
Because in the beginning, it's going to be slow.
In the beginning, it's going to be hard to get that first viral pop.
But the most important thing is staying consistent.
Whether you're posting, whether you're getting creators to post, you need to stay consistent with it,
right?
Don't worry about the time that you post the content.
all the small little details of the content.
Do not be a perfectionist.
Your goal here is volume.
Your goal here is knowing generally what direction your content should be going.
You're just looking for that first viral video.
The way to get there is by posting volume.
Volume negates luck, right?
So, you need to be posting as much as possible.
And when you get a video that pops off, recreate that concept.
If you look at the most viral people on Tik Tok, let's forget about businesses for a second.
Let's think about just creators, influencers.
The most viral people on Tik Tok, on YouTube, they do the same style of video over and over and over again.
There's a reason they do that.
And we could take a page out of their playbook and we could do the same thing for our app.
The most important part is to stay consistent.
Post every single day.
Post based on your market research.
It'll give you a much better chance of going viral.
And then once you do find a video that pops off for you, continue to recreate that video.
It will become easier and easier for you.
An important thing too is once you get that first viral video, the floor of the amount of views that you get will increase over time because the platforms trust you more and there's more engagement to your videos so they will be shown more.
All it takes is that first viral video to get you out of that 200 view jail.
And also, if you're posting on one platform, why not post on all of them?
Download the videos, post them on Tik Tok, post them on Instagram reels, post them on YouTube shorts,
post them on Twitter.
Twitter is so slept on.
Do not sleep on Twitter as a distribution.
As you start to create more and more content, you're going to understand some formats don't drive high intent installs.
They don't drive any conversions for you.
There's one example that comes to mind.
Yeah.
So, this video here got 11.6 million views, close to a million likes, and it drove me close to no installs.
Number one, because I didn't have a call to action, but number two, you know, I'm not really talking about any pain points here.
There's not a lot going on.
It was kind of a bad video in terms of conversions.
It was great for the account and great for driving views and and followers and shares and engagement and stuff like that.
But this didn't really drive installs for me.
And I think it's important to keep track of that.
And you can see here, you know, there's two videos.
These were my two highest converting videos in terms of installs and sales on PuffCount.
So I pinned those to the top of my profile.
And you'll see these are very different styles of video.
Again, these follow our proven framework of hook storyline solution.
I pinned these videos on my profile because they drove the highest amount of conversions.
Your profile itself will become its own funnel.
So, everyone who visits my profile now is going to watch these two pinned videos for sure because they're the first videos that show up.
And I chose to pin these videos because they were the highest converting videos.
And what I've come to find is the highest converting videos for me personally were public interviews,
simple product demos like this video.
There's trend hijacking as well.
And you can also have the problem solution narratives like this video here.
All right, so we've gone through the content creation phase, which is probably the hardest phase.
If you can get through this and create viral formats that work, you're pretty much set.
But you can't create content yourself forever.
So, what's the next step after that to really truly grow, build something that you can sell like you did for Puff Cat?
Pat, I'm so glad you asked.
So, we finished phase two.
We have this library of organic content and now we want to scale.
There's a couple different ways to scale.
You yourself, you can go beast mode.
You could post a,000 videos a day, but that's not very likely.
You can hire and outsource creators, which is easier said than done.
I think everybody's going through a super distortive process to hire creators right now.
You have to email a thousand of them.
Only one gets back to you and they give you some outrageous price.
But that is exactly why I built my next product which is posted.
On posted, what we did was we made connecting with creators as easy as possible.
So this is the best way to work with creators.
We have this feature called deals.
For example, you create a project brief.
You explain what your product is.
You have some rules for the content you want.
You could choose where you want the creators to be from.
And then you have your inspiration content right here.
Going back to our market research, this is where we give the creators our market research.
We tell the creators what videos are going viral in our niche, what's working in our niche,
and then creators will actually submit videos to your deal for free.
So, for example, this creator submitted this video to my deal and I can watch it for free.
And this is what the creator wants to be paid.
I can approve this piece of content or I can reject this piece of content and I can ask for another price or whatever it is.
But you can see all these creators made videos for my product for free.
And there's all different types of bids, right?
This one wants $40.
This one wants $50.
This one wants 100.
So, you can scroll through these, approve or deny, you only pay for the ones that you love.
And then when you do choose one and you do pay for one, you own the video itself and you own the ad code so that you can scale it further on paid ads.
For example, this creator right here who has 552,000 followers, she made a post for us for 110 bucks.
It got 30,000 views.
This creator here with 2.7 million followers, 110 bucks a video.
or this creator right here who only had 768 followers but made an amazing piece of content for us that got 53,000 views.
And again, you know, we own these videos for life.
Copy the ad code and scale further on paid ads using meta or Tik Tok ads.
The first thing that we need to do is start giving data into these paid ad platforms cuz Tik Tok and and Facebook or any paid ad platform doesn't have enough data on your app yet.
So, you will need an MMP, a mobile measurement partner to send these events into the paid ad platforms.
Adjust is a great one.
Appsfire is a great one, but we need to feed the paid ad platforms with enough data,
right?
So, your first campaign cannot be a purchase campaign.
You can't optimize for those users just quite yet because Tik Tok and Facebook don't really know who those users are yet.
CAC is your customer acquisition cost.
So, with all of our content and all of our paid ads, our customer acquisition cost on PuffCount was anywhere around 20 to $24.
And our lifetime value was anywhere from $55 to upwards of $70 per conversion.
So, that was profitable math for us.
We knew that if we put $1 into paid ads, it would get $2, sometimes even more, out on the other end.
So, here you'll see our paid ads dashboard.
We spent a total of $82,000 on our paid ads before exiting the business.
This is how we scaled from 3K to $44,000 in monthly recurring revenue.
And you can see here, look at the cost per click.
3 cents, 18 cents, 21 cents, 15 cents, 35 cents, 9 cents.
We got these results almost like day one of running ads because we had this library of proven content.
We knew exactly what videos we were going to upload to the paid ads dashboard because we had validated it all organically.
So, we were spending smarter.
And this is our four-step scaling process in order to optimize your paid ads.
Everything is a funnel.
Just like our Tik Tok videos, Tik Tok profile itself is a funnel.
So are paid ads.
If you think of everything as a funnel, it becomes so much easier because you don't have to go straight from a view to a sale.
That's so hard to do, right?
Think of it in a stepby-step process.
Everything is a funnel.
So at the top of the funnel, we have our views and then obviously we have our clicks.
So our views on our paid ads and then people who have clicked our paid ad and then people who have installed our app from our paid ad and then people who have purchased from our paid ad.
And your views are going to be top of funnel and the sales are going to be at the absolute bottom of the funnel.
And inherently there's going to be less people who purchase your product compared to the amount of people that view your product.
So, when you're starting on paid ads, it's very important that you fill up each step of the funnel first before you start to optimize for the bottom.
So, first we're going to optimize for views and then we're going to optimize for clicks on those ads and then we're going to optimize for installs and then trials and then subscriptions.
These are all different events that you can optimize for in your paid ads.
Depending on which event you target and optimize for, the cost and the return on that spend will change a ton.
So you fill the ad platforms with enough data so that eventually you can start to target your trials and subscriptions.
And as far as the platform strategy goes with paid ads, it really depends and it's different for every app,
right?
From my experience with PuffCount, Tik Tok was much cheaper traffic, but the quality of the traffic was a little bit lower.
Whereas on Meta, the traffic was more expensive, but the quality was a bit higher.
Facebook and Tik Tok are really the only two places that you should start running paid ads.
Ultimately, you can test both depending on your budget.
I think it's important to lock down one paid ad platform at first because again, you need to fill these ad platforms with as much data as possible for them to be the most effective.
So, if you're splitting your budget everywhere and you're spending $5 here and $10 there,
it's not really going to work for you.
I would try to focus on one platform in the beginning until you lock it down, you nail it down,
you scale your budget, and then you can shift to another paid ad platform.
For me personally, we scaled most of our spend on Tik Tok ads.
And that was because all of our content that we used on our paid ads was made for Tik Tok.
I was in my apartment making Tik Toks all day.
So naturally, where our content performed the best when we scaled on paid.
And a lot of people are scared of paid ads and they don't want to do it.
But Facebook and and Tik Tok are some of the most profitable companies in the world for a reason.
It's because paid ads work.
It's because companies are using this.
It'll make it so much easier for you to scale.
I'm a solopreneur.
I'm bootstrapping these products.
I don't want to waste my money on paid ads.
And you don't have to.
You just need to identify what content goes viral organically and then you can spend confidently on paid ads and feel way more confident that you're going to get a return on your ad spend.
And paid ads are so great because you can optimize for certain events in your videos.
And this is really where your content creation skills and validating the content organically comes into play because for our specific paid ad strategy,
we are optimizing for the people who are most likely to purchase.
So, we're tracking all these events on Tik Tok ads, on Facebook ads, and we are telling Facebook and Tik Tok,
go find us more people who are most likely to purchase our product.
With the killer organic content library that we had, telling Facebook and Tik Tok to optimize for certain events inside our app,
those are the two things we needed to crush with paid ads.
We were profitable almost instantly while running paid ads.
And we were able to scale very quickly because we had done all the work up front.
And not only that, you can have a call to action in your videos.
my view to install rate skyrocketed.
Obviously, running paid ads because Tik Tok will give you a call to action on the video if you're running paid ads in an organic piece of content if you're not running paid ads.
You have to rely on someone going to the app store, searching in your product.
That's a lot more effort.
Although you're spending for this reach, the reach is much more effective on paid ads.
The campaign structure on your paid ads is very, very important.
Again, we want to upload our best performing organic videos and then we simply let the platforms optimize.
Again, when you're starting, you want to optimize for the top of funnel.
And as you get more data and more spend into these ad platforms, you can start to optimize for the bottom of the funnel.
And it's very important to track everything.
And use analytics tools like Superwall or like Revenue Cat.
You can effectively track your cost per install, your trial conversion rate, your subscription rate,
your retention rate, and most importantly, your lifetime value.
The lifetime value of every customer that comes into your app because that is your northstar metric.
That is your golden metric.
Because Tik Tok will tell you how much it costs to acquire those customers, but you need to understand what their lifetime value is.
You want to increase the lifetime value of your customers so you can spend more to acquire those customers.
And if you can get to a 3:1 CAC to LTV ratio, congratulations.
You've built a money printing machine.
So that's it in a nutshell.
That is our three-step process that helped us scale PuffCount to $44,000 in monthly recurring revenue before exiting the business to a larger mobile app studio in Europe.
That's it.
You start with market research.
You give yourself the best chance to go viral.
You start posting consistently.
Hire creators and start to validate content organically.
And then you take your best performers and put them on paid ads so that you can scale.
Well, thank you for sharing your playbook, Stephen.
This was amazing.
It's super cool to have someone who has actually done this.
You showed all your examples from Puff Count.
You didn't hold anything back.
This is a business that changed your life and it's super cool to see the behind the scenes of it.
So, thank you for sharing.
And if you are watching this right now, we want to bring Stephen back on the channel for hopefully a third time.
So if you have any questions for Stephen, put them in the comments.
Hopefully we'll have you back on for a third time.
>> Our next video is going to be in person, Pat.
>> Oh yeah, we will make sure to do a video live IRL.
>> I'll be back for the third one because I'm going to sell my third company.
Maybe that'll be our next video.
>> And that's what it takes these days.
So thanks for coming on, Stephen, sharing all this.
You're awesome, man.
>> Absolutely, Pat.
Thank you for having me, bro.
>> I hope you enjoyed this video and got some inspiration from Steven's story.
But real quick, I want to remind you the whole point of these videos is to help you find an idea and actually build it.
Learning is cool, but action is what will get you that dream outcome.
And with AI tools getting better and better every day, it's never been easier to get started.
You can spin up a working app in just a few hours and start turning that into a real business.
If you're looking for a proven system or road map to build with AI, then definitely check out Starter Story Build.
Our programs will help you find an idea, build it with AI, and ship it to the real world fast.
Just click the first link in the description if you want to learn more.
Thanks again for watching.
We'll see you in the next one.
Peace.