If any viewers is watching this and does a video on YouTube for 45 days, if they don't make at least $5,000,
I'll just PayPal you $500.
>> This is Vasco.
He built an AI app that in just 2 years went from 0 to $70,000 a month.
>> Most our users come from YouTube.
>> But here's what's crazy about his story.
He did it all with YouTube.
One video a day, nothing fancy, no crazy tools, and it worked.
>> The way in which you get people to buy from you is if they know, like, and trust you.
Using a simple strategy, Vasco turned YouTube videos into a million-dollar business.
And I brought him onto the channel to break it all down.
In this video, we'll dive into his YouTube strategy that generates $70,000 a month.
How you can create money-making assets that sell your product while you sleep, and why YouTube beats every other platform for building trust and getting conversions.
All right, this one's going to be fun.
Let's dive in.
I'm Pat Walls, and this is Starter Story.
All right, welcome Vasco to the channel.
Tell me about who you are, what you built, and what's your story.
>> Hey, my name is Vasco.
I built a software company called Arvo.
We scaled it from zero to around 70K in MR fully organic.
And I think the most interesting part about this is that we leverage just one platform,
which was YouTube.
>> Before we get into this YouTube playbook, which I think is amazing.
I think people watching this are going to love it.
I just want to understand what your product does.
What is Arvo?
What does it do?
Who are the customers?
So, Arvo helps marketing agencies, business owners do SEO a bit faster leveraging AI.
SEO tends to be a tedious process, takes a lot a lot of time.
We try to shorten the time until where you can see results.
It starts from around $99 a month.
It goes all the way to almost $700 a month.
We do of course as a SAS have charge.
So, along the way, we have a lot of clients, but at the moment, we have around 600 paying clients.
>> That's amazing.
This business is doing basically a million dollars a year.
How do you find the idea for Arvo?
How do you get to this point?
It was 2016 or 2015.
I was just browsing YouTube and I came across this guy called Alex Becker and I saw a video from him where he was making supposedly 10K a month doing rank and rent SEO.
And so I started doing that.
Bought my first domain, started doing local SEO with rank and rent.
Got a couple of clients then got a bit tired of dealing with clients.
So I just took my SEO services and started selling them on Fiverr, Upwork and other marketplaces.
But then I noticed that these marketplaces, they were missing a lot of things that I wanted to see in my own marketplace.
And so I built my own SEO marketplace called Vetted.
We sold it last year and the AI bubble was just coming.
When I sold Vetted, I knew that I wanted to still build something in the SEO space, but now applying AI to it.
And so we thought an AI writer could be a good idea.
So we built it.
That's basically the whole story of how Argo came about.
>> Okay.
Well, what I'm really excited and why I really wanted to have you on the channel, Vasco,
is what you told me about how you grew this business.
I think a lot of people watching might be wondering how you built it, what the product does.
I think one of the coolest things about what you did is how you grew this business.
So, can you give me a breakdown of what the main growth channel is for your SAS?
Most our users come from YouTube.
The way in which you get people to buy from you is if they know, like, and trust you,
right?
And I think the best way to have someone know, like, and trust you is if they see your face and they hear your voice for long periods of time.
All in all, I think YouTube has everything you need to have someone like, and trust you,
and then buy from.
It's not to say that Tik Tok doesn't work, blogging doesn't work, Twitter, LinkedIn doesn't work.
But I think as in terms of a ratio to effort to results, I think YouTube is the best one.
>> Okay, that's amazing.
This business was grown purely with YouTube.
But what I really want to get from you, Vasco, is the full playbook.
Tell me exactly how you went from zero to a million-dollar business purely with YouTube.
>> So this was basically our playbook in three core steps.
First one is you have to focus on producing money making assets.
I just produce a bunch of long form content in basically three buckets.
First bucket again is evergreen.
So a video that I know that if I post today, it will still keep on getting views a year,
two years from now.
And we do have those videos.
I'll give you an example.
We have a video on the best AI SEO writer.
The second bucket is news relevant type videos that get a lot of views in the first two or three days and then die out.
These are basically a new Google update comes out.
This is good to get a bunch of subs and a bunch of new eyeballs onto your channel which then you can funnel into your products or services.
Then the third is just sort of viral like Mr.
Beast like videos but applied to software which is quite hard to do.
Then we just do that over and over again.
The issue with that is that I'm just one so I'm sort of capped as to how many videos I can do.
And so I say this to say that this goes into the second part of the strategy which was how can I multiply myself?
And so what I did then was I created a bunch of YouTube channels.
Vasco SEO tips, Tim SEO guru, SEO news, whatever.
I had all these channels we owned.
And so then I had to find creators because my goal was to have all channels and post a creator in each one of those channels.
The wrong way to go about finding creators is going and finding creators because they're very expensive and they have a big ego.
And so what I did was let me find people who I think can become creators.
So I went on Upwork and I skimmed through people's profiles who for example had a video.
Having a video on your Upwork profile tells me that you're sort of comfortable in front of the camera.
So I went and went after those guys.
And so all in all, I had all these channels and I paid people per performance and I paid people per uh per video.
On top of that, why not expand to other languages?
So we found Portuguese creators, we found Spanish ones just like Mr.
Vist does with these channels.
After you've done step one and two, you want to focus on the third step, which is scaling and expanding with paid ads.
Most of your videos graphs will look like this.
They go up, get views, and then they stagnate and get no more views.
And so what I've noticed was that when we were getting views, we were getting sales.
And then when the views stagnated, we stopped getting sales.
I didn't felt like recording the same video over and over again just to get those initial views.
And I think that's where paid ads came in.
So on YouTube, you can run what's called infeed ads.
These ads appear in um two places.
First one is on on your YouTube homepage.
And then when you're watching a video, it shows up on the right hand sidebar.
So they look like organic pieces of content.
I took the videos who performed well, who got views, got sales, and then stagnated and I paid YouTube for infeed ads.
The issue with YouTube and YouTube ads as well is that it's very hard to track.
To track YouTube organic, what we've done is three things.
First one again is have a dedicated UTM in each video.
If maybe 1% of people click the links in the description, you know that they came from that video.
Something else we did to increase the tracking accuracy was have a dedicated coupon in each video.
I would say something like,"Hey guys, if you want to check out arvogar.com and by the way,
if you want a coupon code, just click the little chat bubble at the bottom and ask the guys from support saying,
"Hey, Vasco told me I can get a coupon code.
I came from this video.
Give me a coupon code."
And third thing, if you go on to arbor right now, if you sign up, we have like a welcome questioner where if you select you came from YouTube,
a bunch of our channels faces pop up.
So, you can choose which creator you came from.
When I mentioned about scaling with paid ads, you have to be careful because you never know if you're not promoting a video that's not bringing in many sales.
Two extra tips on CTAs.
before I was doing the call to action at the end of the video and that doesn't make any sense because most people don't watch all the way through.
So just the simple fact of moving the CTA towards the beginning and the middle of the video just increased our numbers of of signups by by a lot.
Second thing is don't just make generic call to actions like uh yeah just go check out the website.
What we've been doing is we create specific call to actions.
So we make them sort of interactive not just a generic one and prompting them to do an action inside of the site.
That's it.
I think your strategy is really smart.
You built this awesome tool and then you use YouTube to grow the business.
But it still reminds me, you can't make YouTube videos about a product that doesn't exist.
If you watching this don't have something built yet, all the content strategy in the world won't help you.
And this is exactly why we launched Starter Story Build.
It's our flagship program where you will learn how to build and launch your project using AI coding tools in just a couple weeks.
You'll get access to our build experts.
You'll join thousands of other builders and you'll learn our complete framework for building and shipping apps.
Once you have something built, then you can go start creating YouTube videos just like Basco did.
So, if you're ready to build, just head to the first link in the description to check out Starter Story Build.
All right, Vasco, let's get to the next question.
I would love if you could actually show me a real example from your YouTube channels for your business.
Can you show me a YouTube video that kind of changed your business?
>> Yeah, sure.
I guess this is the very first one where I realized the power of YouTube which again this was posted I think 2 years ago.
It's a video on how to make a Wikipedia page.
It's a very bad tutorial but still till this day it gets 1.2 million impressions.
I think around 300 views every single day.
65% of traffic comes from YouTube search.
How to create a Wikipedia page, how to make a Wikipedia page.
20% of the traffic comes from Google search.
Not only does a video rank on YouTube, it also ranks on Google.
And I can go on to the LLM type of things because nowadays we see a bunch of our videos being recommended in these LLMs.
So if I can give any tips is to yes build out these evergreen videos.
Granted though it's very important to know that mix up these evergreen ones with sharing case studies,
sharing news, just produce valuable content and know that there's some chance that those videos can become evergreen in the long run.
>> Okay, thanks for sharing those real examples.
My next question for you for anyone watching this that wants to do this YouTube thing to build a business through YouTube content,
what would be your advice on how to get started if you're getting started right now in 2025?
>> I think as cliche as it sounds, like with anything, you have to be consistent and do a lot of volume.
I think Alexis said this, it's very difficult that you do something a lot of times for a long period of time and you don't see success.
So for YouTube, what I advise is, okay, just post a video every single day for 45 days.
Most people will watch this and won't do it.
The rest of the people will try to do it and will stop after a week.
Maybe like one or two people out of all them will actually do it.
And those who do it will actually see success.
If any viewers watching this and does a video on YouTube for 45 days, if they don't make at least $5,000,
I'll just PayPal you $500.
By the way, don't think that you need to have these very polished videos, right?
all our videos that got this from literally zero to 70k MR just myself in my basement recording just a micro board like a whiteboard going over valuable stuff.
Well, on that note, I think that's cool.
You know, starting small, just using Loom.
What are the tools that you use and would recommend other people to use if they want to be recording every day,
creating lots of content on YouTube.
>> You don't need much.
You need Loom.
Get the premium version so you can record in HD.
You need Myro.
That's the whiteboard I use.
Then you need some sort of way to edit the videos.
I use Camtasia.
I think you should put more work and more effort into the hardware than the software.
Have a good mic, have a good uh camera, and have good lighting.
So, a regular running light or mic.
I use this Sure SM7B.
That's it.
Don't over complicate it.
I think the hardest part is getting going.
>> Okay, cool.
I mean, that's a nice stack.
Last question that we have for everyone who comes on starter story.
If you could go back in time, stand on young Vasco's shoulder when you were just getting started out or for anyone who's watching this that wants to do what you did,
build a million-dollar SAS, what would be your advice?
I think it's very important to know that this is very hard.
This is very difficult.
The best piece of advice I can give you is that to increase your chances of succeeding,
is you have to work very hard.
I did 20 to 30 minute videos every single day for almost a year.
Who's willing to do that?
To be in the 1%, you have to be willing to do what the other 99% of people aren't willing to do.
>> There are no shortcuts.
I believe that.
Thanks for coming on, Vasco.
I love the business that you built.
Thanks for sharing this whole YouTube thing, sharing those YouTube videos that you've created.
I think people are going to love this.
If you enjoyed this video and you're watching this, let me know if you want to have Vasco back on and we can go deeper into the YouTube playbook.
So, put a comment down there if you want to see that.
We can do it.
Otherwise, thanks for coming on, Vasco, and we'll see you soon.
>> Cheers.
>> All right.
I want to thank Vasco again for coming on to the channel.
I'm a huge fan of YouTube, obviously, and I think his YouTube strategy is genius.
So, congrats on the success, Vasco.
But I do have to remind you, if you're watching this, that all of this still starts by building something.
Without a product, you'll have nothing to promote.
And that's why we launched Starter Story Build.
We'll help you build and ship your idea faster than ever before.
And in just a few weeks, you'll have a full working app ready to share with the world.
So, if you're interested, head to the first link in the description to check out Starter Story Build.
All right, that's it for this episode.
Thank you guys for watching.
We'll see you in the next one.
Peace.