this guy quit his job and built a $10 million business by accident and the crazy part is he did it using a marketing method that cost z i from the
beginning knew that were going to be the secret to our growth I invited Ian to my house to Deep dive with him ask him exactly how his business Works how he
got his first customer and how he grew to over 10 million a year in just 3 years before all this success Ian was chasing empty dreams working for others
in finance and VC but eventually he had enough and so I got on that path and I got on that treadmill but very quickly I was like no this is not for me shortly
after he quit he raised money to start his own app company but then quickly realized that was just another rat race so he quit that and then decided to go out on his own but this time with no
expectations that he'd strike a big then he stumbled into an opportunity that would change his life forever I realiz I think a lot of other people are realizing I just want a good place in my
life where I can live and do the things I want to do with the people I want to do them with you don't have to be a billionaire to do that and that's what led me to in this video Ian shares his exact
strategy on how to build a business that gives you Freedom including the best niches to build an offshoring business how to scale a team and hire A+ talent
and the marketing strategy he uses that costs $0 and he still uses today I'm Pat walls and this is starter story all right
man thanks for coming thanks for coming to my house my pleasure and doing this tell me about who you are and what you built I'm e Meers founder CEO of oceans it's a Services business that offers
High skill operational Outsourcing to hundreds of clients entrepreneurs Ecom Brands Services businesses all across the world the idea came in late 2021
signed our first contract in Fe feary of 2022 we did 650k in Revenue that year which is a lot for year one of any businessing last year we closed at about
15 million in Revenue so it's just been up up up and it's very profitable millions of dollars in profit since we started so give me a further breakdown the business how does this business work
what kind of clients do you serve how much do you charge so for us we hire people all over the world mostly in Sri Lanka few in South Africa and other places we match them out full-time 40
hours a week longterm to our clients they're part of their team they're at the All Hands they're on the calendar on the slack everything they're doing real work we charge around3 to $4,000 a month
per headcount you know if you're getting an EA it's going to be a little less if you're getting a financial controller it's going to be a little more then we pay our you know we pay our people all their wages and everything like that all their benefits and we pocket The Profit
between yeah before the success I understand you had a bunch of different roles and you had a bunch of different things can you tell me a little bit more about that and how that led to building this huge business yeah well first I
thought I wanted to be an academic so I was like getting my PhD in international policy security policy that was like really intellectually fascinating but I didn't want to live in my car which a lot of my colleagues were doing after they graduated so I was like oh let's
change course here went into Finance was working like at fund investing so we investing in Venture funds private Equity Funds stuff like that and so I was working with all these entrepreneurs I was talking to them all they were all
psyched they were getting up out of bed every day like really excited about their idea they just wanted to build something do something and at some point you're like you know what I want to do that so decided to start my own company
the first one we took investment it was venture-backed it was an app I I'm not really an app guy but I was somehow like had started an app company and found myself there and we eventually sold it
but I realized if you go that route you're not really working for yourself you you're like okay I want to build something I want to own something I want to do something but the second you raise money your board's telling you what metrics you got to hit you're sort of
like on this treadmill of raising the next round and so I got on that path and I got on that treadmill but very quickly I was like no this is not for me and so after that experience I was sort of like
okay now this time I actually want to do something where I'm it's mine I'm in charge I make the decisions I can go fast or slow and that's what led me to profitable Services businesses because I
have a I want to like live my life and enjoy my life and I approached this business from what do I want my life to be like how do I make the most money or how do I get the most Venture financing I realize and I think a lot of other
people are realizing I just want a good place in my life where I can live and do the things I want to do with the people I want to do them with you don't have to be a billionaire to do that so where you
live how you want to live these are all decisions that should actually go into what kind of business do I want to create okay so you kind of you leave this crazy VC world you're you're looking to start something that makes
your life better maybe makes $200,000 a year but then you stumble onto a massive opport so tell me a little bit more about that the opportunity of offshore Talent as a whole why is this such a big opportunity
it's been a big opportunity for a long time but for only people that had a lot of money to invest in huge teams so for instance Google has like 180,000 FTE
around the world they have 120,000 people offshore Microsoft same ratio this has been the secret sauce of the biggest companies in the world for
decades the business opportunity for me was was because Co changed everything right suddenly everyone had to go online if you can work with someone who's just moved to Montana because it's co and
they want to move back in with their parents you can work with someone in Sri Lanka yeah this opened the door to companies who hadn't considered offshoring before to start doctor's
offices accounting practices law firms creative agencies people who are like whoa my whole team's remote why don't I just throw Global Talent into the mix when it's
better priced often times higher quality and more eager to get the work done so I saw that the offshoring industry was sort of taking off and I thought to
myself well what if I just have a better product like this industry exists I know people want this and that was the light bulb moment go find something that people already want and do it
differently or better and there's your equation for a successful business for our audience who's watching right now they're looking to potentially build something on in this space in the offshore Talent what kind of ideas have
you come across what's an idea that comes to mind that you don't have the time to build that you'd recommend our viewers could build creating a small vertical in which you can succeed is really key I'm the I'm the founder and
CEO of an offshoring business I get 10 emails a day from other offshoring businesses trying to sell me offshore Talent yeah it's a commoditized space so you have to stand out and one of the best ways to stand out is to be the best
in your category so I've seen a lot of companies be the best at video editing be the best at certain very specific types of design like illustration be the best at like CAD design for architecture
firms and things like that specializing in a vertical where you're going to be talked about it's easy to get to $1 to $2 million in Revenue doing that like Ian said the tides are shifting and
right now is the best time in history to be building a business that makes your life better and the best part is you don't need thousands of dollars or hundreds of employees to do it with all the tools and resources out there today
it's 10 times easier and cheaper to build a business than it was back then especially if you want to do it as a solopreneur but you need to know the right information and the right steps to
take so if you're anything like Ian and you want to take advantage of this opportunity and build a business like his right now then head to the first link in the description to get this free solopreneur business guide this is one
of the best ways I'd recommend if you want to learn the information necessary to become a solopreneur it includes a bunch of tools templates and even an extra list of 70 solopreneur business
ideas to help you get started right away I personally found the systems for solopreneur Section to be really helpful because it gives you action steps on how to scale hard things like onboarding and
project management just head to the first link in the description to download it for free this guide was made by HubSpot which is today's video sponsor a big shout out to them for putting together this free resource all
right let's talk about the early days how did you set up this business how did you get your first customer how' you get your first 10 customers what did that look like so at this point we hadn't raised any money it was totally me I Own
100% of the business I knew nothing about this space nothing at all and I thought okay if we're going to be doing vas we probably should train them to be great vas so there was a lot of training
built into our model I hired someone someone who has been in EA for 10 years to make me a training course and then we just hired three people that I had sort
of gotten connected to through my time in Sri Lanka to do our first cohort just three people and I was like we're just going to test this out with some friends so I gave the the pitch to some friends and I give much reduced pricing so we
didn't make any money on um our first three customers but I just wanted to put this in someone's hands and see what
happens so for me it was all about if I make this business can I call someone tomorrow and they'll buy it from me and I think that's really important don't go
into business being like Oh I'm going to buy Facebook ads and sell it to some stranger in Arkansas it's got to be something that you can not just give people to test but will someone give you
money for this thing within you know however many days of launching it but it's got to be someone you know yeah so that for me was how we got our first couple of customers but there was a lot
of anxiety when I tapped out my network I was like what if this is just a business where people I call and they like me or they know me will buy it and then it
stops and luckily we started getting like referrals from our existing customers I didn't know these people in the business sort of grew from there but there was a moment of real anxiety about
like do I have a real business or am I just selling my friend something that they can probably maybe use enough to pay me all right let's talk about marketing um this business makes millions of dollars a year but you haven't really done a whole lot of
marketing around it I think that's cool tell me more about that so I from the beginning knew that referrals were going to be the secret to our growth if you have a great service business they usually grow through Word of Mouth
everybody needs Lawn Care everyone needs house cleaners like those types of businesses if you pick the right ones grow through word of mouth because people have excellent service so the first step is make sure you have a great
service nobody's going to recommend a service or a product that sucks and then like if you're building referral business before you get to the here's our funnel here's our engine here's how
it works click here to join put your customers in the position to be a hero to their friends by recommending your service and you'll succeed so if I look
tired and Haggard and you know whatever I want someone to see that who's our customer and be like man you look like [ __ ] I should hook you up with oceans because they're going to change your life a lot of our customer base or business owners are always thinking
about hiring I think that's also true for great like lead generation businesses like that how do I get more business constant topic how are you growing dude how are you marketing where
are you spending yeah if you're in those categories you've got a builtin word of mouth that's really important yeah double click on the the quality of service thing how did you make sure that
the service was so good specifically what did you do to ensure that this was the best service possible so that it could scale in terms of how to deliver an incredible experience just think
about what happens in your daily life if you send an email to someone and they get back to you in 5 minutes that feels amazing MH if you have a problem and you get on the phone with somebody and
they're like you know what I totally understand that's our bad let me comp you a month of service because this is not the experience I want you to have just keep going with this going in day
by day with these EAS helping them touch up their emails helping them do their canva work there's so many pieces of lwh hanging fruit out there in terms of delivering exceptional customer
experience that people can do if they're just willing to be on for a pretty long period of time in that initial stretch even though I wanted great you know easy lifestyle I knew the first 20 the first
50 you got to really lean in you got to be there you got to pick up the phone you got to call people and you just got to go beyond the bounds of what you might do when the company's large yeah so tell me what kind of tools and
software run this business I I'm a big fan of not spending on tools so we don't have a lot we use mostly Gite for everything I think that what you can get done in Google Sheets is incredible and
people should go on YouTube and realize you can run an entire company's dashboard in Google Sheets and we use um stripe for payments we use notion for a
lot of like organization and um you know sort of material reference guides and things like that um and we use a company called TLD DV which is video recording and and meeting recording and then of
course we use HubSpot for our CRM so we try to keep our tools pretty slim you would be surprised how much you can get done in Google Sheets Google Classroom G Suite um and then for the stuff that you
can't get done we use pretty popular providers like notion and stripe and things like that so let's talk about scale you built this to a million a year and then now it's doing over $10 million a year talk about that timeline how did
you scale this business this was the most interesting thing for me that I learned and [ __ ] up is there's a real Gap when you go from the first five to
eight people doing everything where one person has all the knowledge they don't have to share that knowledge because the person who made the process is doing the process and everything works well to now
we're an organization now we have a team now someone who comes in needs to be able to learn about how to do this everything breaks getting the knowledge out of people's heads and into processes
was one of the biggest challenges for us as we grew and it was painful so that for me was the hardest thing hiring you
know we hire 30 30 to 40 people a month my biggest thing is I like to hire um from non-traditional places I think there is a wealth of incredible talent
that exists outside of New York City Silicon Valley I mean that's the foundation of my business obviously but even for our hires that were in the US
um our first outside hire in the US she was the head of children's summer camps at mass aabon and I wanted her to take
sales calls and I was like man if you can deal with like coordinating a bunch of screaming kids at summer camp and then like 20 to 30 angry parents every
week coming and yelling at you you can do this job and it's going to seem like a vacation so now she's my chief of staff so looking not totally at like
have you done this before but is what you've done before going to set you up for success in this job really really important and that's how we approach also hiring our EAS we don't hire people
that have been EAS before we hire people that have had really unique operational backgrounds that are really smart and really intelligent are they going to be able to keep up with a business owner
with a Founder yes then we'll train you to be a great EA and you're going to be successful yeah all right let's talk about what you do outside of business tell me about some of your passions or
what this business has enabled you to do I'm an easy guy to shop for because I have like five categories of things I like I like space like buying anything space related uh love books I like video
games and board games any kind of game which takes up a lot of time uh and I like being in a rural place I lived in New York for 10 years cuz I had to be there I recently moved to New Hampshire
I grew up in Vermont I feel so much more at home and at peace and this is this is like what I wanted when I started this company was I just want the freedom to be in an environment I want to be in and
do the things I want to do so every morning I read with my coffee for an hour I read a non-fiction book biography history whatever it is I like I play
video games every Saturday morning from 6 6:00 a.m.
to 11:00 a.m.
it's 5 hours it's kind of insane and sometimes sometimes I actually play them on week nights but don't tell people that I think there's a stigma around
entrepreneurs doing things that aren't related to their company and I'm like if that's true you have a shitty business if you can't do the things you want to
do if you can't step away and be like man I'm able to read the books I want to read I'm able to like go visit friends I'm able to travel I'm able to do all these things then what are you doing it
for so that's sort of my Mantra is like it's okay that I play video games it's okay that I'm not spending 24/7 thinking about this business because that means I've built a business that can run on 10
hours of my work or whatever and I've got a great team that's taking care of things while I'm traveling so that's the life I set out to accomplish and it's a little bit different than what I thought
it was but I feel kind of like I'm there so tell me what a typical day in the life is what does a Tuesday look like for you building this business well there's no furniture in my house that I just moved into so I usually get up off
my air mattress and I go downstairs uh make some coffee I sit and read I start work around 7:30 I get up at like 5:36 I start work around like 7:30 I usually
have most of my meetings in the morning I'll have lunch you know make my own lunch whatever and and have it at my desk I usually work till 6 or seven so you know like 10 11
hour days but it's punctuated I'll go outside and I'll walk around I'll go get groceries I'll call my parents or I'll call somebody and talk to them and like
breaking up my day in a way that makes sense is um something that is afforded to to me because of the business I have whereas like if I was going into an office I wouldn't be able to do that and
also the people that work for me I'm always like look if you want to go out and like take your kid to go get some toys or something at 2 o00 that's fine go do that come back we'll finish up so maybe I do put in the hours but I do it
in a way that doesn't feel like it and I think that's a real crucial difference last question that would ask all the founders on the starter story channel is if you could sit on Ian's shoulder and give him advice when you were starting
out what would that advice be so many people in our generation get freaked out by like I'm going to make the wrong decision should I take this job should I start my own company should I do this thing and I'm not going to do it because
I'm afraid that it's not the path there's like LinkedIn stocking that happens today where like I see like kids in their like mid 20s going out and they're being like well but this person's we went to college together and
they're working at this company and they have this title and that's farther ahead than me and I'm really freaked out and like what should I do about it and I'm like I went through so many miserable experiences in my life and it ended up
here yeah and if I hadn't made all those mistakes and done all those things this door wouldn't have been open I would have been in a different house different neighborhood and this might not have ever happened so don't approach decision
making in a way that is from fear of choosing the wrong thing just take on New Opportunities because you always are able to maneuver into what you want to
do and even if you're like oh I think I want to do this but I don't eventually the thing you think you want to do is the thing that you're going to want to do and then you'll end up happy that's great advice thank you for
coming on the show man my pleasure you're awesome the businesses you built is awesome follow this advice then you will have a multi-million dollar Sri Lankan Outsourcing business good luck
guys what's up guys I hope you got inspired by Ian's story it was great to have him in my house and I hope you got some good takeaways from him I think what he said Rings true for me and
probably for a lot of you as well that building a business that makes you enough money to give you the lifestyle that you want is really the goal something that allows you to be able to work on what you want live wherever you
want and do whatever you want to do throughout the day but for that to be possible you first need to be working on a good problem and a good solution now if you're still looking for something
like that a good problem to build a business around then head to the link in the description and I'll send you over a list of $99 million problems worth solving right now it has a bunch of cool
stuff around ideas and industries that are worth building in and if you're really serious about building something then please come join thousands of other builders doing it inside starter story
all right guys I'll see you the next one peace