I mean man my life has been so wild when I was 19 years old I was going off a big jump and I landed on my back shattered my spine and was paralyzed
instantly that was literally Rock Bottom this is Ryan Chen a guy who let no obstacle stand in his way I worked in the organic chemistry lab then I worked
at Hulu and then I think I found my true calling in just like being a builder being an entrepreneur so he went all in I cashed out my 401k to get like the first R&D samples to pay for legal fees
to form the company we're basically just living off of like credit card points and then using the company funds for just meals and just that was it after 4
years of grit the business finally worked we were at Skyhigh off Shark Tank the business was growing and I was like somebody's going to try to take this business away from
us some lady sued us we we would have won if we got to court but getting us to court would have bankrupted us this is the story of how Ryan Chen and his best
friend Kent built a $ 100 million Company by overcoming the odds welcome to starter story Ryan grew up
in an immigrant family of entrepreneurs with a natural ambition to become more he started his childhood playing sports at an extremely high level National Kendo team cross
country state champ but when he went to college his Ambitions to become an athlete took a turn when I was 19 I was at a friend's birthday party and I was going off a big jump out in Big Bear
California and I over rotated on the jump and and I landed on my back shattered my spine and was paralyzed instantly and literally my life changed in a split second and I basically spent
6 months in the hospital going through surgeries going back to school part-time and also part-time rehab and that was literally Rock
Bottom in my own head I would I would go through scenarios where I'm going to be a burden I'm going to slow people down is this life worth living I was kind of
you go down this like Spiral right and that was about a year two years of really depression and and figuring out what can I make of this situation so
Ryan was really struggling to accept his new self but luckily he had some true friends by his side it took one of my best friends Marcus to me like hey like
come on this trip with us we're road tripping from LA to Austin we're filming this documentary called No cameras allowed that was the first big trip I did with a group of friends after my accident and I think I was like one I
yes I can travel two I felt like I was closed off before where I only wanted to talk to people who knew me versus like now I'm like this is who I am this is like what I represent and it was like
this fundamental like mindset [ __ ] for me if oh I can do [Music] this the reason why I'm alive and and and well is because of the support
system I've had and I I'm extremely grateful for having two parents that supported me sister all my friends and family that without pushing me they were
just there one of my best friends said that hey man you're still the same guy but now you're just in the chair chilling and I think that perspective also was like oh I'm still the same person I just get from point A to point
B in a wheelchair and sometimes I'm faster because wheels are pretty fast one of Ryan's biggest supporters was his college best friend and eventual
business partner Kent I met him my first day uh freshman year in college so it was like one of those things that you you meet somebody and you click we bonded over video games and Super Smash
and uh we just stayed friends we would go out to eat we'd go out to party we'd uh Bond over Fitness he was training like I think 6 hours a day at the time with both of them having a passion for
Fitness the boys were constantly looking for ways to increase their performance during training I was training for the par Olympic team at the time Kent was training with the Olympic jeto team out in Japan and we were both very focused
on Fitness at this point we were taking pills during training for Not Just Energy but for Focus especially and the pills were made in Kent's dorm room
mixing powders racatan parasan for things like lucid dreaming different types of creatine and we've changed the formula so many times right like we hope that could be like the recipe that's
like that secret formula recipe that people want not thinking much about it Kent and Ryan were experimenting with different pill formulas and getting different results
then one day Ryan got an email that would end up sparking an idea I got this group on email for you know 50% off on scuba diving and I knew that Kent would be down and we were both in between
graduation starting our first jobs and I was like hey do you want to get scuba certified and of course he said yes and so we're on this boat we meet all these really cool people getting scuba certified with us we didn't have the
energy pills but even if we did I think sharing it with people you had just met would be like oh no I'm okay that was the aha moment of like what if we can make supplementation more accessible and
approachable by putting these great ingredients instead of pill form into gum and mints and and that was that was our idea the seed was planted but Ryan and Kent couldn't Risk Everything to
follow this dream so they had to go get real jobs so I started off as a financial analyst for Hulu Kent worked as a music producer for Sony Music we both just had this idea in the back of
our heads like we want to launch neurog gun this is such a great idea but one we didn't have the funding to do and two no one taught us about how to start a company or how to build a business so we were both kind of just saving up some
money and then putting that into the business of like starting some type of fund and I cashed out my 401k which I highly don't recommend people doing but that was the risk that we were willing to take it was just like a year of like
R&D trying to find a manufacturer that would even pick up our calls and take us seriously Ryan and Kent knew they had to follow their dream so they went all in spending all their savings on the
initial research and development and a couple of samples and finally they got the product back we had all these different formulas and and I would sample them around to like all of my
co-workers at Hulu so like my managers other people in the finance team my manager was like yo mother eer he was like I was up till 3:00 a.m.
I couldn't sleep and I was like that's me I was like so the product works he was like yeah product works but I couldn't sleep cuz there was like you know he was just like so wired and and so I knew that we had something Ryan and
Kent finally had something great but literally zerar to make another batch and Market it to customers with their backs against the wall the boys had one
last desperate shot to make their dream come true crowdfunding we officially launched on Indiegogo Kent Luckley was a big redditor so he got the Reddit new
ICS group to support and I think we hit like our goal like of 30k in like 3 or 4 days Time Magazine wrote an article saying like half native gum is now a
thing and then we got invited to Dr Oz and all of a sudden we had a lot of people moms who watch Dr Oz buying the gum and it worked Ryan is proof that
with a good idea and some attention you can start moving products and make money but that can only happen if you have a website to sell your products on and the fastest way to do that is by using
hostinger the sponsor of today's video entrepreneurship is about speed if you're wasting tons of time messing with button design logos or worrying about
the layout of your website then check this out the hosting or business plan comes with a suite of AI tools and e-commerce features that will allow you to go from 0 to one with a website in
minutes let's say you want to build a website for your e-com brand you can select the AI website builder add the name of your brand and describe exactly what you want to do and voila now you
have a professional brand website in minutes and if you want to tailor it more to your liking it's as simple as a drag and drop and don't forget to use the AI heat map as an Ecom brand
conversions are everything and the AI heat map will tell you how to improve your customer experience and help you increase those conversions if you want to stop wasting tons of time and launch
your brand website quickly head to hostinger.com starter story and use the code starter story for 10% off they're running a huge sale right now and you'll
want to take advantage of it while you can now back to Ryan's story after seeing some initial success in raising $30,000 from strangers on the internet
Ryan and Kent knew it was time to truly get their hands dirty when we first launched we were working at Hulu and Sony Music respectively for Kent for like a year and a half the first 4,000
lb of gum was sitting in Kent's apartment we didn't have a warehouse like Kent's apartment in downtown La was the warehouse and we'd ship 4,000 lb of gum going to USPS every day in those moments we're like okay things are
working it's like a slow grind and the first year I think we did like a little over 100k and then year two was like 750k and then we're like oh wait this is like this can be a real thing 2 years
into the business the boys realize that nuro has outgrown Kent's apartment and they have a tough choice before them keep it as a side hustle or go all in I
think Kent and I both trusted each other we knew that this product helped a lot of people and we had so much user feedback and we would see the number of repeat buyers and the percentage of repeat buyers as a percent of Revenue so
we knew that we had some type of base and some type of adoption rate right so when we first left our jobs it felt very real when we no longer had a stable paycheck right we had to like survive
off of like what we were making and like eat what you kill kind of per se year three year four I don't think we took any salary I I think we're
basically just living off of like credit card points and then using the company funds for just meals and just that was it I was playing semi-professional poker
to kind of make rent we had so many inventory challenges couldn't get the products in time we were sold out we weren't uncertain about freight cost raw ingredients we've had products that get
stuck on the border that's like three four five six weeks out of border and then you're just losing money there's so many things that you go through in the business that are are not Glitz and glamour it's it's like a grind and and
you're kind of in the trenches and at the end of the day it's like who do you want to go go into battle with and like I want to go into battle with my best friend because I trust him Ryan and Kent are struggling to get nuro to the point
of a stable scalable business not just a startup they're desperately looking for a way to crack the code and then something crazy happens 2019 a group of
investors were just like hey guys like you guys have such a great story you should tell this story at think Shark Tank would be a great way for you guys to tell the story they convinced us I didn't want to do it to be completely honest Kent was like we should do it
like they're right it's great for marketing but it's really great to get an investment we got two offers that were like below what we were asking for and Kent and I just had this floor we're like we're just not going to go below
this and we stuck to our guns the boys walked away from the sharks with no money in their pockets but little did they know the exposure and connections
they just got would change their lives forever it's been like a step change right it's not just like linear or just hockey stick it's like you grow and then it's this and then there's another big
milestone that you hit I think we had a big step change with Shark Tank the business was growing and I was like somebody's going to try to take this business away from us some lady
sued us for um a trademark we we would have won if we got to court but getting us to court would have bankrupted us and I reached out to investors friends and no one really was
that helpful four years in thousands of hours of work poured into this business it was on the verge of bankruptcy but
then Ryan remembered a guy named Daniel lubetsky one of the sharks from Shark Tank Hail Mary I DM Daniel leeski on Instagram and I said hey Daniel I don't
know if you remember me but me and Kent were on Shark Tank you were our guest judge we loved you you mentioned that if I ever needed some advice I can reach out to you I really need your help on
something and he messaged me back and I told him about this trademark lawsuit about this lady who is suing us he hopped on a phone call with us right away for 18 months consulted us defended us he was talking to his lawyers our
lawyers their lawyers her he was like Hey listen like at the end of the day if you if this goes to court you know Ryan and Kent are going to win based on Merit and it's going to cost you a lot of
money and it's going to cost me a lot of money because I'm going to back all their legal fees and Ken's like like you know she's worth like $300 million and Daniel OBET is like I'm worth 3
billion turns out not making a deal on Shark Tank didn't matter they made a friend that would save their business and with all the legal stuff cleared
nuro went on a well-deserved growth hot streak you know we've been really fortunate with Organic earned media so like I said Shark Tank was huge for us we've had a lot of major celebrities
kind of talk about our product organically Ashley Graham a lot of professional baseball players Steve Aoki is actually a huge neuro user Joe Rogan big fan of neuro he talks about it
organically none of that's paid Andrew Schultz a lot of people just have been picking up nuro and just kind of talking about it so I think we're a top 10 Tik Tock shop brand we're continuing to go
viral on different videos that people are repurposing from Joe Rogan mentioning us or Shark Tank or different videos that our teams are doing but it's just all kind of compounds and adds so
I think like I said it's like years 1 through 5 is like the hardest part to get to that kind of inflection point it was until like year 7even where we're really taking like a very good salary and and and things started to click we
are now doing almost $10 million a month one of the the things that we're really proud of is like we had employee satisfaction survey and I think we had like 96% satisfaction rate that's like my most proud stat this year despite the
revenue like has been amazing it's just like to see the team engaged and to see the the organizations that we can help impact and donate to like good to good causes like it's been awesome
I mean man my life has been so wild you know it's like obviously like no one expects to go through an accident I've gone through but then to be able to pick yourself up from Rock Bottom
through the support of others it's surreal you know it's it's really wild and I asked my dad one time I was like Hey like how do you define success and and this was years after my injury my
dad said that success is defined by how high you bounce back from Rock Bottom and that that really stuck with me cuz he was like you know you you hit rock bottom and you [ __ ] bounce back
higher than anybody could have imagined and so yeah I feel like I'm happier now than I was as an angsty teenager when I was like 18 19 and I think there's
whenever there's like a door that closes I think there's like two more that open and I think it's just like about you just going through that door Ryan is proof that entrepreneurship is for everyone doesn't matter current
situation or your current skills or your current income the truth is nothing will ever be perfect so you just have to start if you don't start then all the
dreams you have in your head will have a 0% chance of coming to life I hope you guys are all inspired after watching Ryan's story and I hope it's enough for
you to just take that one step of action today and if you're ready to take that first step today then you should definitely download our free deep dive of 50 AI business ideas that you can
start right now I put a link at the bottom of the description so just head over there if you want me to send those over to you all right I'll see you in the next one peace
[Music]