I've just built an AI Resume Builder is a side project that is currently doing and its second month about $20,000 a month how does this guy make $20,000 a
month from a simple website well it's because of two letters AI right now you can get open AI credits dirt cheap and I don't think it'll be like that forever
but there are plenty of AI apps out there that don't make any money so I had to give Colin a call to see actually how he grew this thing to 20,000 a month so
quickly and turns out there is just one very specific thing that gave him this advantage in this video Colin breaks down his unique AI business blueprint
including how to find and validate an idea using AI the launch strategy that made him $1,000 in his first week and the hiring strategy he uses to scale
this side project on autopilot this is not my full-time job I have built this to scale without me now let's dive
I'm Pat walls and this is starter
story welcome back to starter story Colin tell us about who you are and what you built yeah so I'm Colin Macintosh I am founder and CEO of a company that some people probably have heard of
because I've done a starter story before with it called sheets and Giggles but funny enough I'm actually here to talk about sheets res.com which is an AI Resume Builder
that I created with a friend it's $99 for Lifetime access $29 for one week access in our second month of business
we did $220,000 of sales that's nearly 100% margin as well so it has been extremely rewarding for me already as a
side project and I am really thrilled to be helping as many people out as I am wow so you built this AI tool to $20,000 a month in Just 2 months as a side
project that's very impressive man tell us now why building an AI business right now is such a massive opportunity so the cool thing about AI is I don't have to
code to teach the AI nor do my developers a resume review probably would take me three hours I would say to
do but now I can do 20 30 100 1,000 resume reviews a day with this AI that I built for a fraction of the price and infinitely more people will be able to
use my service and my advice than were so the one thing I wish I could do differently about sheets and Giggles is not start the company in 2017 and start it in 2024 it has never been easier for
someone to start a business but I would recommend that people like move very quickly because right now you can get open AI credits dirt cheap and I don't think it'll be like that forever they're
just doing user acquisition right now on their end clearly right now is the best time to be building an AI and like Colin said this opportunity won't last forever if you're anything like Colin and you
want to take advantage of this opportunity and start making money with AI right now then head to the first link in the description to get this free list of 200 plus AI money-making ideas this
is the easiest way to find an idea for an AI business especially if you don't know where to start or what you should build it includes a bunch of unexplored ideas the niches they serve and even how
you can get started on those ideas right away I personally found that how to get started section really helpful because it gives you something that you can act on right now just head to the first link in the description to download it for
free this list was made by HubSpot which is today's video sponsor a big shout out to them for this free resource HubSpot is awesome that's crazy I mean all this
AI stuff is just nuts but what I want to know is a little bit more about how you got into resumés and Entrepreneurship can you tell me a little bit more about your backstory yeah yeah sure so I
started my career at the world's largest hedge fund a place called Bridgewater Associates in Connecticut I got fired in 5 months ended up getting hired as a recruiter at the company that hired me
at Bridgewater and I adored recruiting and I just had such a strong affinity and natural talent for it and around February 2018 I was just on Reddit
somebody had posted the resume and I gave them a bunch of feedback and I was like he this is wrong this is wrong you're not going to get a call back with this like you got to change this up and I got like 500 up votes and then I got a
bunch of people replying to me being like you know hey can you can you look at my resume like can you please check this out that was kind of one of my first moments where I was like man no one knows how to make a good resume okay
so you find out that the common knowledge that you have about résumés isn't really common but what happens after that I just sat down and I wrote out a whole long resume guide of dos and
don'ts and that post on Reddit blew up so much that it is now the first result on Google for resumé advice Reddit it was the top post on the job subreddit
for for like years and over the last 6 years since 2018 I've given away so much of my time and energy answering questions on this Reddit post that
continue to flow in I'm talking probably 20,000 questions that I've gotten over the last 6 years from people but then last year I asked my friend Nate my old recruiting partner who hired me at my
first job do you have time to do resume reviews for people because it's just like the Matrix for us like we can just see a resume and know what's wrong with it so we started doing resumé reviews for like a couple hundred bucks the
demand was out of control I didn't have time for all the people that we could could help raised our price to 300 then 400 bucks and eventually get to the point where I was not comfortable raising the price anymore because there
are so many people that are going through this time in their life and they don't have the cash that one day earlier this year Nate said hey why don't we build like an AI version of this you know he's currently a software engineer
at Eventbrite took about 4 months for him to build it I I just gave him kind of my ux notes and what I think it should look looked like I trained the AI on like my rules for a resume and we
launched it August 26th of this year and within one week we had gotten our first $1,000 day that's awesome so basically
you just took the skill that you already had and you turn it into a $250,000 per year business with the help of AI let's now talk about how our viewers on starter story could do
something similar how can anyone get started with an idea for such a business so I do think that the question that people should be asking themselves is like what do I do better than anyone
else in the world and then just help people like put good things into the world that are helpful for free for the
purpose of being helpful prove out that you're solving a person's problem and especially if you can prove out you're solving a lot of people's problems then eventually you can monetize solving that problem if you help people in something
that you're good at you're going to build that incredibly strong trustworthy reputation that you're going to carry for the rest of your life gotcha so get good at something start helping people
with that thing and eventually they'll be willing to pay you for it once we've done that though how do we go from zero to one in terms of actually building a product how do you get going from zero
to one well first validate the idea by doing it for people in a way that either isn't for sale or doesn't scale and then you can build a brand identity map to understand what the brand will look like
how it will talk to people how it will engage with people what the value propositions are the demographics that you're going after that's the document that I recommend everybody do first is a brand identity map and Tech Stars
actually has a wonderful one for free then I would probably build out a business plan so like a little two-pager about what you want to do why it's different the products already on the market maybe five or six or seven points
of differentiation and really flush out the business idea on a two-page piece of paper then people should not use AI for any of this any of it should not that all right so once we have a clear understanding of how the business is
going to look like how do we actually build it since you're not a technical person yourself how did you manage to get a software engineer as a co-founder on board you're not going to ever
convince some random software engineer to work on something with you that is like your idea without paying them a lot of money nor should they I'm 34 years old I've been working like a dog since I
was 22 by the time that it came time to build this whether it was working with Nate one:1 for for years and staying in touch over the last decade where we haven't worked together for it was all
the redditors I've helped out one to one and in fact Nate and I found a third parter in the business from Reddit I split this three ways with these two other guys I just give them the features and the notes and the things that I want
to build and my vision and I cannot tell you how freeing it has been for me in my time I probably spend 5 hours 10 hours a week maximum on this project so that that would be my best advice is like
work your ass off be kind to people be the business partner that you would want to work with and then eventually you're going to find someone who wants to build something really really special with you
if you're not a technical founder that's that's really good advice after you guys built Sheet's resume how did you launch it and make that $1,000 in its first week so initially we launched it for
free we just wanted to see if people would use it I edited into my my post I said hey there's this new Builder we built and and I'm really proud of it and
we were blown the away by the usage statistics I think we built in the first like week I don't even know how many
thousands of resumés for people for totally for free and it was like this huge boost of Word of Mouth where people were just like immediately this is amazing I got to tell everybody about
this we turned on pricing I think a week a week in 99 for Lifetime access seems to be the sweet spot for people and then we have a $29 onewe option for people
that are just like hey I just need this as I'm starting my job search but we also don't want to do monthly subscriptions because I do find that predatory and we want to make sure that we're not taking advantage of anyone during a you know a hard time in their
life awesome so you launched sheets resume got a bunch of free users and some paid ones after you turned on the pricing but how did you end up making $20,000 in the second month of running
the business what user acquisition channels worked best for you so the beautiful thing about this is that it's not about the money it's about like helping people on this journey and if
you get helped on your way by somebody and that really personal onetoone way whether you got a refund or you got it for free from me or you just really loved it when you bought it and you're like this is amazing that word of mouth
is huge it's it's so invaluable So to that end I've said okay what other things can I do to get word out about
this Resume Builder that are going to scale with without my time first and foremost we just hired an affiliate marketing agency I did set up some
rudimentary Google ads like a training mechanism for Google's algorithm and then the organic traffic I've got multiple posts on Reddit how to build a resume the top 10 questions I get during
a job hunt how to interview how to negotiate salary that's like a big SEO hack is like just piggyback off of reddit's incredible SEO and you can link
to your products or to your company somewhere in there but it should not be the front and center call to action because then people will be suspicious of your intentions then they may not you
know react as strongly as they should to like what is valuable content so you have to want to help people and they have to believe it I love this approach now let's get a little bit more technical what's the tech stack you've
been using to build this business so the stack that we're using is open AI Gemini it's a PHP app built with the Laurel framework rest API and that sort of
thing so AWS it's not it's not overly complex and then we just use Gmail stripe for payment processing Mercury bank for Banking and I mean yeah it's
not an overly involved company this is like my mission to give back and help people it is so damn fulfilling dude gets me out of bed in the morning nice awesome are there any other tools that
you'd recommend for Founders there are more tools available for solopreneurs and entrepreneurs than there ever have been get an AI chat bot for your website that reduces customer care tickets and
increases conversion plug into AI customer care services do AI image and video content generation do long form videos like this and then feed them to an AI and chop them up into 10 or 20
second interesting blocks but go do it now because these tools are the lowest they're ever going to be and so I hope more people see this and they're like I'm going to go start my own AI
business or my own my own thing that I can scale I I love it man if you're comfortable sharing it what are the profit margins for Sheets res.com dude it's close to 100% margin
product I'd say we're probably operating around 90% net margins when it comes to the sale it just enables so much more ability to to help people for free so
cool man now last question we ask all founders we interview what would be your advice to any entrepreneur just starting out right now start a business that's my advice if you feel like you're at a
point in your life where you have an expertise you understand a problem you think you can build a solution you feel disillusioned with working at a large company or another company and you're
and you're tired of taking orders I cannot tell you the value and the learning that you're going to get out of starting your own company versus staying the course if your worst case scenario
is that you're just going to keep doing what you're doing philosophically I would just tell you like get started do it it's not as scary as you think and your worst cas scenario is the one that you're already living in which is a
pretty awesome thing to say start the business as Colin said the worst case scenario is that nothing happens and you're still in the same spot as before you don't need thousands of dollars or
an entire Dev team you just need an idea in action I appreciate all of you for watching these videos and hopefully they continue to inspire you but watching is
not as valuable as doing action is the thing that's going to get you to the position that you actually want to be in a position of freedom freedom to work on the things you enjoy and make a living
while doing it but if you're still struggling to take action or you don't know where to start then I highly recommend that you check out the starter story Academy it's the community I wish I had when I first started and it's got
a road map to help you find an idea build it get those first users and make those first few dollars just head to the first link in the description if you want to learn more about it much love
and I'll see you guys in the next one peace [Music]