This is by far the best channel to get users on your products.
>> Meet Roman, [music] a guy who launched his SAS just six months ago and already surpassed $30,000 MR.
>> We've generated over 11 million views in just a few months.
>> His strategy, Reddit.
>> This post alone got us thousands of visitors to our website.
>> But Roman wasn't just posting randomly.
[music] He had a very calculated approach to finding content ideas, creating them, and then getting them on the front page.
I asked Roman to come on to the channel to break down his entire Reddit system, the one that took his SAS from zero to now $30,000 [music] MR,
and he broke down everything, including how to warm up your accounts properly, how to make sure your posts always get seen,
and why Reddit is still the untapped channel to grow your SAS in the early days.
All right, this one is one you cannot miss.
I'm Pat Walls and this is Starter Story.
All right, before we jump in, Roman is about to share his entire system for how to get seen and how to get users on Reddit.
What he's done is not new.
We've covered a bunch of Reddit growth stories here on this channel.
So, I decided to put together a playbook that you can download right now on how you can get your first 100 users on Reddit.
It is the combination of many different strategies from actual founders that I've talked to onto this channel.
I put it all in one place and you can download it right now.
I will put the link in the description.
But without further ado, let's get into the interview.
All right, Roman, welcome to the channel.
It is amazing to have you on.
Tell me about who you are, what you built, and what's your story.
Hello everyone.
My name is Roman.
I'm the co-founder of Goji Berry AI.
We are an intentbased outreach tool.
We do about 30k [music] MR.
four months ago, we were doing zero in revenue and Reddit is an important part in [music] our success.
So, I'm really excited to talk to you about that.
>> Okay, I'm really excited to talk about this, especially Reddit because Reddit is one of my favorite channels,
especially for early founders.
This is going to be a fun one.
But first, before we get into that, I want to understand what is the business that you built?
What's the business model?
And then I want to walk through some of your dashboards and show off how much this business is making.
>> Uh, yeah.
So, we are a SAS business.
We have three types of subscription.
Most of our users are on the $99 plan.
So you get an unlimited amount of high intent lead and [music] you can connect them directly through our platform.
So our users get better results than using [music] regular outreach tools.
One of our main ways to get users or at least at the beginning was Reddit.
So we [music] got 11 millions impressions on Reddit which is insane.
If we would have paid for that, that would have cost us [music] hundreds of thousands of dollars.
And so that way we got our uh let's say 100 first customers and we are still getting customers today.
[music] So here you can see that's 24K MR.
So that's around $30K [music] and the growth is pretty good.
So we are really happy with how it's going.
11 million impressions on Reddit is insane.
We're going to dive all into exactly how you got that, what kind of posts you did and everything.
But before we do, I want to understand your background.
How do you get into building apps and building SAS?
How do you get to this point?
>> So, originally I was a mechanical engineer and a bit before COVID, I was wondering if I wanted to stay an employee.
So, I learned how to do affiliate marketing.
I got my first success.
So, I made a bit of money.
I got into freelancing.
So, in 2023, I launched my first SAS called Coco AI.
We scaled [music] it to 50K MR with Outreach and then we sold it to a US venture.
Then when we sold this business, we looked at what made this business great and actually it was the acquisition.
So the acquisition method we had in marketing was outreach and so that's what made us build good AI.
>> Okay, cool.
Well, thank you for sharing that.
Before we get into the nitty-gritty details, can you just give me a highlevel overview of how Reddit impacted your business and how it helped it grow?
>> So I think we cracked [music] the Reddit distribution.
We got more than 11 million impressions and more than 40,000 visitors on our website,
which [music] is insane.
But that's only the visible part because every time we have a demo call or we [music] talk to other leads on other platforms,
almost all of them have seen [music] us on Reddit and so they say, "Oh, you are the Reddit guy."
And so that helps us a lot because the more your leads see you, the more you are likely to close them during a call.
Let's dive into an example.
I want you to show me one or two actual Reddit posts and walk me through these and why they worked and how others could do something similar.
>> Sure.
This post [music] is called I paid five inferences on LinkedIn to promote my SAS.
Here's what $1,250 got me.
And it got 160K [music] views, 543 up votes.
In terms of visitors, it [music] got us something like 2,000 visitors.
And out of 2,000 visitors, we probably got something like [music] 10 or 15 clients out of these posts.
Also, something that's really important when you do a post like this, you have [music] to tell a story and you have to show proof.
So here, for example, I've [music] included the influencer post and all the proof that are available.
For the people that are listening [music] here and are thinking, okay, but I haven't launched or I don't have any success to share.
Then you can also explain what [music] you are doing.
For example, I got rejected from the Y Cominator interview.
So, we got selected from the interview, but we failed the interview.
Well, I said, "Okay, why not make it a post?"
And we got more than [music] 179,000 views.
We got maybe 15 clients out of this.
So, you can turn any event happening [music] in your life into a Reddit post.
What Roman is doing here is just amazing.
He's generating millions of views on his app just from Reddit.
This is an incredible marketing system I haven't really seen anyone do before.
And if you love crazy growth strategies and stories like these, then you definitely need to check out The Hustle,
which is today's sponsor.
The Hustle is a free email that covers awesome business case studies and stories just like the one you're watching right now.
I'm talking wild stuff like how a guy made millions renting out backyard pools or why gas station pizza is secretly dominating fast food.
I've been reading The Hustle for years.
It's an email I read every time it lands into my inbox.
It's quick, easy to read, and it always gives me a story to share with my friends.
So, if you just love discovering new business ideas before everyone else, then definitely check out The Hustle.
Just hit the link in the description, subscribe to The Hustle, and you'll get daily stories to keep you in the loop on what's working in business,
tech, and startups.
Thank you to The Hustle for sponsoring this video.
Let's get back to the story.
All right, Roman, I want to dive into this Reddit post you have right here, this Y Combinator post.
What do you think would be like the top three reasons why this post went viral that people watching this can learn from and try to do with their own Reddit posts?
>> Sure.
So, first thing would be using AI.
So, how I write my post is really simple.
First, I'm not [music] English native.
So, what I do is I tell my story to Chad GPT by [music] voice and then I ask Ted GPT to translate and correct my post.
[music] So that's something that works really well because you can dive way deeper into details [music] than if you have to write everything.
Second thing why it worked is the initial start.
So you [music] need to get as many up votes as you can in the first 5 to 10 minutes.
[music] So what I do to make it work is I have a group of friends where we share each other's Reddit posts and every time someone share the post we all go like up
vote and comment.
And then third thing that's really important is never putting your SAS directly in the post.
You can trigger curiosity by highlighting it.
And as [music] I said before, putting some proof and the people reading this post know that it's real and that we are not telling [music] a fake story.
Okay.
So what would be your playbook for starting over right now in 2026 in getting Reddit off the ground as a marketing channel in a way to get your first 10,
100,000 users?
>> So first you need a fresh account.
You need one account per brother.
So for example, I have one account on Chrome, one account on Modilla, one account on Safari,
and that's more than enough to keep it safe.
And when you create an account, do not create it with a new email.
So if you do the combo, new email plus new Reddit account, you will get banned right away.
Step two, once your account is created, you have to add a profile picture, you link your SAS in the bio,
and you activate the secret feature that hides your feed.
So when you do Reddit marketing and heavily post on Reddit, some people are going to go to your profile and see that you are always talking about the same SAS and [music] they will say he's advertising way too much.
So that's a really useful feature.
Step three, for the first 7 to 14 days, don't even think of doing marketing.
You will just post comments.
You will upvote.
This will warm up your account and gets [music] you the first karma.
The more karma you have, the stronger your account is.
Step four.
Once you've done that, after 7 to 14 days, you can start posting.
And step [music] five, once you reach that stage, you can start doing marketing.
So, there are still some things to know.
Some [music] subreddits don't allow promotion.
Like the way you combinate a subreddit, it's [music] almost impossible to post anything and so it's not worth posting there.
Step six, with every post, you change the angle.
Either you can redirect to a YouTube video, to a Twitter post.
So you can really [music] get creative and that's really the magic of Reddit.
Step seven, after that you need at least 10 up votes in the first 10 minutes.
[music] What we've done internally is we have a group of 15 marketers where everyone share their Reddit post.
Everyone upvotes the other post and [music] then external people are going to like is going to rank higher and higher and higher.
Step eight, you reply to every comment, absolutely every one of them.
This is going to give you traction.
This is going to show engagement and the more engagement you have on the [music] post,
the more up vote you get and the higher you are going to rank.
>> Okay.
What I'm curious about is how do you come up with these ideas for different content,
different stories?
Are you using AI to come up with these ideas?
Are you looking at top posts?
How do you find this?
>> Yeah.
So, the main source of inspiration is what I do in my daily life as a SAS marketer.
[music] The more things I do, the more stories I can share.
Same for white communator.
We get rejected.
We do a post.
And even if you don't have experience, even if you are starting your business and you want your 100 customers,
you can still create stories about how your SAS is going, what problem you are trying to solve,
everyone can get views and get [music] traffic on Reddit.
>> All right.
Well, one thing that I hear a lot from people is, I posted on Reddit, I got negative feedback,
my entire account got banned.
How have you handled this and how has your experience been with that?
>> The only way to deal with that, actually, there are few ways, but first one is show proof.
So no one [music] can argue with what you are saying.
You make 25k MR, you show that you make it.
So that's [music] really easy and then you block all the people insulting you or being really negative,
[music] but it can be really frightening at the beginning because when you post you get 15 bad comments saying that you will never make it,
what you are doing is wrong.
And so you [music] really have to stick with it and believe in what you are doing.
>> That is great advice.
You may not be aware, but I grew starter story on Reddit.
That's how we got our first thousand users monetized the business.
People were so mad that we were sharing these business stories on Starter Story that they created a petition to ban us from Reddit and it got all these up votes and all this stuff.
[music] At the time, it felt really scary and like everything was going to fall apart.
Now, when I look back on that time, it didn't matter at all.
So, for anyone watching this who is worried about what people are going to say about them on Reddit,
none of it matters.
Just like Roman said, block these people, continue building your app, sharing your story and everything will work out and it'll be worth it.
But anyways, Roman, we didn't really talk a whole lot about your app and what it does.
Could you give us a quick demo of what you built and how it works?
>> Yeah, sure.
So, we built Gojibberry to find high intent leads on LinkedIn.
So, an intent can be many things.
[music] can be someone liking specific post, interacting with competitors, someone who has just fund raise,
hired and so every day our software is going to find the best leads with their signals.
So for example, just engage with a competitor and every day we get the warmest lead on the market and then we can launch campaigns directly from our software like this.
[music] And so this will automate the LinkedIn outreach.
So connect with these people, send AI personalized messages and the results we get in terms of acceptance rate and reply rate are way above industry just because the leads are great and the
messaging is really tailored to every lead.
>> Thanks for showing that.
Looks like a super cool app.
I'm curious how you built it and how you run this app.
What tools are you using every day to build and grow this app?
>> So I'm the marketing guy, so I'm going to talk most about marketing tools.
So we use [music] Instantly AI, a great tool to do cold email.
So that cost about $800 per [music] month to run it because we do very high volume.
We use Outr Rank for SEO.
[music] This cost about $99 per month.
And we of course use Goji Berry AI to do LinkedIn outreach and high intent lead outreach.
That's [music] about $99 per month as well.
We use Canonly to book calls, so that's about $20.
We use Framer for our website to build landing pages.
So that's about >> [music] >> $49 per month.
We use Cad GPT plus Nano Banana to create every post, every graphic design as well.
So that's [music] maybe about $40 per month.
And then we use also Sales Navigator on some of our accounts for $100 per month.
>> All right, cool.
Well, thanks for sharing that.
Last question that we have that we ask everyone who comes on to Starter Story, what would be your advice to young Roman or anybody who's watching this today that wants to build SAS?
>> So that's going to be really simple.
It's advertised the way you would love to be advertised to.
For example, I love watching entrepreneurs stories like starter story.
[music] So when I hear successful stories how they made it, that's something that triggers me and I want to learn more.
So this is the way I advertise as well.
>> Cool.
Well, thanks for coming on, Roman, sharing how you built this business in 5 months.
It's insane.
It's a great story.
I love Reddit.
So thanks for coming on and sharing everything.
I think people are going to love this one.
>> Thank you so much.
Well, Gus, producer of Starter Story, what do you think about that one?
>> That was pretty awesome.
I mean, if you try to figure out like how do I do anything on Reddit, I feel like it doesn't get any more practical than that.
You know, you talk about this sometimes, how you started Starter Story, like with Reddit,
and obviously it's evolved and changed, but that that is still like a platform that essentially works the same way.
He was [music] just talking about how he posted stories and his experience and you know subtly linked his product and it's kind of kind of crazy that that still works.
>> Yeah, I think Reddit is not a platform to get scale.
It's not a platform to hit 10,000 MR 20,000 MR but Reddit is amazing and why it's especially valuable for anybody watching this right now.
If your product is not good enough, go post on Reddit.
If you're worried that your product is not good enough, go post on Reddit right now and you'll get product feedback from real people.
get your first 10 customers, your first 100 customers, probably not your first thousand customers,
but that's what Reddit is for.
Go post on Reddit right now.
Re-watch this video, watch that playbook, and do it over the next month.
>> Totally.
Not that it's easier to post on places like Twitter or Instagram.
But with Reddit, you kind of there's like a vibe on there, right, where you're just like,
"Don't BS me kind of vibe on Reddit," which is probably what someone who's just starting out like really needs,
right?
I think about myself like it would scare me to post on there, but it probably is exactly what I need,
the exact feedback I need to know whether what I'm doing is good or not.
>> Yep.
Rip off the band-aid.
Just go post on there right now.
Post anything.
See what happens.
I remember when I first posted on Reddit, it didn't go viral.
It didn't even make the front page.
It was like maybe the fifth or the sixth or the seventh post where I got 400 upvotes.
That's when I realized I had something with Starter Story, that one piece of content.
So, rip the band-aid off.
Worst thing that can happen is it doesn't get any up votes and no one will ever see it.
So, if you enjoyed this video and you're ready to build something, you're ready to launch something,
you should definitely check out Starter Story Build.
It is our platform where you will find an idea, you'll build that idea, and you will ship that idea to real customers.
even something enough to maybe plug it into chat GBT and come up with your first Reddit post and put the link to your app right there and get your first users.
You can start right now by going to the link in the description and starting to build your app right now.
All right, guys.
Thank you for watching.
We'll see you in the next one.
Peace.