- Hi, guys, it's Mark.
So did you know, if you
saved $200 per month,
at an eight percent annual
return, and in 45 years,
you would have over, wait for it.
(ominous music)
- One million dollars.
- To be honest,
when someone first
explained this was possible
by investing in index funds,
I hardly understood a
word they were saying.
It was like they were
speaking a different language.
Today, I thought it was about
time that I made the video
that I wish I'd seen when I was younger,
and explain everything, step by step.
And because I like people
that actually practice what they preach,
I'm gonna be investing
$10,000 of my own money,
during this video, so you can
see exactly how it's done.
Just a quick disclaimer though,
I'm not a financial advisor,
I'm a businessman,
and this is just some of
the real life strategies
that have worked for me.
Personally, I always
thought of index funds
as my backup plan.
If my businesses hadn't been successful,
then I would have become
a millionaire anyway,
through these investments.
Just remember if you like the video,
then smash the Like button,
as it really helps push this
video out to more people,
and also consider subscribing,
if you wanna grow your wealth.
Part one, uncovering the lies.
So let's cut to the chase,
you've been put at major disadvantage.
People have been telling
you lies about investing,
all of your life.
For instance, at school,
when I was growing up,
I remember asking my
teachers about investing,
and they always said,
it's just for rich people,
as they can afford to hire
professionals to do it for them.
For the longest time, I believed
investing wasn't for me,
because I wasn't a pro, and
I didn't have much money,
and I thought I wouldn't stand a chance.
Then we've got friends.
One of mine said I'd have to look
at all the financial newspapers,
learn how to read the
charts, and according to him,
it just wasn't worth my time.
And on top of this, every
time I mentioned investment
to my family, they seemed so scared
because they thought it's the
most risky thing in the world,
and not for normal people.
My dad even said, if I started investing,
I'd lose all my money.
Can you believe that?
These lies are exactly what the
experts want you to believe,
as they know that index fund investing
is extremely easy to do.
You don't need much money to
start, the risk are pretty low,
and on average, it will
make you more money
in the long-term.
The dark truth is that the
average actively managed fund
returns two percent less a year,
than the market in general.
This means that professionals
on average are doing worse
than index funds, and even if
they end up losing your money,
they still charge you
fees, no matter what.
Now, according to my
favorite film, "The Matrix,"
you have now taken the red
pill and you've woken up
to the truth.
It's now time to move on to part two,
understanding the game.
I know when I first started investing,
I felt like I was gonna
make so many mistakes,
but once you understand that language,
it all becomes so much easier,
and that's what we're gonna
be talking about in this part.
So I've been banging on about index funds
in many of my videos,
so I think it's about time
I explained what they are,
and why they're so cool.
I'm a big football fan,
and if you've ever followed any sports,
you'll be familiar with
a league table like this.
The better your team performs,
the higher up they'll be on the list.
But on the other hand,
if they do really badly,
they might be removed
from the league entirely.
This is almost exactly
the same as an index.
All you have to do is switch
out the teams for companies.
Let's take the S&P 500, for example.
This is a list of the 500 best
performing public companies
in the U.S.A. the big dogs
being Amazon, Google, Apple,
and more recently, Tesla.
And just like a league table,
if a company doesn't perform well,
they're at risk of being
removed from the list.
- Hasta la vista, baby.
- The idea of an index fund
is to be a little bit sneaky,
as it allows you to invest
in every single company on the list,
with just one click.
(clicking)
It's a bit like a friend of mine
who picks a different
football team each year.
He just wants to pick
the winner every time.
So investing in index funds means
that even if a few companies do terribly,
then it's balanced out by the companies
that are doing extremely well.
The average return on the S&P
500 over the last 10 years,
has been 13.6%.
Now, that is higher than
usual, but get this,
no one has ever lost any money,
if they've bought and
held an S&P 500 index fund
for more than 20 years.
So if this is so foolproof,
then why do people still
buy individual stocks?
Well, personally, I like to
do this just for a bit of fun.
I also think that some
companies are currently working
on awesome technology for the future,
but aren't making a lot
of money at the moment,
so they won't make the cut
into the popular index funds.
So now and again, I like
to invest some extra money
into these up and coming
company, so I don't miss out.
And that reminds me, Webull
are currently given away,
four free individual stocks.
If you wanna pick them up,
I'll leave the link in the description.
And for everyone that's
outside of the U.S.A. or China,
I'll leave a link where
you can claim a free stock
with Trading 212.
- Hey, that's pretty good.
- You'll often hear people
throwing around the terms,
Roth IRA, in the U.S.A.
stocks and shares ISA in the U.K.
TFSA in Canada, and Supers in Australia.
But what does it all mean?
Well, these are types of accounts
that allow you to earn
profits on your investments,
and you don't have to
pay any taxes on them,
but they generally have limits
because they're just so powerful.
These are kind of like
Captain America's shield.
So let me explain.
If captain America just sat
at home with his shield,
then he wouldn't ever get anything done,
but when he takes that shield into battle,
he has an advantage.
So these accounts are like your shield.
Make sure to use them
when you're investing.
A way you can do this
is by using the money
inside your shielded account
to invest into index funds,
and all the profits will be yours
because the government won't take a cup.
One of my biggest questions
when I first started,
was should I invest all
my money at the same time,
or do it gradually?
Now, this is something lots
of investors argue about,
so I'm gonna give you my view on things.
Remember later, I'm gonna be
investing this $10,000 in full,
so that kind of gives you
an idea of what I believe.
Investing all your money as a lump sum
is certainly more risky.
However, if I'm investing
in something I know
will increase over time,
like an S&P 500 index fund,
then there's no point waiting.
The longer you wait, the
worse of an average you'll be.
However, if you don't have the cash,
I wouldn't wait to save up the money.
I would just invest what
I could every month,
and sometimes you're gonna
buy when a stock's high,
other times, you're gonna
buy when the stock's low,
but overall, this is gonna balance out,
and this is known as
dollar cost averaging.
When you log onto an
investing website or app,
you'll see that there is
something called ETFs,
which are very similar to index funds,
and a lot of people get them confused.
Both allow you to invest
into a basket of stocks.
However, the easy way to
remember the difference,
is just a think of what ETF stands for,
Exchange Traded Fund.
If we break that down simply,
it just means that it can be
traded on the stock market
throughout the day, whereas an index fund
can only be bought and sold
for a price that is set
at the end of each trading day.
But let's cut to the chase.
You probably wanna know
which one's better.
On average, if you're
starting with little money,
then ETFs may be a better option,
as they have lower minimum
investment thresholds,
and many brokers don't
charge a trading commission.
Now, if you're still watching this
and you're younger than 18,
then I'm really impressed
that you've been listening to
a boomer like me for so long,
but seriously, not many people learn this
at such young ages, they
don't teach it at school.
But why you can start investing under 18,
is to open up a custodial
account in the U.S.A.
or a Junior Stocks and
Shares ISA in the U.K.
To set up these accounts, you
just need to ask your parents.
The real secret ingredient
to this millionaire formula is time.
And when you're younger,
you have so much of it.
That's because every year,
as you keep adding to your investments,
the interest starts to compound
and grow at a rapid pace.
It's a snowball effect.
Once you reach a certain tipping point,
the interest you're making is much more
than the amount you're
investing on a monthly basis.
It's a bit like when you
see someone take ages
to get to a hundred thousand
subscribers on YouTube,
and then within a few months,
they managed to hit the big million.
The sooner you get started, the better,
as time will be on your side.
Now, I wanna clear something up.
When people talk about index
funds, you will hear S&P 500,
again and again, people just love it.
As I mentioned before, this
is at top 500 public companies
in the U.S.A. but the cool thing
is you don't actually
have to be in the U.S.A.
to invest in this.
I'm in the U.K. and it's one
of my favorite investments.
I just love to think
that I own a small part
of all the biggest companies in the U.S.A.
Part three, mastering the strategy.
So lots of people will
teach you what to do,
but they won't actually say how to do it.
So I'm gonna walk you through
everything, right now,
while I invest my own $10,000.
The first thing to really do
is to work out your goals.
Let's say you wanna become a millionaire.
That was one of my goals,
I just had to work out
how much I would actually
need to invest per month,
to achieve this.
I love using these compound
interest calculators.
You can find them
online, easily, yourself,
if you wanna have a go at this.
So if you're able to invest $250 per month
with an eight percent annual
return, over 42 years,
you'll have over a million
dollars in your account.
Now, if you're able to invest
that for another 10 years,
you'll have over two
million in your account.
Of course, if you wanted
to invest even more,
than you're just gonna
speed up the whole process.
The next thing we need to do
is pick the brokerage website we're using
to set up our account, and invest.
The ones that I love are
Charles Schwab, Fidelity,
and Vanguard.
I call these, the big three.
The founder of Vanguard,
John Bogle, is often referred
to as the father of index fund investing.
And if you think I'm a boomer,
he was even older than me.
His Vanguard Group gave
birth to index funds,
so they're the oldest and most trusted.
Let's jump onto their website,
to see what they have to offer.
So to get onto their full list of funds,
just go up to Investing, and
click on Vanguard Mutual Funds.
At this point, I'm gonna have to ask you
to strap in and brace yourself,
because if you haven't
seen this page before,
it can look extremely
overwhelming, but in a minute,
you'll be able to
impress all your friends,
when you know exactly how to read it.
See what I mean, there
are just so many options.
The main things to focus
on are the expense ratio,
which is how much they're
gonna charge you per year.
You obviously, wanna keep
these as low as possible,
and luckily, with Vanguard fees,
these are very low, anyway.
The other thing to look
at is the average returns,
and they break these down nicely,
on the right-hand side of the screen.
But of course, it's
always good to remember
that past performance doesn't
always mean future returns.
My wife's a bit like Vanguard,
she likes everything in order,
and nothing out of place.
So they have arranged all of their funds
into different categories, so
everything is easy to find.
Category one, is bonds.
(clicking)
These are a type of contract
that companies and governments sell
when they need extra money.
If you invest in these,
they promise to pay
you back in the future.
These are often seen as pretty low risk,
but also, pretty low returns.
Therefore, the older you are,
the more bonds you should have
in your portfolio.
Number two, is balanced funds.
The idea of these is to pick the age
at which you wish to retire,
and they'll do all the
rest of the work for you,
and find the right mix of index funds.
Actually, you can see, these
go up in five-year intervals,
and you can pick whichever
suits your plans best.
This could be a good option
if you wanted to invest
without thinking about it too much,
but personally, I always
prefer manually investing.
It's a bit like driving an automatic car,
that does all the work for you,
it just isn't as much
fun as a stick shift.
Number three, is company
location and size,
known as small, medium, and large cap.
Here, you can find VFIAX,
which tracks our old friend,
the S&P 500.
This little s means it's one
of Vanguard's selected funds,
which they recommend.
If you click on it, you're able
to see exactly what companies
you would be investing in,
and also the risk level.
VTSAX is another good one,
which is a total stock market index fund,
which has over 3,586 different stocks.
This allows you to invest in
the entire U.S.A. stock market
in one click.
There's a minimum
investment of $3,000 again,
but as before, there's also an
ETF version with no minimum,
called VTI.
Then you have international stocks.
Quite a cool one is emerging markets,
which invest in companies
based in China, Taiwan, India,
and many more.
But as you can see, this is
a five on the risk scale.
So I wouldn't personally
invest a lot of money
into this fund because look at me,
I'm a bit old to be taking too many risks,
and I need to sleep at night.
Number four, the last
category, is sector based.
So if you have a particular
interest in energy, health care,
or real estate, you can
invest into these sectors.
And there are also a lot more options
for sector investing in the ETF.
So now we've broken down what's on offer,
hopefully, it all looks a
bit more understandable.
Now, for the moment you've
all been waiting for.
It's time to invest my $10,000.
I could split this between
lots of different funds,
but personally, I like to
invest the majority of my money
into American companies.
I would say, probably, about 70% American,
20% in other countries, including the U.K.
and 10% in some bonds.
I like to keep the bonds quite low,
as I don't mind this
little extra bit of risk,
because I'm only 53,
and I have a bit of time
before I've got to rebalance my portfolio
to secure my investments.
But that's a personal choice,
depending on your risk tolerance.
The funds that are available
are different in every country,
but the index is they
track it very similar.
So you may need to invest
in a different fund to me,
but obviously, you can still
use my percentages as a guide.
So I'm gonna the U.K. Vanguard
site to invest five k,
straight into this ETF,
that tracks the S&P 500.
So here we go, all done.
(clicking)
$2,000 is going into an index fund
that tracks the total
American stock market.
So again, we go on the screen,
click.
(clicking)
So far that 70% invested
in the biggest economy
in the world, which of
course is the U.S.A.
Now, I like to balance this out
by investing in a different economy.
As I look back in my own country,
I'm gonna be putting two K
into the FTSE 100 Index Fund.
So looking good.
(clicking)
All done, great.
Now, I've invested 90% of my 10 K,
and I'd like a bit of security.
Let's just put the remaining one K,
into a Global Bonds Index Fund,
and let's just do that.
(clicking)
So just like that,
I've invested in the U.S.A.
companies like Apple, Amazon,
Tesla, and Google.
I own a small piece of the
biggest companies in the U.K.
like HSBC, BP and Unilever,
and I have some bonds to
balance out my portfolio.
It really is as easy as that.
So I'm gonna leave the next video up here,
but don't click on it just yet,
remember to subscribe to the channel,
if you want to grow your wealth,
ring that Notification bell
and smash that Live button, okay?
I'll see you on the other side.