- Hi guys, this is Mark.
So let's talk about something I think
pretty much everyone wants to know,
how to make some extra money
with your laptop while sitting at home.
But don't worry, guys, I'm
not gonna be suggesting
you spend hours watching
ads, testing websites,
or filling out those
useless online surveys.
They only pay a few dollars anyway,
what's the point?
Instead, I'm interested in the big bucks.
So I'm gonna be grouping all my favorite
online side hustles into four tiers.
Of course, the faster you
progress through those tiers,
the more money you'll be able to make.
I'm talking about generating
at least a $1,000 a day
if you reach the top tiers.
So if you're up for the challenge,
click the like button to let me know.
So let's start with the base tier.
These are things you can
just get on the start
and do straight away without any skills.
They're all about
generating that fast money.
So the first idea I have for you
is flipping Instagram theme pages.
These are pages that are
focused on specific subjects.
When I first heard that you can make money
from flipping these, I was quite shocked.
Back in my day, I had to buy
actual physical products like cars,
but now this actually
makes complete sense.
Just think about it,
when was the last time
you scrolled on Instagram
and didn't see a sponsored post?
They're everywhere, aren't they?
This just shows brands
are putting loads of money
into Instagram adverts, which
makes the pages more valuable.
If I were you I'd only buy
pages with active followers
and continue to grow them
by posting regularly.
I would pick a car-theme page
as I used to race cars myself.
So I know the niche has a
big demand from advertisers.
Here's my old crash helmet,
custom painted with my
logo till both lines even.
Great days.
Next up is selling on items
on Facebook marketplace.
This is such a great way to sell things
without having to deal with
postage or selling fees.
Recently, I had my backyard ripped up
as we're having a total redesign,
and I was left with 400
heavy concrete slabs.
Now I could either pay
to have them taken away and dumped for me,
or find some alternative option.
And you know me, I don't
like wasting money.
So I put them up for sale
on Facebook marketplace.
I thought it's gotta be
worth a go, isn't it?
Later that day, my phone exploded
with message from people
who were over my area,
asking if they could come
and get some of my slabs.
I couldn't believe it.
People came and removed my garbage,
and I didn't even have to lift a finger.
The best part of all though,
I made an extra $650 that day.
A more longterm example
is selling vintage clothing online,
and one of my friends does exactly that.
She finds them through poorly
advertised eBay listings.
And you can do a similar thing
by using a website called Typo Hound.
This is really cool
because it looks through
all of the misspell items on eBay.
So you can buy with a lower competition,
and get a great bargain.
She cleans the clothes and
does any repairs needed.
Then she dresses a mannequin
so she can take great photos,
and she posts them on social media.
You know what?
It's so successful, she
struggles to get enough clothes.
So, if I could sell dirty paving slabs,
and my friend can sell secondhand clothes,
I'm sure there's something in your house
that you can sell and
start making a profit.
Next up is the mid tier.
This is all about going out
and selling your skills.
These online side hustles require
more upfront work to begin with,
but as you develop your skills,
you'll be able to charge a lot
more than the average person,
as you're providing more value,
and this of course equals higher pay.
One of the things that comes to mind
is being a social media
manager for small businesses.
I've actually just hired someone
to help me post more on my Instagram.
That reminds me, if you
haven't already followed me,
drop me a follow @RealMarkTilbury
for regular posting updates.
The person I've hired is great.
She's able to look at the
graphs and the numbers
and tell me how everything's performing.
All I have to do is supply the
content, reply to you guys,
and the rest is all taken care of.
I found my social media
manager through her own page,
I could see how passionate
and talented she was,
and after a quick chat,
I knew I had to hire her.
So if you wanna stand out,
it's probably a good idea
to imagine you are your first client,
by marketing your own
social media accounts.
If you spend time learning
how to maximize your accounts,
then you'll be able to
offer your future clients
a much better service.
As you start working with more businesses,
you can slowly up your prices,
and before you know it,
you'll be making more than $150 per day.
Over 600,000 new businesses
are started every year
in the USA, and guess what?
They all need a logo.
So if you're a creative person,
why not learn how to use
photo editing software
then you can use your
skills to make money online
through freelance graphic design?
For this type of work,
no one cares about your school grades.
Instead, your past work
acts as your qualifications.
So it's really important
to build a great portfolio
to seal the deal with your clients.
When hiring someone new,
I feel more comfortable
if they offer their services for free,
as it reduces the risk for me,
and gives them a way to
build their portfolio.
I know that working for free
sounds like a waste of time,
but it's a great way to
check out the competition,
and also see how to price your services.
Once you have a solid portfolio,
you can either go
directly to your clients,
or offer graphic design
services on websites
like Fiverr, that already
have a huge marketplace.
If you're good, there's no reason
why you couldn't be earning
$150 per day in your spare time.
How about this next one?
When everything locked down in early 2020,
my son's girlfriend
had a great side hustle
as an online tutor, and is
still going strong today.
Before the illness happened,
I probably wouldn't have
added this one to the list,
as most people wanted in-person tutors.
However, I really think
the world has changed.
If you're talented at a particular subject
it may be a great option
to teach it online.
She advertised her services on Facebook,
and before she knew it,
her DMS were full of potential clients.
So if you find the right Facebook groups
the demand is sky high.
The great thing about doing it online
is that you cut out all the travel time,
which means you can work with more people
and earn more money.
You also don't have to just work
for people in your local area,
as you can teach anyone
anywhere in the world.
If you're doing this in your spare time,
you should be out to expect
a good $50 plus per day.
If you enjoy writing, then maybe
you should try copywriting.
This is the art of selling
a product through writing.
This is like being a sales person,
but reaching out to everyone.
You can write sales pages,
ads for Facebook, email newsletters,
the list goes literally on and on.
And the more you specialize
in one specific area,
the more you learn.
I first learned about
the art of copywriting
when I read an amazing book
called "Breakthrough
Advertising" by Eugene Schwartz.
This book currently sells
for over $200 a copy,
and is considered the holy
grail in the copywriting world.
This just proves how in demand
copywriter services are.
If your writing is able to
convince lots of people to buy,
then you're able to justify charging
really high prices as effectively,
you're paying your own wages.
This couldn't be more
true than for the guy
who took three weeks of studying,
to come up with the winning concept
for a Rolls Royce advert.
The final headline read,
"At 60 miles an hour,
the loudest noise in a Rolls Royce
comes from the electric clock."
It took him a while, but he
managed to find a golden nugget
that people still remember to this day.
His skill with copyrighting
made him a small fortune.
Now, no business can survive long
without a good website these days,
and most people are lacking
the skills all the time,
to build one themselves.
So if this interests you,
then why not sell your
web design services?
I know two teenagers that
decided to take up web design
and they went in two totally
different directions.
One decided he'd use website
builders such as Squarespace,
which means he only had to
edit really simple templates
to build a basic site for his clients.
The other decided to code
bespoke websites from the ground up,
for larger clients that wanted
something more original.
Now, both are very
successful at what they do,
but they serve entirely different markets
at different price points.
You'd get paid more for bespoke sites,
however, this takes a
lot more time to learn.
If you like something a little
bit more simple to pick up,
then video editing might be for you.
If you have a computer,
then you probably have some
video editing software.
Apple Macs are great because
they come with a movie.
Filmmakers are often looking for people
that can edit their videos
quickly and to a high standard,
as this means they can
take on more filming jobs.
I know this, my first son Curtis
has actually hired an editor
to help him with projects,
and he's also looking for a few more.
There are also a lot of
great YouTube ads out there
that need help with this,
and it's a great way to
build good connections.
The most important thing is
you're able to produce good edits quickly,
and are able to stick to a deadline.
Being trustworthy and reliable
really makes you stand
out and get more clients.
Now for the Alpha Tier.
This is all about taking
a few of the skills
we've already mentioned
and combining them.
Think of it a bit like Minecraft,
as you're taking the raw
materials which are the skills,
and crafting them into
something more valuable.
This is really the
point when you can start
generating some passive income.
An easy way to get started is
we have an E-commerce business
like dropshipping or Amazon FBA.
Neither of these require you
to have warehouses like me,
so you can get started with just a laptop.
These types of businesses
seem to get a lot of height,
as people think that they're all about
selling cheap and shoddy
products from China.
The truth is that nearly
everything you buy
is made in China these days,
and most is of a pretty high quality.
But unfortunately, you
only ever seem to hear
the horror stories in the scams.
You don't need a lot of
money to start dropshipping,
if you don't have to buy any stock,
but one thing you do need is
good digital marketing skills
to make your products that
you're selling stand out
from others in an extremely
competitive market.
Lots of people don't take the
time to learn these skills
and they just go for it with dropshipping,
because they see people
like Biaheza making fortunes
and they think anyone can do it.
The truth is it's like anything.
It takes time and commitment.
You may remember Jack from
one of my previous videos,
he is doing very well with Amazon FBA.
He finds products from China,
that are either very
popular or very unique,
and then he sells them for Amazon.
He has to come in and buy the stock,
but he doesn't have to
store the products himself,
as he can just ship them
to Amazon's warehouse
and they take care of the rest.
If you have a chat with Jack,
he'll tell you that this is
superior to dropshipping,
as you have access to so many customers
on the Amazon platform,
so you don't have to
advertise your products.
But I would say that this comes
with a cost of losing your customer data,
so it's completely up to you.
Now let's get into creating
and selling digital product,
as the profits you can
make are much higher.
A friend of mine created
a bundle of templates for Instagram,
and she sells them for $30 per download.
Last year, she made a
quarter of a million dollars,
now that's pretty amazing.
A digital product could be many things
from these Instagram templates
to eBooks and online courses.
If you invest your time making these,
then you can sell them year on year,
and never run out of stock.
If you don't wanna sell your own products,
then why not just sell someone else's?
This is known as affiliate marketing.
An easy way to get started with this,
is to create a simple
unboxing video on YouTube.
Loads of people love these videos.
Just look at Unbox Therapy,
it's got over 17 million subscribers.
The key here is to reach out to companies
and get an affiliate link.
So whenever someone chooses
to buy through your link,
the company will pay you
a commission in return.
I always put some links
in the descriptions
of my videos that are relevant
and beneficial to you guys
such as free stocks from platforms
like Webull and Trading 212,
and a link to all the
filming equipment that I use.
So if any of that does interest you,
feel free to take a look,
but ultimately it's all
about the supreme tier.
The main goal this stage
is to build your own brand,
as it will last the test of time.
My focus was to create a machine
that delivered as much value as possible
for as many people as I could.
I did this by launching
my own product range.
I took the designs I drew as a kid,
and turned them into products
I could sell across the world.
By making your own brand,
you can stand out from everyone else,
and also have a scalable business
that you can sell further down the line.
Here's one of the products I designed,
is actually the most popular
model aircraft in the UK today.
I had to travel around the
world to find all the parts
and a manufacturer to make it.
You can easily invest more than two years
into developing your own brand
before you see any sales,
so it is a long-term commitment.
I've been following Ben
Francis's journey with his brand,
Gymshark with great interest.
Less than 10 years ago,
he started making his own
gym clothes from his home,
with a little sewing machine
as an online side hustle
while he was delivering
pizzas for Pizza Hut.
He's now managed to turn
Gymshark into a huge business.
Your brand could be anything
from radar control models,
clothing, or even some kind of app.
I'm sure that Ben never imagined
that it in a shorter space as 10 years,
he'd be the owner of a
billion dollar brand.
Maybe you could be the next,
and it all starts with a side hustle.
I'm gonna leave the next media up here,
but don't click on it just yet.
Remember to subscribe to the channel
if you want to grow your wealth.
Ring the notification bell
and smash that like button.
Okay, I'll see you on the other side.