- This circle represents how much money
Amazon generated last year, $232 billion.
This circle shows how much
money was generated by people
like you selling on Amazon $53.7 billion.
This little dot represents
the share of the profit
you would need to claim in
order to become a millionaire.
When you zoom out, it looks
like a drop in the ocean,
but is it actually that easy?
Well if you believe the
majority of the online gurus
then you would think, yes,
they like to sell you the dream
of escaping your nine to
five and living on a beach
watching the money roll in,
all by starting something
called Amazon FBA.
I want to get to the bottom of this.
Is it a legitimate way to make money?
Or are these gurus making
money just by teaching it?
Now it's no secret that over 40,000 people
generate over $1 million
per year on the platform.
But are they making any profit?
More to the question, is
this something anyone can do
and your golden ticket
to millionaire status
or it all just a pipe dream?
That's exactly what I'm
going to be uncovering
in the first episode of
The Secret World Of Passive
Income Millionaires.
Hi guys, it's Mark.
So recently I can't escape
the phrase Amazon FBA
I'm a massive fan of
YouTube, as you all know
and on nearly every video I watch,
an advert pops up saying it's the key
to becoming a millionaire and fast.
So of course I was intrigued
as I made my millions
through running traditional businesses.
The way I've always done
it is to have warehouses.
And I buy the stock in containers,
bring it in from China
or America or Europe.
And we stack it out.
And we're pretty much sold out
and we're waiting for containers to come.
The way Amazon FBA works
is a little different.
FBA stands for fulfilled by Amazon.
Meaning instead of
having warehouses like me
you can just ship all
the items off to Amazon
and they deal with all
the storage, the packaging
and the sending out of all your items.
So on the surface, it
sounds pretty great, yeah.
I mean, less worries, lots of customers.
What's not to like?
Maybe it's something you could do
as a side hustle and maybe
make a little bit of money.
But is it a long-term business?
I'm just not convinced.
If you're doing Amazon FBA successfully
then I want to hear from you.
I want you to persuade me
that this is more than a side hustle.
- Mark, I'll take you up on that offer.
I'll show you how these online businesses
are taking over and how
they can be so sustainable.
As you can see, we don't
play around with stock.
- Here are my concerns.
Imagine them as bowling pins
in order for me to change my mind
they're all going to
have to be knocked down.
Number one is the startup costs.
Can anyone really start this business
or do you need a huge amount
of cash to buy in products
and then test them out?
Number two is over
saturation and competition.
Can it really be profitable in 2020?
On one hand the marketplace is massive,
but also millions of people are selling
similar products on Amazon.
Number three is actually finding
a winning product that sells well.
With lots of other people searching
for the next best thing, it must be
incredibly hard to actually strike gold
and find that one product
that makes you millions.
Number four is the amount
of money Amazon takes.
If they're sending out
all the orders for you,
I imagine they take a pretty
big slice of the profit.
I don't have this expense so
I'm really interested to
know if this is a problem.
Number five is picking bad products.
My worst nightmare would be storing
lots of products in Amazon's warehouse
and not being able to sell the stock.
As time goes on, I imagine the fees
are going to really add up.
Number six, now this
really is the big one.
Lack of control.
I've always been in control of everything
from manufacturing all the way through
to shipping the product
to my customer's door.
But as Amazon take all the control
of the selling and shipping,
I would be concerned
about losing all the
information about my customers.
I wouldn't want Amazon to
shut me down and have to build
up all those customers all
over again from scratch.
All right, so now all the
bowling pins have been set.
Jack, I'm on my way.
Jack is a no BS young
entrepreneur who has amassed
nearly a hundred thousand
followers on his TikTOK account
and 8,000 on Instagram,
where he gives straight to
the point business advice,
as well as recently
even carving his quote,
"Stay loyal to your goals
and they'll stay loyal
to you" into his Porsche.
So quite a character.
So have you had it all repaired now?
- It's in there now,
so I drive the four by four at the minute.
- Jack, what's your
age and what do you do?
- So I'm 19 years old or 19 years young.
And I do Amazon FBA.
It's a business that you can get into
at a very entry level.
You can, you know, it's
you don't need too much money for it.
And the numbers you can
build up with a lot of effort
and determination are very impressive.
- So what inspired someone of your age
to get into this and be an entrepreneur?
- I tried out full-time work,
personally, I didn't think it was for me.
A lot of people, you
know, are better at it.
For me, I don't fit the norm.
People thoroughly believe
that the way to get rich
is to work, work, work,
put money into a pension.
And when you're 60, you've
got a million pounds.
And personally, I don't want that.
And that's not the road I'm taking.
If that's people want, that's fine
but that's not the path I'm taking.
I want it sooner, so I will get it sooner.
If that makes sense, you
know, and it's possible.
- So if I can be a bit
cheeky, what are your numbers?
- So, first year we did
about 140, 150,000 pounds.
This year, the last 12 months
we're pushing nigh on 200,000 pounds.
- That's a working
business then, that's good.
So for someone watching this video
what do they need to invest into this
to really get going?
- I always recommend 1500 pounds.
Which as you know is a very entry level
amount of money to start a business
especially a retail business.
What that'll get you is good software
that you need for Amazon selling.
It will pay for your first month of stock.
You don't need a certain
amount of money for stock.
You can start with a hundred pounds
and you can make your money on that.
You could start with a thousand pounds.
It's just a case of ratios,
you know, and scaling it up.
Just please think of it as
an investment in yourself
yet don't expect that money
to come back very soon.
It's not gonna start
paying you soon, you know.
It's a long-term game,
but for long-term gain.
- What point did you work
out that you can quit it
as a side hustle and make
it your main business?
Where do you think that
break over point is?
- I'd say three solid months.
That's what I was so, you know,
I remember speaking to my dad
and I said, dad, I would
quit, I'm gonna quit.
I had one good day, one good day.
I think we did like 800 pounds in profit.
I was like I'm going,
I'm leaving, I'm leaving.
No, he said, you need to be,
he said, if you want to do that, he said
you need to make sure your
business is going to support you.
So I waited three months for three
good, good months of sales, where it was,
you know doing two, three,
four, five, six times
what I earned at a job.
And then I was like,
okay, now that's time.
And it's definitely something,
it's not something that
should be rushed into.
- So I've always seen
drop ship in an FBA really
as just a stepping stone,
just a starter type business.
Can you persuade me otherwise?
- I see massive longevity,
not with what I'm doing now.
What I find is this is the cash cow.
So it's building up the
cash for what I want to do
which is private label.
You're building a story, you're providing
top quality products where you can control
the quality of the product, the packaging
the branding, the customer
relation, you know
with nice cards and
appreciation, stuff like that.
Which is huge because what you've then got
if you've got an
established brand on Amazon,
you're not just getting money from sales.
Your brand is being featured
on the most visited website
on the planet by Google, which
they'd find it on anyway.
Private label, you're
creating a sellable asset.
A longterm business that is going to
one, keep ticking over.
If you boost it to the first
page and you keep ads on it,
that product is going to make you money
for three, four, five, six years,
however long to keep it there for.
- How'd you go about
finding your products,
because a lot of people who write to me
and they say, you know how
can I find that niche product?
And how long does it take you as well?
- It could take me 20 minutes.
It could take me 15 minutes.
- 20 minutes that's impressive.
- Or it could take me
two, three, four months.
It's totally a case of sitting down there
how my mentality is going towards it.
I think finding that key product is tough.
However, they all have an
expiration date, for sure.
It's not, you will never
ride off just one product,
you need to keep on pushing,
keep on finding more.
But for me, it is a case
of sitting down in my zone
and I will not get off
my desk until I find one.
That'd be picking up the phone quite a lot
dealing with a lot of rejection.
You know, how old are you? I'm 19.
And you know, how old your business?
Well, just over a year.
You know, the second it's a no
or the second it's showing
that it's not happening.
Just phone down onto the next.
You know, really detach emotions from it.
Yes, it's the constant contact,
speaking to people and
the networking as well.
The networking is huge,
like meeting people
who know other people or companies.
Just getting in touch with them,
going around, there's
just so many roundabouts,
but it's about going over
them and going around them
and not being scared to do so.
But it is hard work.
- So obviously Amazon take
quite a cutout from you.
So is that a set percentage
on every item you sell
or is that a variable percentage?
- It varies a lot on
size and weight as well.
So something, for example, a pen
they're not going to charge
very high fees on this,
probably about the lowest band of fees.
So it depends on the weight and the size
and how much it's going to cost them
to ship it and move it around.
- Say you've sent a lot
of product to Amazon
and it's not selling.
How do you handle that situation?
- I've had two types of products,
two products that have just been a loss.
I've had to accept that
they're just doing nothing.
And that was T-shirts and there were these
they were called juicy Lucy
picture frames, basically.
They didn't go well at all.
They were not as anticipated.
And it was a bit of a kick, you know
it's a lot of money to expect to lose.
That's how, that's my instant,
Oh, it's not working, damn it.
What I did was I put ads on them,
which I don't usually do,
which I kind of stay away from.
Because when you start doing
ads, it cuts your margins.
And that would have been my profit.
So it worked out that
actually I'm doing that
and I'm making no profit,
but then I sat back and
thought, that's amazing.
How wonderful was that?
Because at first I was beating myself up.
Why did I do that?
How did I get the product wrong?
Then I'm like, hang on, I tried it out.
It didn't work, did I lose it? No.
Did I get my money back? Yes.
- And learned a lesson.
- And learned a lesson
and took lesson from that.
So I think to myself, for me going forward
I don't see much going wrong for me.
But you know, if I find something
that's not going to sell,
I have the ability to get rid of it.
Whether it be 10P loss
per unit, it's not drastic
it's not going to kill
my business, you know.
Which was a very amazing eye-opener.
So to think to myself,
actually, that didn't work
but I still got rid of it
at breakeven and I got my money back.
- Okay, so are you afraid of the fact
that Amazon could find
the same products as you?
If you're doing really
well with them and they go,
you know what we're going
to relabel those as ours
and sell them and stop you selling them.
Is that a fear with it
or do you think you can ride through that?
- For me, yes, that can happen,
I've heard it happening.
Personally it has happened to me
by one product actually recently.
But for me, it's part of the game.
It's part of the business,
it's a stepping stone
you need to get over.
Yes, they'll throw blockades in there,
but again you work harder,
you find another product,
you keep pushing it and keep
working on profits, that's all.
- Is there ever a problem?
If you're unable to stock
do Amazon put the pressure
on you to keep that stock flowing?
Will they cut you off
if you're not supplying?
What's the arrangement there?
- In regards to that, Amazon have
like a process where they'll say to you
they'll recommend a
certain amount of stock
you should be sending in.
So yeah, they prefer it
when you have constant levels of stock,
they will favor you as a seller.
For sure, for sure.
If it's too sporadic they'll just be like,
obviously they will encourage
you to get more stock in.
They'll put widgets on your
screen saying, source this
get this product in, you
know, we need more of this.
- Your customer base is
Amazon's customer base.
How do you make contact
with those customers?
How do you retain that information?
- I'm not allowed to take information
from Amazon and email them.
It's not, that's not
what they signed up for.
You know, people don't want
that when buying on Amazon.
They just want to buy an Amazon,
get the product and that's
it, that's their journey.
It is part and parcel of it.
And so in regards to, you know
retention of customers and
keeping their information
Amazon take that, that's fine.
But then Amazon will pay me
and sell my products for me and send them
to the customers and do
all the customer service.
That's fine.
They can have that side of the business.
You know if they can give me my profits,
they can give me my profits.
That's, that's how I see it.
It ha got its pros and cons, it has.
You know, in regards to
keeping them on an email list
and stuff like that, again,
Amazon's impulse buys,
people just go on there and buy.
With the size of their customer base,
you don't need returning customers.
- So did you learn from a course
or did you learn from experience?
- I learned from experience
and a few losses.
- School of hard knocks, hey?
- Yeah, that's it really.
So, yeah, my first shipments,
it was quite a lot, it was huge
was basically a whole loss.
It was, you know, my money
out my personal savings,
you know, 2000, 3000 pounds gone.
So it was pretty brutal.
But again, I was paying
for those lessons, you know
I could have bought a course of 500 pounds
which probably would have
saved me that two and a half
thousand pounds or 3000
or whatever it may be.
So, yeah, personally,
I didn't take a course.
I just went in head first.
I just went head first and that was,
that's one of my biggest strengths
and my biggest weaknesses.
Cause I just get it done, I
go for it and I learn quickly.
But as you can tell, obviously, you know,
you can slip up and make a few mistakes,
which you learn from.
- So you're starting to persuade me here.
So what's the future for Jack?
- It's very funny, I've
got huge goals, massive.
So obviously I'm 19 now, by
21 I would like 10 businesses
doing 10,000 pounds a
month net profit each,
which I would think would be unbelievable.
I think Amazon FBA will
carry most of that.
Maybe 20, 30, 40, 50, 60% of it.
I want to retire by the time I'm 30.
Now, when I say retire,
physically I don't have an obligation
to get up and make more
money to work and go forward.
The catch is there's a
quite a lot of hard work.
A lot of, you know, research, long days,
down days, a lot of rejection.
Amazon FBA it really is,
putting in the work first
but you're doing that for long-term cash,
long-term money which is what everyone
goes into business for anyway.
no one's in it for fun.
- So overnight success is
a good few months of work.
- It's a good few months of work
before you start seeing profit.
I don't see that as a success.
If you see success as making a hundred,
an extra hundred, 200, 300
pound a month, absolutely.
Success for me is big numbers.
And big numbers do not come
for a little while yet.
I don't even believe
my numbers are big yet.
I want to see millions,
I want to see seven figures on the board,
that's success to me and
that doesn't come for,
I imagine two, three years.
- So did Jack changed my opinion?
Here's what I think.
I have no doubt that Jack is
going to be a multimillionaire.
In fact, I see a bit of me
in him when I was at his age.
I really liked it when he talked about
building his own brand
through private labeling.
This wasn't something that
I initially thought of.
And it definitely seems like a great way
to build a saleable longterm business.
So he's really done a
good job at persuading me
but my only bowling pin left standing
is the heavy reliance on Amazon.
Now, Jack, doesn't see
this as being a problem
but maybe this is because of his age
and Amazon of course has
always been around for him.
So my view on Amazon FBA is that
if you're selling other
people's branded products
then it can be a great side hustle,
however, don't bank on it lasting forever.
So I'm going to leave this
next video for you right here
but don't click on it just yet.
If you want to grow your wealth,
then consider subscribing to the channel
ring that old bell and
smash that like button.
And leave a comment below
on what you want to see
on the next Passive Income Millionaires.
I'll see you over there.