- Hi, it's Mark.
In this video, I'm gonna be revealing
the investing strategies that I used
to go from beginner investor
with very little money
to multimillionaire by the age of 35
and how you can do the exact same thing.
So I've got a simple question for you.
Do you wanna be here rich and
have the freedom that comes
with being financially stable?
Many people do.
Why do you think there's so
many get rich quick schemes
out there?
Most people though, unfortunately
have a lottery mentality.
They're just waiting for
the magic fairy to come down
and hand them a million dollars.
Do I look like the magic fairy to you?
If the answer is no, and
I really hope it is no,
then smash that thumbs up button
and subscribe to the channel.
The truth is, lots of people
think, that winning a chunk
of money will make your
problems just disappear
but there'll be in for an absolute shock.
Without the correct investment
and a mindset strategies
it will be all gone
and in no time, you'll
be back to square one.
You need a solid,
consistent investment plan
which gradually builds
your wealth over time.
Long-term investing
will give great returns.
When I was younger, I always
wanted it be a race car driver.
I just loved everything about cars
but I didn't have enough
money to pursue my dreams.
But as I started building
up my investments,
it allowed me to race in
multiple championships
and win countless trophies like this.
I even got my helmet here look,
you sometimes sit at
the back of the shots.
How cool is that?
My investments even allow
me to spend time having fun
making a YouTube videos,
like the one you're watching.
I don't currently make any
money from this channel
and you can sit back and relax
because I'm not gonna try
and sell you something at the end either.
There are so many different
investments out there.
It's super easy to get distracted
by the next shiny object.
It's also confusing when
you have someone telling you
that this is the best thing,
the latest and greatest
and if you don't invest, you
could end up losing thousands.
You may have heard of Bitcoin,
penny stocks and stock selling
but I found the key for me,
is not to get overwhelmed
and distracted by the latest trends.
Now you've got to face it.
You are never gonna be
an expert at everything
and by consistently changing
your investing strategy,
you will ultimately end up with less money
and at some point, you're
gonna make a big mistake.
I have nothing against experimenting
but I've kept my main
investments very consistent
over the years
and I make sure to only
invest large sums of money
into things that I understand completely.
I'm not gonna pretend that
I have all the answers
but I am gonna be completely transparent
about everything I've done
that's helped me acquire a
multi-million dollar net worth.
I'm a businessman and
not a financial advisor.
So I don't consider this financial advice.
It's just what I've done
and it's worked for me.
First of all, you need to
create more disposable income.
At the end of the day,
you need money to invest
and the more money you have, the better
especially during your
twenties and thirties.
Now lots of people will
say to save save save,
don't go out with your friends,
don't drink that overpriced coffee,
don't buy that nice car.
I don't completely agree.
Of course, saving is a big part of this
but you have to enjoy your life.
There's really no point
making yourself miserable
just for the sake of saving
an extra few dollars.
You should focus most of
your time on an energy
on increasing your income.
You can do this by learning
new valuable skills,
having a side hustle or
building a scalable business.
You don't have to settle for money you get
from your nine to five job.
You need to be focusing your time
on finding ways to
supplement or replace it.
When I was in my early
twenties, I realized my income
as a sculptor, earning
less than $3 an hour
was never gonna give me
enough money to invest.
It hardly even paid my bills.
I needed to find a way to
dramatically increase this
and this is when I started my journey
into the business world.
Investing and business,
really work hand in hand.
The sign is very true.
The more you learn, the more you earn.
And most importantly
the more you can invest.
Be really aware of your lifestyle
and make sure to keep it in check.
Just because you're earning more,
doesn't mean you should be spending more.
Think of someone like
say, I know Ed Sheeran.
He has a huge amount of money.
Yeah, he keeps his lifestyle in check.
He still enjoys the
little pleasures of life.
If you were happy making
let's say $40,000 a year,
and you managed to increase your income
up to a hundred thousand a year
that means you've got an extra 60k.
This should be going straight
into a high interest savings account.
And then into your investments.
You know, you don't
need to be spending it.
Well there is one slight exception
and that's stage number two.
Pay off all your high-interest debt.
If you have student
loans, credit card bills
or even a payday loan, the
needs are pulling you down.
They're destroying your credit score
which ruins your ability to
take advantage of good loans.
By paying off these high
interest debts first,
you'll actually save more money
than you could ever
hope to make elsewhere.
The next stage is to
create a freedom fund.
This is my name for an emergency fund
that puts the power back in your hands.
This freedom fund, consists
of three to five months
of living expenses.
It protects you if you
decide to quit your job,
as well as a lot of other situations
such as recessions, depressions
or even worldwide epidemics.
Okay, so you've increased your income
by learning a valuable skill
or maybe invested in your own business.
You've kept your lifestyle in check.
You've paid off all your loans
and you've created the freedom fund,
now and only now is the time
to start looking at other options.
Let's start off with
the lowest risk option.
Index funds.
An index fund is a collection
of investments that you
can put your money into
and own a percentage of the entire thing.
This gives you a fantastic diversification
and protect you from poor stock choices.
For example, let's say
you got a thousand dollars
and you invest it in, I
don't, let's say Apple stock.
Is there a big company, right?
They're gonna be safe.
As soon as your money goes
in, the company takes a turn
for the worst causing
the stock price to crash.
The result could be, that you loose
the majority of your investment.
This is where index funds come in.
Instead of owning just Apple Stock,
you could take that $1,000
and invest it in something
like the S and P 500, which
gives you small shares
in Apple as well as
Microsoft, Amazon, Facebook,
Visa, Disney and many more.
You're a shareholder of
all these major companies.
Now if something happened to
Apple, it would be balanced out
by the other investments
in your index funds.
Now lots of people will
try and convince you
that a mutual fund is superior.
A mutual fund is very, very
similar to an index fund
except it's controlled
by a very smart person
whose job is to pick
the stocks in the fund.
The purpose of a mutual fund is try
and beat the market and get
better results for the investor.
However, in the vast majority of cases
you'd be much better
off putting your money
into a simple index fund
with less risk and
often a brighter return.
This is because index funds
charge extremely low fees.
The S and P 500 charges, 0.07% annually.
And mutual funds charge high fees
between one to 2% of your
account balance annually.
If you invested $10,000
into a mutual fund,
then $200 would go straight into
that fund managers
wallet every single year.
Even if he cause you to lose money
through poor stock choices.
On the flip side, if you
had the same amount invested
in the S and P 500 index
fund, that only $7,
yes just $7 would be leaving
your account annually.
This is because index
funds are passively managed
and therefore don't have to pay a manager
who may or may not be doing job.
For long-term investments,
I love using Vanguard index
funds, as I like these.
They're so easy to use.
I'm not affiliated with
Vanguard in any way.
I just liked the way it works.
I also like to mix it up a little bit
with some international funds
and bonds to diversify
my portfolio even more.
The older you are the more bonds
I recommend you invest in.
And I don't mean James Bond diva
although he is pretty cool.
The investment method I put the majority
of my money into is real estate.
I am much more of a real
estate guy than a stock guy.
I like real investments
I can feel and touch
but I appreciate that it can be hard
to buy properties with little money
but it's certainly something
you should be saving for.
My first property was
a one bedroom apartment
and I loved it.
It was mine.
It cost me around $50,000
and when I moved out, I decided
to rent it $500 a month.
I had this property for
around about 10 years
and when I sold it, I sold it for 150k
and after this, I was
obsessed with the money
that we could make from real estate.
Now, this is a good time
to decide which type
of investor you are.
The first type is a
capital gains investor.
This is someone who likes
to buy low and sell high
and pocket the difference.
These are investors that are interested
in buy houses of auctions
or you may have seen the
signs outside advertising
that we buy your house for cash.
They like to take
advantage of the situations
when people want fast sales.
They made them move into the house,
do it up and flip it for a profit.
They have to keep repeating this process.
This can work very very well
but it's subject to
fluctuations in the markets
on a year to year basis.
The second type, is a cash flow investor.
This is the kind of investor
I like to think I am.
I'll never buy a property
if the rent won't cover the mortgage.
I like to follow the 1% rule
meaning if I buy a property
for a hundred thousand
dollars, then at minimum
I want it to bring me in a
thousand dollars a month.
Otherwise, to be honest,
I'm not buying it.
Now, let's talk about one
of the most risky options,
individual stocks.
I get asked about this
type of investment daily
and I understand why.
Individual stocks are a
very attractive choice
to lots of people.
This is because with a small investment
you can buy into the market
and sell whenever you want.
Unlike real estate
where you have to look for a buyer
and go through all that
whole selling process,
a tap of a button, you have
complete access to your funds.
When I was in my early twenties,
I looked at a few different companies
and I invested $5,000 in
single stocks and shares.
I'll tell you what, that
was a lot of money for me
back in those days
and within just six months though
have made a profit of a
hundred thousand dollars
and with that,
I could buy a massive warehouse
which really drove my business forward.
Make sure you understand
what you're investing in.
I see many people investing in stocks
because their friends said they should.
If don't understand it,
it's quite simple, don't invest.
I use two methods of valuing stock.
The first way is called
quantitative analysis.
Something that might surprise you is
when you Google the price of stock
that isn't the actual real value,
it's more an estimate.
I like to look at the company's
quarterly earnings reports
which includes things like balance sheets,
income and cashflow,
to get a real sort of feel
for the value of the company.
You can easily find this
information on the internet.
The second way is called
qualitative analysis.
This isn't about the actual numbers
but more about the abstract qualities
that make a company great.
A good example of this is Tesla.
There was something special
about Tesla from the CEO
Elon Musk, to the raving
fans that are his customers.
I also like to take into
account the future value
of a company based on how their technology
will live in the modern world.
I believe the move to
electric is inevitable
and Tesla are at the
forefront of this industry
with the most extensive network
of supercharges and
availability of product.
If you do decided to go down
the route of individual stocks,
then make sure to create
a diverse portfolio,
don't just use one sector.
You've gotta use different things
like healthcare, technology,
various different things.
You really don't wanna leave
yourself open to huge losses.
If you're interested in this,
I'll put some links below
where you can find some really cool books.
You can do this on some great apps
such as M1 Finance, Robinhood,
and if you're in the UK,
you can use Freetrade.
I personally like to control
and add value to my investments.
I want to be able to see
how my money is being spent
and use my experience, my contacts
to be able to sway the odds in my favor.
This brings me finally to my
private business investments.
This allows me to mix buying shares
with my own business expertise.
Think Shark Tank and Dragon's Den,
but on a much smaller scale.
I regularly get messaged about
investment opportunities,
and in return for my money and knowledge
they give me a stake in their business.
Recently, one of my connections
out in China contacted me
as he wanted to give me shares
in his new hotel supply business.
This is me and him
at the biggest independent
hotel show in the UK.
He needed someone he could trust
that understood the business landscape
and also spoke English.
He wanted me to help open the
doors and the opportunities
for him in the English speaking market.
He flew me out to China
so we can inspect some
of the supply chain and
also give me a good idea
of what we could offer
our potential clients.
Now the nice thing is, I'm
extending my house at the moment.
So I was able to get all
sorts of building materials
even a nice hot tub.
It's on its way should be nice.
We'll have to do a
video from there one day
but I'm not sure you're
gonna wanna see that one.
It might be X-rated.
This is just one of the ways
that improving your skills
and contacts can be a great investment
as it allows you to
secure a much better deals
than somebody who's just offering cash.
It can even sometimes lead to free shares
in another company.
You're gonna love this next video.
I'm gonna leave it just here
but don't click on it just yet.
You've guessed it, destroy
that thumbs up button.
I really appreciate it.
And finally consider
subscribe to the channel.
If you're interested in
increasing your income,
hopefully I'll see you in the next video.
What are you waiting for?
It's just there.
See you later.