- Hi, it's Mark.
And today I'm gonna be talking
about how I earn money 24 hours a day.
I know it's not by having
some crazy sleep patterns.
I'll leave that to the Navy SEAL.
So you've probably
guessed it from the title.
Let's talk about five of my
favorite passive income sources
and how you can earn an extra
$500 a day, or even more.
Over my years in business,
I have pretty much
come across everyone at a different
passive income strategies.
If you've watched my previous videos,
you'll know that I
started off with nothing,
no qualifications and certainly no money.
But as I slowly came across
people that inspired me
I started using their passive
income ideas in my life.
I'm so grateful to all of
those people that I've met
along the way from the warehouse worker
to the multi-millionaire businessman.
Each one added to my
life in a different way.
Now, if it's all right with you
I'd love to take you on
the same journey as me.
And no matter where you are in your life
you will be able to take advantage
and some tips and tricks
away that apply to you.
And you can use them to
make more money passively
and change your life just like I did.
So if you're ready to take the plunge
buckle up and smash that like button.
But what is passive income?
Now personally, I don't
like the term passive income
as it suggests that
you're going to be making
a ton of money by doing nothing at all.
Where nothing could be really
further from the truth.
When I first heard about it, I thought
it was some kind of scam, you know,
like a get rich quick thing.
I always think when it
sounds too good to be true
it probably is.
Now your teachers at
school, are gonna tell you
to go to university for you
to get the best jobs you can.
But the downside of that
is you have the same 24 hours a day.
So if you truly wanna be rich,
you need to find a way to make money
while others are asleep.
Imagine if you spend a
couple of days working
but you get paid for that work forever
even when you're asleep.
if you want a day off or
you don't feel like working
then it really isn't a problem.
Because with passive income,
the money is still flowing in.
That's what passive income is.
It's still a lot of work,
but so is working a day job.
Passive income just keeps paying you.
The real aim is to have as many different
passive income streams as possible.
So eventually they can cover
all your living expenses
any extra that you make, you can reinvest.
The dream is to invest the money you earn
by working and live off the
money that comes in passively.
You then are able to retire
early if you choose to do so.
In my teens, I came across
my first passive income idea.
I used to visit a warehouse
during my paper rounds as a teenager.
And I would always overhear
the warehouse workers
talking about the stock market.
Every week they'd be
discussing a new investment
they were gonna be making.
I didn't fully understand
until one of the guys
casually mentioned that he
was a part owner of ExxonMobil
which is a massive oil
and gas corporation.
But what got me really interested
was he got paid a
proportion of the profits
in something called a dividend.
Before this, I'd always
thought that the rich
were the only ones that could
invest in the stock market.
But this really opened my eyes to the fact
that anybody can do it with
just a little bit of money.
So let's break it all down.
What exactly is a dividend?
And how can you get involved
with very little money
and start earning some
sweet, passive income?
So when you invest in the stock market
you're buying very small parts
of companies called shares.
These provide companies with
money so that they can use it
in their business to move things forward
and hit their targets.
So you're really valuable to them.
Without shareholders, public
businesses can't operate.
So a dividend is kind of like a reward
a company gives you
for being a shareholder
in their business.
Now not all companies pay a dividend.
It's completely up to
the board of directors.
But if they want a dividend
and they pay themselves,
it means they have to pay you.
And that board of directors
will make that dividend
as long as it makes sense
for their company to do so.
This money is paid out in
cash on a monthly, quarterly
or even a yearly basis.
You might've heard about
you were buying stock low
and selling it high.
But with dividend stock investing,
you never have to sell the
stock to make money back.
How fantastic is that?
This is all great, but how
do you actually get involved?
Imagine I owned a business that sold
I don't know what we got,
coffee mugs, Mark's mugs.
And I was looking for a shareholder
and I came to you and I said,
"look, I need some money
to fund my business.
Would you like to be a shareholder?"
All you got to do is put
a dollar into the mug
and then I will give you
4 cents back every year.
How does that sound?
This is known as a percentage yield.
And in this particular
instance, it will be 4%.
Cause it's 100 cents in a dollar,
a 4 cents dividend.
That's what you're gonna be getting.
I know that sounds quite small amount
but over time that could build up
especially with a few
different investments.
So you'd have thought the
trick is to find the companies
with the highest percentage yield
because you're gonna
get the most money back.
That's what I thought too.
But when you're thinking about investing
it's very important to think long-term.
And a small company that is paying out
lots of money to its
shareholders has less money
it can use to improve its business.
And you can wave goodbye to
that passive income source
as it'll all be cut off.
So when you're looking to invest
make sure to check these things
so that you can make a good
decision for the long-term.
You can find out all this information
on trading apps like Robinhood and Webull.
If you're interested, you
can also get two free stocks
if you sign up with my
link in the description
and deposit $100.
Individual stock
investing is risky though.
So I would highly
recommend diversifying it
at different sectors.
So if something happens to one industry
then you have others to keep you safe.
My main focus now is on low
cost index fund investing
as it's relatively low risk and low effort
but it doesn't give you
as much passive income.
I talk a lot more about index funds
in many of my other videos.
So make sure to check them out.
So it really depends on your goals
and the time you have to
research individual companies.
My second passive income
idea is selling online.
And this came from a technology
whiz kid called Allen.
Now I used to use eBay personally
but I just couldn't get my head around
how I could use it for my business.
One day I bumped into Allen
and this was a little
kid that I used to help
put his LEGO together with.
And I found out he is now
running his own business
grossing over $100,000 per month on eBay.
As you can imagine, I
wanted a little bit of that.
And this rapidly turned
into a major revenue string
which sells my products
all around the globe
every day, 24/7.
There are lots of different
ways to sell products online
as a side hustle, or even as a business.
And you can use platforms
such as eBay or Amazon and many others.
You don't even have to buy the products
because you can do dropshipping.
Which is where you just market the product
and the supplier sends it directly
to the buyer without you
even seeing or touching it.
I prefer using eBay because
I have my own warehouses.
But if I was just starting out
then dropshipping will
be a good side hustle
to improve my marketing
and business skills.
Some good tips for selling
online are basically,
take care of your profit margins
particularly when you're dropshipping.
You need to be sure you're making money
as any fool can give away the product.
But a good entrepreneur always makes money
on every single sale.
And also try and find items
that are either very popular
or very unique because you're gonna sell
so many more of them and
potentially make more money.
And do a better job of marketing
and promoting than your competitors.
Now, this usually involves
writing your own descriptions
and adding personal detailing
and taking better photos.
Even if you have a great product
it will not sell if you
don't market it well.
My best mate Stewart, was the inspiration
for my third passive income idea.
Stewart is an extremely
successful businessman.
We've gone on multiple ski trips
and he's actually been my best
man(chuckling) at my wedding.
For as long as I've known Stewart
he's been investing in property.
Real estate is one of the safest
long-term investments you can have.
And it took me a little
too long to realize this.
Like stocks, I originally
thought I would start investing
in real estate and making passive income
once I had enough money behind me.
But, that couldn't be
further from the truth.
There are so many different ways
that you can make passive income
from real estate without
even buying a property.
So imagine there's a big pot.
So, say something like this.
And everyone wants to
be in the property game
but can't afford to own their own house.
So they put their money in the pot.
Thank you very much.
And we've got some more,
oh, thank you very much.
Just like so.
The person in charge of
the pot, me in this case
can go and take this and choose
a range of properties to invest in.
And once I start renting them out,
you'll be able to share in
the profit of the investment
and what it creates.
This is known as an investment crowdfund.
But even though you know
where your money is, you don't have
a lot of control over it.
If you want more control over a property
then you could always go
the rent to rent route.
This is a pretty simple idea.
Firstly, you find a house or an apartment
in a popular area that you can rent.
Then you have a chat with the owner
to see if he's up for
renting you the property
which you can then go on
to rent to other people.
So you can actually be a landlord
without actually owning the property.
A great way of doing this nowadays
is with online platforms like Airbnb.
People are making millions
using this strategy
but you need to be aware
that the more properties that you take on
the more responsibility you
have for paying the rent.
So it's a good strategy.
As long as you're willing
to take on the risk.
The way I chose to invest in real estate
was to save up a 20% down payment.
Then I purchased a single family home.
As I believed it would give me
the best passive income possible.
And if you're not at the stage
to be able to do that yet
cause you don't have
enough money, start saving.
You only need 10 to 20% deposit.
As an added benefit, the tenants
also pay off your mortgage.
So you're left with a property
that is completely owned by you.
And then you have the ability
to rent it out monthly
bringing you a nice bit of passive income.
My fourth passive income idea
is starting a YouTube channel.
My son has always enjoyed watching YouTube
and he actually grew
his own YouTube channel
which landed him trips all over the world.
With brands like Red Bull at
the age of just 20 years old.
This really showed me the
power of social media.
And recently, when I had a bit more time
I realized that I could make videos
helping people to grow their wealth.
An added benefit was that we
could put ads on the video
to cover my equipment costs
which allows me to make
better quality videos
all through a passive income source.
Actually don't tell him
but we're only 2,000
behind him on subscribers.
So, don't forget to subscribe
and we'll beat him by
the end of this month.
This is something anyone
can do with just an iPhone
and some basic YouTube knowledge
which can all be found for free.
Guess where, on YouTube itself.
Now ads aren't the only way
to make money on YouTube.
Another passive way is
affiliate marketing.
I understand that not everyone
wants to be a YouTuber.
So a good way to make some easy money
will be to film simple
review videos on a product
and ask people to use your
Amazon affiliate link to buy it.
Think of it like Unbox
Therapy, the amount of views
they get on that channel every
day is just mind blowing.
Whenever they buy from your affiliate link
then you'll get paid a small commission.
The most important thing
is that the video content
is always relevant and it
never goes out of date.
So once you've made the video
you could be making
passive income forever.
My fifth passive income idea
is selling digital products
and was inspired by a meeting that I had
with Richard Branson.
You know, the guy that owns Virgin.
I discussed with Richard,
how the world was changing
and how information was becoming
more valuable than gold.
What an age to live in.
Just think about some
of the top companies.
Airbnb has no real estate.
Facebook creates no content
and Netflix isn't even a TV channel.
The internet has truly changed the game.
This simple meeting really
had a dramatic impact
on my life and my business.
As I started to be more open
to new online opportunities
I started selling a digital
flight simulation program.
We only had to create that once
and then we can sell it
hundreds and hundreds
and hundreds of time.
Passively in my sleep, it was perfect.
Here are some ideas that
you can try, create an app.
One of the ones were the in-app purchases.
You've probably seen a lot of YouTubers
promoting Raid Shadow Legends.
I mean, this would be a perfect
brand deal if I had one.
You can upgrade your armor in that,
your weapons, you name it.
There's an upgrade for it
for a little bit of money
and that money is going straight
into the app developers
pocket, because guess what?
He doesn't have to go
out and make a sword.
He doesn't have to go out
and make a new suit of armor for you.
It's just a little bit of code
and he can sell that simple line of code
over and over again.
And how about this?
Not everyone has the time to build up
a social media account.
So if you don't have a lot of money
but you do have a lot of time
you can create a theme page
on Instagram for example.
And then sell that on for a profit
to whoever wants to buy it.
The most important thing to remember
is your most valuable possession
is locked away in your brain.
I'm talking about your knowledge.
Your knowledge is something
that can be packaged
into some kind of online product
and sell that many, many, many times over.
I'm talking about online courses, eBooks
anything that takes a
little bit of time to create
but allows you to sell your
knowledge over and over again.
I've met so many great
people along the way
that have helped me build
my passive income sources.
So, never underestimate
what someone can offer you.
Just because a guy works in a warehouse
does not mean he doesn't have
an angle on the stock market.
And just because someone
used to like sitting
and playing with LEGO
models, it doesn't mean
that he's not gonna grow up
to be a great businessman.
And then he buys SupRemo.
Anyone can surprise
you including yourself.
You're gonna love this next video.
I picked it specifically for you
but don't click on it just yet.
Don't forget to subscribe to the channel,
like the video and ring
that notification bell
so you can grow your wealth.
See you on the other side.