-Hi, it's Mark.
So the world is going crazy.
I'm talking countries in lockdown,
schools shutting, people panicking.
The story is the same every
time there's a global crisis.
Most people panic, they're
all over the place.
Smart people take
advantage of the situation.
That's why these strategies will work
whenever there is fear and panic around.
So today I'm going to be running through
how you can make millions from
the coronavirus market crash
and any recession-causing
crisis in the future.
By having the right finances in place,
I was able to ride out
the last two recessions
and grow my business back to full strength
in an incredibly short amount of time.
Before implemented
anything, make sure to speak
to a financial advisor about
your individual situations.
Let's first break down
what the market crash is
and why it's happening.
Our economy has seen incredible
growth over the last decade.
It is been up, up, up,
but now recently it's come
to an end and it's started to crash.
Now, when companies are making more money
it of course, creates
more demand for jobs.
And when more people have
jobs, they earn more money.
Now this chain of events
is extremely delicate.
If just one link breaks, such
as people not spending money
then the whole system, it
just collapses around us.
We are currently seeing a
chain of events breakdown
on a huge scale, partly
because of the virus
but mainly because of the
mass fear caused by the media.
It's not the end of the world
like the media would like you to believe.
Their main aim is to get more people
watching and reading the news
as they can make more money
from advertising revenue
that they depend on.
On top of this there are
huge disruption problems
to supply chains, especially
people like Apple and Amazon
who depend on all of these
items coming from China.
It causes a trickle down effect.
This is why you may have
seen bare shelves in the shop
and people even fighting
over toilet rolls.
Who would have ever thought that?
Lots of investors see this
unfolding and start to panic.
They sell off stocks and shares.
Now the biggest takeaway from this is that
fear is the number one
enemy of the stock market.
But you know what?
It could be your number one friend.
In situations like
these, you have to adapt
just like a virus.
Look for the opportunity and don't become
paralyzed or over analyze everything.
Be smart and take action.
Even if it's not perfect,
just take that action.
Without any further ado, let's jump in.
Number one, reduce your spending
and build a safety fund.
Be unbelievably stingy, put it all
towards building a safety fund.
If you don't already have one
it's the most important
thing you need to do.
This safety fund should consist
of three to five months
of your living expenses.
And only use in an absolute emergency.
Now this safety fund is
like your protective shield.
You can hold it up, hold
it against everything,
it's going to protect you.
Against unexpectedly getting fired
or if you have a slow month
with your own business.
But most importantly fear won't
affect you in the same way.
Number two, index funds.
Now you have your safety fund,
you can afford to invest the extra money
that you have coming
in into an index fund.
These funds are one of
the safest long-term
Because people are currently scared,
the market has dropped
in value dramatically.
Now my prediction is
the market will be worth
a lot more money in a year from now.
If things start to improve
with the current situation
and people start getting better,
then it will kick start
the chain of events
and the market will
bounce back dramatically.
I wouldn't recommend
this strategy to anyone
that isn't prepared to invest
for at least five years.
Now, one of the most popular index funds
is called the S&P 500.
This is comprised of the
biggest 500 companies in the USA
such as Apple and Amazon and Microsoft.
Now, the amazing thing is that
buying and holding this fund
for a 20 year period has
never lost anyone any money.
Just that sink in, over a 20 year period
it has never produced a negative result.
So come on, Mark, I hear you say.
How do I get started?
Now, I love using Vanguard index funds.
You can just jump in their
website, it's really easy.
Open an account.
You can pick your own risk tolerance.
Now general rule here
is the older you are,
the less risk you should take.
Don't be put off by the complicated words.
Do some extra research
around what funds are best
for you and start investing
consistently each month.
The same amount, just keep invested.
If you can make it
automated, then even better.
Like the saying says the best time to
plant a tree was last year
but the second best is to
do it today and get going.
The main thing to remember is don't panic
when your investment goes down.
Don't even look at it
because if you leave it there
for long enough, you're
going to make a profit.
Now, obviously I don't have time to go
through my exact investing
strategies in this video
but if you'd like to see a video like that
in the future, give this
video the old thumbs up.
Number three, selling shovels.
There are two different
types of entrepreneurs.
Number one, the gold miner.
These are the entrepreneurs that go
out search for the money.
They work hard and tirelessly.
Sometimes making nothing at all.
And other times, being
very, very successful.
This is the type I am in my everyday work.
I look for gaps in the market
and then go sourcing for that item.
hoping that when I'm at a show in Asia
I will spot that nugget of gold
and be able to tie up an exclusive deal
and supply that product to
as many people as I can.
The second is the shovel seller.
These are the entrepreneurs
that supply the tools
that the miners need to make money.
It doesn't even matter if the gold miners
find the gold because
everyone's looking for it
and they need the tools to do it.
This is important because
the current crisis
is causing the demand to shift
and opportunities are being
created in other areas.
Just think about the coronavirus outbreak.
People are having to self isolate,
causing a demand for virtual technology
that allows people to work
from home to skyrocket.
Even school's are turning to
online streaming services,
to teach their students.
So as soon as you can start
creating and selling products
which allow businesses to
continue mining for money
despite this crisis, then
you'll be onto a winner.
Now you may be thinking
that all sounds good during a crisis
but what happens when
everything goes back to normal?
Well, the truth is that
even after all this is over
you will have the greatest
sales pitch in the world.
You know, I could go into many companies
these have been caught off
guard by the coronavirus
show them my product and
tell them that this product
can safeguard them in the future,
should we have another crisis.
Remember, fear is a fantastic motivator.
It's the sole reason why
insurance companies can exist.
They insure against
your fear of your loss.
Without that there wouldn't
be any need for them.
Number four is investing in real estate.
If you have excess cash
then you should consider
investing in real estate.
This is a long-term strategy.
People don't often buy houses
and then sell them straight away.
So I wouldn't worry too much
if your house was to lose
a little bit of value
say over the first six month period.
By buying in a recession when
things are less expensive
and interest rates are low,
over a 10 to 15 year period
you will see a dramatic
return on your investment.
The trick here is to buy low
and if the market is down,
you can squeeze that price.
You only have to wait for the seller
to say yes to your offer.
If they say no, you've lost nothing.
The key to a good
negotiation on real estate
is to take your own emotion
out of the situation.
And with the current situation, really,
people are desperate to sell.
And remember in a recession or crisis,
your cash in your pocket is worth 10 X.
Just as Grant Cardone would say.
So here we are, the big one.
Number five, buying individual stock.
Now, as you've probably
guessed, I've left this,
the most risky option, until last.
I'm not usually too keen
on buying individual stocks
as there is potential
to lose a lot of money.
However, if you can predict the market
is going to do the correct thing,
then there are huge
amounts for you to earn.
Should I say huge?
They are monster rewards to be had.
I invested in individual
shares a few years ago,
but only with the money
I could afford to lose,
which is a really good way to keep
basically your money in check.
I selected three or four different shares
I thought would do well.
And as my luck would have it,
I really did well in two of these shares.
They went through the roof
and ended up increasing 14
times plus at one point.
My general rule on investing
in individual stock
is when everyone is panicking and selling,
it's time to buy.
But on the flip side,
when your Uber driver
or your hairdresser is telling you
how much they're buying, then you sell.
But how do you know what stocks to buy?
When people aren't
flying buy airline stock.
When restaurants are empty,
buy restaurant stocks.
And when the movie theaters are empty
buy movie theater stocks,
it's pretty simple.
Ride that wave until you
see the signs of others
getting in and getting
too confident, then sell.
So remember huge disruption to the economy
causes a lot of pain,
but it also brings massive opportunities
for those that are
prepared to take action.
Keep the faith.
Remember when it all gets going again,
your competition will be playing catch up.
This is your golden time for growing
your personal wealth and your investments.
Now, if you liked that video
then you're going to love this one here
but don't click on it yet.
As always, if you've got any questions,
please leave them in
the comments down below.
And finally consider
subscribing to the channel.
If you're interested in
increasing your income
and hopefully I'll see
you in the next video,
what you waiting for? It's just there.