- Hi guys, it's Mark.
If I had to pin
down one thing that really
helped me become successful
then it would have been all
the little extra jobs I did
on the side from when I was a teenager.
And even through to today.
Having a side hustle helped
me to have extra money
on top of my normal job.
And that had allowed me to save
and invest a lot more money
than would have been possible
from just a nine to five job.
But deciding what side
hustles are the right
one for you can be tricky.
I mean, there's just so
many options out there.
That's why today I'm going to run
through some of my favorite ways
you can make some extra
money at every age.
I'm also going to share with
you my financial targets
I aimed for at each stage.
If you watch the video until the end
you'll know the perfect
side hustle to start
at whatever age you're at
and how you should pivot
and adapt over time to make
the most money possible.
From 13 years old, all
the way up to my age, 33.
I think I got away with that didn't I?
Well just.
Think of it like a Pokemon.
You start small with just a
few skills and then you evolve
and you become more skilled
and a lot more powerful.
Maybe one day you'll be powerful enough to
absolutely destroy that thumbs up button
and subscribe at the same time.
Right, so let's start off
with level one, which is when
you were 13 to 16 years
old, my side hustle target
for this age was around
about 50 to $150 per month.
Of course, this is just a
benchmark for you to aim for
but if you're making more than this
then you're ahead of
where I was at that age.
When I was younger, I
didn't have much money.
So I had to start a side
hustle that was cheap
to get up and running.
I saw this as the perfect
opportunity to try everything
and figured out what I
did and I didn't like.
I also made a lot of mistakes
but you know what, really,
it doesn't matter because
I didn't have much money
to lose in the first place.
All I had was my time.
And I had plenty of that.
My first idea for you is starting
some kind of service based business.
When I was 14, I washed cars.
I used to charge $2 per car, and then $1
if they had a second car, it was great
because the stop costs were really low
and all I needed was a sponge
a bucket and a bit of hard work.
You can also pick up
these pressure washers now
from the home depot,
which only costs $149.
And you could use this to
clean people's driveways.
If you charge $50 per drive
then it's only going to take three jobs
and you've got a jet washer
that's paid for itself.
So everything after that is
a hundred percent profit.
One of my customers worked
for a big chocolate company and as a tip
he would always give me a
massive box full of candy
which I never thought about eating
as I was more interested
in selling it at school.
This is something you can
think about doing as well.
A boy in the UK did this
and he was making over 50K per year
in multiple different schools
until he got shut down.
Wherever there's a
demand money can be made.
At school there was
always a demand for candy.
You may have to check if this
is allowed at your school, but I didn't.
I just got on with it.
You could just sell
this from your backpack
but what I would suggest if it's
really successful is get
your friends to sell it
for you and you can pay
them based on a commission.
So for every candy bar they sell
you could give them 25 cents.
It's amazing how much you
can learn about business
and entrepreneurship by doing
this from a really young age.
It helps you understand how to
manage people and make a profit.
It was definitely a big reason
I fell in love with being an entrepreneur.
The only issue was starting a side hustle
at school is you can only
make money during the week.
So a good way to make some
extra money at the weekend
could be to become a sports referee.
This is a great side hustle as
you get paid to stay fit.
It keeps you mentally strong.
As you have to make decisions quickly and
you get to meet lots
of interesting people.
You can start a $14 and expect to make
around $16 a game, which
ain't bad at all really.
Level two.
This is when you're between
the ages of 16 and 18.
When I was at this level,
I had a much better idea
of what I enjoy doing and what
I really didn't like doing.
I use this time to focus on
getting better at the things I love doing
and developing my skills
in those particular areas.
My side hustle target for this age
was between $250 and $400 per month.
One of the easiest things you
could do is become a tutor.
Let's say you earn around
about $20 per hour, but
if you're not the greatest at
school like me, for example
and you don't think that
option is open for you
then you don't have to
just teach school subjects.
Most people have some kind of skill.
Other people are interested
in learning, and it's all
about finding that skill and
offering to teach it to them.
So like I said, I wasn't
the best at school.
There was no way someone
would pay me $20 to
teach them English.
That's for sure.
So instead I used to teach
people to fly model helicopters.
A bit like this one.
With any tutoring side hustle the money
is always limited to the amount
of clients you can get.
And most of them only
want an hour of your time.
So it's a good idea to find
another way to sell something
of value to your clients as well.
As I was able to make most
model helicopters fly
better by tuning them up.
I decided to offer this as a
service and take their models
home with me after they had a lesson.
So it's all about finding
that win-win for your clients.
A good idea could be
selling your school notes
or charging to be in an online group where
they can ask you questions
whenever they want.
The next side hustle is
drop-shipping and it's great
for anyone that is good with
computers and the internet.
Drop-shipping is where you
advertise someone else's product
send them to an online store.
Then the manufacturer sends
out the product directly
to your customer.
You physically don't have
to touch the product,
which is great.
But Mark, drop-shipping is terrible.
It adds zero value to society.
Do something decent
instead, terrible advice.
Now, hold on, let me explain.
Drop-shipping probably
won't make you a millionaire
like the online gurus
selling courses are going to
tell you the market is
extremely competitive.
The profits are very low
and it's not a great
long-term business model
but I still think it's worth doing
as it's a great way to
learn how to run a business
with very little startup costs.
Drop-shipping is like a trial run.
You're jumping in at the deep end
of an extremely competitive market.
It might take a wall to make a profit
but the skills you are learning
along the way are going to
be worth so much more to you.
In fact, they're going to be worth more
to you than the money
you'll probably make.
Most of the boomers
running huge companies have
no idea how to use social
media to boost their business.
And their physical stores
are going bankrupt.
They're being bought out
by younger entrepreneurs
who have developed these
skills, and they're able to
use those to make the
businesses more profitable
and moving forward into the digital world.
So think of drop-shipping
like a video game
the more you play it, the
better you'll get and the more
valuable skills that you'll
learn and if drop-shipping isn't
for you, but you still want
to learn digital marketing.
Then YouTube is a very,
very similar side hustle.
It's very competitive and
it will focus you to level
up your video production
and your marketing skills
and all you need to start this as a phone
a decent internet connection
and some editing skills.
Right,
so now level three, which is
between 18 and 29 years of age
my side hustle target for this age
was 800 to 1.2k per month.
My main focus was making the most
out of the skills that I had mastered.
Lots of people call this
working in your genius zone.
For the next 10 years or so it's all
about working as smart as possible.
And now you're 18.
You can start investing that
extra money long-term instead
of spending it.
For example, if you
just put $250 per month
into a simple low cost index
fund, at 7% average return
per year, then by the age of
65, you'll have $1.1 million.
And that's just a small part
of your side hustle income.
So it shouldn't affect
your day to day life.
I explained this in my last video.
So make sure to check it
out if you've missed it.
The key here is to look at the
skillset you've been building
up over the last few years and think
about how you can level
them up and charge more.
If you did drop-shipping,
when you were younger
then maybe you could upgrade
to selling your own products or
running social media marketing
adverts for other businesses
You can get paid a lot for
helping other businesses
with their social media marketing.
It's just by hiring you.
They're actually going to
be making more money instead
of losing it.
You effectively pay your own wages
which means you can charge higher prices.
A good way to get your
first client is to offer
to work for them for free for a few weeks
use your skills to boost their sales.
And then they're unlikely
to say no when you
ask them to start paying
you for your skills.
Even if they do say no, you
can go to another business.
You can say, look what I did for them.
I can do that for you too.
And the great thing about
this is you can do it all
from the comfort of your
own home in your spare time.
If you had a YouTube channel,
when you were younger
you could upgrade and
become a graphic designer
or a photographer or videographer.
A friend of mine is a teacher
in Australia and his side
hustle is wedding photography.
And he's booked out every
weekend for next year.
For me, instead of just improving
people's radar control models.
I started building them from scratch.
If you wanted a good quality
radio-controlled model
and didn't have the ability to
be able to build it yourself.
I was the only option in my area.
And this was how I met one of my mentors.
He had seven Ferrari's
and a Bugatti Veyron.
I just loved working in his garage.
I was surrounded by all those cool cars.
And to this day I'd say
I gained more from his words of wisdom
than I charged for the job.
So by upgrading your skills you're able
to start earning a nice
bit of extra income.
And we all like a bit of extra cash.
A great way to use this extra income to
create another side
hustle would be saving up
for a down payment on a duplex
house and getting a mortgage.
This is called house hacking.
It's one of the fastest ways
to increase your net worth
when you're in your twenties.
A duplex has two separate living areas.
And the idea is that you're able to rent
out one side of the house
and live in the other.
By doing this, the other
person pays a big part
of your mortgage for you.
This means you could
end up with a completely
free house when the mortgage is paid off
and you also have a place to stay in
for free and all the money
you would've been paying
on rent you can use to invest instead.
So now the boss level, level
four is for 30 and upwards.
My aim was to shift my side hustles to
make more passive income.
As I had more money to invest
in different opportunities.
By this stage what I valued
more than money was time.
And I wanted more of that
to spend with my family.
At this point, I was
looking to make 1.5 to
3k inside households per month
but I've definitely surpassed that now.
I decided to invest in property.
And to this day, it's one of
the biggest extra income sources.
When I bought my first rental property
it needed loads of work being done to it.
I took on the challenge and
used up all my spare time
I had to fix it up.
With YouTube, you know,
there's really nothing
you can't learn and I was
able to do all the work
and have the house rented
out within six weeks.
Now, of course I get professional
in to fix up house, but
when you're starting off
it's sometimes more
profitable to do it yourself.
And to be honest, it was
definitely a fun challenge.
That first rental property
still pays me a passive income
to this day.
At 30 plus you'd have gained lots
of knowledge that is
valuable to other people.
So you could use this to coach
in areas that you're super confident in.
This could be anything
from carpentry to fitness, to business.
There's a market out there for coaching
everything that you can think of.
The key is to do this
one to the many online,
rather than one-to-one
as you're able to help
more people and not sell your time.
To do this you can
create a digital product
or you could create a YouTube channel that
helps people for free.
Just like I've done.
By working your way through
all of these levels.
You'll have a massive array of skills,
multiple rental properties,
digital products
and a huge investment portfolio.
When you reach this you'd have
passed the tipping point
where your side hustles
are bringing in more than your day job.
This means your money is working
for you and not the other way round.
And this is what the truly rich
have known and done for years.
Now you gonna love this next video.
I'll leave it up here for you
but don't click on it just yet.
Don't forget to subscribe to the channel
ringing that old bell and smash
that like button
I'm also posting daily on Instagram.
So check out over there.
@realmarktilbury
See on the other side.