- Hi, it's Mark.
So, have you ever had $100 in your pocket
and wondered how you
could turn it into 1,000,
10,000, or even $100,000?
Well, sadly, this isn't
something they teach in school.
Come to think of it,
it'd have been pretty awesome if they had.
Because of this lack of
knowledge, it seems pretty scary
for most beginners to
get started in investing.
But in today's video,
I'm gonna simplify the whole process.
Investing my money allowed me
to become a multimillionaire,
and guess what I started with?
That's right, $100.
Well, probably less
than that, to be honest.
I'm not saying becoming rich is easy,
but by taking calculated risks,
you'll be able to grow
your wealth over time.
I understand that everyone has
a different risk tolerance,
so today I'm gonna be revealing
how to invest for beginners with $100.
And as we go through the video,
the risk is going to increase,
but remember, as the risk goes up,
so does the potential reward.
I'll also be putting my
money where my mouth is
and investing $100 into
each one of these options
so you can see exactly how to do it.
I'm just about to invest in something
I never thought I'd actually do.
Here goes.
When someone asks me how
they should invest $100,
I usually say, invest in yourself.
You can do this by buying books
and improving your skills,
but assuming you've already done this,
now we're gonna be talking
about the specific places
you can actually put your money.
Now, I'm a businessman.
I'm not a financial advisor.
These are just some of the ways
I've invested my money over the years,
and they've worked for me.
You can also sit back and relax,
because I'm not gonna try and
sell you anything at the end.
Just remember, if you enjoy the video,
then smash that like button,
because it really helps push
this video out to more people,
and also consider subscribing
if you want to grow your wealth.
The first investment is a
high interest savings account.
This is a one out of 10 on the risk scale,
so the lowest possible
risk that you can have.
Nowadays, it's extremely hard
to find any savings account
that will pay a substantial
amount of interest,
but that's not the main
reason it's on the list.
By putting your money
into a savings account,
you're actually starting to create
what I like to call an emergency fund,
which I believe everyone should have.
This is money that you can access
if something unexpected comes up,
and it's extremely low risk.
And by having money on hand,
you can avoid getting into debt
and having to pay crazy fees back.
I remember when I bought
my first apartment,
I had a minor crisis
after about two months,
as the hot water system went
wrong and it needed replacing.
Because of my emergency
fund, it saved me over $200,
as I didn't have to
take out a payday loan.
When you leave your money in the bank,
it slowly loses its value,
so when I am looking for
the best savings account
to combat this, I look for two things.
The first, of course,
is a good interest rate,
which depends on the economy, mostly.
The second thing is having the ability
to access my money instantly.
Some banks that are
really worth looking at
and consistently have
a good rate of interest
are Ally Bank, Marcus by
Goldman Sachs, and Citibank.
I currently have an account
with Marcus by Goldman Sachs,
and their interest rate is
0.7%, which isn't very high,
but is currently one
of the best available.
So, there we go, nice and easy,
$100 deposited into my savings account.
Now for gold, often
referred to as a safe haven.
I'll give this also a two
out of 10 on the risk scale.
Did you know that,
since the creation of the
Federal Reserve in 1913,
the U.S. dollar has lost 95% of its value?
So, you're actually only left with 5%
of its original purchasing power.
So, if you want to stop
your money losing value,
then maybe gold is for you.
If you had a hundred dollar
nugget of gold in the year 2000,
it would now be worth approximately $580.
The piece of gold hasn't
actually changed in size.
It's still the same piece of metal,
but what has actually changed
is the value of your dollar
to how much gold you can buy with it.
Gold was actually our original currency
used by our forefathers.
I remember those days well.
It's perfect, as it can't be manufactured
and it lasts for thousands
and thousands of years.
So, if you've ever
watched "Gold Rush" on TV,
you'll know how hard it is
to actually mine this stuff
out of the ground.
Now, you may be wondering,
if it's so safe,
why have I given it a two
out of 10 on the risk scale?
It all comes down to opportunity cost.
You have to ask yourself
if you really want
to just protect your hundred
dollars against inflation
or if you want to invest
it in other opportunities
which could make it grow a lot quicker.
If you invest in gold, then
you will be missing out
on these potential profits,
making it a little bit risky.
I would say that this is
the perfect investment
if you have a lot of money already,
and all you want to do is just protect it.
There are two different ways
that you can invest in gold.
The first way would be to
actually buy physical gold,
but if I bought jewelry, I don't know,
gold bars, coins, and that sort of thing,
I'd probably be paying too much,
because the person selling it
would want to make a profit,
which means I would be paying more
than the true value of the gold itself.
The alternative is to invest
in gold within a broker app,
like Robinhood in the USA,
or Trading 212 in the U.K.
Then you're able to buy
gold at its true value
and have the option to sell much quicker.
In the USA, I would look for
the GLD ETF on Robinhood,
which is one of the largest
gold ETFs in the world.
As of June 2020, they hold over
36.49 million ounces of gold
in vaults all around the world.
As I'm currently in the U.K.,
I'm gonna invest using Trading
212 in a similar share.
And with just a click of
a button, there you go.
I'm now Mr. Gold Man.
If that doesn't sound
exciting enough for you,
then why don't you try a
simple low cost index fund?
I'll give this a three out
of 10 on the risk scale.
If you invested just $100 per month
into an index fund with
a 7% annual return,
then after 30 years, you'd have $123,000.
That's the power of compound interest.
You can do all of this
without having any knowledge
of the stock market.
I remember when Warren Buffett,
one of the richest men in the world,
placed a million dollar bet
that a simple S&P 500 index fund
would outperform a professionally picked
portfolio of hedge funds
over a 10-year period.
Now, this contest wrapped up in 2017,
and the results were made public.
Warren Buffett had actually
won a million dollar bet,
which really shows the
power of index funds
and that the everyday
person can take on the pros
with little to no knowledge.
Imagine an index fund is
like a bag of Haribo gummies.
The machine in the factory puts a range
of the most popular candy into one bag
so you can enjoy the best of the best
without having to pick and buy
each and every one individually.
Now, just replace the
candy with companies.
That's what an index fund is.
You can buy your own selection bag
of the most popular
companies in the world,
such as Apple, Microsoft,
Amazon, and Facebook,
and your money is split
between all of them.
Now, let's go back to the Haribos.
Imagine you left these on the side
and they're open for a few days or so.
They'd go hard and they
certainly wouldn't taste as good,
would they?
But by putting them in a container,
you can stop that from happening.
This is very much like index funds,
as if you leave them unprotected,
the government will start taxing you
on the profits you make,
but you can protect them
with a sort of container like this,
which is known as different
things in different countries.
In America, it's called a Roth IRA,
and in the U.K., it's an ISA.
These containers allow you to
protect your money after tax,
and then any profits you
make are yours to keep,
but because they're so good
and they're so powerful,
there's a cap on how much
you're allowed to invest each year.
So, if I was you, I
would take full advantage
as soon as possible and
max out your allowance.
There are more in depth
strategies you can use,
but for the purpose of this video,
I'm gonna be investing $100
into an S&P 500 index fund,
which, over the last 20 years,
has an average yearly return of 7%.
Drop a like if you'd like a
full video covering this topic,
'cause there's so much on
this we could talk about.
But Mark, $100 isn't enough,
as the S&P 500 is over $3,000 a share.
Well, you don't actually have
to buy a full share to invest.
My favorite brokers are Fidelity,
Charles Schwab, and Vanguard.
So, if we head over to
Vanguard's website now,
and we find the S&P 500,
here you can see what
companies are in the index fund
so you can buy the right one.
So, all you have to do
is create an account.
I already have one,
and deposit some money,
and then click, there you go.
Job done.
The fourth way to invest
is in a real estate investment trust,
otherwise known as a REIT.
I'll also give this a three
out of 10 on the risk scale.
Now, imagine your friend
collected $100 from 3000 people.
He will have $300,000.
Then he takes this money
and he buys a property.
He rents it out and splits
it with all 3000 people
that helped him buy the property,
which helps them start generating
some of that sweet passive income.
That's the basic way of explaining a REIT.
It lets everyone benefit from investing
in income-producing properties
without actually buying one.
Think of it like buying a
small share in a property.
Let's say you own the front door,
someone else owns the windows,
and a few other people own all the bricks,
but all together, you own the property.
Equity REITs own things like offices,
shopping centers, apartments,
hotels, and much more,
and they get their
income through the rent.
By law, they have to pass
on 90% of all profits
to the investor, like a dividend.
However, they're taxed
a little differently.
The cool thing is that,
at the start of 2019,
the 10-year average return for REIT ETFs
did better than the S&P 500,
with an average return of 10%.
If you're in the USA, by investing
in the VGSLX by Vanguard,
you can average a 12% return,
which beats the average
real estate investor.
How awesome is that?
As I'm in the U.K., I'm gonna
use the Trading 212 website
to put $100 into a similar REIT.
It has high global diversification,
meaning I can invest
in all the up and coming property
markets around the world.
The next option is
buying and selling items.
The risk on this really depends
on how good you are at
finding great deals,
but I'll give this a, I don't know,
four out of 10 on the risk scale.
The good thing about doing this is that
you can buy and sell something
that you're interested in
and have knowledge about,
which can lead to bigger possible returns.
Now, I'm going to invest my $100
in either pre-owned
radio control model gear
or golf equipment.
Both of these I've got an interest in,
so I should have a reasonable idea
of what each item is worth.
Pokemon cards would be a great area
to have some expertise in,
as their value at the
moment is skyrocketing.
Logan Paul just bought a
Charizard card for over $150,000.
How mad is that?
So, I've been on Facebook marketplace,
as most people have
access to that platform,
and I found myself a model engine
that I'm gonna go and try and buy.
It's up for 75 pound,
which is approximately 100 U.S. dollars.
We've sent a few messages back and forth
and I'm gonna go and have
a look at the item now.
(gentle music)
Hello there, I've come about the engine.
- Oh, yeah, here you go.
- Oh, in the box as well!
Cool, that's good.
- Yeah, it's all boxed.
- Cool, that's right.
So, would you take 70 for it?
- Nah, I've got 75.
In its box, in good condition.
- Can you do a bit better?
- I'll tell you what I can do.
There you go, I'll throw that in.
- Really?
- That's what it came out of.
75 quid.
- That's a deal.
- Okay, a deal then.
- Here you go.
I'll give you 75 quid.
- Lovely, thank you very much.
- We're videoing this
for our YouTube channel.
Do you mind?
- Oh, no, that's fine.
- All right then, see you again.
Thanks a lot.
Thanks for that.
So, I've done a listing on
eBay for the model engine,
and the model plane, I'm
gonna actually advertise
on a specialized website for model flying,
as I'm sure I'll be then
selling to the right people
and hoping for big profits.
Now we're starting to get serious.
It's time for individual stocks.
This gets a 6.5 out of
10 on the risk scale.
There's a certain amount of risk
that comes with investing
individual stocks,
but if you pick your companies well,
then it can be really exciting,
as there's the potential
to make a lot of money.
During the dot.com boom back in 1995,
I was really lucky to
pick a few great stocks,
which I cashed in and
I made a lot of money
in a very short period of time.
When the bubble burst, some of
the companies I'd held on to,
which had cost me very little,
went completely out of business.
Luck and timing can be a very crucial part
of stock investing.
I've picked these stocks using
what's called fundamental analysis,
which means I looked at the
business financial statements,
their market, and also the
leadership of their companies.
Back then, this was a lot of work,
but now it's easily found
out on Yahoo! Finance.
A while ago, I read an
article about an experiment
where they simulated 100
monkeys throwing darts like this
at the financial page of a newspaper.
The stocks the monkeys picked
on average outperformed
the so-called smartest hedge
fund managers on Wall Street.
So, for this video, I thought it'd be fun
to put this theory to the test.
I don't have a monkey, so
I thought I have to do.
So, I'm gonna throw a dart at the board,
and as you can see, I randomly
selected 20 different stocks,
and wherever the dart lands,
that's what I'm going to invest in.
Now, I've just got to put on a blindfold.
Okay, here we go.
- Oh, you hit it.
- Right,
let's see what we got.
And we've gone into Samsung.
Right, so I'm gonna jump straight
onto my brokerage account
and set an order for Samsung.
If you want to invest your
$100 in individual stock,
then Webull are currently
giving away three free stocks
for a limited time when you
deposit $100 into your account.
I'll just leave the
link in the description
if you want to pick up those free stocks.
So, now we're gonna be
moving into the realm
of gambling and speculation
rather than investing.
Number seven is cryptocurrency.
This is a nine out of
10 on the risk scale.
So, you've probably heard of Bitcoin.
This is currently the most
popular type of crypto.
If you'd have bought $100
worth of Bitcoin in 2015,
today it would have been
worth around about $5,000.
That's a 5000% return on your investment,
and that's pretty unheard of.
Therefore, many people
that invested in Bitcoin
in the early days became
millionaires overnight,
but a lot of people also lost money.
If you'd invested around
$100 in December 2017,
when Bitcoin was at an all-time high,
by December 2018, you'd
have had less than $17 left.
So, really, no one really
knows what it's gonna do next.
It's extremely risky, but
still very attractive,
because it has the potential
to make you millions.
There are three main types of cryptos.
These are Ethereum, Ripple, and obviously,
the big one, Bitcoin, but let's
just focus on Bitcoin today.
If you want to learn more
about other types of coins,
you can read something
called a white paper,
and it will give you all the details.
The cool thing about Bitcoin is that
it uses something called blockchain,
and it isn't regulated by the government.
You also can't create any more Bitcoins,
which makes inflation
absolutely impossible.
In my opinion, this investment
will probably only make sense
if you're investing an extra $100
that you don't really need,
so I'm gonna jump onto the
most popular Bitcoin app,
which is called Coinbase and
invest my $100 in Bitcoin
and forget about it.
By the way, if you wanted
to give this a try,
I'll put a link to Coinbase
in the description down below
and you can pick up $10 of free Bitcoin.
At least that gives you
a bit of a headstart.
The last is definitely a full on gamble.
You may have guessed it
already, it's the lotto.
This is definitely a 10
out of 10 on the risk scale
and isn't something I
would recommend doing.
However, I thought I'd include
it in this investing video,
as so many people choose to do it.
In fact, 57% of all Americans
buy at least one lotto ticket per year.
The chance of actually
winning is one in 14 million,
which might sound quite possible,
but let me just try and put
that into a bit of perspective.
You're 4,000 times more
likely to win an Oscar
than win the lotto.
Millions of people lose
their money every year,
but they keep playing,
as the rewards are sky high if you win.
I'm just about to invest in something
I never thought I'd actually do.
Here goes.
Can I have a hundred
scratch cards, please?
Lovely, thank you very much.
Thank you, help.
Cheers, now.
Thanks, bye.
As you can see, this is
gonna take me quite a while.
I'm gonna leave a counter on the screen
so you can see how much I've spent
versus how much I've heard
back from my investment.
Let's do this.
(playful music)
I hope there's a bit more in this lot.
There's gotta be, hasn't there?
So, we're halfway through.
The most we've earned so
far is $3 on one ticket.
I'm gonna need some help.
I've got 50 more to go.
Come on, Curtis.
I know you've been itching
to have a go at this.
Have you got your coin ready?
- I do, ready.
- Let's race to see, wait for it,
who can find the most money
in the remaining 50 cards?
Ready?
- Okay.
- On your marks.
Get set.
Go!
(upbeat music)
♪ Y'all ready to go ♪
♪ Come on ♪
♪ Let's do it ♪
- $15.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- No.
- Oh, wow, $15.
- $15.
- He's only just started doing this.
He's got more than me.
- I've beaten you already.
(upbeat music)
Find a 2x to win two times.
- There must be.
$10, we think.
- Is that $10?
- $10.
I think so.
- What have you got?
- You say you're smashing me,
but I'll tell you what, how about this?
How about this, another dollar.
(upbeat music)
♪ Y'all ready now, I'm making my move ♪
♪ Better stand back,
'cause I'm coming though ♪
- I'll tell you what,
this has got to be an
astonishing last four cards
if we're gonna get any
money back from this.
So, we just came back
and we double checked it.
We made back $50 from our $100 investment.
Now, you may think that
sounds pretty good,
but that's actually a negative 50% return.
This was meant to be a little bit of fun,
but it's pretty sad to think
that people play this regularly
and on average are losing half their money
when they could pick any one
of the other investments in this video
and have a much better
chance of being successful.
I hope this has taken
some of the mystery away
from the other forms of
investing and made them
a little bit more
understandable for beginners.
If you'd like me to make
a part two of this video
to see how these investments
have done over a month,
then make sure to smash
that thumbs up button
to let me know.
I'm gonna leave the next video here,
but don't click on it just yet.
Remember to subscribe to the channel
and ring that notification bell
so you don't miss out on part two.
Okay, I'll see you on the other side.