Hi, guys, it's Mark.
So, I've got a secret,
and it's about time we talked about it.
This is my crystal ball
and it allows me to protect everything
the stock market's going
to do in the future.
Look, if anyone tells you
that, never believe them.
They're probably just trying
to sell you one of those courses for $997.
So, even though there's no magic ball
that can tell you when to buy a stock
before it rockets in value
and makes you a millionaire overnight,
there is certainly a few things I do
to tip the odds in my favor,
and that's what I'd like to
share with you guys today.
As I've got older and slightly grayer,
I found that knowing the reason
behind why a stock might change in price
help me make and save a lot of money.
If you're new to the stock market,
then a stock is a small part of a company,
and when you buy it, you
actually become a part owner.
The idea is to buy parts of a company
that you believe will go up in value
so you're able to multiply your money
without doing any extra work.
But let's face it,
investing in the stock market
can be pretty confusing,
and most people just
pick companies on a whim,
however, that's not how I do it.
So, by the end of this video,
you'll know my actual strategies
for picking great stocks.
And don't worry.
I won't be trying to sell you anything,
so you can just sit back and relax.
So, there are two main ways
to attempt to predict the stock market.
These are called technical
and fundamental analysis.
A good way to think about
this is like a scale.
Usually, short-term day traders
are purely focused on technical aspects.
These include looking
at charts and patterns.
They believe that they can
predict how the stock will change
in price by judging the highs
and the lows on the graphs.
They're the geeky ones.
Nah, I'm only kidding.
It's just not how I do it.
My whole investment strategy
is about keeping it simple.
Lots of people talk about
using margin and options,
but that's really not
something I worry about.
I'm a long-term investor,
so this means I'm a lot more focused
on the fundamentals of a company.
This includes the
financials, the leadership,
and the brand recognition,
as I believe this is
where the information lies
to indicate the long-term
success of a stock.
However, like I mentioned, it's a scale,
so I do pass my eye over
the occasional chart
in order to find the best time to buy.
This approach has helped me
to find some really good
investments over the years,
rather than just dipping in and out
and trying to make a
profit on a daily basis.
The amazing thing is the majority
of professional traders are still unable
to be a low-cost index
fund over the long term.
This may sound quite complicated
but it's actually very simple.
So, this bucket represents
an individual stock,
and the water is me
pumping all of my money into that company.
This represents an index fund,
each cup being a different company,
and the water I'm putting in
is the money I'm spreading
between each of them
in one easy investment.
For whatever reason,
if this company goes
bankrupt, then guess what?
All my money goes down the drain.
Now, this is the same company
and it still goes bankrupt,
but the good thing is
I might lose my money
in that small investment,
however, I've got so many more stocks
and I've done really well in some of them,
which means I've actually
made a profit overall.
My favorite index funds track the S&P 500
which are the top 500
public companies in the USA.
So, even though the majority of my money
goes into index fund investing,
I also have a lot of fun
picking individual stocks
and watching my portfolio grow.
On this note, if you'd like
an easy way to get started,
Public are currently
giving away a free stock
worth all the way up to $50
when you fund your account.
If you want to pick that up,
I'll leave a link in the description,
and if you're in the UK,
Freetrade are giving away a free stock
that could be worth up to 200 pound
when you deposit it as
little as two pounds.
I'll leave that link below as well.
It's a great way to get started
with individual stocks,
and basically, it's free money.
Right, so now you've got your free stock
and you're ready to invest into some more,
but where should you start?
Well, if you're anything like me,
it makes sense to start with the numbers.
We call this quantitative analysis.
Whenever I'm thinking about
investing in a company
I make sure to look at
all these figures first.
If the financials don't look good to me,
then it's very rare
that I'll do any further
research into the company.
It's kind of like when you
go on a first date with someone
and they seem really nice,
however, it isn't until you really start
getting to know all the details about them
that you might start
to notice their flaws,
like eating with their mouth
open or picking their nose.
If only they gave you a
non-biased comprehensive list
of how they actually are
so you can make an educated decision
whether you want to date them or not.
I don't have a solution to this problem,
but luckily that's
exactly what companies do.
It's brilliant.
You can find out this information
for free on Yahoo! Finance,
which is the website that I use.
There are three main
aspects that I look at.
First, let's break down the balance sheet.
I know it doesn't sound too
interesting, but trust me,
this is where you find some
of the real juicy information.
The whole purpose of this
sheet is in the name:
to balance assets and liabilities.
Think of it a bit like this.
You may own a watch or rental property,
and these are your assets,
but let's say you have
loads of credit card debt.
This is one of your liabilities,
so let's break down some
of the gobbledy-goop terms
so you can easily understand
this complicated-looking sheet
and impress your friends.
Assets are broken down
into three categories.
Current assets are things
that could be turned
into cash within 12 months.
Longer-term assets
are things like their headquarters
which they usually don't sell in a hurry.
Companies can also have assets
that you can't physically touch
known as non-tangible assets,
such as the brand recognition
of an established business
that has been trusted for generations.
I like to think of Coca-Cola.
And then we come to the liabilities,
and what I'm really interested in here
are the current liabilities
as this is the debt that they'll
need to repay within 12 months.
With this, there is a simple calculation
you can do to easily know if the company
is high-risk or not,
and that is total current assets divided
by total current liabilities.
A good rule of thumb here
is the numbers should be above one,
but how does this work in practice?
Let's take Apple's balance
sheet, for example.
Apple's total current assets
divided by their total current liability
comes to 1.4 when rounded up.
This is great as now we know that Apple
are able to pay off all
their short-term debt
nearly 1-1/2 times.
The second document is really
important to have a look at
is the income statement.
If you've ever heard the saying
of the top and bottom line,
this is where it comes from.
At the top of the statement,
this is the total revenue,
which is the total the business take,
and at the bottom is the net income,
which is the money that the company makes
after all the expenses have been deducted.
Every business has these expenses,
the cost of operation
and the cost of revenue.
So, let's take a simple business
like a smoothie company.
Their cost of revenue is fruit.
They can't make their
smoothies without buying that.
Therefore, that is a cost
they have no choice about.
It's a simple fact of
running their business,
but the next thing they
do have a choice about,
which is their operating expenses:
who they're hiring
and what kind of wages
that they're paying them.
After these expenses are deducted
from the total amount of money
they take for their customers,
you get the operating income.
So, here's my simple calculation
that lets me know if
the business is healthy:
operating income divided
by total revenue times 100.
Ideally, I look for above 15%.
Using Apple again,
let's take this number
divided by this number,
and we get 27%, which is great.
The last one of the big three
is the statement of cashflow.
I'm not going to spend
too much time on this one
as when you boil it down,
it's pretty simple.
The main thing I look out for
is if the company I'm investing in
has increased in free
cashflow year on year,
which is money they can use
to reinvest all payback to investors.
A big red flag here is sometimes
I see the cash flow is negative
but the company's still paying dividends
back to its investors.
It's just unsustainable,
and eventually the business
is just going to run out of cash.
Now, once I've had a good
look at all these numbers,
it's time to get into the juicy stuff,
and that's all about analyzing
the qualities of a company.
This is known as qualitative analysis.
One of the qualities I look
for is brand recognition.
When I say the word Apple,
most people think about the
company rather than the fruit.
I know I keep referring to it,
but it's a great example
of amazing brand recognition
that won't be going away anytime soon.
Being a household brand name
comes with a lot of consumer trust,
so when they launch a new product,
people are much more likely to try it out,
especially if it's something
unique or groundbreaking,
such as the iPad.
- And we'd like to show it to
you today for the first time,
and we call it the iPad.
(audience cheering)
- This helps companies
like Apple shape our future
and create entire new
markets and revenue streams.
Another great example of
brand awareness is Coca-Cola.
It's the second-most recognized word
in the world after okay.
- Mm-kay.
- Something that really affects
price movements is the news.
I always keep an eye on it,
and in particular rumors on social media.
You may have heard about
the whole GameStop situation
where a small bunch of retail investors
managed to outsmart the top hedge funds
by finding a flaw in their strategy.
They were able to use
this to their advantage
and earn a lot of money.
- [Anchor] Tonight, it's Wall
Street's David versus Goliath.
The struggling video
game retailer GameStop
skyrocketing about 8000% over six months.
- But once the news broke
and more people started to
jump onto the bandwagon,
the big profits had already been made.
This is a great example
of the age-old saying,
"buy the rumor, sell the news."
I learned this valuable lesson
during the dot-com boom in the '90s.
When I started investing,
people were amazed that
I was pouring money
into companies whose main
asset was a .com domain name.
However, within six months,
it seemed that everyone's telling me
that they were buying
shares in.com companies,
even my hair dresser.
I decided to start selling
to buy more real estate just
weeks before the bubble burst,
and I managed to save the
majority of my profits.
Others weren't so lucky.
Everyone thought that internet
businesses were the future,
and they were eventually right,
however, most of the original
companies never recovered,
and I saw some of my friends make millions
just to lose 90% of their investment
when everything crashed.
Only a handful of companies
managed to weather the storm,
such as Amazon.
This showed me that the
hype generated by the news
and other people talking about it
really just caused the prices
to get out of control
and become unsustainable.
So, whenever I feel like hype
is driving the price
of a particular stock,
I know that it probably isn't
a great long-term investment.
Although, with the dot-com bubble,
it is true that a lot of
companies did rebound eventually.
The next important factor is
the leadership of the company,
even more so nowadays with social media,
and what the leaders say
is having a huge effect
on the price of the stock.
A prime example of this is Elon Musk,
who is very clearly the visionary
behind all of his companies,
one of them, of course, being Tesla.
Just imagine if Elon Musk
decided he was bored
of making electric cars
and tweeted that he were
standing down from Tesla
to focus on SpaceX and his
mission to colonize Mars.
I think this reliance on Elon Musk
is one of Tesla's greatest strengths,
but also one of its greatest weaknesses,
as the company is highly
affected by his actions.
This brings me to my next point,
which is to look out for
emerging future industries
like electric vehicle technology,
which Tesla is leading the way in.
These types of investments
are really your growth stocks.
My friend, Simon Squibb
often tells me he believes
that in the future,
doctors will be replaced
by artificial intelligence.
This sounds like the
stuff of science fiction,
however, when I was younger,
this was what I used to see on Star Trek.
- Spock.
- [Spock] Spock here.
- In fact, this is even better.
I actually first heard of Tesla
when it was featured
on "Top Gear" in 2008.
It wasn't a very flattering review
as they showed the car running
out of batteries in 50 miles,
which was only a quarter
of the advertised range.
Elon wasn't very happy about this
and he actually later filed
a lawsuit against the show.
However, the segment
certainly piqued my interest
and I could see they were onto something.
During my time investing,
I've seen a huge shift in each sector.
- Oh, it's the American on Sectorus.
- Let me take you back
to when I was younger,
if you can imagine that far back.
I remember sitting at my grandma's house
and watching this guy come along
with a sack of coal on his back,
which he would deliver to my grandma
so she could heat her house.
Nowadays, most people use
gas, so no more Mr. Coal Man,
and this sector is all set to change again
with the introduction of
renewable electricity.
But that's three major shifts
that I'll experience in my lifetime.
If I'd been stuck in my ways
and not taking notes to these changes,
then my investments would
have been left in the past,
just like the coal industry.
So, before investing in a stock,
I always think about whether
a future shift in sector
will have a positive or
negative impact on that company.
But how do I predict when
the best time to buy is?
You don't,
but there's a strategy I
use to get around this,
and it's called dollar cost averaging.
Let's imagine you were
to invest once a month
for three months.
Month One, the stock might cost you $200,
Month Two, $150,
and Month Three, $130.
Of course, if you knew it
was going to dip to $130,
you'd have bought then,
however no one knows how
low the price will go.
But by doing this,
instead of investing all
your money in Month One
when your stock was at $200,
you actually lower your
average buying price to $160.
This is also known as buying the dip.
Instead of getting scared and selling
like the majority of people would,
the idea is to buy more,
because it's like having a garage sale,
and if you've done all your research
and you like the company,
then the stock is at a bargain price.
So, I'm going to leave the
next video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe for more videos
and pick up your free
stocks with the links below.
Okay, I'll see you over there.