Hi guys, it's Mark.
So investing is the best
way to build your wealth,
especially if you start at a young age.
Believe it or not, it only takes the price
of a coffee a day invested early enough
to become a millionaire.
On that note, about a month ago,
I gave Laura $1,000 to
invest, however she liked.
She'd never done anything
like this before,
and you guys loved it so much
that you've been asking for an update.
So, here it is!
Firstly, we discussed how to
overcome the fear of investing
because it's all about getting started.
- Not really for me.
I don't really know much
about it. Bit risky.
- Next we'll be revealing
how much money she made.
- Today, I put £240 in
and it's now worth...
- And finally, unpacking
her plans for the future.
- Not many girls, I feel
like, are investing into it.
I kind of like to be there and go,
"No, we can do it as well."
- Watching this video all the way through
will put you in the best position
when it comes to making
money from investing,
as we're gonna be showcasing real results
with realistic amounts of money.
So make sure to smash
that thumbs up button
for the Altube Yougorithm
and we'll get started straight away.
Hi, Laura. How are you?
- Hi. Good, thank you.
Thanks for having me back.
- Yeah, you're more than welcome.
D'you know what? It's
been a couple of months
since we've started
this investing journey.
- That's gone so quickly.
- It certainly has.
So what I really wanna know is
what did you actually
think about investing,
and what are your thoughts on it?
- So, before I kind of started,
I was a bit apprehensive about it.
Didn't know much about it at all.
But the best way to start
learning more and more
and become really invested in
the whole investment process,
is to actually start, so that was great
that you gave me the
ability to start doing that.
I think it's just the unknown,
and the whole link, it kind
of seems a bit like gambling.
I think you have to just
kind of build the trust in it
and learn for yourself,
and know that if you
invest and you lose some
then you can live with that.
- So it's more of a
misunderstanding isn't it?
And probably because it's
not being taught in schools,
to give people the confidence
to go ahead and to do it.
And what about your friends as well?
Because that's another
key thing, isn't it?
So have you spoke to any of your friends
about the investing?
- I have a little bit.
I know I mainly spoke
to my brother about it
and I got him, I was trying
to get him to sign up
for a free share and then,
it's just the signing up process for him.
- Yeah.
- So he just, once he signed
up I think it'll be fine.
And I was going, "Look,
Mark and Curtis do this.
It's absolutely fine."
Yeah. It's just building that trust.
And I think, as he sees
whether my investments
have done well and things like that,
I think he's just keeping
a little sneaky eye on mine
and then he might do it himself as well.
- Yeah, I think that's
always a bit of a shame
to look at it that way,
from the way he's looking
at your investments
and only gonna go into
them, if they go up.
I think he's, people need to look at them
as a very long-term thing
that you'll put your money
into over a period of time.
So maybe you can give him a nudge and say,
"Look, don't wait," 'cause
there's no time in the market,
it's time in the market that you need.
You've gotta stay in there.
- You've also, actually,
just reminded me of something
he said the other day.
He said, whether he was a
bit too late to the Tesla?
So I don't know whether, 'cause
there are so many stories
about people having shares
and coins and things,
and then it goes up
exponentially and then,
they wonder whether it's gonna
plateau or go down from here.
There's...
- Well that's the whole thing
about time in the market.
Nobody really knows where the market's
gonna physically go.
Now if you take Tesla as a prime example,
if I said to you, Tesla's gonna be $2,500
this time next year,
would it be too late to invest?
No, exactly.
So, we don't know where it's gonna go
and trying to time that market
will mean you'll never actually get in
because the excuse to get in will be,
"Oh, the market's too high,"
and the other excuse will be,
"Oh, it's falling. I don't wanna
get in while it's falling."
So there's always an excuse not to invest,
and that generally stems around people
trying to time the market.
So, I think you might need
to have a word with him.
- I will, I feel bad now. Sorry, Michael.
(they laugh)
- So you mentioned a free stock there
and that's a really
good way to get started.
And we've partnered up
with Public.com in the USA,
who are actually offering you a free stock
worth all the way up to a $1000
when you sign up.
And if you're in the UK,
you can sign up to Freetrade
and they're offering a free stock
worth all the way up to £200.
It's basically free money
and I'll leave the links
in the description below,
if you're interested in getting started.
Let's talk about stocks.
Can you remind us all,
'cause we all wanna know,
what stocks you bought?
- Yeah, so I bought Tesla and an S&P 500.
- Okay. So how are they performing?
- They're actually doing really well.
I feel like there's been a little boom
in the market at the moment, so.
- Okay. Well remind us how
much you invested first of all
in each stock.
And then we can see where
it's gone from there.
- Okay. So, in Tesla I put
£200 and it's now worth -
(cash register rings)
£341.82.
- Wow.
So the gain is £141.82,
which is, in dollars, $190.
- That is unbelievable, isn't it?
- I know, it's crazy.
- And how much work did
you actually need to do
to generate that money?
- Absolutely nothing, apart from checking
every now and then,
'cause I got so excited,
and goes up and down, up and down,
and then it kind of went up.
- And that's really because
they've come to an agreement with Hertz
to supply them 100,000 electric vehicles,
and that's the equivalent
of a $4.2 billion deal.
Not only that, in Europe
over the last three months,
Tesla Model 3 is the best selling car.
Not the best-selling electric car,
the best-selling car, period.
So, you know, what great news
when you've got shares in Tesla.
- Yeah, definitely.
I can kind of tell as
I'm driving on the roads,
I see more and more Teslas
pop up everywhere, so.
- Well it used to be a
rare sight didn't it?
I remember when I first
suggested to Curtis
that we get a Tesla,
that it was like, "Well,
no one's driving 'em.
Never see any of them about.
They can't be that popular."
And we really did look, you know,
and you only saw them now and again.
Now it's, they are literally
everywhere aren't they?
And they've got a good charging network,
that's all I can say.
That certainly helps the Tesla brand
because you know you can charge up quickly
and it's, yeah it just works.
We're really happy with ours
and it seems that it's the growing thing.
- Yeah, definitely.
And the kind of move in the
future to all-electric cars,
I know that's kind of been
pushed back again recently, but yeah.
- And that gain is in a
two-month period as well,
which is outstanding isn't it?
I mean, again, we'll talk
later about other investments
but I think that is certainly
a hard investment to beat.
So you're really happy with that?
- Definitely. I haven't done anything.
It's just kind of -
(he laughs)
made itself.
Yeah exactly. You haven't
had to work for that money
have you, so that is true passive income.
You've literally, the money you've earned,
that's where you put the
work in to earn that money.
You've then invested it,
and passively it's earned you that reward.
- Yeah, exactly.
- Perfection. Now for your S&P 500.
How is that doing?
- So I put £240 in
and it's now worth £255.42
(cash register rings)
so I gained £15.42, which is $20.
- Okay. And have you got
the percentage on that?
- The percentage is 6.34%.
- So Laura, that's a really great return.
I bet you're really pleased with that.
- Yeah, definitely.
- Well if you look historically,
it should take around about a year
to get eight to 10% growth.
So you're well performing
outside of what's expected
on those type of investments.
And the reason a lot of
people put this down to,
particularly on the S&P 500,
is it's loaded with a
lot of tech companies
and the tech companies are
doing so well at the moment.
It's ramping up what you can expect.
And it's fantastic really.
- Yeah. That makes sense.
- Now let's talk about crypto.
Now I remember, you did
actually invest in some crypto.
I can't remember what you invested in
but it's been a crazy couple
of months on the crypto market,
that's for sure.
- It has. I invested in Ethereum.
- Wow.
- Shall I tell you how much I put into it?
- You're gonna tell me, but
I know it's gonna be high
cause Ethereum, it's really done well.
- Yeah. It has.
- Fire away.
(both chuckle)
- So I put in £230
and it is now worth £307.16.
- Woo hoo.
- So I have a gain of £77.16.
which is basically $100.
- Well, that is absolutely amazing.
And cryptocurrencies just
seem to keep on climbing,
particularly the blue chip currencies
such as Bitcoin and Ethereum.
And you picked the one of the two
that has climbed the most in
that period, that's for sure.
So, what a fantastic pick.
So what made you pick
Ethereum, just out of interest?
- If I'm honest, you
gave it a good review.
(he laughs)
So I kind of put my trust
in you for that one.
But yeah, it also sounded
like one that wasn't,
Bitcoin's already, I don't know
if it's kind of had its day
or it's the highest invested?
- I certainly don't think
Bitcoin's had its day
but Ethereum, of course, has
had a really, really good run
and it's got a lot of other
use cases for it as well.
So, I think long term
Ethereum could actually
outperform Bitcoin.
And if you guys would
like to get into crypto,
you can get $10 worth of free Bitcoin
using my link down below for Coinbase.
So, give it a go. It's
basically free money.
So now you've started investing,
how do you feel about it?
- I feel very happy to be
part of the club as such,
and especially because not many girls,
I feel like, are investing into it.
I kind of like to be there and go,
"No, we can do it as well,"
and like, kind of learn a lot from it
and yeah, just be part of investing.
- So what are the things
you thought about investing
that you've actually now
changed your mind on?
- So, I was never a very big risk taker,
so I automatically thought,
mm, not really for me.
I don't really know much
about it. Bit risky,
But now, the way you've explained it
and what I've learnt from it,
is how you can take bits of money out
and only spend what you can kind of afford
and what you're willing to lose.
So, by thinking of it in
a different perspective
and like that, then I
feel like it's a lot safer
and yeah, it's definitely something
that I am enjoying being part of.
- So the way I like to look at things is,
if you're putting your
money into a savings account
you're already taking a risk.
In fact, you're getting a
guaranteed loss of value
on your money.
Whereas, if you are investing
you at least got the
chance to make some money,
as you've proven in the
last couple of months.
- I'm definitely going
to keep my money in there
and keep on the journey with it.
I don't see myself, kind of
coming away from it completely,
and taking all my money and leaving it.
It's something that I'm learning about
more and more as I go along,
and I'm definitely gonna
stay on that journey,
'cause I'm really enjoying
checking up and seeing how
well my money's doing, so yeah.
- Well, I wouldn't be taking any money out
but it seems that we've made
an investor out of you anyway.
And that's really great. 'Cause
that's what we're all about.
We're trying to help you build your wealth
and all the other guys watching as well.
So, hopefully they can
replicate what you've done.
- Yes, hopefully.
- Okay. So I'm gonna leave
the next video right up there
but don't click on it just yet.
Don't forget to subscribe to the channel
if you wanna grow your wealth.
And also, don't forget to pick up
your free Bitcoin and your
stocks in the links below.
Okay, I'll see you over there. Bye.