Hi guys, it's Mark.
So today I'm gonna be talking
about how passive income allowed me
to go from a normal teen
working a nine to five job
to becoming a millionaire in my twenties.
I'm gonna be sharing with
you all the strategies
that actually worked for me,
as well as lots of my mistakes,
so hopefully you can do even better.
This is the story of how I
went from a small English town
to the rolling hills of San Francisco
and the bustling city of Shanghai, China,
including all the challenges
I faced along the way.
Who knows, by watching
this video to the end,
it may open up a new pathway for you
that you might wanna walk down.
You'll also find out why
a simple desk like this
can mean so much to me.
If that sounds good,
then give that like button a smash
and strap in for the wild
ride that is my life.
Let me take you back to 1985.
That's the last time I
walked out of those gates.
I was 16 years old.
I was tall, skinny, and I had ginger hair.
And I was broke, unfortunately,
but I knew I wanted to
make my mark on the world.
And there was no way I could
do that sitting in lessons,
learning about things
I wasn't interested in.
So I went out to seek my fortune.
Before we get there, let me
take you back to my teen years.
I was always looking to make money.
I know it's a little cliche,
but when I was a teen,
my main side hustle was
selling candy and cans of soda
to all the other kids in the playground.
On the weekend, I would also go fishing
and catch hundreds of mackerel,
which I sold around the neighborhood.
I remember knocking on
every single door possible.
I was offering a great
deal, 10 fish for $1.
But unfortunately, no one wanted 10 fish.
so I was forced to go
back to the drawing board
and restructure my business
with a new strategy.
I decided, from now on, I'd
be selling five fish for $1,
and I was shocked by the results.
Everyone wanted some.
Looking back now, these
years were so important,
as I was practicing some of
the most important life skills
out there, sales and confidence.
Without these skills,
I don't think I'd have been
able to achieve success
in later life.
So if you just take one
thing from this video,
then it should be to start
honing your sales skills
and being confident.
This brings me back to these school gates.
When I left here, I had several
paths that I could follow.
I decided I wanted a nine to five job.
I needed to learn a skill
to set me up for life.
Going to work at 9:00 AM
and finishing at 5:00 PM
was the life that school
had been drilling into me
for years.
So I really threw myself into it
and actually lined up five different jobs
because I was so keen to be successful.
I had the choice between being
a builder, an electrician,
a refrigeration engineer,
a shop assistant,
or a carpenter's apprentice.
It was a tough decision, but in the end,
I decided on becoming a carpenter.
The pay wasn't great, around $2 an hour,
but I was learning a skill,
and I could see the potential
for moving up in the company.
And I really thought that
this was my ticket to success.
I really threw myself into
my carpentry apprenticeship,
and I learned everything I could.
I even won leadership awards,
and I really felt like I was
moving forward with my life.
I finished my apprenticeship
with honors from the college
and thought, "Here we go.
All the big jobs are coming my way."
But unfortunately, my managers
seem to take a dislike to me.
Maybe they started to feel
a little bit threatened
by my success.
And therefore decided to
give me all the bad jobs.
For months on end,
he assigned me to make wooden
trash cans in the back room.
This gave me no ability to show off
my skills that I'd learned
and prevented me from
working my way up the company
to a higher paid job.
I thought to myself,
I hadn't really studied all this time
to make wooden trash cans.
Nowadays, it's the sort of
repetitive job a robot would do.
What was even worse is, when
I looked around the workshop,
I saw many other people doing
lots more interesting jobs.
So I asked to speak to the manager,
and where we're filming,
this is the exact spot where we stood.
I said I needed more of a challenge.
I couldn't keep making these bins.
And you know what he said to me?
He said, "You're making these bins today.
You'll be making these bins tomorrow.
We've got a five-year
contract with Walmart.
You're gonna be making
a lot of these bins."
Now, that's when I realized
I was completely powerless
working a nine to five job
at the mercy of whoever was in charge.
The pay was only just
enough to cover my bills,
which meant I couldn't just quit,
but I was also unable to save any money.
I was essentially trapped.
So I got a Saturday job working
in a radio-controlled model shop.
I also started a side
hustle flipping cars,
which basically consisted
of finding underpriced cars,
fixing them up, and then
selling them for a profit.
To this day, I still own
this Ford Fiesta XR-2 Mark 1.
It's a 1985 model.
And the cars I was buying at that stage
would cost me two to $300.
And I was usually flipping
them for, I'd say, 500 to $600.
This little beauty is worth
a little bit more than that now though.
As well as doing all of this,
I was also teaching people to fly
radio-controlled helicopters on Sunday.
There was a huge demand at the time.
And all Sunday, I will be booked out
as long as the weather was good,
having these multiple side hustles
allowed me to finally build out
some kind of emergency fund.
This is so important.
It gives you the freedom to take advantage
of any opportunities that come your way
without having to worry
about paying your bills.
There is a huge opportunity cost
that comes from living
paycheck to paycheck,
as you're so focused on next month's wage
that you end up going through life
with your eyes half-closed
and passing up on many opportunities
without even knowing it.
One day at work,
the boss asked if anyone wanted to help
install this beautiful
staircase at a customer's house.
I jumped at the chance.
It was one of the most impressive
houses that I'd ever seen.
It had everything.
I'm talking marble floors, chandeliers,
a private swimming pool,
and a garage full of
beautiful sports cars.
It was my dream house.
I started daydreaming and
adding up how many years
it would take me to earn enough money
to buy a place like this.
And I got gradually more
and more demoralized,
as even with all my side hustles,
I realized I still would
never have enough money.
It was so close, but just
so far at the same time.
And I felt there's really
nothing more I could do
to achieve it.
I was absolutely exhausted,
physically and mentally.
I was working every hour of every day.
While installing the staircase,
I would often look out the window
and see the owner relaxing in the garden,
or going off to play golf.
And I really couldn't understand
how this guy managed to
have the life that he wanted
and go and have fun whenever he wished.
So I had to ask him a few questions,
and he told me all about
how running his business
gave him the ability to
make money while he slept.
This is when I first
discovered passive income.
I'd never thought this was
really possible for me,
as school had only ever taught
me one way of making money,
and that was working a normal job.
This concept of making passive
income was so alien to me,
but it really got the
wheels turning in my mind.
If this was a normal guy and
he was able to do all this,
then I was pretty sure
that I could do it too.
I started thinking back to my school years
and selling those fish.
That was my first real experience
of running a small business.
And I'd loved every second of it,
from sourcing to selling the product.
I couldn't believe that I'd
been suppressing this for years
and trying to conform to
what society wanted me to do.
Nowadays, "passive income" has become
a bit of a buzzword on the internet,
and I don't completely
agree with the term,
as it can sound a little misleading.
Kickstarting a passive
income is certainly not
an easy thing to do,
but the idea is that you
can do something once,
like setting up a business
or investing some money,
and then earn from it even
when you're not working.
Of course, this requires some maintenance,
but in my opinion,
it's a better way to make money
than working a nine to five job
if you want to be successful
when you're younger,
as your time is limited,
and therefore, your income is capped.
Now I knew that passive
income was the answer.
I devised a plan of escape.
To have the best chance of success,
I knew it was important to
create a business in an industry
that I was both familiar with
and also passionate about.
And I was lucky.
I had the perfect idea.
The shop I was working in on Saturdays
was a radio-controlled model store.
Over the years that
I'd been working there,
I spotted lots of things they
could be doing differently
and all the mistakes
that they were making,
I researched and found the
perfect location for a store.
I even came up with the perfect name,
which was inspired by an old TV show
I used to watch when I was
younger, "Model World."
I could really see the
potential with this shop
and how it would eventually operate
without me even having to be there,
essentially creating passive income.
It finally gave me some hope and direction
while I was working my normal job,
as I knew that it was now
only a temporary situation.
Unfortunately, not a lot
of people believed in me.
I came from a working class background,
and I had little to no qualifications,
so no one thought I'd be able
to break into the market,
except for one of my friends,
who I told my entire plan to.
I couldn't wait to quit
my job and get started,
so I could prove everyone wrong.
I just needed to get enough
money together first.
Within a few months, Model
World Shop was up and running,
but it was nothing to do with me.
My friend had stolen my
idea and done it himself.
I felt so betrayed and frustrated
that I'd trusted him with all my plans.
I even started thinking to myself
that maybe being an entrepreneur
wasn't actually right for me.
I was stuck in my nine to five job,
being ordered around by my manager,
with every bit of hope shattered.
The worst part was watching
my friend living my dream.
I felt like a sprinter chained
up in the starting blocks,
unable to release all that energy.
It was one of the worst
feelings in my life.
The whole future I built in my head
started to come crashing down.
Looking back, this was a
great life lesson for me,
although I didn't see it
like that at the time.
If you have a great idea,
then it's best to operate in the shadows.
Maybe tell parts of your
plans to different people,
but don't give the whole
game away like I did.
After the huge setback,
I decided to pick myself
up and keep working.
I grinded as hard as I could
and bought my first apartment
to build up my credit score.
I thought I was working hard before,
but this was really the next level.
I worked every hour under the sun,
as I wasn't gonna let
my financial situation
leave me open to having my
dreams taken away from me again.
This just shows the path to passive income
is by no means easy.
There can be a lot of
setbacks along the way,
but if you stay focused,
then opportunities will
present themselves.
As if by magic, one day,
I heard some great news that my friend
wanted to sell Model World.
I'd visited a few times
and noticed that he wasn't giving it
the attention it needed.
It had huge potential,
but his passions were not in the business.
I knew I needed to buy the shop
and get my dreams back on track.
This was the opportunity that
I'd been preparing myself for,
and I wasn't gonna let it
slip from my fingers again.
I had a little bit of money behind me,
but it still wasn't gonna be enough,
nowhere near enough.
But I'd built up a good credit score,
so I thought, "I know what.
I'll leverage the money I had
and see if I can get a bank loan."
He'd taken my great
idea, he'd taken my name,
but the one thing he couldn't
take from me was my passion.
And I knew that was the secret ingredient
to making this business
a great passive income-generating machine.
So I created the best
business plan I could
and got a meeting with the bank.
I'd banked there since I was a kid,
and I had a good credit score,
so I was hoping that
everything would go smoothly.
Within 10 minutes, I'd
been denied the loan.
It was the worst interview of my life.
Oh, it felt like I've been
kicked out of the bank.
It was unreal.
My head was down.
I was walking back to my car
Do you know what?
I really didn't know what to do.
It was like being back
at that house again,
so close yet so far.
I had to pick myself up,
and as luck would have it,
the next building I stumbled
on was this bank here.
I hustled my way in, and I got a meeting,
right there and then, with the manager.
He actually said it was
a very interesting idea
and not only gave me the loan,
but promised to be one
of my first customers.
I have since asked him what
made him take a chance on me,
and he said he was
always eager to help out
the younger generation,
and when he saw how passionate
and hard-working I was,
he just couldn't say no.
This is a perfect example
of where preparation and
resilience meets opportunity.
You never know when
your next stroke of luck
is around the corner.
And for me, it quite literally
was just around the corner.
So without any hesitation, I
closed the deal on Model World,
the rights to the name and
all the products they had.
It was finally mine.
I knew the hard work was yet
to come, but it was mine.
The first day I opened the shop,
I had a sleeping bag behind the counter
because I knew, if I didn't
make enough money that day,
I'd be sleeping there
because I certainly didn't have enough gas
to drive the car home.
Luckily, the first day
was a great success.
All the selling and negotiation skills
I'd learned when I was
younger came in really useful.
Without them,
I wouldn't have been able to
make my business profitable.
After three years, we turned
over a million dollars,
and it was crazy.
It was crazy times, but
it was good fun times.
And we had more challenges along the way.
After 10 years,
we had three shops and a
warehouse stuffed full of gear.
But we wanted to be number one,
so we had plans to push on even more.
I was generating millions
in passive income,
and I felt like I'd finally made it,
but I didn't realize just how open I was
to losing everything.
When it seems to be going amazingly well,
you can start to get a little complacent,
as it seems like nothing
can stand in your way.
This is really dangerous,
as you stop innovating and
take your eye off the ball.
I was so heavily focused
on one stream of income
from my retail shops
that when internet shopping struck,
I was completely taken by surprise.
It was really sink or swim.
Everyone I knew was getting
wiped out of business,
and I knew it was only a matter of time
before that was gonna happen to me
if I didn't quickly adapt to the times.
Luckily, I had a little longer than most
because I'd been investing
in the stock market
and real estate from a young age.
If I didn't have these assets,
then I would've probably gone bankrupt.
By the way, if you're in the USA,
then Public is giving away a free stock
worth all the way up to a hundred dollars.
I'll leave the link below.
And if you're in the UK,
then Free Trade has
given away a free stock
worth all the way up to 200 pounds.
I'll leave that link down there too.
I wish I'd had them when I was younger.
While lots of people saw
the internet as the problem,
I also saw it as the solution,
as it gave me the ability
to reach far more people
than I ever could before,
even while I was sleeping.
So instead of focusing my
efforts on building more shops,
I decided to create a
big central location,
complete with warehouses,
which could be used to serve
customers all over the world,
instead of just in my local area.
But I knew that if I
wanted to protect myself
from something like this
happening in the future,
then adapting wouldn't be enough.
I need to create more
passive income streams,
so I wasn't just balancing my life on one.
My passive income streams
has always been B2C,
meaning I sold from my
business to my customers,
but I had always had the idea
of starting a business that
sold to other businesses,
which will create an entirely
different income source.
I happened to know someone
who had a similar business out in America.
So me and my girlfriend,
she's now the wife,
packed our bags and took
a spontaneous trip to LA.
(upbeat music)
The trip was so unplanned
that I even forgot my driving license,
so when we landed at LAX Airport,
I had to go to the most dodgy
car rental place in history.
All I managed to rent was this
old Dodge Dynasty town car,
which was falling apart.
Then, following the map,
we drove that baby all
the way up the coast road
to San Francisco.
That's where the guy I
wanted to meet lived,
in a small town called
Milpitas, just near San Jose.
I didn't even have a hotel
booked, so we just winged it.
And as the song goes, I thought,
"You'll always find a room
at the Hotel California."
However, it turned out to
be a big convention week.
There wasn't a room to be had.
We ended up in the most dodgy motel
I'd ever stayed in in my life.
We didn't even risk getting undressed.
We just slept on top of the bed
in case we had to get out fast.
It was just one of those things.
He was very shocked to
see us when we arrived,
as he had no idea I was coming.
I just rolled up, knocked
on the door, and said,
"I was just passing."
He said, "That's one hell
of a road trip from the UK."
He then helped me
structure my new business,
and, in return, I agreed to
stock some of his products.
I knew that if I wanted to
sell to other businesses,
then I need to build out my
own unique product range.
My experience as a carpenter
came in really handy
when designing my products.
Now, all that was left was
getting them mass-produced,
so I decided to travel
to Shanghai in China
to find a factory.
Before I knew it,
I'd been interviewed at the
Chinese embassy in London,
issued with a visa,
and I sat on a plane with
a few faxes printed out.
And they said on the top of these faxes,
"Hand this to the taxi driver
when you get to the airport."
I couldn't read the rest of it
because it was all in Chinese characters.
I could have quite
literally ended up anywhere.
The trip went really, really well,
and I gained lots of new contacts
with many invites to travel to Shenzhen
to visit their factories.
I still think that if you take the trouble
to meet people for real,
then you can grow a real bond in business
where you help each other.
You have to press the
flesh to gain that loyalty,
and that's why politicians
always wanna shake your hand
because it's almost like a
contract to secure your vote.
That brings me to today.
My businesses are thriving,
and my passive income streams
are stronger than ever.
One of the most important things
I've learned from my experience
is that there is less risk
in stepping out of your
comfort zone and adapting
than there is in not
taking any risk at all.
If you've been considering
quitting your job,
then know this.
If you've got the right plan
and the right motivation,
you have as much chance
of success as anyone else.
You don't have to come from a rich family.
You don't have to have
lots of connections.
The barriers to entry
in the business world
have never been this low.
All you need is a computer, some brains...
That certainly helps.
And an internet connection
to make your first bit of startup money.
Who knows?
One day, you could be
sitting in the boss's seat
behind the boss's desk.
And this is literally the boss's desk.
I was once sitting just where you are now,
having my interview to become a carpenter.
When that firm went into receivership
and it came up for auction,
I went straight down there,
and I bought this desk.
So I'm gonna leave the
next video up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you wanna grow your wealth,
and don't forget to
pick up your free stocks
with the links below.
Okay, I'll see ya over there.