Hi guys, it's Mark.
So I'm gonna take a wild guess
if you're subscribed to this channel,
then you're interested in making money,
and therefore this video
will be right up your street.
As you guys probably know,
I've got a bit of an
obsession which turned in $100
like this into as much as possible.
And I think $100 is the
perfect starting point.
And I feel that most
people will be able to find
this amount of cash by doing
some sort of side hustle
or working some overtime.
Today, I wanted to do
something a little different
and introduce a time limit.
So all the money making
ideas I'm gonna be discussing
with you today should be able to turn $100
into $1000 consistently
over a 24-hour period.
But Mark, if it was really that easy,
everyone would be doing it.
Oh, well, this certainly
isn't gonna be easy.
So if you think that,
then please start watching
the video right now.
I'm not gonna lie to
you, this will be hard,
but the rewards are
definitely worth the grind.
But seriously guys,
I've always believed that getting
rich is entirely possible.
However, getting rich easily
just doesn't really exist.
So I'm gonna be starting
with the least risky ideas
and work my way up to the riskiest ones.
But before we get into this,
make sure to hit that like
button for the (mumbles) group
because it really helps get this video out
to more people like you.
The first one is creating
digital products.
I'm putting this as number
one on the risk scale
'cause you might not
even need the full $100,
provided you've already
got a laptop or a PC.
The internet is definitely the
place to make lots of money
as its growth has been absolutely huge.
Just in 2020 alone, there were 305,000
online businesses created
compared to just 13,000 in 2019.
With all these people
starting online businesses,
you may think that the
competition is gonna be sky high.
And yes, of course it's harder.
However, I think there's a huge gap
in the market for digital products.
Just think about it, everyone
is talking about e-commerce
and drop shipping,
but far less are actually
selling quality digital products,
which have the benefit of
never running out stock
and no shipping costs as it's
all done over the internet.
The thing I love about digital products
is it can be fairly passive.
Of course, no income is truly passive,
but if you can create
a digital product once,
you can sell it over
and over and over again.
This sounds great, but what
actually is a digital product?
A friend of mine created
a digital template system
you can use on Instagram,
just off the back of a problem send to him
by one of the followers
who wanted to stand out.
Within a couple of hours and
no more than $100 invested,
the templates were designed
and now she sells thousands
of dollars worth every week.
So you could use your $100
to buy some editing software
to create these products.
Or you could even pay someone on platforms
like Fiverr to do the work for you
then you could list them
on websites like Etsy
and start making some sales.
I've seen these templates selling
anywhere from five to $ 100 plus,
and you only have to make it once.
And it sells again and again,
that's the beauty of it.
Once you've got some
more money to play with,
nothing is stopping you from
running efforts on Facebook
and reaching even more customers.
But if Instagram templates aren't for you,
then it doesn't stop there.
You can make software, YouTube
banners, e-books, games,
email templates, or even online courses.
Creating and selling online courses
is a booming market internationally.
And in my opinion, it's one
that's lacking a lot of quality.
There's a massive demand
for quality courses
that teach useful skills
rather than all the fake gurus
who sell those for $997.
I feel like I have given the
e-learning market a bad name,
however, it's expected to
exceed 325 billion by 2025,
and we have a yearly growth of 5%.
The second one is starting
a service-based business.
I'm putting this at number
two on the risk scale
as the initial setup is
pretty straightforward,
we've only $100.
This type of business is only
really limited to your time.
If you're prepared to put in lots of work,
then you will be able to turn your $100
into $1000 consistently
once you've built up your client base.
Some jobs you can make an
absolute fortune from doing
because your customers don't
feel it's worth their time.
I don't have to be
honest, I agree with this.
I'm typically busy with business
and it doesn't make sense
for me to waste two hours
washing my own car when I could just pay
someone $20 to do it for me.
And this is something you
can take advantage of.
Washing cars could be a
great service-based business
to get into, but it probably
won't make you $1000 a day
unless you become a professional detailer
or start employing your
friends to work for you
so they can serve more of your customers.
Once again, it's all
about getting creative
with the service and value
you can provide your potential customers.
My son, Curtis is 23 and he is behind
a lot of the strategies that
helped my YouTube channel
grow from zero subscribers
about a year ago
to now over 700,000.
Because of this, he can
now comfortably charge
over two and a half thousand
dollars for a few hours
of his time as a consultant.
The list is endless.
Mobile dog grooming, dry
cleaning delivery and pickup,
mobile locksmiths mechanic.
And that's just to name a few.
It's all about playing to your strengths
and finding a unique mixture of skills
that can add a lot of
value to your customers.
Maybe it won't make your
$1000 in your first day,
but with some hard work and dedication,
you could absolutely scale it
up to $1000 a day and beyond.
Next up is reselling.
I'm talking, flipping
items from garage sales
and charity shops.
I'm putting this at number
three on the risk scale.
As with this strategy,
you will have to purchase the items
before actually selling them.
This means that if you make a mistake
or buy something no one wants,
you may be stuck with
the item and no profit.
A garage sales, you will have
lots of motivated sellers
because they probably just
want to clear out their house.
This means some valuable items
get very easily overlooked.
Just think how many
price this Pokemon cards
were sold at garage sales.
When I was younger, this
wasn't as easy to do
as I didn't have a phone
with an internet connection,
but nowadays you have such an advantage.
Of course, it helps to
do some research before
to know what you're looking for,
but whenever you're unsure about the item,
all it takes is a quick check on eBay
to see what the market value is.
You even have the advantage
of putting your negotiation
skills to the test.
If you can manage to get the price down,
you'll make even more profit.
I recently turned $100 purchase
of secondhand model trains
into just over $1000
because two of the items
happened to be very rare.
I gave a fair price
based on what I thought
I could sell everything for,
and then as luck would have it,
I had people fighting over them on eBay.
I had a bidding war on my hands,
and this is a great thing
to watch is that price
just keeps going up and up and up.
You could spend the day
hunting for hidden gems
and then go home and sell
them on global marketplaces
like eBay, Etsy, Amazon, and Facebook.
This is the perfect way to sell them
as online shoppers can be lazy
and not everyone can be bothered
to go and find a good deal.
Of course, you don't have to buy products
at charity shops and garage sales,
you can turn to the internet instead
and hunt for some great deals.
A good strategy I've used is searching
for common spelling mistakes,
because this allows you to find listings
that no one else has seen.
And therefore there's less competition
when you're trying to bid for the items.
I work out what I can sell the item for,
and then I offer 50% or less.
I aim to at least double my money.
And who knows, maybe
you'll even scale this
into a real business and begin
buying inventory in bulk.
I really believe that with a bit of skill
when a large range of garage sales,
you would be able to turn $100
into 1000 within 24 hours.
Let's now talk about buying materials
to create physical products.
I'm putting creating your
own products as number four
on the risk scale as it does require you
to have some creative
skills and also the ability
to do some proper market research
to make sure people want your
product in the first place.
But with that said, by
making your own products,
you can generate much
more money than reselling
as you're only paying for the materials.
This means you have a much higher chance
of securing that $1,000 profit per day.
When I was younger, I used
to build literally hundreds
of radio control cars.
I was friends with a model shop owner,
and I noticed that many customers
didn't want to build their
own cars from scratch
as all they wanted to do
though was race them around.
So after identifying this demand,
I decided to buy the materials
and charge a minimum of $30 for my time.
It took me two hours
to complete each model.
So in 24 hours, I could make $360.
But that was way back in the 1980s.
So you could definitely
charge more for your time now
and possibly hit that $1,000 mark.
This could apply to so many areas
and all you need to do is
promote yourself online
be it building model cars,
making arts and crafts,
or even building furniture.
Now that takes me back to my
carpenter days that's for sure.
Now let's get into crypto trading.
I'm putting crypto trade in at number five
on our risk scale because
it's such a new investment,
which means certain coins
can be extremely volatile,
sometimes even shooting up
over 1000% within a few days.
Of course is very excited,
but it also means the opposite is true
and you could end up
losing all of your money.
You may be wondering why I've
skipped investing in stocks
and dive straight into crypto.
The truth is, it's just not very common
to make $1000 from $100 investment
in the stock market over a 24 hour period.
Of course it's possible
with certain penny stocks
and short squeezes like
the GameStop situation,
but these are often hard to spot.
Because of the juicy returns from crypto,
I've actually noticed that a decline
in the amount of people
interested in the stock market,
especially from the younger generation.
The thing to remember here
is that although stocks
might not be as exciting,
they can still offer some great
returns over the long term
and have been around a lot longer
so generally regarded as a safer bet.
On that note, public.com
is currently giving away
a free stock worth all the way up to $1000
if you're in the USA.
And Freetrade are giving away a free stock
worth up to 200 pounds
if you're in the UK,
I'll leave the links in
the description below.
But back to the crypto,
a crisis statistic I found
was that 13% of all Americans
have traded or at least
purchased some crypto
in the last year and the
industry is forever growing.
Where most people think about crypto,
Bitcoin and Ethereum come to mind.
I personally invest in these long-term
as I see them as blue chip crypto.
However, if your aim is
to turn $100 into $1000,
then those kinds of
returns are more realistic
with altcoins.
An altcoin or otherwise
known as alternative coin
is any crypto that isn't Bitcoin.
But I personally think Ethereum
has also outgrown this title.
My assistant's friend has been traded
in an altcoin called Luna,
which is a decentralized currency
and has generated well
over $1000 in profits
from $100 investment.
Shiba Inu also made a lot of people rich.
However, these coins dump pretty fast.
So it's all about knowing when to get out.
This may sound like it
contradicts what I always say
about never time in the market,
but I really don't think
that this applies to crypto
or coins as some of them
pump once and never reach
the same all-time highs again.
It's extremely risky and
takes a lot of knowledge
as well as research.
And even with that,
there's still no knowing
if you'll be right or not.
I only invest 5% of my
portfolio into crypto,
but I do want to do more.
It's exciting, and the
fluctuations in price are amazing.
It's a very high risk
option, a bit like gambling,
but if you only have a little money
and if you want a charter or
an old coin going to the moon,
then I can see the appeal.
Bitcoin was the best performing
asset of the last decade.
So it as crypto gains pace,
it's hard to argue against it.
Not to mention, I've made
way more than $1000 in a day
on numerous occasions.
Talking about Bitcoin,
Coinbase is giving you $10
worth of free Bitcoin with
the link in the description.
So if you're interested
that might show to go
and pick that up.
This is only available
though for a limited time.
Now for NFT flipping,
otherwise known as non fungible tokens.
I'm putting this as number
six on the risk scale.
This is even newer than crypto altcoins
and it reminds me very
much of the .com bubble.
Yeah, that's how old I am.
It seems that recently
YouTube is that celebrities
have been going crazy about
buying these JPEG images
for extortionate prices
and then flipping them for even more.
It does seem like when we were
at the dawn of the internet,
there are lots of projects out there
and most of them are probably trash.
But if you can weed out the good ones,
then you could be onto a winner.
One of my son's friends was
telling me the other day
that he purchased an NFT for $1000,
and now it's worth over 20,000.
If that's not a great return
then I don't know what is.
This is an area I've yet to venture into.
However, I struggle
with the huge valuations
and who will buy an NFT from me.
It's a bit like art.
I might take the approach
I did when I was young
and I was selling pre-owned cars.
Back then, I would only buy a car
that I would like to drive or own.
I did this for two reasons.
The first was my assumption
that if I liked it,
then someone else would as well.
And the second was, if
no one wanted to buy it,
then I'll be happy to keep
it as my personal car.
So I just need an NFT that speaks to me.
Buying NFTs is really popular
on platforms like OpenSea.
And I've also heard that Coinbase
are about to enter the NFT space.
So it could be a good time
to do some further research
before jumping in.
Now, I really couldn't make this video
without mentioning gambling.
Gambling is number seven on our risk scale
because the house always wins
especially if you gamble for long enough.
I like to have a flatter
occasionally with gambling.
I know the online casinos
like Roobet are very popular,
but it's not really my style.
I would much rather get all dressed up
and take a trip to the casino.
It makes me feel like
James Bond for the night.
I did buy $100 worth of
scratch cards in a past video,
and we only made back $50.
So that was actually a 50% loss.
Now, although it's possible to turn $100
into a $1000 in a casino,
the chances of that
happened in a very unlikely.
When I go, I always look
at it as a night out.
If I come out on top, then
it's an even better night out.
We just have to remember
that these casinos
were built off the back of the losers
and not by giving away
the money to the winners.
As you've probably noticed,
the further we got down the list,
each idea required less work,
but also had more risk involved.
So at the end of the day,
provided you've got your
longterm investments sorted
and an emergency fund
of three to six months
of living expenses stored up,
then I really don't see anything wrong
with taking a moonshot with $100
and even trying out a few different ideas.
I know for sure that if I
played it completely safe
all my life, I might have had enough
to retire as a millionaire,
but I wouldn't have become
a millionaire in my 20s
and lived a fun life.
So like anything, it's all
about finding the right balance.
If you want me to try any
of these ideas in a video,
then make sure to let me
know in the comments below.
Some of them could be a lot
of fun, that's for sure.
So I'm gonna leave the
next video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you wanna grow your wealth
and don't forget to pick up
your free stocks and Bitcoin
in the links below, okay?
I'll see you over there.