Hi guys, it's Mark.
So if you ever wished there
was an easy way to become rich
that anyone could do
with no prior experience.
Well, guess what there
is, and I've made millions
doing it myself, but before you click off
thinking this is some kind of scam,
I'm not pumping the latest
crypto coin or trying to sell you
an online course that costs $997,
I'm instead referring to index funds.
Index fund investing is super
easy, incredibly effective,
and in most cases actually
ends up beating the profits
of professional investors.
A study published in 2020
showed over 15 year period,
nearly 90% of actively
managed investment funds
failed to beat the market.
Simply put experts who
spend a full-time job,
trying to beat the market are
unable to beat most investors
that use the index funds strategy.
So today let's discuss what
an index fund actually is,
which ones are best for you
and how you can use them
to grow your wealth, right
after you smash that like button
for the LTube Ugarhythm.
I'm gonna be honest, I almost
didn't make this video.
The world has changed over
the last couple of years,
and now most people only
seem interested in the stocks
and crypto going to the moon, I get it.
It's exciting to see your
money multiplied quickly,
but the harsh truth is
lots of people who invest
in more than I can afford to
lose him risky investments.
This means that when a crash
happens and believe me,
it always does, many people
will be left with nothing.
I've seen this happen time and time again.
And the people that make
it through the storm
are usually the ones that
also invest for the long term.
Of course, I've taken my fair
share of risks over the years,
like investing in a dot-com
bubble and now by investing
in the metaverse.
However, the one thing
I've kept consistent
is my index fund invested.
No matter of the market
is up or down every week
I prioritize those investments.
This is allowing me to grow
my wealth over the longterm.
When a lot of my previously richer friends
have lost everything.
So I like to think of index
funds as my secret weapon,
as they've meant that
I've always had a backup
for when the worst happens.
If you only ever watch one of
my videos all the way through
to the end, and it definitely
should be this one.
So it's been a while since
I've talked about index funds.
So let's break down
what they actually are.
(Skittles chink)
Think of these Skittles as
lots of different individual
companies, this one is
Tesla, this one is Apple,
and this one is Coca-Cola.
Now as an investor, you
could cherry pick the ones
that you liked the most.
This is called investing
in individual stocks.
However, these companies go
bankrupt or crashing value
you're in trouble, mind
you, I do like the new sour
Skittles, they're very tasty.
The great thing about index
funds is with one simple
purchase, you can own all
the Skittles in the bowl
without having to deal with all the hassle
of creating your own
hand selected portfolio,
or have some expensive
managers do it for you.
This is because they're passively managed,
which means they are
extremely cost-effective.
I have a large chunk of
my wealth in index funds,
and I dabble with individual
stocks using my fund money.
This is because occasionally
enjoyed excitement of CNN
investments skyrocket 40% in
a day, which let me tell you,
it's never gonna happen
with an index fund,
but that's not a bad thing
as it's all about building
long-term wealth and not short term wins.
The truth is that if a
stock or crypto can give you
these kinds of returns, then
it could also swing back
the other way.
The great thing about index
funds is if one company
from within the bowl is having a bad time,
like this one, boom,
you've still got all the
other companies holding it up.
An index fund, aims to track
something called an index,
which is a lot like a sports leaderboard.
They can rank company size,
location, business type,
and even currencies.
So because there are so many choices,
let's pretend we're in a supermarket,
and I'll walk you through my
3.5 favorite baskets of stocks
to invest in, the reason I've added a 0.5
is because there's a new kid on the block.
Remember I'm a businessman
and not a financial advisor.
These are just investments I believe in.
And none of this should be
taken as financial advice.
I'm just aiming to make you
aware of these investments.
So please do your own
research before investing.
Basket number one is of
course the S&P 500 Index.
This is the big daddy of index funds,
and you've probably heard
people talking about it before.
I've certainly mentioned
it hundreds of times,
but there's a good reason for
this as it is such a great
investment, and it's done very
well for me over the years.
On average, the S&P 500 has
returned investors eight to 10%
per year, which isn't anything
crazy compared to the latest,
crazy like Shiba Inu, but
it is pretty consistent,
a much less volatile.
That sounds great, but
what's inside the basket?
Well, the S&P 500 is a top
500 American companies.
Well, actually it's
505 stocks to be exact,
in order to be included in the S&P 500,
a company must meet certain requirements,
include in achieving
a specific market cap,
having the majority of its
shares in public hands,
and being a public company
for at least a year.
So if you buy one share of the S&P 500,
you will actually own a small
piece of Amazon, Tesla, Apple,
PayPal, and so much more.
The ultimate flex is telling your friends,
you own all of these companies.
One of the benefits of the
S&P 500 is that it's widely
spread across many great
companies in the USA.
To be honest, they are more
like worldwide companies now,
since the creation of the
internet has a blurred the lines
between borders made the world
much, much more interconnected.
The historical return of
eight to 10% is allowing me
to generate a fortune over
the years due to the power
of compound interest.
However, it's worth pointing
out that the S&P 500
is a bit tech heavy these
days with five big tech stock
dominating 23% of the entire fund.
It's up to you if you see this
as a positive or a negative,
I personally don't mind us
tech is doing really well,
and I do believe it's the future,
but there are so many
different index funds.
So track the S&P 500, which one do I pick?
Well, that depends on where
you live in the world,
and what investing platform you're using.
The best I found in the
USA, the VFIAX index fund,
or the VOO ETF, the best
in the UK would probably be
the VUSI ETF, but there
are tons of other ETFs
that also track the S&P 500.
One thing I look out for
is that the dividends
are reinvested into the fund.
The only real difference between
an index fund and an ETF,
otherwise known as an exchange traded fund
is that these can be
purchased or sold at any time
throughout the day, just like a stock,
as long as the market is open of course,
that's why they're exchange
traded, it's in the name.
Index funds can only be
purchased in full once per day.
So, for example, if the
price of the fund is $500,
you must pay $500.
Whereas an ETF can also be
purchased in fractional shares,
which means you don't
have to buy a full share,
and can instead invest
whatever amount you like.
This is great if you're just starting out,
or you want a dollar cost averaging,
I do this by making a
stand in order each week.
And I don't even know it's
come from my bank account,
really and truly there
isn't a huge difference
between an index fund and an ETF.
So just consider which one is best for you
and take the plunge.
If you want to get started
in Public giving away a free
stock worth all the way up to
a $1000s If you live in a USA
and Free Trader giving you a free stock
worth all the way up to 200
pound, if you live in the UK,
I'll leave those links below.
Basket number two is a
total stock market index.
The total stock market index is, well,
the definition of diversification,
you can't really get any
more skin in the game
for a lower cost than this.
So if you want to invest
for a long period of time
without having to check
or even think about it,
then this is most likely to fund for you.
Investing in everything means
you can experience gains
across the entire market.
And unless a crazy crash
happens, you should be okay.
But even if it does crash,
with time things bounce back.
I've seen three crashes
since I've been an investor,
the dot-com bubble, the
2008 financial crisis
and the 2020 COVID crash.
I'm not gonna pretend
these crashes didn't hurt,
but longterm, every
market I've invested in
has bounced back.
But downside to this index is
that it depends on the entire
market trending upwards.
This means that there could
be an individual stock
that you really believe
in that goes all the way
to the moon, but you might
not experience those gains
because that one stock
doesn't play much of a role
within the index fund.
If you're an active
investor who likes to try
to mess with options, this
index fund is probably great
to have as a safety net that
you regularly invest into.
The best I've found in the
USA is the VTSAX index fund,
and the VTI ETF and the best
in the UK is the VWRL ETF.
These are Vanguard index funds,
but you should be able to
buy them on most platforms,
including public and free trade.
The third basket is the
emerging markets index.
Emerging markets are
predicted by some experts
to be on the rise.
And whether I agree with this or not,
I think it's important to
have at least a little bit
of exposure to these markets.
It's all well, good buying the S&P 500,
but when China or another emerging country
has some great gains,
you'll end up missing out.
I'm definitely more excited
about funds like the S&P 500,
but as I also do a lot
of business in China,
I see firsthand why
invest in emerging markets
is a good idea.
Just as an example of this growth.
When I first traveled to China,
I looked into buying an
apartment in Shen Zen.
This real estate was $47,000,
and is now worth over a million.
This just shows the potential
growth in these markets.
Emerging market funds are
definitely the most risky
type of index fund we've discussed so far.
These funds include stocks
from lots of different growing
markets and can be very
heavy with Chinese companies,
taking a look at the list
of the largest economies
in the world, a lot of
them are emerging markets.
So it just makes sense to me
to throw a little bit of money
in for diversification.
Also, the population of
these emerging markets
is absolutely huge.
So I think there's certainly
potential for growth,
not only in their own countries,
but in exports as well.
As I said before, these are
definitely more risky plays,
but countries are adapting and evolving.
So I do like to invest in their future.
The best I've found in the USA is a VEIEX.
That's a mouthful ETF, and
in the UK, the VFEM ETF.
They don't make it any
easier there, do they?
Basket number 3.5 is a bit of a bonus one
as it's the metaverse index,
recently, I've made a few
videos on the metaverse
and you guys seem super excited about it,
which is great because I am too.
I actually rewatched the
film "Ready Player One"
the other day.
And if you ever want to
see the possibilities
of the metaverse, then I
recommend watching this movie.
This has just made me even more confident
that the potential profit is insane.
And therefore, it's not
something that I can ignore,
because of this, I've been
investing more and more
into companies that I think
will be heavily involved
in the metaverse.
And I'm not just talking about META.
If you want to see my other picks,
I made a video about it a few weeks ago.
It's just here, I've just been
picking my favorite stocks
and building my own portfolio,
but Roundhill Investments
are offering a META ETF.
This makes things easier
is it offers exposure
to lots of companies
that are set to benefit,
and take part in the metaverse
all with one simple bite.
But of course the
metaverse isn't here yet.
And it's all just
speculation at the moment.
Also the top 10 companies in
this ETF are not all selections
I would make.
So that's definitely something
to look out for and consider,
this ETF also has quite
a high expense ratio
of 0.75%, which may not
sound a lot, but trust me,
it's considerably more
than a lot of the funds
I've already talked about.
I think the best way forward
is to look at what stocks
the META ETF holds,
and then buy the ones
you like individually.
But if this sounds like too much hassle,
then ETF is definitely
something to consider.
When I first heard about index funds,
I thought it was fantastic.
'Cause before I'd always thought investing
was only for the rich,
the most important thing
is getting started.
And index funds gave me the
ability to start investing
when I knew very little,
which meant that I could get
the snowball rolling.
So if you're sitting on the fence,
then now is as good a time as ever
to start your long-term investing journey.
So I'm gonna leave the
next video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
And don't forget to pick up
the free stocks and Bitcoin
with the links below, okay?
I'll see you over there. (clicks)