Hi guys. It's Mark. So
student debt has increased
by a whopping 91% in the past decade,
leading to Americans
owing a record-breaking
1.73 trillion dollars.
Therefore, today we're gonna talk
about 10 alternative high paid jobs
that don't require a college degree
so that we can find the
answer to the question,
if going to university is all
that it's stacked up to be.
Especially when you can
just become a friend
of Mr. Beast and be paid thousands for it.
If you're watching Jimmy, give me a call.
But seriously, in my opinion, these jobs
definitely have the potential
to make you a millionaire.
If you invest your money
wisely and correctly
along the way, anything is possible.
To be honest with you. I
wasn't very good at school,
which caused me to leave at
16 with no qualifications,
but I didn't let that stop me
from becoming a millionaire
so if I can do it
I'm sure that you can. Maybe you'll decide
on whether you want to go to college,
or maybe you're just interested
in different job options out there.
Either way, by watching
this video to the end,
you may find a new path
you want to walk down.
A small, but very important job
that often goes unnoticed
is all those people
that smashed that like button
for the L-tube You-garhythm.
You certainly don't need a
college degree to do that.
And even if you do have
one smash it anyway.
Right, all done, let's jump into it.
Number one, a skilled trades person.
Once you have a trade, no one
could take this away from you.
This includes everything from plumbers
and electricians to carpenters
and even elevator mechanics.
These skills are in really high demand
and can justify wages
up to $68,000 a year.
This has also grown
each year as the number
of skilled jobs is far out
pacing the supply of workers.
This could be due to more people choosing
to go down the university route
and not learning a trade.
It's even estimated
that by 2028, there will
be 3 million job vacancies
in the skilled trades. This
is an amazing opportunity,
but it's also pretty scary thought as well
because these jobs are a
crucial part of our society.
I mean, I'm pretty good with my hands,
but I don't ever mess with
the plumbing or the electrics.
Most trades can be learned on the job
without the need for higher
education, which is great.
As you can get right
into making some money
at the same time as making
yourself more valuable.
When I left school, this
is exactly what I did.
I got an apprenticeship and I learned
how to become a carpenter.
I've never regretted this decision
as I've used this skill
throughout my life.
And I knew I had something to
fall back on if I needed it.
Some people look down on trades people,
but get this. If you
compare a doctor's wealth
to a plumber's, then it reportedly takes
the doctor until 41 years old to catch up.
This is because of the
time that doctors spend
studying and building up student debt.
Number two, an air traffic controller.
Imagine sitting at this really cool desk,
earning up to $122,000 a
year. Are you interested?
Because I'm definitely
jealous of that view.
Air traffic controllers are responsible
for directing the safe
movement of aircraft
arriving and departing from an airport
in order to prevent collisions.
It's a bit like the
conductor of an orchestra
of metal birds. They're crucial
to the running of an airport
to keep hundreds of passengers safe.
Although you can make good money
as an air traffic controller,
it can be very stressful,
especially when you have to
deal with people like me.
I actually got in trouble
with air traffic control
once when I was flying a small airplane
from a place called Biggin
Hill to Shoreham airport.
Unfortunately I left a little bit late
and I called up Shoreham and it turns out
they had already closed the airport.
on top of that, it was getting dark
and it was illegal for me to fly at night,
being the Maverick that I was,
I decided to land anyway,
because I had no other options.
And this caused the
air traffic controller,
a great deal of stress.
He even called me up
to the tower to reprimand me and inform me
I had to fill out loads of forms
for an out of house landing
and that I would hear
from the authorities. I
guess he was a nice guy
because I never heard any more about it,
but I was sure never to be late again.
So if you think you can
handle situations like that,
then the good news is
air traffic controlling
is projected to grow 3% through 2026.
So there are plenty of new
opportunities popping up,
but as you've probably guessed,
they're not going to let you control
hundreds of planes without any training.
Luckily you rarely require
any sort of university degree.
In fact, most air traffic controllers
can do on the job training
after completing high school.
Number three, becoming an influencer.
Did you know that more kids now dream
of becoming a professional YouTuber
rather than becoming an astronaut
according to a recent study?
I hardly find the surprise in this.
They see their favorite influencers
having the time of their lives
while making millions per year.
It's easy to dismiss this one
as a dream or not a real job.
And that's what a lot of people my age do.
But I think this is a
really interesting industry.
The amount companies spend on
influencers in the U.S. alone
is going to surpass three billion dollars,
which is a growth of more
than 30% from last year.
This means that we have more money
being pumped into the industry.
There'll be a lot of
space for new influencers.
I mean, if a boomer
like me can start TikTok
as a bit of fun during the pandemic
and rack up nearly 7 million followers,
then doesn't that just prove it.
I've now even started two
more YouTube channels,
which are my new second channel,
where I post quick
finance and business tips,
as well as my podcast channel with my son,
where we discuss all things business
and investing from an old
and young perspective.
At the end of the day, influencers offer
something that TV just can't compete with
real authentic content.
Which therefore means
you don't need expensive equipment
or a university degree to get stuck in.
Number four is a radiographer.
How does flooding people with radiation
and earning up to $69,000
a year sound to you?
You just have to be careful
not to turn anyone into the Hulk.
Radiographers also known
as radiologic technologist,
perform x-rays CT scans, MRIs,
and other forms of medical imaging
to help diagnose illnesses and conditions.
This is commonly confused with radiology.
However, radiographers do not interpret
the results or make a diagnosis.
Blimey. That was a mouthful.
If you have ever had a
passion for helping people
and wanted to go into
something medical related,
then a radiography is one
of the highest paying jobs
that doesn't require a degree.
Actually, my sister
trained as one in the UK
and that skill allowed her to emigrate
to Australia where that
job is in high demand.
And she is earning a massive salary.
Good day, Karen, if you're watching this,
fry another shrimp on the barbie.
The demand for radiographers is set
to remain strong due to a
very large aging population
in need of imaging to diagnose
and treat medical conditions.
What are you looking at? I'm
only 25? Well, I feel 25.
It's easy enough to get
started after completing
a two year job focus course while I admit,
this does take a little bit of training.
It isn't nearly as time
consuming as a college degree,
and it's a lot less expensive too.
Number five, an executive assistant.
It can be extremely fun
being the right hand person
of a business leader. You're both striving
towards a shared mission and you can earn
up to a very respectable $68,000 a year.
Working your way up to being
an executive assistant
can be very rewarding
as it means doing different
jobs almost every single day.
My assistant does everything
from organizing my schedule
to helping me with strategic planning,
by working at this level in a company
you're also surrounded by lots of people
who are wealthier than you.
This automatically means
you'll start leveling up and
find ways to earn even more.
I've often seen assistants
go on to become CEOs
of their own businesses as they learned
so much under the wing
of a successful person.
So it's not all about
the money you're earning.
It's also about the knowledge
and the connections.
My assistant responded to
a post I made on Instagram
and performed really
well in his interview.
He doesn't have a university degree,
but that really doesn't matter to me.
He came across as driven, dedicated,
and very business savvy. I have
nothing against university,
but sometimes I feel like
it can knock the spark
out of people. If you're
never told what you can't do,
then you seem to have less
limits on your potential.
So based on my own experience
of hiring an assistant,
I would say the best thing you can do
is follow the leaders of businesses
that you're interested in
working for on social media.
Whenever one of them
posts about a job opening,
you can be one of the first
to throw your hat in the ring.
And that's exactly what Kai did.
And it worked out very well.
Even if he can't make
a decent cup of coffee.
Number six, a construction site manager.
The demand for construction managers
will reportedly grow 8% by 2029,
which is much faster than
the 4% projected growth
in all other occupations,
you can expect to earn an annual wage
of between $50,000 and $126,000.
A site manager within
the construction industry
is responsible for overseeing operations
of the whole site on a day to day basis.
And making sure a project
comes in on time and on budget.
And as many of you know, I'm
building out my north wing
at the moment and Phil's
my project manager,
- Are you filming me?
- I certainly am. He only
bothers me about 30 times a day.
To be a site manager you need
to be good at problem solving,
have strong communication skills
and have an extensive knowledge
of the construction process.
If you don't have a degree,
then you can eventually move
into a site manager role
after gaining experience
working in the construction
industry over a number of years.
Number seven an artist like videographers,
editors and writers.
Back when I was younger,
artists always used to be broke,
but now with the
explosion of the internet,
I am desperately looking for people
that can tell stories about my products
to increase the sales.
The new generation is highly visual,
and we need artists to connect
and sell products to them,
which makes their skills
extremely valuable.
The earning potential with
this is truly unlimited.
It's just all depends on your ability
to drive clicks and sales.
My son Curtis started
specializing in videography,
editing, and content writing.
Four years later he's earning
more than $200,000 a year
and doing the job he loves.
The beauty of this career
is that a university degree
is nothing compared with
real-world results and experience.
When I spend money on my business,
I want to be sure that I'm
going to get good return.
Now, if I have to pick
between someone with a degree
and someone with experience
and some results,
then I would always pick the latter.
You will, of course, need to invest
a lot of time into learning these skills,
but luckily they can all be self-taught
using books and the internet.
I'm here with Curtis. So what's one tip
you can tell the viewers that's
helped you in your career?
- I would definitely say free to fee.
So I started off doing
a ton of free videos,
and then I started to
charge for them gradually
and it got me in the door,
got me building connections,
and then I could expand
my business from there.
So free to fee is the way.
- Number eight, an
insurance claims adjuster.
These people own tiny devices
that allow them to access
people's memories and
check if they're lying
or not about their insurance
claims. Oh, hang on.
I think I'm getting that confused
with a black mirror episode.
To be honest though,
I wouldn't be surprised
if they started doing this
in the future. In all seriousness,
the top 10% of insurance
claim investigators
earn over a hundred
thousand dollars a year
and the lowest 10% of adjusters earn
just over $40,000 a year.
They're a bit like Sherlock
Holmes as they have to gather up
loads of information and details
to work out what happened in the instant
and find a fair settlement price.
Their job performance is evaluated
based on how many claims
they can successfully handle
without involving supervisors
or corporate lawyers.
So it's highly suited
for competitive people.
All that's required for this
job is a high school diploma.
This is because of the nature of the job.
Analytical and critical thinking skills
are essential qualities
for these individuals.
Number nine is a
professional gaming athlete.
Being paid good money
to play computer games
competitively sounds
like a dream come true.
The average professional
gamer earns $60,000 per year.
And if you're really good, you
can actually earn millions.
This is really crazy to me
because when I was younger,
I used to have to go down the arcade
when I wanted to play games.
But it does make sense
as whenever there is
a lot of attention on something,
then people are going to naturally want
to see the best of the
best go head to head.
Gamers make their money
in a few different ways,
such as tournament prizes,
salaries from being in a team,
bonuses for doing well, sponsors,
and of course, live streaming.
Being a professional gamer is
not an easy career to take on.
It requires thousands of
hours of gaming experience,
just like any elite level sport.
So although the top professional players
earn millions each year, the harsh truth
is only a few people
enjoy that kind of salary.
I'm not saying this to
discourage you in any way,
because if you put your mind to it
and train every day, then
I'm sure it's achievable.
Number 10 is a high ticket
commission sales person.
Imagine selling a product
for more than $200,000
and getting a sweet 6% commission.
That's a $12,000 pay day.
High ticket items are high
price products or services.
These items can include
expensive products like cars,
jewelries, houses, even services
like coaching, webinars, and training.
Many high ticket sales people choose
to work on a commission basis,
selling other people's products
or services to a list of potential clients
who have already shown interest.
This means that once
you learn how to sell,
essentially your income is unlimited.
One of the main reasons I was able
to become as successful as I am
is that I learned how to
sell from a very young age.
It's such an important
skill. And if you learn it,
then you'll never really
struggle for money.
It's also worth mentioning accountancy,
financial advising, and
computer programming
are also great career paths
that do not require college degrees
and you can earn some sweet bank.
So choosing, if you should go to college
is a big decision and
it's highly dependent
on what you decide to study.
If the job that you wish
to pursue requires a degree
then I would agree that
college is definitely worth it.
As you have a clear return on investment,
but if you choose to study
a course with no real aim,
then this might be a
very expensive mistake.
With more people than ever before
going to university it's
becoming a huge business
and degrees are holding
less and less value.
I like to call it degree inflation.
By investing wisely along the way,
all the jobs mentioned in this video
have the potential to
make you a millionaire
without stepping foot in any university.
So if you're like me and
school really wasn't for you,
then it's not the end of the world.
There are plenty of options out there.
It's all about doing what you want to do
and not letting society's
expectations shape your future.
So I'm gonna leave the
next video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
And don't forget to pick up the free stock
and Bitcoin with the links below.
Okay. I'll see ya over there.