- What's the main difference
between someone on minimum wage
and a millionaire, knowledge.
Hey guys, it's Mark.
So today I'm going to help take someone
from below minimum wage to millionaire
by sharing the six steps
that allow me to do exactly that.
And they could do the same for you.
Dream.
- I felt lost within myself.
Like I truly did not
know what I wanted to do.
- [Mark] Finances.
- I have to say I'm also
a barrier erratic spender
- [Mark] Investments.
- So should we compare,
how we done with the investments?
So what was Tom's total job secrets
and what would you ask in interviews
when he says to you at the end,
if you've got any questions.
- [Mark] Side hustles.
- I can show you something
I'll be working on (indistinct)
- [Mark] And starting a business.
- It's time to start pursuing my dreams
is definitely a big thing for me.
- This is a video that you
don't wanna miss one second off,
so grab some popcorn and enjoy.
So it's so great to see you again, Toby,
I've been so looking
forward to you coming back.
- Yeah, I know, it's
good to see you as well.
Yeah, I'm glad to be back.
- If anyone watched the video before
we gave you $800 to invest in way,
and we wanna see how that's gone,
but the other purpose of the day
is try and find a path for you to follow
from this stage on.
And I firmly believe that
anyone can become a millionaire.
I don't think everyone
will become a millionaire
because some people don't
wanna take that path.
I know I've said this before,
but I'll say to you again,
you know, I've always thought
you've got so much potential,
without a doubt.
And it's just finding that path
for you to channel that potential on.
I think that you haven't
found that path yet.
- No, definitely I will
100% agree with that.
I've sort of lost myself
and who I am for quite a few years now.
I got into like a really
frustrating dilemma
of where do I wanna go?
- Mmh.
- Like-
- Do you think that's
a fairly common feeling
of youngsters nowadays,
- 100%.
I think it's really annoying to be.
Cause you go to school when you learn,
a load of subjects, but
then you get worried.
You go, which path do I take?
What if it isn't what you wanna do?
And I felt like definitely
with me after being at school,
I felt lost within myself.
Like I truly did not
know what I wanted to do.
Sometimes I didn't feel
like I was good enough
that I was gonna be stuck in a café job
or something like that.
And I think the worst bit
was seeing my paycheck
sort of get flushed away
because I wasn't feeling
good about myself.
And the only way I could feel
good was to go out and party
- And that feeling doesn't
last very long, does it.
- No it doesn't.
- It might be that evening.
And the next day you
actually got a headache
and you go, Oh, I got a headache,
I don't feel good today.
And I've flown Norma.
- Yeah, looking at the
bank in the morning off.
It's never, never a good thing.
The past sort of two years now,
I've been trying to sort
of get myself on track
- So be it like a spider's web,
you know, you're trying to
get out from the middle,
gradually working your way.
Oh, strands broken.
So that could be, I don't know,
I've been sacked from a job
or something like that.
So you'd backtrack a little
bit, come along the edge
and go up another one.
And there's always a
path out to that million
If I was to say to you, what's
your vision of the future
where you wanna be?
I don't know,
say by the age of 33,
could you paint a picture
of that life that you're gonna have?
You know, what car you've got?
What house you've got?
Whether you've got kids or not?
- Yeah, I think in about 10 years' time,
which I'll be 33.
Well-
- It goes very fast.
Yeah, I do see myself having a family
I definitely want a Tesla
after seeing the Tesla.
I mean, I'd like a house
with a nice garden,
have a dog, maybe two dogs,
maybe a German shepherd and a Husky.
- You're gonna have
some money to feed them.
- Yeah, no, definitely.
No, I really, really want dogs.
I think being just happy and stable,
I don't think you have to be like
the richest man in the world,
but again, you don't
want to be struggling.
- Yeah because money
certainly buys freedom.
It doesn't buy happiness.
There's quite a lot of people
that have a lot of money,
that aren't happy.
But money certainly
gives you the opportunity
to buy time for yourself,
which is quite good,
what I'm quite interested
in understanding.
And that's where the honesty comes in,
is what is your current situation,
how much are you spending for example,
- Well-
- On a monthly basis,
- Well, my situation
I'm currently unemployed
I'm doing some odd jobs here and there.
Obviously it gives me an income
every month of around 400 US dollars.
I'm currently living at home with my mum.
- Hang on, don't be apologetic about that.
You know what?
The longer you can live at home,
the better, absolutely the
better, your bills are low.
Okay, you might want to get an apartment.
You know, particularly
when you get girlfriend,
do everything you want
for you to have a bath
with the door open,
you can do everything, can't you?
It's amazing.
But you know, at the end of the day,
you know, all the while
you can live at home,
that's gonna be the cheapest living
that you'll ever, ever get.
Nobody expects you to live
life like a millionaire.
So all the while,
they're not expecting you to live
life like a millionaire dumb,
you just don't need to, you know,
you don't need to look rich.
- Is it Mark Zuckerberg?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, he doesn't dress
like a rich man at all.
Does he just...
- Not many of them do that.
You don't see Elon Musk
in all the designer gear all the time.
- Definitely dresses slightly, doesn't he.
- He is smart guy, but
he's not over the top.
A lot of people think it's about,
they want the designer clothes.
They want the fast cars,
the big house, the glamorous lifestyle,
and, you know, partying every day.
But the reality isn't that,
the reality is that they're
buying, you know, investments,
you know, they're buying property,
you know, they're
running their businesses.
They're becoming so financially free.
And that's what they're about.
You know, building that wealth.
you know, the people that
buy all these designer gear
are the people that wanna look rich.
And why spend it on some,
just to impress someone
that you don't even like?
- Exactly, I think it's
just a case of some people
just wanna prove themselves.
And you know, and especially
the richest of the rich,
they don't need to prove themselves.
- No.
- And they can feel comfortable
in wearing their own skin whereas...
- Comfortable with what they are.
- Yeah, definitely with a
lot of celebrities and stuff.
You know, they make this big money
from like a few records and stuff
and then waste it on all
Gucci and everything.
And then
- What's the point.
- You never hear about them again.
- They are going on.
- Yeah exactly, one time wonders,
- What do you have left a month out $400?
I'm guessing it's not gonna be that high.
- To be honest I have to say
I'm also a very erratic spender.
So in all honesty,
I wouldn't say I'm left
with anything really.
- The thing is that your proving though,
is you can get by every month on $400.
- Yeah, no, not even 400,
I think I could get by on
even just a hundred dollars.
- Yeah but that's making it
very, very, very difficult
so let's just take the proviso
that $400 is proved you can get buy on.
- Yes.
- So any increase on that through work
is you know, that's investible money.
- Yeah.
- And what about things like credit cards?
Do you have those or
any debts of any sort?
- No, none.
- Okay, well, not having debts obviously
that's a great thing,
absolutely great thing.
But not having a credit card,
that's a bad thing, because at the moment
you're not building up
any credit score, okay.
So, you know, the first
thing I'd say to you
is definitely get yourself a credit card
because at some point we've
aspirations and dreams,
you're definitely gonna want
to borrow at some stage.
- Okay.
- Now, to be able to borrow
you need a credit score,
to be able to borrow well,
you need a really good credit score.
So if they give you a credit card
with a thousand dollar limit,
then only spend a hundred dollars of it.
You know, because that
is a manageable amount
and only on the things you
are going to buy anyway.
So I know you don't drive at the moment,
but for example, for a lot of people
putting their gas on
the card is a good way
of doing it 'cause you
got to buy it anyway.
They can pay it off at the
end of the month in full
and that starts building
that credit score.
It shows that you're able
to handle your money.
And then when it comes to getting a loan
on a mortgage on a car,
preferably not a car,
but certainly on an asset.
You're more likely to get a better deal.
So certainly one of the
things I'd recommend
for you straight away is
to do that without a doubt.
- Yeah, so I apply for a credit card.
- Definitely, yeah.
- Okay, would I have to pay it back,
like so paying it back in full
is probably the best option.
- You definitely gotta
pay it back in full.
- Always back in full.
- Always. The other
thing we need to look at
of course is the investment.
- Oh yeah, definitely, I'm definitely,
I'm excited for this.
- I am absolutely loving
it because my inbox
and our comments on all the videos
have been, how has Tom done?
Everybody's saying, I can't
wait to the next round
so I can see how he's done.
So basically you need
to share that with me
because I haven't seen any of this have I.
- No you haven't seen no.
- I know you messaged me, didn't you?
- Yeah.
- Because you weren't sure
what this was all about
when I gave you the a hundred dollars.
- Yeah definitely.
- And I think didn't you say, in the text,
is it just the profits that are mine?
- I genuinely thought
it was just the profits,
I was keeping.
- No no no.
- So obviously to my surprise
it was like like that's all yours.
- No that's yours I'm giving you that.
Yeah. That's your little head start.
So that's what that's all about,.
- Oh yeah of course.
- Just to get you off and
running should we say.
- Yeah no, and you know
I'm really grateful for it.
And obviously, yeah, like
just it brightened my day
I should just put it that way.
- Hopefully it just,
well, that's nice to know.
I mean, that's why we started
the whole YouTube channel,
was purely was to try
and help other people
to see the possibilities, you know,.
And if you can see the possibilities,
then you can make it happen for yourself
if you choose to do so.
And not everyone else will,
but if you choose to do so,
then that's a great thing.
And if you'd like to get involved,
Webull are giving away free stocks
when you deposit a hundred dollars,
I'll leave the link down below for you.
And if you're in the UK or Europe,
you can use code Mark212[on Trading212]
and pick up a free stock.
I'm really excited, I
genuinely really excited
about these 'cause these
is about to kick in
And I said
- Yeah definitely.
- I'm looking forward to this.
- Right I think we will start start
with investment number one.
- Okay.
- Which was S&P 500 Index fund.
So the return percentage was 3.4%.
- Oh, that's very good.
- The profit I gained was, $6.77.
- Yeah well that's a good investment
because that's a steady investment.
- Yeah.
- It's a long term, so
you're not gonna get
high returns every single
month, every single year.
- No of course.
- And you're looking to try and get,
historically is about 8%.
That's when it starts compounding,
so you get for about 10 years, 12 years.
And the actual amount of
money you're putting in
is not as much as the
interest that's going in
quite often.
And that's how this compounding thing
starts going on.
It's like a snowball going down a Hill.
It just keeps getting bigger
and bigger and bigger.
I'll just keep it rolling along
and keep adding to it when you can.
- Yeah, just keep adding to it.
- You know, a monthly basis
is brilliant if you can
because you don't then miss the money.
- No yeah of course.
- Which is a good way of doing it.
- Yeah, definitely.
- So that's a good hit straight away.
- I'm happy it was a profit.
- Yeah.
- So, you know, it's not a loss.
So investment number two, into Tesla.
- Oh, that's right, yeah go on then.
- So the return was 29.77%.
Yeah so the profit I gained was $60.48.
- And Let's put this into perspective.
That's in a month and a half.
- That is in a month and a half.
- I could see you're
excited about it as well.
So that's good.
- I am, I'm so happy about it.
I mean, I love Elon Musk.
So obviously I was just like-
- He's a big charismatic.
- He is, he's literally
the real life Tony stark.
- Yeah he is.
- So you know he is
the real life iron man.
And, you know, with all
his other projects going on
like SpaceX and, you know.
- I can't get enough of it.
I'm constantly on YouTube trying
to find out when the
next rocket launch is in.
- I know.
- I'm so behind it.
- He's trying to revolutionize the world.
- I don't want to make myself sound old,
but one of the things I really wanna see
in my lifetime is humans on Mars.
- Oh yeah.
- Because my first memory as a kid,
I was two years old,
just over two years old
was man landing on the moon, you know.
- Yeah.
- You know, so just, just
seeing that on the telly
and remembering my dad
freaking out over it.
You know, we've not had that.
No, in our generations, and
I'll include you in that.
So I can't wait.
- Yeah, hundred percent
like even his ambition
to colonize it.
- Yeah, its amazing isn't it.
- Just makes you think like the people
that are gonna go there
eventually live there.
They're gonna have children.
They're gonna be the first Marshans.
- Exactly, yeah.
- And actually quite funny,
we were trying to figure out what the name
of somebody that would
be born on the moon is.
- Luna.
- That's what I thought.
but I don't actually
know what it would be.
- Lunatic.
- Luna, Luna, Lunatic.
(both laughing)
- Could be any of those couldn't it.
So that's another great investment.
- That is.
- So let's have a look
at the next investment
- Investment three was Google.
I don't know why,
but obviously in the back of my head
I just went like everyone uses Google.
Obviously they bought
YouTube out like years ago.
- So what's the best
feature on YouTube then.
- The like, and subscribe button.
- Yeah, and you gotta
smash that like button.
- Smash that like button.
- Just to help out the old algorithm.
The return percentage was 18.9%.
- For pulling one out the part
that's pretty good ain't it.
- Going for Google,
and then my profit was obviously $38.46,
- Again, a blind in return isn't it?
- Exactly.
- That moves us on to-
- The special one.
- I think this one's
your favorite, isn't it?
- Well, do you know that I did a video
not so long ago about obviously,
the same video really,
about looking at lots
of different investments
and I gave it quite a high risk level,
the crypto currency.
- Yeah
- And I think that was fair at the time,
- No, definitely.
- And it's probably fair now
but my word is that flowing
- It peaks like when you least expect it.
- I know, it's unreal
- So obviously I'm going to tell you-
- You're gonna hit with these numbers?
- I'm gonna hit you with the numbers.
- I cant stop smiling
knowing there's a good...
you know they're all good.
So I've gotta smile.
- Well, so return.
- Go on big percentage coming.
- 68%,
- Oh my life, that is so good isn't it
- 68% which means the
profit I gained was $135.31.
- That is amazing.
Absolutely amazing.
- And I'll tell you what,
every time I looked at it,
I was just like, go up, go up, go up.
or sometime I'd just check it
and it'd be a massive spike.
- Did you look at it every single day?
- I did look at it everyday.
- How many times, every
single day did you look at it?
- Like once.
- Did you just once?
I mean a few days you
looked a little bit more.
- Obviously it depended on a day,
like if I saw that they've peaked right up
- Yeah.
- Obviously I would
check it like a few times
during the day just to
see how much I'm gaining.
But like say if I saw written in a loss,
I'm not going to check it.
- No, of course not.
- No, I'd look at it,
see the red. and then go, like nope.
- Do you know the thing
with this investment
look at how excited you are,
I'm excited for you as well.
And this is the great thing.
And the hardest thing with
investing is starting.
- Yes.
- Just starting,
if everyone left school
and was given $500
and said, look, you have to invest that
you can move it around all over the place.
You don't have to add to
it if you don't want to.
And you can't have any of
it for the next five years.
All right.
It'll get everyone investing.
Wouldn't it?
Everyone would get the bag.
Everyone would hopefully
grow that money as well.
And once they have an
understanding in that
it will be such a great thing
- I Think it's because it's not something
that you get taught at school, is it?
- None of this stuff is
- It's definitely something
that everybody should get into
I mean, I'm loving it.
I really am.
And I did not expect it at all.
Like I obviously I've watched it.
Watching my friends do it,
and everything and I just
couldn't understand it.
I have to be honest.
I could not understand it.
- So should we compare how
we done with the investments?
- Oh yes, definitely
- Because I think carrot
has got the actual figures
that compare with yours.
So what was Tom's total?
- [Crew] Tom's total was $241.
- Wow, way that's a lot of money,
- It is a lot of money
- [Crew] You have over a thousand
dollars now that is yours.
- Wow almost last time you had
a thousand dollars while ago.
- Yeah.
- Definitely.
- That's all right then.
- I get that is blown away.
- So I've got to add this
little caveat to my one
from my very randomly
selected investments.
Some of which were the lottery.
Let's see how my one was.
- [Crew] You did $108
- Oh, damn I've crashed and burnt
That's amazing.
So you've done really, really well.
Then how much work did you have to
do to actually create that profit
in actual work?
- Nothing.
- That is pure passive income
- I just had to sit there I
think the only bit of work,
is obviously if I would
have put more into it.
- Yeah, well the work is-
- What just two buttons?
- Work you turn into money, isn't it.
- Yes
- So the work is earning the
money to be able to invest.
So generally, you know,
for passive income,
either costs you money to
create the passive income,
or it costs you your time.
So your time investment to
create a passive income.
Now I have swapped a lot
of my investments round.
I've actually piled every single one
that wasn't working well into Bitcoin.
- Oh, really?
- On the same day you invested in it.
Now I haven't got the figures,
but obviously even you can work from that.
That's a big number.
I've been absolutely flabbergasted
at the amount of growth on that.
- It is so crazy, I just
know....I don't know.
- But you got to remember,
it could be wiped out in
one single fails as well.
So it's definitely a
big bulls game this one,
- Especially those stories that you've...
have you heard all those stories
about people that had like
60 million worth in Bitcoin
and they just can't find the passwords to-
- I know,
I think there's even a story about someone
whose hard drive got taken
out by the rubbish dumped
because he'd finished with the computer.
And now he's trying to get the
council to allow them to dig,
to try and find where this computer
has been buried in the land field.
How about that!
- You joking
- No and there's millions
of dollars on there.
Millions of dollars.
- They're never gonna find that, surely.
- Well, they know roughly apparently
where they dump everything
So it's just a case of getting the license
and getting down there, but who knows?
It's just something I heard.
Well, Whoa, that's for sure.
- That's crazy.
And if you want to get involved
with his Bitcoin mania,
then you can pick up $10
worth of free Bitcoin
by using my link below for Coinbase.
So at the moment, are
you going to keep these,
investments exactly as they are?
Are you gonna move them around
or how do you feel about that?
- I mean, I'm really
happy with what I did.
So I'm definitely gonna
keep it in to the SMP.
And I think I just keep
adding to that one.
I think that's the smartest option.
'Cause obviously later on it will
be a bigger investment in my life.
- Well, most people have got
47 years of work in life.
And if they were to put
from 18 to retirement,
$200 away every single
month until they retired
they'll have over a million dollars.
- Seriously?
- Over a million dollars.
I've quite often said
and to my wife as well,
I put this money away,
it's not for us to spend or ever use
It's gonna be amount of money.
I said, yeah, it will.
But I'm trying to make the money
along the road to get
where we want to get to.
And yeah, that's purely insurance in case,
- In case of-
- Just in case.
And aint a bad thing to
have in the background.
- Definitely not.
- The next stage is really gotta be
getting yourself out there
and getting a job, isn't it
So what do you think you're going to
look for at this stage?
- I'm just trying to get any job
that I'm qualified for basically
and obviously it's also
depending on the distance
'cause I don't drive.
- Yeah that's a bit of a problem.
- It's a massive problem.
- Because I'd give you a job tomorrow.
If you could drive to work.
- I'm really good in a good cart,
(both laughing)
- Well, that's debatable.
How did you do when you raised the way.
- Came second thank you.
- Yeah second, first loser.
- Third, third.
- Oh, we're going back down.
- That it wasn't fair
because obviously you
and my mate Sam were
racing it out in front.
- And where did I start that last rise?
- Where did you start?
I just got lost.
- I started in the pit line cause I said,
look, I don't want to be on the front
it's no fun, I don't want to be going fast
on these people.
- Oh my gosh, it was funny though.
I have to say that was
a really good birthday.
- Obviously you've got to apply for jobs.
- Yep
- Now personally, I would
say apply for anything,
but don't worry about
what you qualify for,
what you want to do
just apply for anything,
anything that's out there.
You know, because obviously
we're over here in the UK
and the equivalent on a minimum wage
is about $19,000 a year.
So, you know, to me, that's
a job that's worth having,
you know, all the while
you've got that job as well.
One you're earning, but secondly,
you're employed when you
come to someone else.
If you come to me and you say,
well, I'm actually currently
working for someone.
I know your work, I don't know if you say
I'm sitting on my watch
and I'm not doing anything,
then you know, how does that appeal to me?
It doesn't really.
- No, of course its not good
- What about any interviews?
I mean, interviews, you've
got to ask certain questions,
What would you ask in interviews
when he says to you at the end
You know, if you've got any questions.
- I don't really ask questions.
I think most, I do ask the
questions during the interview.
So I get a lot of my answers
or sometimes I have a question
and it gets answered during the interview.
- At the end of the interview
when I'm interviewing is
the most important part.
It's your part to impress me.
- Yeah, right.
- When someone says no oh no,
I think we covered everything.
It doesn't really work with me.
Yeah, whereas if you came back with
you know, what prospects are there for me
to be able to move up and get promotion,
you know, or you know
what chances are there
for me to be able to learn more on the job
or what is it of my qualifications
that's worrying you?
- Yeah.
- Anything like that, you
got I remember that guy.
Yeah he asked a good question and, yeah,
he's not quite qualified for it,
but he wants to learn,
you know, that's great.
He wants to, he wants
to come up the ladder.
He wants a promotion
and hasn't even started.
He wants promotion, you
know, you'd look in for,
you know, somebody who
wants to be there long term.
You know, when you're a business,
a lot of money is invested in training
and teaching and people don't understand
that they're getting jobs.
They really don't, you know,
and it can take quite a
long time for an employee
to become profitable.
So if you're giving me the vibe
that you wanna be working
with me for 5 years, 10 years,
I'm gonna invest in you as a person.
- Yeah.
- And I want that sort of person,
so it's quite important how you interview,
and I think if you practice
that, that's really important.
- So yeah, definitely.
- How do you feel about that
because that's gonna change you
from how you're currently doing things.
- Yeah.
I think, definitely I need to like
ask more questions at the end.
- So obviously the great
thing about getting a job
is you've got all that
extra income coming in
and I should pay your way.
You know, it should be more than enough
from what you're saying,
you need to spend.
so after that you wanna start looking
at something like a side hustle.
Now, lots of the comments we got
from the video you appeared
in was they thought.
you should be a model
shouldn't be an actor,
but should be a model.
So how does that appeal to you?
- I guess it, you know,
it always comes down
to a confidence thing and
I don't think I was ever
really confident in myself for that,
but I'm definitely up for giving it a try.
- Okay, it's always all about
getting out there, isn't it.
Pushing yourself a little bit,
maybe getting with an agency
or something like that.
But I know you're obviously
you're a really creative person.
So, you know, that's the thing that
I think is your real mega
future without a doubt.
- Yeah, so yeah, I
definitely wanna start doing
some cosplay stuff.
'Cause obviously like if you're
watching the Mandalorian,
how cool would it be to
have the Mandalorian now,
but I can show you something
I'll be working on.
- Oh you have one with you,
- Yeah.
So this is sort of me testing
sort of a budget helmet
that I wanted to make, you know.
- What's that cost you to make?
- Nothing.
- Apart from your time,
- Apart from my time.
- Three, four hours, maybe a bit more?
- Yeah maybe more but I think,
I think less, to be honest with you,
- The thing would be to
do it as a side hustle
to start with, just to see,
you know, cause there could be
a good market for you out yeah.
- And you've got Comic-con and everything
where you can meet the actors and things
and obviously like people love that.
- People only want the
costumes for the bedroom don't.
(both laughing)
- Where did that come from?
- I'm just thinking of a storm trooper.
- Well, here you go.
- What I'd like to be doing is making it
more sturdy So like 3D printing,
- We're similar in some ways
you might not realize that,
but I like to design you know the things,
so all my aircraft that
I sell for my business,
I design those, but once I've designed it
and done all that work,
set up the manufacturer,
at that point, I'm only interested
in the sales of that item
from there on, and maybe tweaking it
and I'm onto the next
design at that stage,
because that can be produced.
It doesn't need me to be producing it,
and once you worked on another design,
you pop that into place
and gradually your catalog
of available products builds.
- Yeah, of course and I said
I think that's the best bit
because I get bored quite easily.
So it's always nice doing
something new every time.
- And you've got to do
proper customer research,
that's always really important as well,
you just show it to friends
and family they're gonna,
Oh, it's great, it's fantastic,
yeah produce a million of them brilliant.
But actually your real customer research
is what people would actually buy it.
And that's why it's always good you know,
building up an Instagram group,
I know you've started building
it on your Instagram following,
based around the model
in, I think at the time.
- Yeah I'm starting with
the model at the minute
and obviously side-hustle
eventually will be that.
- That's it and the good
thing with Instagram
is you can do a lot of
customer research on Instagram
because you can post a
picture or even just a concept
of an idea and if you get
a good response to that,
that gives you your
first customer research
and guess what?
It's free, free research.
- Yeah, definitely.
- You know, so you can't
go wrong with that really.
So I think you've got a great
future ahead of you, Tom.
You know, I think I've always sold that.
It's just a case of
getting us on that path
- It's time to start pursuing my dreams.
- So I'm gonna leave the
next video right up there,
don't click on it just yet.
Don't forget to subscribe to the channel,
smash that light button or ring that bell,
if you wanna keep up to date
with all the new videos.
Okay, I'll see you over there.