Hi guys. It's Mark.
I believe the biggest reason most people
don't achieve early retirement
is that they were never
given a step-by-step guide.
The only path that seems
to be pushed in schools
is to get a nine to five job,
save your money, work until
you're 65 and finally retire
when you're too old to enjoy it.
(rewind noise)
Luckily, one of the businessmen
I looked up to explained it
in a slightly different way.
He said the word retirement
should be replaced with the word freedom,
because once you reach a tipping point
when you have enough
money to stop working,
you have true freedom.
Every day, you can do
exactly what you want.
No questions asked. Maybe
that's relaxing on a beach,
sipping a pina colada,
or building businesses
that change the world like Elan Musk.
When you have the ability to retire,
it's entirely up to you
how you spend your time.
So on that note today,
we're going to discuss the plan
I used to reach my retirement
goal in my late twenties,
starting from $0.
This may be a little
extreme for some people,
but that's just me. I'm
either a hundred percent in,
or I'm not in at all.
Obviously you can take
this plan at your own pace
and who knows, maybe you'll even beat me.
We'll get into all of this right after
you hit that like button
for the al-tube you-gorithm,
as it really helps push
this video to more people.
Also make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Phase one is all about
your freedom figure.
This is the target that you have to reach
in order to have full
control of your life.
This is something you should know,
even if you've got $0 in the bank.
If you don't know your freedom figure,
then it's a bit like being
blindfolded in a running race.
You can't see where you're going.
So you may end up putting all your efforts
in going in the wrong
direction or even tripping up
and falling flat on your face.
The reality is there are
three types of people
in this world. There are
doers, dreamers, and drifters,
otherwise known as the three Ds.
Actually thinking about it,
when I was at school, they
gave me a cap with D on it.
They must have known I was a doer.
So let's start off with
drifters. They go through life,
living paycheck to paycheck,
without any financial aims,
they don't really see the point
of saving or investing money
as retirement feels like it's
not something a young person
needs to be thinking about.
Dreamers do have financial goals,
but they don't have any plans in place
to actually achieve them.
So they will forever just stay dreams.
And finally, doers. They
have financial goals,
but most importantly,
have a plan to reach them.
And that's where your
freedom figure comes in.
This is a very individual thing
and it all depends on how much
you want to pay yourself
each year when you retire.
There's actually a great
way to figure this out.
And it's called the times
25 rule. So let's firstly,
assume you want to make $50,000
per year without working.
Secondly, we would need
to multiply 50,000 by 25,
which gives us 1.25 million dollars.
The idea is that you're able
to withdraw 4% of this per year
without ever running out of money.
You guessed it, 4% of
$1.25 million is $50,000.
1.25 million dollars,
how am I ever going to
get that in seven years?
This video's a lie!
I know this may sound tough,
especially if you're starting
from $0, but it is possible.
No one said it's going to be easy,
but with the right
approach, it can be done.
I mean, if I can do it, then so can you.
In the early stages of
your retirement plan,
the way you think about money is crucial.
It's all about getting the
right mindset in place.
The key is to prioritize
building wealth over cashflow.
This is because building wealth,
it's about locking your
money away in assets
that increase in value.
Whereas cashflow gives you more money
flowing into your pocket.
Now this may sound great,
but it can lead to a variety of problems,
such as lifestyle inflation
and sky high taxes.
Cash flow is extremely important,
but more so later in life,
once you start to unwind.
This is why whenever I
made some extra cash,
when I was younger,
I made sure to reinvest
the majority of it.
Of course, I get it.
Sometimes it can feel really nice
to secure some profit and lock
it away in your bank account.
It can give you a false sense of security
knowing you've got all your
money sat in your account
for whenever you need it.
But the reality is you often
don't need as much money
as you think.
Forming a habit of in your cashflow
is absolutely essential when
it comes to building wealth,
as fast as possible and
hitting your freedom figure.
Phase two is laying the foundations.
This is kind of like building a house.
You need to lay a solid foundation
to ensure your house doesn't crumble
at the first sign of an earthquake.
Unfortunately,
70% of millennials now
live paycheck to paycheck,
which means they're building their lives
on an unstable base.
Just like building a house on quicksand.
If you find that unbelievable
then this is even more shocking.
40% of Americans with an income greater
than a hundred thousand dollars a year
are still living paycheck to paycheck.
This just goes to show how important
laying the foundations are.
And even though it may seem simple,
many people are failing at this phase.
There are four stages I considered
when I was in this phase
during my early twenties.
The first stage is paying
off high interest debt.
It's crucial to pay this off
before you even consider
investing in your money,
as high interest debt is holding you back,
but saying this,
it is very important to
understand the difference
between good debt and bad debt.
Good debt is anything low
interest that makes you money.
For example, the mortgage
on a rental property
or low interest finance on a laptop
to build an online business.
Bad debt is high interest debt
that doesn't make you any money.
For example, shopping for clothes
on buy it now later credit card debt,
or even a typical bank loan.
All of this debt needs paying
off as soon as possible.
I was in quite a lot
of debt when I was 18.
And in order to get out of it,
I used the debt avalanche method,
which involves making the minimum payments
on all my high interest debt.
Then I used any extra
money to pay off the debt
with the highest interest rate first,
which was my store credit card at 32%.
Crazy, I know. Signing up
for that was a huge mistake,
which I've talked about
in some of my past videos.
I then worked my way through the bad debt
with the lowest interest rate,
which was my car loan at
around 15% of the time.
Within a year, I'd managed
to get everything paid off.
The big lesson here is you
can't invest to build wealth
when being weighed down by bad debt.
Stage two is putting
aside an emergency fund.
This is essential for your foundations
because if you start investing
without an emergency fund,
you might find a few months down the line,
you get into a spot of bother
with an unexpected expense
and no cash to pay for it.
You will then have to
pull your investments out
to cover the expense,
and then you'll miss out
on the potential profits.
Stage three is building
a great credit score.
A credit score is a bit like your resume.
It follows you around in
life, is regularly updated,
and it helps lenders decide
whether you're a worthy borrower.
Having a good credit score
is especially important
if you ever want to get a loan
in the future, for example,
to buy your dream house.
You just never know when
you're going to need it.
I should have actually started
building my credit score
a lot sooner than I did because
it's so easy to get started.
All you need to do, as soon as you turn 18
is get yourself a credit card.
Start putting in a few
little expenses on it
like gas and pay that baby off in full
at the end of each and every month.
This way you pay no interest
and prove to the lenders that
you're a reliable borrower.
Stage four is reducing your tax liability.
Every dollar you earn has hidden costs.
Of all the expenses, however,
taxes can sting the most
and take the biggest
bite out of your money.
No one likes the tax man.
The good news is that
tax efficient accounts
can minimize how much tax you have to pay
and maximize your savings.
In my early twenties,
my income was really starting
to get eaten up by taxes.
So I started looking for the best ways
to save as much as possible.
I then discovered if I opened
up a retirement account,
the I can save money I hadn't paid tax on.
This is known as a 401k in
the USA and a SIPP in the UK.
Of course I will eventually
have to pay tax on this,
but as I'll be older,
I'll be in a much lower tax bracket
because I'll be earning less.
So hence, I should save
quite a lot of money.
But I didn't stop there.
I opened another account,
that allowed me to save
money that I'd pay tax on,
but in the future,
I wouldn't have to pay
tax on my capital gains.
Or in other words, all the
money that the money generated.
This is called a Roth IRA in
the USA and an ISA in the UK.
I firmly believe that everyone
should set up both of these
accounts as soon as possible,
as I know it really reduced my tax burden.
So once you've built up
these solid foundations,
it's time to start expanding.
Phase three is building
multiple income streams.
I like to think about it like this.
Imagine Spiderman is you.
The platform is your life,
and the skittle is your everyday job.
If you get fired, guess what's happening.
Now, imagine this.
Spiderman is you, the
platform's your life.
But now, you have multiple income streams.
The stock market could crash.
You could lose your job, or
your side hustle could fail,
but your life is supported
by your other income streams.
This makes it very hard
for someone or something
to come along and strike you out.
A secured job is nowhere
near as common as it once was
with the average person now
working 12 jobs in a lifetime.
There isn't one perfect
solution for everyone,
but something that has
worked for me over the years
is to pick side hustles
that take advantage
of my existing skills.
So I don't have to learn
something completely new.
This will often end up being something
you're passionate about
as you develop the skills
without even knowing it.
Sometimes we can lean towards
what will pay the most.
But when looking to
build long-term wealth,
sustainability is important.
So when waking up every morning,
being passionate about your
line of work is a great idea.
As Richard Branson once
told me over lunch,
there is no greater thing
you can do with your life
and your work than follow your passions
in a way that serves the world and you.
Well, that's actually one
of his most famous quotes,
but it did say something
along those lines.
It was about 20 years ago.
But one thing I do remember
all the details about
was the fantastic spaghetti
bolognese made for me.
There are many different side hustles
you could start such
as affiliate marketing,
E-commerce, becoming an
influencer, drop shipping
and even good old
fashioned window cleaning,
bin cleaning, driveway
cleaning, photography.
The list goes on.
The main takeaway here is
the higher perceived value
you have according to society,
the more you will get paid.
If you do the bare minimum
or your service doesn't
really help people,
you'll be paid the bare minimum.
It's important to go above
and beyond and provide value
as best you can to maximize your profits,
which can then be invested
to reach the end goal
of your luxury retirement.
Phase four is creating passive income.
Once you have your side
hustles and income in check,
it's time to start looking
into passive income streams.
Side hustle money doesn't last forever.
That's why you want passive income streams
so that your money can make
more money while you sleep.
This is why the rich get richer.
This phase is all about
multiplying your cash
and not chasing high returns.
This is why I always
talk about the importance
of consistent long-term investing.
The end goal is to be on the beach,
sipping a nice drink,
not worrying about anything money related.
Now I do always say that
no income is truly passive.
Everything requires a bit
of work here and there,
but the idea is to get
your money working for you
instead of selling your time.
There is only so many jobs
you can fit into one week.
And that's why trading time
for money has its limits.
I was working a nine to five
job plus all the overtime,
flipping cars on the weekday evenings,
working in a shop on Saturdays,
and tutoring people on Sundays.
I actually had no more time to sell.
So that's when I started looking into ways
to generate passive income
through the markets.
I'm talking stocks, real
estate and cryptocurrencies.
Well, maybe not crypto back
then. It wasn't around,
but I'm certainly interested in it now.
The stock market is probably the easiest
to get involved in, especially nowadays.
Maybe not when I was younger,
as you had to call up
your broker on the phone
and do all your trades that way.
Now it's all done on investing apps.
These apps also have great signup bonuses,
puppet.com are currently
giving you a free stock
worth all the way up to a thousand dollars
if you live in the USA.
And Free Trade are giving away
a free stock worth up to 200 pounds
if you live in the UK.
I'll leave the links down below
if you want to pick those up.
Both of these apps also
offer fractional investing,
which means you can invest
with as little as $2.
This has made it much easier
for the everyday investor
to get involved in the stock market.
It's always a good idea to
max out your tax advantage
accounts before investing elsewhere.
I personally like to put
the majority of my money
into simple, low cost index funds,
which are essentially baskets of stocks.
And like I said earlier, I
like to minimize cashflow.
So I always turn on automatic
dividend reinvesting.
Cryptocurrency is the
second area I would focus on
as it also has quite
a low barrier to entry
with apps like Coinbase
making it easier than ever
to purchase crypto coins.
However, it's definitely riskier.
By the way, Coinbase are
giving you $10 of free Bitcoin.
I'll leave the link below if
you're interested in that.
I personally only have 5% of my money
in well-known crypto
coins, such as Bitcoin,
Ethereum, and Cardona.
I believe that these are the coins
that will stand the test of time
and I'm not prepared to take the risk
of betting on a random
coin that might hit it big.
Like I said before,
my strategy is to get modest,
passive income from the
markets and make fast money
from my businesses.
Real estate is the last on the list
and this is honestly the holy
grail of wealth building.
However, it is a little
harder to get into.
If you're able to save enough
for a deposit on a rental property,
then you can really start
unlocking the power of leverage.
This is because you can get a
tenant to rent out the house,
which should cover the mortgage,
all while hopefully the
house increases in value.
You're basically getting
your house paid for
by someone else.
Obviously the earlier you can do this,
the sooner the debt will be paid
and the house will be yours.
Leverage is an amazing tactic
used by lots of rich people,
but it can be very dangerous
if not done correctly.
This is because you can
become over leveraged,
which means if things go bad,
and you can't meet payments,
your property could be repossessed.
Most people won't tell you this,
but I'm going to be honest.
This step by step strategy
will be hard to achieve
if you don't take your own initiative
and start a profit generating side hustle.
It's still possible
with a nine to five job,
but maybe not in seven years,
unless you have an
extremely highly paid job
that is also secure.
A nine to five isn't at all bad.
It's just most people need a side hustle
to kickstart that wealth building.
Also just a warning from me,
this is not gonna be easy.
Anyone that tells you
otherwise is lying to you.
You're going to have to
knuckle down like I did
and work hard for a few years
to have a lifetime of freedom.
After all, if it was easy,
then everyone would be doing it.
When you hit your first road block,
and I'm certain you will,
just think of it as a
challenge to overcome
and not as a complete disaster.
This plan will only work
if you stay consistent and disciplined.
I'm confident after you reach phase four,
you should be in a pretty good place
to achieve financial
independence and retire early.
So I'm going to leave the
next video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth
and don't forget to pick up
your free stocks and Bitcoin
with the links below.
Okay. I'll see ya over there.