How can you sit on a
beach, sipping a cocktail,
and all the while, money is
rolling into your bank account?
Well, it turns out this
is actually possible
with something called...
- Passive income.
But when millions of people
are chasing the same dream,
things aren't gonna be easy.
- Essentially, I'm broke.
- I don't have any money left.
- I filed bankruptcy.
- That's why I've done some
digging, and compiled a list
of 5.5 unique passive income ideas.
Let's talk about them.
Hi guys, it's Mark.
It's no surprise people love the idea
of not working for money,
but if that was the reality,
then we'd all be passive
income millionaires.
Although passive income doesn't exist,
leveraged income does.
This is by far the most effective way
to earn money long term,
and has enabled me to
become a millionaire.
However, it also involves various risks,
upfront investments of time and money,
and plenty of good, old-fashioned work.
Only highly motivated people will succeed
at creating leveraged income,
as you first need to
take a large upfront risk
in terms of time and/or money.
This is so that in the future,
you're able to earn more than
others could only dream of.
Leveraged income is money
you get for creating value,
and value comes from solving
a problem people have.
The best problems to solve
are the ones that aren't already flooded
with lots of people
offering the same solution.
This is known as finding blue oceans,
as red ones are full of people
tearing each other apart,
competing for the same income.
That's why I've made this
list of 5.5 unique ideas,
so that you have a much
higher chance of success.
Idea number one is Spotify playlists.
This is 1 on the risk scale
and 2 on effort level.
I haven't actually seen
anyone mention this idea
in any other passive income video,
so we're starting off strong,
but what am I talking about?
Well, the other day,
I was just flicking
through Instagram stories,
and I got an ad for a playlist.
I thought the music sounded
perfect for focused work,
so I clicked on it and downloaded
the playlist on Spotify.
I then thought nothing more of it,
and went on with my day, as normal.
Fast-forward to the next day,
and I was getting bombarded
with different Spotify playlist ads.
This is probably because I
interacted with the first ad,
and now the floodgates were open.
However, I then realized
the ads weren't being run
by Spotify themselves,
it was all individual people.
so that got me thinking.
If people are prepared to
spend money running ads,
then they must be making a profit
from owning these playlists.
so I did a bit of digging, and
it turns out I was correct.
This is a great way to
make leveraged income,
especially if you don't have
a lot of money to begin with.
You just need to spend time
putting together a solid
playlist in a specific genre,
gain followers,
and figure out a way
to make money from it.
There seems to be two
main ways of doing this.
I prefer the second, but
you may think differently.
The first way is to charge
up-and-coming artists a fee
for getting featured on your playlist.
When new artists are trying
to break into the scene,
they're interested in one
main thing, Spotify streams.
This is why an engaged
playlist is so powerful,
as once you've built it,
you can supply that artist
with a predictable amount
of monthly streams,
and charge accordingly.
You can even have a
different pricing structure
depending on how close to
the top you place their song.
This is certainly achievable,
and I could see you making
thousands a month doing it.
However, here are the issues.
It's against Spotify's terms of service,
and not very passive,
as you have to be in
contact with the artists
to sell song placements.
The second way is to start a Patreon.
An artist can sign up
to a monthly membership
in return for the chance
to submit their music to your playlist.
This is a lot more passive,
as the money would be
coming in automatically
on a monthly basis,
and all you have to do is review music
and update the playlist.
You could easily charge $5 a month,
and if you get 1000 artists signed up,
you could be making 5,000 per month.
This way also feels less dishonest,
as you can actually pick songs you enjoy
rather than taking money to
put bad music on your playlist.
The best thing of all is that
you can replicate the process
as many times as you like,
Idea number two is actually
called Merch by Amazon.
This is 1 on the risk scale
and 3 on effort level.
One of my friends is a
reasonable digital artist
and has been working on many
different designs for years.
He thought a good way to turn
those designs into profit
would be to sell printed T-shirts,
so he had thousands printed,
but unfortunately, none of them sold.
This was until he took a trip to Germany
and displayed his T-shirts at an event.
One of the designs started
selling like crazy.
Unfortunately, he only had
a limited supply available,
and was unable to meet the demand
as he had already invested all his money
into the stock that wasn't selling.
If only he'd known about Merch by Amazon,
as he would've saved money up front
and tested the market a lot faster.
Merch by Amazon is an on-demand
T-shirt printing service.
It allows sellers to create
and list T-shirt designs
on Amazon, for free.
There are no upfront costs,
and you get paid royalties
when a customer buys your shirt.
All you need to do is upload your designs,
choose the colors, and set a price,
then Amazon will take care of the rest.
Just think about it.
Going the traditional route means
that if you have one design,
and you want to sell that
in three colors, and four
sizes, to men and women,
that's 24 shirts, if
you only do one of each.
If 24 customers call you
and all want a large,
male T-shirt in blue,
you can only sell one.
Merch by Amazon takes
care of this for you,
and also saves you
from having to go to shows and exhibitions
to find a market,
as Amazon already has
a huge one established.
Like anything, the more effort you put
in researching customer demand,
the better you'll do.
Just remember to avoid
any copyrighted content.
This means you can't just start
printing T-shirts like this
without getting permission from Disney.
Storm Pooper!
Idea number three is vending machines.
This is 5 on the risk scale
and 4 on effort level,
so this idea is clearly a lot
harder than the first two.
However, Selecta
is one of the biggest
vending machine companies
in the world
and they reported sales
of over 1 billion in 2021,
which was up 3% on 2020.
This shows that the market is growing,
and the potential is huge.
Before I had my own businesses,
I worked as a carpenter's apprentice,
and can still remember clearly
the old vending machine in the workshop.
It cost me 10 cents for a
cup of coffee, a bargain!
It was such a good price
that the machine was actually
losing my boss money,
so he had a bit of a
predicament on his hands.
The income wasn't high enough
to cover maintenance costs,
the machine took time to refill,
and he couldn't raise the prices,
as the machine was so old
and no one would've paid the extra.
He was considering not
having a vending machine,
but he knew it was important
for us to have hot drinks nearby.
That's when a young guy,
he couldn't have been much older than me,
walked into the warehouse
and offered my boss a deal
he just couldn't turn down.
He offered to install
three new vending machines
in the workshop
and promised to take care
of all maintenance issues and restocking,
as well as giving him a
15% cut of the revenue,
so not only could my
boss please his staff,
he would also make a nice profit.
The new machines were a hit
and could justify charging higher prices
because of the better quality.
The guy who installed the
machines later revealed
that we were his first customers,
and now he has a huge business
with machines throughout the state
all paying him passive income.
The key to a successful
vending machine income
is to find great locations.
Once you've identified
a few different spots
and agreed a deal with the owner,
you can then secure a machine
that fits the customer's needs.
There are lots of used vending machines
going for low prices online,
which would be ideal if
you're just starting out.
You could even get a loan,
and spread the payments,
using the profits.
When picking things to
put into the machines,
it's a good idea to think about the demand
in the specific location,
and slowly test out different ideas
until you have the perfect mix.
After this, it's just
a case of hiring staff
and expanding your empire
so you're able to be as
hands-off as possible.
Idea number four is SaaS.
This is 5 on the risk scale,
and 5 on effort level.
SaaS stands for software as a service.
The beauty of this idea
is that they often use
a subscription-based pricing model,
so instead of a customer
paying once for your software,
they pay on an ongoing basis.
This can be monthly or annually.
This is great,
as it gives you a
predictable leveraged income
each and every month,
and the opportunity for
explosive nonlinear growth.
My best friend decided
to go down the SaaS route
at the exact time I started
selling physical products.
He specialized in software
that handled data for large
membership organizations.
These clients would have
100,000-plus members
so keeping track of all that
data was an issue for them.
At first, he decided to sell his software
as a one-time purchase.
However, he always had to
search for new customers.
When he made the switch to
a subscription-based model,
he increased his average
customer lifetime value,
and secured reliable leveraged income.
He later went on to sell this business
for multiple millions.
In order to achieve success like this,
you first need to pick the people
your software is going to serve.
There are two main categories,
businesses or consumers.
Serving other businesses is
often seen as the least risky,
as you can make more money per client
than if you're selling to everyday people.
Once you've got that nailed down,
you need to develop a
solution for a problem.
In my friend's case, it was
membership organizations
getting overwhelmed by their own data.
Everything up until this point
has been built upon assumptions,
so this is when you need
to put those to the test
and build a minimum viable
product, also known as an MVP.
With this, you'll be able
to conduct market research
and explore different pricing models
all the while you're
establishing your brand.
Now comes a hard question.
How do you actually finance this thing?
Well, if your solution is good enough,
then funding really won't be an issue.
Angel investors love SaaS startups,
so you could pitch for an investment,
or you could use your own
resources to fund the company.
This is known as bootstrapping.
Idea number five is digital downloads.
This is 1 on the risk scale,
and 4 on effort level.
The internet is definitely the
place to make lots of money,
as its growth has been exponential.
In 2020, there were 305,000
online businesses created,
compared to only 13,000 in 2019.
With all these people
starting online businesses,
you may think the competition
is going to be sky-high,
and yes, it's harder now.
However, I think there is
a huge gap in the market
for digital products.
Just think about it.
Everyone is talking about
eCommerce and drop-shipping,
but far less are actually
selling quality digital products
which have the benefit of
never running out of stock,
and no shipping costs,
as it's all done via the internet.
A friend of mine created
a digital template system
you can use on Instagram,
just off the back of a problem sent in
by one of her followers,
who wanted to stand out.
Within a couple of hours
and no more than $100,
the templates were designed,
and she now sells thousands
of dollars' worth every week.
This all came from helping another person
with their problem,
and she thought that if this
person needs these templates,
then others would, too.
If Instagram templates aren't for you,
then you can make YouTube banners,
sell stock footage, eBooks,
games, email templates,
or even online courses.
Idea number 5.5 is investments.
This is variable on the risk
scale, and a 1 on effort level.
Now, I hold my hands up.
This isn't exactly unique,
but I couldn't leave it out.
This is the truest form of
passive income you will ever get.
I've been investing in
different assets for years,
such as stocks, crypto, and real estate.
I like to see this as a way of
really multiplying my money.
I don't go for crazy profits,
as that can often lead to
people losing everything.
A good example of this is when
Luna crypto coin collapsed.
As soon as you can,
make sure to open up a
tax advantage account.
This is a stocks and shares ISA in the UK,
and a Roth IRA in the USA.
Your aim should be
to max out the amount of money
you're able to contribute
as the gains are completely tax free.
A good thing to remember
is to be fearful when others are greedy,
and greedy when others are fearful.
I know it's a cliche
saying, but it's so true.
If you're wondering where to invest in,
public.com are a great option,
and they're giving away a free stock slice
worth between 3 and 1,000 dollars
when you sign up and fund your account
with the link in the description.
Now, I need to address
something extremely important.
People will try and tell you
you need more than one
passive income stream,
which has some truth to it.
However, most people misunderstand
what this actually means.
The mistake I see people
making over and over again
is taking their time off
an idea that's working,
and splitting their attention
by trying something else.
You'll never get anywhere
if you're one foot in and one foot out.
However, I do agree with
creating multiple income streams
within the same idea,
because as you progress,
you'll find even more ways
to profit from providing
value to your customers.
So I'm gonna leave the
next video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you wanna grow your wealth.