- If I told you that you'd never retire
everything is getting more expensive
and then uncovered the terrifying
truth about retirement.
I was head in hands realizing
that I'd cripple myself
financially for the next year.
That would lead me to
revealing how I escaped,
retired early and how you can too.
My eyes were really opened
up to the possibilities
to make a mass income.
But there's a problem, the
system is rigged against you.
The worst thing I've always
no one really wanted to talk about money.
It was so taboo.
Hi guys it's Mark.
So I've got some news for you,
retiring with enough money to
enjoy the rest of your life.
Sitting on a beach, sipping
on whatever your heart desires
is becoming near enough impossible.
Every year, consumer debt rises,
owning a home becomes more challenging
and everything is getting more expensive.
This combined with supply chain shortages
the Russian-Ukraine War,
and an outdated school system
is a recipe for disaster.
Let me take you back to 1902.
When one of the richest men
in history John Rockefeller
created the school system
as we know it today.
As you can probably imagine
this system wasn't created
to help people become rich
and successful like him.
Oh, no, no, no.
It was invented to create
a nation of workers.
You see, Rockefeller was an oil tycoon
that needed an army of
people that worked hard
and didn't ask questions.
So what better way to achieve his goal
than funneling kids down a controlled path
with little individual treatment,
strict deadlines and
teachers enforcing the rules.
When I was at this school
I had no idea that
becoming an entrepreneur
following my dreams was even possible.
My teachers never really understood me
which meant I found
school extremely boring.
The worst thing I've always
no one really wanted to talk about money.
It was so taboo, after leaving this place
I initially went down the carpentry route
making wooden trash cans for
only a few dollars an hour.
This probably sounds all too familiar.
And this broken system is the main reason
why people can't retire.
I'm not bashing schools
or even the teachers,
but the fact that school
still doesn't teach
basic money management, investing,
or even building a credit
score is just crazy to me.
So you turn 18 and leave school
with little understanding
of how money works
and look for a job only to find
70% of jobs never get listed
meaning it's not what you
know, it's who you know.
This makes finding a job
all the more difficult,
but none of that really matters
because slimy credit card companies
are putting preapproval
letters through our doors
giving us instant access to
cash at 40% interest rates
with no consideration of the fact
that the majority of the population
don't know what APR even means.
Let load how to use a
credit card correctly.
As you can probably tell
that really grinds my gears.
Because of this, it's no
surprise that consumer debt
is over $15 trillion and
rising almost every year.
The world is changing so fast.
That school probably couldn't
keep up even if it tried.
Bitcoin was created in 2009,
and it's only now becoming something
people talk about as an investment
even though it's been
the best performing asset
It's very difficult to get ahead
and save money with low income,
especially at the moment
with 8.3% inflation
and supply chain shortages.
It's not a coincidence that fuel
and utility bills are
record break in highs.
And the people are feeling
this hit more than ever.
So the system is clearly
rigged against you.
However, I came from nothing and escaped.
And so can you, this might look
like a normal train to you.
However, this is the exact spot I sat
when I had a revelation about money
that would change my life forever.
After leaving school at 16,
I got a job as a carpenter apprentice
that required me to commute
on the train every day.
I remember one morning
looking around the carriage
all the passengers, both young and old
and I noticed they had
one thing in common.
They all looked miserable.
It was clear that not a soul
was looking forward to going to work.
It was almost like being on
a ghost train full of slaves.
I felt sorry for them until I realized,
I too was wearing the
same unhappy expression.
I was one of them, but
why was I so unhappy?
Well, it all boiled down to my finances
although it's a very popular saying
that money doesn't make you happy.
I think that was probably said by someone
that has never been broke.
Money certainly gives you freedom.
And the lack of freedom
was the main reason why
all of us were so unhappy
on the train that day.
I was only getting paid $2 an hour.
And from that, I had to pay $15
per week for my train ticket
and a fair over $15 to my mum for rent.
I had very little left
at the end of the week.
I thought to myself why
am I working so hard
and still getting nowhere?
Then I realized I'd taken
my eye off the ball.
I was getting so wrapped up
in going through the motions
and doing what I was told
that I'd forgotten to
manage my money correctly
and set goals.
When people don't have
solid financial goals
they turn into mindless zombies
living for the weekend
and never getting ahead.
This is when I discovered
the times 25 rule
although it probably wasn't
called that back then.
I pictured what my perfect
life would look like.
And then how much money I would need
to live like that per year.
I then multiplied that by 25
which gave me my freedom figure.
This is the amount of
money I'll need saved
so that I could fund my life
by withdrawing 4% from
my investments per year.
This is something everyone should do.
As it really put things into perspective.
For me, I became obsessed
with doing everything I could
to make progress towards this number.
I used to do lots of overtime.
This is because over 12 hours
I got paid double my usual rate.
My friends always used to
work just a nine to five job
and then go down the pub.
They never desired any extra income
as they didn't have a
solid freedom figure.
I also started tracking all
of my income and outgoings
with a pad and pen.
Nowadays, there's lots of different apps
that can help you with this,
but here's the best part of all.
I no longer felt like a slave
as I had a clear direction
and an escape plan,.
But things weren't
plain sailing from then,
a few months later, I was
on this very roadside.
I was head in hands realizing
that I'd cripple myself
financially for the next year.
You see, I was young
and I wanted a nice car.
So I bought a green Volkswagen golf
because everyone said
it would be a good idea.
Don't get me wrong.
A VW golf is a great car and I loved it.
But the issue is I took
out a loan for the car
which had a really high interest rate.
This kind of purchase is
typically always a bad investment.
I didn't care about this at the time.
Well, until I was stood at this
rotor with a blown up engine
this left me in a right state
'cause I still had monthly
car payments to make.
And now I had a $1,200 bill
on top to repair the engine.
I'm thankful for moments like this one
as it's the hard life lessons
that make you realize
something has to change.
I had car loans, repair
bills, credit card debt,
and more at the time.
So I thought outside of the box
and decided to use what is now known,
as a debt avalanche method.
The idea is, you use your paycheck
to make the minimum payments
on every single bit of debt you have.
Then use the remainder of your
spare cash to pay the debt
with the highest interest rate.
Rinsing and repeating this method
and taking one step at a time
is the most effective
way to clear debt fast
and can also save you a fortune
by clearing the highest
interest rates first.
It took me a whole year
of using this method
to get back on my feet
but I'm glad I put that chapter behind me.
I then bumped into a man
right here in this very field
who had changed my life forever.
As a youngster,
it's so easy to get
complacent about retirement.
Look, I get it when
you're 20 or even younger
it's not that easy to get
excited about retiring at 65.
If that sounds like you, then don't worry.
I was exactly the same.
However, I was very fortunate
because the man I met
on this model flying field
became a role model to me.
I didn't even know he was my mentor.
During casual chats,
he managed to completely change my mindset
by swapping the word retirement
with the word freedom.
This really resonated with me
as I've always chased freedom
over materialistic things
like cars and drip.
With my eyes set on freedom,
I knew I had to begin investing long term
and start building my wealth.
So I opened a pension account
and began investing 10%
of my standard wage.
Of course, nowadays
you'd open up a Roth IRA
if you're in the USA or
stocks and shares ISA
if you're in the UK.
These are essentially investing accounts
that allow you to grow
your money over time,
completely tax free.
However, there are limits on
the amount you can deposit
because otherwise they'd
just be too powerful.
Investing 10% of my income was a huge step
in the right direction.
It shifted my focus towards
not only making more money
but having my money produce more income.
By the way, if you wanna start investing,
then public.com are currently
giving you a free stock slice
worth between $3 and $1000.
When you use my link in the description
it's a great way to kickstart
your investing journey.
So at this point I was debt
free and I was also investing
but I was still working every hour
under the sun for other people,
but I couldn't shift this niggling feeling
that I was made for more.
Throughout my life,
I'd get glimpses of how
the other side lived.
Like when I used to walk past this mansion
on the way to school, when I was a kid
or installing staircases
in beautiful houses
eventually it became
just too much to ignore.
I remember the clear breaking point
I'd been slogging my guts out all day.
I took a brief pause to catch my breath.
And in that moment I looked up,
above me I could see the senior managers
working at their desk jobs.
They were clearly
getting paid more than me
but it looked like they
weren't working nearly as hard.
That's when it hit me,
that you're not paid
based on how much effort
you put into a job,
be that physical or
mental, you are purely paid
on the value that you
provide and nothing else,
no matter how hard I worked,
there was only so many products
I could produce in a day.
And that was the extent of my value.
As an apprentice, I was
also easily replaceable.
If I started slacking, that
was a secret that separated me
from the really rich.
So I started taking steps
to improve in other areas.
This led me to win the
Wheelchair Leadership Award
which helped me stand out as a person
that could add more value to the business.
However, my manager didn't like
that I was improving myself
and felt a bit threatened.
This led to him, bullying me
and ultimately I decided to leave my job,
but that job was never
gonna let me retire early.
The current retirement age varies
depending on when you were
born, but for the most part,
it's the ripe old age of 67,
and plans are already
in place to raise this.
Now, if you are subscribed
to this channel,
I know that retiring at an old age
is definitely not in your plan.
So let's look at exactly
how you can beat the system
and strike it big.
My eyes will really opened
up to the possibilities
of making mass income
in a humble model shop.
In my 20's, I decided to follow my dreams
and started working in a
radio control model shop.
Just like this one, this
is a huge passion of mine.
And one of the best ways to
make money is from a hobby
because it never feels like work.
While working in a model
shop, I was like a sponge.
I was soaking up every bit
of experience that I could.
I probably annoyed everyone in the shop
with how many questions I
asked but I just didn't care.
Armed with all this
knowledge, I took the plunge
and purchased my own
shop using a bank loan.
I was young and naive and had
no idea how to run a business.
All I knew was, I had to sell something
for more than I paid for it.
It's quite funny reflecting
on this actually.
At the end of the first day of trading,
I opened up the tilt and was
greeted by the most money
I'd ever seen in person before
it really drove home to me,
the value of what I was doing
and motivated me to keep going.
It's safe to say in my 20s,
I was living, eating,
and breathing business.
If I was out, I was at a networking event
or an exhibition to expand my business.
I'm so glad I made the sacrifices I did
as it really helped set
my family up for life.
If you wanna do the same
and even retire early
then you need to deliver
value on a mass scale.
The most achievable way to do this is,
to start a side hustle
and eventually transition
that into a business.
Well, unless you're very good
at kicking a football, of course.
Now, I know passive income
is the go to guru buzzword
but it really is an amazing thing.
I remember sitting right here
when I got my first rental payment.
It was fantastic because I
didn't have to do any extra work
to earn that income.
Of course, buying real estate.
Isn't the only way to start
earning passive income.
You can buy dividend stocks
that pay you every quarter
like Pepsi and McDonald's,
or even state crypto to
create passive income.
You need to spend either
money or time up front.
It's not something you can just set up
with a click of your fingers,
but it's worth the extra effort
as it can pay you for years to come.
Once my business was stable
and it was doing big numbers consistently.
I realized something when
driving home one night
I was building a sizable
investment portfolio
but I was only buying traditional assets
such as index funds,
which have been a great way to
build wealth over the years.
It's no secret index funds make you rich
but it's a very long process
and it takes years for the
compound interest to take effect.
So I decided to take a risk
on individual stocks with $5,000,
which at the time I
considered just my fun money.
If the investment went bad,
I would only be giving up a vacation.
But to my amazement,
the investment went from $5,000 to $50,000
in just a few days.
I could have let this ride
and potentially made more.
But me being me,
I secured that profit
and I never looked back.
I suppose what I'm saying here is,
sometimes when building wealth
is okay to take a calculated risk
especially with money that
you can afford to lose.
I'm not saying just YOLO your money away.
You need investments
working in the background,
a nice safety net of cash fall back on
and a secure income but sometimes
risk really does pay off
and it's quite exciting.
So I'm gonna leave the
next video right up there
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you wanna grow your wealth.