If I told you, we're on
the edge of a recession.
Dip, after dip, after dip.
And then gave you a look
inside my businesses.
It's costing me more
than ever to get hold of.
That would lead me to retracing my steps
during the 2008 financial crisis.
It was a huge shock to the system
when the crisis hit in 2008.
Allowing us to find out
whether this is a spiraling nightmare
or the financial
opportunity of a lifetime.
Hi, guys, it's Mark.
So you're an investor
and you're on a mission
to find the best place
to put your money and
increase it over time.
Where are you putting it?
Well, things aren't looking good.
This is how rocky the stock market was
in the first quarter of 2022.
Dip, after dip, after dip.
It's like being on a roller
coaster, only less exciting.
This is actually the worst
start to the stock market
in more than 80 years.
But that's just a graph.
What this really represents
is thousands of people,
just like you and me,
having their investments battered.
Almost every stock is down,
which means every day we're
just staring at a sea of red,
hoping that things will go back
to the days of positive returns.
So maybe the stock market
isn't the best option
for your money; however,
neither is keeping all your
money in your bank account
as we're facing extremely
high levels of inflation.
The government says this is at 8.5%,
but in all honesty, I
think it's much higher.
On top of this, Putin has
decided to invade Ukraine,
leading to a devastating war
and a squeeze on global supply chains.
This has a side effect of
making certain commodities,
like oil, more expensive,
meaning filling up your car
is hitting your wallet like never before.
This is causing you to have less money
that is quickly becoming even
less valuable by the second.
This pressure on finances has brought
to the surface a common
fear of a looming recession,
and it's fast becoming a reality.
For the first three months of this year,
economists assumed we would grow by 1.1%.
But what actually happened was far worse.
We saw a 1.4% decline,
which means we are halfway
towards a recession.
This means if you put
money into stocks, Bitcoin,
and even your bank account,
you're probably gonna
lose money at the moment.
Honestly, I can see why you would think
that this mission to find the
best investment is pointless
as you seem to be just
throwing your money away.
This thinking has led
to a general loss of
interest in the space,
but could this be the perfect opportunity
for you to make your millions?
Let's take a closer look.
- The stock market is now down 21%.
- Worst day on Wall Street
since the crash of 1987.
- The most serious recession in decades.
- We're now down 43%.
(dramatic music)
(keys clacking)
- But first, I'd like to thank
today's sponsor, public.com.
Public is an investing platform
that I've been working with
for almost two years now
that helps people be better investors.
On Public, members can
invest in stocks and ETFs
to build a modern diverse portfolio.
And even if you're not sure
what exact stocks to invest in,
with Public, you can
explore themes of stocks
like sports, green power,
and even the metaverse.
They also have town halls
where community members
can ask business leaders
questions directly
and watch them answer their
questions live in the app.
And the best part is they have $0 fees
on standard stock trades,
and you can get a free stock slice worth
between three 3 and $1,000
once you funded your account
with my link in the description.
Thanks, Public, for
supporting the channel.
Now let's get back to the video.
As a business owner, I'm
one of the first people
to feel the effects of a coming recession.
I remember seeing the signs in 2008.
People were starved of access
to finance, businesses failed,
and job losses soared.
My businesses source raw
materials from abroad,
deal with foreign factories,
and distribute in shops
as well as the internet.
This gives me a unique perspective
on supply chains and customer demand,
which could be early indicators
of a coming financial collapse.
Sure, you could look at indicators
like the Consumer Price Index,
but these are heavily
influenced by governments,
and it's very easy for them
to manipulate the figures and lie to us.
However, one thing they
don't have control over
is my businesses,
so let's look at how
I was affected in 2008
and compare them to the
problems I'm facing now.
By doing this, we should be
able to get a better idea
of the true financial
situation we're facing.
So let's follow the
journey of this model plane
that was designed by me and
is sold all over the country.
(keys clacking)
So all the products we buy start
in the form of raw materials,
and it's exactly the same
for my model aircraft
as we use plastic, wood, and
also electronic components.
So knowing how raw materials
of price is important
as it has a direct impact on our wallets.
When the 2008 financial crisis hit,
the manufacturing sector
suffered severe consequences.
Industries such as machinery, metals,
and transportation
equipment had huge drops
in customer orders by up to
42% within a single year.
As supply and demand have
an inverse relationship,
this meant that the
cost of my raw materials
actually decreased in 2008
as they were eager to sell
to anyone that had the money to buy.
However, in 2022,
the raw materials market is
under considerable strain.
It's costing me more than ever
to get hold of the raw materials
that are required to produce my products.
This is because market
demand is still high,
and when this is coupled
with reduced supply,
this continues to keep material prices
at rates never previously seen globally.
One of the raw materials I require
to make this model aircraft is balsa wood.
The issue is it's in
extremely high demand,
and one of the contributing factors
is that it's being used in wind turbines.
It's even got to the stage when
I've had to put my customers
on a three-month waiting list.
This is just one example of
how increased raw material cost
is impacting the everyday person.
(keys clacking)
So once the product has been produced,
it actually has to get to me,
and this is where supply
chains come into play.
Now that our everyday products
come from all over the world,
supply chains affect us more than ever.
On the run up to 2008,
things were going great
and economy was booming.
During times like this,
factories really ramp up
their manufacturing capacity
by investing in more
equipment, facilities,
and workers in order to meet the demand.
This leads to supply chains accelerating,
costly transport being accepted,
and large batches being produced
because the goods will
be sold at some stage.
It was a huge shock to the system
when the crisis hit in 2008,
and supply chains had
to totally reevaluate
their business models due
to the lack of demand.
Nobody seemed to have any money,
which led to shrinking customer orders,
increasing competition,
and a decrease in margin for
the manufacturing industry.
However, 2022 is completely different.
This is because of the pandemic.
We saw a complete slowdown
in our actual supply chains,
and they're still not
back to full capacity.
This means that demand
far outweighs supply;
therefore, shipping this product
and many others from China
is getting more expensive.
Ships that used to take four
weeks are now taking six.
A big reason for this decrease in speed
is the rising oil prices
as container ships can save
up to 25% of their fuel cost
just by going slower.
The last container I got
into my warehouse cost me $17,000 to ship,
which is absolutely insane
as pre-pandemic, it cost me $4,500.
That was the best price I ever got though.
(keys clacking)
Once this product reaches me,
it has to be handled by my warehouse team.
This, obviously, has a lot
of costs involved with it.
During times of recession,
most businesses are looking to cut costs,
and this is when people lose their jobs.
In 2008, I was mostly
concerned with my rent prices.
This is when I made the decision
to buy all the buildings my
businesses now operate from
so I no longer have to worry
about landlords increasing my rent
and squeezing my profit margins.
In 2022, I am even more
focused on cutting costs.
Recently, I changed all my light into LED
so I can save on increasing
electricity costs.
I've also implemented automatic lighting,
so the lights aren't
left on unnecessarily.
As more people lose
their jobs due to cuts,
this causes the economy to grind to a halt
as people have less money to spend.
That brings us onto the
final trip for this product,
and that's when someone
buys it and takes it home.
This can happen in-store
or via the internet.
When less people are buying
products, it decreases the GDP,
which pushes us into a recession
if growth is negative for
two quarters in a row.
In 2008, well, 2010 is
when it really impacted me,
demand was extremely reduced
due to most people being low on cash.
Whereas, now it seems like
people have more money
but supply chain issues and
worries about the recession
are causing the main problems.
I have huge demand for
products I can't get
but lower demand for products I have.
So as we can clearly see,
history is not repeating itself.
This recession seems like something
completely different than before.
But the real question is,
is there an opportunity for you to profit?
Well, I've got some good
news and some bad news
about whether or not this
is the financial opportunity
you've been waiting for.
The good news is history has shown
that the US stock market
recovers after a decline,
and investors that have
stayed in the market
for the long term have benefited the most
from the recoveries.
It's a bit like in February and March 2020
when the pandemic first got real.
Imagine selling here, right at the bottom
for fear of what was to come,
only to have the price rebound
and saw to new heights in the
space of only a few months.
I'm like a squirrel
during market declines,
grabbing as many acorns as I can
and hoarding them through the winter
as buying low is where
the real money is made.
And let's be honest,
the recession doesn't
always mean a decline
in the stock market.
You can't time the market,
but index fund investing
and picking the right defensive companies
has always been a great strategy
that I've used in the past.
Now the bad news is, historically,
the stock market takes anywhere
from six months to two years
to recover from a recession,
which really isn't good for psychology
when investing consistently.
This could also impact you more than most
if you're on the verge of retirement
and can't weather two years of no returns.
And let's not forget,
not every company makes a swift recovery
and some never bounce back at all.
Overall, I think job
security is really important
to ensure a constant reliable income.
Extending your emergency fund
from three to six months,
or maybe even more, should stop you
from having to sell your
investments at a loss
should you hit financial difficulties.
I've personally tweaked
my investment strategy ever so slightly
to include more recession-proof
businesses and industries,
as well as consistently
investing into index funds.
Investments like crypto
just don't have enough
historical data surrounding them
to make an educated guess
So I'm gonna leave the
next video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if you
wanna grow your wealth, okay?