I've got a prediction for 2032,
and it may be your key
to becoming wealthy.
- Artificial intelligence
and the financial technology
is valuable data.
Why am I sharing this with you?
Well, the truth is no one
knows what's gonna happen
over the next hours, days or even months.
However, I believe I can make
an educated long-term prediction
based on my years of experience.
I mean, I had a hunch
about the mass adoption of
smartphones in early 2012,
which meant that investing
in Apple paid off big time.
- [Reporter] Apple finally hits
the $3 trillion in market cap value.
- Now I'm interested in
predicting what's next.
This is quite a risky
video for me to make,
as you may not agree with me,
or I could just turn out
to be completely wrong,
which would be embarrassing.
However, I'm confident enough
with my 10 year vision,
that I'll look back at this video
and at least hit a few home runs.
I've never actually
spoken about this before,
but if you wanna get on the
fast lane to millionaire status,
then you need to have a
clear vision for the future.
This applies to everyone,
from investors to everyday people
that just want to work a 9:00 to 5:00 job.
The world is like a river,
forever moving forward
with a strong current.
If you are a strong swimmer,
then sure you might be able to swim
in the opposite direction for a while,
but you will eventually burn out.
The secret is to put all your effort
into swimming fast downstream,
so the current carries you along.
I mean, have you ever thought,
"How is that person so successful
when he is nowhere near as
smart and skilled as me?
I deserve more."
Now, that's the case for a lot of people.
However, they're just not
positioning themselves
in the right places.
The truth is anyone can become rich
by just working in an exploding industry.
But if you are able to be one
of the leaders in the space,
then you'll are become extremely rich.
Everyone has their own unfair advantages.
So the magic happens when
you identify how your unique
skill set fits into one of
these hyper growth industries.
Imagine these as your flippers
that help you swim
faster than anyone else.
So I'm gonna make five very
strong predictions about the future.
Maybe not all of them will be correct,
but I'm willing to put my neck
on the line and say a few of them will be.
(upbeat instrumental music)
You may not agree with
what I'm about to say,
especially the last one.
However, my five predictions
may help you think long-term,
and make your choices
based on a 10-year horizon
in terms of job, side hustle,
business, and even investments.
Prediction one, all our
finances will be digital.
This essentially means
that we'll be living
in a cashless economy.
I honestly don't think
that's too much of a stretch
as when you watch any sci-fi film,
people aren't carrying around paper money.
It's always credits.
This takes me back to 1978,
when I was just a boy,
there was a sci-fi series
called "Blake's 7",
and it was all based
around stealing credits.
I even had to ask, "Oh, dad,
what are these credits?"
And he said, "It's money of the future."
This dystopian future
scares a lot of people.
Many from my generation
don't see the value
in digital currencies as they
don't believe they're real.
However, if you think about it,
why are we carrying around pieces of paper
and exchanging them for items
in such an interconnected digital age?
Financial technology companies are also
some of the best funded
startups in Silicon Valley,
with employees earning
multiple six figure salaries.
Many of these companies
are also putting their
money where their mouth is.
They believe so strongly
that financial technology is the future,
that they're willing to lose millions
Many people are skeptical of crypto
because of the wider array coins
with no real purpose and
crazy price movements.
However, I see a lot of similarities
between the pandemic crypto boom
and the dot-com bubble of the late '90s.
Lots of stocks that just owned
catchy (indistinct) names,
went to the moon,
although most had no business
plan to back them up.
This is extremely similar
to coins like Floki Inu,
pumping like crazy all because
it's named after one of Elon's dogs.
When the dust settled in the early 2000s,
some of these internet companies
with solid business models kept building
and reached new all-time highs,
but this time based on true
value, such as Amazon.com.
The blockchain technology
behind cryptocurrency is a game changer,
as it increases trust,
security, and transparency,
as everything is traceable.
All of which makes it very attractive
to governments as taxi
evaders will be easy to spot.
However, it also means that we'll be able
to see exactly how our
tax is being allocated,
and spot any potential embezzlement.
The point I'm making is
not all cryptos will be the future.
However, there will be some
that will win in the long-term.
If all countries start
creating their own coins,
there will be a need for a
universal global currency,
and Bitcoin might be
able to fill this role.
The future of blockchain
technology is unclear,
but I feel we'll be using
it without even knowing.
It will be adopted by businesses, banks,
payment apps and everything in between,
paying with your risk wherever you go.
Prediction two,
artificial intelligence
will dominate all sectors.
When I say artificial intelligence,
it's very easy to jump to conclusions
and envision of future where
we're all ruled by robots,
a lot like Skynet in the Terminator films.
However, in reality, AI is all around us,
and it's intertwined with our lives
and will only get more powerful.
Imagine a world where everything
you do is informed by AI,
the restaurants you visit,
the medicine you take,
and even the people you date.
This could end up a catastrophe.
However, if done correctly,
it may usher in a new
golden age of innovation
with technology creating technology.
AI is essentially intelligence
demonstrated by machines,
but it actually goes far deeper than that.
I'm sure you've heard me say,
"Smash that like button
for the YouTube algorithm."
But what does that really mean?
Well, YouTube are a massive business,
and have 720,000 hours of footage
uploaded to their site every single day.
But with so much footage
comes a great challenge,
and that's showing the right
videos to the right people.
That's where AI comes in.
As YouTube can't have hundreds of people
sitting behind screens,
pushing buttons and deciding
who sees what video,
as it's just not cost effective.
If that was the case, I'd
have bribed them ages ago.
It feels like not even the
people that work at YouTube
know how these algorithms
operate on a deep level,
as they have essentially
taken on a life of their own.
This type of AI is more powerful
than you may first think,
as it has the ability
to influence millions,
and maybe even change the
result of future elections.
You don't have to be an engineer
to gain exposure to this
fast growing sector.
You can benefit massively
by investing in companies
that have AI as a core component
of their business plans.
Take Tesla, for example.
On the surface it may look very
overvalued as a car company.
However, that's because
there is a lot more going on.
Every vehicle Tesla has sold
has more than four cameras,
which Tesla is feeding
into their self-driving AI.
I mean, what other car company has access
to this much real world data
to fine-tune their algorithms.
They're likely years ahead of anyone else.
That's not even where it stops.
Elon Musk has stated that
Tesla's humanoid optimist robot
will be worth more than the car business.
I'm not saying to go
out and invest in Tesla
just because I believe in it long-term.
Of course, it's important
to do your own research.
That's why I love using the Public app,
as they have a community
of notable investors
all eager to help you
be a better investor.
For a limited time,
they're also given away
a free stocks slice worth up to $1000,
when you sign up with the link below.
Prediction three,
over 80% of our energy will
be from renewable sources.
This one's just inevitable.
It just depends on how quickly we're able
to transition from fossil
fuels to renewable sources.
This transition towards
clean energy is being
supported by many
governments over the world.
By 2030, new petrol and diesel cars
will be banned in the UK
as part of the government's
10-point green industrial revolution.
The ban is undoubtedly set
to shake up the motor in
industry in a big way.
Renewable energy will be a
highly lucrative industry,
as they are set to account
for almost 95% of the increase
in global power capacity through 2026,
with solar power providing more than half.
The amount of renewable capacity
added over the period of 2021 to 2026
is expected to be 50% higher
than the previous five years.
But how can we use this
information to benefit?
Well, renewable energy stocks
could perform very well
over the next decade,
for example, Enphase.
Whereas fossil fuel stocks
and car companies that
don't adapt could fold.
This may sound unbelievable
as oil giants have
dominated for many years.
However, the top companies
are always changing,
and this essential move to renewables
could be the spark that
sets everything on fire.
Prediction four, content
will be more immersive.
Our entertainment's been becoming
increasingly more realistic
over the last decade.
Just think about it.
First we had online
blogs, next it was photos,
now we have access to 5G networks,
with the ability to stream
HD video to almost anywhere.
The question is, where do we go from here?
I believe in 10 years time,
content won't be about passively watching.
It'll be about experiencing.
Imagine combining gaming with films,
where you can be your favorite character,
experiencing being in the
cockpit flying fighter jets,
or alternatively, learning
about the dinosaurs
while having a picnic surrounded by them.
As you're probably aware,
I'm not the only Mark that's
predicting this for the future.
Mark Zuckerberg rebranded Facebook as Meta
and is placing his chips on the metaverse,
spending tens of billions a
year to make this a reality.
This is essentially a huge gamble
he has little choice about making,
as Facebook are being
backed into a corner.
This is because Apple has really affected
Facebook's ability to harvest our data
with the introduction of iOS 14,
which is in turn having
a huge effect on their
advertising revenues.
Meta knows the importance
of controlling the hardware
if they want to be able to
harvest more data points,
and therefore they need their own devices.
However, Apple dominates the phone market,
Samsung rule the TV sector,
and Microsoft and Sony
have the gaming market.
So they could either
compete for the scraps,
or find a completely fresh market
and make a bet on the future.
I believe immersive content is the future.
And according to Statista,
the global metaverse market
will soar to 678 billion by 2030.
There are certainly a lot of
privacy issues to work out,
but the possibilities are endless.
Prediction five,
physical asset, like data
driven companies will rule.
He who rules the data, rules the world.
An increasing amount of companies
are reducing the amount
of assets they hold,
and relying more on their brand
and the value of the data they harvest.
A great example of this
is the hotel industry.
Many people believe it's
being disrupted by Airbnb,
who are making comparable amounts of money
without owning a single hotel,
and instead leveraging the
real estate of the users.
However, something that
may surprise you is that
most hotel chains nowadays
don't actually own much real estate.
The traditional hotel business model
was to build or buy a hotel and run it
until it was able to pay
back the initial investment.
But this often takes
in excess of 10 years.
This leads to a number of issues.
However, the main one is cash flow.
As many hotels are very seasonal,
they need a constant stream of guests
and money coming in to
justify employee wages.
This is why they've
adapted their business plan
to more of a franchise approach.
Instead of building a new hotel,
they simply approach an
existing independent hotel
and offer them the privilege
of branding their hotel,
as a Hilton, for example,
in return for a percentage of the profits.
This means the owner never has
to worry about advertising,
and the initial upfront investment
to the hotel chain is very low.
In 2032, digital assets will be seen
as far more valuable than physical ones.
The facts are all leading
to this conclusion.
Data determines what products you buy,
what ads you see, and companies
know everything about you.
In 2021, 71% of video game sales
were digital, and not on disc.
No wonder blockbusters went bust.
If we're already making
progress like this,
imagine what 2032 will be like.
I feel like the predictions
I've made in this video
lean towards a digital world.
So if you want to become very wealthy,
then allocating some of
your investment budget
to these areas might be a good idea.
As far as fast money goes,
just remember to swim with the current,
and you'll most likely
end up in a sea of wealth.
I guess I'll look back at
this video in 10 years time
and see how many of these
predictions came true.
So I'm gonna leave the
next video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if you
wanna grow your wealth, okay?