There are car dealers,
there's specialist car dealers,
there's supercar dealers,
and there's Tom Hartley.
They're worlds apart.
- [Interviewer] This is Tom Hartley.
Middle school dropout turned billionaire,
who sold over $5 billion worth of cars
to the rich and famous.
Making him Britain's top supercar dealer.
- I wasn't learning at
school, I was called a dunce,
I couldn't read.
It was always my desire and my dream
to be the most famous and
the best at what I do.
And that's exactly what we are today.
This complex cost 10 million.
The lightning system is 300,000.
The lift was 275,000.
This building's made with handmade bricks.
They're £2 a brick, £2 a brick.
We can at any one time
carry stock from 40 million
to a hundred million.
Money's not everything.
Well, everywhere I go, money's everything.
I founded this business on my own back.
The business is worth well
over 300 million today.
As a mature man yourself
and a successful person yourself,
you're going to get doubters in life.
And if you can't handle rejection,
you're never going to make it in life.
- This is the story of how a
young man went from nothing
to becoming a millionaire.
Only to lose it all and
then go bigger and better
than before with his estimated
net worth now sitting
at around a billion dollars.
Right, so today we're setting
off to visit Tom Hartley.
He sent me the address to his estate
and I'm not really sure
quite what to expect,
but I am certainly very excited.
I've always put my
success down to passion,
as I believe this is the
key to pushing yourself
past your limits, in
business and in life as well.
So, I'm really interested
to see what Tom thinks.
The next time you see me,
I'll be sat down with the man himself.
So did you ever feel different
to the others at school?
- I wasn't learning at
school, I was called a dunce,
I couldn't read, I wasn't interested.
And I was told by a school
teacher called Mrs. MacDonald
that I was gonna struggle in my life.
I'd start dodging school
and a friend of my father's
who owned a taxi business, he
was taking me to the auctions
and I'd watch what was happening
'cause I was interested
in watching cars be sold and
bought and how auctions worked.
So, the first deal I'd done,
I was just, before I was 12 years old.
- So you sold your first
car at 12 years old?
- I bought and sold my
first car at 12 years old.
I bought it from a guy called Billy Barty.
He had a new Range Rover
coming and it was £1,950.
I also knew a relative of my father's
who wanted to buy a new Range Rover
and you couldn't get them.
I put the deal together, it's
called supply and demand.
And I earned £250 and
it was a lot of money.
£250 in 1971 was a lot of money.
And that was the start of the journey.
So some of the heritage here
over the years I've enjoyed.
- [Interviewer] Look at all these.
They're amazing, aren't they?
- Yeah, you name an MP,
you won't find a name that
won't be in this office.
There's no computers on here.
It's a telephone, piece
of paper and a pen.
That's what I rely on.
You know, everybody from under Lloyd Weber
to the Sultan of Brunei,
Rod Stewart, Elton John.
- [Interviewer] Yeah.
- [Tom] They've all been
here. They're all there.
- So when you were a
youngster, could you really see
that you'd have all your family around you
as well as these beautiful showrooms?
- Yeah, I mean, I had the vision of that
and I'm living it now.
I'm living my dream for my son Tom.
Passed his driving test in a Ferrari.
And they set up the full
television station here
and filmed it live.
- Amazing.
- From here.
- Yeah.
- Going away and coming back.
(Interviewer chuckles)
A 17 year old.
- So would you say the drive
to be the best you could be
is what pushed you forward?
- Like everything in life,
to be successful you have to take risks.
I broke a few rules at that age, you know,
I drove on the road at 14.
- So did you get stopped
by the police at all?
- Yeah, I've been stopped.
I was 14, I drove a Rolls Royce.
Back in the seventies, guys,
when you got stopped by the police,
the routine check is
nothing like it is today.
You could give your name
to be Peter Johnston
17 Main Street.
They took that name and address down
and they said they'd write to you.
That was it.
You never heard no more.
Because I was in such a rush
to get to where I wanted to get
to, in life and in business,
with the ambition that I had
and the dream that I had.
I wanted to get there quickly
and I had to break some rules.
I discovered a loophole in importing cars.
To an extent, it was like
a cartel in the business.
I was importing, at that time,
probably 10 or 15 cars per week.
when I was importing cars in 1978,
you got four and a half
deutsche marks to one pound.
So, the point I'm making for
yous who can't calculate,
I was able to buy cars from
the factory, import them,
and sell them to dealers in this country.
It was just an unbelievable loophole
I found at the age of 17,
just before my 17th birthday
I was a self paid millionaire.
- So, the classic territory.
I recognized this Porsche.
I had one of these back in
the day with a whale tail.
I had a 1976 Carrera.
And this Ferrari here.
Is this the most expensive car
you've currently got in stock?
No, we've got that car there
which is three million,
this a 1.6 million.
- So when you'd made that first million,
was it all plain sailing from there on?
- It just went crush.
My world was turned upside down.
I didn't lose a million 'cause
I gambled it or I wasted it.
I lost a million because
there was a technicality
brought out because of my success.
The manufacturers, the giants,
BMV, Mercedes, and Porsche
got together on this
young kid, 16 year old.
They've pitched a law out
that you can only pitch
one car, one person.
And we're talking about a
lot of money on deposit here.
A big part of the million.
Here is a young guy who's made
a million and lost a million
and he's not 20 yet.
- How did you feel when
these car companies
started ganging up on you?
- I was overwhelmed because
it was out my control.
I couldn't take on Mercedes Benz,
I couldn't take on Porsche cars.
I couldn't take on BMW cars.
I stood the pain of the
loss for my reputation.
Gets me choked up sometimes
talking about this.
I went back to living in
the caravan with my wife
arriving over there,
where that McLaren is,
I pulled a caravan there.
My wife told me I could do it all again.
- So what steps did you take
to build your net worth back up?
- Back to the drawing
board, traveling up and down
the motorways, collecting,
delivering, washing, polishing.
I've done it all.
We rebuilt it.
The business, rebuilt the name.
- I always think that an entrepreneur
is willing to risk his share on his back,
whereas a businessman
calculates everything.
- That, I couldn't have
just said it any better.
- Forget the pain, but
remembered the lesson.
- It made me stronger.
I knew it was easier to
get there the second time
than it was the first time
'cause I'd already been there.
Once you've tasted honey,
it tastes a lot nicer than sour milk.
When I want peace and quietness,
this is where I come to.
It helps me concentrate
and it helps me focus.
- So as you made it back, were you worried
that your enemies would
take you down again?
- Oh yeah, I mean, look, when
you're successful in life,
you've always got enemies.
That's a fact.
Whoever you are in life,
if you're successful,
you've always got jealous people out there
who try to be critical.
And it's sad that we live
in that type of world.
As a mature man yourself and
a successful person yourself,
you're gonna get doubters in life.
And if you can't handle rejection
and failure and mistakes,
you know, you're never
gonna make it in life.
- Thousands of deals later
and Tom has gone from
strength to strength,
which just goes to show his resilience
in the face of failure.
I then wanted to dive a little deeper
into how a business of this
size actually operates.
What separates the winners from the losers
and the vital traits needed for success?
So what is the breakdown of your business?
If we have to get right
down to the nitty gritty.
- You know, we can, at
any one time, carry stock
from 40 million to a hundred
million paid on the floor.
The valuation of the business today
as an independent family
business, we don't declare our,
we trade as a private company.
So there's never been
any access to our wealth.
But the business is worth
well over 300 million today.
As a brand name.
That's just the car business,
not the park home business,
or the holiday park business.
Everything I've ever made,
I've always reinvested
and reinvesting and reinvested.
- [Interviewer] Talking about investing,
a great way to get your
journey kick started
is by grabbing your free stock,
worth all the way up to a
thousand dollars from public.com.
I'll leave a link in the description.
- I've never portrayed to be
perfect in everything I do,
but buying and selling luxury
performance and classic cars?
There's nobody that does it better.
I've proved it. I've
done it. I've lived it.
- We're actually sat on a glass floor
above multimillion pound
cars in your basement.
- Yeah, yeah. We're sat
on top of a glass floor,
which was a creation unlike
any other in a showroom.
We have a famous car
stage known as the Lake
where we would drive cars
in the middle of water
and we photograph them as
something that we are branded for
all over the world.
- How did you come up with the idea
of the car stage on the Lake?
- I created the Lake,
I phone my son Carl up
at two o'clock in the
morning, four, five years ago.
I said, "Carl, I've got an idea."
He said, "What's that dad?"
I said, "We could put a bridge
in the middle of the lake
and we could photograph cars
in the middle of the water."
And he actually said
to me, "Dad," he said,
"You sound like you're pissed
with an idea like that."
And he put the phone down.
So I thought, I said to his mother,
"So, I'll show him how pissed
I am. I'm gonna do it."
It proved to be one of the best things
I ever done in my life.
- And these photographs on the wall
that have been taken on
the bridge or on the stage
as I should put it,
they're like a history of all
the cars that Tom's owned.
We've got a car going back
on the glass screen here.
How about that?
So you can get a look at
the underneath of your Lambo
and, as I'd expect, just
as pristine underneath
as they are on top on
top, absolutely gorgeous.
What did the showroom cost?
Because you are throwing out numbers.
Quarter of a million pounds,
quarter of a million pounds on the Lake.
You know, all these are
big numbers added up.
They've gotta make a huge number.
- This complex cost 10 million.
The lighting system was 300,000.
The lift was 275,000.
I was happy to fund those two items.
Air conditioning, sound
system, Italian marble,
Italian floor tile, just
there's no end to it.
Handmade, this building's
made with handmade bricks.
£2 a brick. £2 a brick.
Excuse me one second, sorry.
Hello. I'll take your details.
I'll take your details.
- GT2 RS.
- [Tom] That's right, yeah.
Lots of carbon.
- Yeah.
What's the sort of value on that Tom?
- 250,000.
- And you can see the value,
you put a scaffold in the back.
- Yeah, yeah, 250,000, yeah,
scaffolding in the back.
- So you were an entrepreneur
before the phrase even really came about?
What would be the best advice
or single piece of advice
you could give a youngster nowadays?
- I would say to be the
best at what you want to be,
you have to be single minded.
Start thinking about your
dream, what you wanna be,
what you want to do.
Start focusing on that.
Spend more time concentrating on that.
It was always my desire and
my dream to be the most famous
and the best at what I do.
Being luxury performance and classic cars.
And that's exactly what we are today.
- I think you've had a fantastic life.