At the age of 25, I'd
made my first million.
It wasn't school that gave me
my education about investing.
My teacher was the rollercoaster of life.
It came to me one day when my boss asked
if someone wanted to
help install a staircase.
When we got to the house, I
was shocked, he had it all.
Granite countertops, Persian rugs
and a collection of super cars.
I'd look out the window
and see the owner relaxing
or practicing his golf swing.
When I talked to him, he only chatted
about his personal hobbies
and never his businesses.
I asked him, what's the
secret to your success?
He tapped me on the
shoulder and said, Mark,
if you can't make money while you sleep,
you'll work until you die.
This is now known in the
modern day as passive income.
That was the moment I
decided I needed to join
the top 1% of men.
I'd like to retread my
journey with you today.
It's very clearly broken
into five different stages,
just like a video game and
at each individual stage,
I learned something imperative
to my future success.
You'll learn what I focused on
as a hard-nosed businessman.
What I obsessed about in
the world of investing
and most importantly,
the many mistakes I made along the way
that have made me the
successful person I am today.
Stage one, the awakening.
This is when I went from 0 to $20,000.
My journey started as I
emerged from my mother's womb
and my first words were,
which stocks should I buy?
Just kidding.
Like most people, I was pretty clueless
about financial education as a kid,
but I had the spirit of hustle in me.
One of my earliest memories
of entrepreneurship
goes back to when I was
selling fish door to door.
Just imagine wiping the sleep dust
out of your eyes at four in the morning,
heading down to a freezing
pier and sitting for hours
until you'd caught enough
mackerel to sell for a profit.
Not only that
but grabbing a slimy fish from
a bag, ringing a doorbell,
looking a person straight in
the eye and pitching to them.
This built up my confidence
and sales skills.
Two of the earlier
skills I needed to learn
to be successful.
As I earned,
I soon found that any money
I made wasn't really mine.
Instead it would go places like McDonald's
and the girl I happened to be dating.
I always seem to have just enough.
This is called lifestyle inflation,
the tendency to spend
more as you make more.
Whatever you earn,
it becomes your new baseline,
and that's the trap.
But being a car fanatic,
I've always dreamed of owning a Ferrari.
I felt as if they sent
such a strong signal
to others that you've made it.
I'd often speak to my friend Paul
who worked as a valet parking
cars for the rich and famous.
He once told me something
that changed my perspective on luxuries.
He said, when people would
drive up to the hotel
in their Ferraris, they
would watch me gawk
and love every moment of it.
I'm sure they felt admired,
important, even respected
but actually, you know what, Mark?
I didn't care about them
or even notice them.
Instead, I thought,
wow, if I had that car,
people would think I'm cool.
And I wonder how many
people buy these cars
without realizing that
people rarely give the driver
a moment's thought.
I learned
that no one would be as
impressed with my possessions
and luxuries as much as me.
People want to be respected
and admired by others, but
competence, intelligence
and kindness will bring
you so much more respect
than horsepower ever will.
With all the information
out there on the internet
about how to make money or get rich quick,
it can be hard to separate the truth
from the marketing.
Internet gurus have been getting
wealthy for the past decade
telling other people how they can get rich
and there's a whole industry
out there based on fantasy,
but the truth is wealth
is not always what you see
but what you don't see.
I decided instead, I'd quietly
follow my own path to wealth,
but in order to do
this, I needed a budget.
A budget is knowing
where your money will go
versus where it went.
Little by little and for the first time,
I started seeing my savings account go up.
I started building an emergency fund,
basically money for a rainy day.
I didn't know exactly
when or why it would rain
only that one day it would.
One day my boss approached me
and ordered me to start
making wooden trash cans.
I made trash can after trash can,
the hours would just crawl by so slowly.
I went to my boss
and asked him how long I'd
have to keep doing this.
Until the order stopped coming in
which is probably never, he
said, and I felt so deflated.
Although I was saving money,
I didn't feel passionate
about what I was doing, but
I wasn't thinking big enough.
After all, I didn't care about luxury,
so why would I need more money?
Then it hit me.
I realized that control over your time
is the greatest thing money can buy.
If I had passive income,
I could spend my time doing
the things I really loved.
The problem is it takes a lot of time
or money to start making
enough passive income
to become financially free.
We spent thousands of
hours every year working
in the pursuit of money,
so I asked myself what was
I truly passionate about?
I had a burning passion
for radio control models
and I noticed many people
in this industry were
making a lot of mistakes.
I saw the true potential and
the ways that I could improve
on what had come before me.
I once read in a book that if
you could identify a problem
and you had a better way of doing things,
you could turn it into a business.
Stage two, the hustle.
This is when I went from
$20,000 to $100,000.
So I got to work.
I was so excited about my business plans
that I shared them with a
close friend and confidant
and to my shock, the
unimaginable happened.
He stole my idea and set up my
entire business for himself.
But before I get into that,
first I'd like to thank
today's sponsor, public.com.
Let's be honest, 2022 has
been a pretty volatile year
for the stock market,
and that's exactly why
our long term sponsor, public.com
wants to help you become
a better investor.
On Public,
you can invest in individual
stocks as well as ETFs,
all the while learning from
notable investors, analysts
and top CEOs with their
optional social features
and town halls.
My favorite thing about Public
is they don't participate
in payment for order flow
by selling your trades to market makers,
meaning they have no
reason to incentivize you
to trade more than necessary
like some other platforms do.
On Public, you can invest, learn
and see what top investors
are doing all in one place.
And the best part is for a limited time,
you can get a free stock worth
between three and a thousand dollars
with the link down below
in the description.
Anyway, back to the story.
The reality is that I needed
some money to pursue my dream
but my savings just weren't enough.
I wasn't about to give up.
I drew up a business
plan, went to the bank
and applied for my first loan.
It wasn't easy and I had
to visit multiple banks.
However, eventually I
secured the money I needed.
While some people were
in their wealth investing
in the stock market,
I reinvested the earnings
from my businesses
to open more stores and even
buy back my original idea
from my old friend.
I started to know more
and more people in the business world.
A lot of these individuals
became my mentors
and would teach me things
like how to build a business that scales,
how to improve sales and
how to manage people.
As my income grew and I solved problems,
I was not only growing my net worth
but becoming a top 1% man as well.
As the good times continued,
I increasingly bet on them continuing,
which led to one of my most
significant life crashes
and moments of despair.
I remember it like it was yesterday,
walking into the shop
that I had initially started
to give my father a job
in his later years
and instead of being greeted
by the magical emporium filled
with all the toys that I could
have only dreamed of having
as a kid, I was met with a
smashed roof, empty shelves
and my products laying broken,
thrown across the floor.
This hit me so hard
that the memory has been
seared into my subconscious
and I sometimes still see
it when I close my eyes.
You may think, it's all
right Mark, I know you.
I bet you had insurance.
Everything was okay, and you bounced back.
Well, in fact, I'd grown so fast
and I was making so much money
that not everything was
correctly structured
within my business.
Although we were insured,
I'd forgotten to update it
with all the new stock that
we'd acquired since the opening
of the store, but the
disaster doesn't stop there.
It gets even worse.
I got a phone call a few days later
and one of my staff informed me
that another two locations had been hit.
Luckily, one of these
attempts was unsuccessful
on my flagship store
as they couldn't break through the door.
However, they'd driven a truck
straight through the side
of the store that was responsible
for serving the entirety of London,
and the damage was horrendous,
let alone the stock that we lost.
That's when I learned
about the balance between risk and reward.
See, making money requires taking risks,
operating quickly and
putting yourself out there,
but keeping money requires the opposite.
It requires humility and fear
that what you've made can be taken away
from you just like that.
Once you lose 95% of your money,
you have to gain 1900%
just to get back to where you started.
Taking too much risk can bury you so deep
in a hole it can be nearly
impossible to get out of.
I even started to move
my operations online
to adapt to the changing times.
Stage three, the trap.
This is when I went from
$100,000 to $1 million.
I realized that one of
the biggest problems
people face is when
they turn their passion
into a vehicle to accumulate money.
They are now reliant on it
to fund their lifestyle,
leading to their passion
becoming their prison.
I mean, the biggest bottleneck
in my business was actually
the business owner, me.
As the business got bigger
and as we tried to move it online,
so did the number of problems, complaints
and things to worry about.
It always seems like as
soon as I solved a problem,
another one would soon follow.
Don't get me wrong, owning and
running a business is great,
especially if you are passionate about it,
but it isn't as easy or as passive
as a lot of people make it out to be.
I've read a lot of books on investing,
studied the techniques of Warren Buffet
and come across John Bogle's book
about common sense investing.
It shocked me when I learned
that 80% of active fund
managers actually underperform
the S&P 500 Index.
Diversification is important
and buying and investing
in the S&P 500, which is
a basket of 503 stocks,
I could earn a steady growth that grows
along with the US economy.
My goal was to have enough money
in the S&P 500 that in
the worst case scenario,
I could withdraw up to 4%
per year in order to live
off my investments while
still growing my portfolio.
By sticking to my guns, I
was able to avoid suffering
from the internet stock crash of 2000.
Early on in my journey,
I learned that the losses felt massive
whereas a profit seemed so, so slow.
There's an old saying, stocks rise
like an escalator and
crash like an elevator,
and this couldn't be more true.
I kept dollar cost averaging
and adding to my stock portfolio,
even as the .com crash continued.
I was getting more and more
shares of the index fund
at better and better prices.
As a qualified pilot,
I draw this parallel,
hours and hours of uneventful flight
followed by moments of sheer terror,
but it's these moments of sheer terror
that make up the majority of your returns.
The way I conducted my
finances during the .com crash
and the 2008 financial
crisis gave me more returns
than any investing I'd ever done before.
Stage four, the refinement.
This is when I went from
$1 million to $10 million.
As my wealth grew, it
seemed like the matrix
was creating more and more temptations
to take my money away from me.
Having savings gives you a lot of options
like going to a buffet where
you can have every dish
you've ever wanted.
In the previous stages,
once I'd surpassed a
$100,000 in yearly earnings,
I was considered an accredited investor,
which is both an exciting
and a dangerous place to be.
I fell into the trap of
investing in various penny stocks
which initially was very successful.
However, I went on to lose $30,000
with a couple of bad trades.
After this, I created a rule for myself
to only invest in things
that I fully understand,
unless it's an experiment
with a small amount of capital
that I'm not afraid to lose.
It doesn't matter
whether you are investing
in NFTs, stocks or a relationship,
I learned to always do my homework
and take the time to
understand every opportunity.
The thing I understood more
than anything was my business.
I wanted to really push forward,
so I flew out to America
on a bit of a whim to see
a friend on the promise
that he would help me to
restructure my business,
from serving customers B2C
to servicing other
businesses, B2B as well.
He taught me that by focusing
on selling to businesses,
I could increase my numbers
without having to deal
with so many people.
This is known as the 80-20 principle.
I learned that I could focus
on the 20% of things that
produce 80% of my income.
I traveled abroad to China
and Japan where I learned
about the idea of lean manufacturing,
which I related to my everyday life.
I started cutting anything
unnecessary outta my business
and personal life so I could focus on
what gave me the most meaning and results.
Through this, I'd finally
achieved multimillionaire status
but it felt kind of empty, and that's when
I had a revelation that
changed my life forever.
Stage five, the revelation.
This is when I went to
$10 million and beyond.
This brings me to where I am today.
I thought about which
investments were most important
to me in my life, and I realized
it was the relationships
with my family and friends.
You'll be the same person in
five years as you are today,
except for the people you
meet and the books you read.
I started thinking about
how to pass the torch
and I taught my son Curtis about finance.
We started this YouTube channel together
as a way to educate the younger generation
from the perspective, not
of some rich influencer,
but as a guy who did it with passion
and a bit of elbow grease.
I started spending more time
enjoying the little moments,
appreciating what I have
and what I've worked for
and fostering quality relationships.
The final stage for a lot of people
later in life is philanthropy.
Some people like Bill
Gates start foundations.
Others like Ray Dalio, write books.
This is my form of giving back.
When I reflect on my journey getting here,
I'm proud of everything I've done.
I still hustle hard,
but what is really meaningful
to me is being able to share
my knowledge and inspire
a younger generation
to go after their dreams
and achieve success.
So I'm gonna leave the
next video right up there
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you wanna grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.