Hi guys, it's Mark.
So the internet is full of articles
preaching about habits that
will make you a millionaire,
but they're always so generic,
and they're definitely not
from personal experience.
Now, I know I'm a bit of a boomer,
but sometimes that can be a good thing.
I've been around for a while,
and I've learned an
awful lot along the way.
Now, your 20's are a
fun part of your life,
but they're extremely
important at the same time.
So here are seven money-making habits
I wish I'd known sooner because if I did,
I'd have made my first
million a lot quicker,
that's for sure.
By watching this video
all the way until the end,
you'll be able to learn from my mistakes
and hopefully do even better.
Also, the last habit's a
little bit controversial,
so it might be worth sticking around for.
Habit number one is embracing debt.
I know this might sound confusing at first
as lots of people think that debt is bad,
and you should avoid it
like those online courses
that cost $997.
No, but seriously,
it's one of the main reasons
I was able to build my wealth
from absolutely nothing
to a multimillionaire.
In my early 20's,
I was building my businesses
from the ground up,
and I didn't have a lot
of cash available to me.
So I had to get very
creative with my finances.
I knew that if I wanted to grow my wealth,
then I needed to control more assets.
And the only way to do that
was to use the power of
other people's money.
Now notice how I said
I wanted more assets,
and that's a very important point.
Lots of people do the opposite
and get into debt buying liabilities.
Sadly, they're just digging
themselves into a hole
that they will find it
really hard to escape from.
An easy way to find out
if something is an asset or a liability
is to figure out if the purchase
is putting money into
your pocket each month,
or instead just draining your wallet.
My favorite thing about
borrowing money is that I can buy
other companies in cash,
therefore getting a better price.
I actually still do this today
as borrowing money is
currently very cheap.
How can borrowing money be cheap?
This guy's a lunatic.
Well, just think, if I can
borrow cash at a 2% interest rate
and put my money to work
at an eight to 10% return,
then on my head, six to 8%.
I just always make sure to run
the numbers on my decisions
and not leave myself too exposed to debt
so that if something went wrong,
then I would be able to
handle the repercussions.
It's definitely true that you
should be cautious of debt,
but never fear using it to your advantage.
If you're enjoying this video so far,
make sure to smash that like button
for the YouTube algorithm,
as it helps push this video
out to a lot more people,
and it's really appreciated.
Habit number two, being
obsessed with success.
I believe to become a millionaire,
you must have laser focused,
much like an Olympic athlete.
I couldn't agree more with the quote,
"When you want to succeed
as bad as you wanna breathe,
"then you're gonna be successful."
Many of you aren't probably aware of this,
but before I was known as a businessman,
I was famous for flying
radio control helicopters,
and I competed to a very high
standard all over the world.
At one point, I won bronze medal,
at world championships
held in Indiana, USA.
I would be obsessed with every
little detail of my model.
I did everything I could to win.
I was absolutely relentless.
To get to the top of anything,
you need to put in the extra bit of work,
and then a little bit more.
When I started my first business,
I applied the same obsession.
I set myself both short
and long-term goals
to keep focused at all times.
Having a laser light
determination to succeed
is key for your growth.
And I was absolutely obsessed
with hitting my sales targets.
First it was just to
complete a year of business,
then it was to do last year's
turnover in just one month,
then in just one week.
But I always had the ultimate goal
of becoming financially free.
Even Elon Musk claims
he regularly works 80 to 100 hours a week,
and this is fueled by his
obsession to hit his targets
and meet his goals.
How else will Tesla smash earnings reports
and SpaceX land humans on Mars?
The sad news is 60% of businesses fail
within the first three years.
And that's why focus
obsession is so important.
So stay focused and keep grinding.
Amazon wasn't the biggest
retailer overnight.
And Kevin O'Leary said
he would have laughed
Elon Musk out of the building
if he'd appeared on Shark
Tank with a Tesla pitch.
Habit number three is
building income streams.
As I've grown older,
I must say my passive income streams
have become very useful.
I no longer have that
energy of a 20-year old.
However, I don't have to,
as I put in the work when I was younger,
and now I can reap the benefits.
- [Narrator] And you can make
me do all the work as well.
- Well, someone's got to.
I created my first passive
income stream accidentally
when I refused to sell
my apartment in my 20's.
The apartment would have sold
for around 40% less than I'd paid,
and I wasn't interested
in taking a hit like that,
so I rented it out.
This ended up being a great decision
as this paid the mortgage.
And after four years,
the apartment sold for 60%
more than I'd originally paid.
So not only did I receive
rent every single month,
totaling more than the mortgage payment,
I then sold the property for a huge profit
and put that money to
work in the stock market.
This really showed me
the power of passive
income and I was hooked.
Now, I meant the term passive income
has become a bit of a buzz word online.
And the truth is, no
income is truly passive,
as there is always something
that has to be done.
However, some income sources
are certainly more passive than others.
The idea is to create something once
and have it pay you as much as
possible with minimal effort.
Passive income is very addictive,
especially when you wake up
and you realize you just
got paid for sleeping.
A good way to start is
to grab your free stock
from the Public app worth
all the way up to $1,000
if you're in the USA.
And if you wanna grab
$10 worth of free Bitcoin
from Coinbase, then
that's open to everyone.
So I'll leave those links
in the dooblie doo below.
Habit four, knowing when to quit.
Now, I know this one
might sound a bit strange.
Quitting is usually seen as a bad thing,
but in my experience,
it helped me go from a
carpenter's apprentice
earning less than $2 per hour
to a millionaire by my late 20's.
When I was working that minimum wage job
and I first had an issue
with my manager bullying me,
I could have kept going
and worked my way up
the company gradually,
but I decided to quit.
That led me to starting my own business.
And within a few months I was
drowning in all the paperwork.
So I decided to quit that job
and I hired someone to help.
And before I knew it,
I'd replaced all the jobs
I could with other people.
This allowed me to focus
on being the captain
and steering the business
in the right direction.
The big lesson here is not
to be too proud to quit
when you don't like something,
or you feel the effort
is not worth the reward.
I see so many people
struggling at university
and working long days and nights
for a degree they don't actually want.
They've just been pushed down that path
by teachers and parents.
Of course this isn't
everyone, but in my opinion,
quitting has its time and place.
And there is no shame in
admitting something isn't for you.
This isn't to say that you should quit
just because something's hard,
but there has to be a reason
to put in all the hard work.
Don't let others shame you
if you make the hard decision to move on
to bigger and better things.
After all, the opportunity
cost of staying where you are,
could be much greater than you realized.
Just imagine of outside work and as a cop
to making wooden trash cans all my life.
Nah, never have happened.
Habit Number five is treating your body
like a sports car, broom, broom.
I know it might be sounding
a bit like a fitness guru,
but as cheesy as it is,
without good health,
you won't be able to unlock
your full earning potential.
I had to relearn this lesson
recently when the pandemic hit.
Lots of my staff were in lockdown,
which meant I decided to
work three months flat out.
I was even in the warehouse
packing and shipping
orders with minimal staff,
as I didn't want to let my customers down.
I actually worked 15 hours a day,
seven days a week, for
three months straight.
I got very stressed and started
having lots of migraines.
And they only stopped when
I decided to slow down
by going back to golf
and doing more fun things
like whitewater rafting with my son.
I've also climbed Mount Snowden
as well as going on the
fastest zip-line in Europe.
Believe it or not,
these things keep me
relaxed and enjoying life,
which means I can put
more effort into my work.
I now understand more than ever
that a healthy body is a healthy mind.
There's a mountain of
evidence that suggests
a good night's sleep
seriously boosts productivity.
One study of 4,188 US workers
found significantly worse
productivity, performance,
and safety outcomes among those
that slept less than seven hours.
That's why I now stopped working two hours
before going to bed without fail.
I'm trying to exercise more
by building my own gym.
And I always try to eat healthy foods
to boost my productivity.
The way I think of my
body is like a sports car.
You won't fill with any old trash,
you'd made sure everything
was top of the range.
- [Narrator] What kind of
sports car are you dad?
- I'm a Ferrari 355.
Habit six, spending to receive.
If you wanna become rich
it's highly unlikely
you'll ever be able to achieve it
without understanding
return on investment.
If I purchase a product for
$50 and sell it for $75,
my ROI is $25.
50%, but the chances are,
you already knew that.
However, ROI stretches so
much further than profit
on an item you're selling.
As a business owner, I
have multiple employees,
and before making a
commitment to employ someone,
I first have to work out exactly
how much this will cost me,
and exactly how much money
I think that person will
generate for my business.
Without calculating the
return on investment,
I would never be able to determine
whether hiring an extra
employee is the right decision.
Whether you're starting a business,
investing in the stock market,
or even just saving money,
it's important to understand
the return on investment
as well as the opportunity cost.
But return on investment doesn't
always have to be instant.
One of my businesses is B
to B, business to business.
This means I sell products
to other businesses
at trade price instead of
directly to my customers.
I've attended many radar
controlled model shows
over the years to
showcase my product range
to customers all around the country.
This cost my business time
and money attending the show
for no immediate return on investment.
But the payoff later
down the line is great
when I land a big business
customer who buys in bulk.
So the key takeaway here is to think about
how you're spending your
precious time and money,
and evaluate if you'll get in a good ROI.
Habit number seven is not being too nice.
This is a real controversial one,
and I completely understand why.
I don't wanna say nice guys finish last,
but pushovers certainly do.
Even if you managed to
build up some wealth,
you'll end up being taken advantage of
and potentially lose it all.
There is a difference
between being a giver
and being agreeable.
The key is to be a disagreeable giver.
This means you have a vision,
and you know where you're going.
Therefore, you're not going to agree
with everyone along the way.
However, you can still
treat them with respect
and take them on the journey with you.
But the hard truth is not
everybody is worth your time,
especially when you're
trying to better yourself
and brighten your future.
There's a saying,
if you surround yourself
with four millionaires,
you're bound to be the fifth.
And this is absolutely correct.
I grew up pretty poor,
but from an early age,
I felt that I thought a little differently
from my school friends,
'cause lots of them had a,
that I'll do approach of life,
whereas I always wanted
to put in the extra effort
where it mattered most.
Because of this, I only keep in contact
with one person from school,
and two people from my first job.
All three of these guys
have the same attitude to life as I do.
And I find this both
encouraging and fulfilling.
If you look for friends
that align with your values and goals,
then you'll find them too.
With these friends, you can
talk openly about your goals
and also listen to theirs.
It's such a great encouragement,
and it forces you to level up.
Many studies suggest
that you are the average
of the five people you
spend the most time with,
which is why you have to take great care
when you're building your squad.
So instead of always talking to friends
about the latest Netflix series,
try talking about business
ideas and making money.
I find this crucial, some of
my best ideas have been sparked
completely through a conversation.
If all I spoke about was
TV shows and hobbies,
I would never have got anywhere.
All of these habits have undeniably
changed my life for the better
and shaped me into the person I am today.
The best part about all of this
is it requires minimal effort,
and you don't have to spend
an absolute fortune to get started.
As long as you get started right away
and stick with everything
we discussed long-term,
you'll be good to go.
So I'm gonna leave the
next video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you wanna grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.