Have you ever wondered
how to turn $1,000 into a small fortune?
Maybe you think it's impossible,
especially as we're facing
a devastating recession.
However, today I'm
setting myself a challenge
to prove this can be done.
I've hand-selected five
different investments.
These include index funds, business, art,
individual stocks, and cryptocurrency.
But data suggest these
are good investments
during a recession.
Therefore, after looking
at each in detail,
I'm prepared to put $1,000 of
my own money into every asset
so we can see the results together.
However, this might not go quite to plan.
I never thought I'd spend $1,000 on this.
No, get out of it!
Look at that!
If you gave me $5 every day
and I gave you $50 back,
would you be happy with that deal?
Of course you would.
So, why aren't you taking it?
Let me explain.
This leads me into
investment one, index funds.
I'm given this a three out
of 10 on the risk scale
as it's been delivering
solid returns for decades.
The figures don't lie.
If you invest $5 every day,
let's call that $150 per month,
into the S&P 500 at an average
return of 8% for 45 years,
then you would have $791,000.
Now, according to Google,
there are 16,436 days in 45 years.
So now if we divide
$791,361 by 16,436 days,
we can see that every $5 you
put in has turned into $48.
That's pretty close to $50.
Now, I bet that's got you thinking
about your $5 Starbucks
frappe a bit more carefully.
Index funds are seen as one
of the safest investments
over the long term.
However, during a recession,
they become even more appealing.
This is because instead of
betting on individual companies
to pull through the tough times,
you are purely investing
in a long-term success
of the whole market.
Think of it like going to a horse racing,
instead of putting all your
money on one prize stallion,
you decide to spread it
across all the top performers.
So now if one or a few of them lose,
it should be okay,
because you will benefit
from the others winning.
This is a proven winning strategy.
Over a 15-year period,
92% of the top hedge funds are
trailing the S&P 500 index.
I mean, these guys are
meant to be the experts,
but they are getting destroyed
by a very hands-off investment,
which is so easy to manage.
You may think the S&P 500
isn't very well-spread
as it's only made up of the
top 500 American companies.
However, as of 2017, only
70.9% of the companies
that make up the S&P 500's
revenue were from the US.
So it's a lot more global
than you might first think.
But if you want to spread
your money further,
then there are lots of different funds
that cover different
countries and companies.
I have some of my money in
emerging markets index funds,
so I believe we are gonna see a big shift
in global powers over the
next five to 10 years.
Even though I also invest
elsewhere for bigger returns,
I always gradually buy index funds,
whatever the market's doing,
be that trending up or down.
There's multiple brokers you can use.
If you're in the US,
you can use public.com.
I'm gonna use my UK Vanguard account.
Let's put $750 into the S&P 500
and $250 into a global index.
There we go.
All done.
88% of millionaires are
self-made entrepreneurs,
according to Fidelity
Investments research.
So that brings us onto
investment number two, business.
I'm giving this a 3.5 on the risk scale,
as unlike index funds,
you could lose all your
money in a bad business move.
However, the power is in your hands,
not someone else's.
If you haven't started a business,
then now could be the perfect time
as we head into a recession.
There's a good chance
you'll be starting from your
home and have minimal employees
and very little overhead
to maintain at this point.
That combination puts
you in a great position
to provide an inexpensive
solution and win over customers.
In an economic downturn,
businesses and consumers alike
are looking to cut costs,
which may allow you to
break into the market.
But your window of
opportunity could close soon
as recessions are typically short-lived
and followed by long periods
of growth and prosperity.
The period after World
War II, for example,
is considered the greatest
expansionary phase
in modern times.
Similar points can be made for the years
after the energy crisis recession,
the Gulf War recession,
the dot-com bust, and the Great Recession.
Each recession was followed
by longer period of growth
than the period of recession.
The biggest mistake I see
people making on a daily basis
is putting all their money into assets
they don't have direct control over.
As you know, I'm not
against the stock market,
however, I don't think enough
people value their skill sets.
I was on a call the other day
with someone in my free Discord
and he asked me an interesting question.
He was making around $400 per month
selling PDFs that help
people in his country
pass a state exam.
He was wondering how he
should invest that money
to make more.
Later on in the call,
I discovered that he was currently
only selling these templates
with organic marketing,
which proves there is a
real demand for his product.
If he just invested $200 per month
back into paid advertising
within his business,
he could see an immediate return
greater than any stock market investment.
I think of it like
starving a plant of water.
You can't ever flourish in a drought.
So if you've been overlooking business,
then I implore you to dream big
and prepare for the
next expansionary phase.
At the moment, I'm focused
on growing my podcast,
Strike It Big.
We really need a way for
episodes to be edited
as we film them.
That's why I'm gonna invest these $1,000
into some new technology,
which should save me time and
help us post weekly episodes.
Question.
What do Picasso and Banksy have in common,
apart from being eerie-defining artists?
The answer is you can invest in their work
for a fraction of the asking price.
That brings us on to
investment three, fine art.
I'm giving this a five out
of 10 on the risk scale.
You might not have considered fine art
as a potential investment.
To be honest, neither had I,
until I looked into the shocking stats.
You know the S&P 500,
that investment many millionaires
don't stop banging on about.
- S&P 500 index fund.
- The S&P 500.
- Well, contemporary art investments
have actually done better
than the beloved S&P 500
over the last 25 years.
To be exact, the S&P 500 had
a 9.5% average annual return,
whereas contemporary art
averaged 14% price appreciation.
But surely, if we are facing a recession,
the demand for these
expensive paintings will drop
and then the value of our
investment will plummet, right?
Well, actually the global
demand held up pretty well
during the last Great Recession.
In 2007, global public auction
sales topped $32.9 billion,
while in 2008, the
figures hit $28 billion.
This only shows a slight dip in demand,
and it was still higher than 2005
when auction sales were
only $17.2 billion.
Maybe more importantly, during 2009,
Yves Saint Laurent's art
collection set a new record
for a single-owner collection,
totalling $483.8 million.
To put this into perspective,
this happened just five months
after the complete
collapse of Lehman Brothers
and the markets.
Again, if we look at our
old friend, the S&P 500,
this didn't recover the
pre-recession levels until 2013,
two years later than the art market,
due to the eye-watering prices
these paintings command.
Unfortunately, this asset
class has only been accessible
to the already rich and powerful.
There is also a degree of skill involved
with picking the right pieces
that the average investor
just wouldn't understand.
So, how are we gonna
invest these $1,000 in art?
Well, I've been doing some research,
and companies like
Masterworks really stand out
as they use data that isn't available
to the average investor
and a top research team
in order to determine which
high-end artist markets
have the most momentum.
They're even asked by
worldwide groups like Citi
to collaborate on reports
about the art market.
This just shows how much
comprehensive data they have.
They help people get
fractional pieces of art,
rather than the whole thing.
This isn't NFTs,
this is breaking a painting into shares,
so people can add a piece
of it to their portfolio.
Their incentives are also
aligned with the investors,
as Masterworks only make money
when they sell a painting for a profit.
With this said, I still
think investing in art
is for the long term,
and that's why this platform
doesn't actually accept
investors that are older than 70.
Oh damn it, looks like I can't invest
these $1,000 after all.
Only kidding,
I've still got plenty of years
left in me, you cheeky bogus.
Masterworks aims to hold its art pieces
for three to 10 years,
at which point it then sells the painting
and distributes the
proceeds amongst investors
based on their number of shares.
But so far, the paintings they
have sold ahead of schedule
have delivered 25% net returns
for the last four years in a row
through COVID, a bear market,
and rampant inflation.
Past performance is no
guarantee of future results,
but that's pretty incredible.
So with that said,
let's invest $1,000.
I really like Mark
Bradford's "Promise Land".
It even shows a progress bar
that lets us know how much of the asset
has already been bought.
The paintings are valued every quarter,
so I'll be keeping an eye on this closely.
If you also want to get involved,
then I'll leave an exclusive invite link
in the description below.
Imagine you invested $1,000
and woke up in the morning with $10,000.
This is what most people dream of,
and it's happened time and time again
with investment four, individual stocks.
However, I'm gonna give
this a seven out of 10
on the risk scale,
as finding the best stocks to
invest in isn't an easy task.
Investing in individual stocks
give you complete control
over how your money is allocated.
When you invest in index funds,
you can't pick and choose
the individual companies,
instead, you're stuck with
whatever the fund decides to do.
So stock picking gives you the
ability to beat the market,
but bear in mind that
90% of people lose money,
hence, the high risk scale rating.
If you're interested
in giving this a shot,
then now could be a very good opportunity
as the market has fallen from
the highs of the pandemic
and there are lots of deals available
if you can find them.
During a recession,
it's more important than ever
to invest in well-managed companies
that have low debt, good cash flow,
and strong balance sheets.
You're able to find all
this information out
for free on Yahoo Finance.
Some industries are also considered
more recession-resistant than
others, such as healthcare.
If you think about it,
people can't put off
most healthcare spending.
When you're sick,
you need to see a doctor and buy medicine.
Walmart and McDonald's
are also great examples
of companies that have thrived
during past recessions.
This is because when
people have less money,
they flock to discount stores like Walmart
and drown their sorrows in comfort foods
such as McDonald's burgers.
However, I'm gonna invest
my $1,000 in Apple,
as they sit on the
luxury end of the market,
and people would hate to
give up their nice phones.
It's also important to remember
that most people don't even
buy their phones these days,
they finance them through contracts.
This gives people access to iPhones
and puts money in Apple's pocket,
regardless of their
customer's bank balances.
$1,000 of Apple bought.
By the way, if you wanna
pick up a free stock
worth up to $1,000 from public.com,
then I'll leave a link
in the description below.
When you hear about people
becoming millionaires
from a simple $1,000 investment
in a short period of time,
you can only be talking about one thing.
Investment number five is,
of course, cryptocurrency.
And I'm giving this an 8.5
out of 10 on the risk scale.
Back in the day, if you'd
mentioned cryptocurrency to me,
I would've disregarded
it as a short-term craze.
However, as Bitcoin rallied,
I had to take notice.
The more I dived into the
technology behind crypto,
the more interested I became.
I made a goal to invest
around 5% of my portfolio
and face some challenges along the way,
such as my bank account being closed down.
This is because Bitcoin
is a digital currency
that is not controlled
by any authority or bank.
And many experts believe crypto
and blockchain technology
will go on to disrupt many industries,
such as banking, law, cyber
security, insurance, and more.
The top 10 cryptocurrency
coins are always fluctuating,
but the two that remain
in first and second places
by market cap are Bitcoin and Ethereum,
which I like to call
the blue-chip cryptos.
These are the most
popular and safest coins.
At the moment, as we're
heading into a recession,
naturally prices across the board
have dropped quite drastically.
A lot of investors see this
as a great buying opportunity.
Crypto is certainly not
something to overlook,
but should only be part
of a diversified portfolio
due to its high risk.
I'm gonna invest $500 into
Bitcoin and $500 into Ethereum
the rapper Drake has
reportedly bet over $1 billion
for online gambling since December, 2021.
This brings us onto something
I never thought I'd be
doing on this channel,
online gambling.
This is a 10 out of 10 on the risk scale.
The rise of online gambling
is creating millionaires,
but is it the gamblers making
millions or the creators?
Let's put this to the test.
I'm prepared to put $1,000
of my own money on the line
to prove to you how
quickly it can evaporate.
I never thought I'd spend $1,000 on this.
Now, the following clip didn't go to plan
and goes completely against my narrative
that gambling is bad,
so much so, that I nearly
didn't show you this clip.
Honestly, after this happened,
I didn't think this clip
would see the light of day.
Whenever I've done a
challenge on this channel,
I've always kept it 100% real,
such as spinning the crypto wheel
or throwing an investment-picking dart.
So here's what really happened.
Curtis, you better come in.
This looks quite exciting.
Look, we got all these lollipops going on.
- I never thought I'd be doing this.
- Right, 10 free spins.
- All right, here we go then.
Press anywhere to continue.
(Mark giggles)
- Yeah, straight in, straight in.
- I don't know if you
should be doing this.
Oh, is that a win?
- Yes, and some more
and some more
and some more.
Oh, we've got a 50X.
- What, what?
- What?
- $4,000?
- We've actually won 4,000.
- No way.
- It keeps going up and up and up.
- No, get out of it!
Look at that!
- That's crazy!
- That's sensational!
(Curtis and Mark laugh)
That can't be real, can it?
- No, no, it is.
(Curtis laughs)
- Obviously, we weren't
expecting this result.
It's extremely lucky,
and the chances of something
like this happening
are very slim.
After a big win like this,
many people get sucked into gambling
and are always chasing that feeling again.
Over the long term, the house always wins.
It's like the opposite of investing,
when over the long term,
you have a high chance of success.
Gambling is just a rigged game.
To demonstrate how unpredictable
games like these are
and how it can easily go the other way,
we gave it another $1,000 spin.
No.
- We're not getting anything.
This just shows how rubbish gambling is.
- Oh, no!
- It is pretty bad,
considering we put 1,000 in,
and now we've got, what?
How much left?
Right, 350 or so
and we put 1,000 in.
- Yeah.
- Terrible investment.
- That's not a great investment, guys.
So I'm gonna leave the
next video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet,
make sure to subscribe if
you wanna grow your wealth.