- This coming recession is
your opportunity to get rich.
Well, that's what all the
YouTubers seem to be saying.
- You need to get rich and
you need to get rich quick.
- So let's talk about how you can win
while others are losing.
- The opportunity that is at our feet
as I'm filming this video
is absolutely insane.
- So by being aware of
the following eight traps
you'll be able to make much
better choices with your money.
Money trap one, being
scared to take risks.
Being scared of risky opportunities
is understandable in such uncertain times.
As an investor and a businessman,
my job is always to minimize risk.
Risk might sound sexy
but taking too much on
is not a smart move.
I say this, but even when
you've done everything
in your power to minimize risk,
there is still going to be
some in every opportunity.
Otherwise, everyone would be doing it.
And we all know the cliche saying
that when something is too good
to be true, it probably is.
If you are lucky enough to be between
the ages of 20 and 50,
then you're at huge
tipping point in your life.
The decisions you make
in this 30 year window
will cause huge ripples
that affect your loved ones,
like your parents,
grandparents, partner, and kids,
be that positively or negatively.
To put it simply, this
time period could make
or break your financial future.
So when an opportunity
that could completely
change your life present itself,
will you be paralyzed due to the recession
or you objectively analyze the risk
and act not out of fear, but ambition.
Many millionaires say one
of their five biggest life
regrets was not being bolder.
The thought of what could
have been eats away at you
if you don't take that
small leap of faith.
Money trap two, investing in
things you don't understand.
This is the number one rule of investing.
It is extremely true
but every time a crisis happens,
people totally ignore it.
It's great there's so much information
being shared online now.
The rich are finally
giving out their secrets
and people are listening.
However, it is important to be careful
about what advice you act on.
If you don't completely understand
an investing opportunity,
stay away from it until you do.
I get lots of messages asking me my advice
about stocks, cryptocurrency,
and real estate.
It's obvious that some
of these people have
just watched a 10 minute
video on the subject
and are ready to put all
their hard earned money
into something that they
don't fully understand.
Like I said before, risk is good
but it's your job to minimize that risk
by doing as much research as possible.
You should never just take advice
from one person on the internet.
As everyone has different opinions
on investment opportunities.
It's best to pull lots
of opinions together
so you're able to make a
more informed decision.
Many years ago, when I
was in my early twenties,
I nearly put a big chunk of
money into an investment group.
Everything they touched
seemed to turn to gold
and I didn't really understand
how they were doing it.
So I passed on the opportunity.
Had I invested $50,000 a year later,
I would've lost over $300,000
because they were leveraging
every investment by six times.
It's a good lesson to learn though
because I would've
previously thought the amount
I invested would've been
the maximum I could lose.
I had yet to discover the
perils of margin trade in
and I'm glad it didn't cost
me $300K to learn that lesson.
Luckily now there are apps like public.com
where you can interact with
a community of investors
and learn together.
They also give you a free stock
worth up to a thousand
dollars when you sign up.
I'll leave that link in
the description below.
Money trap three, not spending enough.
This may sound a bit
strange, not spending enough.
I thought you were meant to
spend less and invest more.
Isn't that the idea?
Well, you would've thought so.
Well, the thing is,
if you don't spend enough
money on good quality products,
then it could actually end
up costing you more money.
Being frugal with your
money, in some situations,
isn't a bad thing.
Like, not spending too much on takeaways
or shopping around for
the best grocery deals.
However, if people start trying
to cut costs on everything,
then it could be pretty dangerous.
Let's say you have to take
your car in for a repair.
If you go to the cheapest car repair shop
then you might be lucky
enough to get a good service.
However, it's more likely that
you aren't gonna get a quality job done.
As they can't afford to take the time
to look after your car carefully.
They may cut corners and miss something
or even lie about fixing the issue.
This means it's not gonna be long
before your car has problems again
and you'll have to go back
and get it repaired properly.
You might as well have
spent the extra money now
which will save you money in the future.
And of course, that's
the best case scenario.
What if the car is still dangerous
and it causes you to have an accident?
There are many things like a car repair
that is best to pay a little bit more for
to be on the safe side.
Buying quality products and services also
helps support the people
that are offering them.
If no one buys these quality services
then they won't be
there when we need them.
Money trap four, taking
your job for granted.
With more people than
ever losing their jobs
and businesses going bankrupt,
it's really not the time for people
to take their job for granted.
If you have a steady job,
then you are in a better position
than a lot of people at the moment.
And you should do everything in your power
to keep it that way.
If you want the ability to invest
and having a strong income source,
such as a job, is imperative.
Not everything is under our control.
However, when a business is in trouble,
they often have to make some tough choices
about who to fire first.
When the people in my
team go the extra mile
in a time like this, it
doesn't go unnoticed.
If someone makes themselves
indispensable to a business
then they're gonna be the ones holding
onto their jobs longer than anyone else.
I've noticed a trend going around
on TikTok called, "Silently Quitting."
The basic idea is to do just
the bare minimum at your job.
I couldn't disagree more
with this mentality.
It's important to remember
that everyone is in the same boat.
And ideally, an employer would
love to save everyone's jobs.
In order for this to happen,
then the business needs to be performing
to the best of its ability.
One of my past members of staff would moan
and complain about everything.
It brought the whole team down.
Then he decided to leave
because he was offered
a job with a higher salary and more perks.
As he left, I remember him saying,
"You'll be begging for me to come back."
He lasted less than a month at his new job
as he couldn't hit the targets.
He also hated the traveling
and the long hours.
I'm not saying he begged for
his job back, but he did ask.
And as you can imagine,
there was no position
for someone that just
does the bare minimum.
There's an old saying that the grass
is always greener on the other side,
this is rarely the case.
Money trap five, payday loans.
Payday loan companies are like
predators during these times.
They see people who are struggling
and they advertise to them nonstop.
Every time they open Facebook,
every time they look at a billboard,
every time they read a newspaper,
"Get paid now, quick and easy.
Pay us back later."
Although a lot of people have become aware
of this money trap,
there are still lots that
will consider taking out
a payday loan and paying it back later.
This is one of the worst
things someone can do
as it has the potential
to totally destroy your credit score.
Which could mean that buying a house
or a car in the future
could be a big challenge.
The interest rates on loans
like these are sky high.
So you end up paying back way more
than you actually borrowed.
By simply tracking your spending,
you can avoid being in
a situation where these
predatory companies can
take advantage of you.
Money trap six, not having a side hustle.
Although you shouldn't be
taking your job for granted,
it also shouldn't be your
only way of generating income.
Think of a job as the
foundation of your life.
If you're balancing
everything on one foundation,
when an earthquake hits,
such as a recession,
your whole life is gonna crumble away.
By having a side hustle,
you create another stream of income
that strengthens the
foundations of your life.
Now, if you lose your main job,
you still have a source of
income to pay your bills
and it can prevent you
from falling into bad debt.
My early jobs only just paid enough
to keep my head above water.
So I always had a few side jobs.
One that was great was teaching people
to fly model helicopters.
I developed a skill that
many struggled to master
and I charged to pass on this skill.
The extra money I earned
covered all my normal expenses.
So then, I had the ability to invest all
of my salary into
starting my own business.
It might seem impossible
to start a side hustle
when we're going into a recession.
But if you look hard enough,
there are online
industries that are booming
such as selling digital products
and affiliate marketing.
People have the tendency
to turn to entertainment
in hard times like Netflix, for example,
and therefore don't bother putting in
the extra effort after they
finish their day's work.
But this is the time to double down
and hustle as much as possible.
Money trap seven, not
living within your means.
People have got used to the good times.
So many are spending more
money than they actually have.
You've seen the people
buying expensive cars
that you know they could never afford
with their income alone.
People are racking up
the credit card bills
like there is no tomorrow.
This isn't a good idea
in the best of times
but it's especially important
to live within your means
or even below them when
the economy is slowing.
By creating a budget
and cutting out all the
unnecessary spending,
you're able to invest more
and focus on what really matters to you.
After all, is getting the next car,
the latest clothes, and
the most fancy house
really worth it if you end up having
to give up your future hopes and dreams?
Money trap eight, get rich quick schemes.
This is something I had to mention
as I'm seeing it more and more.
Clever marketers are
selling online courses
that promise big things.
More often than not, the
only people getting rich
are the ones running the scheme.
There is usually nothing wrong
with what they're teaching.
Amazon FBA, Dropshipping,
and Affiliate Marketing,
they're all real businesses that have
the potential to make you some money
but they market towards
people without any experience.
They sell a dream that
anyone can become rich
if they follow their simple formula.
You have to ask yourself,
if it was that easy,
why aren't they doing it themselves?
They basically package a
legitimate business idea
in a way that looks attractive
to the everyday person
but fail to mention
that their success rate
is near rock bottom.
So whenever you see an
ad from some guy standing
in front of a Lamborghini promising you
the world on a silver platter,
it's probably a good idea
to be a bit skeptical
and do your own research.
You're now ready to learn
exactly how to invest
and benefit from the Cameron recession.
So I recommend watching this video next
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay?
I'll see over there.