Speaker 1:
That was the average salary in 2022, $53,000. This
is how much passive income I've generated in
the last month alone, $250,000. That's the power
of having multiple income streams.
Speaker 1:
So today I'm going to reveal the five passive
income ideas I've used to make more than
a thousand dollars in 24 hours. But here's a
warning: if you think this is going to be easy,
then please stop watching this video right now.
If it was easy to make a thousand dollars every 24
hours, then everyone would be doing it. However,
I can tell you this, if you're prepared to put in
the work required to set up these income streams,
then it's entirely possible. I should know, as I
started with absolutely nothing to my name.
Speaker 1:
Idea number one, starting an email newsletter.
Hi guys. It's Mark. So what have I told you you
could press Send on an email and earn thousands
of dollars in a couple of seconds? This might
sound impossible, however, people are already
doing it. A popular email newsletter called The
Hustle was actually recently sold for
between 25 and 30 million dollars.
Speaker 1:
The best part about starting an
email newsletter is its very low barrier to entry.
This makes it a lot easier than any other type of
content creation as all you need is a laptop or
even a phone. It's also mostly free to start,
as most platforms allow you to grow to a thousand
subscribers before charging you a single penny.
There's actually a popular saying that you only
need a thousand true fans to become a millionaire.
This kind of loyalty is what email
newsletters are great for building.
Speaker 1:
I've recently started a free newsletter of
my own called Strike It Big, which is loaded with
valuable information and insights about growing
your wealth that you won't get anywhere else.
I only launched this a month ago and I already
have over 10,000 subscribers enjoying the content.
If you're interested in receiving weekly emails,
I'll drop a link below. Due to its success. I've
actually had brands reach out to me and offer
thousands of dollars for one quick mention.
Speaker 1:
I put a lot of the success down to the way I've
always approached life. You should aim to give
more than you get. With a newsletter, it's
so important to offer your audience a huge
amount of free value. Then in the future, if
you do want to ask them to do you a favor,
they'll be happy to help you out. In addition
to this, you need to be interested. I remember
a friend of mine telling me that his company sends
out a long email every week to keep everyone up to
date with what's going on. However, it was a bit
of a running joke in the office that no one read
it. That's why it's so important to entertain, as
people come for the content, but stay because of
your entertainment value.
Speaker 1:
If you don't know what to write about,
then you could just curate things that
you find interesting throughout the week and
share them with your subscribers. This is
what Tim Ferriss does with his 5 Bullet Friday
newsletter, and he now has over 2 million fans,
makes millions from sponsorships and affiliates.
Affiliate links are a great way to instantly make
money if you are growing your list, because if
you want to recommend a product to your audience,
then you'll get a kickback if anyone
chooses to buy using your link.
Speaker 1:
Whatever you choose to write about, it's very
important to make your subscribers a promise of
both quality and reliability. You need to convince
them that it's worth their time. The main benefit
of an email newsletter is that you're able to
own your audience. This is very rare as on other
platforms like YouTube, I'm not able to contact
you directly. That's what makes newsletters a
great way to make passive income, and who knows,
you may end up selling for 75 million dollars
like Morning Brew, an email newsletter Austin
Rief started in his college dorm.
Speaker 1:
Idea number two, collecting royalties. Have you
ever wondered why so many music artists try and
get a Christmas number one? Well, it's all about
the royalties. Noddy Holder lead singer of the
1970s glam rock band Slade once said that his song
Merry Christmas, everybody is his pension, and he
wasn't joking. That one song will pay him a decent
living in royalties for the rest of his life,
without him having to live a single finger.
Speaker 1:
If you can't sing, like me, then the good news is
it's not just musicians who can collect royalties.
Authors, script writers, inventors, and others
benefit from the resales of their products
and ideas. I'm going to be honest with you,
this requires a lot of upfront work. However,
once you've created something, then you can
continue to get paid for it forever. To be honest,
you are taking a bit of a risk because if you
don't get enough people to see your creation
or use your invention, then your time would go to
waste. To minimize this risk, it's very important
to identify a proven demand. Be on the lookout for
something scarce or not being done very well that
you can improve upon.
Speaker 1:
My eyes were opened up to this when I turned
on monetization on this YouTube channel,
I never aimed to become a YouTuber. I just noticed
there was a lack of financial education in school,
so I had to take things into my own hands. I
heard somewhere that if I turned on the adverts,
then YouTube would promote my videos more. Now
I don't know if this was true, but it did seem
to work. To my amazement, what of my early videos
gained 4 million views and has now made me over a
hundred thousand dollars in royalties. Even if
you don't fancy making videos, then you could
team up with someone that does and write their
scripts in return for a split of the profits.
Speaker 1:
Surprisingly, there are
also ways you can benefit from royalties without
actually creating anything. This is because in
order to gain money to fund projects, it's very
common for creators to sell their royalties or a
percentage of them. If this was a songwriter, then
they would still own the rights to those tracks,
but would share a part of their income with an
investor whenever they were played on the radio
or streamed online. I've actually been offered
money to buy my future AdSense for my old videos.
MrBeast has used a service like this before called
Spotter. They've already spent 200 million on
royalties, which shows there's a lot of potential
for you to make at least a thousand dollars per
day in passive income.
Speaker 1:
Idea number three, selling digital products.
Imagine making two million dollars in 10 minutes,
all from the comfort of your sitting room.
Well, my son Curtis was recently telling
me about one of his past clients who did
exactly that selling digital products. Now,
digital products can't be held, tasted or touched,
but everyone consumes them now more than ever.
Speaker 1:
They also come with a whole
host of benefits that make them perfect for making
passive income. Firstly, as they aren't physical,
it means you don't have to pay for storage and
they never run out of stock. Secondly, your profit
margins are very highest. The cost of creating
a digital product only has to be paid once,
and then you have it forever. Thirdly, you don't
have to worry about shipping nightmares or paying
people to send your items for you.
Speaker 1:
Many people have told me that I'm silly for
not selling an online course as there is a
lot of demand. However, as it's
so easy to get into the market,
there are a lot of bad products out there. This
is a shame as it's given the whole industry a
bad name. So that's why if I were to sell
anything, then I'd have to give it a lot of
time and energy. And at the moment, that's just
not possible as I'm running multiple businesses
outside of YouTube. All I ever do is tell you
about the free stock worth between three and
a thousand dollars from public.com that you
can pick up with a link in the description,
as at least it gives you something back and the
channel benefits from people using the link.
Speaker 1:
So just remember,
when you're creating your digital product, just
make sure that you are making something that's
truly valuable. Sometimes the easiest way to
improve an idea is to do what's called a scrappy
launch. The goal is to get something out into the
world as soon as possible so you can put your idea
to the test and improve from there. You can sell
templates, courses, audio books, spreadsheets,
and even licenses With a quality product, you'd
be making a thousand dollars a day in no time.
Speaker 1:
Idea number four, be the middle man. I
recently sat down with a man who made 10 million
dollars by the age of 21 selling items online,
but the funny thing is he never actually held any
of the products in his hands. This is completely
different to me because I generate a lot of money
selling physical products using the internet. But
it's time consuming and it also costs me
thousands in warehouse space, staff wages,
and packing materials.
Speaker 1:
That's where both drop shipping and drop servicing
comes into play. Since the pandemic, online
business has surged beyond belief and by the end
of 2022, these sales will likely reach over five
trillion dollars. There truly is an abundance of
cash out there ready to be collected, and with the
right strategy, you don't even have to be the
one sending the parcels or doing the work.
Speaker 1:
Drop shipping and drop
servicing is selling physical products or services
on the internet without ever stocking the product
yourself. This allows you to start your very own
business with minimal costs as there's no staff,
storage, or inventory fees. If that sounds
too good to be true, then believe me,
it's not. You're getting paid for your marketing
and online expertise. Just think about it,
the people buying the products and services you
are advertising wouldn't have known that they
ever wanted a product without your help. This is
why your skillset is valuable to both the customer
and also the supplier.
Speaker 1:
You're the middle man. All you need to do is find
a supplier that sells popular, winning products
or has a range that excites you and build a store
around it. Every time a customer orders from you,
all you need to do is place an order with
the supplier and have it shipped directly to
their address. You can also do this with services
instead of products, like selling logos. All you'd
have to do is find a customer, get a designer,
and instruct them to make it to your client's
specification for less than you charged. If you
can buy a product for $5 and sell it for $20,
you are making a cool $15 profit every single
sale. Of course, there are other expenses,
like advertising costs and returns, but you
get the idea. As you grow your business,
you can generate higher profits by introducing new
products and achieve the almighty $1,000 a day.
Speaker 1:
Idea number five, launching a membership. At the
height of Andrew Tate's popularity, he had 108,000
members paying him $49 per month. That means he
was making an eye watering 5.3 million dollars
every single month, all from a simple membership
site. I think this example shows you that even if
you were able to get a fraction of Tate's success,
then this can be a very lucrative way to
make a lot of passive income. In my opinion,
this type of income is better than a lot of
others on the list as it's very predictable.
You can easily tell how much will be coming in
every month as long as you retain your members.
The Sidemen have even taken notice of this
passive income stream and recently launched Side+.
They're charging about $10 per month and probably
making millions in reliable, passive income.
Speaker 1:
The beauty of a membership
is that there's no limit to how many members you
can acquire. Plus, it's easy to scale up without
increasing your workload. I actually started
a free Discord group last month for fun called
Strike It Big. It's for anyone that's interested
in entrepreneurship and investing. I just felt
like it was time to have a home for our community.
I'll leave a link down below if you want to jump
in. It's completely free.
Speaker 1:
In order to create a successful membership, you
need to have some kind of niche and value that
you're providing, then host it on the platform
that your audience uses the most. The best I
found are Facebook and Discord. I've seen golf,
swimming, business, and cooking memberships
absolutely smashing it and making far more
than a thousand dollars every 24 hours.
Speaker 1:
These are unpredictable times though,
with the growing fear of a coming recession. If
you want to know what you need to do with your
money right now, then I'd recommend watching
this video. But don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if you want to grow
your wealth. Okay, I'll see over there.