- What you do with your money
right now is so important
if you wanna become rich, but why?
Well, the world is on shaky ground
with a wealth bubble set
to pop and energy crisis
in the works and a looming
threat, a recession.
It seems like all hope is lost.
Well, not quiet.
However, millennials are running out
of time to build wealth.
It's no surprise that
American household debt just
hit a record high of over 16 trillion
and credit card balance has
increased by $46 billion,
in the second quarter of 2022.
I completely get that
the current situation
has left some people in dire circumstances
and sometimes debt is the
only logical solution.
That's why today I'm gonna be running
through the four things
you should be doing
with your money right now.
And they might not be
quite what you think.
Step one, humble yourself.
Hi guys, it's Mark.
So 72% of U.S. adults
now use social media.
So it's no surprise that
a lot of people waste time
and money trying to keep
up with the Joneses.
This means striving to achieve our own,
as much as the people around you.
When it comes to pushing
yourself to achieve more,
this isn't a bad thing.
However, when it comes
to stretching your budget to
buy things you don't need,
it's a big problem.
In reality, luxury goods
are often purchased
to increase self-esteem
and provide a sense
of belonging that often
isn't found elsewhere.
Trying to keep up with the
Joneses with excess spending
and credit card debt is a bad move.
When I was much younger,
the way I was able
to beat my family and friends was actually
by doing the polar opposite to them.
Instead of buying things I couldn't afford
to impress people on the
street that I didn't even like,
I began to think about the kind
of future I wanted for
myself and my family.
This led me to making the
minimum payments every month
on all my debt and then
using any extra money to pay
off the debt with the
highest interest rate.
This is now commonly known
as the debt avalanche method.
This is proven to be one
of the most efficient
ways to clear debt fast.
Give it a try if your
struggling with debt.
I always found it
beneficial to gamify things
by striving to beat targets.
Ripping the debt chain
off your neck allows you
to think freely and move
on to the fun part, saving money
and growing your net worth,
because after all money makes money.
I'd like to set you a
fun, small challenge that
if completed correctly will open your eyes
to the power of saving
money and compounding.
Today, save one penny in a piggy bank.
I know it doesn't sound
like much but stick with me,
tomorrow save two.
On the third day, save three.
We're really building up the
cash here, but seriously,
keep increasing your saving
amount daily by one penny.
And at the end of the year,
you'll have over $650 saved up,
all starting from one simple penny.
If you don't actually
want to use a piggy bank,
then you can use one of
those apps that round
up your purchases then saves
the difference for you.
If you can afford more,
then of course this is great.
While doing this,
it's important not to
inflate your lifestyle.
I actually recently had a guy
called Hugh on my podcast,
strike it big,
who lived on 10K per year
while still paying a mortgage?
- What's it like living on 10K a year?
I sold my car and bike to work two
and a half miles every day.
I made packed lunches every day.
I didn't buy any new clothes
or items unless absolutely necessary.
The goal was really to
try and track my path
to financial independence
by the time I'm 40.
And the way I went at it was level one,
which is why I teach everyone,
is get your expenses down.
I bike to work.
I went pretty extreme.
I'm like an all in or nothing type of guy.
And I probably went a little bit too far.
- Well, I always say that
you can only save so much.
There's a limit to how much you can save.
However, there isn't a limit
to how much you can earn.
So I would always personally
focus more on earning.
- That was the same equation I got to.
- That brings me to step
two, spend strategically.
Now this might sound like the opposite
to what a lot of people tell you,
but usually when you go against the crowd,
you end up achieving far
more than the average person.
It seems like there's a theme
appearing in this video.
When I was younger, my dad
would always stress to me
the importance of saving as much money
as I could in my bank account.
And maybe just maybe,
one day I could afford a house of my own.
However, this is playing
into exactly what the
banks want you to do.
Here's why.
Throughout the years,
the most influential companies
of each generation have been
in different fields.
At the moment, six out
of the top 10 companies in the
world are in the tech sector.
However, as these industries
shift in popularity
one thing remains constant,
the banking system.
But how do banks consistently
manage to stay on top,
grow their power over the years
and build bigger and bigger skyscrapers?
Well, an economist named Richard Werner
had the same question.
He gained access to the back end
of the banking system
and did an experiment.
The aim of his test was
to monitor where exactly
the money was coming from.
Surprisingly, it didn't come
from the bank's deposits,
nor did it come from the reserves.
It effectively just appeared
from thin air backed only by an IOU note.
And he states, this is where 97%
of money comes from.
Debt creation on a mass scale
like this is only possible
because of the millions
of people that save the
majority of their money.
Therefore, by doing this,
you're just helping more bankers get rich.
Of course, I believe you should have
at least an emergency fund
of three to five month
if you live in expenses,
however, once you've done that,
you should be focused
on using the money to increase
your earning potential.
You are paid in direct proportion
to how much value you
bring to the marketplace.
Therefore your main aim should
be to increase this value,
so you have even more cash to play with.
Think of it like leveling
up your character,
instead of just saving useless
gems in your game vault.
My son Curtis started his
business as a videographer.
However, continually spent
his money strategically
to learn new skills.
Quickly, he bought more
cameras that allowed him
to increase his day
rate from $200 to $300.
Next, he gained a drone commercial license
that allowed him to start
charging 500 pound per day.
And now after learning
copywriting, editing, presenting,
social media, branding and leadership,
he's charged up to $10,000 per day.
No matter what job or business you have,
there is always a way to spend your money
strategically to level
up your earning potential.
But we need to discuss how
to spot the good investments
from the bad ones.
But first I'd like to thank
today's sponsor public.com.
Public is an investing
platform with a strong focus
on helping you be a better
and smarter investor.
On Public, you can invest in
thousands of stocks, ETFs,
and even 30 different cryptocurrencies.
The best part for the first time ever,
not only can you build a
portfolio that features stocks
and crypto, you can also
soon add blue chip NFTs,
like a crypto punk
or a pair of game war
Michael Jordan sneakers.
Overall Public is a
great app that I trust.
And for a limited time, when
you sign up at public.com/mark,
you'll get up to $10,000 when
you transfer your account
from another brokerage,
depending on the transfer amount.
See additional terms and
conditions of this offer
by following the link in the description.
Step three, develop your Spidey sense.
You know how Spiderman has the ability
to know when something
bad is about to happen?
You need to be like this with your money.
There are so many sharks
out there looking to scam you
out your hard earned cash.
During a crypto rally,
I unfortunately saw so
many 18 to 20 year olds
YOLO their life savings into scam coins.
This is so disappointing,
as it isn't just about
the money they lost,
it's also about the
opportunity cost involved
with throwing that money away.
There is a phrase that
making your first 10K
is the hardest, and
that is often very true,
as you're able to leverage
that 10K to earn even more.
Everything is easier
once you have momentum.
However, when you lose a lot
on a scam or a bad crypto coin,
it can completely halt that progression.
There are three main things I look out for
when I'm unsure about something.
First, does it sound too good to be true?
Now I took one look at many
of the crypto lending platforms
and wouldn't touch them.
This is because they were
offering eye watering amounts
of interest and it just
wasn't sustainable.
This was a good decision,
as many of these companies
are now bankrupt like Celsius and Voyager.
Second, is the utility of
the investment obvious?
When I look at most NFTs,
I can't see any obvious
uses for the product,
at least not something that
justifies the crazy prices.
This is because during a bull market,
most people are buying them in hope
that they will increase in value,
so they can sell them later
on and make a nice profit.
This means that it's only a matter
of time before the asset crashes in value.
And unless you want a very stressful life
of checking your investments on the daily,
then I'll steer clear.
Third, are you being driven
by your brain or emotion?
This one is hard to identify,
as it's very common for
people to convince themselves
that they're making a logical choice.
However, often it's just a
way to justify their emotions.
Many scammers and hardcore salesmen rely
on this by pushing certain mental triggers
to make you buy whatever they're selling.
A lot of the time it's digital products.
Most of these online
courses can often be useful.
However, before making
any big purchase decisions
it's a good idea to wait seven days to see
if you still want it.
This tricks your brain into
giving you the dopamine hit
and allows you to think far more clearly
about your purchases.
Step four, build your empire.
Becoming a millionaire,
it's a lot like rolling a snowball
down the hill and
watching it gain momentum.
In my early twenties, I
had a houseware of $150,000
a flatware of 46K,
a business with 116K worth of
stock that was all paid off
and a 100K in cash.
My business was also
turning over half a million
and I could have easily
sold it for $300,000.
I know this because I had suppliers
that would've purchased it instantly,
as they were expanding like crazy.
When you have an abundance of cash,
many opportunities open up
and accelerate the snowball.
At this point, you no longer
need the majority of your money
for increasing the value you
offer to the marketplace.
This is because of the role
of diminishing returns.
When you first start
investing in your skillset
even small amounts make a huge difference.
However, once you get to a certain stage,
it becomes increasingly more
expensive for marginal gain.
Now, lots of people will say
that you can become financially free
from property investing,
which can be true.
However, to do this effectively
you would almost have to treat it
like it's its own business.
And it's no longer
the passive investment
it was promised to be.
Therefore, in my opinion,
you should firstly
build up a liquid asset portfolio.
I'm talking blue chip stocks and crypto.
Recently, I heard someone say
that if you can't write a check
for $1 million within
the next couple of days,
then you aren't actually
a real millionaire.
This is a good way to look at it.
As there are so many
millionaires that have
their network tied up in their family home
and never get to benefit from it.
I built a sizable stock portfolio rapidly
and then reinvested the cash flow
into more stocks and finally
investment properties.
Now I'm getting a bit older.
I'm so glad that I have those
investments that bring me
in money without me having
to even think about them.
My stock portfolio is mostly made up
of index funds with quite a
bias towards the America market
through the S&P 500,
This has served me unbelievably
well over the years.
If you just take one thing from today,
then it should be never
lock your baby money away
as you won't reach the major leagues.
Let it play, so your wealth
journey can get underway.
If you wanna increase your income,
but don't know what business to start,
here's some business ideas
I've hand selected for 2022.
But don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe,
if you want to grow your wealth, okay?
I'll see you over there.