Hi guys,
It's Mark.
So the biggest transfer
of wealth in history
is about to happen.
Thousands of millennials and Gen Cs
are set to become crypto millionaires.
And if you understand
the mistakes to avoid,
then you have a much better
chance of being one of them.
Now, I understand that's
a big statement to make,
but let me explain.
We've seen many wealth
transfers like this before,
each one more significant than the last.
First, it was the discovery of gold,
then the real estate craze
caused by colonization,
followed by the industrial revolution
and the stock market boom.
I remember them all like it was yesterday!
But seriously, the next transfer of wealth
is about to happen,
and it will be the
digitization of our currencies,
otherwise known as cryptocurrencies.
But this doesn't mean
that everyone will end
up becoming millionaires,
as there are many mistakes
that could cause people
to lose everything.
So today, let's discuss 7.5
of the most dangerous
cryptocurrency investing mistakes
to make and how you can avoid them
so that you can make the most
from this amazing opportunity.
If you're excited about the possibilities,
then smash that like button
for the AlTubeUgorithm,
because it helps push
this video to more people
that need to hear about these mistakes
before it's too late.
Mistake number one is
believing false promises.
Here's a little warning for you.
Wherever there is
significant money to be made,
there are people trying to scam you.
You may think only gullible
people fall for crypto scams,
so let's play a little game
and see if you're right.
Can you tell which one of
these headlines I've made up
and which one is real?
Shiba Inu trader made
$15 million in a year
from just $17 in crypto boom.
Or, 12-year-old boy makes
£290,000 from whale NFTs.
Believe it or not, they're both real.
So my point is,
if both of these headlines
can actually be true,
then imagine how hard it is
for the everyday person
to avoid the scams.
Cryptocurrencies are
still such a new thing,
and while the industry is
growing at a rapid rate,
there's still a huge amount of people
that aren't very familiar with crypto.
And, unfortunately, those are
the people that will get hurt.
This is because when large
returns aren't uncommon,
it becomes extremely hard
to tell the difference
between real opportunities and fake ones.
It's become very well known that Bitcoin
is the best performing
asset of the last decade.
However, that doesn't mean every crypto
is a smart investment.
Actually, some are far from it.
Because crypto is such a new thing,
it means the market isn't regulated,
like with stocks and shares.
This means that anyone can
actually create a crypto coin,
get people to invest by claiming
it's the next big thing,
only to sell all their coins
and run off with millions of dollars.
This is commonly referred
to as a rug pull.
A YouTuber called Biaheza
recently proved this
by creating a crypto named Fluffy Coin.
He showcases how simple
it is to make a meme coin
and use social media to pump
up the price into the millions.
Now, luckily, Biaheza was
only doing this as an example
and didn't sell any of his coins,
but it does show how easy it is
for scammers to get ahold of your money.
That's not to say you can't
make some cash invested
in pump-and-dumps,
but if you take Fluffy Coin as an example,
if you didn't sell on December the third,
you would have probably
lost most of your money.
- But Mark, if these
scams are so hard to spot,
how can I avoid them?
- Well, there are a few
simple things you can do
to avoid the majority of rug pulls.
Firstly, make sure to check
the coin's social media.
It's really easy for these
scammers to buy fake followers,
to make the coin look
more popular than it is.
A great way to check if they're real
is to use a website called Social Blade.
If the follower number spikes randomly,
then it's pretty obvious
that there's something fishy going on.
Secondly, every crypto project
has something called a white paper.
This is where the coin
creators outline their mission
for the project.
After reading a few of these,
you can usually tell pretty quickly
if the project is legitimate or not.
Thirdly, if you're not sure
about crypto investing,
then just stick to Bitcoin and Ethereum,
as these are now commonly
referred to as blue chip coins,
meaning they're a much safer bet.
Mistake number two is investing more
than you can afford to lose.
Crypto's upside potential
is absolutely huge,
and therefore the temptation
to YOLO as much of your
money in as possible
can be very strong.
I mean, all you have to do
is a simple Google search
to find hundreds of people
that have made millions
and change their entire lives
by taking big risks investing in crypto,
so it's no surprise at all
that people are investing
a lot more than they can afford to lose,
with the hopes that it
will transform their lives
and they will become the next
success story reported online.
What people don't consider, though,
is all the stories of the
people who lost their money,
their house, literally
everything, from crypto trading.
It's extremely volatile
and definitely not for the faint-hearted.
I always try and remember,
for every success story,
there are countless
numbers of forgotten people
that haven't been so lucky.
However, there is a fine line
between buying more than
you can afford to lose
and buying nothing at all,
because if you're not investing,
you're most likely losing
out on potential gains.
I believe it's all about
finding a healthy balance,
especially if you're
investing in riskier projects.
Typically, the higher the
risk, the higher the reward,
so you don't actually need to
part every last penny you have
into a random coin to get your
one-way ticket to the moon.
If I invest in alt coins
then I buy small amounts,
as I know that if the
project goes to the moon,
then I'll make a nice profit,
but if it goes to zero,
then I won't be too worried.
It's all about finding that sweet spot
between risk and reward.
Mistake number three is
buying high and selling low.
This may sound extremely
obvious and simple,
but so many people are
unknowingly making this mistake
and losing an absolute
fortune in the process.
It's very common in the crypto world
to see huge bull runs driving the price
of a crypto far higher
than the average yearly
stock market returns
in just a single day.
And while that's amazing,
imagine FOMOing into a coin
when it's right at the top,
only for it to drop the next day
and you have no choice but to sell,
as you need money for
your rent or groceries.
The way I avoid this mistake
is by following the same formula
that I've used my entire investing life,
and let me tell you,
I've made a lot of money doing it.
And that's quite simply,
buying, holding long-term,
and then buying more when the price dips.
This is known as dollar cost averaging.
Essentially, I'll buy Bitcoin and Ethereum
no matter what the market is doing.
Sometimes I'll get a good bargain
and other times it will be expensive.
However, the idea is
that it will average out
to a pretty good deal.
Because you know me,
(cash register ringing)
I love a good deal.
I also never invest money
I know that I might need
in the next five years,
as that's just a recipe for disaster,
especially in a volatile crypto world.
By the way, Coinbase are
currently giving away $10 worth
of free Bitcoin,
so if you want to pick that up,
I'll leave the link in
the description below.
Mistake number four is being
fooled by cheap prices.
When I tell people I invest in Bitcoin,
one of the most common
things they say to me
is that it's too expensive for them.
One person even laughed at me
and said that one coin costs
more than their yearly wage.
This is probably why many
people prefer to invest
in cheaper coins like DOGE.
You're probably wondering
why I keep doing this.
It's because on the surface
they might look cheaper.
However, when you start
digging into the details,
it starts to fall apart.
I'm talking about taking market cap
and total supply into consideration.
Let's compare Bitcoin and
Dogecoin, for example.
Bitcoin currently has a market
cap of nearly $900 billion
and a total supply of
nearly 19 million Bitcoins,
whereas DOGE has a market
cap of just over $23 billion
and a total supply of just
over 132 billion coins.
So as you can see,
Dogecoin is worth far,
far less than Bitcoin,
but has far, far more coins.
That's why the price is lower.
So just because a coin appears cheap,
it doesn't necessarily mean
it's going to be a good investment.
DOGE will never be the
same price as Bitcoin,
due to the extremely large total supply,
which is being increased
by 5 billion every year,
whereas Bitcoin is capped
at 21 million coins.
It's also important to remember
that you can buy fractions of a coin
and still benefit from their growth,
so the price of one Bitcoin is irrelevant
at the end of the day.
The best solution to this mistake
is not to buy coins based
on their surface cost.
It's so important to take into account
the total supply as
well as the market cap,
in order to get a realistic
gauge of the price
and where it could be heading.
Mistake number five is
investing only in crypto.
Although I believe crypto
is a huge opportunity,
just imagine we wake up tomorrow
and the market has hit rock bottom.
If you had only invested in crypto,
then you would probably
be losing your mind.
Even though I'm pretty
sure something like this
is highly unlikely, especially
with Bitcoin and Ethereum,
I would still never invest
in just one asset class.
The easiest additional
investments to consider
are Index Funds and individual stocks,
but for some people,
real estate could be an option.
For others, like my son,
you might choose an
alternative investment,
such as a Rolex.
I have to say I'm also partial
to the old classic car investment myself.
Broom, broom!
The goal here is to decrease your risk.
Cryptocurrencies are known
to be a volatile asset class,
so diversifying your portfolio
may allow you to make money
if crypto is heading into a correction.
If you want to kickstart
your stock portfolio,
then public.com are currently giving away
a free stock worth all the
way up to a thousand dollars
when you sign up and invest
just $1 on the platform.
I'll leave the link in
the description below,
if you wanna check that out.
Mistake number six is using leverage.
If you aren't careful,
then you can actually lose
far more than you invest
by doing this.
Just imagine only investing
a thousand dollars
of your own money,
but waking up and being $7,000 in debt.
Well, that's what you call a bad morning.
This kind of situation
happens when you use leverage
without fully understanding
the consequences.
Many crypto brokers allow
you to trade on margin,
which simply means you're
able to multiply your money.
Some people are doing this
by a hundred X with Bitcoin.
When you do this,
you maximize your profits
as you're investing more,
but you'll also increase your risk,
as if the investment doesn't go well,
then you may be margin called
and forced to sell all
your crypto at a loss.
Although using leverage
is really tempting,
I always stay away from it personally.
I know a lot of people
would disagree with me here.
However, I'm a long-term investor,
and can't be sure what the
price of some cryptos will be
in the next day.
Therefore, I'm more interested
in the next 10 years.
That's of course, if I'm around that long.
Because of this,
I don't feel like using
margin is a smart move,
even though I could
afford to pay things back
if it all went south.
If you still decide you
want to use leverage,
then I would just suggest making sure
you fully understand the risk
involved before you dive in.
Mistake number seven is not
storing your coins correctly.
Since 2011, over $1.65
billion worth of crypto
has been stolen,
and the numbers are growing every year.
That amounts to a jaw-dropping
$12.6 billion loss
when values are adjusted for inflation.
The nature of crypto makes
it extremely vulnerable
to hackers, and if you don't
store it in a safe place,
once your coins are stolen,
there is no way to recover them.
You see the stories all the time
of people trying to
find their lost Bitcoin.
it's just not gonna happen.
Not your keys, not your crypto.
Most people will buy their crypto
on an exchange like
Coinbase, and keep it there.
And that's the issue.
It's been said that it's
much more profitable
to hack a crypto exchange
than a bank vault these days.
Therefore, it's
understandable why exchanges
are often targeted by highly
complex cyber attacks.
Exchanges lose a staggering
daily average of $2.7 million,
and this figure is set to
increase in the future.
- Mark, this sounds so scary.
I don't know what to do
to fight a cyber attack!
- Well, you need your own wallet,
and there are two different types.
The first is called a hot wallet.
These are connected to the internet
and could be susceptible
to online attacks,
which could lead to stolen funds,
but it does have benefits,
such as being faster and making it easier
to trade or spend crypto.
The second is a cold wallet,
which is how I currently store
the majority of my crypto.
This is typically not
connected to the internet,
so while it may be more
secure, it's less convenient.
to the wrong wallet.
Sending crypto between your wallets
is a pretty scary process.
I once sent over a hundred
thousand dollars' worth
of Bitcoin and I thought
I'd made a mistake
when typing out the wallet address.
The old eyes aren't as good these days.
All it takes is for one
character to be typed wrong
and that hundred K would
have been lost forever.
Luckily, 10 stressful minutes later,
my Bitcoin arrived in my
other wallet, nice and safely.
To avoid this ever happening again,
I now always transfer a
small amount of crypto first,
to check the characters are correct,
and copy and paste the address,
or use the QR code option
to avoid human error.
Cryptocurrency is quickly
becoming adopted by people,
corporations, and now even countries,
with El Salvador leading the way.
We have little choice but to embrace it,
or become extinct, like the dinosaurs.
I truly believe that this is
an extremely exciting time
to be alive,
as by avoiding these common mistakes,
you'll be able to take advantage
of the next big wealth transfer.
So if you're living in this day and age,
you'll never be able to say
you didn't have the chance
to become wealthy.
Just imagine explaining to your kids
how you knew about crypto
and didn't take action,
or rushed in and made silly mistakes.
I'm gonna leave the next
video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you wanna grow your wealth,
and don't forget to
pick up your free stocks
and Bitcoin with the links below.