This is the 23 year old
worth over $85 million.
And this is the story of
how I spent the day with him
and uncovered how he
became more successful
than 99.9% of men on the planet.
But the craziest thing about all of this
is I let him take control of the day.
So I didn't know what to expect.
Good morning.
- How are you?
- I'm very well.
How are you?
Hakim.
- Thank you very much.
- No problem.
- I can't lie, I don't know
what the day's holding.
As we've said, we're just
in one of the best places
on this planet.
I'm really hoping that we
can show how Iman's come
from nothing and grown his
wealth to where he is today.
He's done it in an amazingly
short amount of time.
That's the hard bit to
comprehend is the time scale.
He's 23 years old and worth
around about $80+ million.
It's quite amazing as
we drive along the Palm
when you look at it, you
wouldn't actually think
that each of these branches
was as long as it is
and I'm guessing this is
gonna be about a mile long.
Yeah, t's quite surprising.
(intense music)
How are you, sir?
- Apologies, the place is a bit of a mess.
- I always use that line.
It looks gorgeous.
It's stunning, isn't it?
Absolutely stunning.
Yeah, how long have you
owned this property?
- So this place I'm renting at the moment.
- Yeah.
- Finding a place on the Palm
is very difficult because-
- It looks sold out, doesn't it?
(wall knocking)
- Everything's very cheap here.
- [Interviewer] Really?
- So you'll get like a $10
million house and yeah,
everything's just built so poorly.
(lighthearted music)
That house sold I think for $35 million.
That one right there is
$100 million, but that one
at the end is just crazy.
The rent on this is like $50,000 a month.
- And are you looking to make
this your base, Dubai now?
- Yeah, a hundred percent.
- That and South Africa.
- Yeah, Cape Town.
Cape Town is the best
bro, I'm telling you.
- Now I knew that Iman was doing well,
but having a villa on the
Palm, well that's next level.
It's one of the most desirable
places to live in the world
and he's achieved all of this
from very humble beginnings.
He's living the life that
many people dream about.
I was intrigued to know
if he still wanted more.
You said it was about
$50,000 a month to rent.
- Yeah.
- Do you begrudge that a little bit?
- I mean, it is what it is
because I'm still only what,
six, seven years into having a business?
If you're always on a trajectory
up, then you always know
that you're gonna get to a
point where you can upgrade.
Like I always tell people,
"listen, would you still
buy that same house if
you had $300 million?"
And they're like, "no,
I'd buy this house."
That's why, for example, that
doesn't make sense to spend
you know, $10 million
on a penthouse in Dubai
because there's always
gonna be that new penthouse
that's nicer.
I don't know.
I was looking at a Phantom.
- Yeah.
- So I really wanted to
get a Phantom, but they're
18 months at the moment
to get them specked out.
So I was looking at
what was on the market.
They're all very like
little bit too old man-ny.
- [Interviewer] You get
something like a Lamborghini Urus
or something like that.
- Nah, I hate those cars.
- Really?
- I mean I was thinking about
getting a Wagon as well,
'cause that's my favorite car ever.
And then I'm thinking about
also getting a a Maybach.
But once again, we're still
here only like half the year.
We travel in and out quite a lot.
Even the house, I've
had it for five months.
I've been there for
three weeks, two weeks,
something like that?
- Most people would be
over the moon to be living
in a multi-million
dollar villa on the Palm
but to Iman, this isn't
even scratching the surface
of his ambition.
He thinks he's destined for more.
Maybe has some kind of
superiority complex.
So would you walk around
with that particularly
nice Richard Mille in London?
- Axe, would I walk around
with an RM in London?
- We just have to go through things
and talk about where
we're going and plan it
and if it makes sense,
then we can wear a watch.
If it don't, then we won't wear a watch.
- Yeah.
- Simple as that.
- [Interviewer] So
we've arrived somewhere.
- Yeah, I've got a little gift.
I would've given it to you at the house,
but there's a little bit of-
There's a few options
that you can choose from.
Just for valet up front here.
Simone, I'll message you
maybe like 90 minutes.
Yeah, I'll let you know.
That's another thing.
People come to Dubai for shopping.
- Yeah.
- Dubai is the worst place
on earth for shopping.
For some people it's their heaven.
But for me, like European
shopping, London shopping.
London shopping's the best in the world.
- Because obviously a lot
of high profile stores
actually have queues outside, don't they?
- Yeah, I know.
- You don't need to queue.
- Nah, I mean that sounds bad.
Sometimes.
It depends.
It depends on the brand.
- Iman said he had a surprise
for me and knowing him,
it was gonna be special.
I'm super excited for you to
see the rest of this video.
But first, I wanted to
share something with you
that I think could really help you
with investing in the long term.
Have you heard of Lightyear?
It's an investment app that's
on a mission to help investors
across Europe and they're
kindly sponsoring today's video.
One of the things I love about Lightyear
is that it's so user-friendly.
Even if you're new to
investing, you'll find a wealth
of data and information
on the brands and funds
you want to invest in.
Another great thing about
Lightyear is that it gives you
access to over 3000 stocks and
ETFs from all over the world.
Lightyear is now available
in 20 plus countries
throughout Europe.
So if you're watching
this from a country that
spends the pound or Euro, it's
available to you right now.
And if you sign up with my
code "tilbury" and make your
first trade, Lightyear will
send you a $10 fractional share
of your choice.
But let me remind you,
investing always carries a risk
and the value of any
investment can decrease as well
as increase.
So be sure to invest wisely
and do your research.
Now let's get back to
this video about Iman.
Walking through the mall, I
had absolutely no idea where
we were going, but Iman
seemed to have a plan.
- Because you guys have
been traveling so much,
I thought I'd get you a little gift.
I'm just here to pick
up three large cabins.
I believe my assistant
should have called in.
I saw you guys traveling a lot
so I thought might as well.
My pleasure.
- Thank you very much.
- God, he has the largest
hands, I swear to God.
I feel, like, tiny.
Listen, you guys are gonna
have the best luggage
in the podcast game.
Whoever's bag I'm sitting on.
- [Interviewer] It's
like a trunky, isn't it?
- No, honestly I just roll around.
Just roll around the airport.
That's so fun.
You're paying half for the
suitcase, half of the seat.
- I've seen him giving away
expensive gifts many times
on social media, from
watches to cold hard cash.
But I was still taken aback
with his manners and generosity.
When he gifts you something,
he hits the spot every time.
It's unbelievable.
However, one thing we
can't overlook is how
much this helps to cultivate his wealthy
and kindhearted image on social media,
which is obviously great for business,
but are his intentions pure
or purely self-serving?
- I have a lot of cashflow
coming in and then I have a lot
of resale value and equity
in my software companies
and that just went crazy last year.
I just made an offer, actually.
I made an offer for $2.9 in cash
on a place in Chelsea,
but we'll see.
(hiphop music)
- Iman said we're off
to somewhere really hot.
So I went for a quick outfit
change, jumped in the car,
and off we went.
Without being rude, and
I hope this isn't rude,
obviously you have got an actual dad?
He's still alive somewhere, I assume?
- Yeah.
- Do you know him?
- Not personally, no.
He was alcoholic, abusive.
So my mom left him when she was pregnant.
'Cause then he wasn't
just affecting one person,
he was affecting two.
For me, it would be weirder the idea
of having a dad then not having a dad.
And what I always say is
it's like for the people
that have a father, sure they have a dad,
but it doesn't mean that
they're a good role model.
- By having a father,
some of the things he
taught me, I would say,
have held me back through my life.
My dad was very much, you shouldn't borrow
because that was taught from
the generations before him
from probably World War II
and all the various things that went on.
- It can be a massive advantage
or it could be a massive disadvantage.
If you have a father,
you might take on 20%,
you might take on 50%,
you might take on 80%
of their beliefs and if
their beliefs are wrong,
then that puts you in a
bit of a sticky situation.
So yeah, for me, of
course it's a disadvantage
growing up in a single parent household.
But you know-
- But you've found advantages within that?
- Every once in a while it can work.
- [Interviewer] What would you put down
your accelerated growth to?
- I think it's a lot of life circumstance.
I think a lot of it is genetics, as well.
Like just stuff that's natural, inbuilt.
I think there's a lot of people
in my situation who just no matter what,
would not have the same level
of stress tolerance and
also wouldn't keep pushing.
Becoming successful at whatever you do
is sure, it's difficult.
But I think staying in
that position is really
where legends are made and
that's really where, you know,
you earn your stripes and
you earn that respect.
So I think a lot of people can make it.
I don't know, a lot of people can stay
in that same position and keep
that same level of intensity.
What I achieved, you wouldn't want to,
because you're sacrificing so much.
Basically sacrificing your sanity.
- Iman says he's genetically gifted
with a higher stress tolerance than most,
but he is still young.
And I can't help
but be concerned about
the long-term effects
of living under these conditions.
In my youth, I thought
I was invincible, too.
And after working myself to the bone,
I had a serious health scare
that shocked me back to reality.
I wonder if Iman is heading
down a similar path.
- I'd never called myself British, though.
- No?
- Nah.
- So what'd you call yourself?
- Confused.
- Confused!
Before I knew it, we'd arrived
at our next destination:
The desert.
(intense upbeat music)
♪ You seem to know something I don't ♪
♪ What's going on, can you
tell me what it is, please ♪
♪ I'm not that slow, like you think ♪
♪ Strange vibrations in the
room and I can feel it ♪
- He already knows he's screwed.
- Got it.
I'll tell you what, it's
hurting my hip, actually.
I've gotta be honest.
It's a pretty wide animal.
I thought it was meant to
be a camel, not an elephant.
I'm slightly scared.
Here we go.
Oh!
Oh, that's high up.
Unbelievable.
Look at my eyelashes on my camel.
That's gotta be one of the
prettiest camels in existence.
♪ I'm a hurricane, I'm
bringing thunder and rain ♪
♪ I'm a hurricane if you get in my way ♪
Big downhill section coming up.
Cheese!
(upbeat music)
That's a ride, just getting off!
(pensive music)
Middle of the desert and
we got a classy restaurant.
You said that you didn't want to ever
become a billionaire because
of the responsibility
that goes with it and
the control from above.
- I don't wanna be
viewed as a billionaire.
- [Interviewer] That's a big difference.
- Let's say, for example,
in Middle Eastern families
like you put like the top
10 richest people on earth.
Combine them all times five.
They're still not as rich as the Qataris,
but you're not gonna find the Qataris
on the world's rich list, you know?
So like people don't know
where the real actual money is.
- Do you ever feel like you've lived three
or four lives already in your 23 years?
- Yeah, it doesn't feel like
my first life, that's for sure.
I'm a little jaded 'cause
I've experienced a lot.
(upbeat music)
- After an amazing couple of hours,
I began thinking this is
probably just a normal day
for Iman and if I did all
these things at his age,
what would there be to look forward to?
When I became a millionaire
in my early twenties,
I was very cautious of
letting my lifestyle
get outta control.
I know it sounds funny,
but I had this rule
that I would do something
that made my life
a bit better each year, but
Iman's already done it all.
So I was curious to see
how he approached this
potential issue.
You ever worry when you can
see all the experiences,
do all the experiences,
that you'll eventually have experienced
everything there is to experience?
- You find what you like
and what you don't like.
Like I couldn't care
less about certain things
that people find-
Like for example, I went on a safari.
Super nice, like a hundred
thousand dollars Safari.
Hated it.
- Really?
- Couldn't care less.
There's only so many times you
can watch a Lion Lick itself.
But I know for some
people that's like insane,
like life-changing.
Compare that and then I had one
night in Nepal where I slept
in a tent.
That was one of my best
memories so far this year.
Like sleeping in a tent.
Certain things you can't explain.
You know, there's just little quirks
and little things that
you just enjoy doing.
Like I just really like
for example, walking.
Rather than a hundred
thousand dollars safari,
I'd rather just walk
in Paris.
- Our day wasn't over yet.
What Iman showed me next
was utterly jaw dropping.
Before we open it,
what's the value on
that box I just lifted?
- I dunno, maybe 2?
- Yeah, let's clarify that.
That's 2 million.
- Yeah.
- Pounds?
- Pounds, yeah.
- Two and a half million dollars there.
Oh wow.
Look at that.
Every one's a masterpiece, isn't it?
- I've said publicly,
and I think some people flame me for it,
I said if you have 30,000
pounds in the bank,
why not spend 10 on a watch?
You know, for me it's like
they're easily liquid.
Buy and sell as you please,
and you're not really
gonna lose any money.
(upbeat music)
- That's marvelous, that.
I look at that and it's
an amazing collection.
- Thank you, bro.
- You should be really proud of all that.
So let's get down to it.
Does Iman have a superiority complex?
Yes, but this has allowed dream
big and achieve greatness.
If you don't think you
are destined for more
than the masses, how are
you ever gonna join the 1%?
He treated me to a lovely day
and gave me some thoughtful gifts.
But are his intentions pure?
After spending more time with him,
I think so.
After living a day in Iman's world,
I was concerned that he'll
have soon experienced all
of life's greatest luxuries.
But it's clear that this
isn't what Iman lives for.
He's more interested in the
simple pleasures of life.
There's lots of responsibility
on his shoulders,
which comes with a lot of stress.
Will it get the better of him?
I guess only time will tell.
- Gimme a hug.
Thank you bro.
- Thanks for everything.