A lot of people aren't
gonna like this one,
but making millions doesn't
have to take you decades
of hard work.
Sure, being a millionaire in
your fifties is all right,
but being a millionaire when
you're younger is far better.
Take it from someone
who's experienced both.
And no, I wasn't born into a rich family.
Quite the opposite.
The odds were stacked against me.
I was a ginger, working class kid
without a penny to his name.
So if I can build wealth
in a relatively short amount of time,
then you can too.
This isn't gonna be one
of those generic videos
about investing in index funds
and getting rich when you're old and gray.
I'm gonna be taking you
through the actual moments in my life
where I uncovered the truth
behind building wealth from nothing.
From the moment you step foot into school,
they try to control your ambition,
and one memory that stands out to me
was sitting in a lecture
theater just like this one.
The teacher asked us to
write down our dream job,
our dream car, and our dream house.
I was really excited.
So I wrote down business
owner, Ferrari, and mansion.
She then said, "Life is gonna be tough,
so I'm gonna break the
hard news to you now:
You're probably gonna
have none of those things,
so be realistic and
lower your expectations."
I thought to myself, "Of course I will.
I'll have all of those things."
And I've carried that attitude
for the whole of my life.
(dramatic music)
If you allow the system to
crush your hopes and dreams,
you'll never be able to
create wealth from nothing.
Look, this isn't some fluffy mindset BS.
If you can't even believe
something is possible,
then how on earth are you
gonna do the work required
to become wealthy?
Most people give into the
pressure of being realistic
and end up joining the crowd,
and then they discourage
the next generation
from following their hopes and dreams.
But you can decide to break
the cycle just like me
in that lecture theater.
So if you wanna do this,
then you firstly need to be very careful
about who you listen to.
I'm not just referring to those
fake gurus on social media.
I'm also talking about
the people in your life
who give their unsolicited advice.
While your friends and parents
may have good intentions,
if they haven't built
a large sum of wealth,
why would you listen to them
when it comes to making money?
Secondly, you need to learn
to think from multiple angles
when trying to solve problems.
Most people will come across an obstacle
that they've been told is
impossible for them to conquer
and give up at the first sign of trouble.
The more you let these kinds
of challenges beat you,
the harder it is to break out of the herd
as you are cemented to yourself
that you aren't good enough.
Whenever I come across a challenge,
I think of at least 10 different solutions
and then decide on the best way forward.
If one doesn't work, then
I just try the next one
and so on until I'm successful.
Thirdly, you need to step
outside your comfort zone.
Look, if Harry Potter stayed
in the cupboard under the stairs,
then he would never
have defeated Voldemort.
Sorry for the spoilers, but it's so true.
Putting yourself in challenging
situations helps you grow
and improve more than anything
else I've ever experienced.
When I first joined the workforce
as a carpenter's apprentice,
I was so excited.
It was the job I really wanted to do,
but unfortunately,
the manager took a bit of a dislike to me
and he bullied me practically every day,
give me all the rubbish jobs.
I didn't know what to do.
I couldn't take anymore.
I came home that night, sat on my couch,
and I looked around the room,
and thought to myself,
"What have I got to lose?"
I've got no child or wife to look after.
I'm 20 years old.
I've gotta make this decision.
Sure, I'm scared of quitting a job.
Of course, you're scared,
but I knew that was the best thing for me,
so I quit the very next day.
(upbeat music)
If you're young and have
few responsibilities,
it's a clear choice to take more risks
to increase your income.
Of course, I'm not
suggesting you should go
and invest all your money in crypto.
The risks should be calculated.
Looking back, I didn't
realize at the time,
but the biggest risk in my
life would've been staying
at that dead end job.
For me, increasing my income
meant starting my own business.
However, if this isn't for you,
you could always start a side hustle
or upgrade your job every couple of years.
Studies have actually found
that you're more likely
to build wealth faster
by job hopping rather than
staying loyal to one company.
However, if your goal is to
build wealth as fast as possible
and you decide to pick the employee route,
then you need to choose a
career that isn't dependent
on how many hours you work,
but on the results you achieve.
After lots of hard work
and many sleepless nights,
I managed to open my model shop.
It was a huge success.
I was reinvesting all of
my money in the business
to help it grow
that I didn't have time
to think about investing.
One day, I decided to take
on a work experience lad
for two weeks,
and on the first day, all
he kept banging on about
was stocks and shares,
and I thought, "What
does a 14 year old know
about stocks and shares?"
Anyway, he mentioned
this one particular stock
that he said was gonna go to the moon.
He said, "I've got a thousand pounds
and I'm gonna pile it all in
because I'm so confident."
I thought, "Well, if he's that confident,
I think I'll better have
a little go myself."
Two weeks later, I drove into the shop
and I had a chat with that young lad
and I said to him,
"Do you know how much
money you've made today?"
He said, "But Mark, I
don't make any money.
I'm on work experience.
I don't get paid."
I said, "Son, you've made 10,000 today
because that share we've bought into
has pretty much 10X overnight
and I didn't do too bad myself either."
If you want to build your wealth,
then you need to start
sooner rather than later.
The reality is, the longer
you wait to start investing,
the more difficult it's gonna be
because the more time you
allow for your money to grow,
the more money you'll eventually have.
I mean, check out this study by Fidelity,
which shows that if you miss
the five best trading days
over the past four decades,
you'd have reduced your
long-term gains by 38%.
Even worse, if you've
missed a 10 best days,
you'd have lost out by 55%.
So I'd strongly suggest
getting in the habit
of investing your money for the long-term
in the stock market.
But don't be as crazy as I
was when I first started.
Do your research
and invest in the stocks
you believe in long term.
So what should you look for
when deciding where to invest your money?
Well, firstly, when choosing
an investment platform,.
It's important to make sure it has smooth
and easy-to-use chart features.
You may think this isn't important,
but I can't stress enough
how many times I've
struggled with clunky apps
while trying to track the
growth of my investments.
Having a wide range of stocks
and ETFs to invest in is also
important for diversification
and reducing risk.
It allows you to spread your investments
across different sectors
and asset classes.
Another thing I'd suggest to
look for is paper trading.
This feature allows you
to experience the full investing process
using virtual money.
It's a great way to practice
and refine your knowledge,
as well as test out new strategies,
all without risking any actual money.
But if you do this,
it's important to treat
it like your real money.
Otherwise, you'll start
changing your strategies
when it comes to the real thing
and get completely different results.
Webull, a sponsor of today's video,
offer everything we've just
discussed and way more.
To get up to 12 free fractional shares,
each worth up to $3,000
by clicking the link in the description
and depositing any amount
of money with Webull US.
Just as quickly as I've made my fortune,
I could have lost it all.
I was friends with one of
the richest guys in the UK.
He was featured in the
Top 50 UK rich list,
which is pretty impressive.
And we used to go to his parties.
He used to have these great
firework parties at his mansion.
And one night I sat down
and had a coffee with him.
I said, "How do you
make this sort of money
just from a business?"
He said, "I don't make that
much money for my businesses.
I make money from
leveraging my investments."
And he said, "I'm part
of an investment group,
and that group earns 30 to 40
and sometimes even 50% per year."
You know, I sat there
and I thought to myself,
"This sounds too good to be true."
So there was no way I
was gonna get involved.
Around two to three months
later, that group went under.
It took everyone out.
Because they were leveraged,
they lost considerably more
than they'd actually got invested.
This isn't even his house.
He lost it all.
(dramatic music)
Never invest in something
you don't understand.
And even if you do believe
what you're investing in,
don't put all your eggs in one basket.
When you spread your investments out,
we call this diversification.
This is something I
highly recommend you do
because it reduces your risk exposure.
When it comes to my
stock market investments,
I primarily focus on a strategy
called the three-fund portfolio.
This portfolio consists
of three main components:
a total US stock market index fund,
a total international stock index fund,
and a total bond market fund.
These funds allow for diversification
across different markets
and asset classes,
reducing risk while still
providing the potential
for long-term growth.
In addition to my stock
market investments,
I've also diversified my portfolio
by investing in other
assets such as real estate,
classic cars, and high-end time pieces.
This approach allows me
to spread my investments
across various industries and asset types,
further mitigating risk
and increasing the
potential for good returns.
It's key to remember the
importance of diversification,
not only in investments,
but also in making money.
This is otherwise known
as having multiple streams of income.
My income sources include
my physical shops,
my distribution company, affiliate income,
advertising revenue, stock dividends,
and rental income from
my various properties.
I'm probably missing out a couple,
but hopefully this gives you some ideas.
So remember, when you
are building your empire,
constantly be thinking about
how you can build
different streams of income
so that you can't be completely wiped out
by one wrong decision, like my friend.
If you wanna know seven
side hustles to avoid,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there.
Don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if you
wanna grow your wealth, okay?
I'll see you over there.