I travelled on private
jets, drove a supercar,
and was surrounded by
the best looking women
when I was becoming a multimillionaire.
Sorry to break it to you
but that statement is a complete lie.
The trouble is a lot of
people that want to get rich
are trying to live a lifestyle like this.
Why?
Because many would rather look
rich than actually be rich.
So if you are someone that just wants
to show off a flashy lifestyle,
then this video isn't for you.
Turn it off and go and
spend the next 30 year
spending everything you have
until you get to 50 years old
and have nothing to show for it.
Don't get me wrong.
I did experience all
the things I mentioned,
however, not until I had
at least a million dollars
in liquid assets.
So when I say you have little to no chance
of becoming a millionaire,
at the same time as
living a lavish lifestyle,
I'm not trying to crush your
dreams, quite the opposite.
I want you to do all the hard work now
so you can enjoy all the
benefits of wealth later on.
The biggest being the freedom
to do whatever you want
whenever you want.
So if you wanna become
rich, then listen up,
because if I was in your position
I'd avoid buying these seven things.
Number one, a house.
A lot of people aren't
gonna agree with this one.
But buying a house for yourself
if you're serious about
getting extremely rich
is one of the worst moves you can make.
I didn't always think this way,
but in recent years I've changed my mind
mostly due to a conversation
with my son, Curtis.
One day he revealed to me that
he'd saved up around $70,000
from working a couple of years
as a freelance videographer
and I suggested he used it
as a deposit on a house and
start paying off a mortgage.
Now, before I continue,
I still stand by this advice
if you're just looking
for a slightly better than
average level of wealth,
but now it doesn't apply
to those that wanna become truly rich.
Curtis was, and still
is, very against the idea
of buying a house for himself.
At the time he said to me,
"It's taken me years
to save up this money.
Why would I lock it up in a house
rather than reinvest it
into building my business
which has already made me
a decent amount of money."
I took a moment to think
and I realized he was completely right.
Buying a house for himself would lock up
all the money he'd worked so hard to earn
meaning he couldn't
leverage it to make more
and he'd have to start
from ground zero again.
Let me clear something up though.
I'm only talking
about buying a personal
property to live in,
buying a rental property or house hacking
by renting out part of the property.
It's a completely different
thing and pretty smart.
If you aren't doing any of these things,
then renting is actually a better idea.
Most people find this hard to
get their heads around that.
They just see it as
money wasted every month.
But the return Curtis could
be getting on a deposit money
that would've been locked
away is far more valuable.
I know this is the complete opposite
from what a lot of older
people will tell you.
However, what most don't
consider is backing our day
it was much easier to buy a property
as it required far less money down.
Getting a mortgage is kind of
like a locked savings account
so it's only a good idea for people
that are just gonna waste the money
or leave it sitting in a
bank account doing nothing.
Luckily, Curtis reinvested the
money back into his business
Tilbury Multimedia Limited
which currently generates about
a million dollars each year.
So if you wanna be rich,
then you have to find a
better investment vehicle
than a house to live in.
Number two, the latest tech.
Nobody really cares
if you've got the latest
iPhone or Apple Watch.
Too many people upgrade
to the latest tech items
just because it looks cool
or they think it makes them happier.
I waited so long to
upgrade from my iPhone 3G
that the apps actually stopped working.
I could normally deal with
this without too many issues
but I was doing a lot of
sales on eBay at the time
and I needed to use the app
so there was a value to
upgrade into a new model.
However, instead of going out
and buying the latest model,
I decided to buy an iPhone 4
which is when my son had
the latest iPhone 6S.
He used to laugh at me
using my older phone
but it did everything I needed it to do
and a newer model would've
made me any happier
as I just see it as a business tool.
The truth is, while owning a useful device
like an iPhone or an Apple
Watch can be beneficial,
upgrading to the newest version
for the sake of having
the latest technology
is not a wise financial decision
if you're aiming to become truly rich.
Instead, focus on purchasing items
that can have a much
bigger impact on your life
and avoid being drawn in
by the marketing hype.
Number three, investments
you don't understand.
Let's face it, too many people
got into investing during the pandemic
without really knowing
what they were doing.
They simply put their money into stocks
and hoped the value would increase,
which is a terrible idea.
As Tai Lopez would put it it's all about.
- Knowledge.
- Knowledge of stocks,
the market, wall Street,
and the trading tools that you are using.
That's why Moomoo is sponsoring
this section of the video
as in my opinion, Moomoo is
not just a trading platform
for buying and selling stocks,
but a tool that truly focuses
on helping investors
have a better experience,
especially beginners.
It was founded in Silicon Valley
and has over 20 million users worldwide
allowing them to trade stocks
straight from an their
iPad, laptop, or smartphone.
I love that It provides me
with free vital information
about a company such as how a
Company performed in the past,
what it's projected to do in the future
and how Wall Street analysts rate it.
You can also find more than
2,500 free investment courses
ranging from beginner to advanced levels.
If you join Moomoo today using
a link in the description,
you can receive up to 15 free stocks
each worth between 3 and $2,000.
That's an amazing deal.
These free stocks can help you start
building your investment
portfolio right away.
Number four, gifts for a partner.
I'm not saying don't
buy your partner gifts.
I'm actually going one step further.
I don't think you should
have a partner at all
when you're laying the building
blocks for your empire.
When I was in my teens and early 20s
I had a four week rule.
If I knew a girl I met
wasn't gonna be the one,
then a maximum I would
allow was four weeks.
I thought it was kind to allow them
to move on as it meant
I didn't have to buy
any expensive presents.
As you aren't really socially
expected to buy any gifts
if you've only been seeing
someone for a couple of weeks.
According to the National
Retail Federation
the average person will spend
around $103 on Valentine's
Day gifts per year.
Now, I know that doesn't
seem like a huge deal
but that's just one occasion.
You'll need to budget about $100 minimum
for birthdays, Christmas,
and anniversaries as well.
Let's throw in the extra
$15 a month for flowers
and you are looking at an
extra $180 that's over $580
and we haven't even started
on those little surprises
throughout the year or times
that call for bigger presents.
We've all been there.
I don't wanna come across as being cheap,
but the only person I
wanted to spend any money on
was my future wife.
I knew that would be an investment
but anything else was just a waste.
When I was building my wealth,
I wasn't looking for anything long-term
because I knew I wasn't
the man I wanted to be yet.
So if you wanna become rich,
I suggest staying single
and focusing on building your empire.
You'll have more time and
money to invest in yourself
and your future, and who knows,
maybe you'll find someone who
shares your financial goals
and ambitions along the way.
Number five, a new car.
Purchasing a new vehicle is in fact
one of the very worst financial
decisions someone can make
and the silent wealth
killer nobody talks about.
Let's do the maths.
For a mid-size vehicle worth $25,000.
If you don't have enough
money to buy outright,
you may opt to get a loan instead.
Assuming you have a good credit score
and obtain a 3.5% interest
rate with a $3,000 down payment
and a 1,000 pound trade-in of your old car
you'll be paying $382.02
a month for 60 months.
However, you'll also have to consider
the depreciation of the vehicle.
A new car loses around 22% of its value
in the first year and
around 55% over five years.
This means that halfway through your loan,
you'll effectively be flushing $400
down the toilet every month
for the next two and a half years
as you'll never get that money back.
So what's the solution?
Well, believe it or not, I
didn't buy my first brand new car
till I was about 35 years old.
Before that, I bought cars
that were around five years old
such as Ford Escorts, Peugeot
206s, and Ford Focuses.
As I knew they had experienced
the majority of their depreciation
and they were well under half price.
None of the cars I purchased
lost more than 15% in value
meaning the person who bought
the car when it was new
took the biggest hit.
The only reason I bought
a new car when I was 35
was for my wife who needed
to do a lot of mileage
and I prioritized her safety
over the loss in value.
So if you want to be rich
then you need to be smarter
in purchasing a vehicle.
You don't want it eaten
away at your wealth
month after month.
Number six, impulse items.
You'll never become the
person you want to be
if you can't control impulse purchases.
Let's attack them one by one.
Firstly, stuff that's on sale.
It's important to see
past so-called sales.
Often the sale price of a product
is not actually a real discount.
And the retailer has simply increased it
above the recommended retail price
for a week or so in one location.
Alternatively, it may
be a low quality item
that no one wants.
Secondly, my age old
nemesis, designer clothes.
I have nothing against
buying quality clothes.
In fact, I think it's a good idea
because they'll look better
and they'll last longer.
What I don't like a designer clothes
that only justify their
expensive price tag
due to the hype around the label.
People only buy these brands
for one reason: to impress others.
Thirdly, we have to talk about
entertainment subscriptions.
It used to be fine when
we only had Netflix
but now there seems to be so
many other streaming platforms.
I only sign up for one at a time.
I don't have enough free time
to watch everything anyway
so I just watch everything I want
on each platform during
a three month window
then cancel, jump to a new one.
Fourthly, the scam that
is extended warranties.
For example two years is a
pretty reasonable lifespan
for an iPhone.
So in reality, when you
buy an extended warranty,
you are just paying really
for one extra year of coverage
and by the time you get to that last year
you may have lost details
of your warranty or even sold the item.
These impulse purchases
might not seem like much in the moment,
but when you add them all up,
you realize how much they're costing you.
Number seven, alcohol.
The most important thing
you can do right now
to gain an advantage over
everyone else is to stop drinking.
I haven't really been properly drunk
since a big family gathering
when I was about 19 years old.
They kept buying me drinks
and I just found it so hard to say no.
The drinks just kept coming,
and I ended up very ill.
I couldn't work the next day
and sat in bed thinking
about the night before.
It struck me why would you drink alcohol
when it makes you feel so bad?
Furthermore, why would you drink
when you're at the height of your powers
such a young person?
This thinking has actually been backed up
by a study from the University of Sussex.
857 participants took part
in the Dry January campaign
and abstained from alcohol
for the entire month.
The study found that 71%
of the participants
reported sleeping better.
67% had more energy.
And 58% experienced weight loss.
All of these things are very important
for success when you're younger
so why slow down your brain by drinking?
If you'd like to know how you can retire
before everyone else, then
you can watch this next video
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you wanna grow your wealth.
Okay, see you over there.