- As soon as I left school,
I started my first business,
which made me a multimillionaire
and gave me the life
I'd always dreamed of.
This statement isn't just false.
It's pretty much impossible.
The trouble is many people that
want to get rich are buying
into this narrative as it's
so widespread on the internet.
Why? Because it sounds so
much easier than the reality.
If you wanna get rich but don't
wanna put in the hard work,
then I'd recommend buying a lottery ticket
and crossing your fingers
as it'll probably be more effective.
Don't get me wrong,
I did make my millions from
starting successful businesses.
However,
I didn't just jump straight
into a business idea
after watching a "Top
10 side hustle video."
So when I say you have little to no chance
of starting a successful
business straight out of school,
I'm not trying to crush your
dreams, quite the opposite.
I want you to save your valuable time
and start building the
skillsets you need to succeed.
So if you wanna become rich,
then listen up because if
I was in your position,
I'd follow these six steps.
Step one, find your natural talents.
I hate the saying, "Follow your passion."
What if your passion
doesn't have the ability
to make you money?
Or even worse, you just don't have one?
It feels like one of those
overuse self-help sayings
that doesn't actually have
any real substance around it.
Maybe people are drawn to advice like this
as the general population
seem obsessed with the idea
of living a good,
balanced, and happy life.
This, of course, is an admirable goal.
However,
a starving artist struggles to make money
and they rarely have any of these things.
My passion was to become
an RAF fighter pilot,
but as soon as I found
out I needed glasses,
that dream went out the window.
I could've continued down that path
and wasted valuable time.
However,
I decided to park that
passion for later in life
when I had enough money to
complete my pilot's license
and fly planes for fun.
I made this choice as to be truly happy,
I believe you first need
to fix the money issue
as never having enough
can lead to so many more
problems down the road.
I can tell you this,
the journey to making substantial
money isn't an easy one
otherwise everyone will be doing it.
You just have to be very honest
about what you're actually good at.
Ray Dalio, owner of the
world's largest hedge fund,
Bridgewater Capital, says that
you have to "Find your game,"
and I couldn't agree more.
I remember trying my hand at
a lot of different things,
such as door-to-door fish sales,
being a shop assistant, flipping cars,
and teaching people how to
fly radio control helicopters.
From this,
I identified I had
natural talent for dealing
with people due to my
strong social skills.
From then on,
I really leaned into anything that relied
on me speaking face-to-face with customers
as I knew I could make sales
that others could only dream of.
Have a think about the
things that you're good at.
And if there's a few common
skills that connect them all,
those are your money-makers.
At this stage,
you should only be
focusing on these skills
because it's much easier to get ahead
improving on those rather
than starting from scratch
with something completely new.
You can use these natural
skills to fix your money issues
and then from there start
improving in other areas.
Step two, dedicate everything to a job.
I know it's become very trendy
to wanna escape the matrix.
It's even got to the point
where people are quietly
quitting their jobs.
This means they're doing the bare minimum,
keeping all their energy
for their side hustles.
Although I understand
the thinking behind this,
doing the bare minimum is something
that should never be celebrated.
That is the type of mindset
that ensures you'll never be successful
because the way you do the small things
is the way you'll do the big things.
When I was working as a carpenter,
I'd have days I just hated,
but I knew a sour attitude
wouldn't get me anywhere.
Even a job like this can
give you the opportunity
to practice important skills.
I learned woodwork,
technical design, quoting,
and customer service.
I always believed in the phrase
"Work to learn, not to earn."
(money cha-chings)
When I worked in a factory,
I would always ask questions
and try to figure out how it all worked.
This later came in very handy
when I was traveling the world
looking for the perfect
place to manufacture
my own products as I knew
what I was looking for.
My experience as an assistant
in a radio control model shop
helped me learn sales, communication,
and organizational skills
that I'd like to train
to my employees in my own shops.
In your current job,
try to understand why
things are the way they are
without trying to argue
or question your boss.
By looking just a little bit deeper,
you can find there's a reason why
pretty much everything is the way it is.
If it's good, keep note of it.
If it's bad, also keep note of it.
I'll explain why later.
Step three, nurture your
contacts and your image.
These two really go hand-in-hand
because if you don't have a good image,
then the people you want to connect with
won't wanna be your friends.
It's harsh but true.
We often make a quick assumption
about a person right or wrong
after meeting them just once.
Nowadays, due to social media,
you don't even have to meet someone
to have an opinion on them.
So how you present yourself in-person
and online is very important.
I mean, think about some
of your favorite YouTubers.
They all have something
that makes them stand out.
For me, it's me old age
and of course my wisdom.
Take your strengths from step one,
and try to find a way to show them off
when you meet a new person,
and leave an imprint in their mind.
After failing to qualify
for the Helicopter World
Championships in Austria in 1993
and being absolutely devastated,
I devised a plan to make
sure that I made an impact.
I noticed a loophole
that would allow me to
attend as the team coach.
Once I secured my place,
I loaded my model helicopter
with a secret weapon.
And after the final
competition, I executed my plan.
I flew the first ever model
helicopter firework display.
Everyone was in awe.
The helicopter flipped,
and soared through the sky,
followed by a glitter in trail
of sparks and explosions.
I was featured in many newspapers
and TV shows,
(audience applauding)
leading to me making a bigger impact
than any of the competition winners.
I was even asked to sign
multiple autographs.
That was before selfies were even a thing.
Two years later,
I qualify for the World
Championships in Japan.
And everyone already knew my name
from that breathtaking in night.
So you've gotta be straight with yourself.
The world out there is too
hard for you to be soft.
I think a better way of being
great is to go out there
and practice the things
that will make you great.
Rather than telling yourself
over and over in the mirror "I'm great,"
I'd say having proof is much better.
You don't have to be great at everything,
but the reason most men
are so invisible nowadays
is that they're too afraid to take risk
for fear of standing out.
And in this era of distraction,
social media, and quiet-quitting,
it's easier than ever to
stand out by excelling,
but it's also important not
to be too self-absorbed.
Most people are more
interested in themselves
than other people.
Becoming genuinely interested in others
can take you a long way in
business and friendships,
even though it may seem
like a waste of time.
Step four, identify improvements
and write them down.
Remember how I said to write
down the stuff that was good
and not so good about whatever
business you're working in?
Well, here's the thing.
A lot of people who go into business do so
because the last boss they
work for was a complete idiot.
At least that's kind
of what happened to me.
Businesses are all about solving problems,
but the funny thing is businesses
have tons of their own problems.
Whenever an issue comes up
and your boss has to
hire some outside help,
keep a note of what the problem
was and how it was solved.
I saw all the problems
in the radio control model
shop I was working in,
such as not meeting customer
demand with certain products,
a poor location, and inexperienced staff.
I later used this
information to start a chain
of model shops that absolutely
dominated the market.
This is the same idea
behind hiring a mentor
or paying for consultants.
However,
this way you are actually getting paid
while gaining the knowledge.
Step five, test your
fixes with a side hustle.
Starting a business is scary.
It often means taking risk,
and putting in lots of time,
and money up front without
any guaranteed returns.
That's why it's so important
to start with a side hustle.
Before starting my own range
of radio control models,
I made sure to stock
everything in my shops
to get a real handle on
what actually sold and why.
One of my friends actually
went one step further.
He wanted to start an e-commerce store,
but couldn't afford to take any risks
as he had very limited money.
His biggest fear was
being left with inventory
that he just couldn't sell.
Then he had a brilliant idea.
What if he tried to sell
a product he didn't have?
He first tested this out
with resistance training bands from China.
But instead of buying them
and having them shipped over,
he just listed them for sale.
When the orders came in,
(messages dinging)
it gave him proof that
the product was sellable.
So he refunded all the orders
and decided to buy the product
after he knew he could sell it.
He was able to test so many
products using this approach.
One of the most important parts
of the testing process is measurement.
What gets measured gets managed.
That's the reason why elite athletes
always measure their stats.
There's this idea now
in startups called the
minimal viable product or MVP.
The term was coined by the
CEO of a gaming business.
Basically, they had the
rough idea for the game,
but left the details on
the path of development
largely up to the feedback of the users.
What was once a very scrappy
and buggy game ended up
becoming pretty amazing
by just listening to the feedback
and making constant improvements.
Testing your idea could be as
simple as just asking users
what they think of it in
a Discord or a subreddit.
It's worth remembering, though,
the opinions of those that matter most
are the ones that buy your product.
And you won't know who those people are
until you start selling on a small scale.
Often you'll find that 80% of your results
are due to 20% of your side hustle.
This rule applies to many more things,
such as 80% of traffic accidents
are caused by 20% of drivers,
80% of wealth is controlled
by 20% of the population,
80% of a company's productivity
is due to 20% of its employees,
and there are many more examples.
Step six, launch your business.
Now, before you start saying,
"I clickbaited you with
the title," hear me out.
If you have followed all the steps
I've talked about in this video so far,
then your chances of succeeding
as an entrepreneur are
dramatically improved.
I see way too many people
starting a business
with absolutely zero
skills that set them apart,
which means they're just going to fail
and become disheartened.
It's undeniable that the
biggest billionaires out there
didn't get that way by
just having a side hustle.
They did it by delivering value
to a huge number of
people through a business.
So when you're analyzing the
results of your side hustle,
try to see if you can identify
the best parts of what
you're doing, the top 20%.
Then ask yourself
how can you do more of
it on a larger scale
and reach more people?
If you'd like to be inspired
with some side hustle ideas,
then you can watch this next video here,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if you
wanna grow your wealth, okay?
(tongue clicks) I'll see you over there.