People are making thousands of dollars
in passive income every month
selling videos edited with the help of AI.
- Here is how you can
make $150 in 15 minutes.
- [Speaker] Here is how this channel
makes over $36,000 a month.
- This is how you make $10,000 a month.
- [Speaker] We're using AI in secs.
- This is true AI video editing.
- Can you believe this?
- But is this actually possible?
And how much work does it require?
Well, I'm gonna put
this to the test myself.
I'm making and selling my
own promotional videos,
and I reckon I'm the perfect candidate
as I've never edited a
video in my entire life.
I'm setting myself three
rules for this challenge.
Rule one, I must sell under a fake name.
Rule number two, I have to do
everything from my computer.
And rule three, the
videos I create and sell
should be easy to do for
beginners with the help of AI.
So, no complex editing
software is allowed.
The first thing on my list
is crucial, market research.
Looking at Fiverr, I can immediately see
there's a lot of competition
in the promotional video space.
A lot of people would
see this as a bad sign
and give up before even starting,
but I actually, see
this as a positive thing
as many of these sellers
have lots of reviews,
which means they're clearly making sales.
Something that really stands out to me
is the huge gap in prices.
Some sellers are pricing
their videos at $10.
while others are pricing theirs at $2,500
for a single promotional video.
I'd like to think I can do better
than the lower level sellers.
So, I'm gonna start
selling my videos for $50.
As a beginner starting
out, I need to create
some sort of promotional
video that I can attach
to my advertisement on
websites like Fiverr
to showcase what I can do.
So, let's sign into Invideo
and start editing something together.
This seems like the easiest
tool to use for beginners,
and it's completely online.
So, all I need is my laptop.
This platform has thousands
of video templates
and millions of royalty-free video clips.
First things first, I need a template
as I'm a long way from expert status
and I can't really start
projects from scratch just yet.
So, I'm gonna click Templates here
and find something suitable.
Now, this looks pretty good,
so, let's use this one.
The template's great, but
the text is all wrong.
So, let's work on getting that changed.
Now, that is looking a little bit better.
I'm gonna click on Videos
and search social media,
which has brought up loads
of suitable stock footage
that I can play around with
and insert into my template.
Now, it's just a case of chopping
and changing a few things around,
but obviously, ensuring
that the footage I'm using
makes sense to potential customers.
Here's a quick look at the final product.
(upbeat music)
I think for my first try,
that was, that's all right wasn't it?
Now, is where the fun really starts.
It's time to set up a seller's account.
So, there are many different ways
we can advertise our services,
such as using third party
platforms like Fiverr and Upwork,
or by creating social
media pages and websites.
In my opinion, building your own website
and social media pages
is the best way to go.
As you can build your
brand and reputation.
Have returning customers
and most importantly,
retain customer data,
such as email addresses and phone numbers.
With that said, we need
to gain experience first,
and it's much quicker and cheaper
to go where the customers are.
So, I'm gonna create a listing on Fiverr.
I wanna make this very clear.
We're not being sponsored by Fiverr,
but we probably should be.
We've mentioned them enough.
So, as I already have a Fiverr account,
I'm gonna log in and
from the dropdown menu,
I'm gonna select Seller.
And let's pick the video editing category.
For the title, I'm just gonna steal one
that's working well for a seller
that's currently on the platform,
because if it's not broken, why fix it?
Let's go with, I will create
a commercial sales video,
promotional marketing video ad,
like that makes complete
grammatical sense,
but who am I to judge if it works?
Now, I'm gonna add some metadata
as having the right
tags is very important,
if we want people to find us.
Video editing, video postproduction
and corporate video editing,
should do the trick.
Now, for setting the price.
Let's go with $49 as it's
a bit on the lower end,
but it also leaves room
for a bit of profit.
Right, I'll upload that video
we just created together
to hopefully, draw some
eyeballs to our gig
and also get ChatGPT to
write us a nice description
to add to the listing.
AI is just so useful
for this kind of thing.
We need to stand out so I'm gonna set
a one-day delivery time
and allow my customers to
make unlimited revisions.
Now, let's see if we can make some sales.
Well, it's been a couple of days now
since we published our gig
and we've had no bites.
Not even a single inquiry.
This leaves me with two options.
Option one, quit.
Option two, get creative.
You guys know me?
Of course, I'm getting creative.
So, here's the plan.
I've noticed that all
the people making sales
have five star reviews,
and as I'm a new seller,
potential customers don't trust me.
So, I've got someone
to agree to buy my gig
so I can make a
promotional video for them.
Before you comment saying I'm a faker
and unsubscribe, listen up,
because this is actually
a very common strategy,
especially on platforms like these.
This will help boost my
gig in the algorithm.
Hopefully, leading to me
getting some real sales.
The first video I'm
gonna make is for Chris
who runs a business
called Discord Builders.
He's been my community manager
now for a couple of years.
On that note, if you didn't know already,
I have a Discord and it's free to join.
I'll leave the link below.
The first thing I need
to do is find a template.
So, I'm gonna go up here and
search website development.
I know it's technically not the right one,
but I think this will
bring up the templates
that look tech based.
I'm gonna go with the easy
website makers template
as I think it fits the theme well.
Now, for some AI magic.
I'm gonna go to ChatGPT and
type in the following prompt.
Create a concise promo script
for a Discord community building service.
They specialize in crafting
and managing online communities
for people seeking
connection and engagement.
The script should be
brief, under 30 seconds,
with short and engaging sentences,
simple language, and a witty tone.
The video will rely on text,
music, and video clips.
No spoken dialogue is needed.
Begin with a compelling problem statement
and conclude with a strong call to action
to explore the discord
building services available.
You know what they say
about enough monkeys?
Well, I've just written the
works of Shakespeare there.
I'll leave this prompt
in the description below.
So, all you have to do is
adapt the language slightly,
if you want to use it.
Now, let's jump back onto Invideo
and replace all the placeholder text
with what ChatGPT has given us.
We might need to adjust the font size,
color, and text animations,
but that's pretty simple stuff.
Now, that's looking nice.
Now, we have to replace the media.
Luckily, Chris has given
me some assets to use
so I can start dragging
and dropping those into the timeline.
The last step is often
overlooked by a lot of people,
and it's replacing the placeholder logo.
It's so important you
don't forget to do this.
Hopefully, your customer
provided their logo.
If they don't have one,
then you can always use a free AI tool
like the Wix Logo Maker.
Here's a sneak peek at
the finished version.
(upbeat music)
Let's raise our price from $49 to $99,
and hopefully, get our
first real paying customer.
So, it's been a few days
since I upped my prices
and I've got some great news.
We've made some sales.
Well, it's only one sale,
but I'm excited nevertheless.
Okay, this is interesting
and definitely not what I was expecting.
It's a promotional video for
a caravan and static home park
that wants to showcase their facilities
to potential customers
and increase conversion.
What I like about this job is not only
can I use stock footage
and templates on Invideo,
but the client has actually sent me
some of their own footage,
including drone shots.
This should allow me to
create something really cool.
I'm gonna use the same
step-by-step process
I did before for the
Discord builder promo video.
So, let's fast forward this part,
(reel screeching)
and I've gotta say, I'm pretty happy.
I might even have to add
pro video editor to my Instagram bio,
but you know what?
It isn't down to whether I like it or not.
Let's see what the customer thinks.
So, it's a couple of days later
and I was a little bit concerned,
'cause I hadn't heard back from them,
but they got in contact.
They said they were just a bit busy,
and they've said they
really love the video.
So, now we know we're not
gonna have any refunds.
Let's add up how much profit we made.
The two promo videos I created
brought in a total revenue of $148,
but there were some costs I had to absorb.
Firstly, Fiverr charge a flat
20% commission on all sales.
Secondly, I had to sign up
for Invideo's business
subscription for $25,
which gave me all the tools and footage
needed to create the videos.
They do offer an unlimited plan
for larger businesses and agencies,
but for most people, I
think the business package
is more than suitable.
If you wanna have a go at this,
it will be slightly less expensive
as I've managed to get you 25% off,
if you use the code MT25 and
the link in the description.
With subscriptions deducted,
that brings us to a grand total of $93.20.
This isn't bad at all, judging by the fact
that before this I had zero
experience editing videos
and if I kept this going,
I reckon I could really scale it up.
If you wanna see how much passive income
I made selling blank books on Amazon,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you wanna grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.