- This is Jack.
He slaves away 40 hours
a week at a job he hates,
has no savings and to feel
better at the end of every week,
he goes out and parties.
In his free time, his scrolls
social media and swipes Tinder
chasing the next hit of easy dopamine.
This is Chad.
He has his own business and
reinvests all of his profits
into building his dream life.
During his free time,
he builds connections and hits the gym.
Instead of chasing women,
he lets them chase him.
Ask yourself and be
honest, which one are you?
For most people, it'll be
somewhere between the two.
So if you wanna become
more like Chad, listen up.
I'm a multimillionaire businessman
and today I'm gonna share
the full six Step guide
that you can use to get ahead
of most people this year.
Most people won't even
reach the end of this video,
let alone take action.
So if you manage to actually
listen to all these points
you'll be at a huge advantage.
Step one, become insanely competitive.
I don't buy into the saying,
it's the taking part that matters,
our education system is mostly
to blame for this thinking
as it's failed to prepare today's youth
for the realities of the world.
The only reason to take part
should be to ultimately win.
Just think about it,
if you got a friend to
do your maths homework
because he was top of the class,
you'd be punished for cheating.
But in life, if you got a numbers guy
to help you in your business,
that's called hiring
in a financial officer,
and that's applauded.
So the education system
has got things backwards
but not only that,
social media is making
the problem even worse.
Instagram is allowing
everyday people to see
into their lives of the 1%.
What was once a very simple path
has now become extremely complicated.
Back in my day, it was all about
leaving school to get a job
which would allow me to buy a car
helping me to attract a woman,
and after that of course, buying a house
and finally starting a family.
Now I veered off the path quite a lot
as I chose to quit my
job and start a business,
but that was much rarer in my day.
Nowadays, if a man isn't successful
then he's pretty much invisible.
I mean 20% of the people on
Tinder get 80% of the matches.
This is also leading to rapidly shrinking
motherhood in the West,
with women twice as likely
to not have kids in their forties
compared to the generation before.
The popularity of people
like Jordan Peterson
Hamza and Tate, fervor proved this point
as they're just saying what
a lot of people are thinking.
I know I've gone on a bit of a rant here
but the world is honestly
harder than ever.
If you are serious about
getting ahead of everyone else
then you are gonna have
to get good at playing
the game of life on this harder level.
Step two, become hyper obsessive.
Another phrase I absolutely
hate is work life balance.
There can be no work life
balance when you wanna get ahead,
people are hungrier than ever,
and you need to be
obsessed over your goals.
There's always going
to be someone out there
who's willing to outwork you.
I think the idea of balance
is more often than not
an excuse for people to take it easy.
You need to want to achieve
more than you want to breathe.
This mentality comes from sport
and I see business as the
best sport on the planet
as you just keep getting better with age.
I wouldn't let myself
forget where I was heading
when I built my million dollar businesses.
I even said to my girlfriend,
who's now the wife,
that she needs to accept
that I'm selfish with my work
and it will always come first.
Now I'm able to relax this
rule a little bit more.
However, I set the expectation
as I knew I couldn't be
distracted by a partner
that wasn't fully
supportive of my mission.
It may sound silly,
but one thing that did keep
me on track was writing down
everything I wanted to
change on sticky notes.
I then stuck them to my mirror
so that I'd see them every morning.
This kept me accountable.
I had to wake up and face
the reality of my situation
and ask myself why I wasn't moving faster
towards these targets.
Step three, become a producer.
The truth is, for the world to
go round, we need consumers.
People need to watch
mindless entertainment,
buy products and fall into bad debt
so that 1% can reap the rewards.
I know it sounds obvious,
but if you created something
and there was no one to buy it
then you couldn't become rich.
It's so easy for us all
to fall into consumer mode
as it's baked into our DNA.
We just wanna relax, watch TV
and buy the latest products.
Some people think you should cut
all of the consumer
habits out of your life
but to be honest with you,
I find a whole monk mode movement
a bit unrealistic and cringey.
Monk mode consists of basic rules such as
at least 10 minutes of daily meditation,
no drugs or alcohol
and at least 30 minutes of daily exercise.
Honestly, I've never put
rules like this on myself.
It would've just sucked
all the joy out of life.
However, I do agree with the principle.
I like to think of it as a sliding scale
with producer on one end
and consumer on the other.
I've always aimed to slide
my scale more towards
the producer end of the spectrum.
When I was younger, I gave up the things
I wasn't too worried about,
such as parties with people
I wasn't that close to.
Instead, I'd use that time to
work on my product designs.
Even if you're able to push your scale
just a little bit
towards the producer end,
then you will get ahead of most people
as they aren't even aware
they go through life
fully on consumer mode.
Step four, become better
at asking questions.
Lots of videos like this
will say find a mentor.
However, they're very vague
about how to actually do that.
The secret lies in the questions you ask.
When I was a kid, I loved model airplanes.
I didn't stop asking my dad about them,
so he took me to a model flying club.
The members of the club
loved my enthusiasm
and one of them, a successful
businessman called David,
took me under his wing.
He would give me tips and tricks
to make my models fly even better.
I'd implement them and
then he'd give me even more
the following week.
As I got older his advice slowly
shifted into business tips,
and i applied the same principles
of listening and taking action.
Right, there's something I wanna clear up.
There is such a thing as a bad question.
Anyone that says otherwise is mistaken.
Take this question for example,
can I ask you for some advice?
My Instagram messages are
fuller questions like this
and they never get a reply.
Here's why.
When you are messaging
an extremely busy person
the last thing you want to do
is create more work for them.
If I was to reply to all those messages
then I'll start hundreds
of new conversations.
I'll then have to follow
up after they've replied
with their actual question.
So I've made a rule to
only answer the people
that ask clear and concise questions.
I suspect a lot of other successful people
have similar rules, so the
quality of the questions you ask
will determine whether
or not they help you.
On top of this, if you
ask someone for advice
and then don't take action,
the next time you need advice
they aren't gonna waste their time.
However, be careful as
there's a lot of fake mentors
and gurus out there, so
you need to be very careful
who you take advice from.
Not everyone has your
best interests at heart.
Just remember, a fake mentor
doesn't have experience
in doing what they teach, a real one does.
Step five, become immune to net worth.
Look, I'm just gonna say it,
net worth means nothing.
Bear with me on this one.
In my opinion, getting
ahead of everyone else
isn't just to do with how rich you are.
It's about the skills, the knowledge
and the confidence you acquire
while you are building your empire.
Someone could have bought Shiba Inu
in the last crypto ball run
and cashed out billions.
This doesn't mean they
know anything useful
and how to actually
replicate that success.
The exact same goes for lottery winners.
They often lose all the
money they won very rapidly,
as they became rich because of a shortcut,
not the skills that they developed.
Some industries are much
tougher than others,
so in many cases, an
entrepreneur worth of $10 million
might actually be a better businessman
than a Silicon Valley tech entrepreneur
worth 100 million.
This is why you really
shouldn't be measuring yourself
based on net worth.
I understand why people do it.
It's an easy way to compare success.
However, there is much more to
be in ahead of everyone else
than the size of your bank account.
Step six, become less awkward with money.
Every dollar that you spend,
someone else is earning.
Every building you see as
you drive down the street
someone else owns.
The amount of money out there
waiting to be grabbed would shock you.
Believing that money is hard to make
or that there's a very limited supply
is what keeps so many people trapped.
I was talking with an author called
Daniel Priestley the other day,
and he mentioned that his mentor
actually made him carry around $1,000
in his pocket when he was younger.
This might sound dangerous,
but the reason behind it
was to make Daniel think
of $1,000 as pocket change,
not his entire net worth.
Becoming more comfortable with money
will help you ask for
raises, start a side hustle,
or even a full blown business.
When my son started his
first videography business
I asked him how much he was gonna charge
and he told me $100 per
day, and I just laughed.
We actually had quite a
big argument over that
and maybe my response was a bit harsh.
The issue is, that he
thought that $100 was a lot,
because he was thinking
about how he spends money,
not how business operates.
Long story short, I
convinced him to charge
more than $200 per day,
and now he takes consultations
for more than $5,000 a day,
something that he wouldn't have been able
to even comprehend five years ago.
The other thing that happens
when you start to realize
that money is everywhere,
is you actually become
less afraid of giving,
and this is the real
secret of getting rich.
You need to give far more value
to other people than you take in return.
If you provide value, then
the money will follow.
The size of your income
will also be determined
by the problems you solve.
So if you wanna make big
money, solve big problems.
Look, if we go back to
my flying days as a pilot
a one degree difference in
the trajectory of a flight
will put the plane in a
completely different continent
after a day of flying.
The same is true for getting
ahead of everyone else.
Making a small adjustment
now and sticking with it
will mean that you end
up in a far better place
than you were originally heading.
Well done for making it this far,
and if you did then
leave a comment saying,
I'm in the club,
so that others are confused.
If you wanna start earning more money
then here are 7.5 high
paying online job ideas
but don't click on it just yet,
make sure to subscribe if
you wanna grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there