You might be shocked to hear this,
but I'm actually not the
youngest YouTuber out there.
I've been through a lot in my life
and made millions in the process.
However, if I had the chance
to start investing all over again,
I'll do things a little bit differently.
So, if you can follow
all five of these steps,
then you'll be well ahead of
me when you get to my age.
Step one, adjust your risk tolerance.
In hindsight,
I realized that I may not
have taken as many risks
as I could have during my younger years.
The reality is,
that in your 20s, you typically
have more time than money.
This means, that any risks you take
have minimal downsides
compared to those that have
families and a mortgage.
This is the time to build your empire.
So, being scared of taking risks
is actually the most
dangerous thing of all
as it means you'll fall
short of your full potential.
Of course, you should do
everything in your power
to swing the odds in your favor.
However, you won't be able
to eliminate risk entirely
if you want to become wealthy.
There is still gonna be some
risk in every opportunity
as nothing good ever comes easy.
When times are hard,
people are much more likely
to let that little bit of
doubt get inside their head
and talk them out of
whatever they want to do.
I've seen countless friends say
they're gonna quit their job
to start a business,
but they never make that leap
because they don't wanna risk
their comfortable income.
When I'm judging whether or
not to make an investment,
I compare the potential risk
with the opportunity cost
of not taking that risk.
Opportunity cost is what you give up
when you choose one option over another.
Thinking about this helps
you make better decisions
about how you use your resources.
I'm not saying I always
make the right decisions
but on average, I've come out profitable
when I've used this tactic
and I also never want the
thought of what could have been
eating away at me.
So, the best way for
you to grow your wealth
is to take calculated risk with your money
and use that time to
grow your wealth faster
than everyone else.
Step two, set it and forget it.
I definitely should have
automated my investments
a lot sooner
as it forces you to
prioritize your investments
as the money is taken
before you can spend it.
This is when you arrange to
have a fixed amount of money
taken out of your paycheck
or bank account every month
and put into a predetermined investment.
Invest in a hundred dollars
in an S&P 500 index fund
is a good example of this.
This will allow your wealth
to compound over the years
without you ever having
to really think about it.
This is a very straightforward process.
First, determine how much
money you want to save
and from which account.
Then go to an investment app
and look for an automatic
investment option
and choose how you want to invest.
They'll do all the paperwork.
Once you sign off on the bottom line,
the automated magic begins.
In my experience, the majority
of people that lose money
when investing, waste their time
trying to pick the right
stock at the right time.
And if you've been watching
my channel long enough,
you'll already know that it's
not easy to time the market
For me, investing is all
about growing your money
over the long term.
ETFs allow you to invest
in an entire market quickly
and in a single transaction
by tracking the performance of an index.
You can choose to invest
in specific regions
like the top 500 companies
in America with the S&P 500,
the entire stock market,
or even specific sectors like tech.
Invest Engine is a witch
recommended provider
and is a platform that
really resonates with me
as their entire focus is
on long-term ETF investing.
They offer ISAs
which are essentially
fortified investing accounts
protecting you from taxes
'cause no one likes the tax man.
With ISA accounts,
you can only invest
20,000 pounds per year,
but any profits you make,
can be withdrawn completely tax free.
So I definitely recommend
creating an ISA account with them
and protecting your returns.
If you sign up to Invest
Engine today using my link,
you receive a £25 welcome bonus
when you invest your first hundred pounds
so you can get a 25% return
on your money from the start.
They even have an auto invest feature
which invest any cash
that hits your portfolio
straight into the ETFs you pick
so you really can set it and forget it.
Thanks, Invest Engine
for sponsoring this portion of the video.
Step three, avoid temptation.
I understand why people were drawn
into the crazy crypto
investments a couple of years ago
as this was similar to
penny stocks back in my day.
When there's a craze like this happening,
lots of people feel like
if they don't invest,
they'll lose out on an
amazing opportunity,
so they start investing in things
without fully understanding them.
This has to be one of
the most risky things
that you could ever do,
and it's probably the
biggest investing mistake
I see people making.
I speak from experience.
I made a few lucky
investments in penny stocks
when I was younger,
and had I continued on that path,
I would've lost everything.
To be more exact, I had
the opportunity to invest
in a big group with a couple
of billionaire friends.
Everything they touched,
seemed to turn to gold.
I can't reveal all the details here
but they had investments
in fashion, retail,
and big banks everywhere.
I didn't really understand
how they were seeing
such amazing returns
of over 25% every year.
So I passed on the opportunity
as it seemed too good to be true.
Had I invested $50,000,
a year later, I would've
lost over $300,000
because they were leveraging
every investment by six times,
which led to this whole
operation going bankrupt.
It's a good lesson to learn though
because I would've previously thought
that the amount that I'd invested
would've been the maximum
that I could have lost.
I always think the best
tool I've got is my gut.
You can usually tell if
something feels right.
Most of the time I can.
But I always like to top this up
with some extra research as well.
The other temptation to
avoid at all cost is debt.
I fell into the equivalent
of $20,000 worth of debt
in my younger days
and lost so many years of
possible wealth building.
The ones to really look
out for are payday loans.
Payday loan companies are like predators.
They see people wanting to keep up
with their friends'
lifestyles on Instagram
and they advertise to
them nonstop on Facebook,
billboards, and newspapers,
preying on their insecurities
and offering them quick money.
Taking out one loan could lead you down
a road of multiple months of debt,
which is really, really hard to escape
and can completely destroy
your investing journey.
Step four, learn a high income skill.
When I first started investing,
I thought I could simply put my money away
every single month
and continue with my regular
day job and become rich.
However, I soon realized
that I wanted to become wealthy
while I was still young,
not wait until I was older
to finally reap the
benefits of my investments.
That's why it's so important
to learn some kind of high income skill
that can be turned into
a profitable side hustle.
One of my side hustles
was teaching people to fly
radio control helicopters.
I developed a skill that
not many people could master
so I charged people to pass on that skill.
The money I earned was in
addition to what I needed
for my normal expenses
so it became money that
I could easily invest.
It's essential to have
another stream of income
and a side hustle is a
really great way to do that.
Now, if you lose your main job,
you still have the source of
income to invest gradually
and it can prevent you
from falling into bad debt.
It might seem impossible
to start a side hustle
when things are difficult,
but if you look hard enough,
there are online
businesses that are booming
such as selling digital products
and affiliate marketing.
Here's an idea.
Look at what you do in your normal job.
Can you transfer this to a side hustle?
It doesn't matter what you do.
From an electrician to a forklift driver,
you can find a way to turn
it into a side hustle.
Step five, invest in your lifestyle.
When you come from nothing,
it can be very hard
spending money on yourself
as you know how hard
that money was to earn.
This is something I'm
only recently getting over
as I've always tried to save money
rather than spending a little bit more
on a nicer experience or product.
My son Curtis knows how
hard it is to make money
as he has built his own
multimillion dollar business
but also spends a considerable
amount on traveling
and improving his lifestyle.
He's recently kitted out his home gym,
regularly flies first class,
and just bought a new fancy
standing desk with a treadmill.
A few years ago,
I would've thought that
was an extravagant expense
but now I do think it's important for you
to level up your lifestyle
as you start earning more.
Let me take you back to when I
was a carpenter's apprentice.
We had to buy all our own hand tools
and they were very expensive.
However, I found a cheaper
place down the market
to buy my tools.
I thought how great it was.
A hammer's a hammer, a chisel's a chisel.
What difference could there be?
And these were better than half price.
I bought a bunch of these tools
and I took them back to work.
But to my dismay,
the hammer shaft bent almost immediately.
The chisels didn't stay
sharp for more than a minute,
and the screwdrivers,
they were only good for
opening cans of paint.
So I ended up wasting all that money
and still having to go out
and buy the quality tools,
which I should have
bought in the first place,
and I still use those to this day.
So, if you don't spend enough money
on good quality products,
then it could end up
actually costing you more
in the long term.
Living a better life
changes you as a person,
it makes you more comfortable socializing
with high net worth people
as you don't feel like a fraud.
Spending less, of course, is
a good idea in some situations
like not spending too much
money on takeaway food
or shopping around for the best groceries.
However, trying to cut costs on everything
can actually be a bit of a money trap.
If you want to know
the nine most untapped
side hustles right now,
then check out this video next.
But don't click on it just yet,
make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.