The biggest lie young people
are told when they're 18, 19,
and 20 is "Money doesn't grow on trees."
This process starts in school
when we're taught to follow
the traditional path of
getting a job and a mortgage,
which leads to working
every hour of the day
just to earn enough money to retire at 67,
and finally die.
Let's be real for a second.
Do you think that's how
I make $67,257 per week?
There is clearly something else going on,
and no, I'm not talking
about getting a high paid job
or starting a side hustle.
To achieve this,
you need a way of making
money that doesn't rely
on you working day in, day out.
It's called passive income,
and here are seven ideas I
strongly suggest you consider,
along with my ratings of each.
Idea One, invest in stocks.
There's a bit more to
this than just invest
in the stock market and
you'll make passive income.
I mean, I can see why
people might think this,
because let's say you
buy a share in a company
and it goes up in value.
Technically, you've generated some money
without doing anything,
but in order to actually
get your cash out,
you have to sell your stock.
Some will consider this passive income,
but instead I just think of it as a bonus
and not something to rely on.
I consider passive income as
nothing less than actual money
flowing into your bank account
every month without the need
to sell the asset that's
making you the money.
That's why the only form
of stock market investing
I consider to be real passive
income is dividend stocks.
These are chunks of companies you can buy.
Think Starbucks, Pepsi, and McDonald's,
and in return for owning them,
you get a share of the
profits paid directly
into your pocket, as well as benefiting
from the stock going up in
value as a bit of a bonus.
They're one of the
easiest ways to make money
on a consistent basis
with absolutely no work.
Well, that's as long as you pick
the right ones to invest in.
I strongly suggest you listen
to this next part carefully
so you avoid making any crucial mistakes.
To help you sort the good from the bad,
dividend stocks are ranked in
a kind of social hierarchy.
At the top you have dividend kings.
These are stocks that have
not only paid a dividend
but actually increased
it for 50 years in a row.
Under that, you have the
dividend aristocrats.
These are the stocks that
have increased their dividends
for 25 years.
That's where the official
definition stops,
but I like to think of
the stocks under this
as dividend working class.
Sure, some of them will eventually become
aristocrats and kings,
however, it's very hard to
tell which ones will make it.
I'd be very cautious with these
as a lot of people get drawn
in by companies offering
extremely high dividends.
I can understand why, but remember,
as much as it's about the amount of money
you're being paid, it's also essential
that it's sustainable long-term.
So you can easily compare
these seven ideas,
I'm gonna rate them in
three different categories.
Firstly, how much time does
dividend investing take?
I'll rate this, say, one out of five,
as all you have to do is
download an investing app,
deposit some money and
buy a few dividend stocks.
Look, this isn't financial advice,
but some apps I'd recommend
are moomoo for the USA
and Lightyear for the UK and Europe.
Apps like these often give
out free stocks for joining,
so if I find any,
then I'll pop them down
in the description below.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'll give this a five out of five.
As it's so quick to do, the
trade-off is that you need
a lot of money invested to
make a significant income.
Thirdly, how easy is it to make
a hundred dollars per week?
This also gets a five out of five.
Let's do the maths.
As dividends are calculated
on a yearly basis
and are paid out at the
end of each quarter,
let's first work out how
much money you need per year,
which is pretty simple.
There are 52 weeks in a year,
so let's multiply that by a hundred,
which gives us $5,200.
Now, let's say we invest in
one of my favorite companies,
Starbucks, who currently pay
an annual dividend of 2.4%.
In order to make $5,200 per year,
or a hundred dollars per week,
you would need to invest a grand total of,
wait for it, $216,666.
Now, I know what you're thinking.
This sounds great for people
that already have money,
but what if I'm just starting out?
In that case, it's a much
better idea to use your time
instead of your money
to make passive income,
which is what the next idea is all about.
Idea Two, automate a side hustle.
A lot of people don't
understand the difference
between a job and an
automated side hustle.
When I was younger, I
had a friend called Jamie
who had a small dog training business.
He was fantastic at what he did.
I remember seeing him
tame the craziest of dogs.
One day when we were sitting in the park,
I asked him how much money he made,
and I was surprised to find out
he was only just getting by.
It didn't really make sense to
me how such a skilled person
who obviously had a lot of value to give
was unable to make the money he deserved.
If we put aside the fact that he probably
wasn't charging enough,
we get to the real issue,
which was the business model.
He only had a limited amount
of hours he could sell
and dogs he could train.
Therefore, he could only earn so much
before his potential was capped
as at the time there was no
way to automate and scale it.
But now we have the internet,
these little side hustles
can become much more passive
and make a lot more money.
So how do you go from having
a skill like Jamie to having
an automated side hustle?
Well, here's the steps I'd take,
and I'm pretty sure I could
turn a small side hustle
like Jamie's into a
million-dollar business nowadays.
Firstly, you have to identify
what you're really good at.
Ideally, you should have some
kind of unfair advantage,
but this is where the
majority of people get caught
in the same trap as Jamie,
as they start to sell
every minute of their time
for a small amount of money.
Instead, you need to
focus every waking hour
on building a digital asset of some kind.
For Jamie, this could have been a blog
where he talked about training dogs,
a manual for owners to
train their own pets,
or a course that teaches other people
how to start a dog training side hustle.
Secondly, when you've decided
what kind of digital asset
you want to build,
you have to put it on the internet
so that your future customers can find it.
The best solution I've
found for this is a tool
called Hostinger, which
is an all-in-one platform.
I'm talking hosting,
website builder, logo maker,
and free domain name with annual plan.
I'll personally choose this
as the drag-and-drop website
builder makes it so easy,
as I don't have any coding skills.
Then it's just a case of
effectively advertising
your digital product on social media.
I'd highly recommend making
viral TikToks about your product
as you can reach so many people
without too much time and effort.
So, how much time does
automating a side hustle take?
Well, if you're doing it on your own,
I'd give it a five out five
as it does take a while to
build a digital product,
and then you have the added
headache of making a website.
However, if you do decide to
use something like Hostinger,
then I'll give this a three hour five,
as you don't need to worry
about having any technical
or design skills for the website
as you can just use the
built-in AI website builder
to make the website for you.
Or alternatively, you could use
the designer-made templates,
which is great news for a boomer like me,
but for the people that are
a bit more knowledgeable,
you can further grow your website
by choosing the WordPress option.
Now, let's talk about
how much money you need.
I'd give this a one out of five
as this passive income idea
is way more about spending
your time than your money.
It depends what digital
product you want to build,
but if it's just a course of some kind,
you can do all of that on your laptop
using a program like Canva.
When it comes to hosting
it on the internet,
if you get Hostinger's 24-month plan
then it comes out less than $3 a month.
I've actually been using
Hostinger for a while now,
so I thought, as I was mentioning
it so much in the video,
why not reach out to them and
see if I could get a discount?
They actually did get back to me.
So if you use the code Mark Tilbury,
you'll get an additional 10% off.
I'll leave a link in
the description below.
Finally, the part that
everyone wants to know,
how easy is it to make a
hundred dollars a week?
I'd give this a one out of five,
because once you're up and running,
let's say you price your
digital product at $25,
all you have to do is
make four sales a week
and you've made a hundred bucks.
So within a couple of weeks you
can make all your money back
and then start making profit.
This is easy enough if you're posting
TikTok videos every day.
You might even get a really viral one
and end up making way more sales
than you initially expected,
and that brings me
perfectly onto Idea Three,
make online content.
For decades, millions
upon millions of dollars
have been hoarded by
the traditional media.
I'm talking about the radio stations
and television networks.
The public had no idea how
much money was in advertising
until YouTube opened
their doors for the public
to create their own content.
Then the curtain was
well and truly lifted.
The traditional media hate it,
and that's why every opportunity
they try and discredit social media.
The people leveraging online
content are dipping their hands
into the previously
extremely guarded money pot
and rightfully taking their fair share.
It still shocks me how some
people don't understand
how content creators make money.
I mean, the concept of advertising
is hundreds of years old
and online ads are far more trackable
than just putting a
random advert on the TV
and hoping it increases a business' sales.
Here's the best piece
of advice I've received
about social media.
It's not if you do it,
it's how well you do it.
So how can we use it to make money?
Well, it's like I previously mentioned.
You can start a YouTube channel,
and once you reach a thousand subscribers
and 4,000 watch hours,
you can start getting paid from
the adverts on your videos.
Whenever I say this to people,
they come back with something like,
"Well, the people that
succeed are just lucky."
Maybe this was the case
a couple of years ago,
but now if your content's good
and designed for the algorithm,
you will be successful.
The harsh truth is, too many
people think their content
is good when it's actually just terrible,
and no one wants to tell them this.
This is because they only
ask family and friends
who sugarcoat the truth
to protect their feelings.
If you want an honest judgment,
you need to ask people who
don't care about offending you.
Care more about people
who don't care about you.
It's best to pick whatever you feel
the most comfortable with, be
that writing, taking photos,
speaking into a microphone, or
recording a full-blown video.
As long as you can capture
people's attention,
then you're onto a winner.
It's also worth mentioning
that picking a niche is important.
In the early days of the internet,
you could get away with talking
about anything and everything,
but now there is so much
competition that you need
to specialize in something in particular.
Think about it like your favorite TV show.
Every time you tune in, you
kind of know what to expect.
Similar characters,
locations, and storylines.
So you wanna make sure
your viewers know what kind
of content you produce and
put it out on a regular basis.
This also makes it a lot easier for you
to attract sponsorship opportunities.
I like to think of every
video I put on this channel
as a little asset that will
make me money for years to come.
It also helps that it's
extremely fun to make content.
So how much time does
content creation take?
I'm gonna give this a
five out of five rating
as it's one of the most
time-consuming things in the world.
I'm not gonna beat around the bush,
but making content is
a long, hard process.
I mean, this video has probably taken us
more than five days to produce.
However, the upsides are
worth it in my opinion.
Just think, the harder
that something is to do,
the less competition you actually have.
Now, how much money do you need?
This is a one out of five
as you really don't need much to start.
I see way too many people
buying the latest equipment
or going on crazy long courses
to learn how to create content.
This is a terrible idea.
You just need to become an avid consumer
of whatever you want to create.
Take the good parts from all
of those different things
and then mix them with your own ideas.
There's a great book about this called
"Steal Like an Artist."
Most importantly, how easy is it to make
a hundred dollars a week?
Well, this has to be
a one out of five too.
Within a couple of months of starting
this YouTube channel,
it was able to make more than
a hundred dollars per day,
and you can do the same.
No wonder the traditional
media wanted to hoard
all this money for themselves.
The opportunity is insane.
Idea Four, start private investing.
Now, I want you to
imagine you're an investor
on "Shark Tank."
An entrepreneur walks in
with an incredible business
you think you can help with,
and they're looking for
some money to expand.
You have the opportunity to
get in on the ground floor
of this business.
Are you gonna take the risk?
How about if you're having a conversation
with a family member and
they share their plan
for a world-dominating business
and they just need a small
amount of money to start?
If you answered yes,
then private investing could be for you.
Your first step is deciding which kind
of private investor you are.
There are two main
types, sharks and angels.
Some stay angels and
some morph into sharks,
but it'll help you to know the difference.
Angels often invest in businesses
run by friends and family.
They often don't have lots of money
nor an interest in taking
control of the business.
They're generally seen as
nicer and more forgiving,
hence their name.
On the other hand, sharks
may invest small amounts
of money but have deeper pockets.
They may also seek a controlling
interest at the start
as they're confident their expertise
can make the business more profitable
and therefore grow their investment.
I'm personally more inclined
towards the shark end
of the spectrum as I like
to have as much control
over my investments as possible.
But whichever private
investment strategy you pick,
you can also combine it
with content creation.
Believe it or not, the actor Ryan Reynolds
is a great example of this.
He's one of the smartest
people on the planet right now,
and I'm not exaggerating.
He's extremely good at
playing the everyday guy,
but under the mask,
he's a business-savvy venture capitalist
with many multi-million
dollar exits under his belt,
giving him a net worth
of over $350 million.
He finds interesting companies,
offers to buy a small
percentage as an angel investor,
uses his social media
to drive up the value,
and then when the company sells,
he gets a huge check for
tens of millions of dollars,
and this is almost all passive income.
It's genius.
Now, of course, Ryan is a worldwide star,
but you can replicate this
strategy on a smaller scale
and use it to make a
lot of passive income.
I mean, even if you could
replicate 1% of his success,
that would give you a net
worth of $3.5 million.
So how much time does
private investing take?
I'm gonna give this a 2.5 out of five
as it takes a while to find a business
that you really believe
is worth investing in.
Don't just jump into anything.
Take your time and carefully consider
if you can see that business
being successful in the future.
You also have to ask the
entrepreneur how dividends
will be paid and their
ultimate exit strategy
as that's how you're gonna get
the majority of your money.
The actual investing
part doesn't take long
as it's just a case of
handing over the money
and being assigned your
percentage of the business.
Now, how much money do you need?
I'm gonna give this a three out of five,
as it really depends on the business
that you're investing in.
I've personally invested
anywhere between a thousand
and a hundred thousand dollars.
Of course, the earlier you get in,
the less you're going to have to invest,
but also the more risk you're taking.
So you have to decide how much
risk you're willing to take.
If you do this,
I'd also recommend making
more than one investment,
as I've often found
that one good investment
can make up for nine bad ones.
But importantly,
how easy is it to make a
hundred dollars a week?
I'm gonna rate this a two out
of five as it really depends
on your negotiation skill
and how much you invest.
I've invested 5,000 in a business
and helped them to upgrade their equipment
as well as helping them
grow their client base.
I started making it an
easy hundred dollars
per week in dividends.
The more value you can offer,
the more you'll get in return
as you are taking money
out of the entrepreneur's pocket,
but instead helping to grow
the pot of money for everyone.
Idea Five, become an affiliate marketer.
I remember when recently a
big bank had a promotion.
My son's girlfriend sent a signup link
to all of her friends,
letting them know if
they downloaded the app,
they could get a free $10.
She was shocked by the results.
Every few hours a new friend had signed up
and thanked her for the free cash.
Before she knew it,
30 of her friends had
signed up using the link
and she'd hit the limit.
But she wasn't just doing this
out of the kindness of her heart.
Although she is a kind girl.
She also got paid $10 for
everyone that signed up,
meaning that day she made $300
just sitting in the bed
texting a few people.
Just imagine if there wasn't a limit.
She could have made far more.
This is essentially affiliate marketing,
but real affiliate marketing
doesn't have a limit,
so you can make as much as you want.
It's considered to be one of the simplest,
yet most profitable ways
to make money online
as it doesn't require you
to have any extra skills
or previous experience.
All that's typically needed
as an affiliate is a passion
for your niche and
strong persuasive skills.
Think about all the products you love
and maybe even use on a daily basis.
The chances are that other people
will also like those products,
and you are the perfect
person to sell it to them.
Most big companies have
an affiliate scheme,
so all you have to do
is go onto their website
and do a bit of digging.
If you can't find anything,
then it's worth reaching
out to them directly
and asking if you can become an affiliate.
There are also websites like impact.com
where you can see a lot of
different affiliate schemes
that you can easily sign up for.
Now, you have to make some noise.
You can do this by writing blogs,
using social media or posting reviews.
You may have already
seen this done on TikTok
with those videos about Amazon
products you need to buy.
Every time someone buys through your link,
you as the affiliate
marketer receive a kickback
and make a profit, but bear in
mind if you're doing reviews,
you should actually purchase
the product and test it.
Using it over a period of time
and reporting your findings
will make sure your content
is useful and genuine.
One thing to keep in mind before you start
affiliate marketing is to consider
how you can provide value to your audience
that exceeds what you get in return.
So how much time does
affiliate marketing take?
I'm gonna give this a 3.5 out of five.
I'm not gonna lie.
It's gonna be hard to begin with,
so it's important to have
realistic expectations.
While it is a great way
to make money online,
it's not a get-rich-quick scheme.
It requires patience and
a willingness to learn.
It's totally understandable
to feel discouraged
if you don't see results right away,
but keep in mind that success
in this field takes time.
You need to build trust with your audience
and create valuable content for them.
Now, how much money do you need?
This gets a one out of five
as you don't need any money whatsoever.
That's assuming you already
have a phone or a laptop
you can use to access the
internet and make your content.
But how easy is it to make
a hundred dollars a week?
I'm gonna give this a two out of five.
If we take the example
of my son's girlfriend,
she was kind of doing affiliate marketing
without even knowing,
and she managed to make $300 in one day.
Of course, this wasn't very passive
as she was texting people.
However, once you have your
content up and running,
it'll do most of the
heavy lifting for you.
It's been reported that affiliate
marketers earn an average
of $66,029 per year passively,
with earnings ranging from
35,000 up to $124,000.
Idea Six, create a digital tool.
My best friend decided to do this,
and now he's a multimillionaire
who spends more time
on vacation with his wife
than he does at home.
He noticed a gap in the
market for a digital tool
that helped large membership organizations
keep track of all their customers' data.
At first, he decided to sell his software
as a one-time purchase.
However, he always had to
search for a new customer.
When he made the switch to
a subscription-based model,
he was able to make a very predictable
amount of passive income every month.
Well, I say passive income.
Of course, he still had to
offer support to his customers,
but eventually he hired
people to do this for him
and was completely hands-off.
He later went on to sell his
business for multiple millions.
Before you start thinking you
have to be some kind of nerd
to create a digital tool, hear me out.
The most important thing to
do is to identify a problem
that needs solving.
Often you find people who
have the ability to code
aren't that creative and
need a lot of direction.
So if you can't code, then
you can be the ideas person,
the business brain behind the talent.
You then need to pick the
customers your software
is going to serve.
There are two main categories,
business or consumers.
Serving other businesses is often seen
as the least risky and you can make
more money per customer.
When you've got this,
you'll really be able to
see how people respond
to your solution.
You've got to make sure
you aren't too attached
to your ideas as you may find
it doesn't actually fix
the problem you intended.
Therefore, it's very important to be able
to adapt your digital tool
after receiving criticism.
Even if this isn't something you think
you can start right now,
it's worth just noting down
problems you see businesses
are facing just in case
you stumble upon a solution
no one has thought of before.
So, how much time does
creating a digital tool take?
I'm gonna give this a five out of five.
Not only does the process
of coming up with the idea
take a long time,
so does the testing and
the building of the tool.
So if you decide to go down this route,
I don't want you to be
under any illusions.
Make sure you don't sink years
into building the final tool
before testing it though.
I've seen way too many
people do this and realize
they've actually just ended
up wasting years of their life
on something no one wants.
But like I mentioned with my friend,
if you do manage to build
an amazing digital tool,
then it will pay you a consistent
stream of passive income
and you'll have the added benefit
of being able to sell it
for potentially millions.
Now, how much money do you need?
I'm gonna give this a 3.5 out of five
as making anything like this
is gonna cost you a
decent amount of money.
However, there are two things you can do
to bring down your costs.
Firstly, you can partner with a coder,
and therefore you won't
have to pay for his time,
but you will have to give away equity.
Secondly, once you've
made your first version
of your product or MVP, if it's good,
you'll start to get some
interest from angel investors.
At this point, you have
to make the decision
to either keep using your own money,
known as bootstrapping, or
take on investment in return
for giving away equity in your business.
But the big question,
how easy is it to make a
hundred dollars per week?
This is a one out of five.
If you manage to build
and fund it to the stage
where it can be released to the market
and were to price your
subscription at $20 a month,
then you'd only need 20 paying customers
and you'll be making a
hundred dollars a week.
Of course, you will have other expenses,
but these will be limited
to customer support
and software updates.
It's also likely you'll charge
a lot more than $20 a month
and have a lot more than 20 customers.
I must spend at least a
thousand dollars a month
on digital tools, so the
money's definitely out there.
So we've talked about investing in assets
and building your own,
but one thing that often gets overlooked
is actually making money from
the assets you already own,
which brings me onto Idea
Seven, rent out your stuff.
Most people don't realize
that they're sitting
on a gold mine and could already own
what they need to make
some passive income.
I remember a few years ago,
one of my friends revealed to me
that he was struggling to pay his bills.
I then suggested that he
rented out his driveway
to make some passive income.
He looked at me and laughed,
but then a few weeks later,
he texted me back and said
it was working amazingly.
This is because he lived
near Bromley Train Station,
which meant he could
charge people $70 a week
to leave their car in his drive
when they went to London to work.
He had capacity for two cars,
so he was actually able
to make $140 a week
in extra passive income.
I'm aware not everyone has
a driveway to rent out,
but most people have something
they could use to make money.
Make a list of everything you own
and see if anything jumps out at you.
A few ideas that come to
mind are storage space
such as an attic or a basement, a vehicle,
camping equipment, camera gear,
a garage or a spare room in your house,
or dare I say it, money.
Of course, you could
always go down the route
of buying a second property to rent out,
but you would need a considerable amount
of money to do that.
The world is definitely
becoming more familiar
with renting things as things
are getting more increasingly expensive.
Renting out your stuff can be a great way
to actually justify buying
the asset in the first place.
I mean, if I knew that an expensive camera
would pay for itself after
a certain amount of rentals,
didn't it make sense to buy it?
Once you thought of what
you can rent to others,
all you need to do is find
an app that matches you
with potential customers.
There are so many of these.
In the past, I've used Fat
Llama to rent camera equipment
and camping gear, Turo to rent vehicles
and Airbnb to hire filming locations.
Peer-to-peer lending platforms
also make it possible
for you to essentially rent
out your money to others.
While it does involve some risk,
many lenders have successfully generated
a nice income from this investment.
For example, Prosper, one
of the leading platforms,
has an average historical return of 5.4%.
So, if you're willing
to take a bit of a risk,
this could be a great option to explore.
So, how much time does
renting something out take?
I'll give this a one out of five,
because all you have to
do is take a few pictures
and upload them to an app or a website
that does all the work for you.
The biggest drawback of this
is the potential risk involved.
Not everyone will take
the same degree of care
with your items as you would.
That's why having some kind
of insurance is important.
Normally, this comes with the platform
that you decide to use.
Now, how much money do you need?
I'll also give this a one out of five
because if you're just renting
out things you already own,
it's not gonna cost you anything.
The only cost will be if you decide
to get separate insurance
or you decide you want
to buy things in order
to rent them out.
And the big question,
how easy is it to make a
hundred dollars a week?
I'd give this a two out of five
as it's very easy if you have
enough assets to rent out.
Most people have a house they can use
to make an extra a hundred dollars a week,
even if that means renting out
a driveway or a spare room.
If you'd like to know how you
can get ahead of everyone else
this year, then you can
watch this video next.
But don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.