- Lots of teenagers are
about to get very rich.
- Why is that?
- Well, the data strongly
shows that traditional jobs
are being replaced and
online jobs are booming.
- But surely that means
there'll be too much competition
in the online space.
- Well, teenagers have an advantage,
as they understand the online
world better than anyone else.
It's just second nature.
- But Mark, I dunno what to do.
- Well, that's why I'm gonna be revealing
the 7.5 best paid online
jobs for teenagers.
And this isn't any old list.
For each one, I'm gonna
provide a real life example
of a teenager currently
killing it in that job.
Job one is an advertising deal broker.
Teenagers doing this job earn as much
as 100 to $120,000 per year.
In 2021, I bought a Tesla Model 3,
and I set myself a bit of a challenge.
I wanted to see if it
was possible to use lots
of different side hustles to
earn back the price of the car.
One of the ideas my son and I came up with
was to get it wrapped like a racecar
which would involve securing
paid advertisements.
At this point, we received
a cold email from a teenager
called Christian
completely out of the blue
who said that he was able
to secure the sponsorship
we required for a 30% commission.
Christian managed to get an
offer of $30,000 on the table.
Had we accepted this deal, he
would've made a sweat $9,000
for essentially matching us with the brand
and acting as the middle man.
In the end, Curtis managed
to secure a different deal
with public.com, so we went with them.
However, Christian has managed to secure
many of these deals in the past.
That's why we can still
offer you a free stock
worth all the way up to $1,000 from Public
with the link in the description.
Christian told me that the
best way to be successful
with this job is to make
friends in the right places.
He described it a lot like a jungle
where one branch would lead
to the next one and so on.
Once you start working
with one big company,
it becomes a lot easier,
as you can reference them
as a past client and therefore demonstrate
that you have experience in
the areas that they require.
So how does he do it?
He uses different software
to get the email addresses
of influencers and just fires off messages
until he gets a bite.
Then he evaluates the needs of the clients
that contact him back and
runs a similar campaign
focused on reaching out to brands
on the influencer's behalf.
It kind of reminds me of the book
"How To Win Friends & Influence People,"
where Dale Carnegie
talks about sending mail
to powerful people and getting replies,
only the modern-day version.
If we learn anything from Christian
it's the power of a good
reference and relationships.
Always do your best work
because you never know
where something might lead in the future.
Job two is a Discord
community manager for Web3.
These teens make more than $70,000 a year,
depending on their multitasking ability.
When it comes to marketing for Gen Z,
community is everything.
Every brand under the
sun is trying to build
a community around their product.
This is actually the
main reason why Gymshark
have set up their first store in London.
- The real purpose of
this store needs to be
to really cultivate the Gymshark community
and connect with people.
- Now, if you've ever used Discord,
then you've probably
met a community manager.
They're like the glue that
holds everything together.
I know a guy called Harry
who hires community managers.
He said that he wouldn't bat an eyelid
at paying more than $2,000 per week
if they were good at the job
and represented the brand
in a positive light.
Additionally, if you are
good at multitasking,
there's nothing stopping you
from being a community manager
for three or four
projects at the same time,
which means big money.
The job of the community manager
is to be on the front line.
You have to tell the story of the brand,
be customer service and support,
as well as supporting
people when they're down
and paying attention to global events.
You need to be able to
pause your schedule,
be active when people are looking for you,
and listen when people
need your attention.
Above all, you have to
be the voice of the CEO,
but not always speak on
behalf of the company.
Job three is writing scripts
for content creators.
These teams can earn upwards of $100,000,
but can go a lot higher
depending on the type of content
and your experience.
Words can make you sound smart,
or they can do the opposite,
depending on how they're deployed.
That's why businesses hire copywriters,
basically, salesman in print.
Copywriters can make
insane amounts of money.
I'm talking over $500
an hour in many cases.
It all depends on how good
you are making connections,
your skill with words, and
how fast you can write.
Some charge as much as
$50,000 for just one webpage.
You may be thinking, why so much?
Well, it's all about value.
If you charge $50,000 for a webpage
and it results in a
business monthly profit
going from 200,000 to $400,000,
wouldn't you say it's worth it?
It's all about leverage, making
rich clients even richer,
then asking for your slice of the pie.
And it's not just websites either.
People need quality writers
for all sorts of things.
Everything from TikTok
scripts to threads on Twitter.
Content is king, and the
magician behind all of this
is often the writer.
I know a guy named Adam.
He started off writing blog
posts about his travels
to earn passive income and
lived anywhere in the world.
This later led him to
working as a copywriter
for large influencers.
He followed the same
strategy as Christian.
Got one client, which
led to another and so on.
He told me when he offers a service,
he always tries to be exclusive
and do it in a way that no one else could.
There's always gonna be
someone cheaper than you,
but not always someone more expensive.
Find the client who can
afford to pay the premium,
then learn to offer a world-class service.
Job four is a SaaS software coder.
These teens can earn between
60 and $80,000 a year.
A guy called Sam King came on
my podcast, "Strike It Big,"
and explained how he built a
multi-million dollar business
without ever having a normal job.
Instead of building a
traditional business,
he decided to build a SaaS company.
This stands for Software as a Service.
Just think of how many online tools
you use on a daily basis.
I know I love Notion, MailChimp,
Photoshop, and many more.
These online tools have become
such a big part of our life,
and once the app is built,
it's almost entirely profit.
Sam said there's so many people out there
trying to sell the same type of product
with such tight margin.
It's a race to the bottom
with traditional businesses.
People start businesses to be free
but end up becoming slaves.
That's why he wanted to create
a business with no inventory,
and something that could scale infinitely.
All he needed was a good
coder and a bit of marketing.
This is where you could
help out as a coder
or, alternatively, come
up with the SaaS idea.
He started by Googling and
researching the problems
and challenges faced by
different types of businesses.
Then had his programmer
create the perfect solution.
He ended up building a tool
that helps people and businesses
manage their social media
accounts, called Flick.
So the one thing to
take from Sam's journey
is that the most
important part of business
is solving an issue that
affects a lot of people
in a better way than
what's currently available.
Job five is a content
redistribution editor.
They can make 120 to $150,000 per year.
Ever add some food left over
and decided just to throw it
all in a pot and turn it into a soup?
Well, that's what someone
I know called Josh does,
but with video content.
The idea came to him
while he was at VidSummit.
He was in a room with a
variety of influencers
when suddenly a light
bulb went off in his head.
He didn't have to create his own content.
He just took existing
videos and remixed them
for YouTubers that wanted
to post short-form content.
He took podcasts and YouTube videos
and made them TikTok
and Instagram friendly,
giving his clients the ability
to reach much wider audiences
without actually producing
any new content themselves.
It's called content redistribution.
It's like recycling,
but in the digital age.
It doesn't take too much time,
but large creators don't want the hassle
of editing everything themselves.
Josh later went on to hire team members
so that he could serve more
clients and increase his income.
Job six is a website developer.
Teens doing this can earn
an average annual salary
of around 80 to $150,000 per year.
For many businesses, their
website is their front door,
so they wanna make it
as stylish as possible.
I've got a friend named
Chris who lives out in Italy.
He decided he wanted to niche
down into the e-learning space
and focus on building marketing funnels.
A good website developer knows
that if you keep your clients
on a monthly retainer, you
can earn passive income
just by doing small tweaks here and there.
Chris told me that the best way forward
is to start a subscription business
with reoccurring revenue.
"Think Netflix," he said.
The best job is one that
requires very little maintenance.
You just keep clients
on a retainer of voila.
He now has enough passive income
to live almost anywhere in the world.
He often travels to cheap
countries like Thailand
where he can live on
less than $1,000 a month.
He doesn't focus on earning
as much money as possible.
He said that's just a trap.
The point of making money
is to buy yourself freedom.
Job seven is a Twitter manager.
Teens can earn around 60 to
$80,000 per year doing this job.
Twitter seems to be the
hottest social media nowadays,
especially since the
whole Elon Musk takeover.
I know a college dropout called Sean
who wasted a lot of his
time trolling on Twitter
until he asked himself,
"What if I could actually
make a job out of this?"
So he decided to become a Twitter expert.
He took a lot of time to study the content
put out by some of the best creators.
"Don't just look at the
reason stuff though,"
he told me.
"Look at the post that
really made them blow up.
Then study it. That's
what you want to go for."
He said two of the best ways
to blow up nowadays on Twitter
is to create threads and host spaces.
You need to be able to
capture people's attention
with as few words as
possible and hook them in,
and that takes a lot of practice.
But this is a very
valuable skill to learn.
Just like the others, he said
he takes multiple clients
on at the same time and, much like Chris,
keeps them on a retainer.
Job 7.5 is an executive assistant.
It's a bonus because it can become
more than just an online job.
These teams can make 90
to $110,000 per year.
You'll be doing everything
from scheduling appointments
to making small decisions everyday.
A good example of this is Gabe from NELK.
He does so much for them.
If you make yourself
totally indispensable,
no one will ever get rid of you,
and that's the case with Gabe.
A great per to this job is
potentially traveling around
with these influencers
and seeing all sorts
of cool and amazing places.
Just like with Christian,
Gabe understood the power of connections.
It seems like anything
is possible nowadays
in the digital world.
All you need to do is
think about something
you can offer some kind
of value to the world.
Then send emails, reach out,
and make sure everyone knows what you do.
Artificial intelligence is
gonna be a big money-maker
for teens in and future.
So if you wanna learn how
to use AI to get rich,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there.
But don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over.