- This is me asking a
first class passenger
how they got rich.
You see, I was traveling from
London to Miami first class,
which cost me about $6,000,
which got me thinking,
what do these other first class
passengers do for a living
that enables them to afford
these luxury tickets?
But unfortunately it
didn't all go to plan.
- [Manager] You've been
speaking to all our customers?
- Yes.
- What's it you doing?
- Right, here's the plan.
I've just booked some
first class tickets for me
and my cameraman, Tom.
These tickets come with
free lounge access,
where you can enjoy delicious food,
take a nap on the comfy daybeds,
and even freshen up with
a shower in the spa area.
But unfortunately,
we are not gonna be doing
any of those lovely things,
instead, we are gonna use this time
to interview as many people as possible.
The sacrifices I make for you guys,
I could be enjoying a nice
complimentary massage instead.
But there's one major flaw to our plan,
places like this are very secretive,
which means if we get caught filming,
it could have serious consequences.
As soon as I entered the lounge,
a guy in a sparkly outfit caught my eye,
so I headed over to have a chat.
He explained that he used
to own a jewelry store
that he recently sold for
a nice amount of money.
So how did you start out in business?
'cause that's always a key question
a lot of our viewers ask.
- I worked for six independent companies
with four or five shops.
- And what did that give you
by working for multiple people?
- Experience, and I opened
a shopping in Stamford.
- I mean, I say to a lot of
people, getting experience
is better than necessarily
gaining qualifications,
what would you you say about that?
- Yes, getting experience?
You've gotta love what
you do, you gotta love it.
- I couldn't agree more with this.
I don't have any qualifications.
I actually left school when I was 16,
and became a millionaire in my 20s.
This isn't to say college
and university is pointless,
but in most cases,
experience often steals the
spotlight from qualifications.
There's a brilliant quote
from Sylvester Stallone
that sums this up perfectly,
and it goes something like this,
"The only purpose of a college degree
"is to show your potential boss
"that you turned up to class
"for three to four years in a row,
"completed a series of assignments
"reasonably well and on time.
"So if they hire you,
"there's a semi-decent chance
you'll show up every day,
"and not mess their business up."
Things were starting to get
really tense in the lounge,
I could feel the staff
constantly watching us.
So I knew our time was limited.
What advice would you give to
any youngster nowadays starting out?
- Well, I think the one
piece of advice is, is save.
You know, don't spend your
income if you can avoid it,
you know, make sure you put money aside.
- So I live within your means for sure.
- Well, yeah.
- This conversation
really hit home for me.
I've seen multimillionaire friends
lose it all in an instant,
and others whose lives
are controlled by debt.
But saving is just one side of the story,
you need to invest.
This graph shows the growth of $10,000
invested in the S&P 500 index
from January, 1980 to December, 2018.
The person that invested,
and kept their money in the stock market
without drawing it out,
actually made the most money.
Personally, I would invest in accounts
like a stocks and shares ISA in the UK,
and a Roth IRA in the USA.
These accounts are so powerful
as they allow you to
grow your money over time
for retirement tax-free.
It's so important to ensure
that the platform you use for investing
is something called automated investing.
So the money is just
taken from your account,
and you can forget about it.
Investing platforms have
started implementing
smart advisors operated by AI.
Think of it like a service
that can develop an
investment portfolio for you
using the information you provide
about your personal needs
such as financial goals,
risk tolerance, and so on.
Personally, I really like Webull
as they offer everything we
just discussed and so much more.
If any of that interests you,
sign up for Webull today with
the link in the description
and get completely free stocks
when you open an account.
I was just about to interview a guy
that worked in financial technology
when my cameraman, Tom,
got a tap on the shoulder,
and it took a very serious turn.
- Speaking to our costumes.
- Yes.
- What's it you doing?
- Our names were taken, put on record,
and we were ordered to stop filming.
Honestly, I felt like I was a criminal.
Apparently by speaking
to people in the lounge,
we had broken their privacy
rules and regulations.
If we were caught filming again,
there would be a devastating consequence.
They would terminate our tickets
and still charge us the full
amount, the cheek of it.
For the next hour, we sat in the lounge
planning our next move.
The staff were all
watching us like Hawkes,
and we knew if they saw
us even raise a camera,
it would be game over.
Fortunately, we were
able to board the plane
without any further issues.
(upbeat music)
♪ Never gonna stop ♪
♪ You're never gonna give you up ♪
(upbeat music continues)
♪ Part in the action ♪
♪ You're the main attraction ♪
- Once we were airborne,
it was time to take the risk,
and fill more interviews.
And you know me, I love a risk.
So I've managed to snag an interview
with Curtis Tilbury from
"The Strike Big Podcast."
Anyway, Kurt, how do you make your money?
- Well, obviously the podcast
is a big part of that,
but run a production company
that owns various
different shows on YouTube.
- So what is your net worth currently at?
- It's over a million.
I have about 13 people
working for me at the moment,
so yeah, no, it's a good business.
- How did you actually
build that business out?
Where did it all start from?
- I started making free
videos for lots of people-
- Hang on, hang on, did you say free?
What, you didn't charge people?
- No, I didn't.
At the start when you are
trying to build your skills
as a videographer, which is what I was,
no one really trusts you and
doesn't really wanna pay you
if they haven't seen what you've done,
so you have to build up a portfolio.
So I did everything from wedding videos,
to shooting club videos.
- So how'd you go about going
from a very small startup,
giving away free content,
to actually having people on your staff,
as it were, being a real company.
- So it's all about niching down.
And then when you niche,
and become an expert in your
field, you can charge more.
- Lots of people think
that by doing everything,
you have a much wider market.
And although this is true to some extent,
would you rather be operated
on by a surgeon or a GP?
I can guarantee that you
chose surgeon, but why?
Naturally, we feel safer
in the hands of an expert,
and this is the same
across all aspects of life.
So my advice on how to
become an expert would be,
number one, find your niche.
You need to find a niche that has demand,
which you can add value to.
Number two, gain practical experience.
Try to experience different
areas within your chosen niche
to gain a wide range of skills.
Number three, continuously learn.
You need to stay updated
with trends and developments
within your niche.
Don't be late to the party.
And number four, build
a professional network.
There's one thing better
than being an expert,
and that's being an expert
with expert friends.
The staff was starting to
take notice of us filming,
so I quickly began chatting
to a very interesting man
who set foot in America
with just $40 in his pocket,
and became rich by starting
two different businesses.
What would you say to your younger self
if you were starting out
again, to gain say the wealth,
and the great life that you've had so far?
- Risk management, may be the
core most underrated issue
in business for entrepreneurs.
- Risk management?
- Everything has risk, right?
- Yes, of course.
- And it's understanding those risks
and mitigating those risks
where you may not have the
knowledge base or the experience.
- The fear of failure is a huge
problem in today's society,
and it holds many people back.
Just think if someone can come to America
with is $40 in their pocket,
and become a millionaire
by taking calculated
risks, then why can't you?
Honestly, if I hadn't taken
the leap to quit my job
and start my own business after
being bullied by my manager,
I wouldn't be wealthy today.
All my millions can be traced
back to that one big risk.
Here in the UK, 6 outta 10 people
fear taking risks in life, but why?
Well, 2/3 worry about the consequences,
while the other third fear
the possibility of failure.
This shows that most people
have the tendency to play it safe,
and avoid stepping into the unknown.
But consider this, playing it safe
could be the biggest risk you ever take.
Before I could interview anyone else,
I received a dreaded tap on the shoulder
from the air service manager.
He asked to speak to me
at the first class bar.
To my surprise, he wasn't
annoyed, quite the opposite.
He was interested in being in my video,
so I thought I could do a little digging
into the types of customers
he looks after in first class.
- So we get celebrities, we get
a lot of business customers,
and then we have people
that are maybe new money,
they might have the lottery
and things like that.
- What's the sort of age group
that you get in the first class area?
- Again, it varies.
You have so many
entrepreneurs nowadays as well
who are very, very young.
You'll see them up there,
completely broad age range.
- It's really cool to hear
that there are more and
more young entrepreneurs
flying first class.
According to the New York
Times, major US airlines
are expanding their
fancy seats by 25 to 75%.
But why is the demand increasing?
Well, one of the main reasons for this,
is that making money online
has become incredibly easy.
You can now make a living
from all sorts of online opportunities.
By the way, I'm running
a totally free challenge
to help you earn an extra 2K this month.
It's all going down on my Discord Server
where we have regular mentoring calls,
and you can even win awesome prizes
like a trip to Dubai with a friend.
Head over to 2Kchallenge.com to join,
I'll leave a link in the description.
We landed in Miami, and I spent the week
meeting up with some great
people like Patrick Bet-David,
Luke Belmar, Grant
Cardone, and Ben Marler.
But the most exciting for me was John Fox,
he invited me to a private
airport to fly one of his planes.
I must admit, I did hesitate a little,
I hadn't flown a plane
for around 15 years.
Not only was this guy a plane expert,
but he was a pro flyer,
and I was worried I
wouldn't be as good as I was
when I last flew with
him over 30 years ago.
What piece of advice would you
give to a youngster nowadays
if they wanted to own a
beautiful aircraft like this?
- Go out there and try
everything you think you want.
Try everything you
think you're gonna love,
and try some of the things
that you don't like,
and you'll surprise your inner heart,
and something will spark,
and then follow that path.
- Well, I think that's very
sound advice my friend.
- I'm gonna certify
that, did you get that?
- With that said, it was time
for me to pursue my passion
and take to the skies.
Evaluating the risks was
the last thing on my mind,
flying planes is what
sets my soul on fire.
And deep down I knew that
if I didn't seize this opportunity,
I would forever wonder, what if?
♪ You gotta give all you got ♪
♪ Gotta give all you've got for love ♪
♪ 'Cause you're here for a moment ♪
♪ Give all you've got, gotta
give all you've got for love ♪
♪ Give all you've got, give
all you've got for love ♪
- Absolutely fantastic.
I'm a bit emotional
actually, to be honest.
- [John] That's okay.
(gentle music)