This is the online side hustle pyramid.
It's made up of three different levels.
Level one requires no skills and no money.
Level two demands some
skills, but still no money.
And to reach level three, you
need both skills and money.
As a millionaire who started
off with absolutely nothing,
I've been through all of these levels.
And if you do too, then
you'll certainly be able
to make more than $1,000 per day.
And don't worry i'm
not gonna be suggesting
you spend hours watching
ads, testing websites,
or filling out those
useless online surveys.
I mean, only pay a few dollars
anyway, so what's the point?
Instead, I'm interested in the big bucks.
So these are side hustles
you can make good money from.
Of course, the faster you
progress through the levels,
the more money you can make.
Level one, no skills, no money.
In this level, it's all
about using your time
as strategically as possible
to create the most amount of money.
The first side hustle is
being a content critic.
This one isn't as well known,
but it's definitely in high demand.
I'm even willing to pay
someone to do this for me,
so listen up and let
me know if this sounds
like something you'd be interested in.
The job of a content critic
is to give unbiased, honest feedback.
Honesty is such a rare thing to find.
Most negative comments come from haters,
and fans rarely like to offer criticism,
as many people take it the wrong way.
The majority of content creators
have developed a tough skin
and are actively looking for ways
in which to improve their content.
That's why if you are a genuine fan
of a particular YouTuber,
then you could actually be
far more valuable than you realize.
So if this sounds like something
you could be interested in,
then leave me a comment
below suggesting what content
you'd like to see on my channel,
and I'll reach out to the
people with the best ideas
and be their first client.
I'm happy to pay a fair amount
for a great feedback report
from a viewer, and I'm
sure many other creators
would be open to doing the same.
With multiple clients,
you'll be able to build up
to more than $1,000 in no time.
The second side hustle is
flipping Instagram theme pages.
This is something you can
do with just an iPhone
and a bit of time.
These are pages that are
focused on specific subjects.
When I first heard that you can make money
from flipping these, I was
actually quite shocked.
Back in my day, I had to actually buy
and sell physical products
like cars, for example.
But now doing this online
actually makes complete sense.
Just think about it, when was
the last time you scrolled
on Instagram and didn't
see a sponsored post?
They're everywhere, aren't they?
This just shows brands
are putting loads of money
into Instagram adverts, which
makes the pages more valuable.
If I were you, I would
start and grow pages,
in particular niches, by
posting regular Reels.
Personally, I'd pick a car theme page,
as I used to race cars,
so I know the niche
has a big demand from advertisers.
I've seen some of these
pages sell for thousands.
A bonus one in this level is
using a link in the description
to get 16 free stocks worth between two
and $2,000 in return
for signing up to Mumu.
They're a great investing platform,
and it's basically free money.
Level two, some skills, no money.
These online side hustles
require more upfront work
to begin with, but as
you develop your skills,
you'll be able to charge a lot more
than the average person, as
you are providing more value,
and this of course equals higher pay.
The third side hustle
is designing thumbnails.
I actually ran a competition
to find a thumbnail editor
for this YouTube channel.
I did this on my Instagram,
and we had hundreds of submissions.
You might be thinking if
hundreds of people applied,
isn't there too much competition?
In all honesty, only three designers
actually stood out to
me in that competition,
as they took the time
to understand my style.
And rather than just
creating a pretty graphic,
they really considered how they could
get people interested in clicking.
Creating effective thumbnails is more
of a psychological task
than a graphic design one.
The best thumbnails are
often simple to create,
but the idea behind them is very clever.
Just think, if you can
increase a YouTuber's
click-through rate by even one or 2%,
then hiring you means instant profit,
and you are justifying your own wage.
Out of the three
candidates that stood out,
I hired two of them myself,
and I recommended the
third to one of my friends.
If you can master this skill
and sell 10 thumbnails in a day
for a hundred dollars each,
then that's $1,000 right there.
You could charge less and do more,
or even charge more and do less.
The choice is yours depending
on your skill level.
The fourth side hustle is tutoring.
Now before COVID, I probably
wouldn't have added this one
to the list, as most people
wanted in-person tutors.
And honestly, this
business model isn't great,
as it's very time intensive,
and the amount you can charge
is also pretty capped
depending on the competition
in your local area.
However, I really think
the world has changed.
If you are talented at
a particular subject,
it may be a great option
to teach it online.
The key here is to sell the transformation
rather than a tutor in itself.
I mean, most people don't
really go to a personal trainer
to improve their technique.
They go to become a fitter person.
That's why they're always using
before and after photos to
advertise their services.
The same goes for tutoring.
You need to sell a specific
outcome to a standardized test
such as GCSEs and A levels in the UK.
Facebook is the perfect
place to advertise,
as it's full of moms that
want their kids to do better
than everyone else's.
Trust me, if you find the
right Facebook groups,
the demand is sky high.
The great thing about doing it online
is that you can cut out
all the travel time,
which means you can work with more people
and earn more money.
You also don't have to
just work for people
in your local area, as
you can teach anyone,
anywhere in the world.
If you are able to sell
10 spots in a group class
for $25 each, then that's $250 an hour.
Once you achieve this, you
can start filling more hours.
You may think that people
won't want group classes,
but if you give them the
outcome you promised,
it doesn't matter how you deliver it,
especially if you put all the
students in a Facebook group
and offer them support outside of lessons.
Of course, if you are selling the outcome
of getting into medical school
or completing your exams
as a doctor, then you can charge way more,
as the potential outcome you are selling
is worth a lot more money.
The fifth side hustle is creating logos.
Have you ever looked at a
famous logo and thought,
"That's so simple, I could do that."
I know I certainly have, and I'm ancient.
So I'm sure you younger guys watching this
will be able to master this one easily.
We recently held a competition
on my Instagram account
where we paid the winner
$1,000 for creating a logo
for our brand, Strike It Big,
which is run by my son and I.
We weren't looking for
crazy design skills.
It was all about the idea, even
as the logo was hand drawn.
We were prepared to pay the
money if it was a good idea.
With this side hustle, no one
cares about your score grades.
Instead, your past work
acts as your qualifications,
so it's really important
to build a great portfolio
to seal the deal with your clients.
You may have to work for free
in the early days to do this.
I know that working for free
sounds like a waste of time,
but it's a great way to
check out the competition
and also see how to price your services.
Once you have a solid portfolio,
you can either go directly to your clients
or offer graphic design
services on websites
like Fiverr and Upwork,
as they already have a huge marketplace.
If you are good,
there's no reason you couldn't
be earning 500 to $1,000
per day in your spare time.
The sixth side hustle is
becoming a high-ticket closer.
Imagine being the mastermind
behind sealing deals
and locking in sales for
influencers, course creators,
consultants, and business owners.
These types of people are
usually extremely busy
managing operations,
delivering their products,
and making content so they
need someone with a gift
of the gab that can focus
entirely on closing deals.
This is exactly what one
of my employees does,
and he regularly takes
home more than $1,000
in a day from commissions,
and he has no formal
qualifications to his name.
This just shows how you
can add value to a business
by selling their high-ticket items
and earn more than a doctor's salary.
The advantage of being
a high-ticket closer
is the fact that you don't
need to create your own thing.
You are just simply selling
someone else's product.
It's a much simpler business model
that you can do from
anywhere in the world.
If you have a phone, you have a business,
and that's about it.
The seventh side hustle is web design.
The internet (whooshes breath)
levels the playing field.
It's almost like America was in my youth,
the land of opportunity.
But the internet is far greater,
and it allows the younger generations
to have a big advantage over
the older business owners.
I mean, no business can survive
long without a good website,
and most people are lacking the skills
to build one themselves.
So if this interests you,
then why not learn web design skills?
I know two teenagers that
decided to take up web design,
and they both went in two
completely different directions.
One decided he'd use website
builders such as Squarespace,
which means he only had to
edit really simple templates
to build a basic site for his clients.
The other decided to code bespoke websites
from the ground up for larger clients
that wanted something more original.
Now, both are extremely
successful at what they do,
but they both serve
entirely different markets
at different price points.
You'd get paid more for a bespoke site.
However, this takes a
lot more time to learn.
I've paid anywhere
between 10,000 to $100,000
for custom websites in the past.
It's an absolute goldmine.
Level three, some skills, some money.
Once you work your way up to
this level of the pyramid,
you should have enough skills and money
to start making a great income.
The eighth side hustle is
selling digital products.
A friend of mine created a
bundle of templates for Instagram
and she sells them for $30 per download.
Last year, she made a
quarter of a million dollars,
which is pretty crazy.
A digital product could be many things,
from these Instagram templates
to eBooks and online courses.
If you invest your time making these,
then you can sell them year on year
and never ever run out of stock.
The reason you need some money
is for the advertising costs.
You could run Facebook or Instagram ads,
or even try out TikTok.
There are also some free ways
you can promote your products
such as affiliate marketing,
but this is harder to get going
if you don't already have
a steady stream of sales
and positive reviews.
If I was selling something tech related,
I'd reach out to YouTubers
such as Unbox Therapy
or Marques Brownlee who
have millions of subscribers
and offer them a percentage
of every sale they bring in.
Now, I'm not saying they
would definitely accept.
However, if you reach
out to enough people,
then you'll find collaborators
that are interested
in what you have to offer.
The ninth side hustle is
starting a software business.
To be fair, this isn't
really a side hustle,
but it is the fastest
way to become mega rich.
We recently chatted to Tim
Armoo who exited his business
for a rumored $40 million
before turning 28 years old.
I understand that this may seem
unattainable at the moment,
but I believe that most
entrepreneurs strive
to have some form of technology built
specifically for their businesses.
Tech businesses offer the
potential for significant profits
through huge exits.
But this opportunity
won't be around forever,
so it's important to get
started as soon as possible.
If you wanna know exactly
how I would make $10,000
in seven days, then you can
check out this video next,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay? (clicks tongue)
I'll see you over there.