Want to be rich?
Follow your passion
and you'll never work a day in your life.
This is terrible advice.
So is manifest your success, slow down,
follow the rules and learn to compromise.
In fact, this advice is
the complete opposite
of what actually leads to real success.
It's almost like these well known sayings
are designed to make you feel good,
but ultimately keep you poor.
I'm going to upset a
lot of online gurus here
with this video,
but if you are serious
about becoming rich,
then the people spouting this nonsense
are completely wasting your time.
Most of these people have
never actually made millions
or even worse they have, but
by pretending to be rich.
Look, I've been there and done it
and made a lot of money in the process.
So here's my five step anti-guru formula
which will actually help you become rich.
Step one, don't follow your passion.
Right, let's clear
something up right away.
Often when I say don't follow your passion
lots of people jump to the conclusion
that I'm telling people to
just focus on the money.
This is not the case.
I just fundamentally disagree
with the follow your passion advice.
It's very unclear,
it's highly self-centered,
and very impractical for many people.
Let's break down the issues one by one.
Firstly, the actual meaning of
the word passion is unclear.
It's just one of those fluffy words
that has no real universal definition.
I suppose the best place to
start is the Oxford Dictionary,
which says passion is a strong
and barely controllable emotion.
See what I mean?
It's extremely open for interpretation.
This makes it hard to tell the difference
between an impulsive short-lived interest
and a possible route to success.
The other interesting thing about passion
is that it fades, especially
if you turn it into a job.
This is because once you
get paid for something
that you used to do for fun,
it becomes an obligation
rather than a choice.
Once it fades, another
passion will probably pop up.
Now say you follow that new
passion and abandon the old one.
You've gotta start again from ground zero.
Now that's fine once or twice
and I've got friends that have done it.
But to become rich,
you need to get really good at something
and the only way to do this is
through hours of dedication.
Secondly, following your
passion is all about you
and not others.
The true secret to becoming rich
is to provide what the market
wants, not what you want.
Say you were extremely
passionate about paper airplanes,
it's gonna be really hard getting rich
doing this as a full-time job
because the market is so small.
That's why you have to make sure
there's an actual demand for what you do.
Otherwise, you can follow
your passion all you want,
but it won't make you wealthy.
The only person that cares
about your feelings is you
and maybe your family.
Thirdly, the most important
issue of them all.
Most people don't have a passion.
Look, I'm sick of all
this stereotypical advice.
Just do something for long enough,
this will lead to you becoming better
and ultimately you'll start to love it.
I know people that have worked
in an office job for 30 years
and while good at it,
they absolutely hate it.
So with that said, I'm gonna amend
follow your passion to what
Mark Cuban once suggested,
follow your effort.
Emotions are unreliable.
Cold hard facts aren't.
So if you really want to become rich,
then closely track where you freely choose
to apply your time and pursue that.
Time is your most valuable asset.
You can't make any more of it.
You dunno how much you have left
and you can never buy it back.
This means that tracking what you do
in your free time is a fantastic way
of identifying what you
actually care about,
but this is where you can fall
for the next bit of bad advice.
Step two, don't manifest success.
I'm sick and tired of
these people talking about
how manifestation changed their lives.
When you followed your effort,
the most dangerous thing you can do
is stop taking action
and start manifesting.
I now have everything I ever wanted.
But I'll let you into a
secret, I didn't manifest once.
Before you jump to the conclusion
that I'm saying self-belief
is useless, hear me out,
my main problem with manifestation
of fake guru, survivor bias,
and false expectations.
It's no secret the fake gurus
talk about manifestation nonstop.
Why do you think that is?
It's because it sells false hope,
which is a very profitable product.
They suck people in with the promise
that if they think hard enough,
then everything will be given
to them on a silver platter.
It's also very easy for them
to blame their customers
when their poorly made online course
doesn't deliver the promise results.
I can't tell you the amount of times
I've seen people complain
after buying one of these courses.
When they say something like,
"This didn't work for me."
Instead of receiving a refund,
they normally get an answer like,
"It's because you didn't
manifest hard enough."
This is exactly how most scams work.
They blame the customer.
It's not just these fake
gurus pushing this bad advice,
it's also the people that
it happened to work for.
One of the most famous
examples is Jim Carey,
who famously wrote himself
a $10 million check
before he achieved success.
Sometime later, he found
how he was cast in the movie
"Dumb and Dumber" for you
guessed it, $10 million.
A lot of people point
to this as an example
of manifestation working.
However, this is far more likely
due to the hundreds of other
things Jim Carey was doing.
There are probably
thousands of other stories
just like this one that
didn't have a happy ending,
but we'll never get to hear about those.
It just sets people up for
unrealistic expectation
and promotes the idea
that you can do nothing
and get results.
So once you're following your effort,
instead of spending your time manifesting,
you need to get your head
down and develop grits.
This means instead of giving
up when something goes wrong,
you see it as an opportunity
to learn and stay committed
to the long-term pursuit of your goals.
By developing grit, you
can build a resilience
and perseverance necessary
to achieve last in success.
Once you do this,
you'll have results that
will boost your confidence
and self-belief, which
is 10 times more powerful
than standing in front of the mirror
and repeating that you're
gonna be rich one day.
When you manage to get to this stage,
you'll probably notice people
starting to pull you back.
Which leads me to step three,
don't slow down.
Whoever tells you to slow down
is trying to stop you becoming successful.
Moving swiftly led me
to quicker solutions,
which resulted in me
making a lot more money.
But before you say it,
I'm not saying you shouldn't be patient.
There is a huge difference.
Let me explain.
You need to have a sense
of urgency in your life.
After all, we're only getting older
and your brain is only getting slower.
So its best to push yourself now
while you have the energy to do it.
Small actions lead to big outcomes
and the small things that you do each day
build on each other
and compound over time.
That's why you should take action now.
Phrases like, "If you
build it, they will come,"
are really misguiding as they suggest that
if you wait, then things will work out.
I get it.
Who doesn't want to believe
that when you build a great product
or offer a fantastic service,
as long as you wait long
enough, you'll become rich.
The truth is the world
doesn't work like that.
If you sit back and wait for
the money to start flowing in,
then it probably never will.
Taking your time will lead to you missing
your golden opportunity.
So don't listen to the people
that are holding you back.
If something needs to be done, do it.
There's no point waiting.
You need to move swiftly
with your actions,
but be patient with the results.
However, if you always do everything
the way other people expect,
then you will never reach
your true potential.
Which leads me onto step four,
don't follow the rules.
On my score report, it would
always say the same thing.
Mark has potential, but
he's highly disruptive.
I used to get told off for that.
However, if the same thing was
written on "Times" magazine
with a big picture of me
plastered on the front,
then I'll be celebrated for it.
The truth is, if you
do everything the same
as everyone else, then you
end up with the same results.
I like to think of it
as being a fisherman.
And instead of fishing
where everyone else does,
you decide to go off the beaten track
and find a hidden lake.
That's why when I opened my first shop,
I went back to my disruptive tendencies
and racked my brains for whatever I could
to do a bit differently
from my competitors.
That's when I came up with
this genius marketing strategy
to establish myself in the area.
In the dead of night, I
went around a neighborhood
with hundreds of signs and cable ties.
I stuck these signs up,
directing people towards my
shop from all directions.
It were at wonders.
About three months later, I got
a visit from the authorities
who asked me to remove the signs.
However, by that point,
they'd done their intended job
and now word of mouth was
already spreading about my shop.
You are competing against
a lot more people.
By breaking the rules,
you can quite often find a
lot of new opportunities.
Now you've followed your
effort, developed grit,
and broken the rules,
there is one more advice
trap you can fall into.
Step five, don't learn to compromise.
People say compromising is great.
You need to be able to find common ground
and negotiate with people in life
so that you can all get along
and come to the best solutions.
No, it's not.
That's not what compromising is.
Compromise is about reaching a settlement
that is often lower than the
standards you would expect,
whether or not it feels
the right thing to do.
I see compromise as another
word for mediocracy.
I get you may be thinking,
if you go through life
not listening to others,
then you're gonna come
across as a bit of a dick,
and I completely agree.
Other people may have
ideas and perspectives
that you haven't considered.
Learning from them is vital,
but that doesn't mean
you have to compromise.
There's a huge difference
between someone that
doesn't listen to others
because of their huge ego
and someone that listens
and weighs up their options.
As the author of "Narnia" C.S. Lewis
once wrote, "The safest road
to hell is the gradual one."
To me, this means the compromising
might seem like the easy way at first,
but it'll end up being a nightmare later
when you're too far down
the road to turn back.
You need to be open to ideas,
but close to compromises.
Ask yourself, how do you
want to be remembered
as a person who compromise
on their goals and dreams
doing things to make others
happy and avoid arguments
or the person who stood up
for what they believed in,
had a clear vision and live
their life on their terms.
If you'd like to know seven secrets
that will make you more money,
then you can watch this video next.
But don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.