- People are making thousands
of dollars in passive income
every month selling products
that don't even exist until
someone places an order.
- $34,000 per month.
- The realistic earnings
I've been able to make
with Print On Demand.
- Well over a million dollars.
- 63,000.
- [Narrator] $21,000 per month,
multiple six figures in profit.
(tape rewinding)
- But is this actually
a realistic side hustle
and possible for anyone to do?
Well, as an experienced
millionaire businessman,
I'm gonna put this to
the test myself by making
and selling my own
print on demand product.
As this is a side hustle challenge,
I'm setting myself the usual rules.
Rule one, I must sell under a fake name.
Rule two, I can't spend more than $0
and rule three, I must launch
the business within 24 hours.
Start the timer.
The first thing on my plan is
to find a supplier with easy
to use software.
For anyone who doesn't know
how print on demand works,
here's a very quick breakdown.
You make a design and
partner with a company,
and in return, they print
and ship your product
when someone buys it.
This means if we execute
everything correctly,
then all we have to do
is collect our paycheck.
So I'm just gonna make a
free account with Gelato
as they seem to have
fulfillment centers all
around the world, and from what I can see,
have the most straightforward
software for me to use.
Right, so now we need to decide what kind
of product we want to sell.
There are lots of
different products perfect
for print on demand, such
as t-shirts, mugs, and bags.
But instead of just guessing,
I'm gonna do some market research
to find out what's actually selling well.
I like to use TikTok
for this kind of thing,
as lots of people are using it
to promote their print on demand stores
because they have an
integrated shop feature.
You've probably seen the little banner
that pops up at the bottom
of some Tiktoks giving you the option
to buy what's in the video.
Honestly, my son's girlfriend has bought
so much on TikTok shop.
I'm not just looking for one-off videos.
I want to find an account
that consistently sells the same product.
If someone is investing their time
in creating multiple
videos, it's safe to assume
that the product is selling well.
(dramatic music)
Right, I think I've found the
perfect product, wall art.
Firstly, based on what
I've seen on TikTok,
there's a large market
of aspiring entrepreneurs
who love putting motivational
artwork on their walls
to keep themselves
motivated and working hard.
Secondly, wall art is very cheap to make,
but it seems from my
research that I can sell it
for a high price as it's
more of an impulse purchase.
This means that my profit
margins will be very good
as I'll make more money per sale.
And thirdly, there are
so many different ways
I can scale this business.
Just think if I grew it big enough,
I could even branch out
into premium artwork
that wealthy people can
hang in their mansions.
Imagine how much I could sell those for,
but I'm getting a bit
ahead of myself here.
First, we need to make
some designs, right?
I've got a confession to
make, and I'm not proud of it.
As you know, I'm under a time limit here,
and I don't really have enough hours left
to make my own designs and do
everything else on my list.
If I was a bit younger,
then I could probably use
an AI tool like Midjourney
to create the wall art for me.
But you guys know I'm a boomer,
so it would take me a little
while to get the hang of it,
and time isn't something
I have lots of right now.
That doesn't mean I'm
about to die, by the way.
So long story short,
I've ordered five different
wall art designs from three
different sellers on Fiverr.
I sent them all this brief.
I would like you to create
an entrepreneurial poster
that could be framed and used as wall art.
Please come up with your
own quote, idea and theme.
I think something entrepreneurial
and motivational would be best.
I intend on using the poster
size 30 by 40 centimeters.
That's 12 inches by 16 inches
for all our American viewers.
I look forward to seeing the design.
This is gonna be pretty interesting
as I really don't have
time to make any changes,
and I'm kind of leaving
my fate in their hands.
While we're waiting for
those designs to come back,
let's use this opportunity
to make an online store.
I've decided I'm gonna sell on Etsy
as it's relatively simple and
has a low barrier to entry.
Platforms like this are
great as they already have an
established customer
base for you to tap into.
The downside is that it's
often erased at the bottom
as your product is
nothing but a commodity,
and it's only compared on price.
Although my designs are
unique, there are still a lot
of people selling similar products.
If you wanna build a business
that stands to test the time,
I suggest heading over
to something like Shopify
and creating your own store.
(bright music)
So it's the next morning,
and I've been sent some designs to review.
I haven't looked at them yet,
so let's look at 'em together.
Actually, I quite like this one.
The design looks pretty cool,
and the quote is very true.
I'll tell you what, if I had a penny
for every time someone said
my success was due to luck
and not hard work, then I'd be rich.
Oh, wait, I am.
This next guy seems to have
made five different designs.
Let's take a look.
Honestly, these designs
do look pretty basic,
and the quotes are just
stating the obvious.
The only one I really
like is the last one,
and even that looks like something
I could have done in two minutes.
Okay, so it's all riding
on this last seller.
This is actually my
favorite design so far.
This next one, I'm not so keen on,
but I can see is at least try to play
with the text a little bit.
Maybe this'll appeal to the
girls as it's got that sort
of swirly font.
I think they like that sort of thing.
Right, now we've gotta upload
these designs onto Gelato.
Since this is a print on demand
product, I don't have to pay
for anything until a sale is made.
So this is great if you're
starting out with $0.
So I'm just gonna go to the
menu on the left hand side
and select product catalog.
As you can see, there are a
lot of different options here,
but I'm of course going
to select wall art.
So this pulls up a selection
of different types of posters.
Now I'm gonna pick wooden framed posters.
I'm then gonna go with the
premium matte paper option,
as I can see that this is the best seller.
And to be honest, I don't
think people are really be able
to tell the difference between this
and the museum quality one,
but my profits certainly will.
So I'm gonna select 30 by 40 centimeters
as I think this is the best
size poster for most houses,
and it seems to be the
size most people select.
Then I'm gonna pick vertical
and a black frame color
as that's pretty sort
of gender neutral and ready
to hang because not assembled.
- Ain't nobody got time for that.
- I'm just gonna repeat the
steps with all my designs,
including the ones I didn't like.
After all, I've got nothing to lose,
and who knows, I might even sell some.
(tape rewinding)
Now I've got all the designs uploaded.
I'm gonna go over to the
menu and select stores.
This is where you can
link your Gelato account
with your Etsy store.
If you don't wanna sell
on Etsy, as you can see,
there are lots of
different options, right?
I could just upload
the designs from Fiverr
right onto my Etsy listing.
But to be honest, they
don't look very premium.
So I'm gonna use the built-in mockup
studio by clicking here.
This tool will help me
bring the posters to life.
First, we just have to set the
dimensions for our file size.
Oh, they have actually
on here an Etsy preset,
so I'm gonna just select that.
But you can also set
custom sizes if you'd like
to create mockups for things
like Instagram stories.
Now we need to select
a scene for our mockup.
Oh, now that one looks good.
So let's go with that.
You can zoom in and move around the scene
by just double clicking on it.
So I'm gonna adjust it to make
the scene a little bit bigger
so there's more focus on my poster design.
Next, let's select our poster size.
I'm gonna set it to 30 by 40.
As I said before, most
poster designs are this size.
These are looking pretty good.
Now, the last step, before
we can sell our wall art,
setting a price.
I've just taken a quick look
at the Price Navigator tool,
and in here it lays out exactly
what the product costs, how
much shipping will set us back,
and even the total profit per sale.
Looking at all of this, I think
a good price would be 49.99.
This is a bit high compared
to most competitors on Etsy,
which will definitely impact sales,
but I'm willing to take a bit of a risk
because I always think
a nice profit margin
is around 50%.
(bell ringing)
(bright music)
Right, so I'm over in Miami on business,
but I've been keeping an eye
on our side hustle challenge,
and I'll tell you what,
I've got some results,
but before I share them
with you, check this out.
I actually ordered a
couple of our products
and got them shipped to
me over here in the USA,
and I think they're pretty good,
and the quality as well
is absolutely fantastic.
I think I'm gonna keep these.
Actually, I'm really impressed
with the shipping time as well.
It took three days to get these to us,
which is far better than
the Chinese drop shippers,
and that should give us an advantage.
I'd actually always recommend
ordering your product
before you start selling it,
because reputation is everything
and you don't want customers
speaking negatively about your product.
So I've left it just a few more days
because things were going nicely.
Now, for the moment you've
all been waiting for,
did we make any sales?
Well, yes and no.
Some of the posters generated a few sales
and some didn't even catch a bite.
Overall, we generated 11
saless, which led to 549.89.
But of course, this isn't all profit.
First, we had to pay
for designs on Fiverr,
which was 60.77.
Then Etsy take a small cut of
6.5% on each sale, which came
to 35.74, and let's not forget the product
and shipping costs, which came to 371.69.
By the way, as I use
Gelato a lot in this video,
I reached out to them and
asked them if they could
give you guys some kind
of discount on these fees.
They agreed, so with the
link in the description,
you can get 50% off your first order.
With all those expenses
deducted, it leaves us
with a grand total of 81.69.
Considering that I
accomplished all the setup
within 24 hours and now have the designs,
I'll consider this a success.
This means I can continue
selling these products
over the next few weeks with
minimal additional expenses.
If you guys would be
interested in seeing a part two
where I allow myself more
time to revamp the business
and see how far I can take it,
let me know in the comments.
If you wanna know how to
sell blank books on Amazon,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.