I remember leaving school at 16
without a penny in my pocket.
I was struggling
day-to-day to pay my bills
and falling deeper and deeper into debt.
I was earning less than $2 an hour
working day and night
just to make ends meet.
I wanted to be rich so badly,
but felt like it was
never gonna happen to me.
Little did I know there
was some clear signs
that I was going to become rich
and I've seen this time and
time again over the years
when helping others achieve their goals.
In the past, I've used these
signs as a little checklist
to see if it's worth mentoring someone.
So grab a pen and paper and
let's see how many you have.
Let me know in the comments
if you check all seven.
Number one, you know that the phrase,
"Money won't fix your
problems," is a load of rubbish.
There's nothing worse
than someone rich saying,
"Money won't fix your problems."
Trust me, I've been there.
You see, I believe there are
two different types of problems
we all face.
The first type is your basic needs.
These are things like water,
housing, healthcare, and food.
Now, if you are facing
the first type of problems
then the answer to all of these is clear.
You need to earn more money.
Everything you are stressing
about can be solved with more money.
When you fix the basic needs,
your focus shifts onto type two,
which is the abstract problems.
These are things money definitely
can't fix such as love,
happiness, and fulfillment.
For me, that's always been
about spending time with my
family, enjoying my hobbies,
my interests and running a business
that I'm truly passionate about.
So you can definitely be broke, but happy.
You can also be rich, but sad.
However, wouldn't you
prefer to be rich and happy?
The puppet masters have
brainwashed everyday people
into believing that they
don't actually want money
or while they trade years of their life
working a job they hate for a tiny salary.
If I see that someone actually
buys into the thinking
that money isn't
desirable then I can't see
how they're ever gonna
make enough to be rich.
Even when I was completely broke,
I didn't ever think this way.
If you are able to ignore all of this
then you're on the right track.
Number two, when you see an
obstacle, you overcome it.
Successful people focus
on the opportunities
rather than the things holding them back.
Now is one of the best times
to start a new side hustle
as there are so many different
industries booming online.
Let's say you have the
most amazing business idea
that has the potential to
make you millions of dollars,
but you never act on it
because too many things
are standing in your way.
How much is that idea
actually worth to you?
Well, the answer is absolutely nothing
if you're not going to work on it.
Have you ever chatted with
a friend and they say,
"You know what?
I've got the best business
idea in the world."
They're extremely motivated,
certain that this will make
them richer than rich itself.
You then meet up with them
six months later down the line
and you ask them, "How's
everything going?"
And you're really excited for them.
"Oh, I haven't started yet."
And the reason is,
"Oh, because the government,
my job, the economy."
They've got excuse after excuse.
The list goes on and on.
When most people see a problem
they say it's bad luck.
They quit and they stop trying.
When rich people run into problems
they might scratch
their heads for a while,
but they don't give up.
They strike when they
have the most passion
and the most motivation.
The longer you leave an idea
stuck up here in your head
the longer you'll have
time to convince yourself
that it'll never work.
So if you are the type to just get going
and sort the problems as you go,
then there's a high
chance you'll become rich.
Number three, you prioritize
buying assets when possible.
When was the last time you
thought about buying something
and took the time to decide if the item
was gonna help bring money into your life
or drain money away from your life?
We're constantly living on a seesaw.
On one side, you've got
fancy cars, designer clothes,
and unnecessary gadgets.
On the other side we've
got rental properties,
watches, and stocks.
By taking advantage of when
the economy is on its knees
and buying up lots of long-term assets,
you can easily set yourself up financially
for the rest of your life.
The first $100,000 is the
hardest money you'll ever earn.
The truth is that getting
your money to work for you
and not the other way around
is the only way to achieve
real long-term wealth.
I'm sure you've heard this before.
However, I know that sometimes
it can feel less scary
just letting your money
sit in a savings account
rather than investing it elsewhere.
If this is how you feel
then money market funds
might be a good option for you.
They normally have better interest rates
than savings accounts
while not being as risky
as investing in stocks.
Instead, these money market
funds invest in high quality,
short term debt from governments,
banks, or corporations.
I like investing some of my money
in these funds on Lightyear
because I can easily draw
it out when I need to
rather than having to worry
about the ups and downs
of the stock market.
The interest, otherwise known as the yield
is paid into my account on
the first of every month.
However, the interest
amount does change daily
so it's not super predictable
just like the British weather.
You can do the same if you live in the UK
or one of these countries because on apps
like the one I just
mentioned called Lightyear,
you have access to AAA rated
BlackRock money market funds
and can start investing from
just one pound, Euro or dollar.
So if this interests you feel
free to use my code Tilbury
to get a free $10 fractional share
when you sign up for Lightyear.
Using this affiliate link and code
is also a great way to
support this channel
as I'm able to put the
commissions we receive
into creating more videos.
And let me remind you
investing always carries a risk
and the value of any investment
can decrease as well as increase.
So be sure to invest wisely
and do your research.
Number four, you know there
is so much more to learn.
How many people do you know
that when they have a couple of days off
or during the evening
spend all their spare time
playing video games and watching Netflix?
I'm willing to bet quite a few.
Look, there is nothing wrong
with binging a TV series
once in a while.
I'm talking about the people
that don't watch or read
anything educational.
They falsely believe
that education stops
when you leave school.
To be honest these people
are extremely arrogant
and they don't know it.
They think getting rich is down to luck
because they haven't learned enough
to spot the strategic steps
that every self-made millionaire takes.
They would rather critique others
and then escape to a fantasy land
where they don't have to
think about their problems.
But you know what?
Ignoring your problems just
makes them bigger and bigger.
The strange thing about learning
is that the more we learn
the more we know how much
we don't actually know.
It's about learning things
you never knew before
and then turning those newly learned ideas
into action in your own life.
Think of life like a video game.
It's never a bad time to arm yourself.
So people that read those books
and watch educational videos on YouTube
are at such an advantage.
People will say, "You just got lucky."
That's what they said to me.
But the truth is luck is when
opportunity meets preparation.
So never stop equipping
yourself with the knowledge
and prepare yourself to be one
of the luckiest people alive.
Number five, you don't
compare yourself to others.
Comparing ourselves to others
and trying to keep up with their success
without fully understanding
their situation
can cause us to make some silly decisions
in the heat of the moment.
Let's take Tiger Woods for example.
He spent years learning
and perfecting his skills.
He's now worth millions of dollars.
Now, I love my golf,
but if I was to compare my skills to his,
I'd look pretty awful.
But just because I don't measure up
doesn't mean I should stop playing golf.
I shouldn't get depressed
or jealous or resentful
because if I was to put Tiger Woods
in charge of my radio control
model and design business
then I doubt the models would even fly.
Comparing yourself to others
is literally a shortcut to inaction.
Number six, you spend time with winners.
Back when I was in my early twenties,
look, I know that was a little while ago,
I supplied some products
to one of the richest guys in the UK.
I was so surprised that
he was such a normal,
down to earth guy, yet he'd
managed to strike it big.
We had coffee and we chatted
about life and everything
really and it opened my eyes
to the need for multiple
passive income streams.
This is now more important than ever
because if you were to
hang out with losers
talking negatively about the
state of the economy, bad luck,
everything's going
wrong, blah, blah, blah,
you'll likely end up doing the same thing.
If, however, you start hanging
around with individuals
that are continually talking about success
and business opportunities,
the chances are it's gonna rub off on you.
Number seven, you have
truckloads of confidence.
Have you ever complimented someone
on doing something really well
and they sort of look down
and mumble something like,
"Oh, it was nothing.
I thought I should have done a bit better.
Oh, I made a few mistakes."
Maybe they don't like to
blow their own trumpet
because they don't want to
look cocky or I don't know,
they lack self-confidence
by downplaying their skills.
They make others think they're worthless.
This is even more important
when you have a side hustle
or a high paid job because
the more confident you can be,
the more confident your clients
or your team will be in your abilities.
There isn't much money
going around at the moment
so the more confident
everyone is in your abilities
the better you're gonna do.
Confidence also allows you
to take calculated risks.
As you know, you can come out
the other side with even more.
For example let's say you won
half a million dollars on a lottery
and this was your favorite
car, the Lamborghini Aventador.
Now a person with low confidence
would probably spend it all on the car
because that's what they've
always wanted all their life
as they feel this will
give them validation.
They've dreamed of buying this car
and they feel that they'll
never have enough money
to be able to afford it ever again.
They go out and buy the
car and get an instant rush
and feeling of great, I've
got what I've always wanted.
A confident person would
believe in their ability
to make more money and
instead of spending it
would use it to their advantage.
So the confident person
decides to invest every penny
so that their wealth grows.
Maybe in stocks and shares,
maybe in a side hustle,
or maybe in real estate.
Or even by using the
link in the description
to get 16 free stocks worth
between two and $2,000
in return for signing up for Moomoo.
It's basically free money
and they're a great investing platform.
Let's fast forward a year
or two down the line.
If you lacked confidence
then you'd have none
of your winnings left.
All you'd be left with is
a depreciating dream car
losing money week after week.
You'd probably be desperate to sell it now
that the initial rush has worn off.
Whereas if you're confident
from the beginning
then you would have all your winnings left
plus more from the growth
of your investments.
Using your profits you
could then look to buy
a pre-owned Lamborghini
Aventador for at least 50% off.
The person with the confidence
ends up with everything
he ever wanted and more.
Even though they both started off
with the same amount of money.
If you wanna know exactly
how to start investing for a beginner,
then I'm gonna leave
that video right there.
But don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you wanna grow your wealth.
Okay? I'll see you over there.