This is the best piece
of advice I've ever heard
about building a high net worth.
It came from a millionaire
I looked up to as a kid,
and it stuck with me ever since.
I was worrying that I'd
never have enough money
to afford the things that I'd
always dreamed about having.
His exact words to me were,
"Don't worry about earning millions;
instead, focus on the
first 100,000 because,
after that, your net worth will go crazy.
I didn't fully understand him at the time,
but I did what he said, and
lo and behold, it worked.
So why is the first $100K the hardest?
Well, there are two main reasons for this.
The first one is your earning power.
Think of this like your
level in a video game.
You just haven't been playing long enough
to build up your skills and, therefore,
can't compete with the
more experienced players.
This is the exact same
when it comes to making
money when you're younger.
This issue is actually getting even worse.
A recent study found that Gen Z
have about 86% less buying
power than my generation,
the boomers, did at the same age.
This is partly due to older people
staying in the workforce for longer,
meaning that higher-paid
positions are harder to come by.
But it isn't all doom and gloom,
as the internet offers a
great way for younger people
to make far more money
than the older generation,
as most of them don't
understand how to use Instagram,
let alone build an online side hustle.
When it comes to tech, there
aren't that many boomers
that can keep up with
you guys, not like me.
The second reason your
first $100K is the hardest
is your lack of compound interest.
Think of your money like a snowball.
You roll it down a hill
by investing money,
and as it rolls, it picks up more snow,
which is your compound interest.
The bigger your snowball gets,
the more snow it collects and, therefore,
the more compound interest you make.
Sounds amazing, right?
Well, yes and no. Let me explain.
Right now, if you don't
have at least $100K,
then your snowball isn't big enough
for it to pick up any significant income.
You essentially can't really
benefit from compound interest.
I mean, let's say you invest
$10K in an S&P 500 Index fund
and get an average yearly return of 7%,
which has historically been the
amount investors can expect.
After five years,
your money will have grown
from $10,000 into $14,176.
That's five whole years to earn $4,176.
That's why it's so hard
to reach the first $100K.
It's all about how much you can contribute
to your investing pot
rather than how much compound
interest you're making.
This means you're gonna
have to make more money
any way you can.
Honestly, it was no different for me.
I remember doing at least
three different side
hustles at the same time
in order to earn enough money.
Working this many hours
and also resisting the urge
to spend it on vacations
and the latest designer
clothes is really a killer.
But trust me, it's worth it,
as once you hit that first $100K,
it's way, way, way easier
to grow your money.
So why does net worth go crazy
after a $100K? The answer.
Because compound interest
stops being lame,
and it actually starts to
sound pretty unbelievable.
Take a look at this chart.
If you invest $10K annually
with a 7% average yearly return,
going from naught to $100K
will take 7.84 years.
However, going from $100K to
$200K will only take 5.1 years.
So, overall, it'll take 2.74 years less
to make the second $100K
compared to the first.
That's 35% faster
to make your second 100
grand than the first,
and it gets even better.
If we expand things,
to go from $200K to $300K
only takes 3.78 years.
Then $300K to $400K takes three years,
and $400K to 500,000 is only 2.5 years.
We could keep going, but
I think you get the idea.
Just look at how the
chart starts to go crazy.
But it all happens after the first $100K.
Getting that chunk of money as
fast as possible is the key.
Just think, if you can
shave just a couple of years
off how long it takes you
to reach that $100K mark,
how much quicker you'll
become a millionaire.
Once you get to this point,
it's almost inevitable
that you'll be wealthy
if you just invest in
a low-cost index fund.
If all you wanted to do
was save up this $100K
and invest it in an S&P 500 Index fund
and never invest again,
let's say, I don't know,
you completely forgot about the account,
you would still become a
millionaire within 33 years.
That's how powerful compound interest is
once you've made that first $100K.
So, how do you make your first $100K?
Well, all you need to do is
follow the Growth Method.
I actually came up with this myself,
and it helped me in those
early days of wealth building,
so hopefully it can help you, too.
The G stands for gain
control of your finances.
There's one way and one
way only to gain control,
and that's budgeting.
Yep, I said it. Now, don't get it twisted.
Budgeting isn't a rule book
designed to stop you having fun.
It's more like a guide which navigates you
towards more informed choices.
I'm not saying you have to be
super frugal with your money,
but you do need to
understand the difference
between your needs and your wants.
The R stands for root your investments.
Let's say you invest $250 a
month in an S&P 500 Index fund
and get an average yearly return of 7%:
in 40 years, you'll have $656K.
But what's even more impressive
is that $536K of this
is from compound interest.
In other words,
you only have to put in
$120K of it yourself.
I know what you're probably thinking,
"That's all well and
good, but by that time,
I'll be over 60 years old and
dribbling into my dinner."
I fully understand.
That's why if you can get
this first $100K invested
as soon as possible,
then you'll do much
better than this example.
Now you're making some money,
you need to focus on the O,
which stands for optimize
your tax management.
It might sound fancy, but, in reality,
it's as simple as this: avoid paying tax.
Now, let me make something very clear.
Tax avoidance is completely fine
and something that smart people do.
Tax evasion, on the other hand,
is illegal and not what I'm talking about.
"But, Mark, if you're earning more,
you should pay more tax."
I agree with you,
and the rich do pay the
majority of the taxes.
But there should also be an incentive
for someone to become an entrepreneur
as they provide jobs
for the rest of society,
and luckily, there is.
Entrepreneurs are taxed
off the profits they make
at the end of each year,
which means they can deduct
expenses from their earnings.
These are called write-offs.
This is different from an employee
as they're taxed off their monthly salary.
So, say you're really passionate
about the latest tech,
like the new iPhone;
you could start a YouTube
channel reviewing gadgets,
and once it's generating you money,
you could deduct the
cost of your tech items
from your profit and get them tax-free.
Essentially, the government has helped you
to pay for the item you want.
However, you can only
do this within reason.
Your business or side hustle
has to have a need for this item.
In other words, it must
be a justifiable expense.
That's why starting your
business around your passion
can be a great way to save a lot of tax.
It's what I did with my
radio controlled model shops,
and my son also does with
his video production company.
If this sounds interesting to you,
we're gonna be talking
about this even more
in my $2K Challenge
I'm running on Discord.
I'll leave a link in the description
if you wanna save your spot.
It's completely free, and
there's even opportunities
to win some great prizes.
So next up, we have W: weed out debts.
Did you know the average
American carries $21,800 of debt?
So, if you're in debt,
then you're not alone.
As soon as possible,
list out all your debts
and prioritize them based
on their interest rates.
So, all the debts that you own
with the highest interest rates
are the ones you need to tackle first.
This is the dark side
of compound interest.
If you don't understand it,
then it can actually
start to work against you.
Think of it like the hot sun
beating down on the snow
you're trying to collect
to make your first $100K.
If you have too much debt melting it away,
then you are never gonna get to the stage
where your money is working for you.
So my advice for this one
is to make tiny snowflake
payments where possible
because every little helps.
Don't give up, though,
because neglecting your debt
will cause you a lot of
stress in the future.
So, although it feels like
you're losing money from the payments,
think of it as an investment
towards your first $100K.
T stands for tap into
additional streams of income.
Yes, I'm talking about
starting a side hustle.
As of 2023, 50% of Americans
have a side hustle,
even if they earn over $100K per year.
A side hustle gives
you multiple advantages
by diversifying your income.
You'll have more money
to put into your tax advantage
account, so more investments.
And, again, you're just adding
more snow to your snowball,
allowing for compound
interest to take its course.
H stands for heightened self-discipline.
To put all these things
we've discussed into effect,
you need to find your inner discipline.
Discipline is the currency of success.
The more you mint, the wealthier
your future will become.
If you wanna know how to
build your wealth from $0,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there.
But don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if you
wanna grow your wealth, okay?
I'll see you over there.