This is my father, Mervin Tilbury.
He's one of the hardest
working people I know,
and as a kid,
I remember him working in a
factory job making cable ties
and a side hustle cutting grass,
so he could provide for me and
my mom and my three sisters.
He'd stash away any extra money
he made in a shoebox as well
as a bank account that
paid little to no interest,
hoping that one day he could quit his job
working in the factory.
When my uncle invested some
of his money in the stock market,
my dad said it was an
extremely risky move.
Unfortunately, what my dad didn't realize
is that he was also playing a risky game.
Can you see where this story's going?
Every year, my father's money
was losing value due to inflation.
This is just what happens over time.
As more money is printed,
the money in circulation
becomes less valuable.
This meant he was never able
to quit his job in the factory.
The thought of my money being eaten
away by inflation scared me so much
that I've made sure to
invest throughout my life.
As a result, not only
have I beaten inflation,
but my investments actually now grow
by around $17,000 a week on their own,
which over my lifetime
has made me millions.
I'm no financial advisor,
but I am someone that's
been there and done it.
That's why I'm making this video.
It's exactly what I wish
I had when I was younger.
How can I make money investing in stocks?
To make money,
we first need to beat the inflation issue.
In the last 60 years,
this average is out to
a rate of 3.8% per year.
So if your money isn't growing
by more than this on its own,
then you're getting poorer by the second.
In a perfect world, you
would have a savings
account that provides an average return
of eight to 10% every year,
so that you can both beat
inflation and earn some profit.
Unfortunately, such savings
accounts don't exist.
However, you can achieve returns
like this by investing
in the stock market.
A stock is a small part of a
company and when you buy it
you become a shareholder, and
when you're a shareholder,
there are two ways you can make money.
Firstly, if the price
of the stock goes up
during the time you own it,
you can sell it for more than you paid.
Secondly, you can receive dividends.
Dividends are regular
payments to shareholders.
Not all stocks pay
dividends, but if they do,
this means that you can receive money
without ever selling your stock.
The magic really starts to
happen when you own a bunch
of stocks that grow at an
average of 10% per year,
because the interest applied
becomes larger and larger.
This is called compound
interest, and I have to admit,
a guilty pleasure of mine is messing
around with online compound
interest calculators.
Let's do one now.
If you were able to invest $250 per month,
at an 8% annual return,
in 42 years, you'd be a millionaire
and if you continue to do
this for another 10 years,
you would actually have over
2 million in your account.
Of course, if you wanted
to invest even more
then that would just speed up the process.
This is all based
on historical average data
and it isn't guaranteed,
but it's certainly been my experience.
So as you can see, the
real secret ingredient
to this millionaire formula is time,
which brings me onto when
should I start investing.
The short answer to this
is as soon as possible.
The younger you start, the better.
As you're giving your
investments more time
to grow and compound.
This also means you can take more risk,
as your investments have time to recover
if a stock market crash happens
and it will happen, it always happens,
but life isn't as easy as
this, as there are often things
in the way preventing you from investing.
So here's how I would structure things.
First, you need to make sure you've paid
off all high interest
debt like credit cards.
Just think about it.
There's no point trying to
make 10% in the stock market,
if you are paying 15% to
a credit card company.
Secondly, build up an emergency fund.
This should be enough to
cover three to six months
of your living expenses.
This way, you are not
forced to sell your stocks
in the event of an emergency
which can really ruin your progress.
Once you've done both of these things,
you are ready to start investing.
If you are younger than 18,
then it would be a great
idea to ask a parent to open
up a custodial account, which
allows them to invest for you.
This will give you such an
advantage in the future.
Your next question is probably something
along the lines of how
much should I invest?
When you ask an investor,
they'll probably say as much as possible.
However, I have a different opinion.
I made most of my money
through starting different businesses
and only use the stock market
to grow my wealth over time.
I've also had a pretty fun life
from flying full-size
airplanes and racing cars
to competing for my country
and traveling the world.
If I'd invested all of that
money into the stock market,.
then I'd have missed out on so much.
So my answer would be
to invest whatever you
feel comfortable with, but if
you want a more solid answer
then a 70/20/10 rule
is a pretty good guide.
It states that you should split your money
by these percentages,
70% on living expenses,
20% on investments, and
10% on the fun stuff.
Research shows that people who invest
at this level are much better
equipped to ride the ups
and downs of life and also
get ahead of everyone else.
That's all well and good,
but how do I buy a stock?
There are various different apps out there
that allow you to invest in stocks.
I'll leave some links below.
The key is to open the
correct type of account.
You'll often hear people
throwing around the terms,
ROTH IRA, in the USA and
stocks and shares ISA
in the UK, TFSA in Canada
and supers in Australia.
If you don't have one of these accounts
then you're missing out
as they allow you to avoid
paying taxes on your investments,
but they do have limits
because they're so powerful.
A great thing about these
investing apps is they
actually give you the ability
to buy fractional shares.
So rather than buying a
share of Apple for $190,
you can invest as little as $1.
I wish I had this option
when I was younger,
as it would've allowed me
to get some early investing experience
without having to take any big risks.
One of my favorite investing
platforms is Trading 212,
as they do both of these things.
Since I was planning to
talk about their app anyway,
I reached out to see
if they'd be interested
in sponsoring this portion of the video.
They agreed and are also
offering a free stock worth up
to £100 to anyone that uses the code
Tilbury when they create an account.
One of the really cool things
about Trading 212 is they
let you practice investing
with fake money so you can get familiar
with real data from the markets
without risking any money.
So if you're a little
uncomfortable with investing,
or just want to try some strategies
before putting your own money on the line,
this is a great way to get started.
Another great feature is called Pies,
where you can see how other investors
have allocated their money
into different stocks.
If you wanted to invest
100$ into that pie,
then it would just be
split amongst the various
allocations that that
pie creator has chosen.
If you live in the UK or Europe,
it's worth trying out
Trading 212 because signing
up is completely free and
there are no commissions.
Of course, don't forget
to use the code Tilbury
and you'll receive a free share worth
up to a hundred pounds.
Or alternatively, click
the link in a description
to sign up and see exactly
how to access the free share.
Now, the obvious next question
is how do I pick the best stocks?
There are two main ways to attempt
to predict the stock market.
These are called technical
and fundamental analysis.
A good way to think about
this is like a scale.
Usually short-term day
traders are purely focused
on the technical aspects.
This includes looking
at charts and patterns.
They believe they can predict
how the stock will change
in price by judging the highs
and the lows on the graphs.
As a long-term investor,
my strategy is about keeping it simple.
Lots of people talk about
using margin and options,
but that's really not
something I worry about.
I'm a lot more focused on the
fundamentals of a company.
This includes the
financials, the leadership,
and the brand recognition,
as I believe this is
where the true information
lies to indicate the
long-term success of a stock.
When I invest in a stock,
I don't have an intention
of selling it for at
least two to five years.
However, like I mentioned, it's a scale,
so I do look at the occasional chart
in order to find the best time to buy.
This approach has helped
me find some really
good investments over the
years rather than just dipping
in and out, trying to
make a profit every day.
But with the majority of my investments
I don't actually do any of this.
That's because I allocate most
of my money to index funds.
This is definitely the best
strategy for most people.
So what's an index fund?
It's a way for the average
person to make more money
than the professionals
with very little effort.
I'm a big football fan
and if you've ever followed any sports,
you'll be familiar with
a lead table like this.
The better your team performs,
the higher up they'll be on the list.
On the other hand, if
they do really badly,
they might be removed
from the league entirely.
This is almost exactly
the same as an index.
All you have to do is switch
out the teams for companies.
Let's take the S&P 500 for example.
This is a list of around 500
of the largest public companies
in the USA, the big dogs
being Amazon, Google,
Apple and Tesla.
Just like the league table,
if a company does poorly,
then they run the risk of being removed
from the list.
With this league table
or index of companies.
You could go and buy stocks
in some of them individually.
However, if something bad happens
to those companies that you've picked,
then you can wave goodbye to your money.
The idea of an index fund
is to be a little bit sneaky
as it allows you to invest
in every single company on
the list with just one click.
Even if a few companies do
terribly, then it's balanced
out by all the companies
doing extremely well.
The average annual return of the S&P 500
over the last 10 years has been 13.6%.
Although this is slightly higher
than the average over time
no one has ever lost any
money if they've bought
and held an S&P 500 index
fund for more than 20 years.
The truth is
that the average actively
managed fund return 2% less
per year than the market in general.
This means that the professionals
on average are doing worse
than index funds, and even if
they end up losing you money,
they still charge you
high fees no matter what.
The reason that index funds
can charge really low fees
is because they're passively managed,
which means they look after themselves
and don't need an expert
to keep adjusting them.
Meaning the fees can be
as low as 0.02% per year.
When I tell people about index funds,
it often blows their minds.
However, when they go
onto an investing app,
they get confused at the
different options and ask
what's the best index fund to invest in?
Well, as I said, I'm
not a financial advisor,
but I have had a lot
of success with three
different types of index funds.
Number one tracks the S&P 500 index.
This is the one we
briefly mentioned before.
The historical return
of eight to 10% has allowed
me to generate a fortune
over the years.
This is due to the power
of compound interest.
The S&P 500 tracks 11
different industries/sectors
and no sector is more
than 30% of the index.
However, it is worth pointing out
that it's a bit tech heavy these days,
with five tech stocks dominating
23% of the entire fund.
It's up to you if you see this
as a positive or a negative.
I personally don't mind
as I believe in the future of technology.
There are so many different
index funds that track
the S&P 500, so here are
some of my favorites.
The best I found in the USA
is the V-FIAX Index Fund or the VOO ETF.
The best in the UK would
probably be the VUSA ETF.
The only real difference
between an index fund
and an ETF is that the
ETF can be purchased
or sold at any time throughout the day.
Just like a stock,
index funds can only be purchased in full.
So for example,
if the price is $500, you must pay $500.
An ETF on the other hand,
can be purchased in fractional shares,
which means you don't
have to buy a full share
and instead you can invest
whatever amount you like.
This is great if you just starting
out or want to dollar cost average in.
Personally, I've set up a
direct debit every month
so the money leaves my bank account
without me even noticing.
Really and truly, there
isn't a huge difference
between an index fund and an ETF.
Just consider which one is
best for you, take the plunge.
Number two is a total stock market index.
The total stock market
index has returned investors
an average of 13% each year
over the last 10 years,
which isn't bad at all.
It's the definition of diversification.
You can't really get any more skin
in the game for a lower cost.
If you want to invest
for a long period of time
without having to even check
or even think about it,
then this is most likely the fund for you.
Investing in everything means
you can experience gains
across the entire market,
and unless a crazy crash happens,
you should be okay,
but even if it does crash, with time,
things tend to bounce back.
I've seen three crashes
since I've been an investor,
the.com bubble, the 2008 financial crisis,
and the 2020 COVID crash.
I'm not going to pretend
these crashes didn't hurt,
but long term
every market I've invested
in has bounced back.
The downside to this index is it depends
on the entire market trending upwards.
This means there could
be an individual stock
that you really believe
in that goes to the moon,
but you might not experience those gains
because that stock doesn't play much
of a role within the index fund.
The best I found in the
USA is the VTSAX Index Fund
and the VTI ETF
and the best in the UK is the VWRL ETF.
Number three is the
emerging markets index.
Emerging markets are
predicted by some experts
to be on the rise, and whether
I agree with this or not,
I think it's important for me to have
at least a little bit of
exposure to these markets.
It's all well and good buying the S&P 500,
but when China, or
another emerging country
has some great gains,
you'll end up missing out.
Just as an example of this growth,
when I first traveled to
China around 20 years ago,
I looked into buying an
apartment in Shenzhen.
That real estate was $47,000,
and now it's worth over a million.
This just shows the potential
growth in these markets.
Emerging market funds are
definitely the most risky type
of index funds we've discussed.
These funds include stocks from lots
of different growing markets
and could be very heavy
with Chinese companies.
Taking a look at a list
of the largest economies
in the world.
A lot of them are emerging
markets, so it just makes sense
to me to throw a little bit of
money in for diversification.
The best I found in the
U S A is the VEIEX ETF
and in the UK, the VFEM
ETF, but there are also lots
of other emerging market funds available,
so it's worth having a look around.
Now, I know at some
point I need to address
the biggest question around investing,
which is, of course, is investing risky?
It really depends on how you define risk.
You may be scared that you'll lose money.
However, you also face this risk
by not investing, as my
father Mervin found out
if you have a diversified
portfolio of index funds
and keep investing at a gradual
rate each and every year,
then even if there is a stop market crash,
then historical data
shows you should be able
to endure the storm.
A great way to make sure you're protected
in the event of a market crash is to mix
in a few bonds within
your stock portfolio.
These are just a different
type of investment
that are far more stable than stocks
and you can buy these on the
same investment platforms.
In your twenties and thirties,
I wouldn't worry too much about them,
but as you move closer to retirement
it's a good idea to have
more bonds and stocks.
In my opinion, in your younger years,
the biggest risk you can take
is not taking enough risk.
Now, for the question on everyone's mind,
when should I sell my stocks?
It's possibly one of the
most common questions
in the stock investing world.
Knowing when to sell stocks
or hold onto them mostly
depends on your age.
If you're older, you've
likely been investing
for a while and can live
off them during retirement by
gradually selling when needed.
However, if you're younger,
this usually isn't the case.
In fact, if you are in
your twenties to thirties,
there are only three good
reasons to sell your investments.
Number one, you need
money for an emergency.
Hopefully, if you
followed the video so far,
then you won't need to worry
because you've got an
emergency fund to help you
out in times like this.
Number two, you made a bad investment.
If you have individual stocks that appear
to be underperforming consistently,
it may be time to cut your
losses before those losses stack
up even higher.
Before panic selling,
take a good look at the wider industry.
If other goods like it
are also in decline,
then you know it's the
industry, not just your stock.
If everything's doing poorly,
this gives you a bit of extra context.
Number three, you've
achieved a specific goal,
although I don't really recommend it.
If you are investing for short
or medium term goals like,
I don't know, saving up
for a dream vacation,
then it would be a great
idea to set a target price.
This is a figure
at which you would feel
satisfied selling the stock
and enjoying your gains.
The most important thing
to remember is to not
sell your stocks for as long
as possible so they have
the longest time to grow.
Just invest and forget about it,
until you want to stop
investing and take your profits.
This thinking will also help
you avoid panic selling.
If you wanna know exactly how
I pick my individual stocks,
then you can check out this video next,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.