- So this guy, his name is Jake,
and Jake really wants to be rich,
but he comes from a pretty
poor background, was raised
by a single mother and lacks
any positive male role models.
Despite this, he's still ambitious
and always looking for
advice on how to make it big.
Recently, Jake started working
at one of my favorite cafes,
and while I was sitting
in my usual corner,
I saw him approach an older
guy dressed in a suit.
Let's call him Mr. Grumpy,
because I've seen him around,
but he never has a smile on his face.
So when Jake asked him for some advice,
I knew it wasn't gonna go well.
Mr. Grumpy just bluntly told him
that the younger generation was lazy
and didn't know the first
thing about hard work.
Jake tried to tell him that
he's working hard to pay
for college and has big
plans for the future,
but things aren't the same nowadays.
But it was no use.
Old Grumpy didn't even let him finish
and snapped back.
He said that younger people
are just full of excuses
and want everything handed
to them on a silver platter.
Coming from a humble background
and having made my first
million in my 20's,
I saw lots of similarities between myself
and Jake, so I couldn't
just sit idly by it.
I got up and approached them.
I looked Mr. Grumpy directly in the eyes
and said something along these lines.
Times have indeed changed,
and so are the challenges
young people face today.
Yes, our generation worked hard,
but that doesn't mean
young people aren't working
just as hard today.
Jake is juggling school and a job
and planning for his future.
The world is honestly more complex now.
The path to success isn't
as straightforward as it used to be.
We need to support
and encourage the younger
generation, not belittle them.
They're the backbone of
future leaders of this world.
We should be guiding
them with our experience,
not dismantling their efforts.
I wish I could tell you I
changed his views on youngsters,
but honestly, I reckon my words
pretty much entered one ear
and went right out the other.
Some older people were just
so stuck in their ways,
but we're not all like that.
Later, when Jake was grabbing
a bite on his lunch break,
I sat with him for a good
hour sharing some real world
advice to help him get ahead.
This whole experience with Jake
really got me thinking there
must be thousands,
actually, probably millions
of young motivated people
like Jake out there.
So I thought today I'll break
down the advice I gave Jake
into five principles
that anyone can follow
to become wealthy.
(upbeat music)
For the first 10 years of your life,
you're just a kid having mindless fun,
and the next 10 years you're
stuck in a classroom being
taught mostly useless information
like Pythagoras's Theorem and Shakespeare.
It's only when you hit your 20's
that you step into the big bad world
and start figuring out how to earn money.
So when you see 20 year-olds driving
around in Lambos on social media,
it can make you feel pretty bad,
but don't blame yourself
for not having it all
figured out yet.
The school system didn't prepare
you for the real world.
Really and truly, you're
just getting started.
If this sounds like you,
then don't just focus on
earning millions at this stage.
You need to obsess over
sharpening your act
so it looks a bit more like this.
Lots of people skip
this part of the process
and just try to start a business,
as they've heard it's
the way to become rich.
However, they're doing
the equivalent of trying
to cut down a tree with a blunt ax.
It's simply just not gonna work.
So how do you sharpen your
ax so that when you go
for the big money, you
can easily cut down a tree
with a few strong swings?
Well, it all comes down to
mastering high income skills.
These are the skills that
can make you at least
$10,000 per month.
Some great examples nowadays
are video editing, copywriting,
high ticket closing, and
software development.
The amount you can make with
skills like these will change
depending on supply and
demand, but mastering one
or two of these skills can put you in a
really great position early on in life.
My son Curtis honed his videography
and editing skills while still in school.
Upon graduating, he
quickly acquired clients
and was earning $10,000
a month within a year.
However, the money wasn't as important
as the opportunities his skills provided.
They allowed him to interact
with extremely successful people
and gain access to valuable information
that others paid thousands for.
This is the true power
of a high income skill.
It opens doors.
So think about what doors
you want to open and pick one
or two high income skills
that will help you get there.
Don't rush this step.
Sharpening your ax takes
time and dedication.
This is a marathon. It's not a sprint.
You don't have to make a
ton of money really fast
and just show it off.
You should aim to last and
not become a one hit wonder.
So extend your timeline.
Stop thinking you need to
become a millionaire in one
or two years.
If you learn the right skills,
then the millions will follow.
Just trust the process.
Once you have a sharp ax,
it's also quite nice to know
that even if somebody
took away all your money,
you'll still be able
to make far more money
than the average person.
Most self-made millionaires
say they can make it all back
faster a second time around
as they already have the
knowledge and the skills to do it.
(upbeat music)
Your money is like this stack of cookies.
The more you handle them,
the more they'll just crumble away.
The key is to stop messing
with your money thinking,
I'm gonna put it here,
trade this, buy that,
'cause the harsh reality
is, you're probably making
the wrong decisions.
How do you think Warren Buffet made 99%
of its 137 billion net worth
after his 50th birthday?
It's because he understood
that real money is made
through compound interest.
However, this can't happen
if it's too easy to access your money
as it's just too tempting.
That's why you need to
lock it away somewhere
where it can grow in peace.
But you can't just lock your
money away in a bank account
and expect it to grow.
You need to invest it in assets.
There are lots of different
asset classes you can choose
from, like real estate,
high-end watches, and gold.
However, my favorite has
to be the stock market.
I've personally made millions doing this.
But here's the thing.
Youngsters these days dream about
popping bottles and zipping
around in flashy sports cars.
Saving money, not so much,
but take it from me.
Making a million dollars
once is nothing special.
You are only a legend if you
can do it again and again.
So after you've pocketed
your first million,
the real game begins.
Can you keep it
and more importantly,
grow it into a fortune?
The best thing you can do is
get that money away from you
and into investments as soon as possible.
That's what I did when I was younger
and I made a rule never to
sell my long-term stocks.
I'm now at the point where
these investments make me
around 17,000 a week in passive income,
which means I can more than live off
what my investments generate,
and I never have to touch
the money I work for.
Once I invested my money, I never saw it
as mine, and you know what?
It lit a fire inside me
that you wouldn't believe.
I was always hustling for more
because I constantly
felt like I was broke.
It's like a boxer who's
training in some beaten
down old gym.
Often, that's the guy
who ends up beating the
boxer who's got access
to the most luxurious training facility.
So if you wanna start
investing, then firstly, decide
how much of your income you are
going to invest every month.
Don't make it an exact amount,
but instead a percentage.
As an example,
if you invested $250 a month
in a low cost index fund
and got an average annual return of 10%,
then in 40 years you'd
have over $1.5 million.
Of course, investments can go up and down.
However, the S&P 500 index
fund has actually given a
10.98% average annual
return over the last decade.
It doesn't really matter
what you choose to invest,
just make sure it's an amount
you can stay consistent with.
Here's a fun experiment
my son's been doing.
He set his trading 212 app
to auto invest five
pounds every single day,
the price of a Starbucks
coffee, and guess what?
After about 10 months, he's
already made 164 pounds,
which is about $200,
with an impressive 11.14% return.
The app also gave him a 12
month value projection when he
started and his bang on target to hit it
in a couple of months.
Since I was planning to talk
about Trading 212 anyway,
I reached out to them
to see if they'd be
interested in sponsoring this
portion of the video.
They agreed and are offering
a fractional free share worth
up to a hundred pounds to anyone
that uses the code Tilbury
when they create an account.
Plus, you can get more free
stocks by inviting your friends,
both of you will get a free share as long
as they fund their account.
Also, don't worry if you've
already opened an account within
the last 10 days, you can still
use the promo code Tilbury
in the app and receive your free share.
(upbeat music)
This is the biggest thing
stopping you becoming rich.
You might think you fear failure,
however, in reality, you are
probably more concerned about
how others will judge you if you fail.
You see, I've spoken to so
many young people like Jake
who have big dreams but are
too scared to take a risk
and step out of the norm as
they're so paralyzed by fear.
However, taking calculated
risks is the only way
to get ahead of everyone else.
Think about it for a second.
If you are just doing the
same thing as the majority
of people, then you're gonna
get the same results, right?
These risks might not always pay off,
but luckily, when you are younger,
you have one huge advantage, time.
This is the most valuable thing you have.
If you have this much time,
your fear level should be at their least.
Look, I know the real
world isn't this logical.
I remember feeling scared when
I considered quitting my job
as a carpenter due to the
constant bullying from my manager.
After much thought, I
decided to take the risk.
Quitting turned out to be the
best decision I ever made.
If I'd allowed my fear to overcome me,
then I wouldn't be sitting here today.
This applies to investing as well.
When you're younger, you don't really want
to be investing in bonds and gold.
These investments are more for
older folks like me that want
to protect our wealth and not
experience big market crashes.
I don't have years to wait if my portfolio
loses a lot of value.
However, you probably do,
which means you can afford
to take more risks as you
are leveraging your time.
Sometimes you just have to go for it.
Not taking opportunities
can lead to regret,
and you may find yourself wondering
how your life could have been different.
As you get older, the ability
to take risks will get
smaller and smaller.
So be adventurous.
Don't worry too much about
what might or might not happen.
Don't find yourself saying,
I wish I'd done that,
or I once had a great idea for a business.
As long as you have time on your side,
then failure really isn't a bad thing.
You should just see it as testing.
Most successful people you
look up to have failed hundreds
of times before achieving success.
You can't have one without the other.
Success is just the reward
you get for enduring
and learning from failure.
So if your scales look like
this, then stop worrying
and overthinking things.
Be brave and seize the
opportunities that come your way.
(upbeat music)
This is known as a
Dunning-Kruger Effect Curve,
and it shows how our level
of knowledge affects our confidence.
Most people never get off Mount Stupid.
This isn't because they're
lazy or unintelligent.
It's because of their arrogance.
They believe getting rich is down to luck,
when actually it's a learnable skill.
It's a never ending process
of learning and applying.
Even at my ancient age, I still do my best
to learn about what's currently going on.
I use YouTube, TikTok,
and I keep up to date with financial news.
This allows me to spot opportunities
before other people of my
generation, so remain a student
for as long as you can,
not in the traditional way.
Just make sure to learn from
those that are ahead of you.
This is a long process and
you have to earn your stripes.
You can't just jump to the finish line.
So learn and respect the process.
Even now, whenever I meet
someone new, I challenge myself
to learn something from them
that I didn't know before.
This helps me stay humble
because when you get to my age,
you still don't know everything.
If you get into the habit
of constantly learning,
then I'd guarantee you'll
make far more money.
I mean, if I didn't know
about crypto back in 2019,
then I wouldn't have
invested a small portion
of my portfolio and made
crazy amounts of money.
But we're taught the opposite
in the Western world.
We're told to go to school
till we're about 18,
then choose a college or university.
Go there for three years and
then our learning's done.
So that means most
people stop learning when
they're in their 20's.
This approach to learning
is completely broken.
The world is progressing faster than ever,
and if you want to keep up, then you need
to keep giving your
brain software updates,
just like computers.
If you don't keep updating your brain
and keeping it clear of viruses,
which in this case is outdated knowledge,
it will eventually break down.
The phrase, if you don't
use it, you'll lose it,
has never been more true.
If I didn't start thinking
this way when I was younger,
then right now I'd probably
be sat on the porch dribbling
into my dinner not
knowing what's going on.
(upbeat music)
If you want to become the first
millionaire in your family,
then you need to break the poverty cycle.
This 2024 study by the National Bureau
of Economic Research says
you can improve your chances
of becoming rich by befriending
a specific type of person.
Any guesses who that might be?
Of course it's wealthy people,
but maybe not for the
reasons you are expecting.
They found that every 10%
increase in wealthy friends
was associated with
nearly 3% greater chance
of stock market participation
for that person,
and a 5% increase in the
chance they save money.
This makes sense as when I
post videos explaining how
to invest in the stock market,
I'm always shocked at how
many comments I get saying,
if it's that simple,
why isn't everyone investing
in the stock market?
The truth is everyone should be doing it.
However, they're being held back
by their circle of influence.
People are nervous about investing
and starting side hustles,
but once they start making
friends that can help guide them
and explain things they don't
understand in plain English,
it dramatically improves their
chances of becoming rich.
Look, I'm not saying you should
ditch all your old friends,
and I'm also not saying that
you should become friends
with someone just because they're rich.
Maybe just consider joining clubs
where rich people often spend time
and you'll naturally become
friends with these kinds
of people without having
to force anything.
If you've made it to
this part of the video,
I'm sure you'll be successful
in life as you are young,
ambitious, and clearly wanna make it big.
I love young people like you.
You are the backbone of the world.
Be that in America, the UK, Africa,
or China, I don't care
what country you live in.
Without your brains, ideas and drive,
the world would just fall apart.
I'm gonna die along with
the other older people,
and then it's over to you.
You are the future leaders of
this world, so don't be afraid
to go after what you want.
And remember, there are still
some older people like myself
that understand and care
about the younger generation,
and you have my word,
I will always defend you
if some old fart is talking
down to you guys.
If you wanna learn how
to invest for beginners,
then you should watch this next video,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.