A week ago, I turned 57.
And if I could go back to
talk to my 20-year-old self
and give him some advice,
here are the 50 things I would say.
Number one, work on your willpower.
You'll never reach your full potential
or outwork your rivals
if you can't focus for
long periods of time.
This was true when I was younger,
but it's even more applicable now
with so many distractions
fighting for your attention.
If you can focus and work hard,
you'll be miles ahead of everyone else,
so why not use this video
as a test for yourself?
If you can reach the end without skipping
and actually listen to
everything I say on a deep level,
then you'll be in the minority.
Number two, become more of
a producer than a consumer.
I understand consuming content is key,
especially if you learn a lot.
However, you should always be trying
to put more out into the world
than you're taking,
otherwise you'll end up robbed
of your time and attention.
Number three, be nice
to people on the come up
because you never know where
they're gonna be in the future.
There have been countless times
when I've underestimated
someone's potential,
only to see them achieve
credible success later on.
By treating everyone with
kindness and support,
even if you're unsure about their plans,
you create good karma.
If they strike it big,
they'll likely remember those
who were in their corner,
and you may benefit from
that connection too.
Number four, watch what
most people are doing
and then do the opposite.
It took me a few years to find the courage
to leave my nine to five job
and start my own business.
I was comfortable with the
routine of receiving a paycheck
and accepting life as it was.
However, when I built a staircase
for a wealthy entrepreneur,
I realized there was
another path available.
I'm grateful I took that chance.
I mean, I wouldn't be a millionaire now
if I continued working for someone else.
This is a pretty simple idea
because if you do what everyone else does,
then you're gonna get the same results.
So reject the idea of
being normal and vanilla.
As the saying goes,
if you're everyone's cup of tea,
then you're a mug.
Number five, who you know
matters 1,000 times
more than what you know.
A great network beats money
in the bank every time.
I can't count how many times
my connections have helped me out.
Number six, never talk
behind someone's back.
If you have a problem with someone,
you should address it with
them directly or not at all.
You may think that gossiping about people
when they can't hear you
makes you seem cool,
but it actually makes
you seem less trustworthy
to those who are listening,
as they'll think you're doing
the same behind their backs.
Number seven, give yourself permission
to make more mistakes.
Most of my success has
come from my failures.
I wish I knew this sooner.
I mean, I enjoy skiing with my son,
and I remember one year
we competed to see who
could fall the least.
I won, as Curtis fell over a lot,
however he improved tremendously,
and now he's a much faster skier than me.
This just proves that
failure leads to improvement
if it's embraced.
So remember, if you never fail,
then you're probably
not trying hard enough.
Number eight, make
reversible decisions quickly.
I actually picked this one up
from Jeff Bezos, as he said,
"With a decision that you can go back on,
"your biggest risk is dragging your feet
"and not making a decision."
However, when decisions are irreversible,
slow them down
as the biggest risk here is
making the wrong decision,
so it's worth getting as
much information as possible
before taking action.
Number nine, focus on one thing at a time.
The truth is there is no
such thing as multitasking,
just multi-failing,
so give yourself time
to focus on one thing
deeply without distractions.
Trust me, you'll achieve far more.
Number 10, don't be the best,
be the only.
You can do this by learning
seemingly unrelated skills
and combining them together.
Steve Jobs is well known
for mixing his love
for calligraphy and design with technology
and creating Apple as we know it today.
He was the only person
doing that at the time.
This is one of my golden pieces of advice,
and after every 10 bits of advice,
I'm gonna drop another one of these.
Number 11, if you don't like
something, then change it.
If you can't change it,
then change your attitude, never complain.
I used to be a bit of a complainer,
but as I've gone through life,
I've realized that 80% of the time,
no one cares about your problems,
and 20% of them wish they
had them in the first place.
Even if your whole world is crumbling,
complaining won't do
anything positive for you.
I'm not saying you can't
express your feelings,
however it's important to remember
we all have our own problems
and not many people
care about fixing yours.
Number 12, work smart, not hard.
As I've grown old and gray,
I've seen the birth of lots
of revolutionary technology
like color TVs, the iPhone
and artificial intelligence.
The crazy thing is a lot of
my generation aren't like me
and choose to reject it,
which makes working smart very difficult.
But for you tech savvy youngsters,
working smart and building a
business has never been easier.
I mean, take a look at this, for example.
One of the hottest businesses
at the moment is e-Commerce
as it's infinitely scalable
and provides geographical freedom,
but building a website requires
either a unique skillset
or money to pay somebody
else to do it for you.
But with Build Your Store AI,
you can get a fully custom Shopify store
built completely for free
in less than two minutes.
Here's one I made earlier.
As you can see,
all I had to do was select
the niche of my store,
pick some images that worked
and then let AI take care of the rest.
The website even comes with
winning products and ready pages
like policies and returns.
Of course, this is all fully customizable,
but it's a great starting point
and perfectly sums up
working smart and not hard.
I'll leave a link in the description below
if you're interested in
selling products online
and having a free website built for you.
The link also gives you access
to a special Shopify trial for $1
so you can launch your business risk free.
Number 13, assume you can learn something
from everyone you meet.
I'm not afraid to admit
that in my 20s I was
a little bit arrogant.
I thought I knew everything,
but, looking back,
I now realize how much
more I still had to learn.
I'm very aware that in 10 years time,
I'll look back at what I currently know
and probably think the same.
Even at 57,
I'm still learning new things every day.
So if I were you,
I'd just skip the arrogant stage
and be open to learning new things,
even from those younger than you.
Number 14, never disrespect your elders.
I know on the surface
we might seem boring,
but us older people
have been through a lot.
Our experience can probably
help you avoid many mistakes
if you take the time to listen.
However, if you disagree
with something I say,
you don't have to follow my advice.
All I ask is that you
listen with an open mind
and then make your own decisions.
Number 15, don't be afraid
of change, embrace it.
I started a chain of radio
controlled model shops
in my 20s,
and the goal was to
expand all over the world.
However, when the internet was created,
that all changed.
Suddenly, more and more
people were shopping online
and my shops were suffering.
I could have just given up.
However, instead, I embraced the change
and started the e-Commerce
side of my business,
and started making more than ever before.
There's a famous quote that
sums this up quite well,
and it goes like this.
Once a new technology rolls over you,
if you're not part of the steam roller,
you're part of the road.
Number 16, live in the
moment, not on your phone.
Make the most of every moment.
You don't need to capture
everything for social media.
Focus on what's happening
right in front of you,
especially when it's something
you might never experience again.
I didn't realize how many last times
I went through without knowing it,
whether it's hanging
out with your friends,
that weekly bowling night
or a yearly tradition.
One day, it'll be the final time,
and you probably won't even see it coming.
Number 17, always pay the bill.
This one's for the guys.
Yeah, it might sound a bit old school,
but it's part of being a gentleman.
Paying the bill is just a small
gesture that shows you care,
and, no, it's not simping,
unless you're always doing
it and getting nothing back.
Number 18, say no if you
genuinely aren't ready.
It's okay to admit when you need more time
or aren't quite prepared
to take something on.
Sure, people love to say
fake it 'til you make it,
but if you can't close
that knowledge gap in time,
it's smarter to turn it down
rather than risk being in over your head.
Number 19, present yourself
in the way you wish to be perceived.
It's important to think
about how you want to
come across to others
and then make a conscious effort
to present yourself in that way.
This includes how you
dress, how you speak,
what you post on social media
and even how you carry yourself.
Think of it like building
your own video game character
from the ground up.
Number 20, mentally prepare yourself
for your loved ones dying.
I know this isn't the
nicest thing to talk about,
but you do need to think about it.
When something like this happens,
it can send shock waves
throughout our lives.
And if you aren't ready to withstand this,
then you'll just crumble.
Thinking this way
also helps you to value every moment
you spend with your loved ones,
as nothing is forever.
Number 21, never take
rejection personally.
Whether it's a job
interview or something else,
try to see things from
their point of view.
Use the feedback to improve the next time.
Taking rejection personally
just holds you back from
growing and getting better.
Number 22, don't be embarrassed
to take a nap now and again.
I know this one may sound silly,
but when I was younger,
I thought naps were for
kids and old people.
But I've met so many millionaires
that swear by having short
power naps throughout the day.
So don't be ashamed or
embarrassed about taking a nap,
as it can actually help
you be more productive
in the long run.
Number 23, learn from those
who disagree with you.
Too many people are trapped
in a bubble on social media,
and they can't face their
beliefs being challenged.
Remember, you can learn
something from everyone,
so just because you don't
agree on a couple of things,
it doesn't mean you shouldn't
listen to their opinions.
Number 24, never be late.
Punctuality is a sign of
respect for other people's time,
and shows that you're
reliable and trustworthy.
Early is on time, on time is
late and late is unforgivable.
Number 25, be motivated by
something greater than money.
This comes from your values.
Having strong values means
that no one can buy you,
no matter how much they offer.
These values are principles
you refuse to compromise
under any circumstances.
One of mine is prioritizing my family.
If something isn't in their best interest,
then I won't do it
under any circumstances.
So figure out what you're
passionate about and make a stand.
This will allow you to command
more respect from others.
Number 26, be fueled by vision, not fear.
Fearful people worry about
losing what they have
and can never see far enough ahead
to build something for the future.
Number 27, stand up to bullies.
I stayed stuck in a job way too long,
letting my manager push me around,
before I finally quit and
started my own business.
Trust me, you can't let anyone,
whether it's a man or a woman, bully you.
Most of the time,
if you stand up for yourself once,
that's all it takes.
Bullies can seriously
mess with your confidence,
and that's the last thing you need
when you're young and
trying to find your own way.
Number 28, use your unfair advantages.
Everyone has certain
strengths or circumstances
that can give them an edge,
and it's important to
identify and use them.
An unfair advantage is
something that sets you apart,
whether it's a specific skill,
a connection or your life situation.
It's not about cheating.
It's about recognizing what
you're naturally good at
or the opportunities you
have that others might not,
and using those to your
advantage to get ahead.
Number 29, skip the flashy car.
It's a waste in your 20s.
Buy used but reliable.
I've seen so many young people
come into money quickly,
only to blow it on things like luxury cars
and designer gear.
Sure, it's easy to have short
term success and splurge,
but what's far more impressive
is consistently building wealth over time.
That's what true legends do.
Number 30, prioritize your reputation.
It's one of the few things
that lives on after you die.
I've had the unfortunate experience
of attending many funerals in my time,
and the person is always
remembered for their character.
In other words, their reputation,
not their achievements.
Number 31, don't compare
yourself to your friends.
We all have our own path to walk.
As long as you're improving
on what you've done before,
then you're going in the right direction.
If you do this for enough years,
then you'll look back and be
shocked at how far you've come.
It's all about taking those baby steps
and not getting distracted by
what everyone else is doing.
Number 32, don't let a bad
day turn into a bad week.
It takes less than five seconds
for someone to ruin your day.
And if you're not careful,
that can spiral into a
whole week of negativity.
It's important to let it go
so you don't miss out on
all the good opportunities
that that week still has to offer.
Number 33, always pay
off your credit card.
I had to mention this one
because it's so important.
If you don't pay off your
credit card in full each month,
you're just wasting money and
hurting your credit score.
Be smart about it.
Make paying it off a habit,
and it'll stick with you for life.
Number 34, any job is better than no job.
Being out of work can really
take its toll on you mentally,
so if the only position available
is washing cars for $10 an hour,
go for it.
It's not just about the pay.
It's about getting out there,
interacting with others
and boosting your self-esteem
that comes from showing up for a job.
Who knows, you might make some mates.
I still have a friend
I met during my car
washing days 47 years ago.
Number 35, never buy an investment
without doing your own research.
I've seen so many people lose
money on poor investments,
and usually it's because
they didn't take the time
to look into it.
Make sure you do your homework,
even if you think you might
miss out on something big.
If someone is pressuring you to invest,
that's often a red flag.
Number 36, being a great storyteller
can get you anything you want.
Knowing how to tell a good
story is such a game changer.
Whether you're just
hanging out with friends
or trying to impress a
future business partner,
a great story grabs attention,
makes your point stick
and helps you connect with
people in a more real way.
Plus, it's just a fun way
to get your ideas across
and leave an impression,
no matter the situation.
Number 37, don't live
your life for others.
Don't let haters dictate your choices
or make you shy away from
doing what you truly want.
If friends or family are
pushing you into a career
you're not passionate about,
take a moment to think
about your situation.
You don't wanna end up
in a job you despise
for the rest of your life.
Focus on building and living
your dream life instead.
Number 38, have a solid paycheck routine.
Firstly, use 50% to pay for your needs.
This is your food, rent and electricity.
Secondly, save 20% in a high
interest savings account.
This is your emergency fund.
Thirdly, use 30% to pay
off any high interest debt.
This is your credit cards and car finance.
Fourth, once you've paid off your debts,
use 25% to invest in a Roth
IRA or a stocks and shares ISA.
This is to grow your wealth.
Fifth, put 5% towards some risky place
like starting your own business.
This is your chance to
make some fast money.
Number 39, it's not the end of the world
if you don't have everything figured out.
Everyone is winging it to some degree,
and it took me over 20
years to realize this.
Most people are just navigating
life as best they can.
I used to think I was at a disadvantage
for not attending business
school or even university,
but as I've met more
people over the years,
I've learned that we're
all just doing our best,
learning and failing every day.
You'll never reach the point
where you know everything,
so it's best to start as soon as you can
and just figure it out as you go.
Number 40, retirement might
feel like it will never come,
but it will,
start investing for it now.
I know a lot of YouTubers
are saying investing your
money is not worth the time
as you'll only get 8% per year.
However, they aren't looking
at the bigger picture.
Of course, it's important
to make money quickly,
but it's equally as important
to let some of it grow
passively for your retirement.
Number 41, the quality of your questions
will shape your future success.
I receive a lot of DMs.
And while I try to respond
to as many as possible,
I often have to sift through
them to find the valuable ones.
I assume this is the same
for most successful people.
For instance, if your message starts with,
"Hi, I know you're busy,
"but can I ask a question?"
You've already missed your chance.
Another common one is,
"Hi, can we have a chat?"
That won't get you far either.
Instead, take some time to
think about your question
and craft it thoughtfully.
When you do that,
you're much more likely to
receive a meaningful answer.
Remember, the quality of your question
will directly impact the
value of the response you get.
Number 42, make sure to enjoy the journey,
not just focus on the destination.
There's a saying I've lived by,
"Happiness is a journey,
"not a destination."
What that really means
is that the ups and
downs of a great journey
stay with you forever,
while the destination
is just a brief moment
that quickly fades away.
Think about all those athletes
you see getting interviewed
after winning a gold medal or a big race.
They're always asked,
"How does it feel?"
And almost everyone says,
"It hasn't sunk in yet."
I think that's because they
feel a bit of emptiness
after reaching their goal.
Sure, they've accomplished
something amazing,
but then it's like what's next?
So savor the ride and all the
experiences along the way.
Number 43, nothing is ever free.
If you're not spending money,
then you're spending time.
From an early age,
I always told my son
that nothing in his world
comes without a cost.
If you want something,
then you need to earn money to buy it.
He would often argue with me
about things he saw advertised as free,
and I'd explain those offers
often end up costing you the most.
That's because if something
isn't costing you money,
it's likely costing you your time.
You've probably heard
the saying time is money,
and it couldn't be more accurate.
When you're young,
you tend to think you have
all the time in the world,
but you don't always value it enough.
Don't waste it because before you know it
you'll be 57 reflecting on
your twilight years to come.
Number 44, stop waiting to be inspired
and just get on with it.
Inspiration can be pretty
hard to come by sometimes,
but sitting around waiting
for that ah-ha moment
can really slow you down.
Instead, just start
taking some small steps
towards what you want to do.
You might be surprised,
once you dive in,
that motivation can kick
in and make things flow,
so don't overthink it.
Just get going and see what happens.
Number 45, work hard now
for an easier life later.
Take it easy now and
face the consequences.
Life often feels like
it's turned upside down.
When you're young,
all you wanna do is party,
travel and have fun,
but you usually lack the funds to do so.
Then as you get older,
your priorities shift
towards wanting security,
stability and enough money
to enjoy a comfortable retirement.
You may eventually achieve that,
but it often comes after
years of hard work,
pushing yourself until retirement at 67
and sometimes not living long
enough to enjoy it fully.
If you put in the effort in your 20s
and resist the urge to
follow the usual path,
you can lay a solid financial foundation.
This way, starting in your 30s,
life can become a lot easier.
I did just that,
and it's been an amazing journey.
Number 46, tackle the
tough tasks in the morning.
- [Crew Member] He says when
he's filming at five PM.
- Well, it's been a long day,
but I enjoy it.
I'm a big believer in making to-do lists,
but I used to approach them all wrong.
I thought it was about checking off
as many items as possible,
which often meant I'd do
all the easy tasks first.
While this might have looked impressive,
it left the harder jobs lingering.
Years ago, I shifted my strategy
to prioritize the difficult tasks
first thing in the morning.
This way, I knocked them out
when I was most productive,
and the best part
is that once those two or
three tough jobs are done,
finishing off the easier
ones in the afternoon
becomes a breeze.
Number 47, the name of a university
means absolutely nothing.
Seriously, don't stress
over what uni you go to
or rack up debt just for a fancy name.
At the end of the day,
it's what you learn and how you
apply it that really counts.
Employers care more about
skills and experience
than the university you may
or may not have attended.
Number 48, look after your back.
If you slouch, you'll have
issues in your mid-30s.
Sadly, this is advice that
comes from firsthand experience.
Your back is crucial.
Over time, a bad back can
severely impact your productivity
since it makes it hard
to get anything done.
It's similar to having tooth ache,
but, unlike dental pain, there's
no quick fix to relieve it.
This generation benefits greatly
from technology and the internet,
but it also faces issues
from hunching over keyboards
and lounging on uncomfortable sofas.
Prioritize your back health.
You'll need it for your entire life.
You can replace your teeth,
but you can't get a new back.
Number 49, don't stress
about being different.
You don't have to fit in.
Honestly, I never let the
idea of being weird bother me.
I embraced it.
I was a tall, skinny,
ginger-haired, dyslexic teenager
who loved playing with model airplanes.
Pretty unique, right?
When you accept what makes you different,
you actually gain an advantage
because you become
comfortable with who you are
while everyone else is busy
trying to fit into molds
that don't suit them.
My dyslexia has become a superpower,
allowing me to solve problems quickly.
Being skinny keeps me relatively fit.
My passion for model planes
sparked my first business,
and being tall helps me
stand out and be remembered.
As for the ginger hair,
thank goodness that's gone.
Number 50, choose your partner wisely.
I wouldn't be a millionaire today
without my supportive wife.
A lot of people get caught up in dating
lots of different options,
but, honestly, what really counts
is having a deep connection
and being on the same path together.
When you find someone you
think you could marry,
make sure you really want to
spend your life with them.
Too many people end up with regrets
because they were blinded
by that early puppy love.
A solid partnership can
make a huge difference,
so take your time
and choose someone who you
can build a solid future with.
If you wanna know the smartest route
to earning $10,000 per month,
then I'll leave that video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if you
wanna grow your wealth, okay?
I'll see you over there.