- What's the laziest way for beginners
to make money online?
(cash register chimes)
That's one of the most
common questions I get asked,
and honestly, who doesn't
wanna make good money
with minimal effort, all
while having the freedom
to work from anywhere in the world?
So as a millionaire businessman,
I'm gonna use my knowledge
to finally answer this question.
As you can see, I've got
this grid out in front of me.
We're gonna use it to figure out
which online moneymaking
method is truly the laziest
by judging each one in five categories.
First up, learning curve.
This is how long it takes
before you're earning decent money.
Ideally, we want this to
be as short as possible
to keep things truly lazy.
Next up
is fulfillment.
This is all about delivering
whatever it is you're selling,
and we want this to be
as simple as possible.
Then there's scalability.
This measures how easy you
can grow and make more money
without piling on extra work.
After that, we have startup capital
or how much money you'll need
to invest upfront to get going.
And finally we're looking at risk level.
Higher risk usually means more stress,
which even if it's easy money
can drain you over time.
Today I am only gonna be
covering money making methods
that can realistically bring you in
over $100 a day.
(cash register chimes)
So, no online surveys
or transcription sites.
They pay next to nothing
and just end up wasting your time anyway.
Method one, freelancing.
This is all about using your
skills to earn money online
by working directly with clients.
There are tons of skills
you can choose from,
including video editing,
social media management,
graphic design, copywriting,
and website development.
This is great 'cause you
get to choose your projects
and work schedule, which gives
you a lot of flexibility,
so it's perfect for those wanting control
over when and where they work.
In my opinion, the best one
to focus on is video editing,
as due to the rise of digital content,
there's a real shortage of
great editors at the moment.
But the real question is,
how lazy is freelancing?
Well, let's have a look.
For learning curve, I'm
gonna say six months.
To start making good
money, you'll probably need
at least this amount of time
to learn and build a portfolio.
The most popular skills
like video editing, design,
and copywriting have tons
of tutorials on YouTube,
which can help you level up very quickly.
For fulfillment, I'm gonna
say this is pretty hard.
Dealing with clients
one-on-one can be a bit tricky.
I remember when my son was
freelancing as a video editor.
Every week he'd be venting about a client
who kept requesting changes
that he felt made the video worse.
It was so frustrating for him
because they just didn't get it,
but he had to keep his cool,
play nice, and make those changes anyway.
It's tough to do,
especially when you're
passionate about a project
and feel like someone is dragging it down.
Now, for scalability,
I'm gonna say this one is pretty limited.
In freelancing, your income
is tied directly to your time.
This means there's a cap on your earnings,
unless you either charge higher rates
or hire other people
to do the work for you.
The only way to scale is to
build a good client base,
as this will lead to steady work.
You can do this on freelance
sites like Upwork and Fiverr.
Fiverr is ideal for beginners,
as you can list services
without needing to bid on jobs.
Upwork might be a bit more competitive,
but it often has higher paying projects.
Startup capital, though, is pretty good.
It's practically zero.
If you already have a
computer and internet access,
you're nearly set.
Some tools, like the Adobe Creative Suite
for design or video editing,
can be a great investment,
but there are free or low-cost
alternatives like Canva
that you get started with.
Your biggest investment here is your time.
Finally, for risk, this is pretty low,
mainly because there is
very little upfront cost
and you're directly paid for each project.
The only real risk is
potentially inconsistent income,
so you might have to put
in some effort initially
to build up a steady stream of clients.
So overall, this is definitely
not the laziest method.
However, freelancing could be a great way
to start making money online,
especially if you're willing
to put in the time, build up
your skills and a client list.
Method two, Airbnb arbitrage.
This is a moneymaking method
where you rent out a property
on a long-term lease, and
then rent it out short-term
on platforms like Airbnb.
Essentially, you're
acting as the middle man,
taking advantage of the price difference
between your long-term lease
and the short term rental rates.
This could be a great way
to generate passive income
without having to own
the property yourself.
You'll need to get
permission from the owner,
but you'd be surprised
how many landlords are okay with this.
They either don't know
how to operate an Airbnb
or don't have the time
to do it themselves.
So, how lazy is it?
This one has a one to
three-month learning curve.
Getting the hang of Airbnb
arbitrage doesn't take too long.
You need to spend a bit of time
learning about the platform,
understanding local rental laws,
and getting familiar
with property management.
The bulk of this preparation time
will be spent finding good properties.
Look for places near tourist
attractions, universities,
or business districts.
Websites like AirDNA can give you insights
into rental prices and occupancy rates.
You'd also need to reach
out to the landlords
and let them know you plan to
sublet the property on Airbnb.
Make sure you get their
permission in writing,
as you don't want 'em to find out later
and cancel your lease
after you've put in all that hard work
getting it up and running on Airbnb.
Fulfillment is medium
difficulty.
While it can be a relatively
hands-off way of making money,
you still have to deal
with some customer issues
from time-to-time.
Guests might have questions or concerns,
and you'll need to manage
check-ins and cleaning.
It's not as easy as just
putting up a listing
and forgetting about it,
but it can be manageable
with a good system in place.
That's why it's a good idea
to use management software
like Guesty or Hostfully to
streamline your bookings,
communication, and check-ins.
This will save you time and
help keep your guests happy.
Now, here's where it gets really exciting,
because scalability is very high.
One of the best parts
about Airbnb arbitrage
is that it's highly scalable.
You can keep adding more
properties to your portfolio
and there's really no limit
to how many you can manage.
You just have to make sure you
have the time and resources
to keep everything running smoothly.
Here's the bad news, though.
This is gonna require 5K
to 15K of startup capital.
This is where it gets a bit tricky.
You'll need a decent
amount of upfront cash
to secure a lease, cover any
initial furnishing costs,
and possibly pay for cleaning services.
Finally, risk level is pretty high.
The main downside to this
method is the upfront cash
you need to invest.
However, if you take advantage
of the management tools
I mentioned, it can be
relatively hands-off.
Saying that, I reckon we can
find an even lazier option.
Method three,
an eBay shop.
This is a great way to make money
by selling products online.
You can sell anything from
vintage clothing and electronics
to handmade items or even get
rid of stuff you don't need.
With millions of users, eBay
offers a massive marketplace
where you can reach potential
buyers without needing
to set up an actual shop in the street.
But the question is, how lazy is it?
Well, we're gonna find out.
The learning curve for this
is around about two weeks.
Getting started with eBay
is pretty straightforward.
Before diving in,
think about what kind of
products you want to sell.
Are you into vintage
clothing, collectibles,
electronics, or something else?
You can then use eBay's search function
to see what's popular and in
demand in your chosen niche.
Then you just need to create
your eBay seller account
and source your products.
As I mentioned before,
you can start with things
in your house that you don't want anymore,
or you could order items you've seen
selling on eBay from DHgate.
This process shouldn't take
more than a couple of weeks.
For fulfillment, I'm gonna say
this is a medium difficulty.
You'll have to send your
products out yourself
and you might run into
some customer issues
from time-to-time, like returns
or inquiries about products.
I've been running my
eBay shops for years now,
and in my experience,
it's always better to send a
replacement or issue a refund,
even if you suspect the
customer is trying to scam you.
It's simply better
to keep your eBay
account in good standing.
These kinds of situations
used to stress me out something rotten.
However, now I've learned
it's just the cost
of selling items online and
there's no getting away from it.
The scalability of this one is very high.
You can continually add new products
and there's really no limit to
how many items you can sell.
As you start to make more money,
you might even want to
consider branching out
onto other platforms like Etsy and Amazon.
Alternatively, you could
start various eBay shops
in different niches.
I'd say you need at least
$500 of startup capital.
To get your shop off the ground,
you'll need to use this
initial money for stock
depending on what you want to sell.
$500 can be a reasonable starting point.
You can find good deals at
thrift stores, garage sales,
or even wholesale suppliers like DHgate,
who I mentioned earlier.
I'd say this is
medium risk.
This risk comes from the fact
that you're putting money
into stock that might not sell right away.
However, if you're
smart about your choices
and stay on top of trends, you
can really reduce that risk.
I'd say the eBay shop
method is winning so far,
as it's a pretty lazy money making method.
However, it's lacking in
a few of the categories,
so let's keep going.
Method four, affiliate marketing.
This is a great way to earn money
by promoting other people's
products or services.
You get paid a commission
for every sale made
through your referral link.
It's a win-win.
You help someone sell their products
while earning a little
something for yourself.
No need to handle products
or do any customer service.
So let's see how this stacks
up against the other methods.
The learning curve for
this one is super short,
I'd say one to two days.
All you really need to do is to sign up
to different affiliate programs.
You can use sites like
Amazon Associates, ClickBank,
and my favorite, Impact.
I'd recommend going on to these sites
and seeing what companies are
offering the best commissions.
Then you can start thinking
about how you can get people
to start using your links.
For fulfillment, I'm gonna
say this is very easy.
Once you've shared your affiliate links,
your job is pretty much done.
You won't be responsible
for fulfilling orders
or dealing with customer complaints,
which makes this one a
pretty stress-free way
to earn some extra cash.
The scalability of this one is very high.
You can promote as many
products as you want
and keep racking up those sales passively.
In the past, the go-to
strategy for scaling
was paid ads on Facebook.
These days though, you're
much better off focusing
on organic short-form content.
The amount of free reach
you can get is incredible.
Just look at the way Andrew
Tate skyrocketed in popularity.
Tons of people were clipping his videos
and posting them on TikTok,
Instagram, and YouTube Shorts,
all while including their affiliate links
to his online course.
Some of these kids were making
thousands of dollars a month doing this.
I'm not promoting his
course, but it's worth noting
that affiliate marketing
has been around for ages
and is still going strong, so
you can use similar tactics
to earn some decent money yourself.
In terms of startup capital,
I'd say you'll need at least
$250.
You can definitely start for
less, but that's assuming
you don't wanna create
the content yourself.
With $250, you can get some
solid short-form content edited
to promote your affiliate products.
Starting with organic
content is a smart move.
You can always dive into paid ads later.
It sets a strong foundation
without breaking the bank.
The risk with affiliate
marketing is very low.
This is because you're
not holding any inventory
and have minimal upfront costs.
You won't have to worry about unsold stock
or customer service, which
makes affiliate marketing
a low pressure way to earn money.
Saying this, I think the last method
we're about to discuss is even lazier.
Method five, AI Shopify store.
Setting up an AI-built Shopify
store is a great shortcut
for anyone looking to start e-commerce
without the typical learning curve.
With this approach,
you can set up a store,
have winning products selected for you,
and automate inventory and fulfillment,
all thanks to the power of AI.
The learning curve is practically zero.
This is as beginner friendly as it gets.
Had over to buildyourstore.ai,
I'll leave a link in the description,
and click start your free store.
The tool guides you through each step
beginning with a prompt for basic details
like your name and email.
You'll then be asked to choose a niche,
with popular options like
fashion, electronics,
and pets available.
Selecting a niche that
aligns with your interests
can make the store easier
to promote in the long run.
The AI even helps you
with store aesthetics,
giving you the options
for banners, layouts,
and color schemes to make your shop
look professional and appealing.
Once you're ready, connect to Shopify
by following the prompts.
If you use the link in the description,
you can access a three-day free trial,
and after that, three
months at only $1 each.
This makes the process incredibly
affordable to test out,
and since the platform
walks you through each step,
you won't need any technical
knowledge to get started.
Now for fulfillment,
very easy.
This is assuming you register for AutoDS.
Don't worry, the Build Your Store website
will prompt you to use this.
It takes care of everything,
from adding trending
products to your store
to updating important details
like prices and images.
And when a sale comes through,
AutoDS ships the items
straight to your customer.
It's especially useful if you're looking
to make passive income,
as it removes the need
to keep track of inventory
or personally ship products.
As I was planning on
talking about AutoDS anyway,
I reached out to see
if they'd be interested
in sponsoring this portion of
the video, and they agreed.
So if you go through this process
and use Build Your Store AI
with the link in the description,
you'll also get the trial
on AutoDS for 99 cents
so you can experiment with the app
before deciding to invest long-term.
While you'll need to
enter a payment method
to activate the trial, they'll
only be taking 99 cents,
so this you some time to test
it out pretty much risk-free.
Now for scalability.
This one is unlimited.
Much like with an eBay store,
an AI-built Shopify store
is practically unlimited
in its potential to scale.
You can use AutoDS to continually
add new winning products
to keep your store fresh and updated,
and since they handle shipping,
you can grow the store
without worrying about logistics.
Startup capital, just $1.99.
So this is $1 to activate
your Shopify account
and 99 cents for AutoDS' trial.
The AI tool that builds your
store is completely free.
Now, risk level,
almost none.
With such a minimal upfront investment,
the risk level here is as low as it gets.
Even if you decide this
method isn't for you,
the low cost to try out
makes it a no brainer.
So if you're looking for a low
effort, highly scalable way
to make money online, an
AI-built Shopify store
might be your best bet.
It's passive income that
you can manage from anywhere
without the need to be an influencer,
invest heavily, or
manage shipping yourself.
If you wanna know what
to do with your money
every time you get paid,
and I'm gonna leave that
video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe
if you want to grow your wealth, okay?
I'll see you over there.