What's the best way for beginners
to start investing online
(upbeat music)
with just a hundred dollars?
(cash register dinging)
As a millionaire investor,
this is something I
get asked all the time,
and because of that, four years ago,
I set out to answer this
question by creating a video
where I invested a hundred dollars
(cash register dinging)
into five different things.
Today, I'm gonna compare the results
from those five investments
that you can make from your laptop
and try to finally answer the
question once and for all.
We're gonna be using this grid
to judge each one in these categories.
First up, learning curve.
This is how long it takes to learn the ins
and outs of each method.
Ideally, we want this to
be as short as possible.
Next is passive income potential,
which is how much money
an investment can earn
for you passively while you still own it,
without needing to sell it.
Then, there's tax efficiency,
which refers to the
specific tax advantages
or benefits available for
each type of investment
that can help you pay less tax.
After that, we have risk level,
which is about how likely
you are to lose money
and how much the investments
value might go up or down.
And finally, we're looking at the results.
This is where I'll reveal
my percentage return
over the last four years
and exactly how much
my a hundred dollars
investment is now worth.
Before we jump in, please remember,
I'm not a financial advisor.
I'm just sharing my own results
and strategies that have
worked for me over the years.
Please also do your own research.
(upbeat music)
Okay, first up is individual stocks.
Individual stocks give you
the chance to own a piece
of a company you believe in.
This can be really exciting,
because you're directly
investing in businesses
that you think will grow or succeed.
For learning curve, I'm
gonna say this is high.
If you want to be successful
picking individual stocks,
then it's not just a guessing game.
You'll need to dig into the nitty gritty
of a company's fundamentals.
This includes looking into the financials,
who's leading the company, and
how well known the brand is.
When I invest in individual stocks,
I look through income
statements, balance sheets,
and cash flow statements.
So when I invest in a stock,
I'm in it for the long haul,
which means at least two to 10 years.
A great way to learn how to do this is
by using an investing
app with a demo account,
which lets you play around with fake money
until you're confident
with your strategies.
For passive income potential,
I'm gonna say this is good.
You see, when you own a stock,
there are two ways you can make money.
Firstly, if the price of the stock goes up
during the time you own it,
you can sell it for more than you paid.
Secondly, you can receive dividends.
Dividends are regular
payments to shareholders.
Not all stocks pay dividends,
but if they do, this means
you can receive money
without ever selling your stock.
This is essentially passive income.
Now, for tax efficiency, this is great.
If you use the right accounts,
then you can reduce your tax burden.
In the UK, these are called
stocks and shares ISAs.
You can set one up on most investing apps
and any profits you make
are safe from taxes.
In the USA, there's something
similar called a Roth IRA.
These accounts work like a shield,
protecting your profits from the tax man.
While there are different rules,
depending on where you
live, the idea is the same.
Please bear in mind that
I'm not a tax advisor,
and you should do your own researchers
as everyone's circumstances are different.
So what's the risk?
This is definitely high.
Back in 1995 during the.com boom,
I got lucky and picked a few great stocks.
I sold them at the right time
and made a lot of money in a short period,
but when the bubble burst,
some of the other
companies I'd invested in,
ones that cost me very little,
went out of business completely.
Even though I ended up
making money overall,
it just shows how risky investing
in individual stocks can be,
especially if you put all your money
into just a few companies.
If they fail, you could lose everything.
So let's look at how
much my a hundred dollars
investment is now worth.
Let me refresh your memory.
Here's what I invested in.
So I'm gonna throw a dart at the board,
and as you can see,
(upbeat music)
I randomly selected 20 different stocks,
and wherever the dart lands,
that's what I'm gonna invest in.
Now, I've just gotta put on a blindfold.
Okay, here we go.
- [Crew] Oh, you hit it.
- Right, let's see what we got.
And we've gone into Samsung.
That investment is now worth $67.66,
(cash register dinging)
but don't forget my dividends.
Over the four years, I made 10 cents.
(cash register dinging)
(Mark chuckling)
So that leaves me with a total
of $67.76.
(cash register dinging)
That's a negative 32.34% return.
This example perfectly shows how hit
or miss individual stock
investing really is.
That dark could have just
as easily landed on Apple,
Microsoft, or Nvidia.
So let's have a look at
how much I would've made
if that dart had landed a bit differently.
A $100 investment in Apple four years ago
would now be worth $170.
(cash register dinging)
The same investment in Microsoft
would be $188.
(cash register dinging)
And drum roll please,
Nvidia would be worth $908.
(cash register dinging)
Those stocks have boomed in recent years,
and luckily, I have some of
those in my personal portfolio.
But this just goes to show,
you can't just leave
individual stock investing
down to luck.
You have to be strategic
with your stock picks,
and even then, the
market is unpredictable.
If you want to try this out,
just download Trading 212.
It's a great app for beginner investors,
because it lets you use a demo account
to practice trading with fake money.
This way, you can learn how it all works
without risking any real cash,
just like I mentioned earlier.
It also lets you set up a stocks
and shares ISA if you're in the UK,
which protects your
investment returns from taxes.
But again, I'm not a tax advisor,
so please do your own research,
as everyone's situation is unique.
Trading 212 also lets you
buy fractional shares,
which means you don't
have to a whole stock.
That's how I was able to own
just nought point nought seven
of a Samsung stock,
instead of having to buy an entire share.
As I was gonna mention Trading 212 anyway,
I reached out to see
if they'd be interested
in sponsoring this portion of the video.
They agreed and are offering
a free fractional share worth
up to a hundred pound to anyone
that uses the code Tilbury
when they create an account.
Plus, you can get more free
shares by inviting your friends.
Both of you will get a free share,
as long as they fund their account.
I'll leave the link in a
description if you're interested.
(upbeat music)
Second is a real estate investment trust,
otherwise known as a REIT.
I know this one sounds pretty complicated,
but it's actually quite cool.
Imagine your friend
collects a hundred dollars
from 3,000 people, giving him $300,000.
He then uses that money to
buy a property, rents it out,
and shares the rental
income with all 3,000 people
who helped him buy it.
That's a simple way to explain a REIT.
It allows anyone to invest in properties
without needing to buy one themselves.
Think of it like you own the front door,
someone else owns a window,
and a few others own the bricks,
which means together, everyone
owns the entire property
and shares in the profits.
The learning curve, I'm
gonna say it's moderate,
and that's because getting started
with REITs is much easier
than buying physical property.
It's not like you need a huge
down payment or a mortgage,
and there's no need to deal
with agents or solicitors.
However, you do need to
understand how REITs work.
They own things like
offices, shopping centers,
apartments, hotels, and much more,
and they get their income through rent.
For passive income potential,
I'm gonna say this is great.
REITs are well known for
paying high dividends.
This is because the law says they have
to pass on at least 90% of all
their profits to investors.
So as long as the REIT is doing well
and its properties are rented out,
you can earn a steady
stream of passive income.
Most businesses sign long-term leases
on their commercial properties.
Therefore, most of the time,
income is pretty stable and reliable.
But of course, just keep in mind
that your earnings depend
on the REIT you pick
and the types of properties it owns.
For tax efficiency, I'm
gonna put this down as great.
This is because in many countries,
REITs offer great tax benefits.
For example, in the UK, you
can hold REITs in a stocks
and shares ISA, which means you don't have
to pay taxes on your profits or dividends.
In terms of risk, I'd have
to say this is medium.
REITs are generally less risky
than buying a single property,
because they invest in
multiple properties,
spreading out the risk.
However, they're not risk free.
If the real estate market takes a downturn
or if the REIT struggles to
keep its properties rented,
you might see both a drop in dividends
and the value of the investment.
So what's my investment worth now?
Let's flashback to me making
the investment four years ago.
As I'm in the UK, I'm gonna
use the Trading 212 website
to put a hundred dollars
into a similar REIT.
Ready for the moment of truth?
Looking at my investment now,
I can see it's worth $98.59 cents,
(cash register dinging)
so that's a a small loss of 1.41%.
This shows that even though
REITs are normally more stable
than individual stocks,
they're not guaranteed to perform well.
My REIT likely underperformed
because it invested in
commercial real estate,
which struggled during the pandemic,
but that's not the end of the world.
As I made $11.93 cents back in dividends,
meaning I'm actually $10.52 up,
(cash register dinging)
so that's
(eraser squeaking)
10.52% up.
(upbeat music)
Third is cryptocurrency.
Imagine a form of digital
money that isn't controlled
by any government or bank.
That's what cryptocurrencies
like Bitcoin and Ethereum are.
These currencies run on
the blockchain technology,
which makes them secure, transparent,
and almost impossible to counterfeit.
Cryptocurrencies have
created massive wealth
for some people,
with Bitcoin being the
best performing asset
of the last decade.
But on the flip side,
it's highly volatile,
and people have also lost fortunes.
That's why I describe
crypto as part investment
and part speculation,
and not for the faint hearted.
For learning curve, I'm
gonna say it's moderate.
Crypto might sound complicated,
but I'll break it down for you.
First, you'll need a wallet.
This is where you store your crypto.
Think of it like a digital piggy bank,
and there are different types.
First are online wallets.
These are easy to use,
but you'll need to protect them
with very strong passwords.
Second, are offline wallets,
like hardware wallets.
These are the safest,
because they're not
connected to the internet.
Next, you'll need to
pick an exchange to buy
and sell your crypto.
Some popular ones are
Coinbase and Binance.
These platforms make it simple to trade,
but make sure to choose
a trustworthy exchange
to avoid any issues.
Then there's tokenomics.
This just means
understanding how the supply
and demand of a coin works.
For example, bitcoin has a limited supply,
which is why it's often
called digital gold.
For passive income potential,
I'm gonna also say this is moderate.
Unlike stocks or REITs,
crypto doesn't pay dividends,
but there are ways to earn passive income.
The first is called staking.
This is when you lock up
your crypto, like Ethereum,
to help the system work
and process transactions.
In return, you get paid rewards,
kind of like earning
points for helping out.
The second is yield farming.
This is when you lend
your crypto out to others
and earn interest on it,
similar to how a bank pays you interest
when you save money with them.
These methods can generate decent returns,
but they do come with higher risks.
If the coin's value drops
or the platform you are using gets hacked,
your income could disappear,
along with your crypto.
That's why I personally
don't mess with any of this
and just hold mine on a ledger wallet.
For tax efficiency,
I'm gonna have to say this one is poor.
Taxes are a tricky part
of crypto investing.
In many countries,
even swapping one cryptocurrency
for another counts
as a taxable event,
and if you earn stake in rewards,
those are also taxed as income.
You also can't hold crypto
in tax advantaged accounts
like ISAs or Roth IRAs,
which makes it less tax
efficient than stocks or REITs.
In terms of risk, I'd have
to say it's very high.
Crypto is one of the most
volatile investments out there.
Prices can soar a thousand
percent in a year,
but they can also crash just as fast.
Personally, I just invest in Bitcoin
and Ethereum, as they're more established
and often referred to as
blue chip cryptocurrencies.
Smaller alt coins can be far more risky.
You've also gotta be cautious of scams.
Since crypto isn't regulated,
if someone hacks your wallet
or tricks you into sending your coins,
there's no way to get them back.
So keeping your crypto
safe is just as important
as learning how to invest in it.
So what's my investment worth now?
Let's rewind to when I made
this investment four years ago.
So I'm gonna jump onto the
most popular Bitcoin app,
which is called Coinbase,
and invest my a hundred dollars in Bitcoin
and forget about it.
(upbeat music)
Ready for the reveal?
The $100 I invested in
Bitcoin is now worth
$652.24 cents.
(cash registering dinging)
That's a return of 552.24%.
Now, I know what you're thinking.
That's insane, and it is,
but I have to stress
that this kind of growth is not typical.
Bitcoin has been the best performing asset
of the last decade,
but most cryptocurrencies don't
see these kinds of returns.
Many lose their value entirely.
In my opinion, crypto is exciting
and the technology behind
it has the potential
to transform industries.
However, it's not for everyone.
It's highly volatile, speculative,
and requires a strong stomach
to handle the wild price swings.
Just remember, crypto
is all about high risk
and high reward.
So if you're gonna dive in,
make sure you're doing your
research and investing wisely.
(upbeat music)
Fourth is gold.
This is one of the oldest
and most trusted ways
to store and protect wealth.
Gold is often called a safe haven,
because it's a great way
to protect your wealth
during uncertain times,
like when inflation is rising
or the economy is struggling.
For learning curve, I'm
gonna have to say it's low.
Learning how to invest
in gold is pretty simple.
You have two main options.
First, physical gold.
This includes gold bars and coins.
Many people also think
you can buy gold jewelry
as investments, but you'll often pay more
than the gold is actually worth,
because sellers add a markup
for their craftsmanship.
For this reason, I personally
stick to gold coins.
Just bear in mind, if
you pick this option,
then you'd have to
store it somewhere safe.
Second is gold ETFs.
These are funds that
let you invest in gold
without physically owning it.
For example, in the UK,
you can use Trading 212
to buy shares in something
like the iShares Physical Gold ETF.
It's quick, easy, and you can buy
or sell it with just a few clicks.
Passive income potential
is absolutely zero.
Unlike stocks, REITs, or crypto,
gold doesn't pay any passive income.
It's not an income generating asset.
It's purely a store of value.
For tax efficiency,
I'm gonna put this as good.
If you buy physical gold
like gold coins or bars,
the tax rules can be a little tricky.
For example, in some
countries, certain gold coins,
like the UK's gold Britannias,
are considered legal tender,
which means you don't
pay capital gains tax
when you sell them.
However, this doesn't
apply to all gold coins
or bars, so you'll need to
check the specific rules
in your country.
For gold ETFs, they're
generally more straightforward.
In countries like the UK,
you can hold them in a stocks
and shares ISA, which makes any
profits completely tax free.
Interestingly, physical gold
has another unique advantage.
It can be used to transport wealth
across borders discreetly.
That said, this approach comes with risk,
such as theft or legal restrictions
on transporting large amounts
of gold across borders.
While it's not something
I'd necessarily recommend,
it's worth mentioning as a unique aspect
of owning physical gold.
In terms of risk, I'd
say this is a medium.
Gold is one of the safest
investments you can make.
It's been used as a form of
money for thousands of years,
and it's known to hold its
value during times of inflation
or economic uncertainty.
However, the opportunity cost of investing
in gold can be a downside.
While it's great for
protecting your wealth,
it doesn't have the same growth potential
as other investments
like stocks or crypto.
So what's my investment worth now?
Let's flash back
to when I made this
investment four years ago.
I'm gonna invest using Trading
212 in a similar share.
And with just a click of a button,
there you go.
I'm now Mr. Goldman.
So what's Mr. Goldman's
investment worth today?
Well, it's currently sitting
at $140.10 cents.
(cash register dinging)
That's a return of 40.1%.
Now, that's not as exciting
as Bitcoin's performance,
but it's solid, steady growth.
This shows how gold is better
for protecting your wealth,
rather than rapidly growing it.
(upbeat music)
Fifth is index funds.
Imagine owning a tiny piece
of the largest companies
like Apple, Microsoft,
and Amazon all at once.
That's exactly what an
index fund allows you to do.
It's a basket of stocks
that mirrors the performance
of a specific index like the S&P 500.
So you're investing in the overall market,
rather than betting on
individual companies.
For learning curve,
I'm gonna have to say this one is low.
Unlike individual stocks where you need
to dig into the financial statements
and company performers, index
funds are passive investments.
You don't have to pick and choose stocks,
as they're already
bundled together for you.
Getting started is simple too.
Platforms like Trading 212
let you buy index funds
with just a few clicks.
Once you've invested, all
you need to do is sit back
and let the market do the work.
For passive income potential,
I'm gonna say this is moderate.
Index funds don't directly
pay high dividends like REITs,
but they still provide some income.
Many companies in the fund pay dividends,
and those are automatically
distributed to you
or reinvested back into the
fund, depending on your choice.
While the main focus of index
funds is long-term growth,
the dividend income can be a nice bonus,
especially if you're investing in funds
that focus on dividend paying companies.
For tax efficiency,
I'm gonna say this one is great.
If you hold index funds in a stocks
and shares ISA in the UK,
or a Roth IRA in the USA,
you can avoid paying taxes on dividends
and capital gains altogether.
This means you get to keep
more of your profits over time,
which can make a huge difference
when you're investing for the long haul.
In terms of risks, I'd
say it's pretty low.
Index funds are much
less risky than investing
in individual stocks,
because they're diversified.
Instead of putting all your
money into a few companies,
you're spreading it across hundreds
or even thousands of stocks
in different industries.
Historically, the S&P 500 has delivered
average annual returns
of around eight to 10%
over the long term.
While the market can go up
and down in the short term,
if you hold onto an index fund for 10, 20,
or even 30 years, it's
one of the safest ways
to grow your wealth.
However, of course, there are still risks
like with any investment.
So what's my investment worth now?
Let's rewind to when I made
this investment four years ago.
If we head over to Vanguard's website now
and we find the S&P 500,
and deposit some money,
and then click, there you go.
Job done.
Right, so time for the reveal.
Today, that investment is worth
$179.57.
(cash register dinging)
That's a return of 79.57%.
This result shows why index
funds are such a great option
for most investors.
They're simple, low cost,
and consistently deliver
solid returns over time.
Personally, index funds
are my favorite investment,
which is why I've allocated
the majority of my money there.
However, I also understand the importance
of diversification, so I
spread smaller percentages
across all the other investments
we've discussed today.
This way, I can balance growth, stability,
and risk in my portfolio.
So whether you're diving
into individual stocks,
buying some REITs, exploring
crypto, getting into gold,
or sticking with a steady
reliability of index funds,
each investment has its pros and cons.
Some are better for growing
your wealth quickly,
while others are designed to
protect it over the long term.
The most important
lesson is to start early.
Even small amounts
like the a hundred dollars
we've been working with can grow
into something significant thanks
to the power of compounding.
Time is your best friend
when it comes to investing,
so don't wait to get started.
If you wanna know what the laziest way
to make money online
is, then I'm gonna leave
that video right up there, but
don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe
(mouse clicking)
if you want to grow your wealth.
Okay?
(Mark clicking tongue)
I'll see you over there.