This video is gonna
create future millionaires
because I'm gonna explain
exactly what you need to be doing
at ages 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, and 18,
so you can get financially ahead.
And if you're older, then
use this as a checklist
to make sure you are on track.
I promise if you just implement
a few of these things,
you'll be so far ahead of everyone else,
they won't even believe you.
I managed to become a
millionaire in my 20s.
However, if I watched a video
like this when I was younger,
then I'm sure I could have made
my first million much faster.
Don't just watch the part of
the video that's for your age.
You need to do all of these things.
And if you skip steps, you
might end up regretting it.
Right, let's kick this off with age 13.
(cog whirring)
(bell chimes)
When it comes to investing,
the, hands down, most important
thing is time in the market.
But what does that actually mean?
Well, put simply, you wanna
have your money invested
for as long as possible so
it can start growing rapidly,
like a snowball rolling down a hill
and eventually turning into an avalanche.
So if you are actually 13 or younger
and you're watching this video right now,
I think all us oldies would agree
that you are in the
best possible position.
So how do you actually
start investing at this age?
Well, as you're currently not of legal age
to invest on your own, you
are gonna need to convince
a parent or guardian to open up something
called a custodial account.
Now, I understand it might be
hard to speak to your parents
about money and investing.
My parents never ever
spoke about money at all,
let alone investing.
So if you want to feel free to
show them the next 30 seconds
of this video so I can help persuade them
to open up one for you.
A custodial account is an
investing account controlled
by an adult for the benefit of a minor,
typically, a family member.
These have different names
depending on where you live.
In the UK, we have something called
a junior stocks and shares ISA,
which lets your parent or
guardian invest up to 9,000 pounds
a year on your behalf.
Now, of course, they don't
have to do this much,
but just think every birthday or Christmas
you could ask them to put
some money into the account
and invest in some stocks and shares.
I'm not a financial advisor,
and this shouldn't be
taken as financial advice.
However, over the years,
I've just invested
in a simple low-cost S&P 500 index fund.
This invests your money
across just over 500
of the biggest public
companies in the USA,
so you don't have to worry
about picking individual stocks.
The historical average
yearly return of the S&P 500
is 12.58% over the last 10 years,
as of the end of May, 2024.
Of course, investments
can go down as well as up.
If you've got a junior
stocks and shares ISA,
then you'll be able to start
managing it for yourself
from the age of 16, and you
could start to withdraw money
from the age of 18 if you wanted to.
But if you're anything like me,
once you've got the investing bug,
you'll probably want to keep it growing.
In America, you have two main options,
a UGMA and a UTMA.
These both have unlimited contributions,
but you could trigger gift
tax if your parent or guardian
puts in more than $18,000 in one year.
The only real difference between these two
is that with a UTMA, you can
also invest in real estate
and fine art.
A custodial account can be set up
with most banks and brokerages.
My favorite is Vanguard for
both the UK and the USA,
as they have pretty low fees,
and they've certainly been
around for a long time.
So if you're younger than
18, then please, please,
please promise me you talk to your parents
about getting one of these accounts,
as it gives you such a head start.
Right, moving on to age 14.
(cogs whirring)
(bell chimes)
Besides time, another huge
advantage you have at this age
is that you probably
don't have to pay rent
and other monthly bills.
This means you have the freedom
to try different ways to make money,
since you don't need a reliable
income every single month.
You should go out and try
everything from cleaning driveways
with pressure washers
to competitive sports.
Not everything has to
be about making money.
You can learn a lot from other activities
which you can use to make
money when you're older.
My son, Curtis, used to get
up at 4:00 AM most mornings
for swimming practice.
Of course, he didn't
earn any money from this,
but it did teach him discipline.
So when he started his business at 18,
he could outwork his competition.
I speak to so many teenagers who tell me
they don't have a talent.
But when I ask them
what their hobbies are,
they can't even name a few they've tried.
You can't expect to find your talent
if you don't try a wide
range of different things.
If it doesn't work out,
then that's absolutely fine.
Just try the next thing and the next.
When you find something
you are naturally good at
or enjoy getting better
at, double down on it,
and make it your mission
to become one of the best.
Next, age 15.
(cogs whirring)
(bell chimes)
One of the things I miss
most about being younger
is birthday and Christmas presents.
Not that I got a lot, as my
parents weren't very wealthy,
but I definitely got more than I do now.
That's just the reality of growing up,
especially for young men.
So instead of asking for
presents like PS4 games
and other things that you're
not really gonna care about
in less than a few months,
a huge life hack is to ask
for cash whenever possible.
I'd also highly recommend going
and getting a Saturday job.
Now, don't be too picky at this stage.
Even working in a retail
store behind a counter
can earn you a nice bit of extra money.
You'll also learn a lot
of useful social skills
that will prepare you for the real world.
Doing both of these
things will help you start
stashing away cash as long,
as you avoid the temptation to spend it.
I like to use the word
stash instead of save,
as I have a problem with
the way most teenagers
approach saving money.
They will save for months,
and then go and spend it
all on a new game console
or a day at the theme park.
Now, obviously, we all
like a rollercoaster,
that's for sure.
This shouldn't be what you're
stashing cash for, though.
Of course you should spend
some of it to have fun.
However, see your stash
more like a launch pad
that you can use to make even more money.
The hardest thing in the world is starting
with $0 to your name.
So if you can avoid that,
even if you have as little
as $100, then it's gonna make
everything so much easier.
Oh, and I almost forgot, go and apply
for your provisional driving license.
In the UK, you can do
this when you're 15 years
and nine months old,
so it's worth getting,
even if you don't intend to
start using it right away.
Right, now it's getting serious, age 16.
(cogs whirring)
(bell chimes)
You've got a two-year window
before you enter the real world,
so it is time to really
think about what skills
you are gonna start
focusing on and developing.
By now, if you've done all
the things I've mentioned
in this video, then you should
have a pretty solid idea
of what you are good at.
These may seem unrelated at first,
but pick a handful of them
and start stacking your skills
on top of each other.
When I was younger, I
was talented at selling,
designing mechanics and woodwork.
So I invested my money
into different things
that would help me get
better at those skills.
Now, I had no idea how
I'd link them together,
but I trusted that in the
end, it would all make sense.
I'm not really talking
about buying courses,
as there's so many fake gurus out.
They're just trying to
scam you out of your money.
With that said, there are
some good ones around as well.
Even better though, if you can
find some sort of community
to join where you can chat
and learn, so much the better.
However, the majority of your money
should be invested in equipment.
I remember when my son
bought his first iMac
for $500 from his uncle.
He did this with the money he'd saved
from doing part-time jobs.
Because that was the biggest
purchase he'd ever made
at the time, he would sit at that Mac
and learn everything about it.
This led to him teaching
himself how to edit videos
and use Photoshop.
Investing in tools like this
can really open so many doors.
Between now and 18, your
biggest aim should be to develop
these different skills
that you can later use
to make more money than someone
that just decided to play video games.
This is because you can
come into the real world
with some actual value to offer.
This heavily cuts down
the amount of training
a company needs to give you
which takes the burden off them.
Onto age 17.
(cogs whirring)
(bell chimes)
Now, listen to me very carefully.
You need to pass your driving test.
Yes, I know you probably don't
need to drive anywhere at 17,
but trust me, the sooner
you do this, the better.
In some states in the USA, you
can do this as early as 16.
Remember, you only need to do it once.
Not being able to drive is
one of the biggest things
stopping most people from
starting a side hustle.
I mean, what if you have the
chance to work with a client
but they live 30 minutes away,
and you can't get a lift every week?
You'd have to rely on public transport,
and we all know how unreliable that is.
You'll probably end up getting
a bad name for yourself
and coming across as unprofessional,
leading to that opportunity
going (whistles softly)
out the window.
One of my key rules to this day
is to be early is to be on time.
To be on time is to be late.
And to be late, well,
that is unacceptable.
So if you're watching this now
and considering driving lessons, do it.
Please don't be that person
that regrets not jumping on it sooner.
Yes, it might be a bit scary at first.
I thought it was really
exciting, to be honest,
but think about the bigger picture.
Once you've learned you
can use some of that money
you've been stashing away to buy yourself
a cheap starter car, then
nothing's holding you back.
Now it's time for the big one, age 18.
(cogs whirring)
(bell chimes)
The world really opens up
to you once you turn 18.
Now you're officially classed as an adult,
and there are so many things you can do
to get financially ahead.
I wish someone had sat me
down on my 18th birthday
and told me exactly what I needed to do.
So that's what I'm gonna do for you now.
I've made a checklist of
seven things you need to do
to set yourself up for success.
Even if you're over the age of 18,
it's super important you
do all of these things
sooner rather than later.
Let me know in the comments
how many you've ticked off.
Number one, open your own bank accounts.
Having your own bank accounts
that only you have access to
is the first logical step you should take
once you're over the age of 18.
I say accounts because, really and truly,
you should have two.
The first is a current account,
or as the Americans call
it, a checking account.
This is where your money
should flow in and out.
For example, let's say
you got yourself a job
at a coffee shop.
The coffee shop pays your wage
into your current account,
and then you can use that money
on whatever you want really.
The second is a high-interest
savings account.
This is where you should start
building up an emergency fund
of three to six months
of your living expenses
just in case something out
of your control happens
and your income dries up.
It's like when you chug
a big pot shield potion
on "Fortnite," but keep some minis handy.
So where should you
open up these accounts?
Well, you need to be looking for banks
that don't charge high fees.
I remember I used to get charged
for stupid little things all the time.
Having these accounts
shouldn't cost you money.
I also think you should have two accounts
with different banks,
as it makes your savings
way less easier to spend.
When it's outta sight, it's outta mind.
If you're in the UK,
then I'd recommend going
with a challenger bank like
Monzo for your current account.
Now, this isn't sponsored,
but their app is genuinely very good.
For your savings account,
Chase is a great option,
as they're currently offering
4.1% interest on your money,
so you'll get paid for just leaving
your money in the account.
In the USA, I would recommend
looking at Ally Bank
or Bank of America because
they offer minimal fees
and have really strong
online banking service.
Number two, get a credit card.
When I was younger, I believe
that if you never borrowed,
you'd have an amazing credit score,
since you never took out a
loan or made any late payments.
It makes sense, right?
Well, that couldn't be
further from the truth.
Taking out a credit card when you turn 18
is the perfect tool to
build up your credit score.
You can do this by using your credit card
to pay for the things you
would normally pay for in cash,
like paying for the gas
in your car, for example,
and then paying the card off in full
every month without fail.
Using it this way will ensure
that you never get charged
any interest at the
same time as building up
your credit score.
A credit score is kind of
like you're Uber rating
but for money.
Banks look at this and then they decide
whether or not they're
gonna give you a loan,
and if they do, what interest
rate they're gonna charge you.
Now, lots of people are against the idea
of getting a credit card
because they're taught
from a really young age
that debt is bad.
I know this because that's
exactly what I was taught.
My dad would always say, "Never
a lender or a borrower be."
This was a saying that
originally came from rich people
years and years ago to
keep the workers down,
as they knew, by borrowing,
the working class
could create wealth for themselves.
The rich wanted to keep getting richer
and keep the poor in their place.
If I had a credit card when I was 18,
it would've been much easier
to get a mortgage sooner
and buy my first property.
I would've also been
able to borrow more money
at lower interest rates.
Now, that may not sound significant,
but over a long period, like a mortgage,
this can really add up.
Number three, open an invest in account.
The key is to open the
correct type of account.
You'll often hear people
throwing around terms
like Roth IRA in the USA,
stocks and shares ISA in the UK,
and TFSA in Canada, and
supers in Australia.
So if you don't have
one of these accounts,
then you're missing out,
as they allow you to avoid
having to pay taxes on your investments.
But they do have limits because
they're extremely powerful.
Nowadays, opening an investing
account is very simple,
as you can do it all
from your mobile phone.
A great thing about these investing apps
is that it actually gives you the ability
to buy fractional shares.
So rather than having to
pay $220 for an Apple share,
you can invest as little as $1.
Now, I wish I had this
option when I was younger,
as it would've allowed me to
get in some early experience
with investing without
having to take any big risks.
One of my favorite investing
platforms is Trading 212,
as they offer fractional shares
and also stocks and shares ISAs.
Since I was planning to
talk about their app anyway,
I reached out to them to
see if they'd be interested
in sponsoring this portion of the video.
They agreed, and are offering a free stock
worth of up to 100 pound to anyone
that uses the code Tilbury
when they create an account.
Plus, you can get more free
stocks by inviting your friends.
Both of you will get a free share
as long as they fund their account.
If you aren't quite
ready to invest for real,
one of the really cool
things about Trading 212
is they let you practice
investing with fake money.
You can get familiar with the markets
using real data without
risking any actual money.
So if you're a little
uncomfortable with investing
or just want to try out some strategies
before putting your own money on the line,
this is a great way to get started.
Also, don't worry if you've
already opened an account
within the last 10 days.
You can still use a promo
code Tilbury in the app
and receive your free share.
So feel free to pause a video right now,
get your free stock, and
then continue watching.
Number four, carefully
consider university.
So many teenagers have asked me,
"Is going to university a scam?"
My answer is always yes and no.
On one hand, for some careers,
you certainly need to go to university
like doctors, nurses, and teachers.
There is a direct result
from doing university courses like this.
You get a degree, and the
career path opens up to you.
These professions play
critical roles in our society
directly impacting the way we function,
so are absolutely not a scam.
I actually think these types
of courses should be free
and reserved for the
people with the best grades
and passion for following
one of these careers.
However, on the other hand,
there are a lot of other courses
out there that don't open up
job opportunities directly,
and therefore, why waste your money
and, more importantly, your
time studying at university
for something you don't really need?
Skill trades like
plumbing, entrepreneurship
and tech, well, they
don't require a degree.
It's more about how good
you are at what you do.
Your track record and results
will speak for itself.
I mean, I read through
my comments on here,
and I've seen lots of people
claim they've learned more
from me than they did in
their business degree.
Now, that really says a lot.
For me, and for a lot of other employers,
it's more about your practical experience
and attitude than anything else.
So please, don't be pressured
into go into university
to study something you don't care about
and waste four years of your life.
I mean, I heard there's a
golf management degree now.
How ridiculous. Personally, I love golf.
I just want a major competition
called The Duke of Edinburgh Cup.
I didn't need to go to university
to learn how to play or manage the game.
It's laughable. It really is.
Look, if you really dunno
what to do with your life,
my advice would be to
get an apprenticeship.
They were huge back in my day,
and they're coming back and
getting more popular than ever.
Plus, you get paid what you're learning.
It's a win-win situation, if you ask me.
So will those schools,
then maybe your mates
will try and push you to go to university,
think about what you really want.
Think about the 60 to 100k of debt
that you could have
wrapped around your neck
and ask yourself, is it
worth paying that off
for the whole of your life?
Number five, avoid bad debt.
Debt is like a heavy
anchor that drags you down,
slowing your progress and holding you back
from reaching your full potential.
Don't get me wrong, in some cases,
you can use debt to your advantage,
like when buying a property, for example.
Taking on a mortgage to buy real estate
can be a really smart investment
because property can go up
in value as time goes by.
By using this debt strategically,
you can leverage this
borrowed money to have access
to these assets that
will hopefully increase
your long term net worth.
The same goes for having
your own business.
If you borrow moneys to
start your own business
and it takes off, you can
make some serious profit.
Without that initial money,
you might never be successful.
I know that was the case
for me when I opened up
my first radio control model shop.
Without a loan, I simply
couldn't have started.
However, there is a type of debt
you should avoid at all costs,
and this is consumer debt.
If you can't afford to
buy something outright
that isn't going to create wealth,
then you shouldn't buy it.
A lot of people finance their cars,
and this is just one example
of where borrowing money
actually leaves you worse
off in the long run.
Here in the UK, a shocking
2.2 million drivers
finance their cars, and I'm willing to bet
most of them are stuck in this money trap.
I understand that you might
wanna drive a certain car.
Now, I love cars, so I
totally understand that.
I get it, but is it really worth it?
Just something for you to think about.
Number six, start a side hustle.
Most people's advice when you turn 18 is,
"Go and get a job."
They make it sound so miserable,
and it's like you get no
choice with your life.
That's what you're expected to do.
Go to your job and be miserable.
Well, let me tell you, it
doesn't have to be this way.
You don't have to wake up every morning
thinking that you're
stuck and not progressing.
If you follow this video so far,
you'll have some valuable skills,
and you can use them to start
a service-based side hustle.
This type of side hustle is great.
Think copywriting, video
editing, videography,
web development, and community management.
All of these require very
little startup money.
You just need to master
the skill inside and out.
If you haven't got a
high-income skill yet,
then you really need to catch up.
So no matter what job you
go and get, leverage it.
Use the skills it gives
you and the money you make
to transform your daily
grind into a launch pad
for greater things.
Even if you can't learn
any skills from it,
use it as motivation to put in
the extra work on the weekend
to learn a valuable skill
and improve your current situation.
Start viewing it like this.
Every shift you dread is an
investment towards your future.
Number seven, invest for the long term.
Compound interest is an
extremely powerful law,
especially when it comes to investing.
It means that not only
will you earn an interest
on your initial investment,
but you also earn interest
on the interest that
you've already earned.
This can lead to your money growing bigger
and bigger over time.
It's like when you create that snowball
and roll it down the hill,
it just keeps getting bigger
and bigger and bigger the more
snow that's packed onto it.
For example, let's say you
invest $250 a month at age 18
into a Roth IRA or a
stocks and shares ISA.
Assuming an average yearly return of 8%
by the age of 65, your
investment could grow
to approximately $1.5 million tax free.
Now, if we compare this to
someone who starts investing
the same amount at age
28, by the age he's 65,
their investment would
only reach around $679,000
under the same conditions.
That's less than half the amount.
See, those extra 10 years of compounding
really boost the final amount
because there's more time for
interest to build on interest.
So the younger you start, the better.
Not only will you have time on your side,
but you'll also typically
earn less at a younger age,
placing you in a lower tax bracket.
This means you'll keep
more of your earnings
because you won't be taxed as heavily
compared to when you
earn more later in life.
If you want to dive deeper into
how to pick the best stocks,
then watch this video next.
But don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.