- Believe it or not,
you could be making at least 10K a month
doing something you absolutely love.
This method is what around 85%
of the young millionaires I meet use,
and if I started from
scratch again, I'd do it too.
Selling info products.
I was inspired to make this video
after I stumbled across an
info product the other day,
teaching you how to look
after chickens at home.
The part-time farmer
who created this info product
is making over $20,000 a month
selling 20 of these online programs
at $1000 each.
If you wanna achieve
the same, grab a notepad
as I'm gonna explain the steps
you need to take in order
to make over $10,000 per
month with info products.
(upbeat music)
Unlike traditional
businesses such as this cafe,
info products cater to every market.
Just think, no location
limitations whatsoever.
Right now, I'm at one
of my favorite beaches,
but whether you are in the UK or overseas,
we can still buy the same
information products online.
Since they're digitalized,
they're not tied
to one specific market.
Even though info products
have a global reach,
they're still limited
by the niche you pick.
So make sure there's enough
demand and minimal competition.
Consider the health niche for example.
I normally just think about
online personal trainers
and workout plans, and let me
tell you, that's not for me,
but a guy called Anthony
Metivier thought outside the box
and used his knowledge of languages
to create the Magnetic Memory Method,
which is an info product focused
on enhancing your memory skills.
Now, I could do with a bit of that myself.
It's not just for seniors
looking to stay mentally sharp,
students are also using
it to excel in exams,
meaning he's captured an
extremely diverse audience.
So Anthony identified a niche,
pinpointed valuable knowledge within it,
and as a result is
generating an annual income
of more than $120,000.
So how can you do this too?
Well first choose a skill.
Let's say a sport like
tennis, for example.
If you can become like a
six outta 10 skill-wise,
then people will want to learn from you.
However, taking this
route is time consuming.
Additionally, if you're not an expert,
it could negatively affect sales
because you may not appear
as trustworthy as someone
with prior professional experience.
So how can you overcome this?
Well, you could pair up with
an expert in the tennis world
and build an info product together.
An expert doesn't have
to be an ex-professional.
They might have experience in
tennis tutoring, run a club,
or have a sport qualification.
If you are more business
orientated, then this allows you
to work behind the scenes
to ensure it all runs smoothly
whilst the actual tennis coach
teaches within the videos
or writes the step-by-step guides.
Say you sell 20 programs
per month at a rate
of $997 per month.
It always seems to end in a seven.
That would generate $19,940.
Then shed 50/50 with
your business partner.
That would total around about
$10,000 each, to be exact,
it would be $9,970 profit.
Of course, you need to
minus your expenses,
but you get the idea
and they're not gonna be
that much on an info product.
Now, you could either
choose to scale this up
and sell more programs per month,
or you could partner with another expert
and repeat the process.
It would be a lot quicker
the second time around
as you'll just be
repeating a proven formula.
(upbeat music)
Traditional businesses
are making a real plate
towards building out their own communities
because they've seen
the rise of influencers
and the power of followings.
Take this PrettyLittleThing
order for example,
my son's girlfriend
goes mad for this stuff.
This unmistakable pink unicorn packaging
is so much more than just a plastic bag.
It's a symbolic gateway
into the brand community,
connecting customers
with influencers who wear
and help design the clothes.
PLT's online community pulls
in a whopping 712.2
million pounds annually,
which is the equivalent to
almost $900 million a year.
So they've obviously
been extremely successful
in attracting customers
with their branding,
which not only enhances
the sense of community,
but also helps to convert
fans into paying customers.
So what can we take from this?
Well, if you want to increase
your conversion rates,
then you need to build
some kind of community
around your info product.
But why are conversion rates so important?
Well, let's say you reached
50,000 potential customers online,
then normally you can
expect a 2% conversion rate,
which would mean you sell 1000 products.
Let's say you price them at $1000 each.
With a conversion rate of 2%,
that means you are gonna make
$100,000, not bad, right?
Well, imagine if the people
that you reach felt like they
were part of something bigger,
a community led by you in a
free Facebook or Discord group,
you could boost that conversion rate
to 5%, which means you'd
sell 2,500 products
and make, woo-hoo, quarter
of a million dollars.
Hopefully now you can see
why brands are pumping
so much time and money into
building online communities,
but building communities
from scratch is hard.
So here's how I'd go about
it, build a personal brand.
I mean, there's so much free
traffic on TikTok right now.
I don't necessarily think
you need a personal brand.
Of course you could just run ads,
but it's definitely a much
more cost effective way
to reach a mass audience and
make a personal connection.
One of my old video editors
actually followed this exact roadmap.
He wasn't the best editor
out there and honestly,
he was a little bit lazy,
but he understood how to
make a YouTube channel
and has now launched
his own editing course.
All of his videos combined
have garnered millions
of views in the editing niche,
and he's now making more
than $10,000 per month,
and his community worships
him like some kind
of editing God,
and I bet he still can't
get outta bed on time.
You seriously don't need
to be the next Mr. Beast.
If you build a strong
community of 50,000 people,
then there is no reason
why you can't be making $100,000 a year.
Actually, I take that back.
You definitely should
be making 100K a year.
Just make sure you collect
everyone's contact details
and build an email list as this way,
you can own your audience and not rent it
from a social media platform
that could shut you down at any point.
(upbeat music)
Businesses have been taking
advantage of upselling
for years, and it's only
getting more common.
McDonald's have introduced
digital ordering screens
to almost all of their locations.
These machines always
try to upsell customers
to larger meals, sometimes
even using pulsing pictures
to make you click on them.
Even after you've finished ordering,
another screen pops up
offering additional items
with attractive pictures aiming
to maximize the amount of money per order.
Here's a diagram of something
called the value ladder.
This is what companies use
to upsell customers and so can you.
As you can see, the customer
will always be lured in
by some bait and then encouraged
to the top of the ladder
through various offers.
Let's put this into context.
There's a new video game out
and it hooks you in with
a free trial, the bait,
the temptations take over
and you've bought the full version.
That's the first step.
After this, they offer a weapon pack and
before you know it, you've
spent your entire monthly wage
and you've reached the top of the ladder.
So how can you create a
value ladder of your own?
Well, imagine you are selling
a fitness info product,
so the bait could be a free workout guide
which draws people in.
For your first step, you could
offer a four week program
for $9.99 cents.
Then you could follow this up
with a personalized coaching
package for $999 a year.
I mean, you could even follow this up
with VIP one-to-one sessions
for $5,000 per year.
So if a hundred thousand people
download your free workout
guide and 5% buy the program,
that would make you $49,950.
If 5% of those people, which
would be 250, opt for coaching,
this would add an extra
$249,750 to your pocket.
And then if 2% of those people,
which would be five people,
join your one-to-one VIP coaching,
it would bring in an extra $25,000.
That value ladder would
generate you a total
of $324,700 per year.
And if you wanna make even
more, then you just have
to reach more people initially.
I mean, if you manage
to get 1 million people
to download your free workout guide,
then you can multiply
all these numbers by 10.
(upbeat music)
As we discussed, creating
and selling info products
is the best way to generate
fast cash nowadays.
But when you make fast
money, it can be very easy
to spend it just as quickly.
That's why I've always taken a portion
of the money I generated
through my businesses
and invested it into the stock market.
I mean, surely you'd like to own pieces
of the companies you love
that will hopefully
increasing value over time
rather than a designer
item that won't be cold
in a couple of months.
But how do you pick the
best investment app?
Well, here are the things I look out for.
Firstly, it's so important
to make sure the platform you
are using offers a wide range
of stocks and ETFs,
so you can build a diversified portfolio.
Some stocks have high price tags,
so make sure the platform
offers fractional shares
so you can buy a percentage
of a share and not the full thing.
Thirdly, I like automating my investing
by personally selecting the
stocks and ETFs I want to own,
and the investing app buys
the stocks for me on a daily,
weekly, or monthly basis.
And lastly, ensure the platform
you are using is easy to use
and offers zero commission investing
as this means you are always
getting the best price possible
and not paying sneaky, hidden fees.
Webull offer everything
we've just discussed
and so much more.
So for a limited time, click
the link in the description
to sign up for Webull
and get up to 75 free stocks
when you fund your account.
(upbeat music)
If you wanna grow your sales
sustainably, then you have
to sell to the same
customer more than once.
Otherwise, you'll always be in promo mode.
Gyms like this often roll
out major promotions two
to three times a year,
particularly in January,
so they can capitalize
on fitness-based New Year's resolutions.
Usually they lock people
into a 12 month membership,
but come February, most people stop going,
but this guarantees the gym 12 months
of reoccurring revenue.
This is really important when
you're selling info products
as the more a customer buys from you,
the higher their lifetime value becomes.
Lifetime value is an estimate
of the average revenue
that a customer will generate
throughout their lifespan as a customer.
I know that sounds like
a load of jumbled words,
but really it just means that
companies try to determine
how much a customer will
spend on their products
during their lifetime, in simpler terms,
how much money they can rinse them for.
So this is kind of like your compass
for forecasting future growth
and how much you can spend on advertising
to acquire those customers.
The best way to do this
with info products is
to start an online membership.
So in a paid membership,
you'd expect to see webinars
or in-depth tutorials, member only events
or meetups, personalized
support and access
to a dedicated and like-minded community.
Let's say you charge $50
per month for membership
and you have 100 members,
that's $5,000 in monthly revenue
and over a year that is $60,000.
Now factor in potential growth.
Say you increase your
membership to 200 members.
Now your monthly revenue is $10,000,
which is $120,000 a year.
That's more than enough
to replace your regular nine to five.
(upbeat music)
Right now, I'm on my way to
London for a business meeting
and I'm surrounded by people
on a nine to five grind.
It's almost like they're on autopilot.
They've got their laptops out,
they're all serious faces.
It's like robot city.
In most nine to five jobs,
they want you to be present
in a specific location
for a specific amount of time,
and you're not paid on whether
you've got good knowledge.
You're just paid on the time
that you spend there at the job.
That's why info products
are so liberating.
They're a great way to
unlock location freedom,
meaning you're not tied to
any building or even country.
That's right, you can jet off
to the Maldives, have a swim
with the sharks, bask
in the glorious sunshine
and still earn money.
Of course, this still
requires you to work remotely,
but some people take it one step further
and automate everything.
What I mean by this is
hiring other people to deal
with certain aspects of the info product.
So you could have someone
managing customer support,
you could have someone
monitoring the group chat.
You could collaborate with experts
and have them take certain
webinars so you don't have
to do that week, and you
could pre-record content
and have someone posting it out each week.
If you can find the correct balance
and execute it in an ethical
and positive way, you'll have the ability
to live wherever you want
and you'd be able to escape
certain tax laws by relocating
to places like Dubai,
which don't have any personal income tax.
I firmly believe that you can create
and sell a very successful info product
in a very short amount of time.
And the best thing about all
of this is you can help
change people's lives
by sharing your knowledge.
If you wanna know how I
started a print on demand store
and sold posters like this
for a profit, then I'll leave
that video right up there, but
don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.