So you wanna make $10,000 a month,
but you don't know which route to take?
Most people take the traditional route.
They go to school, study
hard for their exams,
get good grades, go to university,
and then get a nine to five job.
Sorry to burst your bubble,
but the average person
makes $63,795 per year
according to the latest data
from the Social Security Administration.
That's $5,316 per month,
so nowhere near your
goal of $10,000 a month.
Even worse, this data includes people
who've been in the game for ages.
So if you're just
starting out in your 20s,
you'll probably be making
way less than 5K a month
if you stick to this old school path.
But hey, let's say somehow
you hit the jackpot
and score a nine to five gig
that pays you 10K a month.
Maybe you become a
hotshot doctor or lawyer.
Sounds great, right? Well, not so fast.
You'd still be trading away your time
and freedom for that paycheck.
This was the route that my
parents expected me to follow.
They believed it was the
only way to a secure future.
Maybe some of you're
sitting there right now
feeling that same
pressure with your parents
expecting the same of you.
However, deep down you feel
like there must be a faster way
you can make over 10K per
month with more freedom,
and that's exactly where
the new route comes in.
Don't worry.
I know this sounds like it's leading up
to some sort of sales pitch,
but I'm not gonna try
and sell you anything,
so feel free to relax.
You can follow this route
completely for free,
and how you navigate
it will depend on you.
Many successful people like
Steven Bartlett, Joe Fazer,
and Ali Abdaal are taking
this route already,
but they aren't really talking about it.
It also doesn't matter how old you are
as you can switch to this new
route, no matter what stage
of the traditional route
you're currently on.
However, the longer you wait,
the tougher it gets to make that big jump.
Why?
Well, as you keep going
down this usual path,
life starts piling on more stuff,
you know, like a mortgage, a partner,
kids, the whole shebang.
Don't get me wrong, you can
still switch gears at any stage,
but trust me, it's way easier
if you do it sooner rather than later.
I left school with no
money or qualification,
so I was forced down this route early on,
and I believe that's
one of the key reasons
I became a millionaire in my 20s
and have been able to compound
that wealth ever since.
Hopefully, you are convinced
that this new route
to making over $10,000 per month
is at least worth learning about.
So let me break down the
three steps involved.
Step one is consume.
Believe it or not, you
don't know everything.
If you think you do, then
you're delusional and arrogant.
So what's the solution to this?
It's simple, consuming knowledge.
Think of it this way.
It's like gathering
resources in Minecraft.
You need the right materials to build,
survive, and ultimately conquer.
However, the education
system never really teach you
how to find information worth consuming.
It's not as simple as
reading boring textbook
or a quick Google search.
So here's some advice.
Before you even reach for your laptop,
you need to identify
what you want to learn.
This needs to be some
kind of high income skill.
Some examples that come
to mind are video editing,
high ticket sales, web design, coding,
graphic design, and copywriting.
Honestly, there are so many out there.
Just pick one that you feel
you'd already have a little
bit of a natural gift for.
It's always easier to sharpen a strength
and develop a weakness.
Once you've narrowed it down,
this area will become your focus.
Now you need time to seek
out credible sources.
I know I'm biased,
but I think the best place
to do this is on YouTube.
Find some trustworthy
experts with large audiences.
Watch their videos and
note down their key points.
You need to extract the key information,
not copy down their life story.
Ask yourself, what point is
that person actually making,
and what lesson is behind
their story or experience?
Once you've done that and
your notes are looking solid,
I'd start to look at the types
of people that are watching
and engaging with that content.
If you notice they have
a strong community,
then get stuck in.
I'd even go the extra mile
and head over to Reddit and Discord.
This way, you'll be able
to connect with people
that are passionate about
the same niche as you.
Engage with them, ask questions,
and learn from their experiences.
I guarantee you, joining
these types of groups
will give you a proper insight
into the real struggles
that people are facing,
which is far more valuable
than watching only the creators' videos.
It's one thing to learn
from top creators online,
but when you dive into these communities,
you get a front row seat to
see what's really going on,
giving you access to priceless knowledge.
Trust me, this will come
in very handy later on.
A word of warning, though,
it can be very easy
to fall into the trap of
only watching one person
or even just watching YouTube videos.
If you wanna get the most from this,
then you need to be
consuming from a variety
of different people and mediums.
In other words,
you really shouldn't be
shying away from books.
I'm a huge fan of books.
They're like a shortcut to
someone's entire life experience,
but I'm dyslexic, so
plowing through a whole book
can be a real pain sometimes.
That's why I'm all about
these Shortform guides.
For me, Shortform is the go-to
for diving deep into books
like "The Intelligent Investor"
and gaining in-depth insights.
They're the best summary service out there
and let me learn from five books
in the time it takes to read one.
I'll drop a link in the
description that you can use
to try it for free and get 20% off.
Step two is apply.
If you wanna get rich,
then you have to apply
the things you consume.
This is super important,
is you need to get out
there in the real world
and test what you've learned.
The best way to do this
is to consume, then apply,
consume some more, and then apply again.
It's a cycle that only stops
when you want to stop progressing.
Let's say you've decided to
consume content on coding.
Now is the time to make
your first simple app.
It sounds daunting,
and at first you're probably
gonna suck, but that's okay.
You've got to give yourself
permission to fail.
Mark Zuckerberg didn't create Facebook
for his first project.
JK Rowling got rejected 12 times
before she published "Harry Potter."
And Beyonce made hundreds of songs
before her first smash hit.
In the words of Mark Zuckerberg himself,
"The greatest successes
come from having the freedom to fail."
As soon as you feel confident enough,
start charging for your skills.
If you edit videos,
then take on a few lower
paying clients at first
and work your way up.
Just think, all you need to do
is get five clients paying $2,000 a month
or 10 clients paying $1,000 a month
for your video editing services,
and you've already hit
the 10K per month target.
The better you get, the more
you'll be able to charge
and the easier it will be
to make more and more money.
However, this is a game
of diminishing returns,
meaning the hours you put in
learning the skill at the start
will have more impact on your income
than the hours later down the line.
It's like when you first
start to work out of the gym,
you get newbie gains.
It's best to consume and apply
until you get to the point
where you aren't noticing an increase
in the amount you're able
to charge for your services.
This is how you know
you've reached pretty much expert status.
During this time, make sure to keep note
of all the challenges you face
and problems you overcome.
These will become stories
you can draw on heavily in the future.
Believe it or not, during the apply stage,
the most important thing
you'll gain isn't the money,
but instead the experiences themselves.
Once you're an expert in a
specific high income skill,
it can be very easy to get stuck here,
trading every hour you
have to earn 10K per month.
But remember, the goal isn't to reach 10K
and lose all your freedom.
So instead, I recommend
doing these two things.
Firstly, start to scale
your high income skill
into a real business.
I know you might be thinking,
"It's already a business,"
but if you have to be
working to generate income,
then the truth is, you just
have a high paying job.
So how can you scale a high income skill
into a proper business?
Well, I know a guy
that started editing shorts for YouTubers.
He was working every hour under the sun.
However, one day he just got fed up
with working all the time
and not having the
freedom to take vacations,
so he started to note down
all the steps he would take
to make the shorts, from the
way he selected the clips
to the font he used
and the time of day he
posted at the social media.
He didn't know it at the time,
but he was creating a system.
He realized that he wasn't
gonna be able to find someone
to do all the tasks like him.
However, he could split the
tasks into separate jobs,
such as time stamper,
text editor, and poster.
This way he could find
far less skilled people
to fill in the roles for him
so he could focus on the quality control
and take on more clients.
You can do this with
any high income skill.
The system will also become super useful
for the next thing I
highly recommend doing,
teaching others your high income skill.
That brings me on to step three, educate.
Most of the young millionaires
that have gained success recently
have made their fortunes teaching others.
I'm talking Iman Gadzhi, Ali Abdaal,
Graham Stephan, the list goes on.
The education industry is booming,
and I believe everyone making decent money
from some kind of high income skill
should also have an education business.
I mean, just imagine you created a course
that you sold for $100.
All you'd have to do
is sell that course 100 times in a month
and you'd hit that 10K per month.
The great thing is you
only have to make it once
and then you can sell it again and again,
getting your freedom and time back.
Education products don't just
have to be online courses.
You could also start
exclusive membership sites,
subscription podcasts, communities,
personalized coaching, and more.
These types of businesses
are extremely cost effective
to set up and run.
They also have the upside
of being extremely scalable
as they generate predictable,
reoccurring revenue.
Now, reoccurring revenue is the holy grail
in the business world.
I mean, there's a reason why everything
is turning into a subscription nowadays.
If you know how much money
is coming in every month,
then it gives you the confidence you need
to expand your business
and eventually hire people
without worrying too much
about your cash flow.
I know multiple people making millions
using this business model
all from their laptop.
Look, I know it might
sound super complicated,
but all you have to do is sign up
to an all-in-one platform like Kajabi
and they'll handle all
the business stuff for you
so you can focus on creating
your education products.
Just make sure the platform
you choose to host your course
or community doesn't take
a cut from your revenue
and that everything remains
controlled and owned by you.
That's why I like Kajabi,
as you keep 100% of what you earn.
They also give you lots of analytic tools,
easy payment options,
email marketing tools,
and customizable website
templates all built in.
To build a successful business on Kajabi,
all you need is 10,000 loyal
fans buying $100 product
and you've got a million
dollar education business.
I'll talk about how you
can build an audience
like this in a second.
I reached out to Kajabi to
see if they'd be interested
in sponsoring this portion of the video.
They agreed and are
offering a free 30 day trial
to start your business if
you go to kajabi.com/mark.
So feel free to head
over there and sign up
once you're ready to host
your education product
and make some predictable,
reoccurring revenue.
You might be thinking that
giving away your secrets
will impact your earnings.
However, honestly, only a very
small percentage of people
actually take action.
That's what separates us from most people.
And honestly, if you don't teach others,
then someone else will.
But why would someone listen to you
and not someone older
and more experienced?
Relatability. It's as simple as that.
You've recently been in their shoes
and can relate to how they're feeling
much better than an old professor
that's teaching from textbooks.
That's part of the reason my
channel has been so successful.
I've been there and done it.
I know what it's like
starting with no money
or qualifications, and
I put in the hard work.
That's why you can't
just skip to this step
before actually applying
what you consume online.
There are too many parrots out there.
Your real stories and experiences
will make you stand out.
But what if I get lots of hate?
Look, what's scarier to you,
looking back 10 years from now,
seeing your life exactly
as it is, the same job,
same income, same routine,
or facing a few harsh comments online?
To build any kind of audience online,
you're gonna have to deal
with a small group of
people who don't like you,
but that's how you know
you're doing it right.
The worst thing to be is vanilla.
So how can you actually build an audience
and educate people
through your experiences?
Most people will tell you
to start with your story,
but the issue with this
is that no one actually
knows who you are yet.
You don't have that social presence online
to make people care.
Sure, sometimes out of the blue,
these videos can hit an algorithm,
but these people never
build a lasting following.
I would personally start
with posting content
that directly speaks to your
audience and their needs.
You could do a combination of
videos, blog posts, or tweets.
You need to talk about a shared problem
and teach people how to fix that problem
through actionable advice.
Really think back to when you started
and all the problems you were facing.
This is your superpowers.
You can really tap into their thoughts.
When people scroll through social media,
the posts that make them
stop are often the posts
that make them feel something,
posts that hit that emotional trigger.
So hit them hard in your first line.
Make them stop and think,
"Wow, this is just how I feel."
One of the best tips
is to use something I created
called the IMPACT principle.
I is for Inspire.
You want your audience to
feel motivated by your story,
showing them that change is possible.
M is for Message.
You should always try to have a clear
and concise message that's
not only easy to understand,
but easy to remember.
Every time they think of that message,
they'll think of you and your content.
P is for Practical.
You should always be
providing actionable steps
that they can take immediately
to improve their situation.
Forget all that mindset stuff.
That's not helping anyone.
A is for Authentic.
You should always be yourself
and speak about your own
experiences from the apply stage
to really resonate with your audience.
C is for Connection.
You need to build a
really strong connection
with your audience by addressing
their needs and concerns.
So reply to comments.
And within C is another
C, really, Conversation.
You need to be creating a conversation
to help build a strong,
ha ha, you guessed it,
Community, all the Cs.
There's so many.
Lastly, we have T, which is for Timing.
I know what you're thinking,
finding the best time to post using stats.
No, that's not what I'm about to say.
For timings, it's more
about releasing your content
at the right time to maximize
its relevance and impact.
So jump on trends and follow
the news so you stay relevant.
It's all about catching
and riding the waves,
which will shed light
on your other content.
If you aren't comfortable sitting down
in front of a camera and talking,
that isn't the only strategy that works.
Look at people like Steven Bartlett.
He failed at vlogging for many years
and then he started his
podcast, "Diary Of A CEO."
He now gets the experts on
and draws out their
insights for his audience.
There is no right way to go about it.
It's just trial and error,
until you find what works for you.
So don't be afraid to try
a few different approaches.
So are you gonna keep going
down the traditional route,
or are you gonna hop onto the new route
and start making over a 10K a month?
I'll leave that down to you.
If you wanna know the
seven things to avoid
if you wanna get rich,
then I'll leave that video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you wanna grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.