- So you want to become a millionaire,
but you're stuck trying
to find the right balance
between studying and making money.
You're probably on a tight budget,
cramming for exams,
living off cup noodles,
and questioning whether going to college
or uni was the right
decision in the first place.
And I hate to say it, but
you could be right to wonder.
A study showed 23%
of bachelor's degrees have a
negative return on investment.
Even more surprising is that 41%
of graduates are working in jobs
that don't require a degree.
So what's the solution?
Well, most millionaires have
multiple streams of income.
65% have at least three, 45% have four,
and 29% have more than five.
The problem is many
of the popular income
streams aren't realistic
for students to start
from their dorm room.
That's why I've put
together seven great ideas
you can actually start today,
all packed into my trusty toolkit.
So let's get into it, quite literally.
Income stream idea one is TikTok Shop.
This is absolutely popping off,
making it the perfect
opportunity for students
to earn some extra cash,
with zero startup costs
and no equipment needed.
Apart from your phone
and maybe a ring light,
just like this one.
I picked this up for under $20.
When I was younger, I remember
my mum buying from catalogs
and then switching to watching QVC
and doing some TV shopping.
This is the modern-day equivalent,
just way faster and more interactive.
The opportunity is huge, but
don't just take my word for it.
Let me give you some stats.
Last year, TikTok Shop
brought in 11.09 billion
in gross merchandise volume.
And by the end of this year,
they're expected to generate
17.5 billion in sales.
So how much money can
you realistically make?
The truth is the amount
of money you can make
depends on the products in your store.
Some products simply drive
more impulse buys than others.
Beauty and personal care products
are the highest grossing category.
I mean, the second highest category
is women's wear and underwear.
If you target one of these
top-performing categories,
you can make anywhere from a few hundred
to a few thousand dollars a month,
and possibly even more if you land
on a viral product or trend.
How much time will it take?
If you wanna make a lot of money,
around three hours a night is a good goal.
But if your target is smaller,
maybe an extra $100 a month or so,
you can spend less time.
Maybe just an hour a day.
Now, I know some of you're
in tough courses like
medicine, for example,
and three hours a night
might sound like too much.
But don't worry, there's an easy fix.
TikTok Shop has an affiliate program
where other people can
help sell your products.
You don't need a big
celebrity like Kylie Jenner
to promote your items.
You can work with smaller creators,
called micro-influencers,
who can help you get your products
in front of the right people.
So how can you get started?
All you need to do is download
the TikTok Seller Center app.
Once you've got it, you
can upload product images,
descriptions, and prices
directly through the app.
Then just submit everything for review.
It usually takes a few
days to get approved.
Income stream idea two is focus groups.
Believe it or not,
companies are willing
to pay good money just
to hear your opinions.
Your feedback helps them
improve their products,
and they're happy to reward you for it.
In fact, you can earn up to $250
for just a one-hour focus group.
For students, this is a
fantastic option because,
let's face it, after a
full day of lectures,
most people just want to chill out.
And that's exactly what
makes online focus groups
such a good option.
You can earn money while relaxing in bed,
all wrapped up in your duvet.
So how much money can
you realistically make?
The answer is, well, it depends.
Whilst yes, it's true,
you could earn up to $250
for a one-hour session,
the actual amount really varies
based on how niche the group is.
The more specific or rare your feedback,
the more valuable they are,
and that means higher pay.
Think about it.
If a company is doing a
study on people over 6'4",
that's not exactly your average height.
Someone who fits that
description, like yours truly,
could earn more than someone
joining a focus group about,
let's say, chicken wing lovers.
Because it's way harder to find someone
who towers over doorframes
than it is to find someone
who loves Wingstop.
How much time will it take?
Focus groups are usually quick,
ranging from 30 minutes
to a couple of hours,
depending on the topic
and how detailed the
discussion needs to be.
Right. How can you get started?
There are plenty of legit
focus group websites out there,
but there are also some scams.
So it's important to stick
with the trusted platforms.
Some of the top legit
sites include Respondent,
User Interviews, and focusgroup.com.
Legit companies will never
ask you for upfront payments
or private information,
like your bank login.
If something seems off, it probably is.
Income stream idea three is
modernizing boring businesses.
Now, everywhere you look,
there are lots of boring
businesses quietly making money,
like laundromats, self-storage facilities,
and vending machines, for example.
These businesses might not seem glamorous,
but they're absolute goldmines.
They're reliable, recession proof,
and provide services
people will always need.
But because they're so boring,
younger people overlook them.
Therefore, most of them
are run by older people.
This means the majority
are stuck in the past,
with old systems and
little to no marketing.
That's where you come in.
With just a few modern upgrades
that you can do from your laptop,
you can significantly boost their profits
and then take a cut for yourself.
So how much money can
you realistically make?
A laundromat can bring in
around $300,000 a year,
with profit margins between 20 to 30%.
Car washes can generate annual revenues
of 500 to $900,000.
With software like Odoo,
you could set up online
booking for a laundromat
or automate the billing process
for a self-storage facility.
These upgrades save time,
keep things running smoothly,
and make life easier for customers.
Plus, when the business is more efficient
and customer friendly, it's
bound to bring in more money.
The best way to structure a
deal is through a profit split.
This allows you to directly benefit
from the success you
bring to the business.
Let's say your efforts add $50,000
to a laundromat's annual profit,
and you negotiate a 20% cut of that.
That's $10,000 in your
pocket for one client.
A profit split is great,
as it makes sure you're
incentivized to get results.
And it's a good option
for business owners,
since you only get paid
if they see real growth.
So how much time will it take?
Let's take a laundromat as an example.
Using Odoo's accounting app,
you can automate billing and
track payments instantly.
So you can completely get rid
of their messy cash
systems and paper receipts.
Once you set up the service in the app,
it handles invoices and
payments automatically,
save them hours of work every week.
And you know what they say. Time is money.
Setting this up may take a few hours
to a couple of days,
depending on the business,
but once it's done,
your involvement can drop to
just an hour or two a week,
just to review reports or
make small adjustments.
Right. How can you get started?
Well, the first step is
to find a boring business with potential.
Look for ones that are outdated,
poorly marketed, or underperforming.
These are your opportunities
to step in and level them up.
Once you've chosen a business,
you need to work out what
software you're gonna use.
I personally like Odoo, as
they're an all-in-one solution,
which means you can use
all their different apps
to level businesses up, in a
variety of different areas.
Since I was planning on mentioning Odoo,
I reached out to them
to see if they wanted to sponsor
this portion of the video.
They agreed and are also giving you
your first application free for life,
with unlimited support and hosting.
So if you wanna give it a try,
then check out the link
in the description.
Income stream idea four: a part-time job.
Now, I know a lot of
you might roll your eyes
at this one, but hear me out.
It's one of the best ways
to make money as a student
while learning how the
real world actually works.
Ooh, I think they've been in
me toolkit a bit too long.
I hate it when I see people
turning their noses up
at students working at
McDonald's or in cafes.
Jobs like these should be
respected, not looked down on.
Back in my day,
I was making trash cans
for less than $2 an hour.
It wasn't glamorous,
but it taught me
resilience, responsibility,
and the value of every penny I earned.
Whether you believe it or not,
these part-time jobs aren't
just about the money.
They give you the skills
you'll carry forward,
making you more valuable and
employable in the future.
My mate, Daniel Priestley,
worked at McDonald's before
becoming a multimillionaire.
So who's to say that can't be you too?
So how much money can
you realistically make?
This depends heavily on the
type of job you decide to get.
I'd say there are three main types.
The first is a traditional part-time job.
Let's stick with our McDonald's
example for this one.
For a part-time job as a crew member,
you'd be looking at an
average of $12.81 per hour,
according into indeed.com.
The second type is more of
a specialized part-time job,
such as tutoring.
The amount you can make varies
based on what grade level
you are able to teach,
with the lowest being
elementary school level.
However, as most students
will be currently studying
at college level,
they would probably be best suited
to tutor high school kids.
The last type of job is freelancing.
You can learn a remote
skill like video editing,
copywriting, coding, or high-ticket sales.
With this, you can set your prices
at whatever level the people
are willing to pay you.
So how can you get started?
Well, the first thing
you need is a solid CV.
Print it off and hand it
directly to local businesses.
Just keep it clean.
No Friday night photos with a
vape hanging out of your mouth
and a beer in your hand.
Income stream idea five
is selling your stuff.
Now, I'll never understand
how students manage to
collect so much stuff.
And half of it, let's be
honest, you don't even need.
In my last video, I talked
about living frugally
and being mindful of what you buy.
What I didn't mention
is how important it is
to keep an eye on what you can sell.
Most of us have wardrobes full
of clothes we barely wear.
I bet if you went into yours right now,
you'd find at least five
things you could sell.
I'm not saying you need to
sell all your pots and pans
and start eating your dinner
with a spanner from your toolbox.
Just take a look around and see
what you don't need anymore.
Chances are, there's money laying
around your room waiting to be made.
Mind you, if you do find an
old spanner you don't need,
you might as well sell that as well.
So how much money can
you realistically make?
Well, always check how much
similar items are selling for
before you list anything.
For example, if you've got a textbook
that's still in demand,
you could make at least 50%
of its new price easily.
But be careful.
Don't make the mistake
my assistant Millie made.
She went through a Vinted
phase and sold a dress for $5.
But it cost her $4 to ship it,
so she ended up making just $1.
So keep an eye on your shipping costs
and make sure the sale is worth your time.
So how much time will it take?
Listing items on eBay or
Vinted is quick and easy.
You can snap some photos, upload them,
and write a short description in minutes.
The only time-consuming part
might be posting the items.
But even that's easy enough now,
as lots of local shopping
centers have lock boxes
where you can drop off your parcels.
Right. How can you get started?
Well, we've already talked
about platforms like Vinted and eBay.
So just pick one and set up an account.
Upload some clear photos,
write honest descriptions,
and price your items competitively.
Once you run out of things to sell,
you can ask fellow students
for stuff they don't want anymore
and sell it on a commission.
Income stream idea six: dropshipping.
Dropshipping is a modern classic
when it comes to side
hustles, and for good reason.
It's perfect for students
who want to make money
without the hassle of holding inventory
or shipping products themselves.
With dropshipping, you
set up an online store,
choose products from suppliers,
and when a customer makes a purchase,
the supplier handles the shipping for you.
This means you can run your
store from your dorm room
with nothing more than a
laptop and a bit of creativity.
So how much money can
you realistically make?
Your earning potential with dropshipping
depends on the products you sell
and the effort you put
into marketing your store.
On average, profit margins
are around 20 to 30%,
but for high-ticket items
like furniture or electronics,
you can make even more.
If you sell a $50 product
with a 25% margin,
you'd make $12.50.
If you sell 100 units in a month,
that's $1,250 in profit.
So how much time will it take?
Well, setting up your
store is pretty quick
if you use a tool like
Build Your Store AI,
which will set you up with
a great free Shopify store
in less than two minutes.
It just makes things so much easier.
I'll drop a link in the description.
It will guide you through
finding winning products
and suppliers, and then all you have to do
is focus on your marketing.
Income stream idea seven:
language dubbing.
Language dubbing is a fantastic way
to make money by helping businesses
and creators translate their content
into different languages.
And it's something I'm
having done right now.
We're dubbing my YouTube videos
into Portuguese, Spanish,
Hindi, and Japanese.
Businesses need people like you,
whether as a voice actor,
or someone who can help organize
and manage the dubbing process.
So how much money can
you realistically make?
If you're working as a voice actor,
the average hourly rate
in the US is $48.17.
If you are offering dubbing services
by connecting voice actors to businesses,
the earning potential can scale even more.
You could charge clients a flat fee
or take a percentage of
the project's budget.
So how much time will it take?
As a voice actor,
the time commitment depends
on your level of experience.
If you're new, you might wanna spend
a few hours each week
taking voice workshops
or practicing your delivery.
If you are managing a dubbing service,
you'll need to spend time
networking with businesses,
connecting with voice actors,
and overseeing the project timeline.
So how can you get started?
Platforms like Fiverr and
Upwork are excellent places
to upload your samples and get clients.
Focus on high-demand markets like Hindi,
Portuguese, Spanish, and Japanese.
If you wanna know what the
laziest way to make money is,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there.
But don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe
if you want to grow your wealth, okay?
I'll see you over there.