- People are making thousands
of dollars each month
in passive income by dropshipping products
from AI-built Shopify stores.
- I've made millions of
dollars with dropshipping.
- I've been able to make
hundreds of thousands of dollars
with AI.
- $500 a day working from home
or anywhere from the world.
- Hundreds of dollars a day
from this side hustle.
- $600,000 this month alone.
- Apparently anyone can do this
from anywhere in the world,
but is this too good to be true?
Well, today I want to put it to the test
by only using free tools
to make a Shopify store
and see how many products
I can sell online,
but I'm setting myself three rules.
Number one, I must use free AI tools
and keep the total cost of
the shop creation to under $1.
Number two, I have to be able
to do it all from my laptop.
And number three, I need to
finish it in less than an hour.
Okay, start the timer.
Right, I've got a list
of steps to complete.
The first thing on my plan
is to find a free AI tool
to create our Shopify store.
Now, I've done quite a
lot of searching around
and the best one I found
is Build Your Store.
It claims to be able to
build a Shopify store for us,
and let's us sell other people's products
without needing our own inventory
or doing any of the work ourselves.
The idea is when the
store receives an order,
the product is shipped
directly to the customer,
which allows us to make a profit
without any more work on our end.
If you wanna follow along,
feel free to head down to
the description of the video
and click the top link.
So I've loaded up page
and now I'm gonna click this button here
that says Build My Free Store,
because that's exactly
what we want it to do.
Now they're asking for my full name,
which is of course Mark Tilbury,
and they want an email address
and to pick a password.
Right, that's done.
And then just click next.
Now it's asking me to choose a niche.
You have six options here to choose from:
fashion and apparel, pets,
electronics and gadgets,
home and garden, sports and fitness,
and finally, an option for, I'm not sure.
Lots of people would just pick something
they're interested in.
However, it's best to approach
this with a business mind
and think to yourself,
what do you confidently know
that has a large market?
Honestly, all of these
options are pretty good.
However, I'm just gonna
go for sport and fitness
because my son is always at
boxing or running or in the gym.
So I'm pretty sure there's a big demand
for these types of products,
especially amongst younger people.
I've even heard that Gen
Z are now meeting people
at running clubs instead of nightclubs.
Very different from back
in my day, that's for sure.
Right, that's the first one off my list.
The next thing on my list
is to customize the store
and make it appealing to our customers.
Now, there are six banners
on here to choose from,
so let's go through them
and find out what suits our store best.
The first one has a lot of
different sporting items,
which may seem good,
but if we don't end up
selling those products,
it could confuse our customers,
so we'll skip that one.
Then there's this one with
just a woman on her own.
While it's a nice design,
it doesn't really represent
our entire audience,
and we want our store to
appeal to both men and women.
So using this logic,
the bottom right one also feels
well a bit too female only,
so we'll pass on that.
So out of these remaining three,
I think the bottom left one works great,
and the middle right one pops
really nicely with the sunset,
which could help grab attention
and create a positive first impression.
Remember, the banners are the first thing
our customers will see when
they land on our store,
so it's important they
reflect what we're about
and what we're offering.
If you don't feel like
any of these work for you,
then, don't worry, as you can
always change them later on.
Now that we've chosen our banners,
let's hit continue and
move on to the next step.
To let the AI build our store,
we need to set up a free Shopify account.
So that's the next thing on my list.
The first thing I'm gonna do
is click on Access Shopify,
which opens up in a new tab.
Now I'm gonna type in my email address
and then hit Start Free Trial.
Then I just need to pick a password
and click Create Shopify Account.
Now, as you can see,
Shopify is now asking us
a few set up questions,
but since AI is gonna handle
most of the work for us,
we can just select, I
Don't Want Help Setting Up,
to save us time.
Now it's asking us to choose a plan
for when the free trial ends.
The basic plan looks good
enough for what we're building,
as it's designed for solo entrepreneurs,
and it's also the most popular option.
So I'm just gonna go
ahead and select that one.
Then, I quickly add in my payment details
so we're all ready when the trial ends.
But don't worry right now
because it's completely free
and after the trial,
it's just one pound or $1 per month
for the first three months.
As we're not paying anything right now,
this doesn't count towards our $1 budget.
I know we'll probably have to pay it
before we get some sales in,
but technically I haven't paid it yet.
So I think you can let
me off with this one.
Once that's all set up,
Shopify takes us to this
dashboard for our new store
where we can manage everything.
Now, it does look pretty
confusing, but that's fine,
as we won't have too much
to do in here ourselves
because soon the AI
will be taking control.
That sounded pretty scary.
I hope this AI stuff
doesn't lead us into a
"Terminator" situation.
Now we need to install
the Build Your Store app.
This might seem like it's
getting a bit confusing,
but after this, it gets
a whole lot easier.
So I'm gonna click Access Shopify again,
which opens another tab.
On this page,
I'm gonna click the Install
button to add the app
to our Shopify account.
With this done, I can click
Create My Custom Store.
Now we just need to give the AI
a bit of time to work its magic
and build the store website
for us in the background.
We'll check out the results
later to see what it's created,
but for now, let's keep things moving
and jump onto the next step.
Right, the next thing on my list
is to find some winning
products for our store.
This is so important
because the right products
can make or break the store.
They attract customers, drive sales,
and ultimately set us
apart from our competition.
To make this as easy and
efficient as possible,
we're gonna register for AutoDS.
This tool does the heavy lifting for us
by selecting products
that are proven to sell.
It also takes care of pricing,
uploading professional photos,
and once we start making sales,
it'll also ship the products
directly to our customers.
I'm going to go back to the
Build Your Store website
and select Register to AutoDS.
This gives us the option
to either sign up with a Google account
or to enter your details manually.
Just make sure that you
use the same email address
you use for Shopify and Build Your Store
to keep everything linked.
Okay, so now it's asking me
where will we be selling?
So of course I'm choosing Shopify.
Now, we need to pick the right plan.
AutoDS offers the first 30 days
for just 99 cents on any plan.
This gives us a chance
to test everything out
and see how well it works.
In my opinion, the basic plan
doesn't have enough features
to make this truly passive,
but we don't need the
advanced plan yet either.
The Starter 500 plan looks
perfect for what we need,
so I'm selecting start now for 99 cents.
There are a few different
payment methods available.
I'm gonna go with PayPal
as I always use it, right?
So there we go, all sorted.
And just like that, that's my
$1 budget officially spent.
Hopefully, there's nothing
else left to pay for
while setting up this store
because at this point,
I've only got 1 cent left.
Now it's finally time
to publish our store.
I'm actually quite excited to
see everything come together.
The last thing we need to do
here is to click access Shopify
and then uncheck the box that says,
Restrict Access to
Visitors with the Password.
Now, that's done.
I'm gonna press continue and boom,
our store is officially
live with winning products.
Now that our Shopify store is live,
the next thing on my list
is to take a proper look and
make any tweaks we might need
before sending customers over there.
This actually looks a lot
better than I thought it would.
Our two banners are in place,
and the AI has set up buttons
that lead straight to the
New Product Arrivals page,
which should make it easy
for customers to get around the site.
Down here are some of the winning products
that AutoDS has added for us.
First, we have what looks
like some kind of breathing trainer.
Actually, I have seen my
son use one of these before.
It works kind of like
high altitude training
by limiting the amount of
oxygen you can take in.
I think the idea is that
when you're in a competition,
your body can carry more
oxygen in your blood,
which should make you perform better.
To be honest, the more
I'm talking about it,
the more I want one for myself.
So I think this will
sell really, really well.
Next, we've got bag
clips for your golf club.
Now, I personally use these all the time
because they stop the clubs
rattling together and getting damaged,
and if you've ever had to
replace a carbon shaft,
you know how expensive that can be.
Then we have the classic resistance band,
which I imagine is always a good seller,
and a warm jogging hat
to round things off,
as it's getting a little bit
chilly this time of year.
So honestly,
I'm pretty impressed with
the items it's picked,
but if we did want to pick more,
then it's pretty simple to do that too.
I'll just have to head over
to AutoDS, click Marketplace,
and then Trending Products.
Now, this brings up a
page with all the products
that are selling very, very well,
and we could pick any of these,
even if they don't necessarily
fit with our niche.
To be honest though,
it's probably not a good idea
to be too random with it,
as your customers need to
know what your store is about.
So I'm gonna click on this
filter for sports and fitness,
and it pulls up some products
that would fit really well into our store.
Now, if I wanted to add one of these,
then all I'd have to do
is click Import Draft
and then wait for the
import of the product.
Then it gives me the option
to adjust all the information and photos
before publishing it onto the store.
Now I'm pretty impressed so
far, but let's dive a bit deeper
and check out what our
product page looks like
and see if we can spot any
mistakes we need to fix.
Let's click on the golf club clips.
Now, there is a decent
selection of product photos,
and to be fair, they do
look quite professional.
There's also quite a wide
range of different shots,
which is important because
when I'm buying something,
I always like to look at
a few different photos.
According to AutoDS, these
golf clips cost me $6.84,
and dropshippers normally sell their items
for two to two and a
half times their cost.
So I should be able to sell
these for at least $13.68,
which will give us $6.84 profit per sale,
not taking into account
any marketing costs.
Now, I'll be honest, that's
not a crazy amount of money,
but when you're selling at scale,
it could definitely start to add up.
Plus, if I think these clips
could sell for more than $13,
I can always bump up the price
manually and see how it goes.
One small detail I really like on here
is the little animation
on the PayPal button.
Now, I've always found
that having PayPal payments
available on my website
adds a bit more trust
and often improved sales.
The AI has even written the
product descriptions for us
and thrown in some emojis.
I'll admit that is handy
and saves a lot of time,
which I am a bit short of right now.
It's also included related
product suggestions
at the bottom of each page,
which could help with upselling.
I admit it's fairly basic,
but I found that basic
websites often perform better.
This footer is actually
a bit of a surprise, huh?
I wasn't expecting much here because,
let's be honest, footers
are usually an afterthought,
but the AI has done a decent job with it.
All the important pages
are already set up,
like the shipping policies
and terms and conditions.
These little details might
not seem like a big deal,
but they do make the store
look a lot more professional.
Now, let me click into the
Terms and Conditions page
and take a look.
Yep, most of the heavy
lifting's already been done.
All I need to do is drop in
a store name, our location,
and some contact details to finish off.
Now, the only thing letting
the store down right now
is the domain name.
It's just a random jumble of characters,
and honestly, it doesn't
scream professional.
A good domain name is so important
because it's the first
thing customers see.
So I'm gonna head back
to Build Your Store AI
to sort that out.
I'm gonna set up a .store
domain, instead of a .com
because it's specifically
designed for online stores.
There has actually been
studies that show websites
with a .store domain get 87% more traffic
and rank two times higher on Google.
So using a domain like this
should actually help us sell more.
When you think about it, this makes sense
because when someone sees a .store domain,
they know right away
they're visiting a shop.
Luckily, we can get a
.store domain for free
as we're using the Build
Your Store AI tool.
However, if you aren't using this,
then you can also buy one from sites
like GoDaddy and Namecheap.
Let's go with something
simple like Tilbury Fitness
because, let's face it, I
have the body of a Greek God,
and obviously everyone
wants to look like me.
Now, I've got to link the
domain name to the store,
so I'm gonna press Connect Now
and enter the new domain name here.
Now, it will take a few moments to verify,
and then we're ready to go.
Before we officially start selling,
I'm gonna spend my last bit
of time left on the clock
to tweak the website,
stuff like filling in the footer details,
linking some social media accounts,
and making sure everything looks polished.
There we go.
All done and just in time.
Now it's time to move
on to the exciting part,
promoting the store and
getting those first sales in.
Okay, so it's a couple of days later now,
as I needed some time to order
a couple of the products.
The next thing on my list
is to advertise our store.
So to get some eyeballs on our store,
I've decided to work
with some influencers.
Now, Gym Shark has proved
this strategy works very well
in the fitness niche, and it's great,
because I'll get a positive endorsement
from a trusted figure
and traffic to my store.
So it's essentially killing
two birds with one stone.
But don't worry,
I'm not gonna be spending
thousands of dollars
working with huge influencers.
I've got a much better plan.
I'm gonna use micro-influencers.
These are accounts with anywhere
from 10 to 50,000 followers,
whereas macro-influencers
are accounts with 500,000
to a million followers.
So what does that make
me then, super macro?
That is terrible, I'm not.
I'm not doing this just to save costs.
According to Social
Bakers, micro-influencers
boast up to a 60%
increased engagement rate
compared to macro-influencers.
Micro-influencers also have
a 20% plus higher conversion rate.
This can help brands boost
their e-commerce sales.
That sounds perfect for what we need.
So I've reached out to
a couple of lads I know
called the Gray Brothers.
They've been making short
videos for a couple of years now
and have around 14,500
followers on Instagram.
They do have more on other platforms,
but I'm more interested in Instagram
because I want them to
post a story with a link.
I could also get them to
promote the other products,
but first I wanna test
out if their audience
will actually buy before
risking anymore money.
And who knows, people
might even explore the shop
and buy other items
without me having to
promote them directly.
I approved their script yesterday
and they've just sent me the final video.
But before we have a look,
let's do a bit of quality
check on the items I ordered.
This is the breathing trainer
and it feels pretty damn
good and built to last.
I think my son might
even take it for himself,
but seriously, it's always good
to know that the quality is good
because the last thing we want
is unhappy customers wanting refunds.
Okay, so we also have
the hat, nice and wooly,
that should keep nice and warm.
I like the fact it's got a
peak on it, very stylish,
can't be bad.
And the golf clips, do you know what?
They are really good.
They are better quality
'cause my ones slip off
and they've got a lot
more power behind them,
so I think I'll be
having those for myself.
And then a resistance band.
They're always popular,
so I think we should be
onto a winner with those.
Right, let's take a look at the video.
- What are you doing?
- I'm just wearing my respirator.
- Respirator?
You're in a gym, not a hospital mate.
- But it's improving my cardio.
- What are you on about?
- The breathing training respirator
restricts your breathing,
which increases your red blood cell count,
helping you improve your cardio.
Buy it today using the link in the bio.
- Well, that's definitely a bit wacky,
but that's part of the charm.
It's quick, attention grabbing,
and shows off the breathing
trainer in action,
which is exactly what we needed.
That high energy slightly
off the wall style
works really well on Instagram stories
because it stops people from
skipping and pulls them in.
Even though it's not the
most traditional approach,
it fits the Grays brothers
audience perfectly.
Their followers love this kind of content
and it feels so natural coming from them.
I'm gonna get them to put this story up
with a link to the product
page and check back tomorrow.
So let's hope we make some sales.
So it's been 24 hours and
I've got some exciting news.
We've made some sales.
Now, it doesn't seem like my approach
of only promoting one
product really worked,
as people didn't buy anything else,
but as of today, we've sold 12
of these breathing trainers.
Okay, two of those sales were
technically me for testing,
of course, but the other 10 were legit.
So not counting my two orders,
10 genuine purchases for
13 pounds and 42 pence
is 134 pounds and 20 pence,
and converted to US dollars is $170.85.
But of course not all of that is profit.
The items cost me an
average of $3.95 each.
So $39.50 went towards
product costs and shipping.
As AutoDS shipped all the orders for us,
we didn't need to worry about anything.
After factoring in the $50
I paid the Grays brothers
and the $1 Shopify fee after
our three day trial ran out,
our total cost came to $90.50.
That leaves us with a
profit of $80.35 cents.
Now, I know $80 might
not sound life changing,
but let's put this into perspective.
This was all done with minimal effort
using AI tools and a budget of
just $1 to set everything up
and $50 for marketing.
Now, imagine scaling this.
If we promoted 20 products
and they kept ticking
along making regular sales,
this could easily turn
into thousands of dollars
in profit every month.
If you'd like to see a follow
up video in the future,
be sure to give this one a thumbs up.
Of course, before I post this,
I'll need to change the name of the store
to make sure no one
stumbles across the site
and starts buying products
as that wouldn't make it a fair test.
If you wanna see more ideas
for making passive income,
I've got another video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you wanna grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.