"The stock market is doomed,
and I'm selling everything."
This is the type of comment I'm seeing
all over social media right now.
I get it, everything's
taken a sudden dive,
from stocks to crypto.
And I know a lot of you
who watch my channel
have just started investing.
So for you guys, this is
understandably pretty worrying.
So today, I thought it was important
to address your concerns,
explain what's causing all this mayhem,
and finally, give you my thoughts
on how you can best navigate this storm.
I'm prioritizing getting
this video out quickly,
so don't expect the editing
to be as slick as usual.
It's more important for
you to hear the information
so you can use it to your advantage.
This is one video you
should definitely not skip.
So why is the stock market plummeting?
To put this into perspective,
the S&P 500 dropped 3%,
which was the biggest one-day
drop in nearly two years.
The Dow dropped 2.6%,
while the NASDAQ slipped 3.4%.
This sounds pretty alarming.
And from my research, there
are four main reasons for this.
So let's go through them one
by one so that we can see
if we're due another historic market crash
similar to the 2008 financial crisis
or just a little bump along the road.
Reason one, of course,
is the fear of recession.
Now, if the economy went into a recession,
the stock market would
most likely plummet.
This isn't always the case,
as there have been a
few exceptions to this,
like in the 2020 recession,
as the S&P 500 returned
16.3% for that year.
However, that isn't the norm.
This makes sense as during a recession,
less money is being spent
by people like you and me.
Companies then start firing staff,
leading to more people being unemployed,
which causes people to spend even less.
This results in companies
also earning less
and, most of the time,
stock prices being impacted.
This is one vicious cycle,
and I hope you can see
why this would be a pretty
bad situation to be in.
So if we aren't in a recession yet,
why is the stock market going down?
Well, as the stock market is
known as a leading indicator,
whenever there's a hint
of a recession happening,
it reacts to that news pretty negatively.
So you're probably thinking,
what was that hint?
Well, several data reports showed
that the US had only added
114,000 jobs in July,
below expectations of about 150,000,
and that unemployment had risen to 4.3%.
This is higher than any
month since October 2021.
Look, these numbers are
far from a disaster.
The unemployment rate
is still relatively low,
and the underperformance
in hiring isn't terrible.
However, it has triggered
something known as the Sahm rule.
This is a pretty cool
little rule that activates
when the average unemployment
rate over three months
goes up by at least 0.5%
compared to its lowest
point over the past year.
The reason people take this seriously
is because it's accurately predicted
every US recession since
the Second World War.
In response, Goldman Sachs raised its odds
of a recession occurring in
the next year from 15 to 25%.
Interestingly, the woman
who came up with the rule,
Claudia Sahm, doesn't think the law
is gonna be right this time,
and to put your mind at ease,
there have been other
rules like this before,
such as the bond yield curves
that have turned out to
be unreliable recently.
One reason why it might be a false alarm
is that this time around,
unemployment isn't rising
because people are losing their jobs.
Instead, it's because more people
are entering the workforce.
However, as I mentioned before,
unemployment rising is only one factor
in a vicious cycle of a recession.
The other important one
is the amount of money
everyday people are spending.
Unfortunately, it looks like
spending is slowing down, too.
Now, it may sound odd,
but a good way to gauge
this is by checking
how companies like McDonald's
on Walmart are doing,
and both have recently
said their customers
are cutting back on spending.
Another company to watch is Wayfair.
I actually buy a lot of
my furniture from them.
I'm actually sitting on a
Wayfair chair right now.
They recently mentioned
that customers are being very cautious,
with spending down nearly
25% from three years ago.
Now, this all sounds pretty worrying.
However, when it comes to the Sahm rule,
this time around, I'm taking
it with a pinch of salt.
Even Goldman Sachs seem to agree.
Although they've
increased their projection
on the risk of recession,
they still think it's pretty unlikely.
There's also a lot of time
for the big dogs at the Federal Reserve
to swoop in and protect the economy,
which leads me nicely onto
reason two is interest rates.
Right, check out this graph.
The last few times that
the Fed cut interest rates
from their peak, a recession
followed closely behind.
And guess what's just happened?
You got it, the US Federal Reserve hinted,
after its meeting at the end of July,
that interest rates would soon be cut.
Now, this graph also
looks pretty concerning.
However, it really doesn't
show us the full picture.
To understand why this time is different
from those past examples on the graph,
we need to look at why the Federal Reserve
initially put interest rates up in 2022.
The answer is simple. The pandemic hit.
Money printers were on full blast,
and supply chains were suffering,
leading to high inflation levels.
The only way to bring
prices back under control
was to increase interest rates.
This was an unprecedented situation,
which I don't think we'll
see again in our lifetimes,
certainly not in mine.
When they did this, they set
an inflation rate target to hit
and said they would start cutting rates
once they achieved it.
This strategy worked,
and inflation has come
down pretty significantly
from its peak of 9.1% in 2022.
But it still remains
slightly above the
Fed's target rate of 2%.
So now if we go back to the graph,
all those past examples of
the Fed cutting interest rates
was because they were trying
to stop a recession from happening.
However, this time, it's
because are so close
to hitting their inflation rate target.
So the Fed cut in interest
rate should actually be seen
as a positive move for investors,
because it helps boost the economy.
When rates are lower,
borrowing money becomes easier,
which means more money flows around.
This is the opposite of what
happens during a recession.
So on the surface, lots of
these factors look worrying.
However, when you dig a bit deeper,
it doesn't seem as bad as it looks.
So what else has caused the
markets to drop so much?
That brings me on to
reason three, tech stocks.
If you recently invested in
any of the top tech companies,
then you were definitely
hit harder than most,
especially the stocks in a group
known as the Magnificent 7,
which include Apple, Amazon, Alphabet,
Meta, Microsoft, Tesla, and NVIDIA.
Now, you might be thinking, "That's fine.
I don't invest in individual tech stocks."
However, this also impacts the
S&P 500 Index Fund investors,
as these top seven tech
stocks actually make up
about 31% of the S&P 500,
meaning that when tech
stocks get hit hard,
so does the entire index fund.
So I guess the obvious question is,
why are tech stocks suffering?
Well, recently these
stocks have been soaring
due to the promise of
revolutionary AI technology.
I went to a conference last year in Texas,
and all they seemed to be banging on about
was all these different AI tools
I should be using in my business.
I honestly got a bit
sick of hearing about it
over and over again.
It does seem like the AI craze
has caused a bubble to form,
pushing some stock prices higher
than they should have ever been.
Don't get me wrong. I do
definitely see the value in AI.
It's not like the metaverse.
Enough said about that, I think.
I just think the value of
our current AI capabilities
have been widely overvalued
and that investors are realizing this,
causing stock prices to fall
to more reasonable levels.
I'm not alone with this thinking,
as Warren Buffett's Berkshire
Hathaway slashed its stake
in Apple by almost 50%
in the second quarter.
There also seems to be bad news
followed by more bad news
coming from the AI space.
I mean, just recently,
the first preview of
Apple Intelligence failed
to live up to the hype,
and NVIDIA's highly
anticipated Blackwell chips
will be delayed due to design flaws.
These chip delays will
also impact companies
like Meta and Microsoft,
so everything is pretty interconnected.
Look, all in all,
I personally think investors
got a little hyped about AI,
and it became a bit of a buzzword.
It reminds me of when I was investing
during the dot-com
bubble in the late 1990s.
Just keep in mind that the
stocks with the sharpest booms
tend to fall the furthest.
Reason four is the Japanese yen.
Now, imagine you discover
this really clever loophole.
You borrow money from someone
with virtually no interest
and invest it wisely.
Meanwhile, the currency's
value drops significantly.
By the time you need to repay the loan,
the money you owe is worth much less
than when you borrowed it,
but your investment has grown,
so you end up repaying
the devalued currency
while profiting from
your investment's growth.
Now, that would be a pretty
cool life hack, right?
Well, it's exactly what
lots of traders were doing
with the Japanese yen,
as it's been falling
in value for years now.
It's a little more complicated than that,
but I'm not gonna bore
you with all the details.
It's a cool trick to make some easy money.
But why am I telling you this?
Well, everything changed when
the Bank of Japan decided
to raise its main interest
rate from nearly zero,
so once again, countries
messing with the interest rates.
This small change caused the value
of the Japanese yen to increase,
meaning that everyone using
the loophole I just described
were a little bit screwed,
as they had to sell their
assets to cover their losses.
Some experts believed that
this could be contributing
to the current decline
in the stock market.
Since all this went down,
the Bank of Japan has
eased up on the torque
of raising interest rates again.
This has made the yen drop a bit,
which has gone some way
to help calm the worries
that a stronger yen
could mess with the global
stock market once again.
So as you can see, there
are lots of reasons
behind the recent stock market decline.
Now that you have all the facts,
let me give you my
thoughts on all of this,
and how you can adjust
your investing strategy.
As always, I'm not a financial advisor,
and none of this should be
taken as financial advice.
I'm just speaking from years of experience
actually investing and seeing
situations like this happen
time and time again.
Firstly, throughout my investing journey,
one phrase has always served me well:
buy when there's blood in the water.
In other words, when the
stock market is in decline,
and people are panic-selling,
pushing prices down to irrational levels,
that's the time to step in and invest.
Another phrase that
teaches the same thing is,
"Buy the dip."
I know it should go without saying,
but if you want to do this,
then you need to make sure
you have an emergency fund
of at least three to five
months of your living expenses.
This is more crucial than ever,
as the stock market is
in a turbulent time,
and you don't wanna be forced
to sell your stocks at a loss
only to find out later
that if you'd held them,
then you'd actually have come out ahead.
Look, nobody can predict
if the stock market
is gonna go up or continue downwards.
However, I've always come
out on top eventually
by dollar-cost-averaging
into a low-cost S&P 500
Index Fund as it declines.
This essentially just means
buying at regular intervals
as the price drops.
This could be every day or every week.
For all the people that have
been watching my videos,
waiting for the perfect chance
to jump in and start investing,
if I was in your shoes,
I'd start my journey now.
Yes, you can't guarantee returns,
but at least you're entering
at a lower price point.
If you're looking for a good
investing platform to use,
then one of my favorites is Trading 212.
Since I was planning to
talk about their app anyway,
I reached out to see
if they'd be interested
in sponsoring this portion of the video.
They agreed and are also
offering a free fractional share
worth up to a hundred pounds
to anyone that uses the code TILBURY
when they create an account.
Plus, you can get more
free fractional shares
by inviting your friends.
Both of you will get a
free fractional share
as long as they fund their account.
Secondly, make sure you're diversified.
This basically means spreading your money
across different baskets of assets
like stocks, bonds, and even crypto.
This is key to reducing investment risk
and smoothing the ride
through a crazy market.
So if one stock or industry has a bad day,
your other investments may
help offset those losses.
If you're an index fund investor like me,
then you'll be pretty diversified anyway.
But bear in mind that the S&P 500
is top-heavy with tech companies,
so it might be worth investing
in a Total US Stock Market Fund
to get even more diversification.
Thirdly, keep your eye on the long game.
It's easy to be positive when
your portfolio is growing,
but when things start to go a bit south,
and your gains start disappearing,
it can be really tempting
to sell everything.
I've been there,
but holding on has
always worked out for me.
Trying to guess the best
times to buy and sell stocks
is really tough and often
leads to missed chances,
according to Charles Schwab.
Remember, if you sell
when the market is down,
you're making those losses permanent.
For example, during the COVID
market crash in February 2020,
if you had $1,000 in an
ETF, tracking the S&P 500,
it would've lost over 30% of its value.
Selling then would've
locked in those losses.
But if you'd held on,
you would've seen your
investment bounce back by August,
just seven months.
If you're waiting to
jump back into the market
when things look better,
you'll probably end up paying more
and missing out on the rebound gains.
So all in all, remember,
the US economy still remains pretty strong
even after the losses.
The S&P 500 Index is still up
more than 9% since January.
Market corrections or a drop
of at least 10% from their
highs occur on average
every 1 1/2 to two years.
So this isn't crazy or
out of the ordinary.
I actually heard a pretty
good quote the other day,
and it went something like this.
"When the stock market goes
up, it takes the stairs.
And when it goes down, it
jumps out of the window."
And recently, we've jumped out of a window
from a pretty high floor,
because we've been going
up a lot of stairs.
Now, I think that sums up our
current situation perfectly.
If you wanna know how I pick my stocks,
then you can watch this next video.
But don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if you
wanna grow your wealth, okay.
I'll see you over there.