So you wanna start a side hustle
and earn an extra $1000 a month.
Well, here's the key.
I call it the side hustle pyramid,
and following this strategy
took me from broke school dropout
to millionaire in my twenties.
So in this video,
I'm gonna guide you through
the three different levels,
explain what I did at each stage,
and also give you nine
up-to-date side hustle ideas
that you can use to start
making at least $1000 per month.
The first level is
service-based side hustles.
I'd always recommend you start
with one of these side hustles
as you don't need any money to get going.
These will also form the foundations
of your side hustle pyramid,
so it's important not to skip this step.
When I started out, I didn't
have a penny to my name.
My family hardly had
enough money for food,
which meant I was always eating
around at my friend's houses.
Looking back, I think
this was a good thing,
as I had to find a way to make
money, it wasn't a choice.
So I started thinking
about all the services
I could offer to earn some extra cash.
I did everything from washing cars
to mowing the neighbor's lawns.
These side hustle still work, however,
if you don't wanna get your hands dirty,
then there are some great
side hustle based ideas
that you can do online.
Side hustle idea number
one is video editing.
The demand for a good
video editor is sky high.
My son Curtis used to do
this when he was younger
and he managed to make
around $10,000 a month.
Seriously, guys, I know
a handful of YouTubers
that are screaming out for a good editor,
but here's the thing,
not all people who can
edit are good editors.
Most people who call themselves an editor
don't actually have the full package.
I want you to think of editing
like the the yin and yang symbol.
The black side is the technical skill.
You need to be able to cut
and chop around, add music,
and do all that complicated stuff.
But on the white side is
the storytelling skill.
You gotta be able to structure
the story in different ways
to draw out emotions and
keep the video interesting
and the viewers engaged.
I'd hire a great storyteller
over a technically good
editor any day of the week.
So if you can edit and you've
got a knack for storytelling,
then this might be the
right side hustle for you.
Remember, there's so
many different options
when it comes to editing.
There's long form content, like podcast,
short form, like tiktoks,
and even YouTube videos, like this one.
Find a format that you enjoy
the most and go for it.
The last thing I'd say on this
is that when I've recently
been trying to hire video editors,
most of them aren't very impressive.
So take it from me,
it really doesn't take much to stand out.
Side hustle idea number
two is graphic design.
Graphic design is basically
where art meets business.
It's all about arranging
images and texts to get ideas,
messages, and information across
in a way that's super visually appealing.
It's not just about creating
something that looks good,
it's gotta drive results.
This field is relatively easy to excel in.
When I'm hiring graphic designers,
I look for someone with
common business sense,
communication skills, and creativity.
So if you possess all of these attributes,
you should have no problem
attracting clients.
There's so many different
types of clients,
people who want YouTube thumbnails,
logo designs for their businesses,
website designs, and even clothing design.
If you focus on one of these niches,
then you'll make a lot of money
as you'll be seen as an
expert in that sector.
If you choose this side hustle,
then you'll need to be able
to detach your emotions
from your designs.
Clients often request changes,
and that can be hurtful
when you've spent a lot of
time creating something,
but you can't let this get
in the way of making money.
It is okay to explain why
you believe in your ideas,
but never make the client
feel unintelligent.
Keep in mind that they're
the ones that are paying you.
I know that can be difficult to accept
when you know the requested
changes are not beneficial,
but that's part of the job.
Side hustle idea three is writing.
I'm gonna be honest,
some writers make as
little as $600 a year,
but if you get it right,
then you can make thousands.
I know that's a huge
difference, but stay with me
because most writers are
missing the crucial element
to making this side hustle actually work.
The majority of writers
are artistically driven,
but not business savvy.
They wanna write the next "Harry Potter."
This means they aren't actually
writing what's in demand.
So no, I don't suggest you
become a traditional writer
with a whole book series.
Instead, you need to publish
where the readers are.
These readers are online.
You could write copy for sales
pages, emails for businesses,
online articles, LinkedIn posts,
or even scripts for
tiktoks and YouTube videos.
Writing is great
as you can work remotely
from anywhere in the world.
I know so many people out
in Thailand at the moment,
they're living like kings in the day
and just doing their work in the evenings.
If what your writing is valuable enough,
then you could even ask for
a percentage of the sales
that you contribute towards.
While this isn't completely
passive income, it does mean
that you aren't just
trading your time for money.
You are instead getting
paid based on your results.
Side hustle idea number four is coaching.
The pay for this one does vary
depending on what you are teaching
and how many clients you have.
Someone I know is making $10,000 a month
by being an online fish coach.
Come on, Goldie, one more lap.
This could be a personal
best. You can do it!
Oh, but seriously, I'm
talking about someone
who teaches you how to
look after your pet fish.
People honestly love this hobby.
My son's girlfriend just got a tank
and I can see why people
are so keen to learn.
Just like all the other
side hustles I've suggested,
this one really does rely
on you bringing value.
People will only pay for your coaching
if they're able to see improvement.
Your coaching has to provide the client
with lasting change and growth.
For instance, you could
start a coaching course
on how to quit alcohol.
My friend Rury did this and he started
a paid membership group
called, One Year No Beer.
This group supports
people in quitting alcohol
and then helps them drink in moderation
after they've completed the challenge.
Your coaching could provide
different video lessons,
progress charts,
and a community for others
to share their experience.
You could even arrange in-person events,
like One Year, No Beer.
All of these are excellent
choices for beginners.
However, since service-based side hustles
have a low barrier to entry,
competition can be fierce.
One way to stand out is by
having an exceptional website.
In today's day and age, if
you don't have a website,
you might as well be invisible.
A website acts as your
virtual storefront, open 24/7,
offering information,
building credibility,
and ultimately increasing your earnings.
This doesn't have to take long to build
because you can actually
use the power of AI
to make your website for you.
Let me show you how to do
it. I'm gonna use Hostinger.
They have this really awesome
AI powered website builder.
All you have to do is enter
your brand name, like so,
select the website type,
describe your business,
and now wait a few seconds,
and there you have it,
a fully professional website.
You can then customize your website
with their drag and drop feature.
Oh, if you want a cool logo as well,
they've got an AI logo maker
that can do it for you.
It's honestly that simple.
Hostinger are kindly sponsoring
this portion of the video,
so if you are interested in
making a website like this,
then you can use the link
Hostinger.com/MarkTilbury.
I also managed to get
you an extra 10% discount
if you use the coupon code, Mark Tilbury.
Side note, they give you the option
between the premium and business plan.
Now, I recommend going
with the business plan
as it offers top AI tool,
such as an AI writer,
and e-commerce tools with
zero transaction fees,
and a free domain.
If you want access to
all of these features,
then it's only about $4 a
month for the business plan,
but I know from experience
that it can save you far more than that,
not to mention how much
more money you'll make
with a professional looking website.
Right, let's get back to
the side hustle pyramid.
The second level is
attention-based side hustles.
What's the difference
between you and Mr. Beast?
Attention.
Mr. Beast has learned how
to get attention online,
which he's used to become
YouTube's first billionaire.
Attention is honestly one
of the most valuable things
to have as long as you
can use it correctly.
When I was younger, the
internet didn't exist.
Yes, I'm really that old.
So in order to benefit from
attention-based side hustles,
I had to go on TV,
and also compete in world championships
for radio control helicopters
all around the world.
This got me known globally
as one of the best in the game
when it came to RC helicopters.
They used to love me
out in Japan especially,
and I could then use that
attention to make money.
So how can you use attention nowadays?
Well, side hustle number
five is affiliate marketing.
I bet you hear this side hustle
chucked around online all the
time, and for good reason too.
The potential is insane.
You can literally use your phone
and make relatively passive income.
In fact, I've personally earned
more than $100,000 a month doing this.
So let's dive into how to
do affiliate marketing.
It involves you partnering with brands
and promoting their products or services
to your audience through either a website,
social media page, or an email list.
It's even better to use all three.
You can easily find brand partnerships
on websites like impact.com.
I know many of you won't
have an audience yet,
but if you create videos on
TikTok about specific products,
then you can get instant views
by leveraging the algorithm
and start pushing people to
use your affiliate links.
Building up your own
subscribers and followers is,
of course, the more sustainable
way of doing things,
but this does take a little bit more time.
The key is to find the perfect fit
between your content and products.
The products should make the
content better and vice versa.
It's like when I tell you,
you can get a free stock
worth up to 100 pound with
a link in the description.
You're interested in a free
stock. Why wouldn't you be?
And I also get a kickback for
referring you. Everyone wins.
By the way, this is a real
offer in the description,
so feel free to take advantage of it.
If you can find win-win
affiliate offers like this
that fit with your content, that's great.
The best way to do this is to advertise
the brands and companies you align with.
So for example, I wouldn't
go and try and sell makeup
because I know nothing
about it, and quite frankly,
I only wear it on the weekend anyway.
So ask yourself, what sorts
of products or services
are you really educated on,
or even better, if you use them yourself.
The scalability for
this is endless really.
A lot of this money will come in passively
if you put in the hard
work at the beginning.
Side hustle idea six is content curation.
With this option, you
won't need a camera at all,
just an eye for valuable
and relatable content.
I bet you are thinking,
wait a minute, Mark,
what does a content curator even do?
Well, this side hustle involves finding
and organizing content
and making a social media
account to post it on.
So for example, you could
start an Instagram page
for aspiring entrepreneurs.
You might look for some
inspirational quotes
from people like Warren
Buffet and Mark Tilbury.
I had to give myself a bit of
a shout out there, didn't I?
You get the idea. It's
essentially a theme page.
I'm sure you already
follow pages like this
without even realizing.
Lad Bible does this.
It's one of the biggest pages in the UK
and it's worth a ton of money.
The real beauty of content curation
is its limitless potential.
You're not confined to a single page.
You can have multiple pages,
each with its own theme.
All you have to do is hit
the right target audience.
My advice would be to think of this
like crafting an experience.
You want people to visit the page
and feel compelled to post a comment.
This engagement helps build a community,
which is how pages like
this grow to insane levels.
Once you've got a page up and running,
you'll be able to accept
collaborations with brands,
generate advertising revenue,
and even have the ability
to sell products or merch.
Now, side hustle number
seven is content creation.
I know you're probably thinking,
"I don't wanna be a YouTuber,"
but content creation is
so much broader than that.
It's becoming a huge industry
with so many different niches.
So don't just skip this one
before fully considering all your options.
I know this one seems daunting at first,
but I can assure you, it's within reach.
YouTube used to be about who you knew,
as breaking through
meant you had to collab
with the right people.
However now, if you've
got something interesting
or entertaining to share,
then the algorithm will push your videos.
Whether you want to do
YouTube, TikTok, or Instagram,
there are certain elements
you'll need to grow.
In my experience, the winning formula
boils down to these
three essential elements,
value, authenticity, and connection.
So no, it's not just about writing trends.
Yes, it can help with short term exposure,
but if there's nothing to
gain from your content,
then why would people stick around?
So when you infuse your
content with these qualities,
pick a niche, maintain a
consistent posting schedule,
and you'll make progress.
As long as you're either
teaching something valuable
or creating something meaningful
to the right audience,
then there's no reason
why you can't choose this side hustle.
Even if you don't want to
produce content as a side hustle,
you should still do it to
build your personal brand.
This is the most valuable
asset an entrepreneur can have.
The third level is
product-based side hustles.
When I bring up the idea of
a product-based side hustle,
I see a lot of people start
to get a little bit nervous.
It's true, back in my
day, starting a business
that revolved around a product
meant coughing up a decent amount of cash.
Take my model shop, for instance,
my very first product-based venture,
I poured every penny I made
from my service-based side hustles
and TV appearances into it.
Even then, it was a stretch,
so I had to knock on the
bank's door for a loan.
It was a bit of a gamble, and
I knew that if I didn't manage
to sell enough products on my opening day,
I'd be sleeping in my van that night
because I wouldn't have had enough money
for petrol to get home.
But what can you do nowadays?
Well, side hustle idea number
eight is digital products.
I'm personally a big fan of this one,
and if you've got the right skills,
you can make a lot of money doing this.
I've got a friend called
Catya making $100,000 a month
with this side hustle alone.
So this side hustle involves
selling a product online,
most commonly in the form of info products
where your customers can
learn something from you.
So for example, you
could sell a workout plan
that increases in difficulty over time
to help customers lose a
certain amount of weight.
This one really does depend
on who you are as a person,
your skills, and what you have to offer.
This offer has got to be
valuable to a mass audience
so that you can guarantee sales.
It's also a great one to scale because
there's a wide range of different
digital products to sell,
like templates, eBooks,
subscription services,
memberships, stock photos, or even apps.
Side hustle idea nine is e-commerce.
A lot of people get
confused between e-commerce
and drop shipping, so
let's clear that up first.
Drop shipping is a
specific type of e-commerce
where the seller doesn't
have to touch the item,
they just order it from the supplier
when the customer places
an order with them,
reducing costs and risks.
Whereas traditional e-commerce
involves owning inventory
and having direct control over
quality and customer service.
For me personally,
I've always been more
of a traditional guy,
and I even head off to China
to meet with my manufacturers firsthand.
Yep, it's time for my classic phrase,
I like to press the flesh.
But that doesn't mean it's
the right option for you.
I have nothing against drop
shipping or Amazon FBA.
However, it is essential
to build your own brand
with whatever method you choose.
You don't just want to be a one stop shop
where customers forget your name,
in what, T minus one minute.
Having a brand will also mean
you don't always have to compete on price,
as people will trust you more.
It's honestly very possible
to make $1000 a month
from any of these side hustles.
If you'd like to hear some actual stories
of teenagers who've
managed to achieve this,
then you should watch this next video.
But don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.