- The biggest lie young people
are told when they're 18,
19, and 20 is go to university
and you're guaranteed
to get a high paid job.
This lie is drilled into
through the school system
and then reinforced by parents
who are stuck in the past.
While it might have been true in my time,
it's not the reality anymore.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm not saying that
studying is a waste of time.
Many degrees are very useful
and the student experience
is unforgettable.
However, relying solely on a degree
to make you rich isn't the right approach.
That's why it's so important for students
to start some kind of side
hustle that has the ability
to grow into something
much bigger in the future.
Look, I wasn't wealthy enough to be able
to afford university or probably
academically smart enough,
but I always had side hustles.
Ultimately, my side hustles
turned into multimillion dollar
businesses and made me a millionaire.
That's why today I'm gonna
dive into seven side hustles
students can start this year.
To be honest, these can actually apply
to anyone anywhere in the world,
and because I hate those silly videos
that just regurgitate the same
list of side hustle ideas,
I'm actually gonna
share real life examples
of people smashing it
and rate them out of five in
these important categories.
How much time it takes to learn,
how much money you need,
and how difficult it is
to make a thousand dollars per month.
Side hustle idea number one,
faceless short form content.
This is Daniel Bitton.
Like many of you, he
started using social media
for fun at the age of 13.
Now at 16, he's earning
half a million dollars
every single month
creating short form content
on Snapchat without even showing his face.
It sounds unbelievable,
but it's completely true.
My son, Kurt, has actually
bumped into him at LAX airport
and after doing some research,
I can assure you he's not capping.
So why can you make so
much money doing this?
Well, at the moment,
there's a huge war going on
between Snapchat, YouTube,
Instagram, and TikTok.
During the pandemic,
TikTok became so popular
and grabbed the attention of the world.
Since then, all the different
social media platforms
have been competing for this attention.
As the more eyes they have on their app,
the more money they can
make from advertisers.
Stick with me because this is
where it all starts coming together.
The one thing these platforms
need more than anything else
is content creators,
And what attracts the best creators better
than anything else?
Money, because we all
like a little bit of that.
This is a once in a lifetime opportunity,
but once a platform is
established at the top,
competition will decrease
along with the payouts,
so you'll need to jump
in on this one quickly.
If you wanna be making close
to half a million dollars a month,
just like Daniel,
the people that have paid the most
are those that create original content
rather than just cutting up
other people's content from YouTube.
Daniel does this by using existing videos,
but then adding different voiceovers,
music, and edits.
This strategy combined
with consistent posting
led to extreme growth.
He then expanded with multiple
channels in various niches
to attract diverse audiences.
So for example, one of his
channels is about rapper updates
and the others is focused
on live streamers.
Now for those important ratings,
I'll give this a four out of five.
Although making short clips may seem quick
and easy, there's a lot more
that goes into it than
you might first think.
Saying this, if you regularly
watch TikTok or shorts,
then you'll be better prepared the most.
Creating short form
clips is a lot more about
understanding human psychology
than it is about fancy editing.
If you can create a great hook
and build towards some
kind of payoff at the end,
you'll increase the watch time.
This is the only trick you need
to know if you want
your videos to go viral
and earn you lots of money.
Trust me, I've managed to get
7 million followers on TikTok
using this exact strategy.
The best way to teach yourself this
is to watch short form
content on a daily basis.
Make it part of your routine.
This might sound different
from what many people
my age will tell you,
but I'm not talking about
using it for entertainment.
Every time you stop and watch a short,
I want you to ask yourself
a simple question.
What intrigued me enough to stop scrolling
and watch the whole thing?
Make a list in your notes
app and before you know it,
you'll have a ton of
different winning ideas.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'll give this one out of five.
Because if you have a phone
and an internet connection
and you can get started,
and if you're watching this video,
then I'd assume you've
got both of those things.
Thirdly, how easy is it
to make a thousand dollars per month?
I'll give this a one out of five.
As I mentioned, social media
platforms are handing out cash
like there's no tomorrow.
Just think to make a
thousand dollars a month,
all you'd have to do is
be 0.2% as good as Daniel.
Now, if you don't think that's achievable,
then you need to believe
in yourself a bit more.
Idea two, investing.
A lot of people are gonna
disagree with me on this one
as it's technically not a side hustle.
However, it makes me around
about $17,000 per week,
so I thought it was
definitely worth a mention.
It's taken me a lot of
years to build up to that.
However, I've managed
to do it all on my own
without a financial advisor charging
me commission on every investment.
It's really not as complicated
as people make out.
Of course, I'm not a financial advisor
and investments can go up as well as down,
but my dollar cost averaging strategy
has worked wonders for me over the years.
This is when you consistently
buy into the market
no matter if it's high or low.
Over time, the idea is
that the price you buy,
the stock at averages out.
You can do this with pretty
much any stock you want.
However, the real secret
weapon has to be index funds.
If you were to invest
$200 a month for 40 years
and get an average return of 10% per year,
then you'll have over $1.2 million.
I know what you're thinking.
How on earth am I gonna make a 10% return?
You are out of touch, old man.
Well, of course, past
results are no guarantee
of future returns.
However, over the 10 years,
the average annual return
of the S&P 500 was 11%.
Okay, but I don't wanna wait 40 years
to become a millionaire.
This is exactly how
you should be thinking.
I didn't wanna wait until
I was old and gray either.
I went out and made quick
money through my side hustles
started a business,
and made millions all while investing
around half of my earnings
and multiplying it in the stock market.
It's not a choice
between one or the other.
You really should consider
doing both at the same time.
Now, let's get onto the ratings.
Oh, I've forgotten the photo.
Let's use that one.
Firstly, how much time does
investing take to learn?
I'll give this a one out of five
because as I said, the
basics are extremely simple.
I've got multiple videos on my channel
breaking down the core
concepts like passive income,
the different types of accounts to open,
and my favorite, index funds.
Once you master the tricky words,
you'll see that it's really simple.
Especially with different
investment apps allowing you
to automate your investments
every single month
so you don't even have
to think about them.
My favorite for this kind
of thing is Trading 212,
so I reached out to them to
see if they'd be interested
in sponsoring this section of the video.
They agreed and are also
offering a free stock
worth of up to a hundred pound to anyone
that uses the code Tilbury
when they create an account
and deposit as little as one pound.
If you're a beginner,
then definitely check
out their pies feature
as you can have a look
at what other people
are investing their money in
and then either create your
own pie or just copy theirs.
You can then set it to auto invest for you
as often as you like and
your money will be split
between the different stocks in your pie.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'll give this a one out of five
because you can start
with as little as $1.
I don't suggest you put all
of your money into stocks though.
Make sure you are investing it back into
your side hustle as well.
And thirdly, how easy is it
to make a thousand dollars per month?
I'll give this a one out of five.
As for me, I don't have to do anything.
It's just easy.
However, it took me a lot
of years of consistency
to get to this stage.
In my opinion, investing
should always be paired
with a side hustle that
generates you fast money.
Side hustle idea three, discord building.
This is Chris Peters
and he's on track to make
$15,000 a month from building
and managing Discord servers,
and he's only 19 years old.
I remember first chatting with
Chris a couple of years ago.
He must have been about 17 at the time.
I had just started my free discord group
and had absolutely no
idea what I was doing.
He messaged me and offered
to help me for free,
so I took him up on that offer
and he completely revamped my server.
By the way, I am still
running the free Discord group
and I'll drop a link in the description
below if you want to join us.
Over the years, I've been more
and more impressed with Chris's work ethic
and quick thinking, so it's fair
to say I'm not letting
him work free anymore.
If you don't know, discord
is basically this all in one
communication hub with text,
voice, and video chats.
It started off just for gamers,
but now it's pretty versatile,
used by all sorts of
communities and businesses.
There's a huge opportunity here
because as the usage of discord increases,
there are people like me a
few years ago who have no idea
how to operate it.
It's complex enough to confuse a beginner,
particularly those of an older generation,
but simple enough for a youngster
to learn in a short amount of time.
I mean, Chris started his Discord business
while he was still at school
sitting his GCSE exams
and I was one of his first clients.
Just remember to offer huge value upfront
before asking for any kind of payment.
If you do good work and
make yourself indispensable,
you'll start earning big.
Now it's time for those ratings.
Firstly, how much time does
this call take to learn?
I'll give this a two and a half outta five
as you can get to groups with the basics
in a couple of hours.
However, to do the
really complicated stuff,
it may take a bit longer depending on
how tech savvy you are.
I asked Chris for his top tip
for learning discord skills
and he said "It's important
to join multiple communities.
This way you can learn what
makes a successful server."
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'd rate this a one out of five.
You can get started
with just your computer.
Although finding clients
planning community features
and customizing the discord service
to fit your client's niche may take time.
In the early days, you
should be able to manage
all of this stuff yourself.
Thirdly, how easy is it
to make a thousand dollars per month?
I'd rate this a one out of five.
Let's look at the numbers now.
Assuming you can find four clients
and put them on a monthly retainer,
you'd only have to charge
them $250 each and boom,
that's a thousand dollars
a month right there,
and honestly, if you
find the right clients,
you should be able to charge
'em much more than this.
Side hustle idea four, online coaching.
This is Jack Jefferson.
He decided to quit his
$70,000 nine to five in London
to pursue his online fitness
coaching side hustle full-time
as it had started generating
him $7,000 a month.
Now, you may be thinking
that's only $14,000 more
than his full-time job in London.
However, now he has
something even more valuable,
freedom.
He can now operate his
side hustle from anywhere
in the world as long as he
has an internet connection
so he can check in with his clients
and review their progress.
Jefferson Training now has over 40 clients
in is growing by the month.
I get that not everyone is a gym expert,
and this might seem a little niche.
However, notice how the title
of this idea is an
online fitness coaching.
It's online coaching.
That's because there are countless things
you can teach people online
and get the same results as Jack.
From my travels to
Dubai or Miami recently,
all the young millionaires I meet
seem to be coming from
the online coaching space.
They all have some kind of info product
and they're earning in thousands.
It's honestly an absolute gold mine.
I've only started to notice this recently
as most of the millionaires
I've bumped into
before this at their own
physical products like me
with my range of radio control models.
The world is absolutely changing.
People really value online
support and expertise.
This industry just didn't
exist when I was younger.
Now it's time for those ratings.
Firstly, how much time does
online coaching take to learn?
I'll give this a two out of five
because if you already have a skill
people are willing to pay for,
then all you need to learn
is how to package it up and sell it.
Once you've created this process,
you can then rinse and repeat the formula
to get you thinking.
Here's what Jack does.
He starts off by conducting
an in-depth onboarding session
to understand the needs
and goals of each client.
He then crafts personalized
nutrition plans,
detailing breakfast, lunch,
and dinner alongside
tailored fitness plans,
specifying both training and rest in days.
He then sets up regular check-ins
where he guides his clients
through video feedback.
I hope you can see how something
like this can be easily
adapted to lots of
different types of coaching.
I think the key to making
good money relatively quickly
is to offer a degree of personalization
rather than just selling an online course
as people are pretty sick of those.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'd rate this a one out of five
as all you need is your
laptop and you're good to go.
Of course, this does assume you have
some kind of skill you can teach.
It might cost you a bit more
if you have to learn a skill first.
Thirdly, how easy is it
to make a thousand dollars per month?
I'd rate this a one out of five
on the difficulty scale
as from what I've seen,
this is incredibly easy.
People are lazy,
so although they could probably
learn this stuff from a book,
they don't wanna spend
the time doing that.
They would much rather spend some money
and be spoonfed the information.
Remember, people pay for convenience.
Side hustle idea five, AI animation.
This is Mercy.
He's responsible for all the animations
you see on my channel,
and he's making eight to $10,000 per month
creating these for multiple clients.
This side hustle is really interesting
as AI is the biggest thing to happen
to technology since the internet.
Just think how many billionaires
that created despite the ongoing buzz.
You might be surprised
how few businesses have
actually begun to use it.
You see there are five
stages to technology adoption
and they look like this.
First, you have the early innovators,
which make up 2.5% of the people.
They're the people that
are willing to take a risk
and go against the grain.
They'd go out and buy the Samsung Fold
or the new Apple Vision Pro
on its first initial release.
Second, we have the early adopters
making up 13.5% of the population.
Similar to innovators,
they're willing to take a risk,
however they prefer to test the product
before forming an opinion and
recommending it to others.
Thirdly, we have the early majority,
which is 34% of the population.
These are the people that
look at the product reviews
before making a purchase.
They want to see proof of it working
before committing to it.
This is a line where I
believe we currently are
with AI at the very first stage
of early majority adoption.
This is followed by the late
majority making up another 34%,
and finally the laggards,
which is a surprising 16%.
When you get to my age,
you'll find that most people
in the laggards category,
they like sticking with what they know
and they really don't want
to learn anything new.
Now, here's the important thing.
Whether you like it or not,
AI will go through this cycle,
so let me ask you this
very simple question.
Would you rather embrace it now
or wait for everyone
else to get the benefits
and end up having to use it anyway?
There are so many creative ways to use AI,
but let's go back to Mercy.
For a solid example, he
uses tools like ChatGPT
to help him script ideas out
and then uses Midjourney
to bring his ideas to life.
Let's get into the ratings.
I'd give this a four out of five,
although AI can do a lot of
the heavy lifting for you.
Mercy still devoted months
to mastering top-notch animation skills,
which helped inland clients
and build relationships to
keep the cash flowing in.
So I'd recommend mastering the
core principles of animation
and actively participate
in the industry networks
to keep refining your skills.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'd give this a one out of five.
Because we're at an early
stage in the adoption curve,
it doesn't take a lot of
expensive tools to stand out.
When Mercy first started his side hustle,
he managed to get featured on
Andrew Tate's Instagram story
because of some AI artwork he created.
This gave him all the
free promotion he needed
to build a strong client base.
This just shows that you don't
need a lot of cash right now
to make an impact.
Thirdly, how easy is it
to make a thousand dollars per month?
I'll give this a two out of five.
As online creators are getting more
and more popular, there is more money
flooded into the space.
Creators wanna stand out,
and by adding animations,
it's a great way to make their videos
look more premium and engaging.
So get started now and get so far ahead
that the late adopters
can never catch you.
Side hustle idea six,
reselling luxury items.
This is Ben Gallagher,
a normal lad who started
reselling luxury items online
as a side hustle.
In 2023, he generated 7.2 million pounds
through his business, Luxe Collective,
and even recently
appeared on Dragon's Den,
which is a bit like Shark Tank
and received investment
from Steven Bartlett
in exchange for a 3% equity stake.
I'm so proud of how far he's come
since appearing on my
old podcast years ago.
The luxury resale market saw
to a whopping $39.23 billion
in 2023, so it's no surprise that Ben
is having so much success.
The growing millennial
population is driving a lot
of this interest in luxury resale
along with social media culture
increasing the importance
of flexing designer labels.
Reselling is a really cool side hustle
as now with the internet,
you are able to sell
to anyone in the world.
Giving you access to a global marketplace.
So let's look at the ratings.
I'll give this a four out of five.
As Ben spent countless hours
learning how to identify fakes,
learning about the market
and scouting for the best purchases,
Ben looks out for items from
brands like Louis Vuitton,
Dior, Chanel, and even Hermes.
Of course, you can imagine
it's very important
that he knows his stuff
as just one slip up could
ruin his company's reputation.
Ben has to carefully examine each bag
for scent, stitching, material,
and even sends samples
to a company in New York,
which use microscopic technology
to examine the exact structure
of the materials used.
So if you're passionate about design items
and are prepared to put the time
into learning all the details,
then it's worth a shot.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'll give this a 3.5 out of five
as these designer items
can be pretty pricey.
I mean, some of these bags
are worth up to $30,000,
and that's the second hand price.
A lot of these high-end bags
tend to keep their value
or maybe drop slightly.
I mean, it's practically a
designer bag stock market.
Maybe that's why my son Curtis
has bought his girlfriend
so many bags, or maybe he's just a simp.
But of course, you don't have to start off
with items like this.
You can go for more reasonably priced ones
and work your way up.
That's what Ben did.
You also don't have to pay for marketing
as you can leverage social media platforms
to grow your customer
base completely free.
I mean, Ben struck gold on TikTok
when he started posting fashion content
and has now amassed over
1.6 million followers.
Thirdly, how easy is it
to make a thousand dollars per month?
I'll give this a one out of five.
As when you're dealing with luxury goods,
the profit margins are usually very nice.
Combine this with the average sale
and you can make this kind
of money with just one item.
The tricky thing for this
side hustle is getting
that initial money to start,
which is something you
don't have to worry about
with online writing.
This is Adam and he earns
over $10,000 a month
through online writing
before you get carried away.
He's not writing the next "Harry Potter"
or "Game of Thrones."
That kind of writing doesn't
earn you a good income
until you get published and hit it big,
which is a one in a million
chance for most writers.
Adam instead writes
what's actually in demand
and publishes where
the readers are online.
He started off writing blog
posts about his travels
to her own passive income and
live anywhere in the world.
This later led him to
working as a copywriter
for large influencers.
He got one client, which
led to another and so on.
He told me when he offers a service,
he always tries to be exclusive
and do it in a way that no one else could.
There's always gonna be
someone cheaper than you,
but not always someone more expensive.
Find a client who can afford
to pay the premium than
offer a world-class.
Service words can make you sound smart
or they can do the opposite
depending on how they're deployed.
That's why businesses hire copywriters,
basically salesmen but in print,
and it's not just websites either.
People need quality writers
for all sorts of things.
Everything from TikTok
scripts to threads on Twitter.
Content is king,
and the magician behind all
of this is often the writer.
Firstly, how much time
does writing take to learn?
I'll give this a five out a five
as writing is one of the
hardest things to do,
not physically, but mentally.
Especially in this day and age
where it's so easy to get
distracted by notifications.
In order to be a good writer,
you need to achieve a state of flow,
and that only comes when
you're able to focus
for long periods of time.
This is a dying skill.
The declining quality of our films
and TV shows can be partially
attributed to the inability
of many new writers to focus.
So if you can master it,
then you could be making some serious bag.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'd give this a one out of five
as you honestly only
need the bare minimum,
even a cheap phone will do.
This is an ideal side hustle for people
that want to make some instant cash
and not have to worry about ever really
upgrading their equipment.
Thirdly, how easy is it
to make a thousand dollars per month?
I'd give this a one out of five.
As once you've mastered the art selling
through your writing, you can
make insane amounts of money.
I'm talking over $500
an hour in many cases.
It all depends on how good
you are at making connections,
your skill with words,
and how fast you can write.
Some charge as much as
$50,000 for just one webpage.
You may be thinking, why so much?
Well, it's all about value.
If you charge $50,000 for a webpage
and it results in a business
monthly sales profit
going from $200,000 to $400,000,
wouldn't you say it's worth it?
It's all about leverage.
Making rich clients even richer
then asking for your slice of the pie.
If you want another side hustle idea,
then you can check out this video next
where I test out a popular
print on demand side hustle,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.