- This is my honest advice for anyone
who wants financial freedom,
and it comes from years
of personal experience.
You see, back in school, my
teacher saw me as a lost cause,
which pushed me to drop out at 16
and start an apprenticeship
as a carpenter,
which involved making wooden
trash cans for only $2 an hour.
This was just enough to cover my expenses.
Every day felt the same
and blended into one.
I was stuck on a hamster
wheel, never getting ahead.
I knew if I didn't find a way to escape,
then I'd end up just like
my soulless coworkers.
I wanted to be free
to do the things I loved without
being a slave to my boss.
So I came up with a plan
and managed to achieve millionaire status
and financial freedom within my 20s.
A lot of people ask me,
is it still possible
to become financially free today?
And the answer is yes, absolutely,
if you've got the right plan.
So by the end of this
video, my goal is for you
to have a clear roadmap
to get financially free
as quickly as possible.
Let's get into it.
Step one is to find your freedom figure.
Your freedom figure is the amount you need
to live your life without having
to worry about money ever again.
Once it's invested correctly,
it will generate enough passive income
to fully support your lifestyle
without ever running out.
I'll talk more about investing later on,
but first, we need to nail down
what that figure is for you
as this isn't a one size
fits all kind of thing,
because financial freedom
means different things
to different people.
So the first thing you need
to do is set your
financial freedom baseline.
Maybe you want a life where
you go on vacation more often,
drive a sports car, live in a
mansion, or buy a private jet.
Just bear in mind the
fancier the lifestyle
you are aiming for, the
tougher it'll be to get there.
Personally, I've always valued the freedom
that comes from not having
to chase money over
living a lavish lifestyle.
So I made a rule early on
to only increase the quality
of my lifestyle slightly
each and every year.
Let's go through the
different areas of your life
and estimate what each one
might cost to live comfortably.
I'll be basing this on studies that show
what people in their
20s typically aspire to.
Now, grab a piece of paper
and feel free to adjust the
numbers to match your own goals.
So first up, your house,
for most people in their 20s, city life
or a place on the outskirts is ideal.
If you get a spot in
Miami, you could be paying
around about $30,000 per year
for a one bedroom flat,
and if you're in the UK,
then London's rent prices
are pretty similar.
Next up is your car.
Now the Porsche 911 always seems
to appear on dream car list, so let's use
that as an example.
Luxury cars like this
come with higher costs
after considering fuel, maintenance
and insurance on top of the car payment,
you'd be looking at a
total of around $24,125.
Now for vacations, according
to the New York Post,
Gen Zs are far more interested in
traveling than my generation ever was.
Back in my day, one
vacation felt extravagant,
but now the sweet spot seems to be
around three trips for a year.
For three mid-range trips,
you're looking at about $5,000,
and of course, if you're
bringing someone along,
you can expect to double that.
Next, we have to consider
the boring bills.
If we stick with the one
bedroom apartment in a city,
then with electricity, heating, water
and internet, I'd estimate
that this would cost
about $3,000 per year.
Next is food.
Now, I'd assume you'd want a mix
of home cooking and eating out.
I reckon you could do this
for about $5,000 per year.
Now for health insurance,
this isn't really needed in the UK,
but if you're in the
USA, then you can expect
to pay 2,500 per year
for a mid-level plan.
Finally, there's leisure.
This covers your gym
membership, nights out
and any other spur
of the moment spending, a
reasonable yearly budget
for this would be around $4,000.
Once you've written down
your cost for each category,
add them up to see how much you'll need
to live your dream life each year.
In our example, that adds up to.
Right.
That's $75,325 a year.
How's that for a bit of quick maths?
Now, to find your freedom
figure, take that yearly number
and multiply it by 25.
We use 25
because of a rule called
wait for it, the rule of 25.
Who'd have guessed that?
This rule is a way to figure out
how much you'll need invested
so that you can take money out each year
without ever running out.
In our example, 75,325
multiplied by 25 gives us $1,883,125.
Think of it like having a golden goose
that lays just enough eggs
each year for you to live on.
As long as you only take the eggs
and don't eat the goose,
it keeps producing more eggs every year.
That way you can keep living off the eggs
without ever using up
your main money stash.
This is assuming you are able
to get more than a 4% return on your money
and while past results aren't
a guarantee of future returns,
the average annual return of the S&P 500
over the last 10 years
has been around 12 to 14%,
although this is slightly higher
than the longer term average,
no one has ever lost any
money if they have bought
and held an S&P 500 index fund
for more than 20 years based
on historical averages.
So how do you invest in the S&P 500?
Well just download an
investing app like Trading 212.
Once you're in, search for an S&P 500 ETF,
which lets you invest in
the top 500 US companies
all at once.
Trading 212 lets you invest in something
called fractional shares.
This is great as it means the stock market
isn't just for the rich investors anymore
and the average person can get involved.
If you are just starting
out, it's a good idea
to use a strategy called
dollar cost averaging.
This basically means you're
investing the same amount
on a consistent basis, whether
the market is up or down.
The idea is that over time,
this will help you average out your costs
so that you don't buy
all in when the market
is its most expensive.
Rather than doing this manually,
you can actually set up the
app to invest automatically
for you on a regular basis
using the pies feature.
Since I was planning to talk
about trading 212 anyway,
I reached out to them to
see if they'd be interested
in sponsoring this portion of the video.
They agreed and are offering
a free fractional share worth
up to a hundred pound to anyone
that uses the code tilbury
when they create an account.
Plus, you can get more free
shares by inviting your friends.
Both of you will get a free share
as long as they fund their account.
I'll leave a link in the
description if you're interested.
Step two is to hack your life.
I get that reaching your freedom figure
in an investment account
might seem like an impossible task.
It definitely felt that way
for me when I first started,
but there are a few strategies
that can help you get there faster.
I highly suggest taking a
closer look at all the areas
where money might be slipping
through your fingers.
Chances are you are spending
far more than you realize on
things that don't really matter to you.
Don't worry, I'm not gonna
lecture you about skipping
Starbucks or making
packed lunches every day.
I'm sure you've heard enough
of that advice from my Shorts.
Instead, I wanna show you clever ways
to keep living the life
you love while saving money
through some smart hacks.
Let's kick things off with car hacking
because I think a lot of
people need to hear this.
Social media might have you thinking
that everyone is driving around
in Range Rovers and Lambos,
but let me tell you, that's
usually not the case.
Most of these people have
their cars on finance
or loans paying hundreds
of dollars every month
just to keep up appearances.
According to LendingTree, the
average monthly car payment
for a new vehicle in
2024 hit a whopping $734.
That's almost $9,000
a year down the drain.
The worst part, most
people can't even afford
these payments, which is why there are
around a hundred million Americans
with outstanding car loans right now.
So let me give you some advice.
Don't get sucked into this trap.
Just because your mates
are taking out car loans
doesn't mean you have to,
instead think about car hacking.
This means buying a quality used car
that's already hit the bottom
of its depreciation curve.
You can drive it for a few years
and then sell it for
close to what you paid.
No massive monthly payments
and no debt hanging over your head.
Next up, let's talk about something I like
to call brand hacking.
This is all about picking generic
or store brand products
over the big name brands
to save a bit of cash without
losing out on quality.
A study from moneysavingexpert.com
actually found
that people can save up to 87% by going
with generic versions
instead of the branded items.
But let's get practical so
you can see what I mean.
Here's a box of Cocoa Pops.
Absolutely classic.
Everyone loves them and I
always keep a box under my desk,
but they cost around $4.25 for a box,
and here's a box of Choco
Rice, the unbranded version,
which costs around $1.66 a box.
By choosing the unbranded cereal,
you're saving $2.56 each time,
and honestly, I bet most people couldn't
even taste the difference.
Plus you get 500 grams over the 290 grams
in the branded box, so it's
gonna last nearly twice as long.
I know what you're thinking.
$2.56 isn't gonna make me
a millionaire anytime soon.
Well, actually, if you
save $2.56 every day,
that's $934.40 a year.
Do that for five years
and you've saved $4,672
and that's just from one small swap.
Think about how much you could save
by making similar swaps in
other parts of your life.
It's all about those small
adjustments, adding up over time
and making your money go further.
Now for the big one, house hacking,
as we know from step one,
housing is usually your biggest expense,
but what if you could reduce
or even completely eliminate that cost?
You are probably expecting me
to say, live with your parents
or go for a smaller apartment,
and while those are good options,
they don't suit everyone.
So here's a smarter strategy you can use.
Instead of getting a typical apartment,
think about getting a duplex
or a property with an extra room or two.
Sure, this might mean a
slightly higher deposit upfront,
but it's worth it.
You live in one unit
and rent the other one out,
using this rental income
to cover most if not all of your mortgage.
That way you're effectively living
for free while building
equity in your home.
You can also do this if you're renting.
Recently, I went to a nice
Airbnb near London Bridge.
It was a fantastic spot,
and I got talking with the Airbnb host
and found out that he
actually rented the place
for 4K a month.
When he rented it out on
Airbnb, he would just go
and stay at his girlfriend's.
I did some quick maps
and worked out that he only
had to rent out the apartment
for 10 days to cover all of his rent.
Pretty smart if you ask me,
but of course, he did have to
get a nice enough apartment
with a good view for it to
rent out well on Airbnb,
but if you're prepared to take on
a slightly more expensive place,
then it will be easier to
get bookings on Airbnb.
Just make sure to clear
it with the landlord
before doing this is it could cause a lot
of issues if you're not upfront about it.
Now, for tax hacking,
I know this one might sound a bit dodgy,
but trust me, there are lots
of ways you can legally
keep more of your money.
One great tax hack is to
take advantage of deductions.
If you have a small business
or side hustle, you can reduce your taxes
by claiming expenses like
a home office, internet
or travel as long as
they're used for business.
Another is using tax-free
savings accounts.
In the UK, you can save up
to 20,000 pounds per year in
an ISA where all your interest
and gains are tax free.
In the USA, you have a similar
option like the Roth IRA.
Tax Hacking is all about
understanding the rules wherever
you are and using them to
keep more of what you earn.
The aim is to pay what you
owe, but not a penny more.
Now, let's talk about deal hacking.
This is all about negotiation.
Let's say you are looking to buy a car,
never accept the sticker price.
That's what the dealership wants.
Remember, the first
price is rarely the best.
Do your research first so you
know the car's market value.
Get quotes from a few dealers
so you can say the dealer
down the road has offered me
a much better deal and actually
be able to back this up
as it puts you in a
much stronger position.
The easiest way to find out
the true value of a car is
to pretend you are selling
the one you are looking at
to a car buying service
like CarMax or Carvana.
Check out what they'd
offer you for it online.
You want to pay as close
to this price as possible
to ensure you're not
overpaying for the car.
Also, buying at the
right time matters too.
If you go at the end of
the month when salespeople
are trying to hit sales targets,
you'll often find a better deal.
These strategies have saved me thousands
on cars over the years
and they work for lots
of other things too,
so don't be afraid to
ask for a better price.
Everything's negotiable if
you know how to play the game.
Step three is to get a credit card.
The biggest lie young people are told is
that credit cards are evil and
that you shouldn't have one.
A lot of people think credit
cards are just a quick way
to get into debt, but the
truth is they're actually one
of the best tools you can have
for building a solid credit
score if you use them wisely.
Your credit score is like your
financial reputation showing
lenders how reliable you are with money
and with a high score.
You'll have much better options
when it comes to borrowing,
which can save you a ton
of money in the long run.
I mean, let's say you are 28
and you are ready to buy your first home.
If you've been using a
credit card responsibly
and building that score up, you
could qualify for a mortgage
with a lower interest rate.
That means that more
of your hard earned money
stays in your pocket instead
of going to the bank,
but if you've ignored your
credit score, you could end up
with sky high interest rates
or even be turned down altogether.
So don't fear credit cards, use 'em
to build your credit score,
but keep your balance low
and pay it off every month.
Step four is to create an
additional income stream.
If you're serious about financial freedom,
building an extra income stream is key.
Think of your income like
a stool with one leg.
If you're relying on just your job,
that's a single leg holding
you up your entire life.
If that leg breaks, let's
say you lose your job,
then you're left with
nothing to keep you steady.
This happens way more
now than it ever used to.
The truth is secure jobs aren't
as common as they once were.
Most people will have
around 12 different jobs
over their lifetime,
but if you add a few more
legs like a side hustle
or investments, that
stool becomes rock solid.
Now, if one leg fails,
you are still supported by the others.
Building multiple income streams
is like adding extra legs
to your financial stability.
A great way to start is
by choosing a side hustle
that builds on skills you already have.
That way you don't have
to learn something brand new from scratch.
There are plenty of options,
affiliate marketing,
freelancing, E-commerce,
or even classic gigs like
window and car cleaning.
The main thing is the value you bring.
The more valuable your
work, the more you learn.
Now, I know the usual excuses.
I'm too busy.
I don't have enough money to start.
I don't know how,
but let's be honest, these
are a load of rubbish.
Let me be real with you.
There are 168 hours in a week.
A nine to five job takes up 40 hours,
and if you sleep eight hours a night,
that's 56 hours, plus about
10 and a half hours for meals
and 10 hours commuting.
That still leaves you with over 50 hours
of free time every week.
So if you tell me you're too busy,
then you just don't want
financial freedom enough.
Step five is to use money
for its true function.
There's one thing that rich
people do completely differently
to middle class and poor people.
Poor people think that
money exists to pay bills
and fund their lifestyle.
Middle class people think
money's for building credit
so they can get bigger
loans to buy bigger houses
and nicer cars.
Rich people know the true
function of money is expansion,
which means using your
money to make more money.
So once you've got some side hustles
or extra income streams going,
it is time to think bigger,
and I don't mean a bigger lifestyle.
That's the trap that
catches a lot of people out.
As soon as they start making more money,
they start spending more.
Instead, think about how
you can use money as a tool.
This is when you start looking
into passive income streams
where your money can grow while you sleep.
This is why the rich get richer.
They're not just working for their money,
they're making it work for them.
Now, no income stream is truly passive,
but by investing wisely,
you could reach a point
where your money does the heavy lifting.
Back in the day, I was working
long hours flipping cars
in the evenings, working
in the shop on Saturdays
and tutoring on Sundays.
I hit the point where I
physically couldn't fit in
any more hours.
That's when I realized I needed
to put my money into things
that could grow on their own.
The stock market is one of
the easiest places to start,
and as we mentioned with Trading 212,
you can get going with
as little as one pound
and even try out
strategies in practice mode
without risking real money.
Personally, I invest most of my money
in an S&P 500 index fund,
which has delivered some
great returns over time.
Now, let's talk about crypto.
This one's a bit different.
It's got a low barrier to
entry and big growth potential,
but it is riskier than stocks.
I keep about 5% of my money
in well-known coins like
Bitcoin and Ethereum.
I think it's worth having
just in case things pump
like they did after the US election.
However, I am prepared to lose it all
as it's a high risk investment.
Of course, real estate is
the ultimate wealth builder,
but it does need a bit more cash upfront.
If you can save a deposit,
you can take advantage
of the house hacking method I mentioned,
or you could build out a
portfolio of rental properties.
If you wanna know exactly
how to set up an investment
account step by step,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if you
wanna grow your wealth, okay?
I'll see you over there.