- So the stock market will crash.
It's happened time and time again.
This is the scary truth.
However, it doesn't
have to be a bad thing.
As long as you are properly prepared,
you can benefit from the chaos.
I've been investing
for more than 35 years,
and as you can imagine during that time,
I've experienced lots of these crashes.
However, I always seem
to come out the other side
wealthier than before.
So today I wanna share the knowledge
that has helped me make millions
through multiple market crashes.
By understanding these strategies,
you can spot the warning signs of a crash
and use them to your advantage.
So how common is a market crash?
Well, there are three different
types of market decline.
First is the most common type of decline,
a market correction.
This is defined as at least a
10% drop from a recent high.
These can be caused by various factors,
but think of it as the stock market,
realizing it's getting a bit expensive
and cutting back prices.
On average, these have happened
around every 1.2 years since 1980.
The second most common type
of decline is a bear market.
Now, you know when
you're in a bear market,
when prices have dropped more than 20%.
Since 1932, these bear markets
have popped up on average every four
years and eight months.
They tend to keep dragging the market down
for about 289 days, or roughly 9.6 months.
Sure, that sounds like a long time,
but keep in mind that bull markets,
which is when the market is going up,
usually last around 965 days or 2.6 years.
The third type is a stock market collapse,
which I class as an over 30% drop
in the stock market,
normally within a very
short amount of time,
although these are very
uncommon, they can happen.
In my opinion, if Trump had been unalived,
then this could have been
a very real scenario.
That isn't a political
view, just a logical one
due to the way the stock market reacts
to this kind of thing.
The main takeaway from all of this
is that if you aren't
ready for the stock market
to go down sometimes,
then you shouldn't be investing in stocks.
So how do you spot a market crash?
Well, let's discuss the free
phases of a market crash
so you'll know what to look out for.
I'll also share the strategies
I use at each stage backed
by real life examples from my experience.
This way you'll be better
prepared than most investors.
Remember, I'm not a financial advisor,
and this isn't financial advice.
I'm just sharing what's
worked for me over the years.
Number one, the euphoria phase.
This is a stage where
the market is at its peak
and irrational excitement drives prices
to unsustainable levels.
During this stage, everyone
is happy and flying high.
When I start seeing this blind happiness,
I prepare my investments
for when everything comes
crashing back to reality.
Before the 2008 financial crisis,
there was a couple of
things that I noticed
that really made me
cautious about investing.
First was the boom in consumer spending.
Everyone had money.
They were spending thousands
and the economy was thriving.
A more recent example
of this is the NFT craze
a couple of years ago.
Never in a million years
would I have thought
that people would buy JPEG image files
for millions of dollars.
Things like this are a clear sign
of too much money in circulation.
The second thing I noticed
in 2008 was the increase
in the number of people
buying houses or refinancing.
This is because it was easier
than ever to get credit
as the housing market was booming,
which meant if people were
unable to pay their mortgages,
then the banks could take back
the properties without losing any money.
Now, it's one thing
noticing these little clues,
but it's another thing
actually taking action
and preparing yourself.
Between 2007-08, I could have
just gone along with the crowd
as the general herd mentality
was that everything was great
and nothing would ever go wrong.
But instead, I started
to prepare my investments
for the worst.
At the time, lots of my friends
and fellow business owners
didn't quite understand
the decisions I was making.
They may have even seen
me as a bit of a coward,
but from my perspective,
I don't think they understood
how much risk they were taking.
So if your spidey senses start tinkling,
these are some of the things you can do
to prepare yourself for the worst.
First, I would evaluate
and minimize your risk
level wherever possible.
Personally, I'm not focused
on chasing crazy high returns
as that's unsustainable for the long term.
I just wanna be making
reasonable gains consistently
so my money compounds.
I always think about the story
of the tortoise and the hare.
I know it might sound boring,
especially coming from a boomer,
but slow and steady does win the race.
If you're new to investing,
there's a high chance
you haven't experienced
a real market crash.
It can be horrifying
to see your portfolio
completely halving in value
and sitting deep in the red
for a brief period of time.
So you have to ask yourself
if you could mentally handle
this kind of drop without
selling your investment.
Secondly, I would start
to reduce my leverage.
Now, on one hand, leverage is a great way
to accelerate wealth, but it
can also be very dangerous.
The thing is, if a stock crashed too far,
then your investing platform
may issue a margin call,
which means you have a
limited amount of time
to pay off your debts,
and if you don't, your
brokerage may sell your stocks
at the bottom of the market
to recover the money you borrowed.
If this is something you're considering
or even doing, then if I were you,
I would be paying some of this debt off.
I never use margin, but
that's a personal choice,
and I'm well aware that by
not taking on this risk,
I'm missing out on some potential profits.
The truth is I've seen too many
of my friends go from millionaire status
to broke in a blink of an eye.
And now I just stay well clear of it.
Thirdly, I'd start saving some extra cash
in a high interest savings account.
I know I bang on about
having an emergency fund
of three to five months
of your living expenses,
but I'm talking about saving even more.
I did this between 2007-08.
From the outside, it looked a bit strange.
The market was booming,
and by leaving my money in the bank,
I wasn't taking advantage of it.
However, I noticed that more
and more people were getting
interested in investing,
which tipped me off that there was a bit
of a bubble forming.
You see, when everyone
starts getting comfortable
with the idea of investing,
it can be a sign
that things are about to pop
as pricing is being propped up
by inexperienced investors.
The trouble is that at
the first sign of a crash,
lots of these people panic sell,
which drives the prices down even further,
leading to a spiral of doom.
Finally, in this stage,
I would make sure my investments
were properly spread out.
This is called diversification,
and it's one of the best ways
to help withstand a market
crash as quite simply per,
you haven't got all
your eggs in one basket.
This is all because you never know
what sector is gonna be hit the hardest.
During the good times,
it can be very common for people
to do very well with one or two stocks
and end up with most
of their money focused
in only a couple of different companies.
Even if they start out with
lots of different stocks,
it can almost seem silly
to put your money into
other things when one stock
outperforms all your others.
Let's use some of my favorite
stocks as an example.
Say you have a thousand dollars to invest.
Now, you could put all of
that into Tesla with the hopes
of it going to the moon,
but if Tesla gets hit the
hardest in a market crash,
it won't be great news for your money.
Whereas investing into a total
US stock market fund would
spread your money across
multiple different industries.
Look, nobody can predict if
the stock market's gonna go up
or continue downwards.
However, diversifying goes
some way to reducing your risk.
Yes, you can't guarantee returns,
but at least you're investing
in a broad range of sectors.
Another great way to diversify
while guaranteeing a return
on investment is through
something called a high
yield cash account.
Take a look at this, for example.
Let's say you have $5,000
to put by with an additional
$250 being saved monthly.
Within five years,
you'd have earned $3,493
without making a risky
investment because the
account pays you 5.1% interest
that compounds daily.
Public offered this account
with zero fees or subscriptions required,
as well as giving you the ability
to invest in thousands of stocks
and ETFs with very low fees.
I was planning on
mentioning Public anyway,
so I reached out to them to
see if they were interested
in sponsoring this video.
They agreed on offering a
free stock worth up to $300
to anyone that signs up
and funds their account.
Just sign up for Public,
deposit $20 or more,
and enter the code MARK2024
via the rewards hub
in the public app.
I'll leave a link in the
description if you're interested,
along with some other options
if you're not in the USA.
Number two, the reckoning phase.
I like to call this as
everyone gets rudely punched
in the face with the truth
and only the ones that know
how to navigate it will be able
to hold their nerve and make some money.
This is the phase where the reality
of overvaluation sets in,
triggering widespread panic and sell offs.
What I'm trying to get
at is in this phase,
the stock market just comes tumbling down
and it's next to impossible
to be unaffected.
Even my son knew something
was happening in 2008
and he was only 10.
The number of customers that came
into my hobby stores halved overnight,
and even when they did come in,
they didn't spend anything.
on the bright side,
I had lots of products which I owned,
and my warehouses were full.
It was sort of a bit like a
safety blanket, I suppose.
In 2008, I saw dollar stores
opening up everywhere.
It was the perfect mixture
of demand for cheap goods
and supply of products
from failing businesses.
Even if you manage to predict
all the signs of the crash
and in phase one prepared correctly,
phase two is really where you get tested.
It's more about human psychology
as most people's initial reaction
is to sell their investments
and cut their losses.
You need to seriously ask yourself,
what are you gonna do
when the market goes down?
Everyone says they're long-term investors
until the market crashes.
It's very easy to be a long-term investor
while everything's going up.
If you believe in your investments,
then you have to hold firm.
To have this kind of belief,
you need to know why you
invested in something.
That's why it's so important
to understand the fundamentals
of a company before
investing in their stock.
This reminds me of a story
Peter Lynch once shared.
He's a well-known investor,
and back in the day he bought
shares in Kaiser Industries
when they dropped significantly.
The company had zero debt
making bankruptcy very unlikely.
He thought to himself,
how much lower can it go?
But the price kept dropping to under $10.
He was shocked,
but held on
and the stock eventually rebounded to $50.
The point is, if you don't
understand the company,
what will you do when
the stock keeps dropping?
Probably sell and lose
out on potential gains.
This applies to index
fund investors as well.
A study by Fidelity actually found out
that if you invested $10,000
in a simple S&P 500 index fund
between the 1st of January, 1980,
and the 31st of December, 2022,
you would have $1,082,009.
But if you decided to
sell your investments
and ended up missing the
five best trading days,
then you would only have $671,051.
The crazy thing is that missing out
just 50 of the best trading days
brings you all the way down to $76,104.
So you might think you are being smart
by time in the market,
but in the long run,
you're probably only gonna
hurt your own profits.
But if you believe in your
stocks for the long term,
there is a lot more to it
than just holding firm.
In 2008, I saw what the
dollar stores were doing,
and instead of seeing a
competitor, I saw an opportunity.
If they could buy things
for a bargain price,
then it must mean there were
amazing deals available.
So I went out hunting.
I went on a bit of a buying
spree over the next couple
of years and acquired
lots of different assets,
including stocks and
even entire businesses.
I knew that I would be unable
to time the exact bottom
of the market, so I invested every week.
This is called dollar cost averaging.
Cash is really king.
If you have cash,
you can snap up some amazing
investments during this time.
That's why it's super important
to keep a steady income
and supercharge it with a side hustle
during times like these,
as the more assets you can invest in,
the better you'll probably end
up doing in the next phase.
The bottom line here is that
while some choose to panic
sell and lose all their money,
others choose to double
down and buy the dip,
which you've done correctly,
can make you a fortune.
I feel like I should also
mention that some investors like
to short stocks, which
is basically betting
that a stock will go down.
It's not something I personally do.
However, people like
Michael Burry have been very
successful with his strategy.
If you want to know more about this,
then let me know in the comments.
I also recommend "The Big Short"
if you feel like watching an entertaining
and informative investing film.
Number three, the Phoenix phase.
In this final phase, the
market begins to recover
and rebuild rising from
the ashes of the crash.
It usually pushes above and
beyond the last market highs.
I noticed that four years
after the 2008 crisis happened,
just after the London Olympics,
things started to improve.
Businesses were hiring
and money was a bit easier to come by,
but even though people
started to have cash again,
the mentality of not spending
carried through for a while,
so it was another four years really
until everything was back to normal.
I've experienced a lot of crashes.
I'm talking Black Monday, the.com bubble,
the 2008 Financial Crisis
and the 2020 pandemic.
One of the key lessons
I took from all of this
was that a bull market almost
always follows a bear market,
and that the seeds of your
fortune are often sown in times
of crisis and uncertainty.
As long as able to
handle your level of risk
and you're buying into the
stock market consistently
with a diversified portfolio,
then you stand a much better chance
than most at making some real money.
If you want me to walk you through exactly
how to start investing
in the stock market,
then I'm gonna leave
that video right up there, but
don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.