If you spend $5 on a morning
coffee on your way to work,
$15 on a nice lunch from the food truck,
$4 on overpriced transport,
$2 on a sweet treat,
and $1.40 on unwanted
subscriptions every day,
then that's the same as spending
$10,000 every single year.
This is the reality for most people.
As soon as they get paid, the
money just seems to disappear,
and that's because they don't
have a paycheck routine.
This is so important
because being careful with
my money in my late teens
and early 20s was the
thing that enabled me
to become the first
millionaire in my family.
So in this video,
I'm gonna be talking about the five things
I did every time I got paid,
so you can apply them too
and hopefully achieve even better results.
This will not only help
you save extra money,
but also build your wealth
and the beauty of all
of this, you won't have
to work any harder than you currently do.
Right, let's imagine
you've just been paid.
The first thing you should do
is separate your wants and needs.
Believe it or not, this is one
of the hardest things for people,
even though it sounds
simple, especially nowadays,
most people are used to such
a high standard of living
that they find it hard to cut down
on their little pleasures.
These might seem small and insignificant,
but in the long term,
these little pleasures
are actually robbing you
of your financial freedom.
Even if you think this
doesn't apply to you,
I still want you to do this exercise.
You might surprise yourself
with the things you uncover
that are draining your money.
So grab a pen and a piece of paper
and split it into two columns,
so you've got wants and needs.
Now, get some of your
recent bank statements.
It's probably best to get
around six months worth
and start highlighting all the things
you repeatedly spend money on every month.
For now, let's ignore
the one-off purchases.
Unless you are repeatedly
buying a lot of random stuff,
then this shouldn't be a huge issue.
I'm more interested in focusing
on those little purchases
that stack up over time.
Once you finish doing that,
it's time to sort them
into the correct column.
Needs should be things
like rent, insurance,
bills, and other utilities.
The rule is, if you can
survive without them,
then it's not a need.
Your wants should be all the
fun stuff like nights out,
restaurants, bowling, golf,
whatever floats your boat.
Once you've completed both sides,
then it's time to figure
out how much each column costs per month.
Let's start with needs.
Let's say your rent, insurance, bills
and utilities add up to $1,200 a month.
This is the bare minimum you
need to get by each month,
also known as your financial baseline.
Once you know your baseline,
subtract it from your monthly income
to see how much you've got left over.
Many people say your
financial baseline should be
under 50% of your total income,
but to be completely honest with you,
I think it should be closer to 25%.
Now, don't treat this needs column
as something you can't change
as there are things you can do
to bring down the costs
but still meet all your basic needs.
You might need a car, for example,
but it's worth if asking
yourself do you need a car
that costs so much?
The same goes for where you live.
Some apartments can be
mega expensive nowadays,
especially in city locations,
but this is where you need
to start weighing things up.
Would it be cheaper to commute each day?
Probably.
So consider moving somewhere
that you can actually afford.
I mean, if you can
share a house for a year
to save up some money that you can invest,
which could help you buy your
dream home, why wouldn't you?
Look, maybe you don't
want to cut back anymore,
and that's completely fine,
but it's worth seeing
if there are some areas
you can save money
without impacting the quality
of your life too much.
If you can't reduce your bills,
you're gonna have to increase your income,
which is completely possible
by getting a promotion
or start a side hustle.
Remember your earning
potential is always higher
than your saving potential.
I know making your needs
costs less than 25%
of your paycheck might sound
a bit impossible right now
and how it might sound coming
from a boomer millionaire,
but I really do understand
what it's like to earn very little.
I didn't grow up wealthy
and it took me a
considerable amount of time
to boost my income to
hit a financial baseline
of 25% of my salary,
but trust me, if I can do it, so can you,
especially with all the online
side hustle opportunities
you can take advantage of.
So don't think I'm just
saying if you're poor,
then just earn more money.
I understand there is
much more to it than that.
Just treat my 25% rule as
a target to work towards.
Now for the wants column,
add them all up and subtract
them from your wage.
Ideally, this should be
below 25% of your paycheck
because we need a decent amount
of money for the next steps
to start getting you ahead.
The second place your
money should be going is
into a high interest savings account.
So in an ideal world,
you'll have about 50%
of your paycheck left at this point.
Most people would just
tell you to save all of it.
However, that's not gonna
help you build your wealth.
Instead, I recommend sending 20%
into a high interest savings account.
It's best to use a different bank
to your everyday account, as otherwise,
it's just too tempting to spend it.
Some great options are Chase in the UK,
an Ally Bank in America.
I say high interest,
but that's all dependent
on when you're watching this video.
Currently, my savings account gets
around 4% interest a year,
which is definitely better
than my current account,
which is around 0.05%.
I know some of you are already commenting,
"I know a bank account with 7% interest."
Don't get me wrong, this is
great as long as you don't have
to lock away your money
for a set amount of time
and the bank is reliable.
The whole purpose of
this savings account is
to act as a safety net
that you can withdraw
money from in an emergency.
It's not there to make you
money, so locking it away
for a set amount of time
actually completely goes
against the point of doing this.
I can't even begin to tell
you how important it is
to have a safety net.
Now, I know you've probably
heard this 1000 times,
but that's because it's great advice.
Life isn't smooth sailing,
and at some point, an
emergency will come your way.
This pot of gold will always be there
for you when you need it.
So say you got sick and couldn't work
or the car broke down,
you'd be able to cope
with this situation just fine.
I must reiterate that this money's only
to be used in serious situations
and not just something to dip
into when you're running low
and want that extra pint of beer.
It's just shocking to me as of May 2023,
one in five Americans have
no emergency fund at all.
So if something went wrong, which it will,
they have no way of coping with it
and would most likely
have to take out a loan,
which most of the time ends up
with them paying crazy interest rates
and falling even further behind.
So how much should your emergency fund be?
Well, I'd say your emergency
fund should be three
to five months of your baseline figure
that we discussed earlier.
Even better if you can
stretch that to six months.
So once you've put by 20% of
your paycheck for enough months
to hit this figure, then
you can allocate more money
to the next places we're
gonna be talking about.
In an ideal world, you should have 30%
of your paycheck left by this point.
So where should you put the rest?
Well, next is the only place
you'll ever get a guaranteed
return on investment.
Let me explain.
Normally, if someone tells
you they can make you
a guaranteed profit, then I'd say run away
as fast as you can.
It's normally the grift that's
feeding people this garbage.
However, in this instance, it's 100% true
as I'm talking about paying
down your high interest debt.
I mean, why bother investing
in stocks for a possible eight
to 10% return when you can
have a guaranteed 25% return
by paying off the debt
that's constantly eating into
your wealth every single day?
It's kind of like someone asking
you what the best foods are
to eat and exercise routines
to follow while knowingly
having a parasite
inside their body sucking
away all the nutrients.
Of course, a doctor's main
priority is getting rid
of that parasite as it's
pretty much guaranteed
that you'll feel better.
So if you have high interest debt,
then I would recommend
putting the remaining 30%
of your paycheck towards paying it off.
There are two really common
methods that you can use
to pay down your debts.
The first way is the avalanche method,
and this is the most
logical way to tackle debt
because you pay off the debt
with the highest interest rate first.
So let's see how this will
work in the real world.
Imagine you've got three different debts.
Debt A is for your credit card
and it's $5,000 with an
interest rate of 20%.
Debt B is a loan from
your family of $1,500
with no interest rate.
And debt C is a car loan for $2,500
at an interest rate of 15%.
If you decide to pay $500 per month
towards your debts using
the avalanche method,
this would firstly all go towards
debt A until it's paid off
as it's the highest interest rate.
This would take around 13 months
and you'll end up paying $515
and 22 cents of interest.
After this, your $500
payments would go into debt C,
and it would take a further
five months to pay off that,
which would include $98
and 13 cents of interest.
Then it would finally be
time to attack debt B,
as your family are probably
getting a bit impatient
for their money, this
would take three months
and obviously you'd pay no interest.
So with the avalanche method,
you'd be debt free in 21 months
and pay approximately $613 in interest.
The second option is the snowball method.
This is the psychological
way to tackle debt
because you pay off the
smallest debts first.
The thinking behind this
is it makes you feel
like you're making faster progress.
So you'd pay debt B first,
followed by debt C, and
then finally debt A.
However, if you use this method,
it would take you around 23 months
and cost approximately
$1,700 in interest payments.
That's two months
and over $1,000 more than
using the avalanche method.
So if you can stick to
the logical approach,
it'll be worth it in the long run.
Once you finish building your safety net
and paid off any high interest debt,
you can put that combined 50%
towards growing your wealth.
That's why place number four
is a tax advantaged investing account.
When you get your paycheck,
income tax gets taken out
of it right away, go to
the store and buy something
and you'll run into sales tax.
If you own a property, you'll
pay property taxes every year.
Even when you invest
and eventually make a profit,
you'll be hit with capital gains tax.
Unfortunately, I can't
help you with most of them,
but luckily, there's a legal way
to avoid paying capital gains
tax on your investments.
If you're in the UK,
you're gonna want to get
yourself a stocks and shares ISA,
and if you're in the US, you
should get the equivalent,
which is a Roth IRA.
They both have different rules,
which I've discussed in past videos,
but the bottom line is both
these accounts allow you
to invest without worrying about taxes.
If I were you, I would put 35 to 40%
of your excess money into
one of these accounts
and invest it in a low cost
index fund like the S&P 500.
Over the years, this
has made me, on average,
around about eight to
10% tax free per year.
Of course, I'm not a financial advisor,
and this shouldn't be
taken as financial advice.
Stocks can go down as well as up,
so it's important to
understand the risks involved.
Just imagine if you
invested $250 per month,
then assuming an 8% average annual return,
you'll have 1.3 million in 45 years time
completely tax free.
Feel free to head over
to the Compound Interest
Calculator website
to do the math for yourself.
I understand it's a pretty
slow way to build wealth.
However, if you're consistent,
then historically, it's proven
a very successful strategy.
One of my favorite investing
platforms is Trading 212
as they offer stocks and shares ISA.
Since I was planning to
talk about their app anyway,
I reached out to them
to see if they'd be interested
in sponsoring this portion of the video.
They agreed and are also
offering a free fractional share
worth up to 100 pound to anyone
that uses the code Tilbury
when they create an account.
Plus, you can get more
free fractional shares
by inviting your friends.
Both of you will get a free share
as long as they fund their account.
I found the best way to invest is
to set things up on autopilot.
The aim is to reduce as much
of the friction as possible
between you and your investments.
We just get in the way of
ourselves most of the time.
That's why it's best to
just set up auto investing.
It gets the money away from you,
and most of the time, you
don't even notice it's gone
until you check your investing account
and have a nice surprise.
My son has actually
been doing an experiment
on Trading 212.
He started investing five pounds a day,
which is about six and a half US dollars,
which is the average price
of a coffee a day into the S&P 500.
It's now been almost exactly a year
since he started its
experiment, and as you can see,
he's actually invested 1,503 pounds
and his investment is
now worth 1,707 pounds,
which is a 13.68% return on investment.
What's even more amazing is
that he completely forgot
about this experiment
until the other day when
I asked him about it.
It was a lovely surprise.
If you wanna set something
like this up too,
then it's really simple.
I'll walk you through it now.
Once you've opened an account
and used the code Tilbury
to get your free fractional share worth up
to 100 pounds, just head
over to the portfolio icon
and then click on pies
and finally create a pie.
If you just wanna copy
what my son's been doing,
then click on build a
custom pie, add instruments,
and then search for S&P 500.
There are lots of
different ones that pop up
as there are different companies
that offer essentially the same thing.
I personally like Vanguard
the best as they're one
of the oldest and most
trustworthy companies in the game.
Your granddad will probably
even know about them.
I also prefer the Accumulation
Fund, which is this one here,
as it automatically
reinvests your dividends,
which is essentially a
reward the company gives you
for holding their stock.
So just click on the fund, add to pie,
and then this little arrow, next,
and then make sure to select auto invest
before pressing next again.
Here you can choose
how many years you want
to automatically invest for,
how often you'd like to invest,
and how much you can afford.
The longer you can keep
this going, the better.
You won't always make a profit.
However, you have a better chance
if you keep your money
invested for over 10 years.
It also gives you a core
value projection based
on actual stats.
My son's actually outperforming
his at the moment,
but of course, take it
with a grain of salt
'cause nobody can actually predict
what the stock market is gonna do.
You can build out more complicated pies
with many different stocks.
However, I think for 99% of people,
it's much better to just keep it simple.
I used to think of this style
of investing like my insurance,
even though your capital is always at risk
when you're investing,
that's just how I saw it.
I knew I wanted to be
a millionaire one day,
and in my worst case scenario,
I'd have to wait until I was old and gray.
Of course, I managed to make
my first million a lot sooner
through different businesses,
but that didn't stop me from
investing for the long term
at the same time as
building those businesses.
The fifth place you can put
your money is in high risk,
high reward plays.
Now, this isn't for everyone,
so if you're happy waiting years
to make your first million,
then that's absolutely fine.
However, if you're anything
like me when I was younger,
then you'll wanna make it a bit quicker.
Most people online will
either teach you the slow lane
of getting rich, which
is the investing style we
just discussed, or the fast lane,
which involves taking
more risk in the hopes
of getting greater rewards.
I honestly sit in the middle
as I've traveled down both of these paths.
So if I were you, I put five to 10%
of my paycheck towards
starting a side hustle
or full blown business.
You may think that doesn't sound enough
and that you should skip the investing
and put all your money into this,
but I have a different opinion.
When you have less money to play with,
especially in the early days
of starting a side hustle,
you actually become more
creative with how you use it,
which lets you find gaps in
the market that most people
with money just can't see.
Now with the final 5%, I'd
make the riskiest investment
of them all: cryptocurrency.
I've avoided talking about this
in my videos for a long time.
However, it's undeniable
that it's gaining
popularity year after year.
I've got about 5% of my
investment portfolio in Bitcoin
and Ethereum as I believe
in the long term potential.
However, I'm very aware this is very risky
and it could all go to zero at any point.
So as long as you are okay with that,
then it's worth considering.
If you wanna know why net worth goes crazy
after you save 100K,
then you can watch this video next,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.