- I just finished reading
these 40 books about business,
so I can cut out all the
fluff and save you time.
You see, I've got an issue
with most business books.
They have some great concepts
that anyone can learn from,
but they're buried under
so much filler content
that it takes ages to get to the gold.
So as a millionaire
businessman myself, I wondered
if I could use my knowledge
to cut through all the waffle.
That's why over the last three months,
I've made it my mission
to read all these books
and note down the key points
that will actually make you rich.
So I've divided them into four categories.
How to start with no money,
how to sell anything to anyone,
how to market your business,
and how to manage your money like the 1%.
Now, you may think some of
these categories may not appeal
to you, but trust me, put them together
and they could make you a
force to be reckoned with
in the business world.
Let's get onto the first section.
(energetic upbeat music)
(paper rustling)
So how to start with no money
has got to be one of the
most Googled questions ever,
so let's dive into it.
Step one is to find your strengths.
This seems pretty obvious,
however, society has conditioned us
to actually focus on
improving our weaknesses
rather than doubling
down on our strengths.
But the reality is, you can
be 10 times more successful
as you focus on following
the path of least resistance.
In other words, the stuff
you are already good at.
"StrengthsFinder 2.0" says
your strengths come down
to a simple equation.
Talent times investment equals strength.
Let's use golf as an example.
I enjoy playing at my local
club, although I'm not bad.
I'm far from great.
Suppose you took both Tiger
Woods and me at the age of 13
and gave us the same amount
of coaching and practice.
I'm willing to bet that every
hour he practiced would equate
to about 10 of mine.
This is because his inherent talent
for the sport is significantly higher,
given him a larger multiplier.
That's why this book is so great
as it helps you find your
most powerful multiplier
so you can make more progress than others
in a shorter amount of time.
Once you start thinking of weaknesses
as an expense you need to minimize,
your time will become
so much more effective.
You can always find people who can make up
for your weaknesses.
"How to win friends and influence people,"
give some great networking
techniques you can try out.
So before we move on, ask yourself this,
have you been trying to become successful
through fixing your weaknesses
or through developing
and implying your innate strengths?
Step two, come up with an idea.
Now that you understand
the importance of playing
to your strengths, it's
equally as important
to choose a business idea
where you have an advantage.
This is because every company
that goes belly up has
one thing in common,
they couldn't outrun the competition.
"Zero to One" was written by Peter Thiel,
the man who sold PayPal
to eBay for $1.5 billion.
(cash register rings)
What's even more impressive
is that his original team
who received his personal mentorship,
went on to establish companies
like YouTube and LinkedIn.
Given the number of successful
businesses he's influenced,
it's clear that he's mastered the secret
of generating billion dollar ideas.
(cash register rings)
He says that billion
dollar business ideas come
from betting on a contrarian truth.
This is a real truth about how
people will act in the future
that they aren't aware of
or don't want to admit.
Steve Jobs believed
that we didn't want a keypad on our phone.
Very few people agree with him,
especially as Blackberry
was the most popular phone
at the time,
and that thing was literally
riddled with buttons.
I bet you guys don't even
remember Blackberrys,
but he believed in his vision
and was rewarded after
releasing the iPhone
and changing the world forever.
This isn't an isolated example.
Uber believed that we
would feel comfortable
getting into a stranger's car
and Netflix believed we would
want to binge watch TV shows.
If you are struggling to come
up with a contrarian truth,
then give "Start with Why" a read
as it will get you thinking
in the right kind of way.
Perhaps you're not aiming
to start a billion dollar business,
but consider the things
you believe can be improved
by adopting a slightly different approach.
People will probably think
you're crazy at first,
but that's okay.
Going against the grain
lets you carve out a massive advantage
before anyone else even
notices what you're up to.
This means you won't have
to worry about competition
for a very long time.
Step three is create a plan.
Now you know what you're good
at and you've got your idea.
You need to get very clear
on how your business
is gonna be structured.
Otherwise, you're just
gonna be running around
like a headless chicken,
not knowing where to focus your attention.
"Business Model Generation"
is a collective effort
from 470 entrepreneurs, professors,
and CEOs across 45 different countries,
they were able to break
down any business model
into the essential nine building blocks
that make up any business.
They believe that many
business plans are overloaded
with text and that using visuals
can be much more powerful.
Let's do it together so
you can see how it's done.
Rather than boring you with a
cliche lemonade stand example,
which, let's be real, no
one's actually gonna do that.
I'm going to outline a business
that I reckon could be
a real winner right now.
Let's call it Timmy's Membership Builders.
Firstly, Timmy loves watching
educational YouTubers,
but gets frustrated because
lots of the advice is generic
and doesn't really apply to him.
So Timmy decides this is
what he wants to change.
He wants to create a way
YouTubers can interact
with viewers on a more personal level
by building their membership platforms.
This is Timmy's value proposition.
Next, Timmy needs to
identify his customers,
assuming that approximately
nought.1% of YouTube subscribers
will want to join a membership,
he should collaborate with YouTubers
who have over 1 million subscribers.
This strategy will generate enough value
to justify his business venture.
Now, Timmy needs to figure
out what channels he can use
to reach his customers.
He might choose email, DMs
or even physical letters.
You are probably thinking
if a YouTuber has over
a million subscribers,
then they're gonna be
pretty hard to reach.
But I can tell you from experience,
if you have a good value proposition,
then someone on their team
will see your message.
We aren't as unreachable
as you might think.
Building customer relationships
is the hardest part.
That's why Timmy may have to
start off working for free
to build up some case studies
and then offer his first clients discounts
for referring him to their friends.
Focus less on what you can gain
and more on what you can give
as this form stronger relationships.
If you are struggling,
then you can always read,
"Give and Take."
Now consider revenue streams.
Timmy could choose to charge
a percentage of revenue
for managing memberships,
freeing up the YouTuber
to concentrate on producing videos.
If Timmy took a 10% cut from a membership
of 10,000 people each paying $5 a month,
it would amount a $5,000
of monthly revenue.
As the membership grows,
this figure will increase.
Now Timmy needs to work out what he needs
to make this all happen.
These include his key
resources like a website,
key activities such as advertising,
and then key partnerships,
which may include working
closely with a developer.
Finally, Timmy needs
to calculate his costs.
If he can do this business
for less than what he expects to earn,
then he is on the right track.
If not, this evaluation will save him
from disappointment in the future.
That brings us to step four,
building a minimum viable product.
The harsh truth is many
entrepreneurs put their head down
and work for months on a product,
but don't realize that
they're building something
that no one actually wants to buy.
"The Lean Startup" suggests that
instead of working super hard
to create the most polished product,
you should create something
called a minimum viable product
or MVP.
What's great about this is that
it doesn't actually have
to cost you any money.
The founder of Dropbox
made a short video showing
how his file storage solution worked
and managed to increase
his waiting list from 5,000
to 75,000 people in the
space of a couple of days.
The amazing thing about this story is
that the video was fake.
The product didn't even
actually exist yet,
but he was then able
to use the waiting list
to convince investors
that it was a good idea
and then he was able to
make it into a reality.
There are so many ways
that you can make a free MVP nowadays,
especially with the help of AI.
If you want some inspiration
then the "ChatGPT Millionaire"
is a great little read,
you could use your MVP
to appeal to investors,
launch a Kickstarter campaign,
find a business partner
or bootstrap by reinvesting
the profits back
into building your business.
A crucial point to keep in mind is that
if you are starting with no money
and looking for any kind of funding,
you must provide undeniable
proof of product demand.
Step five, execute your vision.
Now, having a plan, an idea,
and an MVP isn't that precious.
Lots of people make it to this stage,
but what really matters is the execution.
The crazy thing is most people
have the capacity to double
or triple their income
by consistently applying
what they already know.
The issue is people don't put in the work.
"The 12 Week Year" proposes a new way
to get more done in 12
weeks than 12 months.
It suggests that we should
break our year into four
and think of those quarters as our year.
This may sound silly as it's
still the same amount of time.
However, this way of thinking forces you
to confront your results
every three months.
I don't know about you,
but personally, when I've got a deadline,
I work a lot harder.
My businesses have a different
buzz around the office
when we're nearing the end of the year.
So by using this approach,
instead of having that
buzz of motivation once,
we can have it four times a year,
as Parkinson law states, "Work expands
to fit the amount of
time we allocate to it,"
therefore, applying the
12 week year approach,
we can actually achieve more
and make significant progress
towards building a business you want.
However, this 12 week approach only works
if you respect your deadlines.
If you are the type of person who battles
with procrastination,
then "Extreme Ownership" is worth a read.
It's packed with Navy SEAL tactics
to whip your discipline into shape.
Can you handle the truth?
- You can't handle the truth!
- Quick one from me before
we get into the next section,
and forgive my voice, I'm
filming this a few days after
as I've been quite ill.
One of the best ways to start
an online business nowadays is
to turn your skills, passions,
and experiences into online courses,
exclusive membership sites,
subscription podcasts,
thriving communities,
personalized coaching and more.
These types of businesses
are extremely cost effective
to set up and run.
They also have the upside
of being extremely scalable.
I know multiple people making millions
using this business model,
all from their laptop.
If any of that sounds interesting,
the Kajabi is the perfect tool for you.
It's the ultimate all in one platform
that helps people build
successful online businesses
by unlocking predictable
recurring revenue.
They're also sponsoring
this portion of the video,
but before you skip, if you're
an entrepreneur, trust me,
you wanna listen to this.
Recurring revenue is the holy
grail in the business world.
I mean, there's a reason
why everything's turning
into a subscription nowadays.
If you know how much money's
coming in every month,
then it gives you the confidence you need
to expand your business
and eventually hire people
without worrying too much
about your cash flow.
Kajabi is a great choice
as they don't take a cut from your revenue
because everything is owned
and controlled by you,
so you keep 100% of what you earn.
So if this sounds like something
you'd be interested in,
then right now Kajabi is
offering a free 30 day trial
to start your business if
you go to kajabi.com/mark.
So go to kajabi.com/mark
and join the creators and entrepreneurs
who have collectively
made over $7 billion.
Right, let's get back to the books.
(energetic upbeat music)
(paper rustling)
So how to sell anything to anyone.
This section isn't just
important for business,
but in all aspects of your life.
Maybe you wanna persuade
your friend to help you,
your boss to listen to you
or even your parents to
give you more pocket money.
The reality is we're
all selling in some way,
although some of us are
much better skilled at it
than others.
Step one, set the frame.
Believe it or not, most people fail
before they even ask for what they want
because they don't warm up
whoever they're talking to
before trying to persuade them.
"Pre-suasion" shares
techniques you can use
to make people more receptive
towards your request
before even asking.
In this book, there's a
story about a consultant
who was having a hard time
because people kept asking
for discounts on his services,
so he came up with a clever trick,
before he tell them his price.
He joked, "Well, as you can see,
I can't exactly charge
you a million for this."
After he started using
this joke, guess what?
No one asked for a discount anymore
and he could happily charge $75,000
(cash register rings)
for his expertise.
This sneaky little trick
is called price anchoring.
It's all about that first
piece of information
or that anchor that people latch onto.
They then base their understanding
of everything else around that,
framing, however, extends
far beyond what we say.
Non-verbal communication makes up 55%
of all communication
and much of that is
influenced by how we dress.
That's why I recommend considering
some of the advice in this
little book "Style & The Man,"
remember, don't be in a hurry
when it comes to setting the frame
before asking for what you want.
Trust me, using these strategies
can flip the whole scenario
in your favor.
Step two is build rapport.
"The Art of the Deal" starts
with Trump taking us
through a week in his life.
The thing that struck out
to me was the sheer amount
of calls he took per day.
We are talking between 50 and 100 calls.
This habit of regular check-ins
kept Trump at the forefront
of people's minds, so when
a business deal came up
that was advantageous for Trump
or he had something to sell, it was easier
to close the deal due to his
multiple nurtured connections.
Today, we can achieve this
by building a personal
brand on social media.
Gary V emphasizes this in
his book, "Crushing It."
Having a personal brand
increases our touch points
with people before we attempt
to sell anything to them.
Therefore, increasing the
likelihood of future sales.
Remember, people do business
with people they like.
Step three, become more persuasive,
so now you've set the frame
and built the rapport.
You need to be able to persuade people
to give you what you want.
"To Sell Is Human" argues
that the most effective way
to do this is to attune
with your prospect.
I know that sounds a bit wishy-washy,
but the experiment the book talks about
makes this all start to come together.
152 students were instructed
to negotiate the sale
of a gas station.
They were divided into two main
groups, buyers and sellers.
The buyer group was further
split into three subgroups.
The first subgroup was instructed
to focus on being
empathetic to the sellers,
the second on the seller's thoughts
and the third on their own role.
The highest number of
successful deals came
from the subgroup that focus
on understanding the seller's thoughts.
Great deals always come when the buyers
and sellers are in tune with each other.
"Pitch Anything" makes a solid point,
that when most people pitch,
they're too busy thinking about
what they want and not what
their prospects are thinking.
They assume that the audience care
as much about their business as they do,
but here's the harsh truth, they don't.
Step four, collaborate effectively.
Now that you are attuned to each other,
what if you could transform
a sales negotiation
into a collaboration, instead
of a one-sided process?
Well, "Never Split the
Difference" suggests you can
by asking something called
calibrated questions.
Once you both feel like
you understand each other,
you can then start using this technique
as it directs the other person's attention
towards your problems.
These types of questions
normally start with what or how.
With the ultimate question being,
how am I supposed to do that?
Let's say your landlord
was gonna put up your rent
at $1,700 a month and you
didn't wanna pay that much.
You could say, it seems like,
you think your house is undervalued,
but how am I supposed
to pay $1,700 a month
when I only make enough money
to afford $1,500 a month?
The key is to say it in a genuine way
that doesn't seem confrontational.
They should hear, "I
value your intelligence.
Can you please help me solve my problem?"
Asking this type of question
will make the other
person think creatively
or even lower their price.
It's not a magic trick
and it won't always work,
but it's definitely
worth giving it a shot,
and here's a quick tip.
If you are on the receiving
end of this tactic,
never let another person's
problems become your problems.
Understand them for sure,
but remember, it's not
your job to solve them
or you might just find
yourself caught in this trap.
Good questions are really a superpower.
That's why it's worth giving
"Better Small Talk" a read.
Step five is closing the deal.
You must never ever leave a conversation
with a potential buyer
without a firm commitment.
Otherwise, all the hard
work will be for nothing.
"Objections: The Ultimate Guide
for Mastering The Art and
Science of Getting Past No"
recommends getting the
potential buyer to agree
to a specific action on a fixed date.
This is known as micro commitment.
When trying to secure a commitment,
be prepared for potential objections.
For instance, if someone
says, "I'm quite busy,
how about you call me next
week to arrange something?"
A possible response could be,
"My week is also looking pretty packed
and I wanna make sure I can
dedicate the appropriate amount
of time for our discussion
to ensure you don't miss out.
Can we schedule our meeting right now?
Would Friday at 03:30 work for you?"
Obviously, you can adjust the time
to whatever works for you,
but see how that question
makes it much easier
for the other person to say "Yes,"
rather than objecting again.
Of course, a bit of charisma
can always help close a deal as well.
Just think of the most popular closer
on the TV show "Suits," Harvey Specter.
Interestingly, the actor
is completely different
from his role in the show,
so this proves that charisma
can be faked to some degree.
If you are interested in
learning more about this,
consider reading "The Charisma Myth."
(energetic upbeat music)
(paper rustling)
So how to market your business.
Let's face it, you could
have the best product
or service in the world,
but what's the use if
nobody knows about it?
Step one is developing your
unique selling proposition.
Ever found yourself wondering
why some businesses explode
and others just don't?
Why people rave about one
business and ignore another?
Well, "Purple Cow" believes
that the key is being remarkable.
Every marketer is traditionally
aware of the five Ps,
product, positioning, pricing,
publicity, and promotion.
However, this book introduces
a sixth P, the purple cow.
I know this might sound a bit
strange, but stick with me.
Imagine you are driving
along a country road
and you see a brown cow grazing.
It's so common that you hardly notice it,
much like the barrage of everyday
marketing and advertising.
Now, imagine instead seeing a purple cow,
you'd stop the car, you'd get out,
you'd take a selfie with it.
It's noteworthy and you
can't help but talk about it.
Imagine if your business
was like that purple cow,
compelling people to talk about it.
So think about what makes
your business unique,
what do you do better than anyone else?
What unique value do you
offer to your customers?
Lots of businesses are
using TikTok and YouTube
to stand out, especially restaurants,
who are coming up with unique dishes
that they're using as purple
cows to draw in customers.
If you want to dive more
into creating videos,
then "YouTube Secrets," which
is down here just like that,
gives you a really good insight
into making viral content.
Step two, gather real world data.
If you want any hope marketing
your product or service,
then you need to know what
people think about it.
However, this is where most
people make the mistake
of asking the people closest
to them for their thoughts.
This results in them just
giving you blind encouragement
and generic support, which might be good
for boosting your ego,
but it won't help you market your product.
"The Mom Test" offers a
solution to this problem.
It says that instead of saying,
"Here's my business, what do you think?"
You should instead ask about their life
in the context of your business.
I know this sounds confusing,
but let me give you an example.
Say you are starting an
online course business
that teaches people how to play the piano
from the comfort of their own home.
Instead of asking your friends and family
if they liked the idea, talk about them,
if they play the piano,
you could ask about the
initial challenges they faced,
the solutions they seeked out,
and any frustrations they had
with the solutions they found.
If they don't play the piano,
you could slightly tweak the questions.
This is an extremely smart way
to get useful data on your business
as it's almost impossible
for anyone, even your mum,
to give you blind support
and encouragement.
You can use this information
to help identify "Blue Oceans,"
which are areas of a market
with low competition,
but very high demand.
Step three, establish your brand message.
Despite having a USP
and necessary data, many
new entrepreneurs struggle
to capture the attention
of potential customers.
People don't like feeling sold to
and because of this,
it's hard to get someone
to listen long enough to actually get them
to want to buy from you.
"Building A Story Brand"
says the solution is used
in a specific story
structure in your marketing
that cuts through the noise
and holds people's attention.
You first need to create a character.
This character isn't your business,
it's your target customer.
This is because everyone sees themselves
as the main character in their story.
You need to make it very clear
what this character wants.
At this stage, it's best to
stick to the universal desires,
like, building wealth and status,
higher quality relationships
or increased health.
Next, your character should
face a specific problem related
to your product that
they want to overcome.
For instance,
if you are running a
piano teaching business,
the external problem
they'd want to overcome is,
not being good enough
at playing the piano.
Their internal struggle
might be questioning
their own abilities and
if they're good enough,
here, you can introduce
your business as their guide
to overcoming this problem
and share past success stories
to establish your authority.
Both these elements build
trust in you and your business.
You need to be able to
get this message across
in multiple formats,
but one of the most
crucial is with writing.
That's why it's worth giving
"Copywriting Secrets" a read.
The main takeaway here is
to portray your potential customers
as heroes in your marketing.
This narrative structure,
commonly known as "The Hero's Journey,"
is frequently used in TV shows and films.
If you make people into
the hero of your story,
they'll sit up and listen.
Once you've sold to someone
once, it's so much easier
to sell to them again
with the right strategy.
That's why step four is create upsells.
It's actually shocking how
many businesses are leaving
so much money on the table
by not using this technique.
"Dotcom Secrets" teaches you exactly
how to build a value ladder
and sell higher price products
and services to your existing customers.
You've probably already
seen this in action
at your local dentist and
not even thought about it.
Normally, a dental practice starts off
by selling you a simple checkup.
Next, they might offer you teeth cleaning,
then teeth whitening.
After that, a retainer
and before you know it,
they've pushed you all
the way up the ladder
to their most expensive
product, cosmetic surgery.
This approach can be applied
to any business you are starting.
If customers have a great experience
with your lower priced products,
they're likely to continue
climbing the ladder.
It's also important to remember
if you don't provide options for them
to spend more money with you,
they may end up going to
one of your competitors.
Ideally, you shouldn't have
to upsell people face to face.
"Expert Secrets" outlines
a way you can use
the perfect webinar model to
upsell many people at once,
whilst keeping that personal feel,
but how do you make sure you
never run out of customers
to climb your value ladder?
That's where step five
comes in, driving up demand.
If you followed all of the steps so far,
you should have plenty of demand,
but instead of trying to sell to everyone,
you could try and limit
your product or service
and increase the price.
"Oversubscribed" states that every product
that is oversubscribed has
people that didn't get it,
even though they were willing to buy it.
Rolex has mastered this
strategy better than most.
If you wanna purchase a new Rolex,
you have to visit an authorized store,
join a long waiting
list and patiently wait.
This process can take up to four years
before you're offered the
chance to buy a watch.
Some people never receive the call
as Rolex doesn't deem
them the right customer
for their brand.
Does this sound a bit snobby? Possibly.
But does it work? Absolutely.
If your product is seen as oversubscribed,
competition becomes less of a concern
and you have the flexibility
to set your prices as you see fit.
It's all about following
the "Don't Make Me Think" principle.
You've got to make it very
easy for your customers
to understand your website and messaging.
(energetic upbeat music)
(paper rustling)
So, how to manage your money like the 1%.
This section is absolutely crucial.
You won't believe how
many people are amazing
at almost everything else
but struggle when it comes
to handling their cash.
This is a big reason why one out
of every three people
earning over 100 grand a year
are still living paycheck to paycheck.
Step one, monitor your finances.
"The Total Money Makeover,"
while not specifically
focused on business finances,
it does offer some valuable principles
for keeping your money under control,
which can be applied to
business finances as well.
Here's the major takeaway
for all you entrepreneurs,
keep a sharp eye on your finances.
It's so easy to get caught up
in the daily hustle and bustle
of running your business,
that you lose sight of your numbers
and before you know it,
you're in a financial pickle
without even realizing it.
Think about it.
Financial laziness is a lot sneakier
than physical laziness.
It's not like you are
forced to confront it
every time you look in the mirror,
you can just brush it under the rug
and only start panicking
when it's too late.
So if you feel like you've lost touch
with your financial situation,
here's a little reality check for you.
Ask yourself this,
if all your revenue
stopped coming in tomorrow,
could you keep your business afloat
for at least three months?
If the answer's no, then
sorry to break it to you,
but you're financially outta shape.
It's time to hit the financial gym.
That brings us onto step
two, remain profitable.
You might think being profitable,
it's the same as being financially stable,
but they're actually pretty different.
Most businesses morph
into cash hungry beasts.
This is because when most
ambitious entrepreneurs
make sales, they pump
most of that sales revenue
back into growing their
business and guess what happens?
Their expenses shoot up,
but they think it's fine
as they make their profits
once their business is bigger.
However, the profits never come
because when sales drop,
expenses stay high,
which causes the business to bleed money
and eventually collapse.
"Profit First" urges entrepreneurs
to think about profit in a different way.
The traditional way is sales
minus expenses equals profit,
but "Profit First" says,
"You should instead
flip the formula around
to sales minus profit equals expenses."
By taking a portion of each sale
and allocating it to profit,
you force your business
to become more efficient.
That's the funny thing about
having less money to spend.
You actually start to
discover you can run things
for far less than you initially thought.
Step three, plan for taxes.
Did you know the average
taxpayer in the US
will spend an estimated $524,625,
around a third of their lifetime earnings
on various state and federal taxes,
and that's the average person.
As an entrepreneur, you're
gonna be paying a lot more.
Many people think the tax system is evil
and just there to get your money.
However, "Tax-Free Wealth" states
that the IRS has written
a tax code in a way
to save us money, that's right.
The book states that the
current tax code contains
over 5,800 pages and
only 30 of those address
how to pay taxes.
This means that the IRS
dedicated 5,770 pages
or 99.5% of the code
to help us avoid taxes
and therefore increase our wealth.
It's very similar in the UK
and other Western countries,
as they want to help stimulate the economy
above taking your money.
That's why it's really worth
getting a great accountant
who can take advantage
of all the tax breaks you are entitled to.
Step four is playing your own game.
To be a successful entrepreneur,
you need to base your decisions on data
and not be easily led by others.
"The Intelligent Investor"
is one of my all-time
favorite investing books.
It discusses a scenario
that perfectly applies
to both running a business
and investing in one.
Imagine owning a small
business that costs you $1,000.
and you have a business
partner called Mr. Market.
Every single day he pops in
and tells you how much
he thinks your piece
of the business is worth.
Not only that, but he's
always ready to buy your share
or sell you more at that price.
Sometimes Mr. Market seems
to hit the nail on the head.
His valuation makes sense
based on what's happening in the business
and what the future looks like,
but at other times, Mr.
Market gets a bit carried away
with his emotions and the price he offers
can seem, well, a little bit crazy.
Now, if you are a savvy investor
or a smart business person,
are you gonna let Mr. Market's daily chat
sway your own opinion of your
$1,000 stake in the business?
Well, you shouldn't.
Most of the time you'd be
smarter to make up your own mind
about what your investment is worth.
Remember, most people are
driven by their emotions.
If you wanna see long-term success,
you've gotta think rationally
with your business and investment.
Step five is mitigating risks.
When you're in the early
stages of business,
you have to take big
risks and think quickly,
but as your business grows,
it makes sense to slow down
and think about mitigating
as many unnecessary risks as possible.
I've had many multimillionaire
friends that didn't do this
and ended up losing everything.
Thinking fast and slow outlines
that your brain actually
has two ways of thinking.
System one is fast and intuitive,
and system two is slow and analytical.
Listen to this question
and answer it in your
head as fast as you can.
A bat and ball cost $1
and 10 cents in total.
The bat costs $1 more than the ball.
How much does the ball cost?
If you're like most people,
you'll have answered
that the ball costs you 10
cents, which is incorrect.
The answer is actually 5 cents.
This is because your
thinking system one came up
with the quick answer.
Then when your system two activated,
you started to understand
why 5 cents was the correct answer.
It's crucial to understand this,
so you don't jump to conclusions
and take on more risks than
necessary in your business.
(energetic upbeat music)
(paper rustling)
I had five books left over
that don't really fit neatly
into the four sections,
but they're definitely
great books to pick up
if you wanna dive even
deeper into business.
Feel free to take a screenshot
and add them to your list
if you find the titles interesting.
And if you wanna keep learning,
then you should watch this video next
where I read 40 different
books all about money,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you wanna grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.