- This is the best piece of advice
I've ever heard about investing.
It came from a millionaire
I looked up to as a kid.
After overhearing him
talk about investing,
I wanted to get involved.
But as a complete beginner,
I didn't know where to start.
So I asked him, "How do
I pick the right stocks
to invest in?"
His answer was very simple.
"Treat it like finding a girlfriend."
This is quite a clever way to look at it.
Because when you buy a share in a company,
you actually become a part owner.
This is like a partnership
between you and the company,
and just like a relationship
you wanna make sure it's
happy, long, and successful.
But look, I'm not gonna pretend
that there's a crystal ball
that can tell you when to buy a stock
before it rockets in value
like most of the fake gurus online.
However, there are certainly
a few things you can do
to tip the odds in your favor.
(light upbeat music)
When you're looking for a partner,
you need to have a strategy in mind.
Are you gonna shower them
with gifts like a simp
or treat them mean to keep them keen?
You'll get very different results
depending on which strategy you choose,
and the same goes for stocks.
So just like dating,
you need to figure out
how you're gonna approach the stock market
so that you get the results you want.
There are two strategies
you can choose from:
the technical or the fundamental approach.
Both of these options are very different,
so let's quickly go
over what they involve.
Technical analysis is mainly
for short-term day traders.
They use charts and price
action to identify patterns
that supposedly help them predict
if a stock is gonna go up
or down in the short-term.
I use the word supposedly
because in my opinion
most of the people using this strategy
are glorified gamblers.
Is it possible that
they trade successfully?
Yes, but more than 95%,
a day traders lose money
rather than making it,
according to The Motley Fool.
Fundamental analysis is
like being a detective
for a company.
You look at everything,
from their financial reports
to how well-known the brand is
and who's running the show.
All these pieces of
information help you understand
how the company is doing now
and how it might perform in the future.
This approach can help
you pick a range of stocks
that can make you a nice amount of money
over a three to 10 year period.
I know saying this will
probably ruin my watch time,
but I only want people getting into this
for the right reasons.
So if you're looking for
a way to get rich quick,
then stop watching my video now.
My goal is to secure
your financial future,
not just help you make a quick buck.
Also remember, with any kind of investing
your money can go down as well as up.
If you're still with me,
then comment down below, "I'm in",
so I know how many of
you are willing to invest
for the long-term.
Right, all done?
Cool. Let's jump into.
(light upbeat music)
When you're on a dating app
and checking out someone's profile,
you usually look at their
pictures and read their bio
to see if they'd make a good match.
It's exactly the same
when you're thinking about
investing in a company.
You have to check out
the company's profile,
which in this case is something
called a balance sheet.
A balance sheet is a financial statement
that provides a snapshot of a
company's financial position
at specific point in time.
It details the company's
assets, liabilities,
and shareholders' equity.
Don't worry if that
sounds a bit confusing.
We'll take a look at one together
and I'll break it down with you.
I'm gonna be using Trading 212 to do this,
which is a great place to
research and buy stocks.
You're welcome to download
it and follow along.
Trading 212 is also sponsoring
this portion of the video,
and if you use the code TILBURY
you'll also get a free fractional share
worth up to a hundred pound
when you open your account.
I'll put the link in the description.
Plus, you can get more free
stocks by inviting your friends.
Both of you will get a free share
as long as they fund their account.
I'm gonna be using their
desktop website for this video,
but you can do all of this on
the mobile app if you want to.
For everyone in the USA,
you can find the same
information on Yahoo Finance.
Remember that nothing in this video
should be taken as financial advice.
I'm not a financial advisor,
and when investing your
capital is at risk.
So to find the balance sheet,
just head to the stock
you're interested in.
For this example, I'm
gonna pick Coca-Cola.
Scroll down the page,
click on the Financials,
and then the Balance
Sheet, and More Financials.
This pulls up a pretty
complicated looking page,
but trust me, it is actually very simple.
To help you understand this balance sheet,
think of it like a cookie jar.
There you go.
At the top, you've got the current assets.
These are like the cookies
you can grab and eat.
(cookie crunches)
Mm, very nice.
For a company, this is the cash,
or anything that can be turned
into cash within 12 months.
Next, you have the longer term assets.
These are like the cookies
that are deeper down in a jar.
For a company, this often includes
the headquarters and equipment.
Here, you have the intangible assets.
These are like the invisible things
that make the cookies taste good.
You can't touch these things,
but they bring a lot of value.
For a company, this is
patents, intellectual property,
trademarks, and goodwill.
This next section is
all about liabilities.
These are like the cookies
that you've promised
to your friends for
borrowing their ingredients.
I'm most interested in
the current liabilities
as these will need to be
paid back within one year
or a normal operating cycle.
So now you know what all
of this information means,
what should you actually do with it?
Well, there's a simple
calculation you can do
to easily know if a company
is high risk or not,
and that is total current assets
divided by total current liabilities.
A good rule of thumb is this
number should be above one.
But how does this
actually work in practice?
Well, let's put Coca-Cola's numbers in.
Their total current
assets are $26.73 billion.
So if we divide that by their
total current liabilities,
which are $23.57 billion,
that comes to approximately 1.13.
This means the company
has $1.3 in current assets
for every $1 in current liabilities,
indicating they have
enough short-term assets
to cover their short-term debts.
This is a great indicator,
but our work is far from over.
(cookie crunches)
Mm.
(light upbeat music)
When you're getting to know someone new,
you're probably curious about
their past relationships.
It's like doing a bit of
a background check, right?
You might wonder whether
they've ever cheated
or how many partners they've had.
It's pretty much the same when
you're considering investing.
Before you put your hard
earned cash into a company,
you wanna check out its track record.
That's where the income
statement comes in.
And unlike people, public
companies have to be upfront
and honest about their past.
An income statement is like
a report card for a company
showing how well it did
over a specific period,
like a month, a quarter, or a year.
Put simply, it tells you how
much money the company made
and how much it spent.
This is normally found in the same place
as the balance sheet.
If you're using the
Trading 212 app like me,
then just click on the first tab
and then you'll see all the information.
Here at the top, we
have the total revenue,
which is the total the business
took in the time period.
As we can see from Coca-Cola,
they took 45.75 billion in 2023,
which isn't too shabby.
If we scroll down a bit,
we get to the net income,
which is the money the company makes
after all expenses have been deducted.
For Coca-Cola, this is $10.71 billion.
So, why does this matter?
Well, every business has
two main types of expenses:
the cost of revenue and
the cost of operations.
If either of these are too high,
then it could be a red flag.
Just think about it.
If you were selling custom T-shirts,
you'd have to spend money
on fabric and printing.
This is your cost of revenue
as you can't create custom
T-shirts without these materials,
so this is a necessary expense.
But that's not it.
You'd also have to
spend money on marketing
and potentially staff.
These are known as your
operating expenses.
Once you subtract both the cost of revenue
and the operating expenses
from the total money you make
from selling your custom T-shirts,
you get your operating income.
Now, if you just scale up that example,
it's the same idea for big
companies like Coca-Cola.
See here, this is the operating income.
So now you know what all
this information means,
what should you actually do with it?
Well, here's a simple calculation to see
if a business is making a
healthy amount of profit.
Operating income divided by
total revenue times a hundred.
According to Tide Banking,
as a rule of thumb 5%
is a low profit margin,
10% is a healthy margin,
and 20% is a high margin.
If we plug Coca-Cola's
numbers into this calculation,
we get approximately
25.73%, which is a high profit margin.
This is a great indicator to use.
However, it's important to remember
that older, more established companies
will be more profitable than newer,
faster growing companies.
So profitability isn't
the most important thing.
I mean, Amazon took years to make a profit
and look at them now.
But saying this, you
should also keep in mind
that a company that's
done well in the past
doesn't mean that it'll continue
to do well in the future.
Past performance doesn't
guarantee future results.
(light upbeat music)
Listen, it might not sound
like a romantic thing to say,
but if you're thinking of
getting involved with someone,
you don't want them to be bad with money.
It can lead to a whole lot
of headaches down the line.
Trust me.
In fact, money issues are a huge reason
why relationships break up.
The same goes for companies.
You don't wanna invest
your money in a company
that can't handle it correctly.
That's why you need to check
out their cash flow statement.
Cash flow statement shows
how much money is coming in
and going out of a company
over a period of time.
It's divided into three parts:
operating activities,
investing activities,
and financing activities.
They sound confusing,
but trust me, they are super simple.
Let's run through them one by one
and I'll let you know
what to look out for.
Operating activities show
the money a company makes
from its regular business operations.
In Coca-Cola's case, that's
selling their various beverages.
All you need to look for here
is a positive number, like this.
It means the company is making more money
than it spends on its
day-to-day operations.
This is a good sign.
Investing activity shows the money
the company spends on investments,
like buying new equipment, buildings,
or other companies.
It also includes money made
from selling those kinds of investments.
Believe it or not, this
negative number here
isn't a bad thing.
This is because the company
is re-investing back
into the business.
I always like it when I see that companies
investing wisely in their future.
Just be cautious that
they're not spending too much
or selling off lots of assets.
Financing activities is about
the money a company borrows
or gets from selling
pieces of the company,
and the money it uses to pay back loans
or give rewards to stock owners
in the form of dividends.
It's very important for you to keep an eye
on how they're managing their
debt and dividend payments.
Be cautious if they rely
too much on borrowing
and if they're paying high dividends
with a negative cash flow.
It's like if you won a chunk of money
and stopped working,
and then kept giving all
your friends expensive gifts.
It's just not sustainable,
and eventually you'll run outta cash.
However, this isn't
the case with Coca-Cola
because even though they
gave away $7.95 billion
worth of dividends to their shareholders,
it's safe to say with that
kind of positive cash flow,
they can afford it.
(light upbeat music)
Have you ever been really
attracted to someone online
who seems perfect on paper,
but when you finally meet them,
you don't feel that spark?
This could be similar to stocks.
A company may appear to be a
good investment based on data,
but there are factors that
spreadsheets just can't capture.
That's why you need to cross examine
with something called
qualitative analysis.
This basically means checking out things
that aren't numerical,
like how well-known the company is,
how loyal their customers are,
and how happy those customers
are with that company.
So yeah, it's not all about the numbers.
You need to seek out this
information from sources
that aren't as easy to find
and really embody your
inner Sherlock Holmes.
So, what information
should you be looking for
and how can you find it when
it's not immediately obvious?
Well, there are three key things
you need to keep an eye on.
The first thing is brand recognition.
If you went to a bunch
of people in the street
and said, "Tell me what
you think about Apple,"
you'd probably get
mostly positive responses
about their product quality
and good privacy reputation.
I mean, most people out
there own an Apple device
and they've built a very
strong customer base.
But what if I asked you about a brand
that wasn't as popular, like Xiaomi?
You'd probably get a
lot more blank stares,
especially in the UK.
If you haven't heard of it,
it's a Chinese tech company.
So just through those two examples,
there is a clear contrast between the two.
And I'd say, 99.9% of you would
rather invest in Apple stock
just based off its brand recognition,
even though Xiaomi is
a major player in China
and emerging markets with
a growing customer base.
But, why is this?
Well, companies with a
strong brand recognition
have built up a lot of
trust with their customers,
meaning that they're less
impacted by any competition.
Therefore, minimizing
your risk as an investor.
It's like they're king on a chess board.
Every move revolves around it
and its position is central to the game,
making it irreplaceable.
The second key thing to check out
is the company's leadership.
You can find all this information
by researching the company's
board of directors,
reading transcripts of earnings calls,
and checking out the
executive's LinkedIn profiles.
However, it's not only important to know
who these leaders are,
but how long they've been working there.
In general, the longer
they've been in charge,
the more knowledgeable they are,
meaning the more successful
they're likely to be.
In addition to this, lots of CEOs
have big followings now on Twitter.
However, this comes
with both pros and cons.
With the power to influence
millions with just a tweet,
it can send stock prices to the moon
or crashing back down.
I mean, back in 2016,
Donald Trump tweeted,
"The F-35 program and
cost is out of control.
Billions of dollars can and
will be saved on military
and other purchases
after January the 20th."
That F-35 program was a
Lockheed Martin project.
After that tweet, Lockheed
Martin's stock price
took a nosedive.
The company shares fell
by 2.5% on the same day,
wiping out nearly $4
billion in market value.
So it's becoming more important than ever
to invest in companies
with a sensible CEO.
Otherwise, the wrong tweet
could lead to a very bumpy ride.
The third important thing to research
is any competitive advantages.
So this can be things like
patents, loyal customer bases,
or disruptive business models.
These advantages set them
apart from the competition,
helping them make more money
and grow their businesses
faster over time.
For example, Tesla has managed to secure
a competitive advantage
through cutting edge
electric vehicle technology
and an expansive charging network.
These competitive advantages
are like gold for investors
because it means lower risk
and bigger potential rewards.
You'll be able to find
all this information
on the company's website
and also through a good old Google search.
It's time consuming, yes,
but understanding these aspects could make
or break your investment.
Remember, research is your best friend.
It's better to spend a
couple of weeks researching
rather than make a rushed
investment and have it backfire.
(light upbeat music)
Let's say you hear a nasty rumor
about the person you're seeing.
You might panic and dump them
without getting to the truth.
This is what so many people
do when they hear bad news
about the company they've invested in.
They rush to sell it
without actually giving it
any proper thought.
They just act on emotion.
The news is actually so powerful.
Think back to when the news broke
that we might see empty
shelves in the supermarkets.
What did everyone do?
They panic bought toilet rolls
until they really did run out.
The panic buying just made
the situation so much worse.
Just imagine if that wasn't
reported on the news,
there wouldn't have been panic buying
and toilet rolls wouldn't
have sold out in every store.
The news has the same
power over investors too,
and can cause abrupt
surges in stock prices.
But more often than not, it
causes extreme panic selling.
One example of panic selling is when
the Cambridge Analytica
scandal broke in March 2018
and personal data was unethically taken,
causing Facebook stock to plummet
nearly 18% in just 10 days
as investors reacted to
the news of data misuse.
But as we can see, if we zoom out,
since then the stock has
gone up by more than 200%.
This was just a blip on the radar,
and long-term investors
that understood that
held strong because they were
confident in their research.
So if the news is full of fearmongering,
then how do you know when
to actually sell a stock?
Well, there's a few occasions
when you should sell a stock,
and this might not be what
you're expecting to hear,
but these occasions actually depend on you
and not the stock market.
For example, if you find
yourself in a financial emergency
and don't have any emergency
fund to fall back on,
then, I'd advise you sell your shares
to get yourself out of
that sticky situation.
Or on a more positive note,
maybe you've hit a financial goal
and you'd like to take a vacation.
I wouldn't normally
suggest this to people,
but if it's a figure at which
you would feel satisfied
selling a stock at,
then do it and enjoy your gains.
The last reason to sell a stock
is when you no longer believe
in the fundamentals of the company
and their future trajectory.
In this case, it may
be time to cut and run.
(light upbeat music)
When looking for a partner,
you don't wanna settle with
the first person you date.
It's important to explore
what different people have to offer.
Some may seem perfect,
but too self-absorbed
while others may have a great potential.
The same concept applies
when building your investment portfolio.
The main types of stocks
are value and growth.
It's beneficial to understand both,
so you can decide whether
to focus on just one type
or mix and match.
Value stocks are normally shares
in big, well-known companies.
These companies have a few key features.
First, their stock prices
are considered lower
compared to other companies in the market.
They also have a low
price to earnings ratio,
which means they make good money
compared to their stock price.
Additionally, they're stable
and they don't have wild ups
and downs in their stock prices
and they pay dividends,
which essentially means
they regularly give
some of their profits
back to their investors.
Value stocks are often found in companies
that people rely on
even when times are tough,
like during a recession, for example.
These companies make or
provide things that people need
no matter what.
Examples include consumer staples,
which are everyday products
like food and household items,
energy companies that
provide fuel and power,
financials like banks,
and industrials that build
things and provide raw materials.
Some well-known examples of value stocks
are Berkshire Hathaway, which
is owned by Warren Buffet
and invest in many different companies;
Procter & Gamble, which
makes everyday products
like shampoo and toothpaste;
and JP Morgan, a major bank.
Growth stocks, on the other hand,
are usually seen as overvalued
compared to the market.
They tend to be pretty volatile,
meaning their stock prices
can go up and down a lot.
These stocks have higher
price earnings ratios.
This means that investors expect them
to grow a lot in the future
and they pay little to no dividends.
Some growth stocks aren't even
profitable for a long time
as they reinvest their earnings
to fuel further growth.
Growth stocks are expected
to grow at a more rapid pace
than the overall market,
which is why they often
outperform the market.
Some well-known examples of growth stocks
include Amazon, Meta
Platforms, NVIDIA, and Tesla.
If you're not sure if the
stock is growth or value,
then a quick way to tell
is by using the P/E ratio.
You can easily find this
here on Trading 212.
Typically, the average P/E
ratio is around 20 to 25.
Anything below that
would be considered good,
whereas anything above would be worse.
However, this is just
a general rule of thumb
and does vary depending on the industry,
so make sure to compare it
with some other companies in that sector.
Once you've determined whether you're
a value, growth, or mixed investor,
you need to ensure you have
a diverse range of
stocks in your portfolio.
This is what we call diversification.
So if one of your stocks takes a dive,
your banking on the others
to balance things out.
A general rule is not to have more than 5%
of your money in one stock
and no more than 20% of your
investments in one sector,
such as technology, for example.
It's a good idea to have stocks
in at least five different sectors,
a minimum of two countries,
and more than 25
different stocks in total.
You could also look into
having a Cash ISA too,
which is basically just an
individual savings in the UK
which allows you to save money
and earn tax-free interest.
At the moment, Trading 212 seem to have
one of the highest paying
Cash ISAs right now at 5.2%.
So if you've already used the code TILBURY
or the link in the description
to pick up your free
fractional share worth up
to a hundred pounds,
then all you have to do is go up here
and they'll walk you through the process.
If after watching this video
you think picking individual
stock seems too time consuming,
then there is a way you can cut out
pretty much all the research
and in a lot of cases
get even better results.
If you wanna understand how
I make around $17,000 a week
using index fund investing,
then you should watch this next video
where I explain everything in detail.
But don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if you
wanna grow your wealth, okay?
(clicks tongue) I'll see you over there.