- I want you to imagine
for a moment you are driving
a brand-new supercar
through the sunny Streets of Dubai.
While passive income
continuously flows into your bank
account, many young YouTubers promise
that this dream is possible
with the print on demand side hustle.
Look, I won't make claims like this.
I've been around a lot longer
and from my experience, if
you need grand promises just
to listen, then you won't succeed anyway.
However, I will promise to
give you a step-by-step guide
to start in Print on demand.
I'm gonna show you exactly where to click
and what to do to make
this business work with $0.
You'll even learn how to
make products like this
and sell them internationally.
This is coming from someone
who hasn't just started a few
little internet businesses
and sold a few print on demand items.
I'm an established millionaire businessman
that's been running
companies for over 35 years,
so I'll be sharing some of the lessons
that you can only learn from
having years of experience.
I know starting a new side
hustle seems daunting.
There's so much to learn.
That's why this is the
only print on demand
for beginner's video you need to watch
before you take action, right?
So I'm gonna split this
into 10 different sections
to make sure to cover
absolutely everything.
Firstly, what is Print on Demand?
But simply it's a risk-free way
of starting out in business.
Let's say you wanted to
start a clothing brand,
but don't have a factory to make thousands
of unique clothing products,
nor do you want to end
up with a basement full
of unsold shirts like a hoarder.
That's where print on demand
swoops in to save the day.
Print on demand allows you
to pay for your products only
after your customers order them.
These products are then printed
with your unique designs
and delivered directly to your customers.
This allows you to run everything
with very little money.
This isn't just limited clothing.
You can also do mugs, posters,
bags, and even cushions.
This side hustle is ideal for someone
who doesn't want the hassle
of starting a full-time business,
but wants to wear in passive income.
You can work from your laptop
and as your income scales,
the time you put into the
business shouldn't need
to change significantly.
Isn't it wild how these days
you can potentially raking
millions without even physically
touching a single product?
This concept would've
blown my mind in my day.
The data backs this up.
As currently the global print
on demand market is worth
nearly $6 billion
and that's expected to
rise to 40 billion by 2031.
From my time in the business
world, I've seen firsthand
how crucial is to operate
in the right market.
Believe me, I've seen some
seriously smart people hit rock
bottom because they were busy
building their brand in a
market that was on the decline.
But here's where print
on demand is different.
Even if you're just an average
Joe in the entrepreneurial
world, you could potentially
raking a fortune if you dive
into a booming market like this one.
To get started, you need five things.
One, a winning product.
Two, a great design to go on the product.
Three, a place to sell
product for a great supplier,
and five of course paying customers.
But don't worry, we're gonna
cover all of this today.
By the way, if you're
new here, then I Mark
and I make video sharing
my years of wisdom so
that you can grow your wealth.
So if that interests you,
make sure to subscribe
to get more videos like this one.
So how do I find a winning product?
This is the first question
most people ask when they're
getting into print on
demand and rightly so.
'cause if you get this wrong,
then it could make the difference
between your store
getting hundreds of sales
and none whatsoever.
From my experience,
a winning product has two main components,
the product category, and the design.
Now, you might think all
of these product categories
are created equal,
but far from it.
You need to be very strategic
about which one you decide
to use for your blank canvas.
You may be thinking, why
not just pick all of them
and use the same design
across every product?
Now, although this may
sound like a good idea,
it really isn't at first,
your designs probably
aren't gonna be that great.
This means you're gonna
waste a ton of time
and money focusing on different products
and not getting any sales.
Instead, I want you to
pick one product category
and give it your entire focus.
Once you hit over 10 K per
month with that product type,
then you can repurpose
the same designs on other
products in a new shop.
It's much better to become a master
of one product than a jack of all trades.
This even applies to color options.
Personally, I'd never offer
more than seven different
variations as that tends
to overwhelm the customer,
and you know what?
They end up buying nothing.
So you have a big decision to make.
So let me help you eliminate
some of the categories.
Cards and calendars are a big no for me,
as they're extremely seasonal.
You want a product that's evergreen
and sells continuously no matter what.
The time of year mugs, iPhone cases, oh,
and stationary, they don't
really sell for very much.
So personally I'd stay away from these.
My role is to have at least
20 to 30% profit margin.
I'm not saying these are a definite no
because if you're able
to sell them in large enough quantities,
then you can make a nice profit.
Take this shop for example.
They have the number one listing on Etsy.
When I search for a mug, now
if I dig into their figures,
I can actually see that they're generating
around $30,000 a month from this store.
If we assume a 15% margin,
then they're probably making
around 4,500 pound a month in profit,
which isn't too bad at all.
If they've managed to
get a 30% profit margin,
then that's even better.
If we're evaluating options
based purely on potential profit
margins, then clothing and
wall art are the clear winners.
In my opinion. It's much
easier to inflate the value
of products like this.
It's the same strategy
that designer brands
and modern artists have
been using for years.
I can actually show you
some real numbers here.
Now, I've sold some wall
art before using gelato.
Honestly, I really like gelato
because they have production
- Facilities over 32
countries on this point.
Over 90%
of orders are produced in
the same country The customer
lives in cutting down
shipping times even more.
As you can see, my price point was $49
and 99 cents, and my costs were $25
and 39 cents for the
product and the printing.
There was also a 6 98
shipping cost as well.
So if we add those together,
that gives us a price
of $32 and 37 cents.
Now, if we take those numbers
and plug them into the
Etsy free calculator,
with everything taken
into account, I made $12
and 42 cents on every sale,
which gives me a 25% profit
margin on every product.
As you can see, it's so
easy for your profits
to be eaten away.
That's why it's so
important to pick an item
with a high profit margin potential.
As I've already spoken about
wall art in past videos,
I feel like switching it up.
So today, let's go with clothing.
So what's the best niche to pick?
It might seem obvious, but
nobody cares about blank clothes.
That's where you come in.
You need to make them care
about what you are selling.
You can do this by attaching one
of their interests to the item.
So I could just make a shirt like this
with storm pooper on it
to attract Star Wars fans.
That's the right kind of idea,
but it will also get you into
a lot of trouble with the law.
This is because a one
simple word, trademarks,
you should always check the text for use
of potential trademark infringements,
even if it isn't from a famous franchise.
Luckily, this is free
to do and super simple.
It's worth checking the
UK and USA trademarks.
This is what the American site looks like.
Just click on basic word mark search
and then type in the phrase I'm gonna use.
Boomers are awesome and click submit.
Change this set into live. There you go.
Well, for this one, we look
like we're in the clear.
Okay, so if I can't use popular films
or TV shows, I'll just do
something completely original.
I like your thinking,
but also, no, I'm gonna say
something that might shock you.
Don't try to be original
school drills into you the
importance of not looking
at other people's work.
But when it comes to business,
this is completely wrong.
I have a theory that C grade
studers often end up hiring the
people who get the A's because of this.
There's actually a really good
book that talks about this,
and it's called Still Like an Artist.
It's based on the saying
that good artists copy
and great artists still,
honestly, it works just as well
for entrepreneurs.
Being to original is
the biggest trap I see
beginners falling into.
They feel like they've gotta
come up with the next big thing
and then just end up trying to
sell something nobody wants.
Yes, you may have spotted
a gap in the market,
but most likely that gap's there
because no one wants what you're selling.
I'd say 99% of people fail at this step.
So here's what you should
actually do. Research the market.
I love using Etsy to do this
as all the sales information is public.
Let's say for this example,
I wanna sell T-shirts.
Now, since the T-shirt niche
is extremely competitive,
we need to find some good sub niches.
These are pockets of the market
that have low competition,
but very high demand.
So let's type in women's T-shirts
and sort this by top customer reviews.
Now look, ah, this is one you don't want
to be taking inspiration from
is it's a clear trademark
infringement of DC
Comics and Wonder Woman.
I mean, if you're gonna risk doing this,
at least pick a decent film,
but seriously don't infringe
on anyone's trademarks.
You might get a ton of
sales to begin with,
but in the long run, it's
just not worth it when you run
into all the legal trouble.
What we're really looking for
is shops with lots of reviews,
as we can tell from that,
that they're successful.
Now, let's click on this one
as they look like they're doing very well.
Now, let's go on their shop homepage
and filter reviews by most recent
to see what's selling at the moment.
Oh, I'm not gonna lie to you even.
I like the look of a few
of these designs myself.
This is a perfect little sub niche.
You'll then just have to spend an hour
or so going through screenshoting designs
that are selling well
and take elements from all of
them to put in your design.
You might think this is
a really small market,
but this T-shirt here
has over 130 reviews.
That's important as the normal rule
of thumb is the time's out by 10,
and then you have the number of sales.
So this seller has sold
in a region of 1300
of these T-shirts bringing in revenue
of $43,628 when you take
shipping into account.
Now with a 30% profit
margin, that would be
around $13,000 in profit
from this one design.
So simple designs really do sell well
and remember, you can have loads of these
as they're pretty easy to make.
Just to set the record straight,
you can't simply copy these designs.
Instead, think of it
like making a cocktail.
You are pulling different
elements from various sources,
combining proven ingredients,
so it's important
to draw inspiration from multiple places.
Otherwise you risk getting banned.
So if you're gonna steal
steal from many, for instance,
you could pinch the font from one design,
borrow the colors from another
and nab a section of a
quote from a third source.
The aim here is to whip up a
whole bunch of unique designs
for your chosen sub niche
because let's face it,
we can't always predict
what's gonna sell like crazy.
So what's the best way
to create your designs?
This step is one of the
biggest roadblocks people
face. I know so many
- People great design ideas,
but they dunno how to
actually make them look
good on a computer.
To be honest, I used to
be one of those people,
but it turns out that
it's actually super easy.
Even for an old boy like me,
there are four main methods you can use.
Firstly, you can use a
free tool like Canva.
So I've got a list
of woodwork related funny
quotes here on chat GPT.
I'm gonna go with this one now.
I'm gonna take some design
elements from other products we
found earlier, like the
font from this listing
and the design from this other one.
It's pretty easy to get
these mocked up on Canva
and it's also a free tool,
which is even better.
Then I just have to click here
to download the image
without a background.
Secondly, you could actually
buy a template or full design.
So if we take this flower
T-shirt for example,
and I download the image,
then use the Google search
by image function, then
you are quite often able
to actually buy the original source file.
Thirdly, and this is one I've
actually been using a lot
recently is AI tools to design it for you.
Now, I think Midjourney is the
best for this kind of thing.
Look, it does cost you $10
a month to generate designs
and also have the rights to
use the images commercially,
but it's such a great tool
and I think it's worth it.
Now I'm lucky that my son
Curtis keeps me up to date
with all the new AI tech.
If I mentioned Midjourney
to the other old boys down the golf club,
they wouldn't have a
clue what I'm on about.
They'd think I'm halfway
to my holiday destination.
It's super easy to use.
You just need to have
a free Discord account.
Once that's set up, go
to Mid Journey's website
and click on join beta.
This will connect you
to the Midjourney server
inside Discord.
You might as well join my free
Discord group while you're in
there because there's about
40,000 people in there that'll
help you out with everything business
and making money related
and it's completely free.
Click on add server,
then me and my friends
and just give it a name.
I'm gonna call mine Mark's Designs.
Now go back to the midjourney server,
click on the Midjourney bot and add app.
There we go, and then pick
the server you just made.
So I'm gonna click Mark's Designs first.
Let's get the settings right,
type forward slash settings,
and you'll get this menu.
Select model six and
Stylization High right now.
Type in forward slash imagine.
Now, if we wanted
to make designs like
this Butterfly T-shirt,
then we would type something
like this, butterflies
in the style of silhouettes
in a tornado pattern on a
white background.
Now these look pretty cool.
I actually think the
colorful version looks nicer.
This arrow circle button here
- Will the same prompt again
to give me more options,
but I'm gonna click V four,
which will give me more variations
like the fourth version.
Once you're happy, then
upscale the one you like
by pressing the corresponding U button.
This just makes the design larger so
that you can use it on your product.
Then you can just use a
background remover to get rid
of the white background, I
personally use photo room.com.
Finally, you can use professional
designers on websites like
Upwork and Fiverr.
Now, I've done this before with wall art
and I've been pretty
happy with the results.
You just have to make sure
that you are very specific with the brief.
Here's a look at the
brief I gave last time
so you can just copy and
tailor it to fit your needs.
These are all good methods,
so it just depends on your skillset,
available time and budget.
So now we've got our designs.
What's the best print on
demand website for beginners?
This is the site you are
use to order your products,
print them, and ship
them to your customers.
This is an extremely important section
as picking the wrong print
provider will result in some
of your shipments getting
lost, poor customer service,
and all around massive headaches.
Most YouTubers recommend
the absolute cheapest sites,
and to be honest, I've got
a real issue with this.
The reason a lot of them can
charge crazy low prices is
because they cut corners in other areas.
Wait a minute, I thought
you were telling us
how we could start with $0.
Now you're telling us we've
gotta pay for websites.
Well, the cool thing about most
print on demand sites is you
only have to pay once you've made a sale.
That way you actually don't
need any money upfront.
I live my life by the saying,
buy nice or buy twice.
This essentially means if you
go with the cheapest option,
then you'll actually end up
spending more money in the long
run as you'll have to take
the hit for the lost items
and that'll start digging
into your profits.
I tested out the gelato
website for myself recently,
and I've gotta say I was super impressed.
The experience was seamless
with both the product quality
and the printing quality being excellent.
Just look at how great
this poster came out.
I only ordered it as a sample,
but I've actually ended up keeping it
because I like it so much.
Alright, so let's jump onto gelato
and start uploading our
design so you can see
how easy the process is.
So I'm just gonna go to the
menu on the left hand side
and select product catalog
and then select men's clothing.
I'm then gonna pick T-shirts.
I think we should be fine
with the heavyweight
unisex crew neck T-shirts.
As I can see, that's their best seller
and to be honest, gelato
has a very high standard
of quality anyway,
it's nearly $2 cheaper than
the other more premium options,
and as I said earlier,
it's super important
to protect your profit margins.
Alright, so here's what I'm thinking.
I'm gonna go with direct
to garment for this design.
Now, don't get me wrong,
embroidery is pretty cool
and definitely has that premium vibe,
but let's be real, it's pricier.
So I'd save that for that design.
That screams embroider me
and hey, if you're shelling
out the extra bucks
for embroidery, make sure
it's super obvious when you're
promoting the product.
After all, if you're paying more,
it should seriously ramp up the perceived
value of your product.
Okay, so I'm gonna start
with the white option
and size large,
but I'll also repeat the same process
with seven colors in all sizes.
Now it's as simple as drag in
and drop in the design we made
earlier into this center box.
There's also an option down here
where you can add different
designs to the back,
neck and sleeves.
But now for this one,
I'm just gonna keep it
simple and do the front.
If you are interested in using them
and you want to get 50% off
your first order, then feel free
to sign up with the link gelato.com/mark.
They also give me a kickback
if you use that link,
which I pass on to my video editors.
So if you use it, then thanks
for supporting the channel.
Once you've got all your designs
uploaded in their different
colors and sizes, it's
time to start selling them.
But where do I sell my products?
I've got a real problem with
how most YouTube channels
approach this question
with one answer.
They'll either say Etsy or Shopify,
but it really isn't that simple.
I'm not interested in
rushing through this video
to get a little bit of extra attention.
I know if you got to this part
in the video, then you want
to know the facts before
you jump into something.
So let's go through both of these options
so you can decide which
is the best route for you
or route for all you American viewers.
Firstly, let's talk Etsy.
If we look at the figures from
February, 2023, we can see
that Etsy had 460.6 million visitors.
That's by far the most out
of every print on demand marketplace,
and that even includes Shopify.
In 20 22, 20 6% of sales were made
to order merch.
In other words, a lot
of print on demand items
and 45% of sales involved in
international transaction.
This means that Etsy gives you access
to a global audience of shoppers.
A lot of people commented on one
of my previous videos mentioning
that I'd overlook the
marketing cost, but I didn't.
That's the advantage of
marketplaces like Etsy,
the customers are already there searching
for these kinds of things.
All you need to do is rank
high enough in the search
results, but it isn't all
sunshine and rainbows.
Lots of people high up
print on demand on Etsy,
but more people fail than succeed.
That's just the harsh truth.
Etsy don't reveal the percentage of shops
that actually succeed,
but they have revealed
that there are 5.4 million active sellers
and the average monthly sales per user was
$2,169 in 2022.
But of course, these
figures are heavily skewed
by the more successful
and established shops.
In my opinion, the reason
for people failing on Etsy is
that lots of folks just go
with their gut selling
whatever they fancy instead
of really studying the market like I've
shown you in this video.
But if you stick to the
system I've taught you,
you'll have a serious leg
up on the competition.
Now, for Shopify customer data is one
of the most valuable things in business.
A general rule of thumb is
that a customer's email
is worth about $1 a month
to a business as they can
use it for advertising
to a previous buyer.
Our Shopify isn't a shared marketplace
and instead is your own website.
They allow you to collect
this valuable information,
whereas Etsy doesn't have an
option to do this legally.
You see, someone has to agree
to be on your email list.
So yes, you can just download
the emails from your Etsy
customers, but you can't really
get away with adding them
to your email list without
facing some issues.
Not only is it against Etsy's policies,
it's also illegal in many countries.
Selling on Shopify also allows you
to set yourself apart
from the competition.
The bad thing about Etsy is
that your products are always surrounded
by your competitors, so
you are somewhat forced
to compete on price.
It's kind of like this YouTube channel.
You've probably got tons
of other print on demand videos
recommended in the sidebar.
I know I don't have to worry
about you clicking off my video
though because it's the best one.
Imagine this, you are
scrolling through YouTube,
but all you are seeing are my videos.
It's either stick with me or
don't learn anything at all.
It's kind of like having a Shopify store.
If a customer wants what you
are selling, they can't go off
and buy it from anyone else.
You've got them right where you want them.
So Shopify sounds like the
clear winner, right? Well, no.
Here's what I suggest.
When you're starting out
as a beginner, it's best
to go with Etsy.
The customer's already there,
which means you don't have
to worry about marketing.
All you have to focus on is getting better
and better at designing
products people want to buy.
The competition aspect
is actually very good
for honing your skills as
the market doesn't lie.
If your product designs
aren't good enough,
then you won't make any sales.
This will force you to find
unique gaps in the market
and level up as an entrepreneur.
You can also easily connect
it with gelato by going
to a menu and stores.
Don't get me wrong, the
end game should be Shopify.
However, before you start
spending crazy amounts
of money on marketing for
products you don't even know sell,
I recommend you post a
thousand listings on Etsy.
This will set you back
about 20 cents per listing,
which will be a total of $200,
but the data you gather
will be worth far more.
Once you've identified
your winning products,
you can start building a Shopify store
and advertising on TikTok.
That way you'll know if your
products aren't selling on
Shopify, then your marketing needs work.
If you just skip the Etsy step,
then the issue could also be your product
and then it's hard to
tell what needs improving.
Think of Etsy a bit like a
testing ground where you can cast
as many fishing lines as
possible into the ocean,
and when you start catching some big fish,
you know it's time to take the next step.
So how do beginners sell on Etsy?
Once you've created an
account, there are three hacks
that you can do to help
you get notice on Etsy
and make more sales.
The first hack is to
make attractive mockups.
This is super important
as people wanna see
what your item looks
like in the real world,
and mockups are an easy way for you
to show them without having
to order all the different
colors and designs
and taking photos.
Mockups also seem
to make the product
look much more homemade,
which instantly makes it seem
more valuable to customers.
Gelatos built-in mock-up
studio actually makes this
super simple.
Now, this one here, there you go.
That looks pretty good,
so let's go with that.
The second hack is to
use the best keywords.
This is extremely effective
as Etsy is a search engine,
so the more information you
can give them about your
product, the better.
Of course, you shouldn't use
keywords that don't apply
to your product 'cause you
only want traffic from people
that are interested in
pieing what you are selling.
This is pretty simple to do.
So let's go back to the listing we found
to inspire our T-shirt design.
As we can see, they've
used wood shirt, men
woodworker shirt, men's
funny shirt, funny shirts
for men and Father's Day
gift and dad's shirt.
So I'll just copy
and paste these keywords
into my tags and title.
It's also worth looking around
for different listings in case some
of them have other unique
keywords you can copy.
The third hack is to use premium branding.
You need to convey quality and trust.
Now, trust is the most
important thing in business
and you're not gonna get there
by looking like a shop
at the local market.
You need to go for that
premium boutique feel.
This is a great example of a premium store
with a clear identity.
You can use the free Shopify
name generator to create a name
that conveys trust and
is relevant to your shop.
Then use the name checker website
to see if it's available
across different platforms.
The most crucial platform is Etsy,
but you should also check if
it's free on other social media
platforms and for the
name, name availability.
When creating your logo
and banner, don't spend too
much time perfecting it.
Instead, focus on making
it clean and professional.
Canva offers numerous
templates that can be helpful.
The key to a good Etsy banner is
to make it reflect the
charm of homemade goods,
which corporate banners often lack.
Lastly, make sure your shop
isn't targeting a completely
different audience.
I mean, you wouldn't expect
to walk into an Apple store
and see a washing machine, even
though they could sell them.
They understand the importance
of maintaining a coherent brand image.
If you wanna make sales quickly,
then you are probably thinking,
when should I run paid ads?
I understand the appeal
of running paid ads
as they can instantly
give your sales a boost.
However, in my opinion, people
start using paid ads well
before they're actually ready.
This means they either
end up with no sales
or as soon as they turn
paid ads off their sales
completely dry up.
I've always built my businesses
with an organic first approach.
We are living in an age of more
free reach than ever before,
and I actually think social
media companies are gonna start
limiting organic reach soon
as they must be losing out on millions
of advertising dollars.
The first thing you need
to put your marketing
money into is creating
short form content.
This is great as you can post
it across Instagram, TikTok,
YouTube shorts.
It's the first type of
content that enables you
to reach multiple different platforms
and it's perfect for
showing off your products.
You'd need to order a few samples,
which I'd recommend
doing anyway as you need
to double check the quality of the items
that you are sending out.
Then it's just a case
of creating some kind
of story around your product.
Don't just get fancy shots
of someone wearing it or using it.
Actually make it a part of a story.
Remember, people are on social
media to be entertained,
so if your content isn't
entertaining, then it won't reach
as many people.
The more views you get,
the more people will buy.
It's as simple as that.
The beauty of doing it this
way is that you are able to see
what videos perform best
with your target audience
before putting any ad spend
into boosting the views.
Once you're seeing some
organic success, it's time
to start supercharging
it with some paid ads.
This way you are building
your side hustle on
solid foundations.
I've seen so many people lose
their Facebook ad accounts
and it's just ruined their businesses.
These platforms don't
have enough employees
to oversee everything,
so they rely on tech
to police it for them.
Don't leave your income
in the hands of ai,
but that's not the biggest
thing people do wrong.
So what's the most common mistake?
A lot of people get drawn
in by the huge figures.
Many people say they're
making with print on demand,
but it's important to remember
anyone can sell at break even
or even a loss.
I have a feeling a lot of
these print on demand, Gus
and drop shippers actually do this.
They just make a loss on their products
and then flex their revenue
figures on YouTube to young
and impressionable people.
Don't make the mistake
of focusing on the revenue
you are generating.
This is a profit gain
and it's important to remember
that your profit margins are everything
and you should be protecting
them at all costs.
I used to sell a lot of items on eBay.
I remember having one competitor
in particular who'd always
tried to undercut beyond price.
Instead of competing, I'd
wait until he sold out.
Then I'd continue to sell my
products at my normal price.
The surprising thing is most
of the time my competitor
only made 5% profit margin.
Whenever I saw him at trade shows,
he would laugh thinking he'd
driven me out of the market.
I just smile to myself as still
have my 30% profit margins
and I was making bang.
The same applies with any business.
Don't let your ego get in the way.
You don't have to be ranked
number one to make money.
As long as your profit margins are strong,
you could be making more
money than the top sellers.
If you are choosing the Etsy route,
this is even more crucial
due to the associated fees.
Etsy charges 6.5% transaction
fee on both the price
and the shipping fee when
the item sells, as well
as a 3% payment processing
fee on the total amount
charged to the customer.
Here's a little secret that
not a lot of people know about.
You might be hit
with a 15% advertising fee if
a customer stumbles upon your
product through an Etsy ad
from outside the platform.
Sure, you can opt out,
but honestly, it's not a bad
deal as long as you're clued in
and factor it into your cost
and hey, don't forget about your time.
It isn't free. You know it's a shame,
but loads of people seem to
forget to value their own time.
I mean, if they were to do the math
and figure out their hourly
earnings, they might be shocked
to find out they're making
less than minimum wage.
Now at the start, you're
probably gonna have
to hustle a bit more and
earn a little bit less.
That's understandable,
but just keep a close eye
on the profits you are
making every so often.
Divide your monthly profit
by the hours you've put in.
This will give you a pretty good picture
of whether your side hustle
is on the right track or not.
But now it's time for the big question.
Can I really make money
with print on demand
or is it too saturated?
Right? So I need to address
a negative comment I received
about this on my last
print on demand video.
Mark, be honest about the
content of your vlogs.
Tell people how saturated the markets are
and stop giving them four solutions.
The world of side hustles are over.
There's no such thing as a quick buck.
First of all, I wanna say thanks
for taking the time to comment.
I really appreciate when
you guys leave comments.
I love reading your opinions
and love to hear about
all your success as well.
Although there are a couple
of things I disagree with,
which we'll get into a bit later.
There is one thing I agree with,
so I wanna start with that.
There has never been a truer word spoken
and there's no such thing as a quick,
but I know this more than most.
I started as a relatively poor
kid with no qualifications,
and it took me years of blood, sweat,
and tears to get where I am today.
No part of my journey was easy or quick.
That's just the reality of life.
However, if someone told me
how hard it was gonna be,
I probably wouldn't have even started.
In my opinion, it's much better
to focus on the positives
than the inevitable late
nights and hard work.
Maybe I should get that
across more in my video,
so I'll take that point on board.
Now, as for the markets being saturated,
what a load of nonsense.
It's hard to break into any market.
You've either gotta be better
or different in some way.
Yes, there's a lot of people doing it.
However, the market is only growing.
Most people that say the
markets are too saturated,
probably aren't put in the hard work.
Raise yourself. There's gonna be a little
bit of a rough patch.
Sales might take a while to kick in,
but you've gotta stick with it.
Don't do all the hard graft
and miss out on the big payoff.
You'll have to gradually chip away
to carve your own spot in the market.
And yeah, this could mean a
few months without any sales,
but don't let that get you down.
Just keep going and trust the journey.
If you haven't listed at
least a thousand different
products, then don't come
back saying the market
is saturated.
The truth is, you've probably
not put in enough time yet,
and the more you work on your
skills, the better you'll get.
As for side hustles being dead,
that's like saying businesses are dead.
If you want actual proof that
side hustles aren't dead,
then you should watch this next video
as I share seven real
stories about students making
thousands per month with
unique side hustles.
But don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.