- It took me 10 years to learn this,
but I'll teach it to
you in under 30 minutes.
To become rich, you need
multiple income streams.
I have seven, which generate
me over $100,000 per week,
so today I thought I'd walk
you through each income stream,
explain how I got started,
and rate them on a scale of one to five.
This video is gonna
create future millionaires
because, after watching it,
you'll have all the information you need
to build multiple income streams
and escape the traditional
nine-to-five life.
First is my retail stores
where I sell remote control planes,
helicopters, cars, and more.
Many young people believe
the only way to start their own store
is by launching an online one.
Now, I can see why people might think this
because there are lower startup costs,
a global customer base,
and you have the flexibility
to run the business
from anywhere you like.
But just because online
stores are easier to start,
it doesn't mean that physical stores
are outdated or unachievable.
I mean, just look at the
amount of physical locations
The Sidemen are opening up,
from fried chicken shops
to clothing stores.
"But Mark, starting a retail
store requires a lot of money.
You're basically saying to become rich
you already have to be rich.
Disliked and unsubscribed."
I understand it might seem that way,
but when I started my store,
I had hardly any money.
I'd recently resigned from my
job and dropped out of school
with no qualifications to fall back on,
so I simply had to make it work.
I'm not gonna sit here and
tell you it was easy for me
because it really wasn't.
I remember on the opening
day of my first model shop,
I put a sleeping bag
in the back of the van
because unless I made
enough money on the day,
I couldn't even afford to fill
my car with fuel to get home.
So how did I manage to start a shop
with barely no money to my name?
Well, I got funding, which
is something you can do too.
I know it sounds a bit complicated,
but I took three simple steps.
Step one is to write a business plan.
I identified the perfect
location for a shop,
how I was gonna attract customers,
how much money I needed,
how I was gonna allocate that money,
and finally how much money
I thought I could make.
Back in the day,
this was about as far as I could go
without professional help,
but now you can go one step further
and find a free business
plan template online
to make your plan look as
professional as possible.
Step two is to do some customer research.
You have to find a cheap way
to test out if your
business will actually work.
So many people come up
with a business plan
and get so carried away with it
that they don't actually
ever consider going out
and asking their potential
customers what they think.
This step is all about going
out into the real world
and gathering actual data.
Trust me, doing this will
save you so much money
and potential headaches.
You may even find you
need to adapt your plan.
I did this without even knowing it
as I worked in someone else's
model shop on the weekend.
This allowed me to talk to customers
and find issues within the business
that I could fix in mine.
You can also walk around with a clipboard
asking people's opinions,
like they probably force
you to do on school trips.
But if you can get a part-time
job in a similar business,
then it can prove to be
the best customer
research opportunity ever.
Step three is to get funding.
I got my initial money in
the form of a bank loan.
It was very hard to secure,
but I eventually got it
by knocking on enough bank manager's doors
until someone believed in me.
Nowadays, there are so many alternative
funding options available
such as crowdfunding.
If you have a solid business idea,
you can use platforms like
Kickstarter to raise money
by pitching your concept
directly to potential customers.
Right, time to rank this
income stream out of five stars
in my three core categories.
Firstly, how much time does
managing a retail store take?
I'm gonna give this a
two out of five stars
because I'm not gonna lie,
it takes a lot of your time at the start.
However, with that being
said, as time goes by,
you can afford to take a step back,
especially when you start
scaling it by hiring staff
and implementing systems
that can run while you are not there.
Now I probably spend less
than a couple of hours a week
actually in this store.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'm gonna rate this four out of five stars
because although the initial stage of,
"Ah, how do I get the money?"
is tricky to overcome,
you don't have to do it all alone
and there are so many investors, loans,
and crowdfunding methods
that can get you there,
especially if they see the
potential in your business.
Thirdly, how easy is it
to make $100 per week?
You know what?
For this one, I'm gonna
say five out of five stars.
If you're really passionate
about what you're selling
and you know the ins
and outs of the niche,
then you'll sell.
To be a top seller,
you have to make the customer
buy into not just the
products, but into you.
Second is my own brand and product range,
which I manufacture in China
and distribute all over the world.
When I was younger,
the idea of seeing my own products
on the shelves of other shops
seemed just like a dream.
I would sit in school
staring at my drawings
of model airplane designs, thinking,
"How can I make this happen?"
I always thought you had to
have millions of dollars,
niche connections or
a huge team behind you
to make it a reality.
I was wrong.
Little did I know years later I'd be sat
clutching onto my designs I drew as a kid
on a plane heading to China.
So how did I go from a kid with
a dream on a piece of paper
to a successful brand owner?
Well, I took three key
steps that you can replicate
to get started with your own brand.
Step one is picking a niche.
Back in my day, model
airplanes were all the rage.
If people weren't watching
the latest competitions
or going crazy for new designs,
they were busy collecting
kits and accessories
to customize their own.
It had what's known now
as a cult following.
You need to identify a popular
niche with lasting appeal,
not just a fleeting fad.
I'd personally start by
following Instagram pages
and joining in on the conversations.
You need to know what
the people in this niche
are passionate about.
Also try to understand their challenges
to use to your advantage.
Step two, keep an eye on trends.
Take a brand like Represent, for example.
I mean, it just got so
popular out of nowhere
and ended up on everyone's Christmas list.
They recognized the growing trend
for oversized clothing
within the fashion industry
and quickly capitalized on it
with their oversized
hoodies and tracksuit sets.
This is where they really
made a name for themselves.
It's interesting because
if you look at them now,
they're moving more towards fitness gear
with their 247 range
because they're following
new and rising trends.
Here in the UK,
fitness has become so popular
with 74% of people
owning fitness products.
I mean, even the nightclubs are shutting
because young people
aren't drinking as much.
It's clear that Represent
have spotted this trend
and created a new clothing
range to meet the demand.
You should aim to do the
same in your chosen niche.
Step three is creating a culture.
If you can build a real
community around your products,
that is the secret sauce.
It's not just about selling stuff anymore.
People feel like they wanna
be part of something bigger.
This way your brand sticks around
because customers are all in
not just for what you're
selling, but for the whole vibe.
My son Curtis recently participated
in the Super 10K Spartan Race
which was filled with
obstacles like monkey bars,
rope climbs, and even
swimming through icy water.
It's become more than just a race.
It's now become a movement
where people go to test their limits
and meet like-minded individuals.
They've built a genuine community
with around 1.5 million people
participating last year.
There's even been a wedding
ceremony on the start line
with a whole wedding party
completing the course.
So maybe have a think about
how you can do this too
in your own niche.
Now onto the rankings.
Firstly, how much time does
creating your own brand take?
I'd say a two out of five for this one,
because you're gonna
have to put in the work.
You'll have to post online consistently
to build the audience,
keep up to date with research,
and also keep up to date with trends
so you can ride with them
instead of drowning in them.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'd give this one a three out five
because you do need some initial capital.
But once sales start rolling
in, growth can happen quickly,
and you can then reinvest that money
to fuel further expansion.
Thirdly, how easy is it
to make $100 per week?
I'd rate this four out of five stars
if you've completed steps one and two,
and five out of five if
you've achieved all three.
Once you've built hype
and people are talking about
your brand on social media,
there's no reason you can't
easily make $100 per week.
Third is my eBay store where
I buy stock from failing shops
and sell it online.
Not to toot my own horn,
but I made quite a name for
myself in the model industry
and people started asking me to help them
with their failing businesses.
With all my experience and knowledge,
I thought to myself, why not?
Before I knew it, it became a side hustle.
I remember the first time I
visited a struggling store
and offered them a lump sum
in exchange for their stock.
I then listed the items
on eBay in my spare time
and I was completely
shocked by the results.
I managed to triple my
money so I just kept going
and bought lots more failing businesses.
Before long, I ended
up with this warehouse
full of gear behind me.
Now my team just lists
these items on eBay for me.
It's become huge part of my business
and I never imagined my little side hustle
could transform into
something as big as this.
I know what you're thinking.
"But Mark, I don't have enough money
to just buy failing businesses.
How can I do this too?"
Well, here's my best advice
for getting started with eBay.
Step one is to identify
businesses run by older people.
The world has changed a lot
and the traditional methods
aren't as effective anymore.
That's just how the world is.
It just keeps on changing
and you've gotta change with
it if you want to stay on top.
Unfortunately, some older business owners
are just left in the dust.
This is where you come in.
Step two is to approach these older owners
and ask if you can try and offload
the stock they can't sell,
then list and sell it on eBay
in exchange for a commission.
This way, they get rid of their dead stock
and you can earn some extra cash.
It's a win-win.
Over time, you'll be
able to build up profits,
and this is where the game changes.
Step three is to use your profits
to start buying directly
from your own supplier.
This is a huge turning point
because you're being in control
of the products you offer,
the pricing and the customer experience.
This gives you far more
flexibility for profits
and enables you to build up a
strong reputation as a seller.
This is crucial for
scaling this side hustle
into a real business.
Okay, once again, it's time
to rank it in my categories.
Firstly, how much time does
running an eBay shop take?
Well, I'll say this is a three
out of five, if not a four,
because you don't need to come up
with any of the products or designs,
you're simply selling
someone else's stock.
If you've got things running smoothly,
then there's no reason
why you can't be selling in your sleep.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'm gonna rate this a five out of five
because you can actually
get started with $0,
especially if you're selling
stuff for a commission
like I recommended.
It's really accessible
and a great way to get stuck into business
and learn on the go.
Thirdly, how easy is it
to make $100 per week?
I'm gonna rate this a five out of five
because all you have
to do is sell 50 items
with a $2 profit on each, and boom,
you've made an extra $100 that week.
Fourth is the stock market
where I invest my money
and let it grow over time.
I'm no financial advisor,
but in my humble opinion,
this is something everyone should be doing
because without investing,
your money's losing
value due to inflation.
Over the last 60 years,
this averages out to be
a loss of 3.8% per year.
So if your money isn't growing
by more than this on its own,
then you're getting poorer by the second.
In a perfect world, you'd
have a savings account
that provides an average
return of 8 to 10% every year
so that you can both beat
inflation and earn some profit.
Unfortunately, such savings
accounts don't exist.
However, you can achieve returns like this
by investing in the stock market.
A stock is a small part of a company
and when you buy it, you
become a shareholder.
When you're a shareholder,
there are two ways you can make money.
The first way is if the
price of the stock goes up
during the time you own it,
then you can sell it
for more than you paid.
The second way is receiving dividends.
Dividends are regular
payments to shareholders.
Now, not all stocks pay dividends,
but if they do, this means
you can receive money
without ever selling your stock.
You can start investing from your phone.
My son has actually been
investing 5 pounds a day
for over a year now
on the Trading 212 app
instead of buying a
morning Starbucks coffee.
It's a bit of an experiment,
and as you can see,
that small investment is
now worth 1,783 pounds,
which is a profit of 276 pounds
or $359 for all my American subscribers.
That's a return of over 18%.
Of course, past results are no
guarantee of future returns,
but that's not bad for
a little experiment.
To set something like this up,
all you have to do is select Pies
and then click the plus button.
Now you can select whatever stocks
you want to include in your pie.
For this demonstration,
let's just pick the same
investment as my son,
this S&P 500 Index fund.
Now let's tap Add to Pie,
and then the arrow button.
Right, tap Next, and then Autoinvest.
This value projection is really awesome
as it shows you how much
money you could make
based on the historical averages.
Of course, when you invest,
you can get back less than you invested
as investments can rise and fall,
but it's still a great way to get an idea
of how much you could make based
on data-backed projections.
I mean, say we invested
250 pounds per month
for 31 years.
This says that you'll have
only invested 94,250 pounds
and your portfolio could be
worth 2.19 million pounds.
And if we expand this to 40 years,
that could give you a portfolio
worth of 8.63 million pounds.
That's over $10 million.
Now, let's rank this income
stream out of five stars
in my three core categories.
Firstly, how much time
does investing take?
I'd rate this five stars out of five
as all you have to do is
download an investment app
such as Trading 212,
deposit some money and start investing.
Since I was planning to talk
about Trading 212 anyway,
I reached out to them to
see if they'd be interested
in sponsoring this portion of the video.
They agreed and are offering a free stock
worth up to 100 pounds
to anyone that uses the code Tilbury
when they sign up and fund their account
with as little as 1 pound or euro.
Plus, you can get more free
shares by inviting your friends.
Both of you will get a free share
as long as they fund their account.
Also, don't worry if
you've opened an account
in the last 10 days.
You can still use the promo
code Tilbury in the app
and receive your free share.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'd rate this a five
stars out of five again,
as I've shown with my son's experiment
you can start with as little as a price
of a Starbucks coffee a day or even less.
Because of the way
compound interest works,
it's much better to get
started rather than later
so that time is on your side
even if you can only put aside
a little bit every month.
Thirdly, how easy is it
to make $100 per week?
This will have to be a 2.5 out of five
because it's very challenging
to make this kind of money
at the start.
As you can see by this graph,
net worth really starts to
accelerate after the first 100k.
For me, making $100 a
week from investments
is now the easiest thing
in the world, so who knows?
By the time you reach my age,
you could be making far more
than $100 a day through investing.
Fifth is my residential real estate.
I rent these out to families.
When I was younger, I wanted
to build an income source
that would constantly bring in money
even if I decided to stop working,
so I did some research
and that's when I bought
my first residential rental property.
It's actually this one
and it's in an up-and-coming area
with great transport links to London
and good local schools.
But the truth is I
regretted the investment
as soon as I bought it.
The reality was it needed
a lot more fixing up
than I'd initially thought
and I just tied up a
big amount of my money.
But I was committed now and
I needed to make it work,
so I spent every free
moment down at the house
fixing everything myself to save costs.
Now, looking back, this was hands down
one of the best decisions I've ever made.
It's over doubled in value
and along with my other properties
has given me a steady income for years.
Look, I'm not gonna lie,
getting into real estate usually takes
a big chunk of change to start,
but there is a good way to get started
without actually buying
any property yourself.
It's called deal sourcing.
This involves you sitting
at a computer finding deals
and then sending them on to
real estate investors like me
and receiving a commission.
I'm always on the lookout for great deals
and so are thousands of
other real estate investors.
So here are the three simple steps
you can take right now to start this.
Step one, educate yourself.
Learn about the local real estate market,
property values and investment strategies.
Become obsessed, watch videos
and read plenty of books.
Step two, build a network.
Connect with real estate
agents, property managers,
and other investors.
Attend local real estate
meetups and join online forums
to expand your connections.
Step three, start finding deals.
Look for undervalued
properties or motivated sellers
through online listings, auctions,
or by driving around neighborhoods.
When you find a good deal,
present it to investors in your
network for a finder's fee.
Even if you don't plan
to deal source forever,
this experience will prove invaluable
when you eventually become a
real estate investor yourself.
You'll already possess all
the necessary knowledge.
In my view, it's a win-win situation.
You're learning and
earning at the same time.
So it's time to rank this income stream.
Firstly, how much time does
residential real estate take?
This is a three out five
as it does take time to find good deals,
and if you're the investor,
you might need to put in some work
to fix up the property at the beginning.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
If you're deal sourcing,
then this is a five out of five stars
as you don't need any
money to get started.
However, if you're investing,
then you'll need a
significant amount of money
to buy the property and also maintain it.
Take it from me.
Being a landlord isn't always easy.
I remember when I dealt with
all my properties personally,
I'd get called up for
the craziest of things.
Once I even found myself
fixing a roof tile
during a major storm.
And thirdly, how easy is
it to make $100 per week?
This is a five out of five
as it's relatively easy
to make $100 a week.
If you're deal sourcing, once
you've learned the ropes,
just one finder's fee can earn
you thousands in commissions.
For investors, you can generate income
from both rental payments and
property value appreciation.
Sixth is my commercial real estate.
I rent these warehouses
to different businesses.
This one is just about
to go on the market.
This is something I explored later in life
after I'd invested in the stock market
and residential real estate,
and I recommend you do the same.
I was interested in boosting my cash flow,
and you can typically earn more per month
renting to businesses
rather than families.
However, my warehouses are
unlikely to increase in value
at the same rate as my
residential properties.
I'm gonna keep this one short
and skip to the ratings.
First, how much time does
commercial real estate take?
I'll give this a three out of five stars.
Honestly, it can be relatively hands off
once you've got the tenants in place.
However, setting it up does take time,
from finding good warehouse space
to making sure it's ready to lease out.
Once you're up and running,
it only really requires you
to manage the tenant relationship.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
This is a one out of five stars
as commercial real estate isn't cheap
and upfront costs can be high.
However, financing
options and partnerships
are often available for
this kind of investment
if you're not ready to put
in all the money yourself.
And thirdly, how easy is
it to make $100 per week?
This is a four out of five stars
as the potential is definitely there,
with most commercial leases bringing in
well above $100 per week.
Once leased, this type of real estate
can provide a strong cash flow,
but it may take a while
to reach this point
since it's a longer-term investment.
Seventh is my personal brand
where I make videos like this one
to help the next generation
grow their wealth.
As a kid, I always used
to see famous people on TV
and in the movies.
It was great entertainment,
but let's be honest,
becoming an actor yourself
seemed like an impossible dream.
You'd never think, "I'll watch
this movie, get inspired,
and then become a star."
The odds were just too slim.
However, nowadays with social media,
you don't need to become
an actor or TV show host
to become famous
as you can do it all from your smartphone
and get rich at the same time.
Having a large following on social media
has so many benefits,
like giving you a sense
of purpose and authority,
making you famous and generating income
while having the freedom
to travel whenever you want
without a boss breathing down your neck.
I'll be completely honest,
when I became a content creator
and posted my first video,
I never actually thought
about any of that stuff.
I just wanted to work with my son,
share my stories with the world,
and hopefully help some
people along the way.
It's more about legacy for
me than fame and money,
although it's really cool
when I get to meet some
of you guys in person.
But let's not beat around the bush here.
Posting these videos does
in fact generate me income
through ad revenue and sponsors,
which I invest in team
members and equipment
to produce better videos for you guys.
I was actually scrolling
through my YouTube channel
the other night reflecting
on a few of my old videos.
It was such a nice
moment for me and my son
seeing how much everything had improved.
But anyway, enough about me.
Let's discuss how you can
start posting on social media,
grow a following and
start producing an income.
Step one is research.
I know it sounds cliche,
but if you want to grow on social media,
you need to have a clear lane and message.
For example, my lane is personal
finance and side hustles,
and my message is helping
the next generation
grow their wealth.
If I just posted whatever I wanted,
let's say one day I was discussing
my passion for RC models,
the next day it was cars followed by golf
and then maybe investing,
you probably wouldn't
subscribe, would you?
And the reason for that is you
don't actually have any idea
what you're subscribing to.
So think about what you're
interested in and experienced at,
research other popular
YouTubers in that space,
and hatch a plan to put
your own spin on things.
Step two is create.
Remember a moment ago when I mentioned
how much my videos have improved
over the last few years?
Well, that's exactly
why you need to create.
I see so many people
trying to be perfectionists
and learn everything there is
to know about creating videos
before actually posting
one for themselves.
So what are you waiting for?
As long as you've done your research
and have a clear goal for
where you want to end up,
start making content
and improve as you go.
Step three is monetize.
It's all well and good
being a content creator,
but if you're not able to
make any money from it,
then it's extremely unlikely
you'll be able to continue doing it.
This is because, believe it or not,
creating content is a job
and takes more time than
you'd probably think.
And if you're not producing
an income from your efforts,
that's all time that could
be spent working a job
or building a different business.
My advice for monetizing
your social media career
would be not to worry
about the money at first
and instead focus on creating
great videos that people love.
Doing this will build a strong foundation
of returning viewers,
which is crucial for
monetizing in the future.
Once you build that audience,
there's three main ways
you can start making money.
The first way is ad revenue,
where YouTube will pay
you for those adverts
that play before, during,
and after your videos.
The second way is brand deals
where you negotiate with a brand
and get them to agree to
pay you either a flat fee,
a commission, or both.
And the third way is by creating
your own digital product
like a course or community.
Now let's rank personal brand.
Firstly, how much time does
building a personal brand take?
I'll give building a personal
brand two out of five stars
when it comes to time investment,
because when you're just starting out,
things naturally take
longer while you learn.
Even when you're an expert,
creating content takes time.
But I'm not gonna give it just a one star
as at least you can create when you want
and not when you're told to by a boss.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'm gonna give this
three out of five stars
as it really does depend.
You could work on quite a tight budget
and create videos with your iPhone
and simple editing software,
or you can go all out
and get the best camera,
hire the best editors, and so on.
Thirdly, how easy is it
to make $100 per week?
I'm gonna rate this four out of five stars
as posting videos online
is almost like building
digital real estate.
At first, there are some
requirements you need to meet
to gain access to monetization,
like having over 1,000 subscribers
and 4,000 hours of watch time.
But once you've gained access to this
and have multiple videos on your channel,
making $100 a week is very realistic.
If you wanna know what
to do with your money
every time you get paid,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there.
But don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe
if you want to grow your wealth, okay?
I'll see you over there.