If you don't wanna
be like everyone else,
then you have to make the sacrifices
others aren't willing to make.
That's what my mentor told me
when I was in my early 20s
and it stuck with me ever since.
I started out with no
qualifications and no money,
but still managed to
become a multimillionaire,
and a big part of that was down
to avoiding the seven things
I'm gonna be sharing with you today.
The first thing to avoid
is working for only money.
Imagine for a moment
that you got a boring but well-paid job.
You quickly start stacking some nice cash
as your earnings grow.
Your friends will think that
you're absolutely killing it
and your parents will
probably be pretty proud too.
However, over time, your earning potential
would start to plateau.
This is path A.
Now, imagine instead you get a challenging
but lower-paid job.
You might struggle for a couple of years
as you improve and adapt.
You may even struggle to pay the bills.
Your friends will probably
think you're falling behind
and your parents may not agree
with the path you've taken.
However, over time,
your earning potential will
start going through the roof.
This is path B.
So, what's the difference
between these two examples?
Well, path A prioritizes money early on,
whereas path B prioritizes two key things,
skills and equity.
Every self-made millionaire
I know has followed path B
as it's the only way to
build that kind of wealth.
As I mentioned, I left school
at 16 with no qualifications.
However, I immediately
went out looking for jobs
and actually got offered
more than five opportunities.
So, I had a big decision to make.
Which should I choose?
I decided to become a
carpenter's apprentice.
The pay wasn't great,
but I knew the skills I'd learn
would be extremely valuable,
so, I prioritized those.
There was no way I was gonna
get equity in the business,
but at least I was working
for more than just money.
That job taught me a lot,
and although I was forced to quit
after being relentlessly
bullied by my manager,
I still use many of those skills today
when I'm designing my bestselling brand
of radio-controlled planes
that I sell across the world.
By learning a wide range
of high-income skills,
it makes it almost impossible
for you to ever be broke again
as you become your greatest asset.
I like to think every job
I had when I was younger
added to my skillset
like a Swiss Army knife.
Nowadays, I'd recommend prioritizing
online-based high-income skills
such as copywriting,
video editing, and coding.
The demand for these
skills is only growing,
and I can speak from experience
that there is a huge skill
shortage at the moment.
Sure, there are lots of
people doing those things,
however, 99% of them are
just not up to standard.
Honestly, your competition
really isn't that tough.
Now, let's move on to
the second thing, equity.
This just means owning a
percentage of a business
so you can benefit from the profits.
My radio-controlled model brand
is a perfect example of this.
You can gain equity in
a few different ways.
The most obvious way,
and the way I did it,
was to start the business myself.
However, you can also
gain it by working for it
if you're extremely
skilled in certain areas.
This is known as sweat equity.
Lastly, you can purchase
equity in certain businesses,
although, I wouldn't
recommend this as much
unless you have the skills
that can help accelerate
that business forward.
My friend Simon Squibb
often goes around in public
telling people to start
their own businesses
or ask for equity from their boss.
While I 100% agree with the sentiment,
you need to have some
self-awareness with this.
Firstly, it's worthwhile working
for someone to gain skills
before starting a business of your own.
Secondly, you need to be realistic.
I didn't think for a moment
that I'd get equity in
the carpentry business
when I was an apprentice.
So, when you ask, make
sure you have a solid case
for why you deserve it
and how you can add value to the business
instead of just taking from it.
You need to first focus
on becoming someone worthy of equity.
The main takeaway here
is that too many people
get blinded by money,
forgetting the importance
of skills and equity.
This is the biggest trap.
The more you obsess
over earning just money,
the less you'll likely
make in the long run.
The second thing to avoid is
buying a luxury lifestyle.
Picture yourself cruising through Dubai,
sun-drenched streets in a
bright yellow Lamborghini.
You pull up to a swanky restaurant
and order a $500 fillet steak
without batting an eyelid.
How does imagining that
lifestyle make you feel?
Pretty successful, right?
Well, here's the truth.
Most people you see living this
way are far from successful.
The majority are paying for
cars that they can't afford,
taking trips to Dubai on credit cards
they'll spend five months paying off,
and ordering steaks at
Salt Bae's restaurant
that leave them with a
bill they can't handle.
These people are living a lie,
pretending to be rich
while drowning in debt.
It's all smoke and mirrors,
as it's much easier to
impress others on social media
than build real wealth.
Seeing people live these luxury
lifestyles might tempt you
to start playing the flexing game too,
as you feel like everyone is
living a better life than you.
However, this is far from the reality.
In fact, 37% of Americans can't afford
unexpected expenses over $400,
39% worry they can't pay their bills,
and 60% of American
households can't afford
to buy a new car.
Once you've made your millions,
you can buy whatever you want.
That's the point of becoming wealthy.
However, in the early days,
you can't live like a king
and build wealth at the same time.
Instead of buying depreciating items
like flashy cars, designer clothes,
and dining in expensive restaurants,
invest in assets, such as
stocks, shares, crypto,
and real estate.
These assets will increase
in value and generate income
that you can then use
to do whatever you want.
The third thing to avoid is
doing everything yourself.
You might be really great at what you do,
but no matter how hard you try,
you'll never be able to outcompete
a group of talented
people working together.
Look at anyone who's made it
big in sports or business.
If you do some digging,
you'll see they all had help.
Let's take Elon Musk as an example.
On the surface, it might appear
like he's a genius entrepreneur
who's achieved everything single-handedly.
However, that couldn't be
further from the truth.
He was part of the group
that launched PayPal.
When eBay acquired PayPal
for $1.5 billion in 2002,
these newly-wealthy tech experts
spread across the industry like a virus.
Now they're known as the PayPal Mafia,
as they've become such a powerful group.
After leaving PayPal,
they started many successful companies.
These include big names like YouTube,
Yelp, LinkedIn, and SpaceX.
They often invest in each
other's projects and give advice.
But what if you're not aiming
to launch the next billion-dollar company
and instead just want
to earn some extra money
with a side hustle?
Well, a lot of older business
owners are kind of lost
when it comes to everything tech-based
and using the internet
for their companies.
I mean, a lot of them don't even know
there's online tools for
literally everything,
whether it's managing your
team, handling invoices,
keeping track of projects,
or even building a website.
I don't blame them as back in the day,
we didn't have any of these things,
but now the younger generation
has a real advantage.
So, if these older
business owners don't know
how to do a lot of this online stuff
and they understand they can't
do everything themselves,
guess who they need?
You.
You can help them bring their businesses
into the 21st century
and make a lot of money in the process.
It's all well and good saying this,
but how could you actually do it?
Well, if you wanna give this a try,
then I'd recommend using an
all-in-one management platform.
Odoo is a great choice
as it includes the tools
I just mentioned and more
all in one place.
Here's a great example of a website
that needs a proper update.
It looks like it was
built over 10 years ago.
Let's jump on Odoo and make
something a bit more up to date.
So, I'm gonna go over here
and select the eCommerce app option.
Now let's fill this in.
I want a business website, there we go,
and I want it for my gardening business.
After this, I've got the option
to choose my color palette here,
but instead, I'm just gonna add their logo
so that Odoo just builds a palette
based on their brand colors.
Now we've got to pick a theme.
All these look pretty good,
so let's go with this one.
I can use the drag-and-drop feature
to easily edit the page
and customize the images.
They also have this cool AI
tool to help me out with words.
Let's fast-forward about 30 minutes
and I'll have something
pretty cool to show you.
(upbeat music)
Check this out.
It's way better than the
old website in my opinion.
You could make some serious cash
helping out older business owners
with all the different apps on Odoo
or even use it to manage
your own business.
I reached out to Odoo
to see if they to sponsor
this portion of the video.
They agreed and are also giving you
your first application free for life
with unlimited support and hosting.
And the cherry on top,
Odoo offers a personalized
domain name for one year.
So, if you wanna give this a try,
then check out the link
in the description.
The fourth thing to avoid
is having too many inputs.
Do you ever feel like you're being pulled
in a million different directions?
This happens with everything in life,
from side hustles to fitness training.
Everyone seems to have a different opinion
on what you should be focusing on.
It can look a little bit like this.
This is you,
and these are the people telling you
what they think you should be focusing on.
For the sake of simplicity,
let's just call them inputs.
All these inputs create hundreds
of paths you could follow,
like becoming a doctor, entrepreneur,
joining a family business,
getting a stable
nine-to-five job, traveling,
and having a family.
Let's call these your potential paths.
The sheer number of these
pathways can create something
called cognitive overload,
which is where your
brain simply can't cope
with the overwhelming amount
of information and choices.
So, what's the solution?
Well, I've always started with
my end destination in mind
and worked backwards.
Of course, I didn't know exactly
what I wanted to do in the future.
However, I had a decent idea.
I then made sure to only listen to inputs
that help me reach those targets.
The clearer your goal,
that easier it becomes
to select the right inputs
to help you achieve it.
So, limit the number
of opinions you receive
and prioritize quality over quantity.
Most people have too many
opinions being thrown at them,
but not from experts.
Cut out general opinions and
instead seek expert advice.
This could come from a mentor,
someone successful in your field,
or even educational videos
from experts like myself.
By doing this, you'll get
more valuable, focused,
and specific guidance for your end goal.
Remember, even when you
work your way backwards,
you still don't need to
know everything at once.
Fully listen and implement
what you learn from an input,
and then when you're
facing another challenge,
you can seek out more inputs
that'll help you overcome it.
If you don't do this, then
you'll get mental fatigue,
which can lead to decision paralysis
where you find yourself
unable to take action
or move forward.
Some people might even
mistake this for being lazy,
but in reality, your brain
just gets overwhelmed.
The fifth thing to avoid
is being ego driven.
Let me start by saying this,
arrogant people won't
even finish this video.
They think they already know everything,
so, why bother sticking around?
But that's exactly the problem.
Arrogance blinds you to the opportunities
that could genuinely change your life.
Ego-driven people are often
too focused on the big picture,
constantly dreaming of the end goal.
This might sound productive,
but it's a dangerous trap.
When you're always looking too far ahead,
you end up overlooking the
small but crucial steps
that lead to true success.
For example, some might be tempted
to scroll through this video
just to see all seven things
rather than sitting down
and actually absorbing
the knowledge in each one,
but by doing so, they miss
out on the valuable insights
that could fast-track their journey.
When you're too egotistical,
you start to believe that you
don't need advice from others,
especially those who
might know more than you.
You might dismiss the wisdom of people
who have already walked the
path that you're trying to take.
But here's the truth.
True wealth isn't just
about being confident.
It's about having the
humility to keep learning,
to understand that you don't know it all,
and that's where the real growth happens.
The more you learn,
the more you realize
how much you don't know.
This is called the iceberg principle.
What you know is just
the tip of the iceberg.
The massive chunk of knowledge
is underneath the surface.
That's what truly matters,
and arrogance makes you
forget that it's even there.
In short, arrogance is
a silent wealth killer.
It convinces you that
you're too good to learn,
too smart to listen,
and too important to take the small steps
that lead to greatness.
The sixth thing to avoid
is passing the blame.
One of my favorite Chinese proverbs
is the man who blames others
has a long way on his journey to go.
The man who blames
himself is halfway there.
The man who blames no
one has already arrived.
In front of me, I have two objects,
a magnifying glass and a mirror.
In life, you're gonna have to choose
to reach for either of
these on a daily basis.
You might be thinking, "Mark's gone mad."
But let me explain.
If you choose to pick
up the magnifying glass,
it gives you the ability to
hyper-focus on other people.
This is a dangerous path as
it leads to the blame game.
Look, I do kind of get it.
When anything goes wrong in life,
it's natural to wanna pass
the blame onto someone else,
anyone but yourself.
I'm sure there's been times
when you've blamed your
teacher for a test you failed,
even though you spent more
time binge-watching Netflix
than actually studying,
or maybe you passed the blame
onto the traffic for being late,
even though you left the
house 10 minutes later
than you should have.
But here's the thing,
these small instances of
blame don't stay small.
Over time, they grow into a habit
that's hard to break free from.
I'm sure you've seen
people say stuff like,
"The government hates young people,"
"The system is rigged
against people like me,"
"My boss doesn't like me,"
"I'm not rich enough to start a business,"
and, "Life didn't give me
the right opportunities."
The more you reach for
the magnifying glass,
the bigger your excuses become.
However, if you pick the mirror,
then you instead focus on the stuff
you can actually control,
your own thoughts and actions.
So, to embody the wisdom
of the Chinese proverb,
to be the person who has already arrived
at their destination,
you need to pick up the mirror,
not the magnifying glass.
The seventh thing to
avoid is staying static.
This is your comfort zone,
where you retreat seeking
safety and security.
Notice how there are
no gaps in this circle.
Almost like a self-imposed prison
with no way out and no way to grow.
If you're currently here,
then you're not alone.
According to some studies,
over half of Brits don't
leave their comfort zone,
and 45% of them are worried
that one day they might regret it.
So, what can you do to
break out of this prison?
Well, you need to expand the circle.
This can be really difficult
when our minds are conditioned
to avoid taking risks,
but it's something I
learned at an early age.
Let me show you how I did it.
When I was younger, my
comfort zone was narrow,
school, studying subjects
I wasn't good at,
like maths and English.
The traditional education
system didn't suit me.
I didn't wanna be a
banker, doctor, or lawyer.
I wanted something more hands-on.
So, I stepped out of my comfort zone
and pursued the apprenticeship
I mentioned earlier.
This created a new space for me.
But I wasn't satisfied yet.
I knew I needed more from life,
so I started experimenting
with side hustles,
which pushed me further
into unfamiliar territory.
Suddenly, the world was
full of possibilities.
The next step was clear,
starting my own business.
This was a pivotal moment
requiring a big risk, a bank loan.
It was the best decision that I ever made.
To expand my empire further,
I traveled to China in
search of a manufacturer
for my own brand of
radio-controlled models.
Despite the language
and cultural barriers,
I managed to build valuable connections.
I ran my business for many
years and enjoyed success,
but eventually I felt complacent.
My family was happy, my bank was happy,
but my mind wasn't.
I wanted more.
So, I expanded my comfort zone again
and started posting videos
on YouTube at the age of 53.
I'd seen so many people
on YouTube faking it,
so I wanted to share my
knowledge and help others
who, like me, didn't
fit the traditional path
or those who wanted to grow their wealth
and feel more secure in life.
Remember, you can expand your comfort zone
as much as you want.
This space is infinite.
But you have to claim it for yourself.
If you don't push beyond
your current boundaries,
you'll miss out on all the possibilities
that could have been yours.
If you wanna learn what to
do every time you get paid,
then I'll leave that video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe
if you want to grow your wealth, okay?
I'll see you over there.