- I want you to imagine for a moment
that you started investing in 1998.
The world's going mad for the internet.
New companies are
popping up outta nowhere,
and every investor is convinced
they found the next big thing.
So you take all your money
and invest it in a few tech stocks
just because they have
catchy dot-com names,
and for a couple of years, your
money keeps going up and up
and everyone thinks you're a genius
until the year 2000.
- [Reporter] Nothing
short of breathtaking.
A points drop never before
seen on the US markets.
Traders and investors shellshocked.
And spare a gold for Bill Gates,
the Wall Street collapse
cost the world's richest man
$1.8 billion this week alone.
- When the bubble burst,
the NASDAQ fell nearly 80%,
and only 48% of dot-com
companies managed to survive.
I watched many of my friends lose millions
within a blink of an eye,
and even though it was a
crash I'd half been expecting,
my own investment still took a hit.
The crazy part is, the internet
was the next big thing,
but even then, the overconfidence and hype
created one of the biggest
bubbles in history.
So why am I telling you all this?
Well, fast forward to today,
and I can't help but feel
that same energy again,
but this time, it's not
driven by the internet.
It's AI.
People are calling it a
once-in-a-lifetime opportunity,
and maybe they're right,
or maybe it's the same story
playing out all over again.
"History doesn't repeat, but it rhymes."
And every generation thinks
they found a new era.
But as John Templeton said,
"The four most expensive
words in investing are,
'This time it's different.'"
But is this time actually different?
Well, as over 7 million of
you have started investing
because of my videos,
I feel a responsibility
to give you my honest
take on this situation.
So before you panic, let's
take a step back and look
at the three hidden forces
behind this potential bubble,
why they matter, and what you can do
to benefit from all this mayhem.
(bold electronic music)
Right now, the fate of
the entire stock market
and your portfolio is being
decided by just seven companies.
They're called the Magnificent Seven.
These are Amazon, Microsoft, Alphabet,
Meta, Apple, Tesla, and Nvidia.
Together, they now make up
around 36% of the entire S&P 500,
and they're all locked in an arms race
to dominate artificial intelligence.
So even if you only own
one share of the S&P 500,
you're already betting on these companies.
And whether you realize it or not,
your future returns depend
on how this race plays out
because every dollar
these companies invest
sends ripples through the
whole market from chip makers
to energy companies to your index funds.
And when you see how
much they're predicted
to pour into AI this year,
you'll understand why.
Let's go one by one.
Tesla plans on spending $5
billion on autonomous driving
and xAI, which is Elon
Musk's new AI startup.
Apple, $10.7 billion to make Siri smarter.
To be honest, it's probably
gonna take more than that.
Meta, $60 billion on data
centers and the metaverse.
Google, $75 billion rebuilding
the internet with AI.
Microsoft, $80 billion funding
OpenAI and supercomputers.
And Amazon, $100 billion on AWS
to own the infrastructure
everyone else relies on.
That's a total of $330 billion
in one year.
To put that into perspective,
that's more than the entire GDP
of countries like Finland or Portugal.
All that money is going
into building the future.
Some people are even calling it
the Fourth Industrial Revolution.
I get it. This all sounds pretty exciting.
However, all of this spending seems to be
what's keeping the economy
alive at the moment,
and without it, the US might
already be in a mild recession.
So the question is, how long can it last?
Well, it doesn't seem to
be ending anytime soon.
Global AI spending is
expected to reach $500 billion
by the end of 2026, with
spending on power and resources
for electricity demand topping
$3 trillion annually by 2030.
That's how bad these companies
want to win the AI arms race.
I mean, I can see why.
The International Monetary
Fund estimates that about 60%
of jobs in the developed
world are exposed to AI.
This means they could be transformed
or replaced by automation
in the coming years.
So whoever manages to
crack this technology first
will be rewarded with a
crazy amount of power.
Mark Zuckerberg even said,
"If Meta end up misspending
$200 billion, it's worth it"
because if they move too slowly,
they're out of the competition.
But this race isn't just
between companies anymore.
It's between nations.
The US and China see AI as
the key to global dominance,
and they're both burning through billions
to make sure they're the
ones holding the reins.
For everyday investors, this
could go two different ways.
If AI delivers on its promise,
the next decade of investing
could be just like the
internet boom of the 2000s,
but if the profits don't
arrive fast enough,
the same stocks pumping up
your investment portfolio today
could drag it down tomorrow.
But where is all this money coming from?
Well, that brings us on to...
(energetic electronic music)
When I first saw what
I'm about to show you,
my mind was blown.
But before we dive in, if
you're finding this video useful
and you've been subscribed
to me for a while,
then I just wanted to let you know,
I'm working on something really exciting
that a few of you will be
able to try out for free.
It's a platform that'll
help you grow your wealth.
There'll be lots of
in-depth videos on there
about investing and side hustles,
as well as the opportunity
to ask me questions directly.
So if you'd like to get
exclusive early access
and the opportunity to
try it out for free,
then I'll leave a link
in the description below
where you can sign up to the wait list.
With that said, back to this.
It's being referred to
as the AI Money Machine.
It's the main reason I'm
starting to get worried
about the state of the AI industry.
So let's rub some of these arrows out
and walk you through how it all operates.
Intel, AMD, and Nvidia are the companies
that design the chips
that power the AI models.
OpenAI and xAI and other smaller players
are the companies that buy these chips.
Then you have Oracle and CoreWeave.
These are the data centers
who also buy these chips,
then lease out the computing
power to the AI companies.
Think of them like the middlemen.
At first glance, nothing
seems out of the ordinary,
but once you look at how these companies
actually work together, the
red flags start jumping out.
It started when investors at Microsoft
gave OpenAI $58 billion in funding.
OpenAI then paid that back to Microsoft
to use their data centers.
Microsoft then used that
money to buy Nvidia chips.
Nvidia then invested
that back into OpenAI.
Doing this allows each company
to record that flow as revenue,
which of course pushes
their stock prices up.
It's kind of like if I went out
into the woods with a friend
and paid him $1,000 to dig a hole,
then he paid me $1,000 to fill it back in.
We then both have $1,000 in revenue.
Now, if we were valued like OpenAI,
which is currently trading
at more than 40 times its revenue,
that would mean our whole
digging and filling business
would be worth over $40,000 each.
Obviously, I'm heavily
simplifying things here.
These companies aren't just
passing around the same money,
however, the idea remains the same,
and this has only been getting
crazier recently with OpenAI
announcing a deal worth
$300 billion with Oracle.
After this, Oracle said
they would spend tens of
billions on Nvidia chips.
Then Nvidia agreed to
invest up to $100 billion
back into OpenAI, but to
unlock that investment,
OpenAI has to buy more of their chips.
Nvidia are definitely
the real winners here.
Their share price is up
1600% since ChatGPT launched,
and they sell their chips to everyone.
I'm talking Microsoft, Meta, Google,
Amazon, OpenAI, and even Oracle.
Then they invest back
into the same companies
that buy its products.
This is like paying your
customers to buy your product
and could be artificially boosting
the demand for their chips.
Do you see how messy this is all getting?
Let me try and simplify it.
Nvidia sells the shovels,
Oracle provides the land,
OpenAI digs the quarry, and
they're all helping each other
to lure people into the mines,
but nobody's struck gold yet.
I mean, OpenAI is currently
valued at $500 billion,
but it's only making roughly
12 billion in revenue.
It's losing money every month.
Now, that's the main problem
I see with all of this.
AI services are just
not making enough money.
So will these AI companies
ever make the kind of profit
needed to justify their stock prices?
Well, it is possible,
as they do still have some
huge levers they can pull.
I mean, each week,
over 700 million people are using ChatGPT.
That's a huge amount of attention,
and even more importantly,
an enormous amount of
data about all of us.
Imagine when Sam Altman turns
on ads and allows companies
to use ChatGPT to recommend their products
directly inside our conversations.
It could be like nothing
we've ever seen before.
In addition to this, OpenAI
has surprisingly announced
that it will start to
allow erotica in its chats
for verified adults, which
of course is a huge industry,
not that I know anything about that.
On top of that, these AI
companies are building systems
that are aiming to undercut
the human workforce.
They're betting that once
corporations become dependent
on AI, they'd have no
choice but to keep paying
no matter the cost, and
that's when the AI companies
could hike prices sky
high and finally cash in.
So there's no doubt these
AI companies are valuable,
but much of that value
still depends on one thing,
the belief that progress
will keep accelerating,
and that leads us on to...
(dramatic electronic music)
AI has been improving at a breakneck speed
for the past couple of years.
I mean, we've gone from an
AI video that looks like this
to this.
It's funny that Will
Smith eating spaghetti
has become one of the ways we
now judge AI's improvement.
The stock market is relying heavily
on the rapid rate of
improvement to continue.
However, we're not far
off hitting something
called the data wall.
For years, AI has been
devouring every scrap
of public data available.
By 2027, it's expected to have consumed
nearly all human-generated online content.
It's like climbing a ladder in
a game of snakes and ladders.
Everyone assumes the
ladders will keep going,
but we're running out of data to climb
so we might have to start
moving square to square instead.
I mean, just think how long the data sets
that we're feeding AI have taken to build.
Centuries.
No wonder progress seems
to have been so rapid
as we've been feeding it
books, research, and data
going all the way back to the dinosaurs,
and I'm not talking about me.
If AI companies can't find a way
to scale beyond the data wall,
we could see progress slow down,
expectations collapse, and
the bubble many investors
are banking on finally bursting,
but is beating the data
wall actually possible?
Potentially.
Think about it, humans don't have to worry
about this data limit.
That's because we don't just
learn from being fed data.
We learn from interacting with the world.
I mean, if AI tried to make
this video, it couldn't.
It hasn't lived my life,
had my conversations,
or made my investing mistakes.
My perspective comes from my experience,
which is something AI can't simulate.
So in my opinion, scaling past
the data wall is possible,
but it isn't just a question of more data.
It's a question of different data.
But look, I'm not a scientist
so let's get back to
investing in the stock market.
That brings me on to...
(futuristic electronic music)
So I started this video by
comparing what's happening now
to the dot-com bubble of the late 1990s.
However, is it actually the same?
No, not entirely.
The main difference is
that these AI companies
have real utility and a
clear path to profits.
How big those profits will end
up being remains to be seen.
However, it's a much better situation
than the dot-com bubble where companies
were getting their crazy
valuations from fancy names alone.
So does that mean it's not a bubble?
Well, honestly, I still think it is.
The signs are all there.
Overvaluation, faking revenue,
geopolitical mania, and scaling limits.
However, there's no way of
telling what stage we're in.
This could be the start of
a decade of crazy investment
or closer to the end than we realize.
So what's the best thing
to do with your money?
Well, I'm not a financial advisor.
However, these are the things
I'd be focusing on if I were you.
Firstly, continuing to invest.
If we're at the start of the bubble,
then the prices we're seeing right now
could seem like bargains
in a couple of years time.
That's why it's so important
to set up an automatic investment
that leaves your account every month
and goes into a broad low-cost index fund.
I did this during the dot-com bubble,
and although my investments took a hit
when the bubble burst, I don't
regret a thing, as over time,
the market bounced back, as
historically, it always has.
The real secret is not to panic
when you portfolio goes down.
As long as you're
investing in an index fund
that tracks the overall stock market,
then continuing to invest for a crash
could be the best thing you ever do.
That's how I ended up making millions
from the dot-com bubble bursting.
But in order to do this,
you need to make sure
you're not in debt or
over-leveraging yourself.
This is exactly why my
friends lost millions
while I was able to keep investing.
The next thing I'd do is use
the link in the description
to sign up for free early access
of my new wealth building platform
so you can ask me questions directly.
I'm only joking.
But seriously, you should do it.
Secondly, focus on increasing your income.
Your income is the fuel you're
using to grow your wealth.
So if you can increase
it by getting a promotion
or starting a side hustle,
then that's gonna
supercharge your returns,
especially if you can do this
while the stock market's falling
because you'll be
picking up some bargains.
Thirdly, focus on diversification.
Putting all your money
into one type of investment
is a recipe for disaster.
The key to surviving market
bubbles is diversification.
This means spreading your money
across different types of assets.
My portfolio includes stocks, bonds,
precious metals like gold,
real estate, and even cryptocurrency.
It's also worth considering
dividend-paying stocks
as they actually perform
well during downturns
because they generate passive income
even when prices are low.
Just remember, this bubble bursting
won't be the end of the world.
If you understand situations like this,
then you won't be the one panicking,
and you'll be the one taking
advantage of the opportunities
while everyone else is
running for the exit.
If you wanna learn how to
benefit from a recession,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.