- If you are ambitious but lazy,
this video's for you.
Here's the harsh truth.
Your clock is ticking
and nothing is changing.
Yes, your head might be racing
with ideas and ambition,
but without action, the
life you've always dreamt of
will start to fade away.
Every day you wait,
the more time you waste.
And if you're not careful,
your life will start to look
a little something like this:
flat, predictable, and
totally uninspiring.
This is the reality for most people,
spending the past five
years in the same job
with maybe a couple of
pay rises if you're lucky.
You can even see after these pay rises,
the line doesn't improve that much,
and sometimes even goes down.
This is because the more people earn,
the more they tend to spend.
The worst part of all is
that this lifestyle pattern
has become normalized by society,
telling you that you are lazy
and don't have what it
takes to be successful.
But even if this has been you
for the past 2, 3, 4+ years,
it doesn't have to be you this year.
I don't believe you are lazy.
You are just trapped in a system
designed to keep you spinning
your wheels on a flat line,
convincing you that slow
progress is the only way.
So what you are feeling isn't laziness.
It's frustration with a path
that was never designed
to help you thrive.
Today's video is all about
my five-stage process
to escape this trap
and start creating some
real momentum in your life.
So, let's get to it.
(bright music)
Stage one is called stagnation,
and I'd imagine that is likely
where you are right now.
The reason you feel
like you've been thrown in at the deep end
without any preparation or guidance
is because that's exactly what's happened.
You leave school and get
your first job and that's it.
You're left to your own devices.
So you play it safe by sticking
it out in the same job,
taking zero chances.
If you stay in this stage too long,
you risk becoming a debt
slave where your income
barely keeps up with
your monthly expenses.
Right now, the national debt clock
is sitting at $36 trillion
and increasing by the second.
If this doesn't prove that
our society is built on debt,
then I don't know what will.
People are owning fewer
houses, fewer cars,
and fewer luxuries
as the trend of renting
instead of owning grows.
This isn't just happening
because times are changing.
The elite have made their plans clear
with something called the Great Reset.
This aims to shift power away from people
by depriving them of ownership
and controlling it all themselves.
Imagine the government owning your home
and then letting someone else live there
whenever you are away.
This is the future they want,
and it means escaping society's trap
will be nearly impossible.
They've sold us the lie,
that money doesn't make you happy.
This was created by the
rich to control the poor,
keeping us dependent on state pensions
that barely cover anything.
In reality, money equals freedom
and freedom equals happiness.
The rich are just gonna
keep getting richer.
So, why not just join them?
If you can recognize this stage early,
then you can take those calculated risks
to get out before it's too late.
Don't be part of the 58% of Americans
living paycheck to
paycheck, which I reckon,
will increase over the next few years.
The first action you take
is the most important.
Start by gaining full
control of your finances.
Track every dollar you spend
and be honest about what's
essential and what's a luxury.
Use this awareness to
automate your savings.
So you consistently put
money aside each month,
no matter how small the amount.
At the end of the day,
even your Xbox is smart enough
to save your game progress.
So why not save your funds?
The next stage is called Ignition.
Now, believe it or not,
more than 50% of people
never even get to this stage,
which means this is when you
might start to see a difference
between you and your friends.
At this stage, you are
doing everything you can
to break out of stagnation
but it's pretty hard
because you've got a couple of things
that are holding you back.
First is your friends.
They won't always like your new attitude
as it forces them to
either change themselves
or be left behind.
Both of these things are very painful.
So instead, they will
try to drag you back down
to their level as that's
the easier option.
I'm sure you've experienced this before.
When you tell a friend about
one of your achievements,
they don't seem that happy for you
and try to shift the conversation
to be all about them.
The second issue you are
gonna face is inflation.
Keeping all the money you save in the bank
will actually slow you
down in the long run
and create more stagnation
stages along the way.
So how does this happen?
Well, due to inflation,
the value of cash in your account
diminishes year after year.
Here's a calculator that shows
you the impact of inflation
on your savings over time.
Now, let's say you have
$5,000 in your bank account
and you're not earning any interest.
If inflation happens at
a rate of 2.5% a year,
which is pretty normal,
in 20 years, your $5,000
will still look like $5,000
in your bank account,
but it will only be able to
buy the same amount of stuff
as $3,051 could buy today.
So even though the numbers don't change,
the real value of your money shrinks
because things get more expensive.
That's why saving money in
a way that grows over time
is so important.
So now let's compare that with a scenario
where you invest your money.
So if you were to invest that same $5,000
into something like the S&P 500
and the average, a 7% annual
return adjusted for inflation,
the estimated value of
your money after 20 years
would grow to over $20,000.
However, it's important to note
that there are no guarantees.
Investment returns can go up and down
and past performance is not a
guarantee of future results.
So this really shows the power
that compounding returns
can have over time
instead of letting inflation
eat away at your hard-earned cash.
If you wanna get involved with investing,
then I'd recommend you
download the Trading 212 app
where you can invest
as little as one pound
or euro to get started.
Even if you manage to invest five pounds
or euros per day for the next few months,
it will really help you get
started with those first steps
and break out of that stagnation stage.
Since I was planning to talk
about Trading 212 anyway,
I reached out to them to
see if they'd be interested
in sponsoring this portion of the video.
They agreed and are offering
a free fractional share
worth up to 100 pounds to anyone
that uses the code TILBURY
when they create an account.
Plus, you can get more free
shares by inviting your friends.
Both of you will get a free share
as long as they fund their account.
I'll leave a link in the
description if you're interested.
Just remember only to invest
what you can afford to
and don't starve yourself of cash
as there's a lot we need
to do in the next stage.
Next is the acceleration stage.
Now, this is where you're starting
to gain some real momentum,
but what got you here won't be enough
to carry you to the next stage
unless you want to wait decades
to achieve financial freedom.
This is the time to accelerate.
You need to fully commit
to taking advantage
of current opportunities as
they won't be around forever.
At this stage, there are
three Cs that I focused on,
which helped me accelerate
my wealth dramatically:
cashflow, connections, and confidence.
Let's start with cashflow.
You need a constant supply of money
coming into your bank account
so that you can use it
to generate more wealth.
Think of cashflow as the fuel
for your financial engine.
The best way to generate cashflow
is to start a side hustle that
provides immediate income.
This doesn't have to be your
billion dollar unicorn idea.
It can be a small
service-based side hustle
with low startup costs
that meets a specific need,
whether it's offering
social media management,
video editing, or Facebook
ads to businesses,
your goal is to bring money in fast.
If I was starting over,
I would set up a service-based business
targeting other businesses,
especially during economic uncertainty.
Companies are willing to pay for anything
that boosts their profits
and positioning yourself as
someone who can deliver results
makes you indispensable.
Now, for connections.
Surrounding yourself with the right people
can have a massive impact
on your trajectory.
It's no coincidence that successful people
often associate with others
who have achieved similar
or greater success.
You know the saying, "Surround
yourself with five losers
and you'll be the sixth."
Talking to like-minded individuals
opens your eyes to new
opportunities, motivates you,
and provides valuable insights.
Make an effort to network on platforms
like Instagram or LinkedIn
and don't shy away
from reaching out to
people who inspire you.
Finally, there's confidence.
This is what separates those
who accelerate their progress
from those who stagnate.
Confidence allows you
to take calculated risks
and make bold moves that others
are too afraid to try.
Without confidence, you'll
hesitate at crucial moments
and miss out on
life-changing opportunities.
Push yourself to step
out of your comfort zone
and take risks,
whether that's pitching to a big client
or investing in a skill
that sets you apart.
The next stage is expansion.
Now you've built up some
acceleration with the three Cs,
it's time to focus on expansion.
This is where your wealth
starts to grow exponentially
as you invest in assets
that generate passive income
and appreciate over time.
The first step is
understanding the difference
between assets and liabilities,
which you've probably come across before.
Many people waste their
resources on liabilities
like expensive cars or homes
that don't generate income.
While these might look
good on the surface,
they drain your wealth over time.
Instead, try to focus on assets
that put money into your pocket
such as rental properties,
dividend-paying stocks, or useful skills
that you can use to start a side hustle.
I know you might be thinking
this sounds a bit daunting right now.
But remember, everything
in the other stages
would've built towards
this phase in your life.
You might be 8 to 10 years deep
into this plan at this point.
So although you're sat
at home now thinking,
"I'm not in a position
to do this," you will be.
There are two main approaches
you can take at this stage.
Let me explain them both.
First, diversification,
spreading your investments
across multiple asset classes
to protect your wealth
and reduce risk.
Second, high-conviction plays,
concentrating your resources
on a few investments
that you have a deep understanding of
and strong confidence in.
This approach carries more risks,
but can lead to faster and
larger returns if executed well.
Many billionaires, including
Elon Musk and Jeff Bezos,
built their wealth
by focusing a high-conviction
place like these.
The approach you choose
depends on your risk
tolerance and expertise.
If you are just starting,
diversification might
be the smarter route.
However, as you gain
experience and confidence,
high-conviction plays can help you
expand your wealth even further.
Remember, the goal at this stage
is to acquire assets that work for you.
Every dollar you invest
should have a purpose
to grow your wealth
and to move you closer
to financial freedom.
Welcome to the final stage, mastery.
This is where you've
achieved financial freedom
and can live life on your own terms.
At this level, money
is no longer a concern.
Your assets generate enough
income to cover your expenses,
fund your lifestyle,
and allow you to focus
on what truly matters.
But mastery isn't just about enjoying
the fruits of your labor
on a beach in the Maldives.
It's also about leaving a legacy
and helping others
achieve their own success.
The wealthiest people in the world,
from Warren Buffett to Oprah Winfrey,
understand the importance of giving back
and building something that
lasts beyond their lifetime.
At this stage, your focus should shift
from accumulating wealth to
managing and preserving it.
This means reinvesting
profits that maintain
and grow your portfolio, mentoring others,
and sharing the lessons
you've learned along the way.
Ultimately, mastery is
about more than just money.
It's about achieving true freedom;
freedom to spend your time as you wish,
freedom to pursue your passions,
and freedom to create a lasting
legacy that benefits others.
So are you ready to
follow this path to wealth
and take control of your financial future?
The journey won't be easy,
but if you follow these stages,
you'll unlock the life
you've always dreamed of
and end up right here at the top.
So if you wanna learn how to
invest in stocks for beginners,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe
if you want to grow your wealth, okay?
I'll see you over there.