Have you ever noticed
that the highest paid remote
jobs are often the most boring?
To be honest, you probably haven't,
as most people only talk
about the flashy ways
to make money online.
However, they often ignore the ones
that aren't considered cool.
But the problem with cool remote jobs is
that the competition is
sky high, whereas the ones
that aren't as popular
are almost always hiring
'cause people don't even know they exist.
You see, I made my millions
in the radio control model industry
as well as investing in the stock market.
Many people would consider
that pretty boring.
So I'm living proof that boring
and sometimes even nerdy
jobs pay extremely well.
That's why today I'm gonna be
revealing my top seven boring,
but high paying remote jobs.
(bright music)
First up is a short-form strategist.
Believe it or not,
if you're guilty of a
late night TikTok scroll,
then you probably know more
about short-form content
than someone with a film degree.
This job is all about
spotting viral moments
in long-form videos and then
telling editors what to cut
and what to keep in.
Don't worry, this doesn't
involve creating content yourself
or being on camera.
It's purely a strategic role.
For each of these jobs,
I'm gonna be looking at their ranking
in these five different categories,
and then we're gonna put
them head to head to see
what job comes out on top.
If you haven't already guessed,
I've decided these, like, huge
top trump cards that I used
to like playing with when I was a kid.
Let's start with the category
you guys probably care
about the most: earning power.
Now, this is a hard one
because the better you get, the
more you'll be able to earn.
Indeed.com puts a salary
range between 22 and $172,000,
but that's because there
are so many different things
you can offer as a short-form strategist.
So if you're just starting out,
I think $48,000 is a
very realistic estimate.
Next, let's dig into the beginner score.
This one is super easy to start
as you don't have to learn
how to edit or film videos.
Instead, you can just focus on coming up
with the best hooks,
learning video pacing,
and cracking the code for viral videos.
That's why in this category,
it ranks a solid nine outta 10.
Next is growth potential.
This is important when picking
a job as you want to know
that there's the ability to
earn more as you get better.
If you wanna earn closer
to those higher figures
that I mentioned earlier, then you'll need
to take a more active role
in planning out videos from scratch.
You could also look into
negotiating some kind
of view-based bonus.
So whenever a video goes viral,
you also benefit financially.
If you can prove your strategy works
and gets good results
for multiple clients,
you'll be able to charge much more
and hit much larger numbers.
That's how you take it
from $48,000 per year
to a hundred thousand plus.
For this reason, I've ranked this category
as eight out of 10.
Now for a category I'm
calling survivability.
This is all about if the job
will be around in the future.
The last thing you want
is for the job you pick
to be replaced by AI in
the next couple of years.
Luckily, content strategy is something AI
is incredibly bad at.
That's why this gets a solid 8.5 outta 10.
Finally, let's look at its freedom factor.
Look, at the end of the day,
clients don't care if
you're in Texas or Thailand.
They care about results,
and as long as you perform, you
can have the freedom to live
and work anywhere.
So it ranks 9.5 outta 10.
As this job is the first
one we've talked about,
it's currently leading in all categories,
but that won't be the
case for much longer.
(bright music)
Job number two is a customer
service coordinator.
Have you ever been on a website
and needed some help only
to be directed to an AI bot
and just frantically
typed in talk to a human?
Well, if you choose
to become a customer service coordinator,
then you'll become the
human on the other end.
Think of it like being a middleman
between bots and customers.
As far as earning power
goes, indeed.com puts this
between 52,000 and $120,000 per year.
However, it is dependent on
where the companies you work
for are based and what they're selling.
So let's go with a more
conservative estimate
of $65,000.
This one is pretty beginner-friendly
because all you need is some
great communication skills,
a knack for problem solving,
and a little bit of patience
to understand the business
you're working for.
That's why it gets a
solid eight out of 10.
Now, growth is where the potential
of this job really shines.
Every business, big or small,
needs customer service,
but not every company has the budget
or time to hire a whole team.
So this job really fills that hole.
By having one person manage the bots
and only step in when things go wrong,
it means that it's far more efficient
than bringing in, say,
five or 10 support agents.
So for these reasons, I'm
giving it a 10 outta 10.
Onto survivability.
AI can handle the basics
like password resets,
order tracking, and frequently
asked questions really well.
But as soon as things get
personal or emotional,
it all falls flat.
In fact, about 69% of UK
customers say chatbots miss tone
and frustration.
So could this change in the future?
Probably, but there's no telling how long.
What I can say is that
there's lots of money
to be made in this right now.
So I'm ranking it 7.5 out
of 10 in this category.
Now it's time for that all
important freedom factor.
To be honest, once the
bots are set up and tuned,
you can work from home, a coffee shop,
or even a weekend getaway
as long as you're available
to jump in when things go sideways.
So I'm giving it a nine out of 10.
All right, let's see how it stacks up
against job number one.
So it's already taken the
lead in two categories,
earning power and growth potential.
Let's see if the next
job can put up a fight.
(bright music)
Job number three is a
remote tech specialist.
If you've ever helped a
family member figure out how
to use Zoom or restart their iPad,
this one might be for you.
The thing is, technology
can be pretty scary
for older people, especially
older business owners
who know they need to embrace
tech but just don't know how.
That's what this job is all about.
It involves going into small businesses
and helping them set up
smoother and faster systems
with modern tools.
This role typically brings
in around $60,000 a year.
This job is pretty easy to get started
as you don't need any
official qualifications.
You'll just need to be
confident using software
and patient enough to
walk people through it.
That's where I'd struggle.
I've tried before with my mates
and I end up ripping out
what's left of my hair.
This job is just about understanding
what's slowing the business down
and then using tech to solve it.
That could mean setting up
a simple project dashboard
so they can track tasks and deadlines,
or helping 'em centralize all
their paperwork in one place.
You could use a platform
like Odoo for this
as it has over 45 easy-to-use,
beginner-friendly apps,
which help you with sales,
invoicing, projects,
contracts, and much more.
It's like a business toolbox
where all the tools
actually talk to each other.
So I'm gonna give this
one a seven out of 10
for beginner-friendliness.
Now let's look at the
all-important growth potential.
Here's the way I see it.
It's not a matter of if
these small businesses choose
to update their technology, it's when.
If they don't, then they'll
end up going bankrupt
because they won't be
able to compete with new,
more streamlined businesses.
And on top of this,
with e-invoicing now
becoming a legal requirement
across parts of Europe,
this is clearly a need
for businesses rather
than a just nice to have.
This kind of thing would be easy
to sort out using something
like the Odoo invoicing app.
So demand for this kind of
help is only gonna go up.
That's why I'm giving it
a 9.5 outta 10 for growth.
But Mark, surely this is
something AI could just take over?
Well, I see where you're coming from
as the tools are getting
better at a crazy fast rate.
However, they still need
someone to set them up
and adapt them for each business.
As a tech specialist, you
should think of AI as something
that will help make your job easier,
not replace it entirely.
So this one's getting a nine
outta 10 for survivability.
Now let's look at the freedom factor.
This job gives you
complete location freedom.
Once you've set up your client's systems,
most of your work simply
involves occasional check-ins
to ensure everything's running smoothly.
If you wanna get set up quickly,
I'd recommend using one
platform to manage everything
and Odoo is a great option.
I mentioned it earlier when
we talked about invoicing,
contracts, and task management.
Honestly, it just makes
your job way easier
as a tech specialist.
I mean, it could be simple
as using their signature app
to help small businesses send
and sign documents online
in just a few clicks.
As I've talked about it so much,
I reached out to see if they wanted
to sponsor this portion of the video.
They agreed and are giving you
your first application free
for life, as well as
unlimited support and hosting.
With Odoo, you can walk into
almost any small business
and instantly start making things better.
If you're interested, I'll
drop a link in the description
where you can get your hands
on that free first app.
I'm gonna give this one a
freedom score of nine outta 10.
Ah, nice.
So it's keeping pace with job number two
in almost every category and
smashing it in survivability.
Let's see if job number
four can step things up.
(bright music)
You might need to brace
yourself for this next job.
A funeral sales specialist.
A lot of people aren't gonna like this one
as it's quite morbid, but
the pay is far from it.
This job is all about giving
families peace of mind
by helping them plan ahead
and protect their loved
ones from future stress.
So let's get into earning power.
You'll start at around 75,000 a year.
This is the average for
pre-need funeral sales reps
in the US and top performers
regularly break 90 to $100,000
with some hitting over 106,000
when they crush targets.
So this is the highest
paying job we've had so far.
But how easy is it for
beginners to get started?
Well, there are no real
qualifications needed here.
I guess some sales
experience would be useful,
but it's not 100% needed.
I'd say it's more about
your empathy, confidence,
and the ability to navigate
emotional conversations .
Because of this, I'm gonna
give it a beginner score
of seven out of 10.
But what about growth potential?
Well, unfortunately, we're
all gonna die someday,
and funerals aren't going
out of style anytime soon.
In fact, I remember reading
in "The Washington Post"
that there are now more deaths than births
in most US counties,
showing that the demand
for end of life planning is only going up.
Look, funerals aren't cheap.
The average one costs $8,300,
and if you add extras, the
total can rise to nearly 10,000.
So with the amount of deaths going up due
to aging populations, this means that
so much money is gonna
be spent on funerals.
So growth has to be 9.5 out of 10.
Another benefit of this job
is that it's pretty AI-proof.
There's no tech about right now
that can actually comfort
a grieving person,
not in a way an actual human being can.
It hasn't lived, so how can
it possibly understand death?
The human connection is
just something technology can't replicate.
So for survivability, I'm
gonna rank it a 10 outta 10.
Now, lastly, let's talk about freedom.
Although this is a remote job,
there are far more time restrictions
than the other jobs we've covered so far.
It's not exactly a nine to
five clock-in corporate job,
but it also doesn't give you
the full on digital nomad lifestyle.
When it comes to freedom,
there's a mental aspect too,
and with this job, there's a lot
of emotional weight you have to carry.
So for that reason, I'm gonna
give it a six out of 10.
Now let's see how it stacks
up against our current leader.
Okay, wow, it's actually taken
the lead in earning power
and survivability.
So let's see if the next
one can win any categories.
(bright music)
Job number five is the
statistics validator.
Look, companies are
spending millions on ads
and you could get paid
just to make sure their
numbers aren't fake.
I mean, have you ever wondered
who actually checks those claims?
Like nine outta 10 dentists
recommend this product?
Well, that's exactly what a
statistics validator does.
They fact check these kinds
of bold marketing claims
so companies don't get sued.
Entry-level roles start
from around $40,000
and more experienced
validators can make up
to $64,000 plus bonuses
per completed audit.
To be honest, I'd say you do need
to be a bit more skilled
than all the other jobs
we've talked about so far
as you'd need a strong analytical
eye, statistic knowledge,
and attention to detail.
Saying this, you wouldn't need a degree
as all these things can be
learned on YouTube for free.
So overall, I'm gonna
give this a beginner score
of six out of 10.
However, things are looking better
when it comes to growth potential.
Companies are literally
desperate for these roles
because one wrong stat in an ad campaign
could cost them millions
of dollars in lawsuits,
and these roles will only be
more needed as time goes on.
So that's gotta be a 10 out of 10.
But what about survivability?
Well, AI can spot and scan data,
but it doesn't understand nuance, intent,
or legal risk behind how a
stat is used in marketing.
Even if it was to eventually
understand these things,
it's still very risky to let
AI check over these kinds
of claims as they're
known to make mistakes,
and that's not something
worth rolling the dice on.
So I'm gonna score this an 8.5 out of 10.
You can work remotely
for this one fully online
with standard hours and
no surprise office visits.
Of course, there is a bit
of pressure on the line here
because if you miss something,
then it could have huge
ramifications for the company.
So I'm gonna give this a freedom
factor of eight out of 10.
Okay, let's see if it managed
to win in any of the categories.
Well, it's managed to tie in
the growth potential category,
and this is definitely important
as you want your income
to be able to grow in the future.
Now I have a feeling the next one
is gonna really shake things up.
(bright music)
Job number six is a remote setter.
Have you ever seen those influencers
making thousands a month
selling courses or coaching?
They all need one thing
more than anything else.
Someone like you to fill their calendar.
That's what a remote setter does.
They slide into the DMs,
ask the right questions, figure
out if someone's a good fit,
and then pass them to the
closer to seal the deal.
So if you've ever been
told you talk too much,
then congrats 'cause that
skill might finally pay off.
The earning power for this
one is anywhere between 3000
and $7,000 per month,
and if you're hitting
targets consistently,
you can scale up to $84,000 a year
without closing a single deal yourself.
Because you're not actually being pushy
and trying to close the deal,
it's pretty beginner friendly
and a lot of companies will train you up.
That's why I'm giving this
one a score of nine out of 10.
Now let's look at growth potential.
Since most companies use
commission-based models,
if you're good, your income can grow
just as fast as the business.
So for that reason, I'm
giving this a nine out of 10,
so pretty good so far.
But how AI-proof is it?
Overall, this job is all about connection,
trust, and timing.
AI is just not there yet.
So I'm giving this a survivability rating
of 8.5 out of 10.
As for freedom, this is
where it gets interesting.
Most setter jobs are
remote, which is great,
but they're not exactly passive.
You'll be tied to your
inbox throughout the day,
especially during launch
periods or campaigns.
You're free from the office
but not from your phone.
So while there's no commute,
I'd say freedom lands
at a seven out of 10.
So how does this compare
against the last jobs?
Well, it's definitely taken the top spot
for our earning potential.
This is because it's a job
that directly brings in money
for the business and
therefore, has a clear return
on investment for the company.
They also want you to be
incentivized to keep pushing
and booking more calls.
It's also tied in the
beginner score category.
So definitely a great one
to start if you don't
have a lot of experience.
Let's see if job number seven can come in
and take a last minute win
in any of the categories.
(bright music)
Job number seven is a
content risk reviewer.
Now listen carefully, because
this job isn't for everyone.
You need to be able to
handle the consequences,
which I'll get into a little bit later.
Content reviewers can make in the region
of $80,000 per year, depending
on clients or platform size.
This isn't a super hard job.
If you binge content
and catch awkward tones
or stumble across videos and
think this shouldn't be public,
you're already halfway there.
So I'm giving this a solid
a outta 10 beginner score.
YouTube and other social
media sites make most
of their money from advertisers,
which means they need
to make sure ads don't appear on videos
that reflect badly on the brands.
This happened a few years ago
and it was called the Adpocalypse.
This is when lots of brands
pulled their advertising money
from YouTube over fears
about their ads appearing
alongside inappropriate content.
This costs YouTube lots of money.
Therefore, they need to do
everything in their power
to make sure it doesn't happen again.
This makes content risk
reviewers so powerful.
Over 500 hours of video are uploaded
to YouTube every single minute,
which adds up to a massive 720,000 hours
of new content each day.
This is only expected to grow
and more content means
more reviewers are needed.
So this is getting a nine
outta 10 for growth potential.
But surely this is something
that robots can just handle.
Well, AI can scan for
inappropriate content like stuff
that includes swear words, but
it can't detect everything.
If you need further proof,
then we've seen companies like YouTube try
to go down the AI route
and ultimately fell
and revert to human moderators
as AI just isn't up to scratch.
This is why I'm giving
it a survivability score
of 10 out of 10.
But why did I start out
by saying this job isn't for everyone?
Well, some flagged content you're asked
to review could be highly disturbing.
That's why I'm giving this
a freedom factor score
of 8.5 out of 10.
So let's have a look at
our final scoreboard.
Wow, so nearly every job
we've talked about today
has made it onto the scoreboard
for at least one category.
So it's really up to you which
area you want to prioritize.
Let me know which one you like
most in the comments below.
If you wanna know the
seven best side hustles
students can start right now,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.