- This is me in 1995, a
28-year-old self-made millionaire
who thought he had money,
figured out I've built a thriving
business empire consistent
of multiple shops and warehouses.
Then, almost overnight, the
internet made it irrelevant.
I had two choices, give up or adapt.
You know me, I wasn't about to quit,
so I threw myself into learning everything
about making money online
and like most people today,
I fell for the hype.
I tried every method out
there, and guess what?
None of them were as easy as people said.
But through trial and
error, I cracked the code
and rebuilt my businesses.
But this time with the internet
at the core of my strategy,
fast forward to today,
and making money online
isn't just important.
It's an essential thing
everyone should be doing.
That's exactly why I'm making this video.
I've spent years testing, failing,
and refining, losing
millions, making millions,
and learning what actually works.
Now with this knowledge,
I can help you avoid all the mistakes
and fast-track your success.
So if you're tired of false promises
and ready to commit for
the next six to 12 months
and build something real, this is for you.
No gimmicks, no BS, just the
process that actually works.
All right, so this is
The Online Wealth Wheel,
and whether you realize it or
not, you are already on it.
There are three main stages that define
where people are in their
journey to making money online,
plus a secret fourth stage
that only a few ever reach.
We'll discuss that one at the end.
(upbeat music)
Let's kick things off with Stage 1.
This is where everyone
starts with no side hustle,
and sadly, 55% of people
never start at all.
Inflation is making
everything more expensive.
And let's be real,
relying on a single paycheck
is more dangerous than ever.
So, if having a side hustle
is essential, why do 55%
of people still avoid it?
Because the online space is a jungle.
It's full of ads pushing proven methods
that confuse more people
than they actually help.
The key to starting the
right way is picking a method
that suits your skills,
budget, and lifestyle.
If you already have a
skill like video editing,
graphic design, coding,
or even setting up discord
servers, people pay great money
for these services and
there's no shortage of demand.
But what if you don't
have a skill to sell,
or quite simply, don't
want to deal with clients?
That's where product-based
businesses come in.
One of the best options
is setting products online
without ever holding inventory yourself.
But I'll get into this
in more detail later on.
That brings me on to...
(energetic music)
Running a failing side hustle.
I'm classing a failing side
hustle as earning less than $50
per month online,
sadly, 28% of people are trapped here.
A lot of people aren't
gonna like me saying this,
but it has to be said.
It's almost never your
side hustle that's flawed
or doesn't work,
you are most likely just not putting
enough time and effort in.
I know that could be hard to hear,
but this isn't really your fault.
It's down to something
called Shiny Object syndrome.
This is when you constantly jump
from one trendy online moneymaking method
to another without committing
and putting your absolute
all into any of them.
One week it's dropshipping,
then print on demand,
then selling books on Amazon
KDP, then trading stocks,
and then starting a social media agency.
The truth is,
all the online moneymaking
methods I just mentioned, work.
But each requires a different
level of time commitment,
and you'll never get anywhere
by jumping from one to the other.
It's like that classic diagram
of miners tirelessly digging
for gold only to give up
just before striking it rich.
Instead of pushing through,
they abandon their progress,
start fresh somewhere else,
and waste all that initial
effort repeating the cycle
over and over again.
If you get stuck in this
dangerous pattern like the 28%
of other people, then
you need to recognize it
and simply pick a method and stick to it.
Forget the idea of a perfect side hustle.
Just pick one that's easy to start
and has the potential to scale.
If you don't have a
high-income skill to sell,
then I'm gonna make this
super simple for you.
In all my years of experience, the thing
that has made me the most amount
of money online is e-commerce.
So I recommend you focus on that,
but not in the way most people do.
A lot of beginners assume starting
an online store means dealing
with inventory, suppliers,
or complex setups,
but that's not the case anymore.
That's because you can now
utilize AI-built Shopify stores.
Instead of spending weeks
setting everything up like I had
to back in the day,
you can now use a free tool
called buildyourstore.ai
to launch a fully automated store
that would normally cost
two to $300 to set up.
But this does it for free
in a matter of minutes.
You just enter your name and email,
pick a niche like fashion, tech, or pets,
and the AI chooses winning
products, designs your store,
and makes it look
professional from day one.
If you wanna go through this
process completely for free,
then just click the
link in the description
and it'll walk you through everything.
From there, it syncs
directly with Shopify,
giving you exclusive access
to a three-month Shopify
trial for only $1 per month.
But what about making sales?
Well, the biggest mistake people make
with e-commerce is giving up too soon.
Surprise, surprise.
This is probably because
they don't want to deal
with inventory or fulfillment.
That's why the free AI store
builder also walks you through
how to integrate a tool
called AutoDS, which is kind
of like the autopilot system on a plane.
It imports trending products,
updates pricing and images,
and even ships orders
directly to your customers.
This means you don't
have to touch inventory,
package anything, or deal
with supply negotiations.
You focus on driving traffic
and making sales while the
system handles the rest.
Full disclosure, AutoDS
are long-term supporters
of this channel,
but even if they weren't
sponsoring this portion
of the video, I'd still recommend them.
You can easily create a
buzz around your products
by creating videos about
'em on TikTok for free.
If you get 100K views and
just 1% of the people go
and buy your product for $10,
then that's $10,000 in revenue.
So if you are serious about breaking out
of the failing side hustle trap,
then choosing a simple automated
model like this gives you
the best chance at success.
No more bouncing between business ideas,
just commit, launch, and put
in the work to scale it up.
Stage 3 is running a
successful side hustle.
Believe it or not, only 16% of people
who start making money
online ever make more
than $50 per month.
The people in this percentile
make anywhere from $51
on the low end all the
way up to $10,000 a month.
Of course, the higher end is
what I'd consider actually successful.
So what are these 16% of
people doing differently
and how can you start
applying it to yourself?
Well, there's some clear
things that I've noticed
that separate the people
who struggle from those
who actually make money online.
And to help you get there,
I'm gonna break them
down into four key steps
that you can follow.
Step 1 is to stop trying
to appeal to everyone.
You might think cast-in a wide
net will get you more sales,
but in reality, it does the opposite.
If you try to appeal to everyone,
you'll appeal to no one.
So before you even start
promoting your store,
grab a notepad or open your Notes app
and describe your ideal customer.
How old are they?
What are their interests?
What are their struggles
and what type of content do they consume?
The clearer you are about
this, the easier it becomes
to create content that
actually grabs their attention.
Think of it like this.
It's always easier to get
one person's attention
by speaking directly to them
than it is to shout at a crowd
and hope someone listens.
Step 2 is to stay consistent.
Most people go all in for a few weeks,
fueled by a burst of motivation,
then vanish the moment they
don't see instant results.
The key is putting
consistency over perfection.
You don't need to be working 12-hour days
or waking up at 5:00 AM.
You just need small daily actions
that keep your store in front of people.
So here are some actionable
things you should focus on
every day.
Post content about your
products daily to stay visible
and consistently appear in people's feeds.
Engage with comments and
messages to build trust,
strengthen relationships,
and increase the
likelihood of conversions.
Test different product descriptions
and images since even small tweaks can
significantly impact sales.
Step 3 is to show, don't just tell.
Most people's marketing
strategies completely missed
the mark, no pun intended.
They just don't make it clear
why someone should buy
their product, for example,
let's say you are selling
custom gaming controllers.
Just posting a gameplay clip
with a link in the
description isn't enough.
People need a clear reason to buy.
Instead of assuming they'll
connect the dots themselves,
you need to show and tell.
Start by showcasing the
controller up close,
demonstrating how the extra buttons,
or as you gamers know them,
paddles and trigger
stops enhance gameplay.
Explain the real benefits
like how these features
help players react faster
and gain an edge in competitive matches.
Finally, compare it to
a standard controller
to highlight exactly why yours is better.
If customers can't
clearly see the product,
understand why it's different,
and immediately grasp
how it benefits them, they won't buy it.
It's as simple as that.
Step 4 is to build
trust with social proof.
People need proof before
they spend their money,
especially when buying from a
brand they've never heard of.
Think about it for a second.
Would you buy a fitness program
that promises insane results
but has zero before and after
photos and no testimonials?
Probably not.
If you're just starting
out, order your own product
and record an unboxing
video to show exactly
what customers will receive.
Even if you don't have sales yet,
ask friends or family to test them out
and leave honest reviews as it's better
to have some feedback than none at all.
Finally, showcase real
people using your products
instead of relying solely on stock photos.
People have been burned
by bad online purchases before.
I mean, we've all seen those situations
where the product is
nothing like the picture,
so make sure your customers know exactly
what they're getting and
why other people love it.
(upbeat music)
Now, I told you that there
was a secret stage at the end.
Well, that's Stage 4,
running an elite side hustle.
We've talked about breaking
past the early struggles
and building a solid side hustle,
but this is the level that
I estimate less than 1%
of people ever reach.
So what sets these 1% of
people apart from the rest?
One word, reinvesting.
As soon as you start making money,
put a small portion back
into your side hustle.
A lot of people think the
goal of making money is
to spend it on nice things,
but the real power of money is using it
to make even more money.
I've talked before about
investing in the stock market,
but when you are just starting out,
the best investment isn't stocks.
It's your own business.
Unlike stocks where you have to sit back
and wait, you have full control
over growing your own side hustle.
So how do you reinvest in a way
that actually helps you make more?
Well, firstly, you focus
on upgrading your tools.
In the beginning, you might
be doing everything manually,
but once you start making
sales, reinvesting in tools
that save you time can help you scale.
Secondly, you can put money
into getting more customers.
The people that make the most
money online don't just wait
for people to come to them.
They reinvest in marketing
to bring in more traffic
and sales, whether that's paying for ads,
testing new content ideas,
or working with small influencers
to get their store in front
of the right audience.
Thirdly, you can start to outsource.
Instead of trying to do everything alone,
the 1% reinvest in outsourcing small.
Now, if you are just getting started,
this might sound like
something you should worry
about later, but that's
exactly why most people
never reach this level.
This could be as simple as
paying someone on Fiverr
to design a better logo for your store,
or paying your friend to film
some social media content for you.
If you start thinking
this way early on, knowing
that your first profit should go back
into growing your side hustle,
you'll already be ahead of 99% of people
who get stuck at these lower levels.
If you're ambitious but lazy,
I'm gonna leave that video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, (finger snaps)
I'll see you over there.