If you don't want to
be like everyone else,
broke, stressed, and stuck
in a never ending cycle,
you need to focus on one thing:
making your first $10,000.
When I was 18, I had no
money and no qualifications,
but I did have big ambitions.
Instead of worrying about making millions,
I set myself the smaller,
more achievable goal of making 10K.
Now, as a self-made millionaire,
I can tell you that first $10,000
was the hardest to make.
But once I hit it, everything changed.
It wasn't just about the money.
It was about proving to myself
that making money is a skill and not luck.
Once I figured out how to make 10K once,
I knew I could do it again and again
and eventually scale it into real well.
So if I had to start from zero
and make that first
$10,000 all over again,
this is exactly how I
do it in three steps.
(slow upbeat music)
Most people make this way
harder than it needs to be.
They jump into crypto
because their friend made money from it,
or they tried day trading
because some guru promised
it would make them rich.
The problem is both these methods
need huge upfront cash
reserves and crazy luck.
These are side hustles
and they should never be seen
as your main source of income.
Instead, think of them as
tools to multiply your money.
When you are just starting out,
you need something that requires
a small amount of money to begin with
and constantly puts cash
in your pocket every day.
When you strip away all the noise,
there are only really four options.
I've tried all of these,
and take it from me,
this choice is crucial
because some options
offer higher scalability
while others are more limited.
In the same way,
some generate quick cash
while others take more time to make money.
Option one is selling in-person services.
Look, you've probably
heard of these before,
but I'm talking personal training,
delivery driving, dog walking,
nail designing, barbering, videography,
and so many more.
Although these services
sound so common and basic,
they're actually one of the
fastest ways to make money,
so don't overlook them
as they give you a way
to get paid immediately.
It's also pretty cheap to get started.
All you need is some skills
and maybe a few tools,
which means you can get up
and running very quickly.
If you choose to do this,
then please don't mess around
trying to build a website,
run ads, or make a logo.
Just get out there.
Find some customers in your local area.
Deliver the service and get paid.
I even did this when I was in my teens.
I used to walk around rich neighborhoods
and offer to wash people's cars.
I'd look out for tidy
gardens but dirty vehicles.
Now, this might sound strange.
However, I was betting
if they were obsessed
over keeping their garden tidy,
they'd also want a nice
shiny car on their driveway
to impress their neighbors.
Because these kinds of services
are limited by your local area,
it meant my demand was pretty up and down.
Some months were busy
and others I struggled to make anything.
When I was busy,
I was only able to work
with one person at a time,
which kept how much I could make in a day.
So in-person services are
great to get started with,
but you can quickly feel
like they're limiting your potential.
That brings me onto option two,
which is local products.
This is selling things
like home baked goods, handmade items,
artwork, fresh produce,
and much more.
This can be a great way to make money,
but it's not something
that happens overnight.
Unlike services where you get paid
as soon as the job's done,
selling local products takes time.
I gave this a go using some of the profits
from my car washing business.
I bought some cheap model playing parts,
then spent some time building each one up,
and then sold them to people
at the RC Flying Club,
which I went to on the weekends.
However, I quickly realized
I was putting a lot of work
in for very little money.
This was hard for me to come to terms with
because I really enjoyed building them.
Most of my earnings were being eaten up
by the cost of materials.
And on top of that,
my customer base was very limited
as there weren't enough people
willing to pay what I needed
to make it worth my time.
So selling local products can be fun
and it's definitely worth it
if you wanna make some money
from something you love.
Option three is global products.
This includes starting a clothing brand,
drop shipping, sneaker reselling,
print on-demand, and so much more.
Unlike in-person services
or local products,
going global means you have access
to a much larger customer base,
which gives you more
opportunities to make money.
You are not limited to just the
people in your town or city,
anyone anywhere can buy from you.
I was so excited about launching
my own global products.
I even flew all the way to China
to partner with a manufacturer
to produce my model airplane designs
and sell them worldwide.
Of course, you don't have to do this
if you choose to go down the drop shipping
or print on-demand routes.
However, this wasn't really
an option when I started.
If I'm honest, things started
off pretty slowly for me
because I had to keep
reinvesting my profits
back into new products to sell.
Every sale required more investment.
Once I sold 10 items,
I then needed to buy 20 more to keep up.
Instead of pocketing the profits,
my money kept getting trapped
in this endless cycle of restocking.
Ultimately, was it worth it? 100%.
However, you should only do this
if you have the patience
to wait one to three months
for everything to start kicking off.
So when this is up and running,
it is probably the most
passive laziest way
to make money that actually works.
So that brings us onto option four,
selling online services.
This option wasn't
actually possible for me
when I was younger,
but this is such an advantage nowadays.
There are so many different
online services you can offer.
These include copywriting, video editing,
thumbnail design, running ads,
social media management,
the list goes on.
Selling online services actually combines
the two biggest benefits
from the in-person services
and global products.
This is because you get the global reach,
but the profit margins of a service.
With products, you might
make 20 to 30% margin
that needs to be reinvested.
With services, you are
looking at 70 to 80% margins
that go straight into your pocket,
plus you can start making
money from day one.
Look, all of these are fantastic ways
to make $10,000 as a student,
especially these last two options.
However, if I wanted to start making money
as fast as possible,
then I'd go with option four:
selling online services.
So now we need to figure out exactly
what online service to offer.
So start by asking
yourself three questions.
What are you really good at?
What do you enjoy learning about?
And what problems do businesses
consistently struggle with?
The sweet spot is where
your answers overlap.
Most people get stuck at this stage
as they spend months or even years
trying to perfect their skill
before offering it to anyone.
That is totally backwards.
You need to start getting
real-world experience
as quickly as possible.
So start by setting your prices
under the normal market rate.
Your main aim here is to earn
and learn at the same time.
Now, let's take this one step further.
(slow upbeat music)
This is the skill pyramid
made up of four elements
that when mastered together,
transform a high income skill
into a $10,000 income.
Miss just one and you'll
stay stuck at the bottom,
working hard but never breaking through.
Element one is positioning.
You see, not all online
services are equal.
The real money is in
offering to help businesses
make more money.
That's because businesses
think about money
differently to individuals.
When a business is making $50,000 a month,
spending 2,000 to solve a
problem isn't a big deal
as long as it helps 'em make more money.
And take it from me,
they have a lot of these problems.
They need more customers.
They need better systems.
They need to stand out
from their competition.
And they need to convert
more leads into sales.
These problems never go away
and businesses are always
willing to pay to solve them.
On top of this,
some industries simply have
more money to spend than others.
And if you think about how
you can reposition yourself,
you'll start making real money faster.
Here are some ideas to get you thinking.
Instead of being a video
editor for small YouTubers,
you could edit videos for an entrepreneur
who sells a product.
If you make random thumbnails for clients,
you could instead aim to
become the main designer
for an established creator.
And if you're a copywriter,
don't write cheap articles.
Instead, focus on
optimizing landing pages.
This isn't about learning more skills,
it's about putting yourself
where the money's being made.
Element two is leverage.
You'll never make $10,000
without leveraging value over time.
Businesses don't pay for effort.
They pay for results.
If you stop charging
for the hours you work
and instead for the return
on investment you provide,
you'll instantly make more money.
Let's say you choose to run Facebook ads.
If you charge per hour,
you are stuck with a fixed rate
and the client will always
want to keep your hours low.
But if you charge based on the money
you bring in for the business,
suddenly they're not thinking about cost,
they're thinking about profit.
And when they see that your work
is directly making them money,
they'll happily pay you more for it.
The same goes for if you decide
to offer social media management.
If you just schedule posts
and reply to comments,
you are replaceable.
But if you can prove that your strategy
is bringing in more engagement,
more leads and more sales,
you become a valuable
asset, not just an expense.
Trust me, the moment you shift your pitch
from what you do to what they gain,
you'll find a lot of people
are suddenly willing to pay a lot more.
Element three is reach.
One of the biggest mistakes
people make when starting out
is thinking they always
have to chase clients,
but that's not how the
game should be played.
Right from the start,
you need to be thinking
about how to make clients come to you.
Recently, I was looking
for a graphic designer
for a specific task,
making movie-style posters.
So the first thing I
did was look on TikTok
for people who made these kinds of designs
and one person dominated
the search results.
So I reached out to him and
asked him for his prices.
He told me he was just
posting some of his designs
for fun on TikTok.
He wasn't even doing it as a side hustle,
so politely declined.
However, his videos kept
growing in popularity
and his inbox was flooded with
DMs asking to work with him.
A few weeks later,
he reached back out to me asking
how to start getting paid.
I helped him set up a proper business
and now he works for me
and many other clients.
This just goes to show that
you should always be putting
your work out there online,
even if you're just starting out
or just doing something
'cause you enjoy it.
You never know what
opportunities might come from it.
So if you edit videos,
show before and after clips
to highlight how much better
your edits make the content.
If you design thumbnails,
explain why your design got more clicks.
And if you are learning social media,
document how you are growing
an account from scratch.
Element four is automation.
95% of people that tried
to start a side hustle
or business fail before
they even really get going.
Here's why: After working
with countless copywriters,
thumbnail designers, web
developers and video editors,
I can tell you that 95% of them
promised to deliver on time,
then completely miss their deadlines.
The thing that will make
you stand out the most
isn't talent or charisma,
it's reliability.
And overlooking this
is the biggest mistake
young people make when starting out.
The people I've ended
up paying thousands to
aren't always the best at what they do,
but they're the most organized.
They never miss deadlines.
They always communicate clearly
and they make working
with them effortless.
So take it from me.
Being good at what you do is one thing,
but being reliable is what
gets you paid again and again.
So how do you do this?
Well, the most successful people I know
don't rely on memory or messy notes.
They use automation.
And if you're thinking
about making money online,
you need something to help
you keep track of everything.
That's why I recommend using a CRM system.
Odoo CRM is great.
It helps you remember who you talk to,
what they wanted,
and what you need to do next.
Instead of scrolling through emails or Dms
trying to find what the client said,
everything is in one place.
I mean, you can visualize
all your opportunities
with this call board,
which helps you see the
expected revenue at each stage
so you know where to focus your efforts.
You can also use it to schedule calls
and meetings effortlessly.
Plus with your emails, notes,
and files all in one place,
staying organized is very easy.
You can use it to easily track
your clients and projects,
so you never miss a deadline.
You can set reminders to
follow up with people,
so you always look professional.
At the end of the day,
clients don't just want someone skilled,
they want someone they can count on.
As I was planning on
talking about them anyway,
I reached out to Odoo
to see if they wanted
to sponsor this portion of the video,
and they agreed.
They also offer your first
application completely free
with unlimited support and hosting.
So if that interests you,
I'll drop a link in a description.
(slow upbeat music)
I don't care how much money you make.
Until you see at least
$1 million in your bank,
you shouldn't be wasting it.
The supercars, the designer
clothes, the nights out,
none of it matters unless
you can turn your income
into long-term wealth.
The rich see their income
as something to spend,
whereas the wealthy use
it to make more money.
So how do you do this?
Well, you need to start investing.
In front of me, I've got a risk scale
and I'm gonna walk you
through the four key areas
where I put my money starting
from the safest investments
all the way up to the highest risk plays.
Remember, I'm not a financial advisor.
I'm just sharing what's
worked for me over the years.
Let's kick this off with my
high interest savings account.
They call it a high
interest savings account,
but honestly, at 3%, I have no idea
how to get away with that name.
Now, sure, you can find better rates
if you're willing to lock your
money away for a set period
or agree to strict
deposit limits each month,
but I don't want my savings held hostage.
I want access to my money when I need it,
not stuck behind some rule
that says I can only withdraw
on the first Tuesday of every leap year.
And I know what some of you are thinking.
"Mark, this isn't really investing.
This is just holding cash."
And yeah, you've got a point.
But having some cash
on the sidelines means
you're not forced to sell
investments at the wrong time.
Imagine the market crashes
and you suddenly need
money for an emergency.
If you don't have cash saved up,
you'll have no choice but
to sell stocks at a loss
and that's the fastest way
to lock in a bad decision.
A high interest savings account
is like your financial safety net.
It's not about making big returns,
it's about having a buffer
so that when life throws
unexpected expenses at you,
you are covered without wrecking
your long-term investments.
Investment two is index funds.
Have you ever heard the saying,
"It only takes the price of a coffee a day
to become a millionaire"?
Well, that's down to index funds and ETFs.
I've made a lot of money
from simple long-term
index fund investing,
and as an added benefit,
it's extremely low maintenance.
There are tons of different
index funds and ETFs,
but the most popular buzzword, of course,
is the S&P 500, which is 503
of the top publicly traded
companies in America,
all packed into one easy investment.
Even though this is the biggest index fund
in my portfolio by percentage,
I do also invest into a
total stock market fund.
The best I found for
US investors is VTSAX,
and for the UK people is the VWRL ETF.
Additionally, I think it's important
to have some money invested
in an emerging market index fund.
The best I found in the USA is the VWO
and in the UK is the VFEM ETF.
But there are lots of other
emerging market funds available,
so it's worth having a
bit of a look around.
If all those index fund
names made you glaze over,
then here's an awesome
fact to wake you up.
The average return of the S&P 500
over the last 10 years has been over 10%,
which means if you invest just $5,
instead of buying a
coffee every single day
from the age of 18 to 67
and achieve the same return,
then you'd retire with over $1 million.
And if you don't wanna
wait until you're 67,
just invest more money.
That's what I've done for many years
and it's worked really well for me.
Investment three is individual stocks.
Now, this is where things get exciting.
Individual stocks can be a
great way to start investing,
especially with smaller amounts of money.
They allow you to get hands-on experience
with the market in a way
that index funds don't.
When I first started, I
really enjoyed picking stocks
and learning how to read
company's financial statements.
Honestly, if I hadn't actually
invested my own money,
I doubt I'd ever have been motivated
to understand how it all worked.
That's why when you're starting out,
individual stocks can feel more engaging.
Of course, they also
come with higher risk,
but if you're only
investing a small amount,
it can be a useful way to learn
how the market moves without
putting too much at stake.
Another big advantage is
that you get direct exposure
to specific companies.
With index funds,
even if a company's
performing incredibly well,
it may only make up a small
part of your portfolio.
With individual stocks,
you get to experience
those gains more directly.
But of course, this
means more ups and downs,
which is something to keep in mind.
By the way, Trading 212
are currently given away
a free fractional share
worth of up to 200 pounds
when you use the code TILBURY
and fund your account.
So if you wanna pick that up,
I'll leave the link in
the description below.
Investment four is cryptocurrency.
When Bitcoin first came out in 2009,
I, like a lot of people,
just assumed it was a scam.
I was used to investing
in real tangible assets
like property and stocks,
things backed by actual companies.
The idea of some digital currency
with no one in charge
seemed way too risky.
But as time went on, I
started paying more attention.
By early 2019, I decided
to dip my toes in.
And over the last few years,
I've been steadily buying
more Bitcoin and Ethereum.
Looking back, it's been a solid move
and it's made me a decent amount of money.
Now, I won't deny that altcoins
and meme coins can make
people crazy returns,
but they're also way riskier.
For every person who makes a fortune,
there's plenty who lose it just as fast.
These days, I'd say I'm a
lot more bullish on crypto,
but I'm still playing it smart,
building my position slowly,
dollar cost averaging,
and making sure I'm not just
jumping in at bad prices.
Of course, crypto is super volatile,
and unlike any investment,
it carries risks.
That's why it's important
to do your own research
and only invest what
you can afford to lose.
If you're ready to learn how to invest
in everything I just talked about,
then I'll leave that video right up there.
But don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe
if you want to grow your wealth, okay?
I'll see you over there.