- Let me tell you something
that will change your life
if you let it sink in.
The richest people in the
world are 75% entrepreneurs,
15% investors, 7% inheritors of wealth,
3% athletes, entertainers and artists,
0% employees who just earn a salary.
So if you wanna know how to
manage your money like the 1%,
you have to understand
what those first four
categories have in common.
So let's think about it.
Entrepreneurs own businesses,
investors own assets,
rich kids own trusts.
Finally, athletes, entertainers
and artists own rare skills.
So it's clear if you don't own something,
you are what's owned.
That's the secret most people miss.
So how can you start
owning things like the 1%?
Well, you need to follow
the 25-15-50-10 rule.
I designed this rule so that anyone,
no matter what their income,
can manage their money like the top 1%,
because the truth is it's not
about how much money you make,
it's about how you manage what you make.
I'm not just some YouTuber.
I've actually used this rule for decades,
and it's enabled me to
become a multimillionaire,
even though I started out
with no money and no qualifications.
So let's get into it.
(smooth jazz music)
The first 25% of your income
should be going towards growth.
This is the 25% that works for you.
By growth, I don't mean some
kind of mindset nonsense
about growing as a person
with the power of meditation.
I mean using this money to buy things
that increase in value.
You see, when most people
get their paycheck,
they pay the bills and then blow the rest
on useless things they
don't even remember buying.
This is exactly why 99%
of people are trapped
owning nothing of value.
The truth is, this is all by design.
The system wants us rich for a week,
then skint by the end of the month
waiting for the next payday,
so we've got no breathing room
and then we're forced to work even harder
next month just to keep up.
This is effectively modern day slavery.
Just think about it.
Slaves used to work every day with no pay,
but they got free food,
shelter, and water.
Today, people work nearly
every day and get paid.
However, their money is mostly spent
on food, shelter, and water.
The only thing that has changed
is the illusion of freedom.
Once you understand this,
you can start fighting back
by taking that first 25% of your income
and putting it straight into assets.
This is anything that
grows in value over time
and puts money in your pocket.
The idea is that while you're out working,
these assets that you
own are working for you
in the background.
Eventually, these assets
could even make you more money
than your day job.
You might think you
don't have enough money
to invest in assets.
However you need to find the money,
because the sooner you start, the better.
Let me show you something
that will blow your mind.
This is Billy.
He started investing $200
a month at 20 years old,
and this is Phil.
He start until he was 30, but to catch up,
he invested $300 a month.
Now, let's fast forward it
to when they reached 60,
and they both stopped investing.
Now I'm gonna give Phil a walking stick
and I'm gonna give Billy some glasses.
Right, that's better.
Now let's add up how much each one saved.
Billy put in $200 per month for 40 years,
so that's a total of $96,000.
However, Phil put in $300
per month for 30 years,
which is a total of $108,000.
So Phil ended up with more money, right,
because he saved more each month.
Well, not exactly
because they were investing
instead of just saving.
If we assume an average
annual return of 10%,
which is the average return of the S&P 500
over the last 100 years,
then the numbers start to
look a little bit different.
Fuel's investment will be worth $678,146.
Not bad.
Whereas Billy's investment would be worth
a staggering $1,264,816.
How crazy is that?
Billy invested $12,000 less,
but ended up with nearly $600,000 more
all because he started earlier.
That's the power of compound growth.
That's why you should start
now, even if it's small,
because waiting will cost
you more than you think.
But how can you actually get started?
Well, step one is to
select your growth assets.
There are loads of ways
to grow your money,
but not all of them carry
the same risk or reward.
So I like to think of them as a scale
from relatively safe and steady
to high risk, high reward.
At the lower risk end,
we've got index funds.
Honestly, this is where
most people should start.
You are not trying to pick winners.
You are just buying a
slice of the whole market,
like the S&P 500 I mentioned before.
You don't need to check
charts or time the market.
You just let it sit there
and grow quietly in the background.
Then there's real estate.
That could be rental property
if you've got the money
or REITs if you haven't.
REITs lets you invest in real estate
without buying a property.
It's kind of like buying a
small share in a building
with a bunch of other people.
In the middle is skills.
Learning a skill that makes
you money is hands down
the fastest return on
investment you'll ever see.
I'm talking about things like
copywriting, editing, sales,
coding, anything you can
actually use to bring in income.
Unlike stocks or property, no
one can take it away from you.
However, it does take more time to learn,
and that's why it's
higher up the risk scale
than the other two.
Further up, we've got online businesses,
stuff like dropshipping and
selling digital products.
These can pay off big, but
they take a lot of effort
and you've gotta be
ready to fail a few times
before you find your.
Then we get to individual stocks.
I know it's tempting to try
and pick the next Tesla,
but unless you've done your homework
and you really know what you're doing,
you're basically just guessing.
So if you're gonna do it
without learning the specifics,
keep it small and treat it like a hobby,
not your main strategy,
and right up the top is
alternative investments.
I'm talking Bitcoin, Ethereum, NFTs,
gold, wine, sneakers, you name it.
Can you make money with these? Absolutely.
Can you lose it overnight?
Also, absolutely.
I've played around with some of these,
but I never risk more
than I'm willing to lose.
These are your moonshots, fun to try,
but not where you build long-term wealth.
So if I were you, I'd start with the stuff
that actually builds a foundation,
which are index funds
and high income skills.
Then as you grow more confident,
you can start dabbling with the rest.
So now you know what to invest in.
Now we've gotta talk about how to invest,
because if you're doing it
through the wrong kind of account,
you could be handing over thousands
in unnecessary tax
without even realizing it.
That's why step two is to set
up tax-advantaged accounts.
Right, let me show you the smart way
to legally save as much money as possible.
Before we dive in, remember,
I'm not a financial advisor.
I'm just sharing what I've
personally done over the years.
Okay, let's start with the UK.
One of the best options is
the stocks and shares ISA.
You can invest up to 20,000 pounds a year
and anything you earn is tax free.
You can set one up on
platforms like Trading 212.
All you have to do is select
the stocks and shares ISA
when you sign up.
Since I was planning to talk
about Trading 212 anyway,
I reached out to see
if they'd be interested
in sponsoring this portion of the video.
They agreed, and are also giving away
a free fractional share
worth up to a hundred pound
to anyone that uses the code tilbury
when they create an account.
You can also invite your friends,
and once they fund their accounts,
you'll both get a free fractional share.
If you are working a nine to five,
you've probably got access
to a workplace pension.
Usually you'll put in 5%
and your employer will match with 3%.
That's basically free money.
You don't pay any tax
on the money it earns
while it's growing.
You only pay tax when
you take it out later on.
If you're in the US, your
setup's a little bit different.
The Roth IRA is one of the
best accounts you can open.
You invest money you've
already paid tax on,
but every penny it earns
grows completely tax free,
and when you retire, you can
take it out with zero tax.
The limit on this account is $7,000 a year
if you're under 50.
Even billionaires use this account.
Peter Thiel, one of
the guys behind PayPal,
reportedly turned his Roth
IRA into over $5 billion.
He did this by investing
in early stage high growth companies,
including PayPal and Facebook,
which then increased value significantly.
Then there's the 401k,
which is basically the
US version of a pension.
The money you put in comes out
of your paycheck before tax.
It also grows over time
without being taxed while it's invested,
and if your employer offers
a match, definitely take it.
Now, I know a lot of you
aren't in the UK or USA,
so here's a list of all
the tax advantage accounts
I could find.
Hopefully you can find
an account in this list
that lets you take advantage
of the tax savings your
country offers you.
The problem is lots of people
open up these accounts,
put their money in every month
and don't actually invest in anything.
That brings us onto step three,
actually start investing.
Alright, so now you've
picked your growth assets
and you've set up your account.
Whether you're on Trading 212,
Vanguard or something else,
is try to actually put your money to work.
The best thing you can do
is set up a monthly transfer
that goes straight from your bank account
into your investment
platform, ideally on payday.
That way you never even see the money
sitting in your account and
get tempted to spend it.
Once it lands, you don't need
to mess about with charts
or try to time the market.
Just look for some index funds.
One of the most popular methods is
to build a three fund portfolio.
The first fund is normally
a US stock index fund,
which basically invests in
lots of US-based companies
like Apple and Amazon for example.
The second fund is an
international stock index fund,
which is similar to the US-based one,
but instead covers
companies outside the US,
and the final fund is
something called a bond fund,
which helps provide stability
as they're generally
less volatile than stocks
and can help smooth out the
ups and downs of the market.
Let me show you how to
set something like this up
on Trading 212.
If you haven't already signed up,
then I'll leave a link in the description.
If you've already signed
up within the last 10 days,
you can head over to the promo
code section of Trading 212
and enter the code Tilbury
to get a free fractional share
worth up to a hundred pound.
This is a nice boost to get
you started with investing.
Then go over to pies and
then click the plus icon.
Now you can select
whatever stocks you want
to include in your pie.
For our US stock market fund,
let's search for the S&P 500.
This Vanguard one should do nicely.
If you're based in the
US, then you can also pick
the Vanguard Total Stock Market Index Fund
known as the VTSAX.
This fund is like owning a tiny piece
of 500 of the biggest most
famous companies in America
like Apple, Amazon, and Coca-Cola.
By the way, look out for
the terms accumulation
or distribution in the brackets.
Personally, I always go with accumulation
as it reinvests your dividends
back into the stock automatically.
Then let's go and search for our next one,
which is our international fund.
For this, let's select
iShares, MSCI World,
UCITS ETF with the ticker
IWDA and tap Add to pie.
This fund is like having
a collection of companies
from all around the world.
It includes big businesses in places
like Europe, Japan, and Canada.
Now for our bond fund,
let's search for iShares USD
treasury bonds, 7 to 10 years,
UCITS ETF with the ticker
IBTM and tap Add to pie.
This fund is like lending
money to the US government.
They promised to pay you
back with a little extra,
which helps you keep your
money safe and steady
even if stocks go up and down.
Right, now those are added,
we can click the arrow
to go to the next step.
On this page, you can adjust
the percentage allocation
of your money to each fund.
If you go with an aggressive approach,
this involves investing more in stocks,
which can grow faster, but
can also go up and down a lot.
For example, you might
choose an investment mix
where 90% of your money is in stocks
and only 10% is in bonds.
This set up is the
potential for big returns,
but also comes with sharp ups
and downs in the short term.
If you prefer a slightly less risk
but still want a chance for high returns,
then a slightly less aggressive approach
might suit you better
with around 80% in
stocks and 20% in bonds.
Don't get put off by the terms aggressive.
It's all down to your age.
As a general rule of thumb,
the older you are, the
more bonds you should have,
so let's make the S&P 500 60%,
the iShares world fund
30% and the bond fund 10%
and click Next and then Auto invests.
This value projection is really awesome
as it shows you how much
money you could make
based on historical averages.
Of course, when you invest,
you can get back less than you invested
as investments can rise and fall,
but it's still a great way to get an idea
of how much you could make
based on data back projections.
Once your investing is
automated, your job is simple,
stop fiddling and go and make more money,
because the truth is the people
who build wealth aren't the ones
picking the fanciest stocks.
They're the ones consistently
putting in more over time.
That means your focus should now be
on increasing your income
so you can increase your investments.
This is where the skill building
I talked about in step one
really starts to come into play.
If you haven't yet,
learn something valuable.
Do it as a side hustle,
bring in more cash,
then feed it straight back
into your investments.
(smooth jazz music)
The next 15% of your income
should be going towards stability.
This is the 15% that
keeps you in the game.
A lot of people don't realize
that not all your money should be thrown
into growth investments or spent.
Some of it needs to be set
aside to protect your progress.
I wish someone had told me
that when I was younger,
'cause I had to learn it the hard way.
I didn't grow up around money,
so when I turned 18 and
needed a car to get to work,
I didn't have any savings set aside,
so I did what most people do.
I took out a loan
and bought myself a solid
little German whip, a VW Golf.
I even got a new stereo with
the extra cash the bank gave me
and for about three months
I felt like I was on top of the world.
Then outta nowhere, the engine blew up.
I had no backup, no safety
net, and no clue what to do,
and on top of all this, if
I didn't get the car fixed,
I'd lose my job.
So I borrowed even more,
which piled on more debt,
more pressure and more stress.
To me, that car didn't just
break down, it broke my finances
and it set me back a whole year.
If I just had 15% tucked
away for stability,
I'd have been in a completely
different position.
Most people don't have a money problem.
They have a stability problem.
One unexpected bill,
and it all falls apart.
Even if you are investing,
you'd be forced to sell your
investments at a bad time,
which may lead to a loss.
That's why you need a margin
for error built into your life.
Let's get into how you do it.
Step one is to calculate
your stability fund.
To do this, you first need to
list out your core expenses.
These are things like your groceries,
rent, utilities, transportation,
and any essential services
like your internet connection,
which you might need for
work, not for Netflix.
All of those things combined
should give you a total.
That number is called
your monthly baseline.
Let's say that adds up
to $1,500 per month.
Now take that number,
multiply it by five months.
This will equal the ideal stability fund
that you should be aiming to save.
So in this example, that should be $7,500.
So each month when you get your paycheck,
15% of your wages should be going
towards building up this figure.
You might be thinking
this is quite extreme,
and I admit it is on
the more cautious side.
However, I know from
experience that when life hits,
it usually comes all at
once without warning.
So if you only have a
couple of months saved up,
then you won't be as bulletproof.
Step two is to store it correctly.
Now that you've worked
out your stability fund,
don't make the mistake of
parking it in the wrong place
because where you store this
money is just as important
as having it in the first
place, and for that reason,
I've got three rules I always stick to.
Firstly, it must be easy to access.
This money should be
available within 24 hours max,
so don't lock it up in some account
that penalizes you for withdrawing early
or won't let you touch it for five years
in return for a bit more interest.
I've seen people lose their jobs
and still not be able to
access their stability fund.
That defeats the whole point.
When things go wrong, you need speed,
not some nonsense waiting period.
Secondly, it must be zero risk.
This is not money you invest,
gamble or chase returns with.
Whatever you do, and I
mean whatever you do,
do not put your emergency
fund into the stock market,
not even the safe stuff,
because when an emergency
hits, the market might be down.
The same goes for crypto, long-term bonds,
or anything else that's
meant to grow over years.
Thirdly, it must always earn.
Although this isn't your growth pot,
that doesn't mean it should sit
in a dead end account doing nothing.
You want it somewhere that
earns a bit while it waits
without any risk.
This is because if you leave it somewhere
with zero interest, then it
will be eaten away by inflation
as money gets less valuable over time.
That's where high yield
savings accounts come in.
As I'm filming this video,
you can get savings accounts
with 4 to 5% interest rates
and with no penalties if
you need to dip into it.
I'll leave some banks in the description.
I'd recommend checking out SoFi,
Ally, and Marcus by Goldman Sachs,
as they're offering decent rates
and they're FDIC insured
so your money's safe.
Step three is to stack it quickly.
Most people think it takes years
to scrape together a
decent stability fund,
but if you play it smart,
it doesn't need to take
anywhere near that long.
When I was building up my savings,
I used three tactics that
stacked on top of each other.
Using them all together
help me really accelerate
how fast I could save.
Tactic one is called the paycheck sweep.
This is when you take 15% of
your income the second it lands
and move it straight
into your emergency fund.
You can automate this with a direct debit
or scheduled transfer so
it's completely hands off
just like we did with the
25% that goes towards growth.
Tactic two is the replacement promise.
This is a promise you make to yourself
that if you dip into your stability fund,
you immediately replace it.
Let's say you knock off your wing mirror
and it costs $250 to fix, that's fine.
That's what the fund is for,
but the next time you get paid,
you top that $250 straight
back up like it was never gone.
Tactic three is the save by spending hack.
This one might sound a little bit crazy,
but you can do it by using roundup apps.
These round every purchase
up to the nearest dollar
and drop the difference into your savings.
So if you spend $3.60, it rounds up to $4
and puts that 40 cents away.
It sounds small but it adds up fast
and you won't even notice it.
The other way to do
this is with cash back.
So if you're using a cash back credit card
and paying it off in full every month,
then take those rewards
and put them straight
into your stability fund.
Once your stability fund is fully stocked,
you've got two options.
You can either roll that money into growth
or you can shift it into the final 10%,
which we'll talk about later.
(smooth jazz music)
The next 50% of your
income should be going
towards your essentials.
This is the 50% that
feed you, not your ego.
Surprisingly, over 60% of Americans
earning over $100,000 a year
still live paycheck to paycheck
as most are too caught
up in trying to look rich
instead of actually becoming rich.
This shows that you can
be on a great salary
and still feel broke every month,
because it's not about how much you earn,
it's about how much you waste.
Let me show you what I mean.
This was me age 20, and that's my mate.
On the surface, he looked
like he had everything.
Designer shirt, an expensive watch,
and was always outspending.
I was the opposite, baggy top,
cheap watch, just the basics.
Sure, my fashion sense
could have been better.
I could have at least picked up
some inexpensive smart clothes,
but I was young, so cut me a bit of slack,
but here's what people didn't see.
He had $43 and 20 cents in his account
and a few credit card payments overdue,
whereas I had $1,000 plus
quietly sitting in investments
and a decent stability fund.
I'd learned from my experience
with my car loan disaster,
and I'd worked extremely hard
to build my money back up,
which meant cutting out
any unnecessary spending
and looking like this.
Although this might not seem like a lot,
remember, money was worth
a lot more back then.
This $1,000 was a start,
and that's the part most people miss.
Wealth isn't what you see,
it's what you don't see.
I get it though.
It's easy to justify the upgrades
by saying things like, I need a safer car.
This new house is closer to work,
and I deserve a nice meal out,
but that's exactly how
lifestyle creep starts,
so how can you keep this under control?
Well, step one is to get
clear on your essentials.
A lot of people aren't gonna like this one
because what many people
consider essentials nowadays
are actually just luxuries.
Essentials are the things
that keep you alive and functioning.
That means your rent
or mortgage, groceries,
utilities, transport,
insurance, and clothes.
Not the latest designer drops.
Just what you absolutely need.
Now, let's talk about what doesn't count.
Takeout isn't essential.
Neither is the Amazon
subscription you forgot about.
The gym you haven't visited since January.
All the stack of streaming services
you keep meaning the cancel,
and the list goes on.
If you are using a gym,
that's a different story,
but so many people sign up
for stuff they never use.
That's why one of the
easiest things you can do
to free up money is to go
through your bank statements
and cancel anything you're not using.
Just think to yourself,
if it's not helping you
live, work or stay healthy,
it probably doesn't belong in your 50%,
so why do I recommend capping it at 50%?
Well, because the average
person is already spending
60 to 70% of their income on
what they think are essentials,
so blocking in your lifestyle at 50%,
it forces you to actually
eliminate what you don't need.
It also changes your mindset
from wanting to spend
more of what you earn
to wanting to earn more
and increase your income,
which is always something
you should be doing.
Step two is to shrink
the two key categories.
So many people talk about
cutting out the little expenses
like Starbucks coffee.
Honestly, I'm guilty
of saying this myself.
However, if you wanna
make the biggest impact,
then you first need to focus
on the two key categories.
Let's start with housing.
For most people, this
is the biggest expense,
but it doesn't have to
grow with your income.
Always renegotiate your
rent when the lease is up.
Most landlords would rather keep a tenant
than go through the hassle of listing,
cleaning and showing the place again.
Even a small reduction or
freeze can save you thousands.
If you wanna go further,
think about house hacking.
That could mean renting out a spare room,
splitting a place with mates,
or even moving back with your parents
while you build your buffer.
If you can manage to limit house
into half of your essentials fund,
then that's a pretty good place to be.
Now, let's talk about transport.
Car payments are one of
the biggest wealth killers.
People lease brand new cars
for the monthly status here
and end up paying for years
on a depreciating liability.
That's why I always recommend
buying used, reliable cars
that have seen the majority
of their depreciation
at least until your income
can support a nicer car.
By that I don't mean if you
can just about afford it.
It should be under half
of your essentials fund.
In walkable or city areas,
you could even consider
getting rid of the car entirely
as it can free up hundreds
of dollars per month,
because it's not just the
car payments you save,
but also the insurance,
maintenance, and parking charges,
all added up, this can be a big saving.
Once you've got those
two areas under control,
that brings me onto step three.
Use rules, not willpower.
When you're tired, stressed
or even just bored,
your willpower disappears,
and that's exactly why the
top 1% don't rely on it.
Instead, they build systems
that make the right choices automatically.
When I was building my wealth,
I had a simple system
that kept me on track.
Every time I was tempted to buy something
and wasn't sure if it was essential,
I'd run it through a few key questions.
These questions stop me from
buying things I didn't need
and help me stay focused
on the bigger goal.
So firstly, ask yourself,
is this an impulse purchase?
If the answer is no, then buy it.
It's likely something
you've been thinking about for a while,
and if it fits into the
essential categories
we discussed earlier,
then it's a no-brainer.
However, if the answer is yes,
then it is time to use the seven day rule.
The trip behind this is
pausing for seven days
before you buy anything.
Then after those seven days are up,
ask yourself again if you still want it.
Most of the time the answer will be no.
That's the funny thing
about waiting seven days.
You often forget all about it
as the excitement has faded
and it wasn't that
important to begin with.
But if after seven days you still want it,
it is time for the next question.
Are you buying for the brand or the value?
If the answer is the
brand, then don't buy it.
You are likely being drawn
in by great marketing.
If it's an essential,
then there will be an
unbranded alternative
that will do the job just
as well, if not better.
This is where most people mess up.
Wealthy people don't throw money at brands
because they like the marketing.
They really think about the value.
So what does value really mean?
Well, if you buy a $60 pair of boots
and wear them a hundred times,
that's 60 cents per wear.
Good value.
But if you buy a $200
pair of designer trainers
and wear them twice, that's
a hundred dollars per wear,
and going too cheap isn't smart either.
I mean, a $5 shirt that falls apart
in the wash is still a waste of money.
So don't chase brands, chase quality.
So if you answered value,
that brings us onto the final question,
will this improve your life?
If the answer is yes,
a conscious intentional
purchase, go ahead.
But if the answer's no,
it's probably just about
impressing someone,
killing boredom or chasing a dopamine hit.
It's not worth your money.
Once you go through this
process a couple of times,
you'll be able to decide
if something's worth buying or not
without even consciously
thinking about the questions.
They just get your mind
working in the right way.
Remember, it isn't about being tight,
it's about being intentional.
(smooth jazz music)
The last 10% of your income
should go towards rewards.
This is the 10% that keeps you sane.
Let's be honest, money
isn't just about growth,
stability and essentials.
You're allowed to enjoy it too.
Most people skip this entirely
and then wonder why
saving feels so pointless.
As I've gotten older,
I've realized it's the
little things that refuel you
and remind you
why you're doing all this
boring money discipline stuff
in the first place.
This is backed up by the facts.
92% of people say they overspend
after intensive saving sprints
because saving without joy starts
to feel like a punishment very quickly,
and that's exactly why this
10% exists, not as an excuse.
It's a strategy, kind of
like having a cheap meal.
It's a thing
that makes your whole
financial diet comfortable
and most importantly sustainable.
But to maximize its impact,
you have to be strategic
with how you use it.
So step one is to make it guilt free.
To make something guilt free,
you have to see the value in it.
The truth is you can spend
your 10% on whatever you like.
However, some categories are
more valuable than others,
which should make them more guilt free.
The first category is vacations,
such as trips away or
just weekend getaways.
This is valuable
because you are buying
memories that last forever.
It's also a great way to de-stress.
When I was building up my
businesses in my younger years,
I completely ignored the
importance of vacations,
which led me to becoming very sick.
The doctors diagnosed me
with stress-induced shingles.
They recommended I took a vacation,
and that's when I went on
my first ever ski trip.
I had a great time.
Since then, I've made it a priority
to take a vacation every year.
Instead of seeing it as
a waste of time or money,
I now see it as an investment in my health
because it helps me stay
sharp and more importantly,
prevents me from burning out again.
Next is hobbies.
This could be painting,
gaming, photography,
fly a model aircraft, the list goes on.
This is valuable as it
keeps you passionate.
You don't always do
what you love for work,
so by doing it in your spare time,
it helps keep your spirits up
so you can work harder for longer.
Next is nights out.
Dinner, concerts and experiences.
This is another thing I
ignored in my early years,
and it was a big mistake
as I ended up losing most of my friends.
Having a strong social
network is so important,
especially nowadays.
Finally, we have gifts.
Now, I'm not talking about for yourself,
but for your loved ones.
This is another one I overlooked.
You can see how most of the
stuff I teach in these videos
comes from me learning from my mistakes.
Back when I was focused
on chasing my goals,
building businesses and
growing investments,
I often forgot birthdays
and special occasions.
I was so locked in on the future
that I overlooked what
mattered in the present.
The truth is I never really cared much
about receiving gifts.
There's not much I wanted,
but it wasn't until I married my wife
and we started exchanging
anniversary gifts
that I finally understood.
Gifts aren't about the item.
They're about the thought, the connection,
and the relationships they strengthen.
Step two is to preload the fund.
I would recommend opening
a separate bank account
and call it your joy jar.
This doesn't have to be with a new bank.
You can actually have
multiple current accounts
with the same bank
and have them all appear
on your mobile banking app,
which makes things very simple.
Then set up an automatic transfer
of 10% of whatever you
make to be deposited
into this account every single month.
So if you make $2,000, send 200.
If you make 10,000, send 1,000.
It doesn't matter how much it is.
The percentage is what
keeps it sustainable.
Just make sure you don't cheat.
You can't just top the
account up from growth,
stability, or essentials when it gets low.
If you hit zero, you have
to wait until next month.
When you know this fund money is limited,
you look to maximize it
in the best possible way.
This is exactly how you protect your goals
without feeling like you're missing out
every time your friends suggest dinner
or you pass something in a
shop that you really love.
Step three is to prioritize experiences.
If you don't have a
particularly large joy jar
at the moment, please
prioritize experiences
above anything else.
People always say to me in the comments,
what are you saving for?
Bro's gonna die with all
his money, and I get it.
From the outside, it might
look like I'm depriving myself,
but I'm really not.
I just spend differently to most people.
I don't need a garage full of cars
or shelves full of designer gear.
That stuff might look rich,
but it doesn't feel rich to me.
My 10% goes on things
I'll actually remember,
such as a ski trip with my wife,
a great day out at Universal
Studios with my son,
meeting you guys in New York,
and a weekend away golfing with my mates.
So there you have it, the
complete 25-15-50-10 rule.
If you wanna know how to
make $10,000 as a student,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.