I want you to imagine
that you suddenly became rich overnight.
Maybe one of your
investments went to the moon,
a side hustle you started took off,
you got a large inheritance,
or you won the lottery.
Believe it or not, many
of you will find yourself
in one of these scenarios,
so this video was recommended
to you for a reason.
I mean, let's take the
most unlikely option:
winning the lottery.
This channel's had over 1.5 billion views.
Statistically, that's
enough that a few of you
have already won the
jackpot on the lottery,
and the odds say
at least a couple more
of you watching right now
will win in the future.
So that's a good thing, right?
Well, actually, when
you suddenly get rich,
you're far more likely to
lose friends and family,
have a greater risk of substance abuse,
and finally, divorce.
Most people who get rich fast
have never actually built wealth before
and have absolutely no idea
how to manage everything.
So here are the seven
things you need to do
when you suddenly get rich,
from a millionaire businessman.
(rousing music)
I know it might be tempting
to go screaming it from the rooftops
and rubbing it in your enemy's faces,
but the absolute best move is
staying as quiet as possible
and telling no one.
Privacy is really your main
priority at this point.
You want to be what is
known as stealth rich.
A guy called Jack Whittaker
won $314.9 million
from the Powerball in 2002.
At the time,
it was the largest jackpot
ever won by a single ticket.
He was the opposite of stealth rich.
He went around telling everyone
and even became famous for
giving money to strangers
that asked him for help.
He gave away millions to the church
and even bought his friends
new cars and houses.
Now, you're probably thinking
he sounds like a lovely guy,
maybe a bit silly, but he had a good heart
and good things come to kind people.
Well, that couldn't be
further from the truth.
His wife divorced him,
friends abandoned him,
and his granddaughter,
who he spoilt with money,
tragically died from an overdose.
He later admitted that
being too much of a nice guy
destroyed both his fortune and his family.
So now you understand the
importance of being stealth rich,
how do you actually do it?
Well, even if you keep
this as quiet as possible,
some people will still suspect you.
It's like those TikToks that say,
"I won't tell anyone when I become rich,
but there will be signs."
This means you'll become far
more likely to get robbed,
sued, blackmailed, or scammed.
Once people know you have a bit of money,
they descend like vultures.
Trust me, I've experienced it.
They say this is because
money changes people.
However, over my years,
I've realized that money
actually just reveals
who that person really is.
The only person you should
tell is an attorney.
Make sure you get a good one
that specializes in trust
and estate planning.
A trust can save millions in taxes
and provide a healthy layer of privacy.
(light upbeat music)
A lot of people will tell
you not to quit your job.
However, I disagree.
If your job isn't
bringing you satisfaction,
then quit the job.
Don't quit working, but quit that job.
You could even wait for the perfect moment
when your boss is pulling
a power trip, like,
"You need to step up your game
if you want to continue working here,"
and then quit gloriously.
But please go and find another
job that you actually enjoy,
at least for a bit.
When people quit working entirely,
all they have to think about 24/7
is how they're gonna spend their money.
Many end up starting a random business
they know nothing about
because they're bored and
now have the money to do it.
Some people even buy restaurants
and end up on Gordon Ramsay's
"Kitchen Nightmares."
Being rich and bored
is a really dangerous situation to be in.
The way I've always thought of it is,
if you're working, then
you're not spending.
So keep your life as normal as possible
for at least six months.
You need to process having all this money
and not give in to the
temptation of spending it.
(suspenseful music)
You might think this doesn't matter.
You're rich now,
why worry about a few little debts
when you could pay it
off if you wanted to?
Well, these debts can quickly start
eating into your fortune,
and before you know it,
you'll be left with nothing.
Focus on paying back your highest
interest rate debts first.
The main culprit here is credit cards.
These often have 20 to 30% interest rates,
which eat away at your money
faster than almost anything else.
Then you have car loans
and personal loans.
These are worth clearing
if the rates are high.
Finally, you have mortgages.
Paying off their house
is often one of the first things people do
after suddenly becoming rich.
However, this might not
actually be the best idea.
If it's cheap debt, I'm talking 2 to 3%,
it might be smarter to
keep it and invest instead.
This is because you should be
able to get a better return
from your investments,
and that will offset the amount
that debt is costing you.
So focus on clearing
that high interest debt.
It's a guaranteed return,
unlike investing which can go up and down.
Paying off debt
is the same as earning that
interest rate risk-free.
So use this as a reset button,
and once you're out of high interest debt,
promise yourself never to
fall back into that cycle.
(dramatic upbeat music)
When you become rich all of a sudden,
the people closest to you
often feel entitled to a share of it
because in their mind,
you didn't earn it with honest hard work.
They'll start asking for loans
that they often don't intend to pay back
or even come up with genius business plans
they need you to invest in.
Trust me when I say
the fastest way to lose family and friends
is to lend them money.
Just don't do it.
They may resent you a
little in the moment,
but they'll get over it.
That's far better than
getting into a messy situation
where everyone falls out.
But what if you want to
help out family and friends?
Well, I have a simple rule:
If someone I know asks me for help
and they genuinely need it,
then I give them the money
and don't expect to ever be
paid back on one condition.
They never ask me for money again.
- [Staff] Can I have
some money then, Mark?
- No, you're joking in. I pay you plenty.
I recommend you do the same
because you don't want people using you
as their emergency fund.
If you help them out once
and they know they can come back for more,
they're less likely to be
responsible with their own money
because they know you just
bailed them out again.
I know this point sounds quite heartless,
but it's really the opposite.
Sometimes you have to be cruel to be kind.
This will save you far more friendships
than just being someone else's piggy bank.
(tense upbeat music)
When most people get rich quickly,
they still have a consumer mindset.
They look at the money
sat in their bank account
and think about all the
ways they're gonna spend it.
My son's friend's family
actually won the lottery
when he was younger,
and his parents went out
and bought a new house
worth over $10 million,
a couple of sports cars,
and sent all their kids to private school.
Only two years later, the dream collapsed.
Curtis' friend was yanked
out of private school,
sports cars were sold off,
and their $10 million home
was desperately listed
for $6.5 million after bad improvements
and crushing debt forced them to sell.
This all happened
because they didn't
understand the golden rule:
Never spend the principle,
only the interest.
You should be trying to grow a money tree
that produces new income every month,
not cutting it down
for temporary firewood.
That's where your freedom figure comes in.
Work out exactly how much
income you need each year
to live the life you want,
then multiply it by 25.
So if you want an income
of $200,000 per year,
you'll need to invest at least $5 million
of your new wealth.
The idea is that you'll
never actually have to dip
into the 5 million
and be able to live on the
$200,000 of interest every year.
Even if you haven't received
a large sum of money
and become instantly rich,
it's still worth working
out your freedom figure
as it's a great target to aim for.
The rule of 25 is based on
a 4% safe withdrawal rate.
I personally aim to grow my
money by more than 4% though
just to be safe.
That brings us on to...
(smooth upbeat music)
The most common thing I hear is,
"Where can I find those
kinds of interest rates?
My account only gives me 0.5%."
The truth is,
you're not likely to find
the kind of interest rates
you need for the rule of 25
in an ordinary account.
You need to open an investing account.
So let's say you somehow got your hands
on that $5 million we
talked about earlier.
How could you invest it?
Well, at this stage,
it's way more about
preservation and growth.
Of course, this does depend on your age
and how much risk you want to take.
But here's an example
of how I would consider splitting it up.
Remember, I'm not a financial advisor,
and this isn't financial advice.
First of all, I've put $1 million
into a low cost total
stock market index fund,
just like this one.
It includes over 1,300 different stocks,
so it's very diversified.
Its top holdings are big
companies like Apple, Microsoft,
Amazon, NVIDIA, and Alphabet.
This is your long-term growth engine
and has averaged about 9% per
year over the last 20 years.
But future returns could
be higher or lower.
On $1 million, that's
around $90,000 a year.
Second, I'd put $1 million
into a low cost total
bond market index fund,
such as this one.
A bond fund is a pool of loans
you give to governments or companies.
Instead of owning one bond,
you own a basket of many,
which pays you regular interest
and is generally considered
safer than stocks.
This should help you with stability
in the event of a market crash.
Broad bond market indexes have
averaged 4% returns per year.
On $1 million, that's $40,000 a year.
Third, I'd put half a million dollars
into residential real estate,
like single-family homes,
and another 500,000 into
commercial real estate
like warehouses.
I like this split,
as residential real estate
is great for property appreciation.
US housing has historically
grown at about 7% annually,
so on 500,000, that's $35,000 a year.
Commercial real estate is
great for steady cash flow,
as tenants normally stay for years
and also maintain the property.
If you buy right,
then this historically gives
returns of around 8% per year.
So on $500,000, that's 40k a year.
Fourth, I'd put half a million dollars
into blue chip crypto
like Bitcoin and Ethereum.
Bitcoin has been one of
the best-performing assets
of the last decade,
so it makes sense to have it
in an investment portfolio.
However, it is highly volatile
and can go down just
as fast as it goes up,
so treating it as a 5 to
10% moonshot allocation
makes sense.
Bitcoin's last decade saw
explosive gains of 49% annually,
but past performance
doesn't predict the future,
so let's normalize it
to a 10 to 15% range.
$500,000 could average
roughly 62.5k per year.
Fifth, I'd put $1 million
into a high interest savings account
such as this one from SoFi
that offers up to 4.5%.
On $1 million, that's 45k a year.
Altogether, that example portfolio
could generate around $312,500
per year in passive income
if markets perform like
their long-term averages.
But remember,
past performance is no
guarantee of future results.
If you want to get started
building an investing portfolio,
I actually reached out to Trading 212
to see if they wanted to sponsor
this portion of the video.
They agreed and are actually giving you
a free fractional share
worth of up to 100 pound
when you use the code TILBURY
in the promo code section of the app.
Don't wait to win the lottery
to get started with this,
just get it set up now.
And trust me, you'll thank
yourself in the future.
(dramatic jazzy music)
The ones paying very close
attention will realize
that I missed out 500k
from that $5 million
investment portfolio example.
That's because you should spend that 500k
on whatever you like.
Call it fun money.
I went through this stage and
realized that having money
isn't about Lambos or mansions.
It's about never having to do
things you don't want to do.
Real wealth is waking up and
deciding how to spend your day.
Don't be like those lottery winners
who blow it or chasing possessions,
not freedom.
The rich that stay rich
are the ones who buy back their time.
Once you secured yourself,
think beyond yourself and leave a legacy.
If you want to learn exactly
how to invest for beginners,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there.
But don't click on it just yet,
make sure to subscribe if
you wanna grow your wealth.
Okay? (tongue clicks)
I'll see you over there.