- If you save just $5 a day
by skipping your daily Starbucks,
cutting back on pricey Uber Eats,
or resisting the temptation
to buy new Fortnite skins,
and instead invested it
with an average annual return of 10%,
in 45 years you'd have
nearly $1.6 million.
I've shared this idea before,
and while many people are amazed
at how saving a small amount every day
can grow into a fortune,
there's always three
common hate comments I get.
The first is, "I don't want to save.
I want to enjoy my money while I'm young."
The second, "I don't
wanna be a millionaire
when I'm old gray like you.
I want it now."
And the third, "What kind of investment
actually gives me these
returns over the long term?"
After hearing these doubts
time and time again,
I thought, why not put it
to the test once and for all?
That's why I'm kicking
off a year-long challenge
to show you that investing $5 a day
doesn't have to feel like a sacrifice
and can lead to real measurable returns.
First, I'll walk you through exactly
how I'm setting up my investments.
Then, we'll fast forward
to reveal my results one year later.
Yes, by the time you
are watching this video,
a whole year will have passed,
so hopefully everything went to plan.
Before we start, remember,
I'm not a financial advisor.
I'm just sharing the
knowledge that has allowed me
to become a millionaire investor.
Right, so step one is to find a platform.
For this investing challenge,
I've got a few non-negotiables
when it comes to what I'm
looking for in a platform,
and if you ever wanna do
something like this yourself,
these are the things you'll
want to keep in mind too.
Let's break them down.
The first thing, of course, is low fees
because you don't want your
potential profits eaten up
by unnecessary charges.
The next thing is a
beginner friendly interface.
Although I'm confident with
complicated investing terms,
I know most beginners
that wanna try out this
challenge will be put off
if it looks too confusing.
So we need something that's
simple to understand.
Security is such an important one.
What's the point of investing
if my money isn't safe?
So I'll need a platform
that is fully protected
by the financial services
compensation scheme.
This compensates you for up
to 85,000 pounds in the UK
in case something happens to the platform.
However, bear in mind this
protection doesn't protect you
from investment losses.
We also need a platform
that accepts pretty low minimum deposits
because this is, of course,
a $5-a-day challenge.
Next, we need some kind of
automatic investing feature
as there's no way I'm gonna be remembering
to invest $5 every single
day without automating it.
You might be better at
remembering than me,
but my boomer brain is getting pretty old.
Finally, we'll need access
to fractional shares.
This will allow us to
invest in high-price stocks
without needing to fork
out hundreds of dollars
to buy an entire share upfront.
For example, Apple is, as of August, 2023,
trading in at around $178 per share,
which clearly doesn't work
with our $5-a-day budget,
but with fractional shares,
we can invest any amount we
want, no matter how small.
There are other features
you might prioritize.
However, these things
are my non-negotiables.
Now, if you are doing this challenge too,
feel free to use whatever
platform has these features.
I've used a lot of investing
platforms in my lifetime
and one of my favorites is Trading 212,
as it ticks all of these boxes.
So that's the platform I'm gonna be using
for this challenge.
Right, let's move on to step two,
which is to open and fund an account.
When it comes to this step,
there's one key decision
that many people overlook,
a decision that can make
or break your long-term results.
And if you are taking on the
$5-a-day challenge like I am,
this choice becomes even more critical.
This is because the type
of account you choose
will determine how much
of your profits you
actually end up keeping.
Let me explain.
There are two main types of accounts
we need to consider.
For now, let's call them
account A and account B.
Now, let's imagine we've
got $2,000 to invest.
We'll split it equally between both boxes.
So $1,000 goes into account A,
and $1,000 goes into account B.
At first, everything looks the same.
Both accounts have the same
amount of money invested,
but here's where things start to change.
When you use account A,
your profits aren't
entirely yours to keep,
and that's because of the dreaded tax man.
First, he takes a slice
of your dividend earnings.
Dividends are like a reward
companies give their shareholders.
Now, not all companies
pay them, but many do.
How much the tax man takes
depends on your income and tax bracket,
so the more you earn,
the bigger the slice he takes.
Next, he takes even more
for capital gains tax.
This happens when you sell an investment
for more than you paid for it.
In the UK capital gains
tax is typically 10 to 20%.
In the US, long-term
capital gains tax rates
range from naught to 20%
based on your income level.
Now, what about the money in account B?
Well, this account has special protections
that stop the tax man from reaching in
and taking your profits.
Everything you make here is yours to keep.
That's because account B is known
as a tax-advantaged account.
Meanwhile, account A is just
a general investing account.
In my humble opinion,
you shouldn't even be looking
at a general investing account
until you've fully taken advantage
of everything a tax-advantaged
account has to offer.
So how do you do that?
Well, it depends on where you live.
In the UK our tax-advantaged accounts
are called stocks and shares ISAs,
and in the US they're known as Roth IRAs.
Both of these special accounts come
with incredible tax benefits,
but there are a few
things to keep in mind.
In the UK you can contribute up
to 20,000 pounds per year into an ISA.
In the US Roth IRA contributions
are capped at $6,500 each year
or $7,500 if you're over 50.
For most people, these limits are plenty,
allowing you to build your future
while still covering living expenses.
The ISA allows you to withdraw
money at any time tax free,
which makes it very flexible.
So while a general investing account
isn't necessarily a bad option,
it often falls short when it
comes to maximizing your money.
Of course, if a tax-advantaged account
isn't available where you live,
you'll have no other
choice but to use option A,
a general investing account.
I'm gonna use option B,
a stocks and shares ISA,
because when we pull the
money out of this box
at the end of the year,
we want to keep as much as possible.
As I mentioned earlier,
I use Trading 212 all the time
and already have an account,
but for this challenge,
I wanted to show you the
process of starting fresh.
That's why I've asked
my son Curtis to step in
and take on the challenge
using his account.
If you also want to set up an account
and join in with the challenge,
just head over to their website
or download their app from the app store.
The setup process is
pretty straightforward.
The only part you might need
a bit of clarification on
is choosing the right account type.
You'll be met with four options like this.
At the top is the
general investing account
we spoke about earlier.
Underneath is a CFD account
for short term trading,
which we don't need to worry about.
At the bottom is the cash ISA.
And right here is the Stocks ISA.
This is the account
I'd open if I were you.
Now, assuming you've set up your account,
head over to this tab and
select use promo code,
and enter T-I-L-B-U-R-Y, TILBURY,
and you'll get a free fractional share
worth up to 100 pound when
you fund your account.
Now, I know this sounds
too good to be true,
but they're offering this
because I reached out to them
to see if they'd be interested
in sponsoring this portion
of the video, and they agreed.
So next, let's fund the account.
Click this button here.
You'll see a few options
including instant bank transfer,
normal bank transfer card, or Google Pay.
If you're using the iPhone app,
I believe you'd also have the
option of Apple Pay as well.
I'm gonna go with instant bank transfer
and deposit 35 pound from
my son's bank account
as that will cover us enough
to invest five pound a day
for the next seven days.
Now, you don't need a deposit
for an entire week ahead in one go.
This is just the way
I'm choosing to do it,
and yes, I know the title says $5 a day,
but I'm in the UK so I'm
putting five pound in,
which is actually just a little bit more.
The most common mistake I see
people make when investing
is assuming that once they put some money
into an account like this,
their money will
automatically start to grow.
Let me make one thing very clear.
This box only protects
your money from tax.
It doesn't actually invest it for you.
That's why step three is
to pick some investments.
This is all about deciding what
actually goes into the box.
So we could fill it
with individual stocks,
like Amazon, Meta,
Apple, Tesla, and Nvidia.
But to be honest, while
these are great companies,
putting all your money into a handful
of individual stocks can be really risky.
If one of these companies
doesn't perform well,
it could drag down your entire portfolio.
That's because your money is tied up
in just a few companies,
and that increases your risk.
That's why for this challenge,
I'm using a different strategy,
and you might have guessed it already.
It's called index fund investing.
This will give us exposure to loads
of different companies
without all the stress
of picking individual stocks
and praying for a winner.
Index funds can hold shares from hundreds,
sometimes even thousands of
different companies at once.
This makes it easy to
invest in a whole bunch
of companies all at the same time,
making your portfolio more diversified.
Now, here's the best part.
What makes this even more
powerful is that it's going right
inside my tax-advantaged account.
So not only do I get the
benefits of diversification
and low cost,
but I also get to avoid
paying taxes on dividends
or capital gains while it grows.
This is perfect for my
$5-per-day challenge.
Of course, it's important to remember
that stocks can go up as well as down,
and your capital is always
at risk when investing.
However, if you choose to invest
in an index fund like the S&P 500,
which tracks the performance
of the top publicly traded
companies in the United States,
it's worth noting that historically,
no one has lost money when they've bought
and held for over 20 years.
Past performance isn't a
guarantee of future results,
but long-term investing in
diversified funds like this
can help reduce risk compared
to individual stocks.
Let's head over to Trading 212,
and set this up.
To the left,
you can see this option to create a pie.
Once you click it,
it gives you some different options
like copy and model pies,
looking at other people's
pies in the community
and creating your own custom pie.
A pie is just a fancy way of showing you
how your investments are divided
between different stocks.
For example, if you had $100
and split it equally between
four individual stocks,
your pie would have four
equal slices of 25% each.
We are gonna with the custom buy option
and click Add Instruments.
I'm gonna search for a simple
Vanguard S&P 500 index fund.
As you can see, there are a
couple of different options.
One has Acc in brackets,
and that stands for accumulation,
meaning that all your dividends
are reinvested back into your investments.
The other option looks the same
but has Dist in brackets at the end,
which is short for distribution.
This second option means
that you are given a dividends
rather than them being automatically
reinvested into your account.
So for me, I want this challenge
to be as easy as possible,
so I'll be choosing the accumulation one.
Now, I'm gonna click Add to pie.
Alright, so we've got our account set up
and decided what to invest in,
but here comes the tedious part:
investing a fiver every single day.
Honestly, I think a lot
of the hate towards this
challenge comes from people
imagining the effort it
takes to do this every day,
but the truth is it really
doesn't have to be that hard.
That's why step four is
to set up auto investing.
Now, this feature isn't just
great for the $5 challenge.
It's essential for any investor,
no matter how much you are putting in.
This is because it takes your
emotions out of investing
and leverages the power
of dollar cost averaging.
Let me explain.
The reality of the stock market
is that it's completely unpredictable.
It doesn't just move in one direction.
Sometimes the market will be going up.
Other days it'll be moving sideways,
and then there are times
it'll be going down.
When the market is down,
your money actually buys more shares
because prices are lower.
For example, my $5 stretches further,
letting me pick up more
shares at a discount.
And when the market is up,
my $5 buys fewer shares
because prices are higher.
The idea is that over time,
these ups and downs
balance each other out,
which is the magic of
dollar cost averaging.
It's been such a reliable and
stress-free strategy for me
because it takes the pressure off trying
to time the market perfectly.
For this challenge, I'll be
using this exact strategy
by investing the same
amount every single day,
and if you don't wanna do it daily,
you can invest monthly
and still see the same results.
It's entirely up to you.
Let's go back to Trading
212 and click Next.
This then gives us the
option to either choose
to invest manually or use
the autoinvest feature.
We're of course going
to select Autoinvest,
and then click Next.
Now, we have these three
sliders we can play around with.
The first one is our initial deposit.
This is the money we're gonna
be investing right away,
so I'm gonna set this to five pounds.
Next, we have the investment frequency.
As you can see, you can
do this every two months,
monthly, every two weeks, weekly,
but we're gonna select the
daily option and press Update,
and then we're gonna change
this to five pound, too.
Finally, let's set the years to one.
And as you can see,
there's a cool value
projection graph at the top,
which shows us what we can expect
to make in a year based
on historical data.
1,970 pounds may not seem super impressive
when we're gonna be putting in 1.8K,
but if you move that slider
all the way to 40 years,
look how compound interest takes over.
This value projection says our
little five-pound-a-day investment
could be worth 5.52 million
from an investment of only 73,000 pounds.
Of course, this is all estimations,
and if I were you, I'd take
this with a grain of salt,
as one knows what the market
is gonna do long term.
However, playing around
with these compound
interest value projections
is very motivational.
So let's bring it back to
one year and click Next.
Now we get the chance
to name our investment.
So I'm gonna call it Coffee a day,
and then click Next.
Now it's time to fund the pie.
So let's click this,
and as we've already funded
the Trading 212 account,
we can choose the Free funds option.
This isn't free money.
It just takes cash from
your balance on Trading 212.
So as long as we top this
account up every now and again,
then the daily investment
should go through.
Then, I just need to press Confirm,
and boom, that's all set up.
So a year from now, hope I'm still alive.
I'll catch up with you.
(upbeat music)
Right, it is time to
check out the results.
I know I'm about five months late on this.
That's how good the autoinvest feature is.
You just forget it's
investing in the background.
But trust me, the results
are worth the weight.
They're really interesting.
I started this challenge
back in August, 2023,
and after the first month I was up
two pounds and 37 pence,
which was a 1.5% return.
Not bad, but then September came along,
and things didn't go quite so well.
I was actually sitting
at a loss of 79 pence,
which was a -0.5% return.
This right here is why so many
people give up on investing.
In the first two months,
I had almost nothing to
show for my consistency.
It's no wonder people decide
to pull their money out
when they don't see immediate results.
So I was determined to stick
with my dollar cost averaging strategy,
and I'm so glad I did
because things really
started to turn around.
Fast forward six months,
and I was up 83 pounds and 70 pence,
which is an 18.2% return.
Not too shabby.
And then by 12 months,
I'd made 161 pounds and 34 pence in profit
with an 18.1% return.
That's where the
autoinvesting feature stopped,
but I've continued tracking
the growth since then.
Now, it's jump to today.
This is where it gets a little bit crazy.
In total, I've invested 1,505 pounds,
but my investment is now
sitting at 1,972 pounds.
That means I've made a profit
of 467 pounds and three pence,
which we can convert to dollars,
and that works out at $576.59,
which is a staggering
43.8% rate of return.
Now, this is proof
that time in the market
beats timing the market.
If I'd panicked and pulled my money out
after losing some in a second month
or stopped the challenge altogether,
I'd never have reached this point.
Even I couldn't have dreamt
of results like this.
It's down to the wild year
the stock market has had.
However, it's important to note
that these results are not typical,
and past performance doesn't
guarantee future results.
I'm thinking about continuing
this challenge long term
just to see how much it could grow.
If that's something you'd like to see,
let me know in the comments,
and I'll make another
update video in the future.
If you wanna learn more
about how I pick my stocks,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.