- "The stock market is over,
and you should get out
before Trump triggers a
full-blown recession."
That's what the mainstream
media want you to think.
Headlines are screaming disaster,
social media is in a frenzy,
and everyone is asking the same question,
"Should I sell now before it gets worse?"
But there's more to
this than meets the eye.
If you followed me for a while,
you know I'm a serious investor
who's obsessed with the stock market.
And since so many of you
have started investing
because of my videos,
I feel a responsibility
to give you my honest
take on the situation.
So before you panic,
let's take a step back
and look at the bigger picture together.
Every market crash has a cause,
and this one isn't random.
There are three main triggers behind it.
And all of them tie back to one man,
Donald Trump.
Now, before anyone jumps to conclusions,
this isn't about politics.
I'm not here to take sides.
And as a British investor looking in,
my only concern is how
this impacts investors
like you and me.
So let's break down the
three biggest triggers
behind this crash,
why they matter,
and what you can do to
benefit from all this mayhem.
(keys clacking)
(upbeat music)
Trigger one is Trump's trade war.
Trump has always pitched himself
as the ultimate deal maker.
He's the guy who fights for American jobs
and plays hardball with other countries,
but the trade wars he's fighting
could increase your weekly shopping bill
and cause a recession.
The last time the US tried this,
it helped trigger the Great Depression,
wiping out jobs and wrecking the economy.
Now, history might be repeating itself.
Stocks are already crashing,
prices are rising,
and if this spirals,
it won't just hurt Wall Street,
it'll hit you where it matters most,
your bank account.
Let me take you back to 1930,
when I was just a boy,
the US government decided
to slap massive taxes
called tariffs on imported goods
to protect American businesses
from foreign competition.
It was called the Smoot-Hawley Tariff Act,
and it turned out to be
one of the worst economic
mistakes in history.
At first, it seemed like it would help.
American companies
wouldn't have to compete
with cheap imports,
and more products would
be made in the USA.
But there was a big problem,
other countries fought back.
Nations that used to trade with the US
started raising their own tariffs,
making it harder for American businesses
to sell products overseas.
Trade slowed to an absolute crawl,
businesses collapsed and
millions lost their jobs.
Instead of fixing the economy,
it helped turn a regular recession
into the Great Depression,
one of the worst financial crises ever.
Fast-forward nearly a century,
and Trump has brought
back tariffs in a big way.
In February, 2025,
Trump announced a 10% tariff
on Canadian energy imports,
and a 25% tariff on other Canadian goods.
In retaliation, Canada
imposed a 25% tariff
on American imports.
Then in March, Ontario
implemented a 25% surcharge
on electricity exports to the US,
affecting states like New York,
Michigan and Minnesota.
However, in my opinion,
this was more of a symbolic move
that wouldn't have seriously
damaged the US economy.
However, Trump didn't hold back,
and instead of just brushing it off,
he fired back by increasing tariffs
on Canadian steel and aluminum to 50%.
Unlike Canada's move,
this wasn't just for show,
it hit Canada's
manufacturing industry hard,
while also driving up steel prices
for American businesses
that rely on imports.
But why am I telling you all this?
Well, this is where the
real problem starts.
Tariffs sound good on paper,
as they're meant to
punish foreign businesses,
while encouraging more
stuff to be made in America.
But in reality,
they end up hurting regular people
more than anyone else.
As a business owner
who manufactures products in
imports from China myself,
I know that when businesses are forced
to pay more for materials,
they don't just absorb the cost,
they pass it on to their customers.
That means higher prices on cars,
appliances and electronics.
In addition to this,
food becomes more expensive
because supply chains get disrupted,
meaning that everyday
essentials cost more,
stretching household budgets even further.
On top of that,
other countries aren't just sitting around
while Trump raises tariffs,
they're forming new alliances
to trade without the US.
China is leading the charge
with the BRICS Alliance,
partnering with Brazil,
Russia, India and South Africa
to reduce dependence on American trade.
So the more the US isolates itself,
the more other countries
look elsewhere for business.
So what's my opinion on all of this
as an experienced investor?
Well, if Trump goes all
in on this trade war,
history suggests it'll
do more harm than good.
While some industries might
get a short-term boost,
the long-term damage,
such as higher prices, weaker global ties
and a slowing US economy,
could far outweigh any benefits.
But if I'm being completely honest,
I don't think Trump
actually wants high tariffs.
I know that sounds crazy,
but hear me out.
Trump is at his core, a
businessman and a deal maker,
just like me.
That's why I believe he's using tariffs
as a negotiation tactic,
not as an end goal.
So if that's true,
what does he actually want?
Well, I think he's
after free global trade,
but on terms that favor the US.
And if he pulls that off,
it could pay off big time.
However, the problem is,
his approach is creating
massive uncertainty.
The constant backtracking,
new tariffs and mixed signals
are spooking the stock market
because investors hate unpredictability.
If this drags on too long,
it could shake confidence so much
that it pushes the
economy towards recession.
Something even Trump's own administration
has admitted they're willing to risk.
Right now, the market isn't
just reacting to tariffs,
it's reacting to uncertainty
about what comes next.
And in investing,
uncertainty is one of the
biggest killers of confidence.
(keys clacking)
(upbeat music)
Trigger two is Trump's stance on NATO.
Trump has openly questioned
the role of NATO,
the military alliance that
protects Western countries.
He suggested that the US
shouldn't keep defending allies
unless they start paying more
for their own protection.
While that might sound like a fair demand,
if the US steps back from
its NATO commitments,
it could create a power vacuum
that countries like Russia
and China might exploit.
Markets hate uncertainty.
The second investors sense that
world stability is at risk,
they panic.
If NATO weakens,
it could encourage Russia
to push further into Europe
or even lead to new conflicts
as countries try to adjust to a world
without the USA acting as
the global police force.
More conflicts mean
higher military spending,
unpredictable trade relationships
and spikes in energy prices,
all of which can rattle the stock market.
(keys clacking)
(upbeat music)
Trigger three is Trump's secret plan.
There's been a theory circulating
that Trump may be crashing
the stock market on purpose.
I know that sounds crazy,
but there is some evidence for it.
Trump has never been a fan
of high interest rates.
In fact, he's called them ridiculous,
and has openly attacked
the Federal Reserve
for keeping them high.
Now, here's where it gets interesting.
The Fed is technically independent,
meaning Trump can't just tell them
to cut interest rates,
but their decisions are
based on economic conditions.
If the stock market crashes
and a recession seems inevitable,
the Fed has no choice
but to step in and slash interest rates
to prevent a total meltdown.
But why does Trump want lower rates?
Well, because high interest rates
slow down the economy,
businesses borrow less, stocks struggle,
people stop spending as much,
and for Trump, who loves growth
and hates anything that
makes America look weak,
they're a problem.
It's not just about making
the stock market go up,
it's way bigger than that.
The US government is drowning
in $36.5 trillion of debt.
And when interest rates are high,
the cost of that debt
goes through the roof.
Think of it like a
massive credit card bill.
Imagine you owe $36,500,
and your credit card company
charges 10% interest per year.
That means before you even start
paying down the actual debt,
you're being charged
$3,650 every single year
just in interest.
Now, imagine the credit card company
suddenly slashes the interest rate to 3%.
Instead of paying $3,650 per year,
your interest drops to
just $1,095 annually.
That's a saving of
$2,555 every single year.
Now you can put this money
towards actually paying off your debt,
instead of just keeping
up with interest payments.
Well, that's exactly what
Trump might be doing,
but on a $36.5 trillion scale.
If the Fed lowers interest rates,
the government can refinance its debt
at a cheaper rate,
saving billions, if not trillions,
in interest payments.
This wouldn't be the first time
something like this has happened.
If Trump can create that
opportunity on purpose,
it could go down as one of the
smartest economic power moves
in history.
If this theory is true,
we're not looking at a
long-term economic collapse,
we're looking at a temporary shakeup
before a massive rebound.
So you're probably wondering,
"How can you benefit from this crash?"
Well, you need to understand
that stock market crashes
aren't rare disasters.
They're a normal part of investing.
Every few years, the
stock market takes a hit.
People panic and headlines scream,
"The end is near,"
but history tells us a different story.
Every crash of the US market
has been followed by a recovery.
The people who panic and
sell usually lose money,
while the ones who stay calm
and invest strategically
often come out on top.
Instead of freaking out,
this is the time to prepare,
make smart moves,
and hopefully set yourself
up for massive gains
when the market bounces back.
Look, I'm not a financial advisor,
however, I have made millions
during stock market crashes.
So here are my thoughts
on what you can do to prepare.
(upbeat music)
Step one is to invest
while the market is down.
Before you even think about investing,
you need a rock-solid
financial foundation.
I know I've said it before,
but it's worth repeating.
That means building an emergency fund
of at least three to six months'
worth of living expenses,
and eliminating any debt
with an interest rate above 8%.
Assuming you've done that,
if you've never invested before,
this could be one of
the best times to start.
Stocks are essentially on sale.
During the 2008 financial crisis,
I was still investing at the bottom
and saw my investments double
within a few years.
However, many of my
friends panicked and sold,
locking in their losses
and missing out on the recovery.
No one can perfectly predict
the exact bottom of the market,
but if you invest consistently
while prices are low,
you'll be buying assets at a discount.
If you wanna get started,
then Trading 212 are currently giving you
a free fractional share
worth up to 100 pound
when you use the code TILBURY in the app
and fund your account.
If you've been waiting for
a good time to do this,
then this could be it.
I'll leave a link in the description below
if you're interested.
(upbeat music)
Step two is to stay disciplined
and think long term.
Market crashes aren't random,
they follow predictable cycles.
There are three types of crashes.
Corrections, which is a 10% to 20% drop.
These happen frequently
and are part of a healthy market.
Bear markets, which is a 20% to 40% drop.
These happen every few years
and last about 289 days on average.
And full collapses,
which are more than 40% drops.
These are rare,
but have historically been followed
by huge recoveries in the USA.
The biggest mistake new investors make
is letting emotions
dictate their decisions.
When stocks drop,
fear kicks in and people sell at a loss.
When stocks rise, greed takes over,
and then they buy at inflated prices.
This cycle is why most
people fail at investing.
So if you're already investing,
the worst mistake you can
make is panic selling.
Selling while the market is down
locks in your losses
and keeps you from benefiting
from when stocks recover.
Instead, consider
increasing your investments
while stocks are cheap.
Stick to a long-term strategy,
like dollar-cost averaging.
Invest in a fixed amount every month
no matter what the market's doing.
This reduces the risk of
buying in at the wrong time
and ensures you are
steadily building wealth.
Remember, the best investors
see downturns as a chance to buy more.
(upbeat music)
Step three is to diversify
your investments.
Putting all your money
into one type of investment
is a recipe for disaster.
The key to surviving market crashes
is diversification.
This means spreading your money
across different types of assets.
My portfolio includes stocks,
bonds, precious metals like gold,
real estate, and even cryptocurrency.
It's also worth considering
dividend paying stocks
as they actually perform
well during downturns
because they generate passive income
even when prices are low.
Just remember, market crashes
aren't the end of the world.
If you understand how to navigate them,
you won't be the one panicking,
you'll be the one taking
advantage of the opportunities,
while everyone else is
running for the exit.
This isn't the time to fear the market.
It's the time to prepare,
invest wisely and stay patient.
The ones who make the smartest moves now
will be the ones who come out on top
when the market rebounds.
If you wanna know how to invest in 2025,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there.
But don't click on it just yet,
make sure to subscribe
if you wanna grow your wealth, okay?
(cheek clicking)
I'll see you over there.