- If you are young, ambitious,
and tired of being lied to about money,
this video is for you.
Here's the harsh truth.
Society wants you to accept a normal life
with average paying
maybe a trip away every
year if you're lucky.
If you want more than this,
they shame you into
thinking that you're greedy.
However, what's really greedy
is the system keeping you
stuck at the bottom.
While the rich enjoy a life of freedom,
I always knew I wanted to become rich.
So in my early twenties, I quit my job
and within a few years managed
to become a multimillionaire.
This means I know exactly what
it takes to build real wealth
and continue to grow it over the years.
So today's video is all
about my five stage process
to actually getting rich
while you're still young.
Let's get into it. The fastest way
to get rich is drop
shipping or is it crypto?
How about day trading?
That's the exact problem
most young people are facing.
Everyone tells you something different,
which leaves you frozen because
you have so many choices,
and what if you end up
picking the wrong one?
The thing is, life isn't like score
where there's only one correct answer.
There's actually multiple right choices,
but when you don't pick one
because you're too scared
of making a mistake,
life picks it for you.
And if you let that happen,
then the system will make
sure to keep you broke.
That's why the first
stage is called drifting.
People stuck here just float through life,
letting things happen to them
instead of taking control
and steering their life in
a direction they want to go.
They drift from one job
or side hustle to the next, hoping
that one day they'll strike it big.
There's a famous quote that says,
if you aren't building your own dream,
then someone else will
hire you to build theirs.
This is exactly what happens
when you are stuck drifting.
I mean, nobody's waking up
in the morning thinking,
how can I make Jimmy Rich?
The only person who will ever
put your success first is you.
So I want you to be really
honest with yourself.
Are you drifting? I meet
so many young people
who say they want to become rich,
but their actions just
don't match their ambitions.
They say things like Money
doesn't make you happy,
but this is just a lie.
The richer fed the poor for decades.
Money equals freedom, and
freedom equals happiness.
So there's no shame in
striving for it. Mark my words.
A drifter won't build serious
wealth for themselves.
They might get handouts
or win the lottery,
but they'll never be able to
become rich on their own merit.
So how can you avoid being a
drifter that brings us onto,
you can change your life in a
moment with just one decision.
You just have to choose to stop
being pushed around by life
and instead become obsessed
with just one thing.
Get him rich.
That's exactly why stage
two is called obsession.
Now, the outcome from that
decision may take a few months
to materialize,
but it's that single choice
that can propel your life
on a whole new trajectory.
If me suggesting that you should
obsess over becoming rich,
made you cringe, then you need to change
how you think about money
because there's nothing shameful
about wanting to be rich.
The truth is, having money allows you
to live life on your own terms
and avoid being controlled by others.
But as I said, the only way
to achieve this is with obsession.
Now, lots of young people
I talk to think they want
to be rich more than anything else,
but actually they're just arrogant.
They say they want to become rich,
but also learn to play an
instrument and run a marathon,
and also at the same time become
fluent in another language.
I mean, imagine your friend
tells you they wanna become a
professional footballer,
but also do all of those things too.
You'd probably laugh at them.
Becoming a footballer is hard enough,
let alone stacking all
those things on top of it.
Becoming rich is something
only a small percentage
of the population will ever achieve.
So why do you think you can
get there whilst also pursuing
12 other goals at the same time?
I can tell you from
experience, if I didn't lock in
and only focus on becoming
rich in my early years,
then I wouldn't be sitting here
as a multimillionaire today.
But being obsessed over
becoming rich isn't
enough to get you there.
You need to figure out how
you're actually gonna make money.
That brings us onto the truth is you get
paid in proportion to
the value you provide,
and the reason you aren't rich yet is
because you lack value.
So the question is, how can
you become more valuable?
This is the part a lot
of people get stuck with.
They think they have to
come up with some kind
of revolutionary business idea
or find the next crypto coin
before it goes to the moon,
but you really don't
have to be an innovator.
All you need to do is discover something
that's working right now for many people
and ask yourself, how can you do it too?
The fastest way to master
a moneymaking skill is
to find someone ahead of you
and uncover their proven pathway.
Some great choices of video
editing, drop shipping,
deal negotiating, short
form content creation,
or starting an eBay store.
That's why stage three
is called discovery.
When I was in my twenties
and thinking about opening
my first radio control model
shop, I didn't just dive
in and set one up anywhere.
I got myself a Saturday
job in a local model shop.
It was great for earning some extra cash,
but the real value was in
discovering the exact proven
pathway to run in a successful business.
I was like a sponge, always
asking questions, chatting
with customers, and jotting
down anything useful,
but even more importantly, making a note
of the things holding them back.
I even spent my Sundays
talking to modelers
and customers to find out
what they wanted from
their local model shop.
Now, I know you probably don't
want to open a model shop,
but the principle is exactly
the same When it comes
to learning any high income skill.
Find a person who's already
achieved what you want to do
and discover exactly how
they became successful.
It's basically a cheat code.
You get a blueprint to skip their mistakes
and end up progressing
even faster than they did.
This person doesn't have to be famous.
It's actually better if they aren't.
As you know, the money they
say they're making is coming
directly from their skills
and not from their personal brand.
You can find 'em in Discord
communities on Instagram
and even at sports clubs,
but how can you get someone to
reveal their proven pathway?
Now, I'm not gonna lie
to you uncovering this is
probably the hardest part.
That's why I've gone out
and done the discovery for you by hand,
selecting some very
impressive young people
who are currently making over
a hundred thousand dollars a
year in profit and asked them
to reveal their proven
pathways for you to copy.
They're all on my new platform
called the Wealth Portal,
which you can currently try out for free.
Each pathway is over three hours long
and condenses their many
years of experience into easy
to follow, step-by-step lessons.
I'm also in there every week
posting specific lessons about
making and investing money.
I'll drop a link in the
description if you want
to check it out For now, just
pick a pathway to follow.
Once you've done that, it's time
to focus on closing the
skill gap between you
and the person you are copying.
That brings us onto now it's time
to follow the proven
pathway you discovered
and start making money.
This stage is called acceleration.
At this point, you need to
get in plenty of practice,
so just get started.
Even if you don't fully
know what you're doing yet,
if you're offering a
service, do some free work
to get experience.
If you're selling products,
launch your first Shopify store.
The results won't be
amazing, and that's fine.
The truth is, before you
can be great at anything,
you've gotta be willing
to suck at it first.
Now, if you wanna speed up
your acceleration, you need
to get constant constructive criticism.
I mean, so many teens come up to me
and tell me they wanna be a YouTuber.
They swear blind that they,
they're making amazing videos,
but the algorithm just
isn't pushing their content
and they think one shout out from me will
blow their channels up.
However, when I take a
look at their videos,
I can see they aren't anywhere near ready,
so why do they think they are?
Well, the people they're asking
for feedback from are
often family and friends.
These are the worst
people to get advice from.
As firstly, they don't
want to hurt your feelings,
and secondly, they also
probably don't know what to say
as they're not experienced
enough to give you useful advice.
This leads to most people not pivoting
and changing their approach when they're
going down the wrong path.
There's a famous saying, if
you do what you've always done,
you'll get what you've always got.
That's why learning a high
income skill isn't just about
putting in more hours of practice.
It's about getting good advice
to help spot the things holding you back.
That's exactly why you need
more constructive criticism from
people outside your bubble,
which I understand can be hard to find.
That's why I spend a lot
of time running interactive live events
and answering your specific questions
inside the wealth portal,
which as I mentioned,
you can currently try out for free.
This process of getting feedback
them putting your head down
can be pretty brutal.
Most rich people look back
on this period of their life
as their lonely chapter.
You'll start to feel
disconnected from your childhood
friends, because let's be honest, most
of them don't share the
same ambitions as you,
but at the same time, you're
not yet successful enough
to connect with the people you look up to.
So it's this strange middle ground,
which can be very lonely at times.
My son went through this.
When he left school, instead
of going off to university,
he decided to start learning videography.
He was so focused on
building up his side hustle
that he lost contact with
many of his old friends
for a good couple of years.
He grinded away on his
own, putting in the reps,
staying self-aware
and slowly refining by
doubling down on what worked
and cutting out what didn't believe me.
It took a while before he was
rich enough to make friends
with other successful people.
This lonely chapter is
where most people give up
and slip back into being average,
and honestly, I don't blame them.
It takes a crazy amount
of dedication to push
through when you're on your own.
So if you've outgrown old friends
but aren't rich yet, who
can you turn to for support?
Well, when I was growing my wealth,
the best friends I made were
the ones chasing success
and leveling up at the same time.
Honestly, the motivation
and value you'll receive from
the people in the trenches
with you as well as those one step ahead
of you is far more valuable
than the stuff you'll learn from
YouTube videos alone.
That's why I've put the
community at the heart
of the wealth portal.
I love seeing people share their wins,
helping each other out,
meeting up in real life
and having a bit of a friendly competition
for the monthly prizes.
But even if you aren't
part of the wealth portal,
there are plenty of other
communities that you can join,
and I'd really recommend
doing this so you don't have
to do it all alone,
but when you start making a lot of money,
where should you invest it?
That brings us onto the truth is the most
valuable investment you'll
ever make isn't stocks,
crypto, or real estate.
It's you. You are the asset.
You are the one thing you'll
hold for your entire life,
and the skills you develop
compound just like money does.
This is the point where your
hard work starts paying off.
That's why stage five is called freedom.
If you've managed to
follow a proven pathway
and master the skills
involved with making it work,
then you'll have no problem becoming rich.
You'll be able to buy whatever you want,
work from anywhere in the world
and never have to answer
to your boss ever again.
I remember getting to this point
and trust me, there's no better feeling,
but here's the thing.
Being rich and being wealthy are actually
two separate things.
You see, when you start
earning a lot of money,
you have two choices.
You could spend it all
on the things you want,
like a flashy car, designer
clothes and luxury vacations.
Or on the other hand, you could
reinvest a decent percentage
of that money while you're still young
and build true wealth.
This is entirely up to you at this point.
You've achieved financial freedom
and have enough money rolling in.
However, if you are aiming
to impress other people,
I'd say this, wealthy people
like me will never be impressed
with someone young
spending all their money.
We'll just look at you
and be disappointed.
As we know, you could achieve far more
by reinvesting some of it.
So how can you actually reinvest?
Well, when I was younger,
I wasn't satisfied
with just one income stream.
I actually built multiple.
This can be passive
investments like index funds,
cryptocurrency, and individual stocks,
or even better additional skills
that can help you make more money.
Most people never make this shift
because they bloke all their
money on stupid things.
They happily spend a thousand
dollars on the latest iPhone,
but won't reinvest $200 into themselves,
and that's exactly why they
never reach true wealth.
Just think about it.
Whatever you spend today
on meaningless crap,
you are taking from your future self.
Wealthy people reinvest in
their skills, businesses
and stocks to become more successful.
Poor people spend money to
impress other poor people.
So even when you have
freedom, still spend a couple
of hours a day learning, read
books, watch YouTube videos,
and join communities.
These things have the highest return on
investment you'll ever get.
If you wanna learn more about
building wealth from scratch,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.