This is the best piece
of advice I've ever
heard about side hustles.
It came from a millionaire
I looked up to as a kid
and the wisdom has stayed
with me ever since.
I was worrying that I'd never have
that one big revolutionary
idea that changes everything.
His exact words to me were, you don't need
to reinvent success, just
recognize the patterns
that already working
and make them your own.
From that day forward, I stopped guessing
and started studying what truly
successful people were doing.
This led to my side hustles,
turning into multimillion
dollar businesses,
making me a millionaire,
and I owe it all to that simple principle.
So you are probably thinking
what side hustles are working
for people right now?
Well, that's exactly why.
Today I'm gonna be sharing
seven real life examples
of young people currently
making over a hundred thousand
dollars a year from their side hustles
so you can follow their proven pathways
and replicate their success.
And yes, I'm bringing back the scrapbook
as it's in need of an update.
I'm gonna be rating each one
out of five in three key areas,
how much time it takes to
learn how much money you need
and how difficult it is
to make $10,000 per month
side hustle Idea one is
eBay reselling.
This is Kai Towers. His
life was going nowhere.
His mum died when he was just a kid
and he never knew his father.
In his late teens, he was
working a dead end job
with no obvious way out,
but one day he'd had enough
of feeling like a loser
and decided to take control of his life.
So he started selling stuff on eBay
and with his newfound motivation, managed
to turn $400 into $317,000
within just one year.
But isn't eBay dead? It's
all about Amazon now, right?
Wrong. eBay's latest
revenue shows it's not
dying, it's growing.
I mean, in the second quarter of 2025,
they brought in $2.7 billion,
which is 6% up year on year.
I know this might sound strange
as you probably never
really hear about eBay.
However, when you understand
where this growth is coming from,
it all starts to make sense.
In the early days, eBay
and Amazon were neck
and neck, both chasing the
same mass market audience,
but as Amazon scaled into
a retail giant powered
by logistics and prime
delivery, eBay quietly pivoted.
Rather than competing on speed
and convenience, it began
dominating in the niches.
I'm talking about
collectibles, vintage items,
refurbished tech trading cards,
and hard to find products in these areas.
Loyal buyers will still
choose eBay over Amazon
every single time.
I know it's a cliche saying,
but the riches are in the niches.
Kai knows this better than anyone.
That's why he was able to make
so much money absolutely
dominating the gaming accessory
niche by selling things like
replacement thumb sticks,
retro memory cards,
and even devices to make
you a stronger player.
Now for those all
important ratings, firstly,
how much time does eBay
reselling take to learn?
I'll give this a one out of five
'cause all you need to do is pick one
of the niches I mentioned earlier
and dedicate a month of
your time to learning
how the platform operates.
That brings us onto how
much money do you need?
I'll give this a one out of
five again, as right now,
without even knowing it, you
are probably sat on a gold mine
and before you say I'm
crazy, let me explain.
To be successful on eBay, you
need to have stock to sell.
But before ordering a load
of products from a supplier,
a useful strategy
that most people will overlook
is warming their eBay account
up by selling unused items
from around their house.
This has so many benefits,
such as allowing you
to learn the eBay ropes, risk
free warming up your account
with some sales history
and positive feedback
and making you some fast
money that you can then use
to reinvest into better stock.
So how easy is it to
make $10,000 per month?
I'll give this a
2.5 out of five.
As Kai demonstrated, it's
completely possible to start
by selling unused items
from around your house.
Then use that money as a
starting fund to scale up
to making over six figures.
Does that mean it's gonna be
super easy? Of course not.
You'll need to stay on top
of your listings constantly updating them
and making sure your
prices stay competitive.
If at any point you want to give one
of these side hustles a try,
then I actually got all the
people I'm mentioning today
to record a video series
explaining the exact steps they
took to start and scale their side hustles
to making over $10,000 a month,
and right now you can
access all of them for free.
I got them all filmed professionally
and made sure they included
their exact blueprint,
which means each series
contains over three
hours of pure value.
I'll drop a link in the
description below where
for a limited time you can
watch them all for free as well
as receive mentoring from me.
Side hustle idea too
is brand deal flipping.
This is Sue hit Amin.
At just 16 years old, he
was diagnosed with cancer,
but instead of letting
his illness stop him,
he used the hours he
spent in hospital beds
to start brand deal flipping.
This is essentially when
you connect an influencer
and a brand and take a cup for yourself.
It's what's known as a
middleman side hustle.
He didn't have any
connections when he started,
however, now just six
and a half years later,
he generates over $4
million per year working
with the big brands like
Ubisoft, Netflix, and asa.
He also works with some
of the biggest influencers
and public figures like
the Sideman, Logan Paul,
Steven Bartlett, RD,
and even Mark Tilbury.
The crazy thing about all
of this is the opportunity
is only growing.
When Sue hit first started,
he had to convince big brands
that online creators were
worth spending money on.
He was fighting an uphill battle
because nobody really
respected influencers.
However, now the landscape
has completely changed.
In May, 2025, the New
York Times announced that
for the first time,
Americans watch more
streaming content than cable
and broadcast TV combined.
And guess what? The top
streaming platform was Netflix,
Amazon Prime, maybe Disney?
No, it was actually YouTube
with a whopping 12.5%
of TV viewership
with its closest rival
being Netflix at 7.5%.
That's why brands are throwing
more money than ever are
online creators,
and if you can be the middleman
that negotiates the deals,
then you can take a big
slice of the profits.
But why wouldn't influencers just get the
brand deals themselves?
Well, I want you to
think about the biggest
companies in the world.
Airbnb doesn't own a single property.
Uber doesn't own any cars.
Amazon started by just
connecting buyers and sellers,
and DoorDash helps you order food.
They're all middleman
businesses just like brand deal
flipping, and they work so
well because of convenience.
It's really convenient
for an influencer to work
with someone like you
who can handle the deal.
So all they have to do is focus
on creating great content.
Let's get to the ratings.
Firstly, how much time does brand deal
flipping take to learn?
I'm gonna give this a two out of five.
As a brand deal flipper, your main job is
to bridge two worlds.
The creators who are usually younger
and the people running the big brands
who are typically older.
The real value lies in managing both sides
of that relationship.
As long as you understand YouTube,
you've already done half the work.
If you then take the time to
understand how brands operate,
you're onto a winner.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'm gonna give this a n out of five
because as Sue hit proved,
all you need is a laptop
and a bit of time to invest
into building your connections.
He started out by following
creators on Instagram
and then finding related
creators using the
suggested feature.
He spent hours following his process
and reaching out to people,
and within his first six
months made $30,000 in profit.
Thirdly, how easy is it
to make $10,000 per month?
This gets a two outta five.
The hardest part is
convincing people to work
with you once you do this.
Earning $10,000 a month
is more than achievable.
Think about it this way.
Let's say you find one brand
who books just five
influencers through you.
Each month, each influencer
has an average deal value
of $7,000 and your margin
is 30% from one brand alone
and just five influencer partnerships.
You have an agency doing
$400,000 a year in revenue
and netting around $10,000
per month in profit,
and these are not
unrealistic numbers at all.
These are completely possible
in the influencer economy
that we live in today.
Side hustle. Idea three is video editing.
This is Tom RAs.
Just a few years ago,
he was sitting in his uni bedroom
staring at the student debt.
He was racking up thinking there has
to be a better way to make money.
He had no idea where to start,
so he grabbed the closest
thing to him, his laptop
and decided to learn video editing.
That single decision led him
to learn a skill far more
valuable than his degree.
Before he knew it, he'd made
his first a hundred thousand
dollars in yearly
profit, working with some
of the biggest companies
and creators on the planet
and editing influencer collaborations
for brands like Coca-Cola,
Nintendo, and Gym Shark.
He also escaped his small uni room
and gain the freedom to travel the
world and work from anywhere.
There's no reason you can't
do this too, as the demand
for skilled editors is only growing.
In fact, video now makes up 82.5%
of all global internet traffic.
This means companies need
to create video content,
otherwise they're invisible as we speak.
They're urgently looking for people
who can take their message
and turn it into something
people actually want to watch.
Once you become good, you'll
be able to charge a lot
as you'll be directly increasing
the company's revenue.
But won't video editors
just be replaced by ai?
Good question, and here's the truth.
Yes, AI can cut clips and sync to a B,
but there are two main
reasons why it will never
replace real editors.
First emotion.
It can't feel tension, build anticipation
or spot the moment that
gives you goosebumps.
Second, AI can't innovate.
It can only imitate it, studies
what's already been done
and then copies those patterns.
Real editors do the opposite.
They don't copy, they create.
So yes, AI will be a
tool editors use a lot,
however, it won't be a
suitable replacement.
So let's have a look at my ratings first.
How much time does video
editing take to learn?
I'll give this one a
three outta five.
Look, video editing isn't
something you master overnight,
but it's also not something
that takes years to learn.
Tom mentions in the wealth portal
that beginners make the big mistake
of focusing too much on fancy
transitions and crazy effects,
but in reality, this isn't
what most clients are looking for.
His advice is to master
the basics first, like how
to cut pace and add music.
Then practice putting together a story.
If you can make a viewer feel something
or keep them watching until the end,
you've already cracked 80% of
what makes an editor valuable.
Next, how much money do you need?
This is definitely a one outta five.
Video editing is one of those rare skills
where you can start with almost nothing.
If you've got a half decent laptop
and an internet connection,
you are good to go.
Of course, you can save up
and invest in paid
software, a faster laptop
or even better storage,
but none of those things are
required to start earning.
In fact, some of the best
editors I know began on laptops
that could barely export a
10 80 p clip, so don't wait
until you've got the perfect setup.
Start with what you got.
Learn the craft and the
upgrades will follow the income
not the other way round.
Lastly, how easy is it to
make $10,000 per month?
I'll give this one a three
outta five because here's the
honest truth in the beginning,
you'll probably take on smaller
jobs like editing tiktoks
and reels for smaller
creators or businesses,
but don't overlook them.
These jobs are gonna lay the groundwork
for your future earnings.
They're your ticket to
building a strong portfolio,
and that's what attracts
the higher paying clients.
If you take on multiple clients
per month, then you'll reach
that 10 k mark in no time side hustle.
Idea four is branded drop
shipping. This is Jimmy Barlow.
Not long ago, he was just
like most students broke,
stuck in a neighborhood
he wanted to escape
and wondering how he'd ever get rich.
He didn't have any money, connections
or experience, just a laptop
and some motivation, so he
started branded drop shipping
and learnt on the go, and that
decision changed everything.
Now, he's regularly pulling in
around $40,000 in profit per month.
Drop shipping has been around for a while.
However, branded drop shipping is
where people are making
the most money right now.
It's much more effective
compared with the old approach.
Let me explain why.
A few years ago, the classic drop shipping
model looked like this.
Someone visits your store
and buys a product for let's say, $30,
and then you jump over to
AliExpress, grab the same item for
around $10 plus shipping
and have it sent straight
to your customer.
On paper, that looks like easy money,
but it never really
plays out that smoothly.
To get that sell, you probably
spent five to $10 on ads,
and by the time you deal
with refunds, delays
or shipping issues, you're
barely scraping a profit.
That's the problem with
old school drop shipping.
It works, but it's fragile.
Now, branded drop shipping
changes everything.
The backend looks similar as
you're still selling online,
but the way you position the product is
completely different.
You focus on building trust,
designing better websites
and branding a product.
People actually want to be seen using.
Suddenly, that $30 item
isn't fighting for pennies.
It's an $80 product that people buy
because they believe
in the brand behind it.
Your margins grow, you refund rate drops
and your side hustle starts
to feel more sustainable.
That's why branded dropshipping
isn't just the next step.
It's the smarter, more sustainable way
to build a side hustle that lasts.
Now for those all
important ratings, firstly,
how much time does branded
dropshipping take to learn?
I'm gonna give this one a four
outta five, not because it's hard, but
because it takes time.
You're not gonna be profitable right away,
and that's completely fine.
This isn't a get rich quick play,
it's a long-term side
hustle that builds steady,
predictable income over time,
and like anything worth
doing, it takes a few months
to get it off the ground.
Here's what that journey
really looks like.
Month one is all about getting started.
I'm talking building your
store, testing your ideas,
and figuring out how
the pieces fit together.
You'll have some small wins
and a few frustrating losses,
but that's part of the process.
Month two is when things start to click.
You've got data, you've
learned what works,
and now it's about doubling down on what's
actually getting results.
Month three is where you
shift gears into growth.
By now, you've likely
made your first sales
and maybe even your first
50 to a hundred customers.
That's your proof of concept.
Now it's time to scale
your ads, reinvest profits,
and start thinking bigger,
and by around month six,
if you stay consistent
and kept learning, you'll have a stall
that's generating reliable
profit every month.
Of course, you'll get there faster
with the right proof strategies to follow,
and that's exactly what
Jimmy runs you through
inside the wealth portal.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'm gonna give this a one hour five
because you can get started
almost completely free.
The beauty of drop shipping
is that you don't actually pay
for product until you've made a sale.
The only thing to keep in mind is
that there can be a short delay
while your payment's clear,
but that's about as risky as it gets.
Thirdly, how easy is it
to make $10,000 per month?
I'm gonna give this a two out of five
as it's much easier
than most people think.
Let me break it down.
$10,000 a month is just $333 a day.
Now imagine you're running a
branded drop shipping store
where each sale makes you
around $25 profit after costs.
To hit $333 a day, you'd
only need to make around 13
or 14 sales per day.
That's not hundreds of
customers or a massive audience.
That's literally a handful
of people finding your store
and buying something that
solves a real problem for them.
Side hustle. Idea five is brand identity.
This is Jack Watson.
He grew up with no money and
after leaving school, found himself stuck
in an accounting job.
He hated watching his life
passing by in a soulless office.
He knew he needed a plan
if he was gonna change his
circumstances, so he locked
himself away for six months,
researching, reading
and watching whatever he
could get his hands on.
That's when he stumbled
across something called
brand identity.
Six months later, he went
from a negative bank balance
to hitting his first 20 K month, so
what exactly is brand identity
and why is it on the rise?
Well, imagine a company comes to you
and says, we want people to
recognize us instantly to know
who we are and what we stand
for just by looking at us.
That's where brand identity comes in.
It's your job to design the entire look
and feel of that business from the logo
and colors to the fonts, images,
and overall style that makes
it instantly recognizable and
because it directly affects
how people see the brand
and ultimately how much money
the business makes, it's one
of the most profitable
pathways in the graphic design
world right now.
The thing is, there are thousands
of designers charging $50
for a quick logo or a
social media template,
but very few people are
offering the full package
that makes a brand feel
professional and trustworthy.
That's why the brand identity
market has exploded in the
last few years
and was valued at over
$9.5 billion in 2024,
and it's projected to
hit $40 billion by 2032.
I mean, even governments are
getting in on the action.
Check this out. It's the old Gov UK logo
and this is the new one.
How much do you think they
spent on the redesign?
$10,000, $50,000, a
hundred thousand dollars.
No more like $650,000
or half a million quid.
It's shocking, isn't it?
But it shows that there's a
massive opportunity in this
space, especially if you are
thinking, well, I could do that.
Now it's time for those ratings.
Firstly, how much time does
brand identity take to learn?
I'll give this a four
out of five because it does take time.
It's one of those side hustles
where every project
teaches you something new
and once it clicks, you can start charging
real money for your work.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'm giving this a one out of five
because as long as you have a laptop,
then you really don't need to spend any
money getting started.
The real investment here
is definitely your time
and not your money, so
it's perfect for students.
Thirdly, how easy is it
to make $10,000 per month?
This gets a two out of five
as it's actually very achievable.
I mean, Jack's only been
doing this a few years
and now charges $10,000
for just one project,
but let's say you charge $2,500
for a full brand identity package.
You'd only need four clients a month
or one client a week to
hit 10 k side hustle.
Idea six is short form strategy.
This is Noah Briley.
He was just an ordinary
student doom scrolling social
media until one day.
Instead of passively
consuming, he started studying
what makes content blow up.
He took note of every hook, every caption,
and every transition that made people stop
and watch until he found the exact formula
that led to virality.
Once he cracked the code,
he tested it on TikTok and it worked.
Soon he was helping
creators, tech companies,
and even banks grow their audiences
through short form videos.
This led to him making over
a hundred thousand dollars
before he turned 18 with
nothing but his phone.
The truth is, short form
content isn't just a
trend, it's the future.
The average TikTok user opens
the app 20 times per day,
and TikTok themselves claim
users spend an average
of 90 minutes a day scrolling
this attention is the
new currency.
Just think about all the
young millionaires you
look up to, Mr.
Beast, KSI
or Jake Paul, they all got
rich by leveraging some form
of attention and being a
short form content strategist
allows you to tap into
this power without being a
creator yourself.
Your job is simple.
Help small businesses, entrepreneurs
and coaches grow their brands online.
The opportunities are
absolutely everywhere.
You could work with your
local gym, a coffee shop,
or even an estate agent
who has no idea how
to market themselves on social media.
Every business needs
content and attention,
and right now they happily
pay someone who knows how
to deliver both so onto the ratings.
Firstly, how much time does short form
content take to learn?
I'll give this a one out of five.
You can learn the basics
in just a few days.
The real skill comes from
understanding why something works,
not just how to make it look good.
If you spend even just
one hour a day analyzing
and creating, you'll
start spotting patterns
that most people completely miss.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'm giving this are one out of five
as all you need is your phone,
and most of you're
probably sat watching this
video on one right now.
Lastly, how easy is it to
make $10,000 per month?
This one gets a three out
of five as it really
depends on how you charge.
Once you get good, I highly
recommend charging both a flat
fee, which is what you
get paid no matter what,
and on top something called a view bonus.
This is an agreed upon bonus
that you get paid if the
video ends up going viral.
Most clients will be open to this
as it puts you both on the same page
and incentivizes you to work harder
to make sure videos explode.
If you manage to get a few
viral videos per month,
then $10,000 a month is more
than achievable side hustle.
Idea seven is investing.
That brings us onto this
handsome fella. Oh, it's me.
As you know, I started out with nothing
and managed to build businesses
that made me a millionaire in my twenties.
However, what really took me to
that next level was investing.
My investments currently bring
me in more than $17,000 per
week in passive income.
That's why I truly believe
that investing is the one side hustle
that everyone should have no matter what,
because if your money's
not working for you,
then you'll always be
stuck working for it.
When people stop me in the street,
they always ask me two questions.
The first is, what's the
best time to start investing?
My answer is always the same.
There's never been a better
time to start than right now.
Back in my day, you needed
brokers minimum deposits
and hours of research
just to buy one stock,
but today you can start with
just a few taps on your phone.
The second question they ask is,
how can I actually start investing?
This one isn't as easy
to answer on the street.
That's why I've uploaded lots
of YouTube videos breaking
down my strategies.
If you wanna go even deeper,
the Wealth Portal has hours
of videos from me about investing money
and I upload new videos every single week.
You can even ask me questions directly
and get me to rate your
investing portfolio.
Remember, for a limited time,
you can try everything the
Wealth Portal has to offer
for free by clicking the
link in the description.
Now, let's look at the ratings.
Firstly, how much time does
investing take to learn?
This has gotta be a
four out of five.
It's simple to get started with
something like index funds,
but to pick individual stocks,
you need to master technical
and fundamental analysis,
which takes time.
Secondly, how much money do you need?
I'd say one out of five
because most investing platforms
now offer fractional shares
that let you begin with $1 or one pound.
Lastly, how easy is it to
make $10,000 per month?
I'm gonna say four out
of five because it can take
many years to achieve this.
However, when you do, it
is truly passive income
as it doesn't require any extra work.
If you wanna learn how
to invest for beginners,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay, I'll see you over there.