You'll never make $10,000 a month
until you understand this.
This is Joey.
He got straight A's at school
and graduated from
university top of his class.
He had high hopes for the future
and knew he had something special.
His reward was a job that
pays $5,473 per month,
coupled with a constant
stress over his student loans,
the rising cost of living,
and the fear of being replaced by AI.
That's a real number
based on an actual survey
from over 70,000 bachelor's
degree graduates.
So if Joey worked this hard
and still didn't manage
to make $10,000 per month,
surely it's impossible, right?
Not at all.
This is Kye.
He got kicked out of school
for being disruptive,
and there was no way he was
getting into university.
Like Joey, he also had
high hopes for the future,
but without a path to follow,
he started to think independently.
His reward was an income
of over $15,000 per month,
coupled with no debt
and the ability to travel
the world whenever he wants.
Not only this, but instead of
fearing AI will replace him,
he actually uses it to make more money.
As I'm sure you've gathered,
Joey represents the path most
people are told to follow.
However, Kye, he's a real person
who earns three times more
than people who are 10 times
more qualified than him.
And it's not just Kye.
There are lots of examples
of people just like him,
earning way more than most
people even think is possible.
So while are these people
doing that Joey isn't,
and how can it even be fair?
Well, while others were so
focused on achieving good grades,
going to university, and getting a job,
these guys were paying attention
to where the world was actually going,
and they all became something
called a digital architect.
This is the number one
way to make money online.
It blows every other
method out of the water.
Now, let me be clear.
I'm not saying going to
university is a bad thing.
It's needed for a lot of jobs in society,
and if making money
isn't your main ambition,
then be my guest.
However, if you wanna hit $10,000 a month
and, more importantly,
have a life of freedom,
adventure, and wealth, then in this video
I'm gonna show you how
you can quickly and easily
become a digital architect,
just like these guys.
(light groovy music)
Everyone's talking about looksmaxxing
when they should be
talking about talentmaxxing
because, honestly, the worst
advice anyone can give you
is to improve your weaknesses.
The school system has told
you to do this for years.
If you are bad at maths, they
make you do extra lessons.
If you don't like public
speaking, they force you into it.
And if you hate languages,
then tough luck,
as you'll have to spend hours
trying to learn one anyway.
They treat us all the same
and disregard our natural talents,
and you can actually
see the effect of that.
One study found that 98% of five-year-olds
scored at genius level
for divergent thinking,
which is basically the ability
to come up with lots of original ideas,
but by adulthood, that drops to just 2%.
So it's not that people aren't talented;
it's that it all gets trained out of them.
Before you say, "I don't
have any natural talents,"
check this out.
It's called the talent tree,
and believe it or not, your
talent is on here somewhere.
That's because everyone, no
matter your level of education,
fits into at least one of
these four main categories.
So while I'm going through this with you,
make sure to note down
where you are on the tree,
because once you know
that, we'll know exactly
what kind of digital
architect you can become.
The first type is the organizer.
These are the people who
bring structure to chaos.
They're good at planning systems
and keeping things running smoothly.
The second type is the analyst.
They're good at breaking
things down, spotting patterns,
and figuring out what actually works.
The third type is the communicator.
They're good at explaining things clearly,
influencing others,
and getting people to buy into something.
The fourth type is the creative.
They see things differently,
connect dots others don't,
and come up with new ways of doing things.
So those are the four
types of natural talents.
Hopefully, you've got the area
you identify most with written down.
From now on, if you're
serious about making
$10,000 per month,
then you need to make
a promise to yourself
that you're only gonna work in the area
where you have a clear advantage.
I'm breaking this down in even more depth
in the free virtual event
I'm running very soon.
Not just what your advantage is,
but how you can go from where you are now
to hitting $10,000 per month
without needing startup
capital or experience.
So if you're serious about
increasing your income,
then make sure to sign up for that.
I'll leave a link in the description.
(light funky music)
The fastest way to make
$10,000 a month online
is to sell a digital service,
but you'll never get close
to that amount of income
unless you follow the three golden rules:
make a business more money,
save a business time, or
save a business money.
That's why servicemaxxing is
all about finding a service
that does one or more of those things
and also plays into your natural talents.
This is where most people get stuck,
as they don't know what to actually do.
So to make it easy for you,
I've loaded this grid up
with the top five online
services you can offer right now.
After I reveal each one,
I'll let you know exactly
what this service is, why it makes money,
and, most importantly, who's best suited
based on talent type.
By the way, all of these have
the potential to make you
over $10,000 per month, and
they're in no particular order.
For now, don't worry about
how to do the service;
they can all be learned
very quickly anyway.
The important thing right
now is understanding
which one best suits you.
So let's kick this off
with brand identity.
This one sounds complicated,
but it's really not.
It involves designing the
look and feel of a business,
from the logo and colors
to the fonts, images,
and overall style that makes
it instantly recognizable.
I've made my dislike of designer brands
very clear over the years.
However, they are the perfect example
of how valuable good branding is.
A lot of people say the
designer items cost more
because of the quality
or the level of service,
but that doesn't justify the majority
of their huge price tags.
That purely comes down to the perception
of the brand itself.
That's why a brand identity service
is so valuable to businesses,
as it can allow them to charge
much higher prices for the
same product or service,
which ultimately makes
a business more money.
This type of online service
is perfect for the creative,
as it requires an
out-the-box visual thinking.
However, not just that.
The organizer will do well here, too,
because the timelines,
the client feedback,
and the deliverables are just as important
as the design itself.
Next up is AI automation.
Now, this one is massive right now,
and it's only getting bigger.
It involves building AI systems
that automate repetitive tasks.
Stuff like responding to
customers, generating reports,
scheduling, data entry,
the admin tasks that
someone in the business
is currently doing
manually every single day.
Just think, every hour a
business spends on a task
that could be automated,
it's money down the drain.
So when you come in and fix it,
you're not just saving them time,
you are saving them money too,
which means you are hitting
two of our three rules at once.
This one suits the analyst
because you need to look at a business
and identify exactly where
the inefficiencies are,
but also the organizer
because building these systems
requires quite a structured,
logical approach.
Next: deal-making.
This one might surprise you
because it's not about a
technical skill at all.
It involves connecting
businesses with opportunities.
Think sponsorships, brand
deals, and partnerships.
You are essentially the
person in the middle
who makes things happen.
Businesses will happily pay a
finder's fee or a commission
when you bring something
valuable to the table,
as this directly makes a business money.
So who's best suited to
take something like this on?
Well, firstly, it has
to be the communicator
without a doubt.
If you are naturally
persuasive, confident on calls,
and good with people, this is your lane.
But the organizer can play a big role too,
because juggling multiple
deals, follow-ups,
and relationships is super important.
All right, now for video editing.
This isn't about sitting
there cutting clips for fun.
It involves editing video content
that grows a business's
audience and generates revenue.
Think YouTube channels,
ads, social media content,
and sales videos.
This is the kind of content
that actually makes a difference,
as businesses that show
up consistently on video
grow faster, sell more,
and build trust quicker
than those that don't.
But most business owners have no idea
how to edit and no time to learn.
A good editor who understands
what performs well
is genuinely hard to find
and can both save a business
time and make them more money.
The obvious person that's
suited to this is the creative.
You need a real eye for
pacing, storytelling,
and what looks good on screen.
But the analyst is just as important here
because the best editors
aren't just making things look pretty;
they're studying what performs and why.
And last, but absolutely
not least, funnel creation.
This one is probably the
most directly tied to money
out of everything on this list.
It involves building the online journey
that turns a stranger
into a paying customer.
Think landing pages, email
sequences, checkout flows,
upsells, the whole shebang.
A great funnel can double or
triple what a business makes
from the exact same amount of traffic.
You are not getting them more exposure.
You are making them more money
from the leads they already have.
The organizer will thrive here
because a funnel is
essentially a detailed system
with a lot of moving parts
that all need to work together.
The same goes for the analyst,
because the best funnels
aren't built on gut feeling.
They're built on data, testing,
and understanding what makes people buy.
I know this might just look like
another list of different side hustles,
but don't think of them like that.
Think of them as vehicles
that can get you to $10,000 a month.
As a digital architect,
your vehicle might look slightly different
depending on where you're trying to go
and what suits you best.
But the destination stays the same.
I mean, what if I told you
the type of service you pick
isn't actually that important?
As long as it follows
the three rules we talked about earlier
and it leans into your natural strengths,
you can get to at least
$10,000 a month right now.
The most important thing
is just picking one
and sticking with it,
because in the next steps,
I'm gonna show you how to
take any of these services
and supercharge it as a digital architect.
We'll be going over all
of this in even more depth
on the free live virtual
event I'm running soon,
so make sure to click the
link in the description
to sign up for that if
you haven't already.
(light groovy music)
The biggest lie young people are told
is that learning happens before earning.
I mean, for the first
18 years of your life,
you're forced to sit in a
classroom for hours on end
and learn stuff,
but never actually apply
it to the real world.
The truth is, if you wanna
make $10,000 a month quickly,
then you need to be learning
and earning at the same time.
This is the skillmaxxing loop,
and I designed it for my son
when he left school at 18.
He wanted to become a
videographer and video editor,
but said he wasn't ready.
For context, he'd been making
little YouTube videos for a while
but didn't have any formal training.
I told him to forget what
school had taught him
about learning and
instead follow my method,
as it would make him richer a lot faster.
He actually listened to me,
for once, and thank God he did.
As he now makes way more
than $10,000 a month
following the exact method
I'm about to teach you.
Don't worry if you don't
wanna be a videographer,
it can be applied to any type of service.
First, you need to define your service.
In the last step, you already
picked what you're gonna do,
but now you need to strip
it back to its simplest,
most usable form, not the
perfect version in your head.
This is where people let themselves down.
They take something simple
and then overcomplicate it.
They start adding extras,
trying to perfect it all
because they don't feel ready.
I can't tell you how many times
I've been stopped in the streets
by people saying, "I
want to be a billionaire.
What should I do?"
And honestly, that's part of the problem.
They're aiming so big
that they don't even know where to start.
There's nothing wrong
with having big ambitions,
but if all your focus is on the end goal,
you never actually take the first step.
So instead of thinking about a billion,
focus on hitting $10,000 a month.
'Cause if you don't have something
realistic to aim at right now,
you'll just sit there overthinking it.
So how can you actually
define your service?
Well, for my son,
it wasn't become a
professional videographer
or build a creative agency.
It was simple: edit videos for businesses.
So take your service and reduce it down
to one clear thing that you can deliver.
It'll make your life a whole lot easier.
Second, you need to sell your service.
Not learn more, not tweak your offer,
not sit there getting better, sell.
This is where most people hesitate.
They think they need more
knowledge before they can charge.
My son did the exact same thing.
I told him to get out there
and start selling his videography service
to local businesses,
but he said he didn't
know enough to charge.
I told him, "Trust me, son,
there is no better teacher
than the real world."
So he went out there and
started booking meetings
with local businesses, and
yeah, 99% of them said no.
But that's the point, because
eventually one said yes,
a local caravan park.
So accept you aren't perfect,
and get out there and start selling.
Every rejection teaches you something.
It's about getting in front of people
and learning what actually lands.
Thirdly, you need to deliver your service.
This is where you actually get paid
and, more importantly,
where you actually get good.
Because it's all well and
good practicing by yourself,
however, until you have a paying client,
you never really know
what the most valuable
things are to focus on.
You also don't get real feedback,
which is sometimes hard to hear.
With my son, as soon as
that caravan park said yes,
everything changed.
He couldn't hide behind
"I'm not ready" anymore.
He actually had to sit
down, film the videos,
meet expectations, and
figure it all out as he went.
And that's exactly what happened,
because when there's money involved,
you just operate differently.
You pay more attention, you learn faster,
and you fix mistakes quickly
because there's actual pressure involved.
It's the same no matter
what service you picked.
If it's video editing,
you're not just messing
around with clips anymore;
you're creating content
that helps a business grow.
If it's deal-making, you're
not just sending messages;
you're trying to bring
in real opportunities
that make someone money.
That's where the real skill is built,
and this is what most
people don't realize.
Fourth, you need to fix your service.
This step was always part of the process,
even when I taught my son this years ago,
but back then it was a lot more manual.
You had to rely on experience,
feedback, and trial and error
to figure out what was
working and what wasn't.
But now with AI, you can do it properly.
Because once you've delivered
your service a few times,
you'll start to see patterns,
what's getting results,
what's not, and more importantly,
where the bottlenecks are.
This isn't about
automating everything yet.
It's about improving the way your service
actually gets done.
If you're editing videos
and it's taking you hours
to do something repetitive,
that's a bottleneck.
If you're doing deal-making
and spending ages researching
or writing messages,
that's also a bottleneck.
Using AI to remove those bottlenecks
will make you far more efficient
and therefore more money in the long run.
Lastly, you need to
systemize your service.
Up until now, everything's
been a bit scrappy,
and that's exactly how it should be.
You've been moving fast
and figuring things out,
but if you stay like that,
deadlines get missed,
messages get lost, payments get delayed,
and that's the reason most
people never get repeat work.
Because the thing that
actually makes you stand out
isn't talent, it's reliability.
I mean, the people I've
paid the most money to
aren't always the best.
They're the ones who deliver on time
and communicate clearly.
One of the best platforms
helping you with this is Odoo,
because it's an all-in-one
business management software
that provides you with
a range of applications
to simplify the day-to-day
management of your business,
including invoicing,
accounting, project management,
website creation, and more.
I remember when my son was
asked to send his first invoice.
He had no idea what he was doing,
so I showed him what my
invoices looked like,
and he had to manually make his own.
However, it's much easier now
with Odoo's invoicing app.
It makes it super simple
to add your customer,
your services, and their
price and quantities.
You can then select your invoice
due date and payment terms,
which can be emailed to the
customer, allowing them to pay
directly through Odoo's customer portal.
Odoo will then track if
it's being paid or not,
which saves you from doing it manually.
From my experience,
late payers are very common
in the online service space,
so it's very important
to keep your discussions,
emails, and notes in one place
through this feature called the Chatter,
so you can quickly see who
you need to follow up with.
I used to do this manually,
and all the time I was wasting
could have just gone
into making more money.
As I was planning on
talking about them anyway,
I reached out to Odoo
to see if they wanted to sponsor
this portion of the video.
They agreed and are also giving you
your first application free for life
with unlimited support and hosting.
So that means you can start using
the invoicing app for free.
I'll drop a link in the description.
You might be wondering why this
is a loop, and it's simple.
Because you don't just go through
this once and you're done.
Every time you complete these five steps,
you end up in a better position
than where you were when you started.
You've got more skill, more
experience, better results,
and a clearer understanding
of what actually works.
So when you go back to define,
you're not starting from
scratch; you're refining.
When you sell again,
you're more confident,
your pitch is better,
and more people say yes.
When you deliver, the quality is higher.
When you fix, you are
removing bigger bottlenecks,
and when you systemize,
everything runs smoother.
Then it repeats, and each
time you go round the loop,
your service becomes more valuable,
which is what pushes you towards
$10,000 a month and beyond.
(light peppy music)
Believe it or not, you
can do the same service
as someone else to the exact same standard
and earn 10 times more.
That shouldn't make sense,
as you'd think you get paid
based on how good you are, but you don't.
You get paid based on how
you position your value.
This is where things
start to step up a level
because once you've been around
the skillmaxxing loop a few times,
you're no longer just
someone who does a service.
You understand outcomes,
you understand businesses,
and you understand what
actually makes money.
That's when positioning
becomes super powerful.
Let me show you what I mean.
On the left side is how a
freelancer positions themselves.
On the right is how a
digital architect does it.
Let's start with brand identity.
A freelancer says, "I design logos,"
which is simple and easy to understand,
but it also sounds cheap.
You're competing with
thousands of other people,
and the only thing that
separates you is price.
That's why a digital
architect doesn't sell a logo.
They say, "I increase perceived value
so businesses can charge more
and attract better customers."
See how this involves the
exact same amount of work,
but offers dramatically more value?
Now, instead of seeing you as a cost,
you're now an investment.
Now let's look at AI automation.
A freelancer says, "I
can build AI chatbots."
Again, nothing wrong with that,
but you're just selling a feature.
A digital architect says,
"I remove manual work
and reduce costs by
automating bottlenecks."
Now you're not just building something;
you're saving them time and
money every single month.
And lastly, funnel creation.
A freelancer says, "I
build landing pages,"
but a digital architect says,
"I turn existing traffic
into paying customers."
Now you're directly tied to revenue,
which again is the same
skill and the same output,
but with completely different positioning.
The key is to stop
talking about what you do
and start talking about
what it does for them.
That's how you use positionmaxxing
to go from charging
a few hundred to a few thousand
for the exact same service.
(light groovy music)
A lot of people aren't
gonna like this one,
but most of you will never
get past 10K a month.
Not because you're not working hard enough
or the opportunity isn't there,
but because getting to 10K
per month is one challenge,
making 20K, 50K,
or 100K plus per month is
a completely different one.
I know these numbers might
feel miles away at the moment,
but if you don't understand this now,
then you'll hit that
10K level and plateau.
That's where brandmaxxing comes in.
This is the process of
building a personal brand
so strong and visible that
people instantly see you
as an authority in your space.
One of the most powerful examples
of this is Casey Neistat.
He sold his company to CNN
for a reported $25 million,
but the business itself
wasn't the real asset.
There was no clear plan for what CNN
were even gonna do with it.
What they were really buying
was his personal brand.
That was back in 2016,
and since then, this has
only become more important
because now more than ever,
your personal brand is what
makes you more valuable
than everyone else
offering the same thing.
So how can you easily do
this without trying to build
a YouTube channel with
millions of subscribers?
Well, the most simple
thing you can do right now
is clean up your social media profiles.
Make it very obvious who
you are, what you do,
and why you're the best at it.
Most people are doing the opposite.
They put no time into their profile.
Instead, just focus on cold
messaging hundreds of people.
That's why they just get ignored.
I'm willing to bet you've got
a ton of unanswered messages
just like this in your requests.
But when someone lands on your profile,
and it instantly shows what
you do and how you do it,
you are no longer just another message.
And when you combine that
with actually understanding
who you are messaging and how
to approach them properly,
that's how you break past 10K
a month and scale beyond it.
If you wanna discover the
five levels to getting rich,
I'm gonna leave that video right up there,
but don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe if
you want to grow your wealth.
Okay? (clicks tongue)
I'll see you over there.