AI is forcing me to change
how I manage my money.
You see, I've made millions from investing
over the past 35 years,
and most of that success has
come from one simple strategy.
- An S&P 500 low-cost index fund.
- [News Reporter] S&P 500 index fund.
- The S&P, American.
- The S&P 500.
- The S&P 500-
- Has returned an average
of over 10% per year.
- This is known as passive investing,
as your money automatically gets split
between the top 500 companies in the USA.
So rather than having to
actively pick winning stocks,
you instead just buy a
small piece of all of them.
The idea is that even
if some stocks crash,
owning lots of them protects you,
and you still benefit as
the overall market grows.
I'm not gonna lie, over the years,
this has been proven to
be a fantastic strategy.
As I've said, I've earned
millions doing exactly this.
However, after making my last video
about a potential AI bubble,
I sat down, reviewed my
investments, and made a few changes.
So in this video, I'm gonna be revealing
the five things I changed because of AI.
(lively orchestral music)
Believe it or not,
for every dollar you
invest into the S&P 500,
40 cents of it will go
into just 10 companies.
These companies are NVIDIA,
Microsoft, Apple, Alphabet,
Amazon, Broadcom, Meta,
Tesla, Berkshire Hathaway,
and finally, JPMorgan.
As of filming this video, these
companies currently make up
a whopping 40% of the entire index fund.
What's even more concerning
is that NVIDIA alone
will get between seven to eight cents
of every dollar you
invest into the S&P 500.
This is because the index fund
is called market-cap-weighted,
which simply means the more
valuable a company becomes,
the bigger slice of the fund it takes up.
So what's actually causing these companies
to become more and more valuable?
Well, if we put Berkshire Hathaway
and JPMorgan to one side for a moment
because they don't really
fit the same pattern,
something interesting starts to happen.
What we're left with
is a group of companies
that share one very specific trait.
They're all spending aggressively
on the same thing: AI.
You might be thinking, "That's great.
AI is the future, so
this all makes sense."
However, not so fast.
For all these AI companies
to justify their current valuations,
they would need to make
around $2 trillion in revenue.
To put that into perspective,
that's more than NVIDIA, Microsoft, Apple,
Alphabet, Amazon, and
Meta combined in 2024.
This shows these companies
at the top of the S&P 500
aren't being valued based
on what they own today,
but on what investors expect
them to earn in the future.
Now, this isn't a major issue on its own,
as it's very common for companies
to be valued on their future potential.
However, it is quite worrying
when it's all linked to
one type of technology.
These companies are all
essentially making the same bet
that AI is the future,
and they're financing
it with a ton of debt.
A great example of this
is Sam Altman saying
he's willing to commit
$1.4 trillion in spending
for AI infrastructure,
when his company, OpenAI,
is currently only making
$13 to $20 billion in yearly revenue.
A lot of this debt is also pretty hidden.
As I discussed in my last video,
these companies are
bumping up their valuations
by passing money around to each other.
It's a whole complicated mess.
Long story short, it's all
a massive feedback loop
that keeps reinforcing itself.
Bigger companies attract
more passive investment,
which pushes their prices higher,
giving them a bigger share of the S&P 500,
and therefore even more money to grow
from passive index fund
investors just like us.
This is having a knock-on effect
of making the US economy look strong.
However, data from Deutsche
Bank actually argues
that if it wasn't for
AI spending right now,
then we'd already be in a recession.
So what if instead of prioritizing
the biggest companies,
we could spread our money equally
across every company in the S&P 500?
Well, we actually can
with something called an
equal-weighted S&P 500 index fund,
and on the surface, it looks
like the perfect solution.
Instead of having 40%
concentrated in the top 10 stocks,
it's around 2% as every
company is treated equally.
By investing in something like this,
there is no doubt that
you are less exposed
to the potential AI bubble
that is currently forming.
However, it's not the perfect solution
because we're trying to limit the money
going into larger companies,
it might actually lead
to a much bigger problem,
as it follows something called
a negative momentum approach,
which sounds complicated,
but it's really not.
All it means is that when
a company in the S&P 500
starts to take off, think
Tesla during its big run,
the fund automatically
sells some of it as it rises
and uses that money to buy
companies that haven't gone up.
So you're effectively selling the winners
and buying the losers purely
to keep everything balanced.
On the flip side, a
normal S&P 500 index fund
that's market-cap-weighted
doesn't need to trade nearly as often.
When a company gains momentum,
it's simply allowed to take up
a bigger share of the index.
Instead of trimming the winners,
the fund gradually reduces
exposure to smaller companies
to make room for the larger ones.
But why does this matter?
Well, the more a fund trades,
the higher the costs are.
Therefore, it's something
that's often overlooked
and can eat into your gains.
That's why, although
I'm putting less money
into the S&P 500, I'm
still keeping the majority
of my stock market portfolio
in the regular
market-cap-weighted version.
So now I freed up some of
my money from the S&P 500.
The real question is, where is it going?
Well, that brings me on to...
(light pulsing electronic music)
I want you to imagine for a moment
that the biggest stock market
returns over the next 20 years
don't come from the USA.
I know that might sound crazy
because for the last 14 years,
the American markets have
absolutely dominated.
However, this chart shows
which countries made up
the largest share of
the world stock market
at different points in history.
And guess what?
It hasn't always been the USA.
I know this looks a bit confusing,
but it's effectively showing
the global stock market
just like a cake with multiple layers.
Each color represents a different country,
and the thickness of each layer
shows the percentage of
the world stock market
that country makes up
at that point in time.
The cake itself doesn't change.
It's always the global market.
What changes is which layers get thicker
and which ones get thinner.
Let's look back at 1900.
The United Kingdom was
the global superpower.
As you can see, they had
a nice juicy 24% layer
of the global stock market cake.
London was the financial
capital of the world,
British companies dominated global trade,
and the Empire stretched
across huge parts of the globe.
If you were investing at the time,
it would've felt completely
obvious that the UK
would remain the dominant economic force
for the next 100 years.
Investing anywhere else
would've seemed ridiculous,
and yet that's not how history played out.
I remember seeing something
very similar happen later with Japan.
I went to Japan a lot
throughout the late 1980s
and early '90s, and at the time,
Japanese companies were
performing incredibly well,
particularly in areas
like cars, electronics,
and technology.
Meanwhile, the US economy was struggling,
inflation was high, growth was slowing,
and a lot of people believed
that Japan was the future.
So if you were investing back then,
would you have bet against Japan
and doubled down on America?
Probably not.
However, America bounced back big time.
This shows the only thing
that's ever been certain
in markets is uncertainty.
Leadership changes,
economic dominance shifts,
and no country stays on top forever,
which is exactly why I
don't want my portfolio
to rely entirely on one market,
even one as strong as the US.
Because when you only
invest in the S&P 500,
you completely miss out on
companies like TSMC, Samsung,
Toyota, Tencent, AstraZeneca, and HSBC.
These are global businesses
operating at huge scale,
driving real growth, yet they're excluded
purely because of where
their headquarters are based.
So how am I actually investing globally?
Well, this is Trading 212.
It's the broker I personally use.
And if you go to the search
bar and type in "VWRP,"
you'll find this global stock market fund
that gives you instant exposure
to pretty much the entire world's economy.
This single fund invests in around 3,700
to 3,800 companies spread
across more than 45 developed
and emerging countries, including
the US, UK, Europe, Japan,
and fast-growing economies
like China and India.
And yes, I know if you dig into
what these funds actually hold,
you'll see they're still heavily
dominated by US companies.
The difference is what happens over time.
A global fund automatically rebalances.
If the US becomes less dominant
and China or another country
starts outperforming,
the fund adjusts.
If the US continues to lead,
it adjusts for that too.
It also has an extremely
low expense ratio of 0.19%.
That means for every $1,000 invested,
you're paying roughly
$1.90 annually in fees,
which is pretty cheap.
If you are based in the
USA, then I'd recommend
looking into Fidelity's International Fund
with the ticker "FSPSX."
If all this sounds a bit complicated,
Trading 212 actually make it really simple
with their model pies.
These are pre-built, globally
diversified portfolios
put together by
professional asset managers,
and you can easily choose a risk level
that feels right for you.
Since I was planning to talk
about Trading 212 anyway,
I reached out to see if
they'd like to sponsor
this portion of the video.
They agreed and have given
you free fractional shares
worth up to 100 pound
when you scan this QR code
or enter the promo code
TILBURY by tapping this menu
and head into the promo code section.
If you're new to investing,
then you can put in as
little as one pound,
claim your free fractional shares,
and start exploring the app
before fully jumping in.
You can also invite your friends,
and once they fund their accounts,
you'll both get free fractional shares.
(groovy electronic music)
The best piece of advice
I've ever been given
about building real wealth
is that you don't get rich
by following the crowd.
You get rich by being early.
I've applied this thinking
throughout my whole life.
So, as well as protecting myself
against the potential AI bubble,
I also think it's important
to look for a way to benefit
from this new technology.
So let me talk you through where I see
the biggest opportunities at the moment.
The market naturally breaks
down into four clear zones,
each one filled with
different types of companies.
Well, that's how I look at it, anyway.
Let's start with this one.
I call it the crowded zone.
Companies in this zone
have a large market cap
and expensive valuation.
Think the top companies in the S&P 500,
such as NVIDIA, Tesla, and Meta.
It's crowded, as everyone
is already investing here,
even passive investors.
Under that, we have the defensive zone.
This includes companies
like McDonald's, Walmart,
and Coca-Cola.
These are businesses that people rely on,
no matter what the economy is doing.
These are the kinds of companies
value investors like Warren Buffett love.
They're valuations aren't
low, but they're good value
because their earnings are
predictable, demand is stable,
and they keep generating
cash year after year.
In the top left is the speculative zone.
These are smaller companies
that are extremely hyped
and have valuations that far
exceed their current revenue.
They usually have low
or modest market caps,
but very expensive stock prices
because investors are betting
on massive future returns.
Examples include companies
like Beyond Meat, Peloton,
and AMC during their hype phases.
I personally stay away from
these kinds of investments,
as they're highly speculative
and driven by momentum and internet hype.
If you ask me, it's closer to gambling.
That brings us to this one.
I call it the overlooked zone.
Now, this is where I believe
there is a ton of opportunity,
especially when it comes to AI.
Let me explain.
The companies in this crowded zone
are all betting on the fact
that whoever spends the most money
developing the absolute best AI model
will have all the profits.
But what if that isn't the case?
A pattern I'm seeing more
and more amongst startups,
small-cap, and medium-cap companies
is they're actually giving the user
the ability to pick
between different AI models
within their software.
They let users choose
between Claude, ChatGPT,
and Gemini, just to name a few.
This is important because
they're now all getting
pretty close in abilities.
So the biggest factor
in what a user chooses
might end up being the price,
which would then lead these
companies into a price war,
which is great for people using AI,
but not so great for huge companies
that have spent billions
developing these AI models.
It's kind of like petrol,
or gas if you're American.
Imagine one station sells
it for $1.50 per liter,
and another sells petrol
that's slightly better quality
for $3 per liter.
Sure, a few people will
still pay the extra
for the premium option,
but most people will
just buy the cheaper fuel
because it pretty much
does the same thing.
And that's the real point.
When new technology becomes
good enough and interchangeable,
the value doesn't stay with the companies
that spent the most money building it;
it flows to the companies that
use it in the smartest way.
So that's exactly why I'm
backing the underdogs.
Small and mid-cap businesses
don't need to win the AI arms race.
They just need to apply
AI to real problems
at a lower cost without
carrying billions in debt.
That's why I'm investing
in a couple of small
and mid-cap funds as
well as actively looking
for AI startups to invest in.
So if you are a founder
and you are looking for
an experienced investor
with a large social media following,
then feel free to reach out
using the email in the description.
I'm currently considering proposals.
Look, if I'm wrong, I lose
a small amount being early,
but if I'm right, I'm positioned
where there could be a massive upside.
(light thoughtful electronic music)
I feel like a lot of
people don't understand
that every major leap in
technology creates opportunity,
but more importantly, instability.
I mean, AI isn't just changing companies;
it's changing power, currencies,
and trust in the system.
That's why I'm increasing
my gold reserves,
and I'm not alone.
Check this out.
This chart shows China's gold levels
between 2009 and 2025.
Up to 2023, they were
steadily buying gold,
but as you can see, in recent years,
they've been buying up
more gold than ever.
But why does this matter for
everyday investors like us?
Well, many people believe China
is trying to replace the US dollar,
as they're not just buying it quietly;
they're making it usable.
They've been building something
called the Gold Corridor,
which allows gold to be stored
across different locations
and used as a form of trust
in international trade,
especially with Brazil, Russia,
India, and South Africa,
otherwise known as the BRICS nations.
And it's not just China.
Gold has now overtaken US Treasuries
as the world's largest
foreign reserve asset
held by central banks worldwide
for the first time since 1996.
So why are we seeing this
sudden shift towards gold?
Well, as of 2025,
gold has been reclassified
as a Basel III Tier 1 asset.
Put simply, gold can now
be treated the same as cash
or US Treasuries on a
bank's balance sheet,
which is a big change because
before this reclassification,
banks weren't allowed
to count its full value.
This is having a big
effect on the price of gold
because, before this change,
most financial institutions
like central banks,
sovereign wealth funds,
and pension funds kept around
20% of their reserves in gold
and equivalent hard assets.
However, the Bank of America
have now published new guidelines saying
the gold reserve should be closer to 30%.
That 10% increase is driving up demand
because you can't print more gold.
Some people are even saying in five years,
gold could be worth
double what it is today,
and I don't think that's
absolutely unreasonable.
I won't go much deeper
into gold in this video,
but if you want me to break it down
in more detail in a future one,
just give this video a
thumbs-up and let me know.
If we get, let's say, 150,000 likes,
then I'll make one right away.
For now, let's get to the part
I know a lot of you care about:
How do you actually invest in gold?
I personally do it a
couple of different ways.
Firstly, I buy physical gold.
This is my long-term insurance,
and as I'm old-school,
I like having something
I can actually hold.
Secondly, I dollar-cost average
into this iShares physical
gold ETF on Trading 212.
I like doing this because it
gives me a lot more flexibility
to gradually buy in and move
things around when I need to.
So to be clear, I'm not trying to buy
at the best possible time,
and I'm also not going all in on gold.
I'm simply allocating a
small strategic portion
of my portfolio to gold,
the same way countries
and major financial
institutions are doing.
(soft electronic music)
The biggest mistake young
people make when investing
is not having a big enough cash reserve
in case something happens in their life,
which often forces them
to sell their investments
at the worst possible time.
Even as an older guy,
this is still something
I have to consider,
especially if we're in an AI bubble.
And you might be interested
to know that Warren Buffett,
the most successful investor of all time,
is currently increasing his cash pile.
Check this out.
As you can see,
he's been aggressively
increasing his cash pile
over the last couple of years,
and as of Q1 2025, he has a whopping
347.7 billion in cash
and cash equivalents.
This makes sense as he's a value investor
and only buys when the price makes sense,
and right now, he simply
doesn't see many opportunities
that justify putting that cash to work.
That's why I'm gonna be
holding slightly more cash
because if the markets crash,
I don't want it to
negatively affect my life.
Having a bit more cash on hand
also gives you the opportunity
to buy more investments
when the market crashes,
and I say "when," not "if,"
because it always happens at some point.
I was also focused on improving
my money-making skills
during the dot-com crash
in the early 2000s,
and that came in super handy
as I was able to generate
fast money that I could then
invest into the stock market.
On that note, I'm actually teaching you
the fastest path to making
$10,000 a month online
without needing startup
capital or business experience
in a free live online event very soon.
So if you are serious about
increasing your income,
then make sure to sign up for that.
I'll leave a link in the description.
This is super important
because cash is king during
a stock market crash.
(light groovy music)
I've seen way too many people
wait years for a market drop
and miss out on massive
gains in the process.
That's why my strategy is simple.
I'm still gonna keep
putting most of my money
into the S&P 500 so that if
AI continues driving growth,
I'm invested in the businesses
leading that change.
But to protect myself from
a potential AI bubble,
I'm also diversifying
into the global markets,
small- and mid-cap stocks, gold, and cash,
because the truth is
nobody knows what the market will do next.
So instead of trying to predict it,
I'm preparing for both outcomes.
If you want to learn exactly
how to invest for beginners step-by-step,
then I'm gonna leave that
video right up there.
But don't click on it just yet.
Make sure to subscribe
if you want to grow your wealth, okay?
(clicking tongue) I'll see you over there.