so my team and I sat down we really wanted to figure out what are business ideas that are working right now that are making $1,000 a day I think we might have found some of the answers so in this video we're going to be going over
three different business ideas exactly what they do and why we think they made money and grew quickly these business ideas are Super Fresh and one of them is even making over $1,000 a day so if you
love finding fresh business ideas and learning about the stuff that's actually working right now then I think you'll like this episode please leave us feedback in the comments about this new format and tell us which business idea was your favorite all right let's get
into it let's talk about the first one and I'll share my screen for all of these so this first one is called sou farama and it's built by this guy in our
community named Tom Orion and he actually wrote my case study with us and what sarama basically is is an AI generated book business that's doing at
least at the time of this writing you know four or five months ago okay mrr and there's a lot of cool things about this business that we can talk about but some of the things that I found is in
this first like 15 months of building this as a side project he only made like $1,500 and then he jumped into the starter story Academy and did a bunch of bunch of the things that we talked about
in there and was able to grow it to 4K Mr um and then obviously now eventually he's up to 12K Mr um so that is sarama if you look through the kind of this web
page here you can see that it's all geared towards like kids book and I'm pretty sure the idea is like the book is about the child that that they're
covering I think he markets a lot to grandparents um and sort of older folks some other things I think he said he started with started it with like $500 yeah that's what he wrote here in
the case study that's pretty interesting right that he started with such a little amount of money and was able to grow it all the way up to 12K per month have you guys heard about that
yeah yeah Tom such a good guy I remember when he first joined the community he was saying like ultimately his goal was just to be able to quit his job so he
could drop F bombs on LinkedIn that's it wasn't even a revenue goal he said he was like I just want to just be me man yeah I talked to Tom a bunch and I think
probably like my favorite thing about his business is that the customer for him is like old granny's mhm and you know like so many people that end up
sharing their stories on the internet and on Twitter and all this stuff is kind of like they're creating tools for developers or creators or whatever it is his customer he has no benefit of
sharing his story his customer are like old granny's and I think what's also cool is like I I was scrolling through his um his his website and although this is
an AI tool and like the reason why this is business is possible is because AI you know generative of text and images but nowhere on the landing page will you
find the word AI right and that kind of shows you like a lot of people get caught up in AI business ideas and all these things but at the end of the day AI is just a tool to serve you know a
specific customer maybe be cheaper or faster or better and I think people will buy this they might think it's AI they might not but it doesn't say it at all in the page and that's like a good like
a good thing to remember when building stuff is it's not about the tools it's about the problem being solved yeah I mean I was looking at this here every page carefully crafted to inspire young
minds to explore the world make it seems more Boutique than than what we know about in the back end and I think it's cool one other thing I wanted to talk about is um in the case study he talks
about how he grew through Facebook ads you can actually find what meta ads are any business is running and so I I was just I I was curious to see like what
kind of things he is sharing in these ads so like this one archry starring your child create a personalized book that'll remember 12 original portraits of your child say no
more to uninspiring birthday presents and hello to personalized art books personalized picture book about an art history featuring 12 original part so it's so this good copyrighting first of
all but it's all geared towards like pulling at those heart strings on so that was kind of interesting to me too I don't know if you could see more you can see more feel like just even with his
like the colors that he's using and the facial expressions you can just you know it's just smart in the way that he's targeting probably people over the age
of 60 65 years old this like Joy look that they want to give you know their grandchildren or their children yeah I think it's like a when I look at these ads they're so simple they don't seem
like they're like super crazy convincing or anything like that just it's very matter of fact it's like personalized picture book about art history you know that's it's really
simple I think that's when I see that I see it from the lens of like oh like actually like this business is this is a good business right now because the ads don't seem like super crazy over
optimized there's no video right there's no crazy like production of the ad creative is just really simple so that is another thing is like and I've seen a bunch of ideas AI coloring books that's
one that I've seen recently there's a bunch of AI children's books businesses is I feel like this is yeah color Joy I saw this one too AI St story member I think right yeah someone had joined our
was now called the accelerator and uh they had built this and I think made some money with it too which is cool Pat did you talk to tomad all if he had tried anything like any other ads outside of
Facebook or is Facebook I mean I guess that's his main probably target audience right yeah I think Facebook was his big thing the last that weend before we move on to the next one what I thought was interesting is I was talking to Tom and
I was asking him you know what a lot of people will ask is like do you think like AI you know you're going to have more competitors or AI is going to like take over your business and you know put
you out of business because chat GPT gets so good it won't be able to generate these books and I loved his answer from that which was basically I'm not in the AI business I'm in the
children's books business right so he didn't even see himself as an AI business Builder he saw himself as someone who you know helps grandparents feel good about themselves when they
give a gift right no one is going to stop giving gifts no matter what even in when AI takes over people will still give each other gifts right so he's in the gifts business he's not in the AI
business and I just think that was a really especially for someone who's somewhat new and just made their first $10,000 a month that was a really cool perspective and he's Australian too so
that's cool awesome yeah so that's South farama okay the next one is something called hold and uh we actually learned about
this one through the Lazar tutorial or how to build an app with lovable Shameless plug and so what Cod guide is
is it creates in detailed documentation for your AI coding project so basically what that means I think in plain language is a lot of people are trying
these AI coding tools like lovable cursor Vo Dev yeah Dev yeah so there's
these AI coding tools which on face value make it look like I'm just going to type in a few prompts that say you know build me a landing page and in a
few prompts the idea is like can go from prompt to an actual so all these are kind of more or less the same thing but
what problem people run into is it quickly goes like a little bit out of whack like the AI sort of has a mind of its
own and build something that I don't necessarily want or thought would happen and so what code guide does is you can
essentially create like a plan or a document that you feed the AI coding tool that helps keep it un front so yeah here it says give your a model is a
clear blueprint with code guide and so that's that's what this business is and what I think is really cool about it is I found this slack post that this guy
posted in the community back in December he goes it was November 26 I built an MVP in 30 minutes I launched the wait list and got 1300 emails the idea was
validated so in 20 days I built the app and then 76 hours after launch he had 320 paying customers in 6.3k Mr it just seems like pretty cool that he he did
that in such a short amount of time then the last thing and then you know I would love to hear your thoughts is I found this post that he did that is basically outlining like what the
problem is with coding with AI you know 80% AI hallucinations code errors things like that and this post got a ton
of views and then within here he plugs code guide I think this is code guide this is code guide here and showing off you know go join code guide I have 30%
discount 17,000 views on this post alone and obviously 430 on the main post wow um so that's Cod guy what do you think really cool what I just think is
so cool about this story is like you see that slack message and it's like oh I built this in 30 minutes I had this success it looks like an overnight success but I know for a fact this guy's
been you know in the community building in just a member of ss are building for a while I I don't know what worked and what hasn't worked in the past but you know sometimes something just
hits and it takes off so looks like an overnight success but you know it's that's something that's ears in the making so pretty cool to see cool thing to add so I talked to this guy this
project he actually had started this code challenge the 12 startups in 12 months crash this was the 11th app that it cut that
out son of a can you hear me has no can you hear me Marco get on some
Wi-Fi he's on his phone I agree Marco let Marco get some Wi-Fi and I'll share some sauce here you want to share your screen or
yeah let me just make sure yeah I'll share maro's gonna get his Wi-Fi figured out okay okay that's what he shared in the community when did share that
December yeah December he dm'd me few couple weeks ago 10 days ago and he's at 177,000
Mr and he told me that he's going to be closing in February at 27,000 Mr so I told him that we should definitely chat and uh dude he's just on
a rocket ship and I also checked out his account I wanted to see how long he'd been in starter story and it's funny because he was one of the very first people that joined one of our very first accelerators that was over that was
probably about a year ago so sounds like he once he found this idea I'm sure he tried a bunch of things before then it just took off like a rocket ship so I think that's so cool to see it's awesome
what do you think about his just the tweets that he's doing and the kind of strategy around linking his business like why is that doing so Welling off
for him yeah saying how how do he how does he use Twitter to plug his product and something I noticed in a lot of his posts is he links back to code guide and
so the reason I bring this up is because in a lot of our social media posting that we do the starter story is we're constantly linking back to like the main thing we want someone to like remember
her know and I that's that's like a strategy that I've seen obviously us do and a lot of other creators do and I think the reason that works is you become known for like one thing and in
this case it's code guide and you start to like associate that word with this person and you expect to see that in in their post so I think that's something interesting I've noticed about yeah some
of these creators that use social to to grow their business yeah it's interesting like when you look at the Impressions or just the clicks it's it's typically happening in the replies
because you're engaging with people you know people are asking questions it's like a golden moment to just you know plug your business a little bit shamefully yeah for sure so even this
one posted an hour ago it's about post is about something else and then in the end he plugs Cod guide that's something Marco you talked to him yeah yeah I talked to him I'm sorry if my audio
sounds like there's a sugar factor in here but I talked to this guy and um yeah really cool cuz his emphasis was heavily on Twitter he said there's actually like a direct correlation between how much he posts on Twitter and
how many sales that he gets and he said you know he tries to focus on just like educating the market giving people value and then he sees a lot of success with it he said another another one of his
marketing tactics was um tutorial marketing which seemed like in his tweets it's almost like here's you know something wrong and then here's how to actually use it in the right way and um
so I just found that actually really cool so interesting that he just basically makes most of his money or at least drives a lot of sales from Twitter he said he tweets daily and that
actually correlates directly to sales so pretty cool yeah I mean the fast growth is the probably the most interesting thing there I've never seen anything grow that fast and that's usually not
although he sounds like he's doing a good job with his marketing but often times that comes from just building on what do they say like a rising tide lifts all boats so just the rising tide
of AI coding tools look at that yeah look at that growth right there that's crazy zero and that just shows you everything you need to know right there AI coding tools are just going bananas
right now and this solves a painful problem within those AI coding tools which we already talked about so that's just in that's absolutely Bonkers yeah
yeah yeah yeah I think um what's cool about this we made a a viral Instagram re a while ago about AI when it started kind of popping off and it was about
making shovels for just whatever industry you're trying to build for and when I talked to him he said the same things like you know this kind of shovel building strategy can work really well
with AI products because people just like you said it's such a painful problem people need to use it and figure out how to use AI better insane so the shovel things yeah yeah so the I guess
the if you're looking for like a similar idea that could grow like this like all you have to do is just go start using these tools and then run into problems there's I I could I couldn't tell you right now I don't really use these like
no code AI tools so I couldn't even tell you what the problems are but if I use them I'm sure I'd run into more and then they're always changing so then there are always new problems you know when and that's kind of like the nature of
the world is like there's always going to be things that are changing therefore there will always be new problems which that's kind of what we try to find at starter story is find find those new
problems yeah so that's code guide all right I want to talk about this guy his name is Dan gorby I think is his name he built this business it's called the
focus project I'm sure it will pop up here because I actually use it but basically the the premise behind this business is every 15 minutes something pops up on your screen that says hey
what did you work on in the last 15 minutes and he does it on purpose like that because it's hard to get distracted within a 15minute time interval whereas if it was an hour long you'd be like oh
I was working on support you know coding whatever but this is like it's meant to kind of keep you on track so at the end of the day you can see all right where am I spending my time and how can
I organize my day better so I think this business is really cool just because he's I mean he's an awesome guy he's in our community he's pre Revenue right now
but he has been doing a lot of attention earing or Focus we call this term attention earing but he's focusing right now on just getting users and getting attention on his product so Pat I don't
know if you want to share his some of the stuff that he's been doing recently I know you're a little closer to it yeah let me find it real quick what I think it's pre-revenue it's a cool idea you know I think there's a little bit of a
you know it's tough to monetize uh productivity apps because there are so many free ones you know if notion is free to use and tro is free to use and
all these you know time whatever a lot of stuff is free to use so it is hard to monetize something like this but I also think it's a really good first business idea because it's B to see anybody can
use this your ideal customer is anyone anybody wants to be more productive they want to get more done I think he's doing a really good job of just like building it I mean that landing page looks really good and I gotta find his how can I find
his Reddit post that he did yeah let me get it okay this is it okay cool I'll share my screen so yeah he's in the growth accelerator right now and we had this thing called office hours where you
come and show off all the different marketing things that you've tried and I just think he's crushing it because he's getting over his fear of sharing stuff and I think he had this app for a while before and it was just sitting dormant
and nobody was going there we had the basically these templates in uh in starter story accelerator where you can go and like plug it into chat gbt with your project and look at this right here
like he posted it in this random subreddit that has 52,000 members r/productivity apps it's like the perfect ideal customer right and like what I
always tell people is you gotta share your thing from the angle of you the Builder instead of like download my app or not even that as like let me tell you
everything about my app no let me tell you about me and me building this app and like you know achieving this dream and I just love this title right here which is I finally released the focus
project like I did it I finally launched it and he just literally this is ad for his app right and it doesn't seem like a lot but it got 34 upvotes and 22 comments and you know the top one is
this sounds amazing these are all people and he showed me some of his numbers and I think he got hundreds of users from this and I I just think that is like super cool and you can go and replicate
this strategy on Twitter on X and it just reminds me of this other guy that we interviewed and his name is Jack Frick and he had this app called curiosity Quench and this is basically
this is just so cool is um it's also a productivity app it or it helps you stop scrolling and the way that he grew this to hundreds of thousands of users is
just purely through kind of similar to this Reddit one here but in Tik Tok and I'll go and pull up his Tik Tok right now yeah this is curiosity quench it only has 3,000 followers you're like
okay that's not much but look it has 114,000 likes which means there's probably a lot of views too if you start scrolling through and you look at all
these Tik toks they're all the same right they all look like the same visually and he has this like basically this meme format Marco do you want to explain that yeah so this meme format he found it's like this 2 by two meme
format he picked it up just scrolling through Instagram trying to find ideas to make content with and he finds this format he makes videos with it he started posting it and they started
getting traction so he templatized this format like this simple you know 2 by two four pictures on it with some copy at the top copy and paste strategy and
then he just switches up you know the pictures the copy because his app is about replacing like you're scrolling with Hobbies so he just replaces it with these different Hobbies so you can kind
of reach different Target markets and then just copy and paste it over and over again you can just put this on repeat yeah but yeah super cool that you can just basically have this format that
probably takes like 2 minutes to recreate and just keep on posting and posting posting and still get results yeah I mean what's so crazy is like look at that it's like 15.8k views 100,000
views 200,000 views 1.1 million views which is insane yeah that reminds me of there's a different app it's the trip BFF this is like a Solo Traveler app and
one of the ways they grew is through mostly through Instagram I'm pretty sure but they do a similar strategy where they have like these videos that are all more or less the same I think that's is
a good example they have these images of pretty looking people and then it's like they pull up the app in use and I imagine that's what the other one does too yeah this is the thing that I've learned been just like Marco and I have
been just interviewing so many people lately and what what is the number one theme is that they all post a bunch of on Tik Tok see what sticks when one
thing works instead of posting it like oh one more or two more they post it literally 300 times until it literally stops working until they've done it
they've gotten millions of views their competitors have done it it's got million millions of views and then the only thing that will stop them from doing it is just it not getting views anymore and like I remember I posted
about this it's just it's just crazy the everyone is doing this and someone on Twitter I think I was talking about it on a tweet or in replies or something like that and they're like this is so sad because I think people think that
like I mean I think when the when you know YouTube first came out and Tik Tok first came out it's like you know it's all about the creativity something in the algorithms changed recently that it doesn't reward creativity anymore and
now these Founders are just like all right well if you're not going to reward creativity anymore I'm just going to go make some money on this thing so I think that's like something to think about I think something like you've always said too Pat that's always like stuck with me
over the years is like people don't remember what you post like you can post something and a week later do something really similar and even if it hits that same audience people forget they're
scrolling all day long we're all over simulated by media in general and it's interesting cuz like you did the same strategy with starter story what S8
years ago on rdit you found a format that worked and you kind of did it over and over and over again until you had to find the next thing you know so well we talked to David Park who is the founder
of Jenny Ai and he had a good explanation for it was that we're all creatures of habit so we actually like to consume the same thing over and over again and it's not maybe just not the
algorithms like for example I don't know why do people watch Oprah every day for 20 years it's the same format every time it's habit right just want to be
entertained and why does it always have to be something new and creative I think there is definitely a market for creativity and content but probably not
for the mass yeah awesome all right well that's it I hope you guys enjoyed getting a little bit of a behind the scenes fly on thewall look of you know
what we're doing here starter story our entire Mission journey is to find the business ideas the niches the new problems that are worth solving right now our whole goal is like find the
stuff that was working tomorrow right and uh hopefully you're able to see some of that and uh hopefully you enjoyed this and we're going hopefully going to keep doing it let us know in the comments which one you like the most and
if you want to see us cover any other topics whether it's gaming or side projects or whatever you want us to cover put it in the comments thanks for watching and and we'll see you in the next one next week