Welcome back to the Starter Story podcast.
Let me ask you a question.
Do you think every business idea is taken?
The answer is probably yes.
And that's unfortunately why most people give up.
But what if I told you that if your idea has already been done, that's actually a really good sign.
Every single day I see the same businesses hitting 5K, 10K, 100K a month doing the same exact thing.
So why is this the case?
So today we're going to dive into why this is actually a good strategy, why this makes sense,
and three very specific examples of businesses who took an idea that was already being done and did it in a slightly different way and now they're crushing it.
We're going to break down each of these businesses, exactly how much money they make,
and what they do differently and why that made them successful.
So if you think every business idea is taken and that's stopping you from getting started,
please watch this entire video.
I'm going to prove to you that's not true.
and at the end share some examples of billion-dollar companies that you could rip off.
I got Gus here.
Thanks for coming on the show.
Let's talk about billion-dollar ideas and how you can use these to create your own little business that crushes it.
I do a lot of obviously research starter story and something I see a lot in our case studies or the stuff that people submit is that there's lots of ideas that are like the same.
I find that really interesting.
So I have three examples today that I want to talk through of companies that are more or less the same thing as like a really larger competitor or you know 100 million billion dollar companies and how
these essentially tiny clones are making money off of those large ideas.
Cool.
So to start off there's this everybody knows this business.
It is a giant company called Calendarly.
And so everyone's heard of Calendarly.
It's a simple way to share your link and you know get people to talk to you.
And actually Calendarly is for some reason getting a lot of online recently cuz for some reason I I don't actually know I've used Kal in the past.
I think it's fine but I think they're some of their features are you know lacking for some reason.
I'm looking up right now I like to see okay is this really a billion dollar business.
Yeah.
In 2023 calendarly revenue reached 276 million.
So that's revenue.
And then the previous year it had done 181.
So I don't know what they did in 2024, but I'm guessing that they probably grew.
They're probably doing upwards of 350 million, which makes them a billion dollar business.
Maybe even a three Yeah.
billion to2 billion business.
Yeah.
Sure.
Which is insane, you know.
But just a few weeks ago, someone submitted a an interview with Starter Story and it's this little company called Cal.
C A L D A Y.
It's only making $5,000 a month, but from everything I could tell about it, and we're going to poke around this website a little bit.
It is essentially the same thing as Calendarly.
There's some specific things that I saw that were different that I'd love to jive on.
But yeah, if you kind of take a look at this, it's, you know, uh, let's see if I can log in here.
Yeah.
So, calday.me/gus.
I'm going to put that in my browser.
And yeah, essentially select time, whatever.
I'm sure I can sync it to my calendar, but it's like the same as Calendarly.
Yeah.
And so that it just got me thinking like what what does this do like different?
So the first thing I always try to go to is like pricing.
Okay.
Cal pricing for Calendarly $10 per seat per month.
So that's not that different.
What is different then?
Yeah.
And the one thing that I found that was slightly different and we can talk about whether this is a big enough like market or not is it
seems like they market more towards like service industry people.
Pet sitting coaches, accountants, photographers, recruiters.
So there's like a maybe a more specific focus of people that they're trying to get to use this to use the software.
Whereas Calendarly is like everybody anybody and everybody can use Calendarly 20 million professionals etc.
You know obviously it's huge.
If you look at like who we serve you'll see there's all these like sort of niche smaller types of customers.
I'm sure they even have articles.
I'm sure this is like SEO.
When you go to that page and they say that it's it's this is better for tutors.
Do they have like specific features that like are you know you wouldn't get with Calendarly that a tutor would need?
That's a great question.
Yeah.
So there must be something on on there that tutors need more of.
Simplified schedules for students.
All lessons in one calendar.
Automated notifications.
This is I mean it's all the same thing Calendarly does, right?
Yeah.
Connect apps.
There is no differentiator at all.
I mean it looks nicer.
Yeah.
It looks like nicer, cleaner.
Customizable.
But I imagine Yeah.
A lot of these features.
Why is Kelly the best alternative?
Like if I search like calendar booking for tutors in Google, it would not come up in the top page.
Yeah.
But I am seeing all the different calendarly knockoffs.
Ton.
Yeah.
So, I think that was something that I was interested in as I was like looking at this business and reading,
you know, reading the the case study is like in some ways there's like nothing that different about this company,
which I think what it makes me think is like that's awesome that you can essentially build a very similar type of business.
I bet they're doing like SEO stuff or just like marketing stuff to get their word out.
Yeah.
And still make Yeah.
five grand a month.
You know, I'm sure that's gonna just keep growing.
I think competing on features is a bad move.
So, even if this did have better features for tutors, it probably wouldn't necessarily sell more,
right?
Yeah.
I think what this proves is two things.
Is that this is a huge total addressable market.
Every single professional, basically, every adult has a calendar, needs a calendar, right?
Even if you work at a company, you need a calendar.
Even if you work as a freelancer, you need a calendar and most people need calendar scheduling software.
Like even I use calendar scheduling software and I consider myself a pretty big minimalist when it comes to like tools and that sort of thing.
The other thing is that it just goes to show you that attention and distribution is everything,
right?
Just the fact that they have a page called tutor scheduling for tutors.
Yeah.
Can you search Calendarly scheduling for tutors and see if that comes up?
Let's see.
If Calendarly doesn't have that, then they're just winning from a marketing perspective,
right?
For education.
Yeah.
Right.
So, their their article is clicked that scheduling software for education.
The tutor who goes into this is probably going to they're going to be like, "Oh, well,
I'm not really education.
I'm not a work at college or something like that.
I'm a tutor.
So, I might go for that."
Even though the features, if you were to like pound for pound go and try both of them out,
the Calendarly may have more features because it's just a bigger app, but they don't have the marketing.
And that marketing makes me feel good if I'm a tutor and maybe I just try that and I use that and I never try anything else.
Yeah.
So, this is like imagine if they had I don't know Tik Toks for talking about how to,
you know, reduce no-shows.
Like they're showing the right features in their marketing, not necessarily having the right features.
And that's something that I see from a lot of people is like, "Oh, I'm just going to build these features or build these features better."
No, you need to think about how you're going to, yes, build those, but market them and also the right ones and then market them correctly.
Right.
So, yeah, that would be the two things that makes me think, look, it's $5,000 a month,
but like you said, this is a subscription business.
It's going to grow.
And I can think of so many calendar scheduling apps that people use more than Calendarly,
right?
Yeah.
Cal.com.
They're huge.
There's so many different ones.
Savvy Cal, uh, you can book me.
Yeah, there's so many that that's that's always a good sign to see like lots of different players in the space.
If you obviously not if you want to build a billion dollar business, but if you want to build a business that can make 5,000,
10,000, $100,000 a month, this is a great place to be.
Yeah, that that is always so interesting to me.
And I think it's probably super easy to get like discouraged when you see all these competitors cuz like,
oh like it's already done.
What am I going to do differently?
But it's it's also at the same time crazy that you see all these companies that are at least moderately successful.
Yeah.
And you can personally define what that means to you.
So yeah, Cal, try it out.
It looks easy to use.
Did it in two clicks.
Okay, that's the first one.
All right, so let me stop you right there real quick.
I do have to talk about the starter story build accelerator.
If you want to build something like calday, which is certainly possible to build with AI tools,
should definitely check out the AI build accelerator.
It is our brand new program where you will come up with an idea.
You'll build it.
You'll ship it.
You'll get it live on a real website, a real production app with a database, AI APIs,
all hooked up.
You'll come out the other side in a few days with a real working app and the skills to build anything you want going forward.
These AI tools, they work right now, but they're a little tough to really build something real.
Well, we have an expert named Lazar.
He's on site to help you when you get stuck and help you actually build something with these AI tools.
So, I put a link in the description.
If you're serious about actually building something and building anything that we talked about in this podcast here,
check out the link in the description if you're curious about building something.
The AI Build Accelerator.
It's awesome.
All right, back to the episode.
Second one.
This one I really like.
A company 1 million% have heard of Mailchimp.
Mailchimp is the, you know, huge.
I mean, I've heard of Mailchimp for decades.
It feels like and Mailchimp is, you know, email marketing platform and now, you know,
they're they do SMS and all this other stuff.
And I'm looking up their their data right now.
Mailchimp apparently hit 800 million in revenue.
That's revenue.
And into it, who does QuickBooks and other stuff, they bought them for 12 billion.
And that was I'm not sure when that acquisition happened, 2021.
They had 1500 employees.
The valuation was 12 billion.
And they were bootstrapped too, which is pretty crazy.
Yeah.
Awesome.
Okay.
So, when I see that I'm like, and I mean, first of all, you can see there's a ton of email marketing tools now,
Claio, which we use, ConvertKit, etc.
But I found this one again through the starter story database, and it's this one called Aumba Mail.
And what I the main thing that I read in the case study and I'm seeing on here is that they market specifically to people in Spain.
And so as you can see on the website here, everything's in Spanish.
You can you can convert it to English if you wanted to, but everything is based in Spanish.
Everything is ba if you look at the pricing.
Where is the pricing?
I think it's I think this is pricing.
Yeah.
It's so funny that they don't even do a translation for you because typically a website would look at hey this person's coming from the US right now.
Let's translate the site.
But they don't even care about that.
Yeah, totally.
Everything's in euros and all the numbers are or whatever.
Everything's in Spanish.
And this business, according to our case study, they're making like over a million dollars a year.
Wow.
And I and I'm pretty sure their main differentiator is cuz you can look at them on pricing,
they're kind of the same.
They send emails, they do SMS marketing, things like that.
But the main difference I see is that they just market to people in Spanish or Spanish speaking users whereas I think Mailchimp is more I'm sure they're global but they're more
specific to like the US customer base I would imagine.
Right.
So and I think that's huge.
So I'm a Spanish speaker myself grew up speaking Spanish etc.
And there is a really strong pull when companies or any type of like small business or whatever is like specific to that I guess you could say like a
specific culture.
And I think there's like a huge draw there even on like a small scale if I know that of a company that like Hispanics love.
Oh that Hispanics love I don't want to speak for all Hispanics.
Um one small example I don't know if this is like like if this is legitimate or not.
There's a food company called Ciiete Foods brands.
It's like healthy Mexican or Hispanic food type stuff like salsas and chips and taco seasoning.
And it's one of the few like specifically healthy brands, but that's also segmented.
It was started by like a Hispanic family.
Oh, I know this brand.
I think didn't they sell for some crazy amount of money?
Yeah, they did.
Yeah, they're huge.
Well, one of the reasons I love this brand is, you know, if someone's trying to be like healthier or whatever,
not that like traditional Hispanic food is not completely healthy, but it it's not necessarily marketed that way,
and this one is.
And and I know it's started by a Hispanic family, so it makes me want to like support that.
Yeah.
You know, as an example.
And so, yeah, kind of going back to this, you know, to this idea, I do think that's like a strong pull for this Yeah.
type of business.
Yeah.
Yes.
And now that I think about it, email marketing business, right?
Yeah.
So it's like it's almost like a founder brand, personal brand kind of angle too, which is because Akuma Mail probably doesn't have millions of customers.
They don't need that because email marketing software.
We pay three to $4,000 a month for Clavio, which is our email marketing software.
They don't need a million customers to have a business.
They could probably have email marketing.
Let's say, I don't know, if they're doing a million dollars a year, that's $80,000 a month.
Each customer is paying them 500 and that's 160 customers.
Yeah.
I mean, that's just rough numbers, but the numbers don't have to get that big for you to dominate,
you know, in the Spanish market for email marketing software.
And obviously this can be replicated across so many other totally Portuguese, you know,
any other types of languages that are specific and that that is a good point like buying from other founders maybe from your area from a specific place.
I think that does make a big difference.
But again, I think it's just another example of like I mean there's so many freaking email marketing tools,
you know, and you can look at this and how am I going to break in here?
But I feel like you see it.
There was I'm trying to think of the example.
It was like it's called like loops or something like that.
What is that?
Yeah.
Loops.
So, I know those guys.
Yeah.
That's like another email marketing tool.
And the niche here is like modern software companies.
Do I want do I want to use like heavy ass Claio or Mailchimp?
No, I want something that's like really streamlined that someone that understands whatever a modern SAS or a micro SAS.
And so, I wonder if there's like an opportunity there.
For sure.
I mean, I think I still think there's a lot of email marketing companies that are to be built and the one that comes to mind is like AI email marketing that doesn't seem to have been solved yet.
So, how can you send emails on me on on my behalf with AI?
I'm sure someone's working on it, but I imagine there's going to be something big there.
And like it's going to be tough for the bigger email marketing players to implement AI into their systems because of like the innovators dilemma,
but someone new is going to come along and and solve that.
And obviously I think they'll do well.
Email marketing is one of those things again every business needs email marketing.
I don't I you you have to send emails.
That is how actually apps are secured through an email address.
So by default emails will always be sent by every single business.
This is a good recession proof business email marketing and SMS too.
Yeah.
I was just I couldn't pull it up right now.
I was trying to find there was another recent case study he submitted in the last like three months of a guy who built an email marketing tool and his niche was like for solarreneurs and that was like his his little niche.
Y so yeah, bunch of segments here.
I bet there I bet there's some for like I don't know different professions for coffee shops for for chefs for things like that.
Yeah, for sure.
Cool.
And then the last one.
So there's there's this big company called Netlefi.
And I'm not 100% familiar exactly with how how this works, but I think what Netlifi is is a way to easily share your projects online.
Is that correct?
Yeah, I mean it's just servers.
So service every single website has a host.
So WordPress, if you have a WordPress site, your host is going to be maybe WP Engine.
If you have our site on starter story is hosted by Heroku.
Netlefi here, I think their their kind of focus is more on the front-end stack.
So if you're building an app with specific technologies like Nex.js and stuff like that.
So they're they're a hosting provider for people's websites.
Okay, cool.
And last I saw they're making in like $40 million a year or something like that.
Netlefi in 24 2024 did 46.3 million up from 33 million in 23.
So yeah, they're growing 10 million AR a year.
You don't really hear about N netifi as much anymore.
I know that Versell is like the big thing now, but they're kind of quietly crushing it.
So, you know, coming off of that, I I saw this and I'll I'll pull up his Twitter because I think it's pretty cool.
This guy Berto, he built a little tool called Tiny Host that he says is doing 400K ARR.
Nice.
And here's Tiny Host.
The simplest way to host and share your work online.
Nice.
And but he he I he recently shared a little thread about how it's like consistently growing and now it's at about 400KR.
And so from what I understand about this business and this is probably, you know, I'm looking at this example here.
It's a simpler way to quickly host your projects online.
So, kind of like Netlefi, but maybe just a little more streamlined or simpler.
Yeah.
Netlefi is going to be like maybe a little bit more you need to write some code and maybe use your terminal to deploy it or something like that where this it looks like you can literally
just upload some files like a HTML and CSS and JavaScript file just to get a website live just by a simple file upload.
That seems to be what they do and it's just simpler.
I wonder what what's their pricing?
Can you pull that up?
Yeah.
So if they're doing 40 400k ARR and the middle plan is doing 13 per month, 150 per year,
400k per year.
So I take 400,000 divided by 156 that means they have 2,500 customers using this.
I mean we can see how much customers something like Verscell has forcell number of customers 42,000 in the US alone.
So they just have if for sale has 100,000 customers which is possible this company just has 2500 customers doing something a little simpler just just a
fraction of that but 400k per year is is nice I mean yeah that's awesome it doesn't have all the bells and whistles doesn't have to that's that's part of the reason why people use it and it's
simpler for the the founder to create you know just the basics of being able to upload stuff.
Yeah, even on I'm pricing it wins a little bit.
You know, 13 a month.
It's a slightly cheaper.
Slightly cheaper.
Yeah, it's kind of interesting.
Yeah.
And what I think may be somewhat overlooked here is it's probably used by businesses a lot.
So, I noticed in the top it said, "Who uses it?"
Yeah.
Go down.
See, it said sales and marketing.
Yes.
Tiny is for you.
And that's what I also love to do is to go and look at who they say they're for.
that will tell you who their ideal customer profile is.
So you might think it's just someone uploading a website, but in reality who's paying for this business.
And they put sales and marketing.
So people working in sales and marketing who want to upload, you know, their PDF.
They don't know how to use, you know, whatever.
This allows them to create a website around a word document, right?
So yeah, maybe that's part of it, too.
That's a I mean, just this little tiny website, right?
Real estate pack.
It looks like they just uploaded three PDFs.
Yeah.
And then like now, boom, I can see whatever this real estate package, right?
Right.
Or whatever, right?
Designers and artists.
I want to show you my I don't know an example of my site here, right?
Quickly put it together or whatever.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
Maybe in the age of AI, too.
This will even get bigger because you can just generate the HTML and CSS with the LLM,
open AI, chat GPT tool, and then upload it to here and then you've got a website.
That's cool.
Yeah.
You're right.
I think that is an interesting point of the specific personas.
It reminds me of like the calday people we were talking about that's like a service or a little business that might be more willing to use something that's simpler versus whatever netifi you know nothing against
Netlifi but it's like you know it's future futury I see all these cool apps but I'm like oh that's those are way bigger than me is is that even like for me kind of
thing.
Yeah.
Whereas tiny host you know it's like it's simple just drop drag and drop.
Yep.
build build and deploy for the web.
That's like it's so different.
Yeah.
So, yeah, those are my three ideas that I wanted to bring to the table, but I think the So,
you see all these ideas obviously and so I think anyone watching is probably thinking like,
cool, what like what are some opportunities to copy and paste today?
Yeah.
Rather than telling you what to do, I'm going to teach you I could try to teach you how to fish a little bit.
So, let's pull up my screen and I'll tell you how to look at look this up because I could tell I could come up with some guesses.
But what if we actually just used my favorite tool AI to come up with an idea and I'm going to say hey I want to build a smaller not
a smaller but a bootstrapped SAS based on a successful billion dollar and as I understand these were all B2B right so I think that's important company B2B huge
TAM and attack a smaller market can you give me the top 10 billion dollar SAS ripe for disruption.
See what we come up with.
We're going to quit.
Hell yes.
Love this strategy.
I love when it just like raises you up.
Yep.
Oh, dude.
AI models are so agreeable.
That's actually a huge problem.
I was talking to someone the other day about they will just do anything you say basically.
They'll question you.
I think that's there's an opportunity there like chat GPT who's like more critical of you,
but that's a podcast for another day.
Yeah.
Okay.
I'm looking through this here and okay, I'm seeing Salesforce CRM that that's a bad place to go.
I think CRM because of the changing landscape of AI and free tools and stuff like that.
But as I go down, I'm looking what's an interesting one.
I like Docu Sign.
That's a good one.
Do you like any of these?
I think like QuickBooks.
Yeah.
You know, I I do a little bit of side business stuff and I don't want to use QuickBooks because it just looks too complicated when I have it.
I So you just use a spreadsheet.
Yeah.
So yeah, let's see what we can do with QuickBooks.
And so I just start chatting it with it like it's my my my mentor.
I like QuickBooks.
Where are the holes right now?
It's built for accountants, not founders.
They are too broad, not tailored to specific audiences.
I mean, yeah, there's there's so many opportunities I'm seeing right here that are already true.
So SA QuickBooks for SAS founders track MR runway and strike payouts, those profit well and banner or what was it called?
Bare metrics.
Those are two apps that were built that yeah, they don't.
Look, replacing QuickBooks is going to be hard because all accountants use QuickBooks and they're going to tell you please don't use anything else.
But there's certain features maybe inside QuickBooks that are able to maybe rip out and turn into their own SAS.
And that's one example is like Stripe will tell you your MR, but it won't tell you like more detailed stuff.
And QuickBooks will tell you your cash flow, but it won't tell you your MR, right?
So there things that come out of there.
Maybe this one here is interesting.
coaches and consultants or agencies, invoices, contracts, and taxes.
Maybe there's something we can dive.
I just like to dive in more specifically.
Let's dive into taxes.
It's interesting and as as this is loading up, I feel like just watching this is interesting in terms of like a kind of continuing to cut in.
Yeah.
Finding like the specific thing I think is like a it's an interesting like a brain exercise.
Yep.
Because a lot of people want to go and you got you got to start small and you know there are tax businesses that are billion dollar businesses and they still only solve taxes.
Quick what what's the tax company called?
Taxes.
I just did them.
Turboax.
Turboax, right?
Yeah.
Live tax.
Somebody build an alternative to Turboax, please.
Yes.
Here's one right here.
This one actually hits me on a pain, which is quarterly tax reminders.
You might not know about this because you don't do quarterly taxes for your business or someone watching this may not have to do that,
but I have to do it.
And I have a calendar invite in my or a calendar reminder every quarter that tells me,
hey, go and do your tax estimates and that would be cool if there and then there's also like a new tax thing that just came up with my accountant,
which is now I got to pay taxes in California and I got to sign up for this thing and it's a huge pain in the ass.
So, there's an idea there.
Maybe, and I might even just drill in further, but for purposes of this, I'm going to give one more little piece of game here before we get you guys get too bored of what I'm doing,
but I don't want to give this away.
But basically, what you do is you go and you go to google.com and you go and search quarterly taxreers site reddit.com.
And there's this more complicated query that we're going to share in our video coming up.
But you can see people, oh, someone's trying to write a Google Apps script to remind them to pay estimated taxes,
right?
That's the same problem I had.
And look at all these people in these Reddit posts.
Missed quarterly payment.
Where do I go from here?
R/tax.
Look at all these responses.
Right?
You guys are going to love this video we're going to do.
We are going Basically, you take all this information from these Reddit posts.
You source like 10 15 Reddit posts.
You put it into this special prompt that we're going to give you and then you put it into one of these AI tool creator generators and it creates a landing page for you based on what people say on Reddit.
So, it understands the pain points.
It creates testimonials for you.
It builds all the features of the app and then it just then you don't even have to like I don't want to say you don't have to validate your idea,
but you've got a landing page without in in one hour.
That's what this video is going to do.
So, it's going to be really cool.
So, I'll that's a little bit of a teaser for what we got upcoming on the main channel.
But, yeah, man, there's so many opportunities.
And what I think is cool is like without if AI didn't exist, AI is is giving people the opportunity to go and create the quarterly payment reminder app.
That was not possible to do before because you need a development team of 10 developers to help you build this.
Now, you don't need it because AI will build it for you.
And that's creating an opportunity to create these apps like this where you can make money.
Cool.
That's all I have for this week.
Yeah.
I think my big takeaway is just that to not be too scared of places where you see people have already started businesses because it kind of I've heard you say this and others like we're saturated really just means
validated.
People are already willing to pay money for that and so finding your little slice there is awesome.
Yep.
Cool.
All right.
Well, thanks for watching another episode of the Starter Story podcast.
We'll see you in the next one.