hey guys Pat here from starter story every week I have a team that spends hours researching the freshest business ideas on the entire internet and then we sit down and we talk about them what
each of those ideas are why they're awesome and if we should go talk to these Founders in this episode I wanted to do something a little bit different you'll get to be a fly on thewall and see how we research and come up with
business ideas to cover So today we're going to be talking about three side projects making over $10,000 of month started by regular people just like you and we're going to go over what that
idea is exactly how they grew it and why we think it works and made money really quickly stick around to the end because we found a mobile app making $115,000 a
month and it's pretty crazy please enjoy I know this is new so please leave your feedback in the comments if you like this and you'd want to see more of it I hope it inspires you maybe gives you some insights for your own projects
let's go all right guys what's up today we're going to be doing something a little bit different if you're if you're a fan of starter story I think you'll like this basically every week I sit down with Gus and Marco this these guys
are part of our research team at starter story they basically spend all day researching the latest boots on the ground realist business ideas that are working right now if you like business
ideas you're going to learn a lot today and today we're going to be talking about side projects specifically what are the best side projects to be starting right now by solo Founders so that you can build something while you
have a full-time job without taking that huge risk so uh yeah let's get into it what cool ideas you guys find this week cool started off yeah so I was scrolling through Twitter doing my normal brain
rot Scrolls and I found this guy named Yuri and he he has multiple businesses but he notably started this thing called
parakeet AI it's this realtime AI interview assistant and what it does is if the interviewer asks a question then you can hit a response and it'll give
you an instant response to that thing um I obviously don't know if this is legal or not for job interviews because you kind of just cheat your way to the top with it but it's pretty cool and the
most interesting thing is he built it in a weekend and in the first month he said he made 700 bucks and then now he's making 16k a month and he basically just
grew it through social media like these short form Tik Tok videos and just got kind of instant growth with it and I think it's really cool because you can spin up a project in a weekend you know
he's a coder I would probably do this with no code or something like that but you can spit up a project in a weekend and then just use these short form free videos making these in your house type
of thing and just get instant traffic downloads possibly Revenue if you have a pay wall setup um which is exactly what he did so I think I like this a lot
because of how fast you can kind of just get off the ground with it especially with AI you know there's hot opportunities everywhere finding kind of this interesting niche in the job market
and then just launching it fast and trying to get traffic and users through short form is um really interesting really cool yeah I saw some of those Tik toks and um obviously that first one has
like almost 3 million views and if you watch it it's pretty simple what it's doing right it's it's showing him on the interview transcribing notes maybe as a little staged or whatever but something I find interesting on businesses like
this is they find sort of a a format that works and they just like do it over and over and over again so a lot of these videos are like somebody walking in and if you look at their Tik toks or their other channels a lot of them are
like the same kind of videos which for me as like somebody who's try to build a bunch of businesses on the side it's like something to keep in mind I guess is when you find something that works
like double down on it and I I don't think I thought about it like that before yeah Marco go back to his Tik Tok and just show me that again from the the main Tik Tok page I think what you said
is pretty interesting is that pretty much like I'm just looking at it visually right now if you keep scrolling down it's it's basically the same thing over and over him sitting in that
position on a laptop taking an interview and like you said it's like clearly all stage but the idea is like all you have to do is find like one format that works
and then you just do it over and over again but you change the text you change the camera angle you change you know something else and you just post this over and over and over over again and
like part of that makes me kind of sad that this is like what the algorithms have become but also I mean this is perfect for like a side project right
like just have a pretty simple app like like this and then you could like Outsource this process of creating content and then all you have to do is just find that one winning format like
what do you think the conversion is you go to the top and you look at that one video has what 3 million views I mean this was in October he probably got a
decent amount of traffic and probably some conversions with this because I mean 3 million views 156,000 likes and it's just I think what's cool about this is this is you know obviously a viral
format but it's showing off exactly what the product does and kind of like solving the pain Point instantly for a potential buyer or user which is almost just like it makes you just want to go
try this thing yeah that's exactly what I was going to say it's like it's almost I don't know maybe controversial like if you look at some of the comments it's like as a recruiter we can tell you know
someone comments on that five replies on there I'm sure there's a bunch and it makes me want to go use it it's like 30 bucks to do three interviews or 60 bucks
for six interviews I don't know I would pay this just to like see just to run the numbers I'll share my screen real quick I think I I I just get like fascinated by the numbers of
what does a 3 million video view video do for a business like this and like this is like I think maybe one of the secrets of this whole Tik Tok game like you hear about these apps that make like
zero so like just like how many views you get 3 million let's say what's the like conversion rate to someone just going and checking out the thing if like it's actually just showing the product
in the video like you can you might be able to expect like a 10% conversion rate of people that go to the website so that's boom immediately 300,000 people just browsing your
website from this over time that's um that's 300,000 people and then what the conversion rate for something did you guys see what the pay wall looked like for this or like do they charge for it
do they do it for free yeah the pricing on it it's no subscription 30-day money back guarantee one credit for an hour interview session is basically they sell
credits like got it three interview credits for 30 bucks six interview credits for 60 bucks those are all hour interviews right what was the average price of it the lowest is 30 bucks for three
interview credits 30 bucks so they're charging 30 bucks and let's say they have a really a really conservative uh conversion rate once the user gets there this is the conversion
rate this would be 300,000 time 1% that means you're going to get 3,000 paid users and you multiply 3,000 paid users by 30 bucks and that's
$90,000 like so yeah this is like back the and math right like maybe they maybe it converts 5% let's just say like be really conservative with the numbers that's
still generated $45,000 so like that specific Tik Tok right there which he just filmed like there wasn't any production or anything like that he just filmed it obviously had to find a bunch
of other ones but that's a good business right there and that shows you the power of this whole organic thing right so for sure anytime you see you go online and
you're just on Tik Tok and you see something that has a ton of views and is advertising some sort of uh side project like this not side project but just any sort of app or and it's organic like
that you can kind of run these numbers and see like oh wow there's something there for sure which I that that just fascinates me that like that's one video right $45,000 for one video yeah and the
crazy part is too it's like you can do this by yourself in your room like he's doing and you can pump those out so fast like if it's just you know the same exact scene over and over again you're
literally just testing different words on the screen every single time like that just so quick just to launch those things probably takes them maybe less than an hour a day to make those one of them hits you know you have a video like that that gets three million views and
then all of a sudden people are flooding in on your website just yeah it's nuts yeah I think that this is an awesome side project and if you guys are
up for it I think we'll definitely reach out to him and see if he wants to come on the channel and talk more about the T talk stuff potentially and I want to see I want to learn more about some of his other businesses too so that's a good
one Marco let's definitely follow up with that one cool all right yeah I got I got the next one okay so it's a guy named Kyle Nolan built a tool called
projection lab which I've actually used and he's currently at 70k Mr so what it is is it's projections for like your finances and I'm somebody that has for
sure some Financial anxieties for lots of different reasons I'm sure a lot of people too um and it's a really easy to use tool to plug in your numbers and sort of start to get this little graph
of where am I going and what do I need to change and what I and I've been following him for probably the last couple years and what I really like
about this guy is that he started it as a side project so I have a I have a bunch of different of his tweets pulled up here and a couple years ago he he launched it and got 200 bucks on product
hunt hit 4K you know couple months later uh shared a little bit more now he's at 6K about a year later all the way I'm going to skip ahead a little bit
to now he's at a million total revenue 70k Mr and fully quit his job and is now going all in on this and I think what I
love about this business is that it started completely as a side project he had a full-time job one of the things he says in like a one of his Hacker News
posts he said like I wanted a tool that was easy to use for like projecting my finances I couldn't find one and if someone who's used a bunch of these they're all like I don't know like
little old or archaic looking and he wanted one that just looked a little better and so he built it for himself and boot shapped it all the way to a million dollars which is just like
awesome to have seen how does it make money it makes money by subscriptions so um you can start for free and there's just some pretty basic you know use
cases or you can subscribe and you get a bunch of other features included so there's like looks like there's a a couple different versions so it's premium version or a pro version and
then he does have a uh a lifetime deal 800 bucks for life um looks like he's getting decent traffic um when I looked this last time you
know 30ish you know 100K visitors per month yeah so that's that's this business is he getting traffic through
just his social media now I think so I couldn't find anything else or like anywhere else that he's sharing his business like couldn't find like an
email like a substack or a beehive or anything like that so yeah to to my knowledge he's totally sharing this
primarily on x and um that's how he and I mean I guess he asked popes that don't like product hunt or Indie hackers Hacker News so he maybe he's getting
traffic from there yeah that's kind of that's what I see so he has 70,000 mrr and his average product price is about $9 so that means he has about 8,000
customers for this business which is actually pretty that's pretty high what you I think maybe there's something there with like the financial anxiety thing
like every year you know people are just you know hearing about all these millionaires online and certainly starter story is not helping with that but um there's like there's definitely
more tell me about that Financial anxiety thing that you were saying like that seems to be maybe what's helping grow this type of business because you want to know what your net worth is and
you know next year and the year after right yeah I think um well for me it's it's really I like to
see the like the full chart right I see my money on a daily basis or whatever that looks like in my bank account but sometimes I'm like where am I going am I investing enough am I you know saving
enough and so to see it all in one clean picture that you can save you know over time in this one tool I think that's what makes it like attractive for me as a user like I said
I signed it for the free version and it's like super easy to just plug in your numbers and start to see it and sometimes that's not fun cuz you're like I need to have a little more
backed up here but it but it at least starts to give me a place to start with that there's something there for sure from um the side project perspective I
like this as a side project a lot because and it seems to be the theme of some of the businesses we shared is that it's like solving your own problem which you know is probably something that if
you can charge a somewhat decent price where it's like consumer type thing there's going to be a lot of other people that also want to solve this
problem and want to use an app like this yeah I like I like what he said here this is from um Indie hackers you know he says I couldn't find a long-term
financial planning app that felt modern and actually fun to use and I spent a year and a half of my free time building one for myself and yeah I think
that's I think about that a lot I do a lot of like writing obviously for starter story and I think about that sometimes I'm like man I wish I could build something for myself that would
help me whatever come up with ideas or write a little better OBS you could use Chad GPT things like that but so I think that's kind of the inspiration that I get from it it's like oh I can think of something that I want to solve for
myself and just there's probably a lot of other people that feel the same way maybe not all the time but at least in this case yeah that seem nice about this is like it's it's a low enough price
point where you don't have to do like customer support for like you know I see a lot of people want to do B Tob SAS that's kind of tough to do when you have a side project because you got to step
out for you know customer support I maybe you're closing deals sales there's just a higher price point just kind of just inherently means more support and
you know being on call at all times with this $9 price point and he seems like he's doing kind of like a free tool thing can start with a free tool everything is kind of like not urgent in the business I think that's important
like when I was starting my business as a side project I wanted to make sure that I could just do it nights and weekends it wouldn't interfere with my full-time job and nothing was like super
urgent so I think that's a theme I mean the business we looked at before and this business is more consumer especially maybe for that first business idea that first side project a consumer
app that is monetized correctly is like a really good first side project and he did this over the course of five years he was passionate about it that kept him going and then also he could just kind
of grow slowly without feeling like oh I gotta get this to you know some crazy Revenue number right away yeah you guys have Financial anxieties or just me yeah I feel like I've experienced
that exact thing where it's it's like this moment where you want to get your finances back on track because you realize you're probably spending a lot on something like I bought I think last year I bought co-pilot it was like a hundred bucks or something like that for
the year but it's like that instant thing where I'm like okay I'm going to make a change and then you buy this financial thing this tool because it's the thing that's going to help you get
back on track and actually cut down your spending so I think like that Financial tick like when you have a problem or something that you're solving that's
really like you said Gus that high anxiety thing I feel like it's way easier to spend money on something like that which is probably way easier to make money when you're actually building
it yep problems like that that's true I mean there's some famous quote I can't remember it right now but it's like if you're going to build anything just the the level difficulty is going to be a
lot easier if you do it in health wealth status and those sorts of things because people like like you say like I want to get my finances on track I'm willing to
pay to do that I'm willing to to you know it's more important to me than I don't know something like what would be something that would not cuz I see a lot of people build like
side projects and it's like this this feels like a like a vitamin and not a painkiller a pain is I'm not where my finances want to be that's a real pain
but sometimes I'll see people doing like I don't know help me meal prep you know help me come up with the recipes for what I can cook for dinner that's not a real pain right that's like a vitamin I
think that's yeah I think of like um we've we've seen some businesses that or like a like a PDF API or something like that which which are cool and they make a lot of money and obviously probably
have some sort of painkiller element but you can say I don't really need that tool you know I can get by whereas maybe something like your finances feels a
little maybe not for everybody but can feel a little more out of control you're like oh I gotta I should figure this out this this impacts my life more than for sure some API yeah that's
projection lab oh all right I got one for you guys this one's interesting because it kind of goes what we're just talking about is maybe not the biggest
pain killer in the world it's somewhat of a pain I think but maybe that's what makes this one the most interesting because I see a lot of people try to build this kind of app and it makes zero
dollars and it fails and so this one right here is called habit kit it's a habit tracker and you if you're watching this youve probably heard of a habit tracker before so there's like I think a
bigger Theme by this book called Atomic Habits by James CLE which is you know like the number one book on Amazon every single month even years after it's been released right it's kind of like how can
I improve uh my life through habits this is kind of the sexy idea this habit Kit app here makes $155,000 a month and what
I think immediately just goes how how the hell does this uh make $15,000 a month when you know I see a lot of first-time Founders try to Launch habit trackers that make Z and even I think
Mark Lou has a habit tracker and like you know you can go to his um Mark Lou's I love Mark Lou he's got so many cool things but you go to his his apps you know I think he has a h habits Garden it
makes $174 a month and he's got like a pretty big audience right I think he might have another habit tracker but that's the main one so like why does
this what what is up with this side project and why is it number one I did a little research into it and um I think one thing is that like
there's this visual element to it so if you're if you're a coder or a software engineer at all there's like this thing called a contribution graph which is basically like has every day I'll kind
of just zoom in here every day is a square and then you kind of it creates this little kind of addiction to making sure you hit the square every day it's
like if you Cod it every day well he did this but he did it for habit so here's my meditation habit every day here's my side hustle habit here's my playing the drums habit and I can track how I've
done it all year it's a way to like see the whole year at once I think that's really cool he took something that's popular in the coding world and he did it for habits so I think something about
that visually just like looks sexy to me I think that's really cool it's like a visual but when I was doing a little bit more research into it what I think actually is why this is successful why
is this making $115,000 a month when and Mark Lou has a habit tracker that's not making $15,000 a month yet this guy has an audience that's a lot smaller and I think it's because it's a mobile app and
I really really think that is a huge Hack That Founders are not willing to do because you got to learn how to build an app you got to get approved by the App
Store it's not AI tools can't do it for you but that's a huge hack right if you go to his uh we'll go back to the Habit tracker go to the App Store
and he has 808 reviews and I don't know if you can look this up right now but like what is the like I'll go to chat
GPT right now and look up like um what is the review to download ratio for a mobile app and this is how I can kind of back
into typical ratio 0.5% to 3% so if we say it's a 1% um I would say that's for every 100
downloads an app might get.5 to three reviews so that would put it at like if I go to his um this one right here that means that if there's like a 1% that
means that this app has gotten 8,000 downloads although I think it would probably be a lot higher um when I see that I immediately think okay he's doing something right in the
App Store and once you get uh a little bit of escape velocity in the app store then then you have free downloads and that's another one of these like thing
that's perfect for a s project is like building on a platform where there are billions or or hundreds of millions of users and I bet if you search habit
tracker on the App Store I I don't have my phone on me right now but I bet his comes up pretty high so it's almost like search engine optimization or App Store optimization I talk to a lot of Founders
that will oh I want to build a Hab tracker they build it they put it on the web no one uses it I think the secret here is is mobile app what do you guys think yeah I'm looking at it right now I
would agree I mean if you pull up so this is what I feel like a lot of the uh guys are using with the app app stuff
is the sensor Tower thing I mean seems like these numbers are kind of lining up 40K downloads last month yeah I think my chat GPT was way off with it because it's saying it's doing 40,000 downloads
a month yeah that's huge rev yeah it's hard to monetize a you know a habit tracker because you know it's just like was it $3 a month or
something like that but he's getting volume this is a volume play right here yeah yeah I think you're right the mobile app too I feel like a couple things like you said I think the
sickness like the cool factor of like the colors and stuff really plays into it I think that maybe maybe like another
thing on top of that is the sharability of like hey I did this thing for a 100 days this year or whatever and you can kind of give like a cool picture of that type of
thing um I think that's kind of like an interesting Insight too oh for sure it's like it's almost like the flex of it like if you had this on your phone which I think was cool is on your phone it'll
let you do the little widget so you're hanging out with your friends and you're proud of your streak or whatever you get on this and you show it to them and they also download it so it's like uh because
it's mobile it's not on the web I think that's another Advantage is just there's more just default Word of Mouth yeah yeah and I think I like the
um that it looks just so similar to yeah those like GitHub contributions I feel like you know I'm on X all the time and you see the folks that post that and sometimes I'm like well I'm not
much of a coder how can I share what I'm working on are the habits I'm building and this is uh it it just looks
cool as something that's I know that's not like a deep analysis but it just looks cooler than the other habit
trackers I've used yeah I think if I could get philosophical for a sec or like what works on social media is like what the Habit tracker the photo of the
Habit tracker of the the contribution graph is how can you encapsulate so much hard work into one photo that's what it is that's why it really can like perform
well on you know for your personal brand or whatever is like you can instead of saying I worked hard for seven years and telling your whole story you can just
share that in one image and everyone kind of already default understands what that means and that's really powerful I think to be able to give a visual to how you
know you walked Every Day in 2025 or you worked out every day or you wrote uh you know code every day
whatever it is and I think that's that's powerful and like you said that that creates word of mouth and uh automatic sharability for sure I mean not to not to put you on blast pet but you know I
think some tweets that have gone off for you are are these right like shout out to all the people who said I got lucky 2.5 million views and it you're right it just shows the like and this is from
GitHub right um it just shows off like like you said how do you how do you say I've worked hard for five years or whatever this is you just show this image yeah
and I think that's pretty cool and a picture is worth a thousand words as they say and I was just talking to someone on the phone yesterday he was trying to build something one of my friends and he's like oh should I build
this personal brand or you know then I can build a product or whatever I was like if the number one thing when it comes to social I think especially personal brand brand is showing people
that you do cool do cool then talk about it you can't I think it's very very hard to build something without doing the cool part so I
had to work for years to make that image a reality but then that image tells one simple story and creates I don't know Authority or shows people online that I
have something to share because of this hard work that I put in I think I'm gonna go download this app okay so I love it guys this is awesome I think all of them are worth talking to
to do potential videos they all have interesting angles I mean is there any like big takeaway that comes that you guys get from you know these are all side projects or side projects you know
you could build similar stuff what's what's your big takeaway Gus I think for that first one parakeet the the fact that anyone you
can build anything right any little tool and drive attention to it through Tik Tok and be like Shameless about it I feel like that's something I'm thinking
about is what prevents me from posting or whatever sometimes it's like I feel stupid and this guy just like did it over and over and over again and it's almost like who cares so that's
something I'm thinking about like if if and when I do whatever side project it's like just be Shameless and share cuz you have a shot like some we saw some of those Tik toks right it was like 400
views 200 views and then like 100k a million it's like you never know which one's going to pop off yeah Marco and I were talking to someone the other day and I've talked to other people too and
they they always say let me let you in on a little secret and then these are people that blew up on Tik Tok Instagram reals you know all these things is we found a winning piece of content
formula and then or it was actually from a guy who was studying uh a lot he had an agency that helped people do organic social and he said here's the one that
nobody knows or nobody talks about they find one thing they post it over and over and over again and then they get scared and they say okay we got to find something new and I always go and tell
them no stop go back and post it over and over and over and over again and don't do anything new in Creative that's kind of sad when you think about it at someone on Twitter be like this is kind of like you know there's no more
creativity left in the world but that's just that's just how it is these days so I think that's interesting it's cheap you know your phone yeah Marco what's your big
takeaway uh kind of on what Gus just said I like that it's almost like everything is so free nowadays to build to like Market things that you almost
have no excuse to not try and build something making the Tik toks takes maybe less than an hour a day and you're just copy and pasting kind of formats
and text and trying different things and yeah on top of what Gus said the Shameless thing like why would you care if you know you launched five videos in a day and one of those videos goes viral
and now your app has thousands of downloads maybe you're making $500 a month now from it and that could change like your entire life yeah all because
of a silly little video that you made that's kind of insane so yeah I think the fact that you can just spin something up fast nowadays too the parakeet guy obviously did it in a
weekend you know maybe not everybody's as technical I'm not as technical but a lot of the tools out there I feel like you can just spin something up pretty
fast in MVP and then if you're good at marketing or just at least posting the Tik toks then you know you can get traffic to something and actually get it
making money so yeah I think might take ways because everything is so free you almost have no excuse not to try and build something like why not cool all
right yeah I think the most interesting thing if I could just like try to find one common them against all these is that it's all consumer stuff I hear a
lot of people talk about B2B SAS uh but I think consumer works for something like this especially as a side project because it it all starts from solving your own problem it's hard to
build a B2B type of business because most people that are just like you and me we're not B business owners we're just consumers so we just want to build stuff like it's cool to build stuff that
you think is cool like the projection lab guy he's like I really want to track my net worth but you know all the things out there kind of suck so I'm just going to build this for myself and then you're passionate about it as long as it's a
low enough price points and you can that the hardest part with consumer is getting the monetization right I think or even just building something that people want to actually pay for it's that painkiller versus vitamin thing and
I think building in health wealth diet relationships these sorts of things are good places and it seems like all of these build their habits being health or
just you know generally self-improvement the projection lab being Finance wealth and the parakeet AI being job so also getting a job making money that sort of
thing so I think that's that's if I was building a side project it's a good place to start it's a good place to get that first 10,000 20,000 and build a business that can't allow you to quit
your full-time job eventually so cool all right well that was fun guys what'you think yeah that's awesome all right well we'll be back next week with more
ideas if you guys like this comment below what your favorite business idea was and why um and tell us what else you'd want us to cover thanks Gus thanks Marco uh we're going to keep finding
more business ideas for you guys and and sharing them with you so thanks for watching