Hey, welcome back to the Starter Story podcast.
This is a brand new format that we're trying out today.
We have our first guest on the show.
His name is Joshua and he built an app called Postal.
Postal is a tool that helps you post better content on Twitter.
And I wanted to bring him on to the channel because Joshua actually just quit his job like two weeks ago to go allin on this app.
I've been following him for like I don't know six, seven months or so since he started building this and his story is just awesome.
If you're early on in your building journey, looking for inspiration from somebody still in the early stages of starting their business,
I think this episode is going to be really interesting for you.
So, leave a comment about what you think about this format.
Thanks for being here.
Welcome to the Starter Story podcast.
Let's go.
So, this is Joshua.
Joshua, welcome to the Starter Story podcast.
Appreciate you taking the time.
I know you're in Germany.
700 p.m.
on a Friday night.
Wouldn't want to spend it any other way, I'm sure.
Before we jump in, we're going to learn a lot about your story and who you are and stuff today.
I first just wanted to say like how I first learned about you.
So, obviously, I work for Starter Story and Starry has a Slack channel for all the people in our community.
And this was like my first introduction to you, which I think is pretty awesome.
So, let me share my screen and then I'll I'll come back.
This post here and it was like, and let me just kind of minimize all this stuff.
You were like, "Hey, in April, I launched the MVP of our SAS three weeks ago, 200 MR,
17 users, blah blah blah."
And I was like, "Hey, this is like pretty awesome."
You know, write engaging content.
You were showing some stats and whatnot.
I think we might have even written about you in one of our like emails or something like that.
But we always love seeing people that are actually launching stuff and and building,
especially inside Starter Story.
So that was my first introduction to you.
So maybe yeah, obviously we're already starting this, but tell us a little bit more about yourself,
who you are.
Let's start there.
Yeah, like first of all, thanks for having me on.
This is super exciting for me.
I'm Joshua, 24 years old from Germany, and I just quit my job 15 days ago to go all in on this thing I'm building together with two friends.
I've met on Twitter, actually, eight months ago, and I've met these two guys uh I think two times in person.
So uh I've never seen them before.
It totally clicked.
I connected with them, veered a bit in public space on Twitter, which is really big,
right?
And we hopped on a few calls and we started like building this idea right away.
And we are working on poster, which is basically a content creation tool right now only focused for like creators on X or Twitter.
And it lets you basically create value content really fast.
Like you can add creators that you like and write like them and reference like YouTube videos,
podcasts, Instagram res and uh any blog article to create like I think uh a thousand content angles that you can play around
with.
And we have been now I think launching uh one like 117 days ago and I've been like a long time uh actually
reader and watcher of the starter story like universe which is great because I found out about the Slack community like I think uh 3 weeks after we have been
launching.
I thought like dude I've actually got something going on right now.
I might share and Yeah.
Yeah.
That's cool.
Well, why don't you show off the app a little bit if you're open to it?
You can share your screen and just kind of show us a little bit how it works.
I'm I'm curious to learn a little bit more about how it works, too.
So, basically, when you go into through the onboarding, you will connect your X account and we will analyze everything about you to create a voice and you will see that here.
You have also the ability to add any creators that you like as writing style.
And then you can go into this view where you can create posts.
So you can spin up random post ideas, select like a topic from your knowledge base where you can add any kind of information or you can add like YouTube videos and select the writing style.
So if I feel like okay for this post I have in mind a writing style like Naval would fit this.
I can select that one and he would depending on the post I will select here.
I can cook up like six threats and you will get like six thread starts.
I don't have a YouTube on hand.
We could take take like a YouTube videos a YouTube video from start a story.
Sure.
Yeah.
Go ahead.
This is pretty cool.
So, it's like a way to help people who want to post on X come up with ideas kind of generate ideas or inspiration from other people they follow.
You know what's funny is I had and this is you probably hear this all the time, but I had thought about something like this for a while back and I was like it'd be able to kind of generate ideas based on
other people's voices or styles and this is kind of exactly what I was looking for.
That's so that's pretty awesome.
Yeah, right now I'm taking like I've just added like the YouTube video, right?
And it's going to reference the content of the video as context basically.
Now I can say for example, hey create a value based with the key insights from the video.
Start the post a fiveword hook and follow up with starter story YouTube channel is amazing.
It's amazing.
So that should be enough.
Now I can select say let's go with Greg Eisenberg for this one.
And now it's cooking up the threat starts and then from there on I can select like the one I like the most and go to the editor and do like the final touches.
And then I can post it either directly to X or schedule it out.
It's like a really simple way basically to go from like end to end, right?
I need to post something to keep active on X and like grow my audience there to just having the post finish and send it out.
Yeah, this one is good because it mentions Lucas.
Yeah, we just posted that video.
That's awesome.
So, it's like it's loading it up into a thread.
Okay.
Yeah.
Then from there on we can go into the editor and you will see it's already splitted like in the usual like threat structure right I could add images or like just just directly schedule it out
and that's it basically and we are just we are like super early as I mentioned like 3 months in we think that just by everything we saw so far there's something bigger behind this idea which
is just basically every I mean you are the content guy you can tell me if I'm wrong for me after have like after starting on X and getting more and more
into content, every content piece is basically downstream from writing.
For YouTube, you need like the script, right?
Depending on your YouTube video, even for Tik Toks like short form videos, you need scripts.
X, Facebook, LinkedIn is also downstream from writing and I think if we pivot like that's the big vision here.
If we add those possibilities and then go back to this kind of view, we are going to create something like imagine lovable just for textbased content writing.
That's cool.
That's that's the big vision here.
Or is as I as I mentioned, we are like super early.
Yeah.
But that's that's what we're working for.
Yeah, that's awesome.
Yeah.
And I yeah I think that does resonate because yeah I do a lot of content for starter story on Twitter and LinkedIn and Instagram and YouTube obviously and all of our kind of written
content on X and LinkedIn for example is downstream of some bigger piece of content whether that's something we wrote something we published something like that and so yeah even as I was
watching you use that tool I was like oh like I could see you know that being really beneficial for us you know to be able to like to give it a lot context to give it specific context and have it
already understand.
For example, I run the Star Twitter account.
Yeah.
To have it understand the voice and that way we can kind of just produce content a little cleaner,
a little faster.
Yeah, that's that's exactly what we're going for.
Yeah.
Cool.
Okay, let's let's just do one step back.
So, obviously like this is an awesome tool and has all these functionalities.
What like were you doing before this?
Like what's kind of your background?
I'm assuming you had some programming experience or Yeah, maybe just tell us a little bit more about that.
So, I was actually sadly I was studying business admin 3 years ago.
How how old are you by the way?
I'm 24.
Yeah.
Okay, nice.
Pretty young.
Cool.
And I Yeah, I've been studying business admin and kind of towards the end I kind of realized way too late when I was far too deep into it to just say,
"Okay, I'm going going to quit."
I realized, okay, I will not spend my career on this.
And then by just a happy accident, I got into data science and that led me into going into a data science job where I was doing like business intelligence engineering.
But I quickly got like ever since I've been to honest like ever since I've been really young.
I didn't see myself like working the normal corporate job, just not something that's fitting me.
I think after two years I got really uncomfortable in that day job and I was so fed up that I started like doing small side projects again like in high school and then my first side project
got like viral on Reddit and because I wanted to share that I started an ex account like last year September I think on the 1st September I made my first ex post.
Oh so like not not even a year ago.
Yeah.
and never had a social media or something like that and I just started to share what happened to me basically after that Reddit post blew up and that got me into like the tech
startup scene on Twitter and I started to just kind of bid in public and yeah then I think it's now 9 months later I'm here I quit my job I said okay let's go
for like all in into this project so I'm a first-time founder and I met like I met my two co co-founders on Twitter
I have way more startup experience but I kind of bring the let's say domain expertise like sure I think I grew a bit fast on like faster than average on Twitter just by doing that and actually
documenting that in public I attracted while still having a day job I attracted a lot of freelance clients for ghostwriting.
So people were asking me to like manage and write posts for them on Twitter and at some point that got so much actually that I had to come up with
a hacky workflow like using chatbt and at the same time like during that time I met Robin my my co-founder one of my co-founders and then after talking for a
bit we decided to basically productize that hacky workflow I had for myself and that's Yeah.
So were you just kind of like copying and pasting stuff into chat GPT and kind of having it write stuff for you?
Yeah, I had like a big really big prompt and I was scraping post by really big accounts in the niche of my clients.
That was like made it really made it kind of easy to go and try out this idea.
Yeah.
Okay.
So, you're kind of you're ghost writing a little bit.
You're you're hacking it together.
I I understand that.
I've done some writing obviously for Starry and others and I did a lot of that where I'm just like copying and pasting big prompts and kind of trying to make it sound good after the fact.
So, then you meet your co-founders on Twitter.
Tell us about that.
like what was that like?
Was it just like a DM?
Was it kind of commenting or how did that work?
Yeah, actually my co-founder, he ran like a community just for builders, just for fun to connect with other ones and like multiple people from that community that were like reaching out to me and I've
just I didn't I'm not the big community guy.
So, I kind of ghosted them for them for a bit after he he contacted me and I was like,
"Hey, dude.
I'm also from Germany.
Let's hop on a call, just connect."
And then we had like three courts and it made really like I was looking for builder friends all my life because I come from like not a big city in Germany.
I have nobody that is into this space.
So meeting people like that was really nice.
And then we connected really good and like I think in the third call it was like hey what are you actually going to work on for your next project?
And we discovered hey we want to work on the exact same problem.
So let's team up.
And the next day we got like the GitHub repo.
Yeah.
created it and then we started to work and that's I think that's 8 months ago and since then I've only met them two times in real life Berlin and we are
like working 20 24/7 in cos actually from the moment we wake up we are like working remotely together yeah cool
that's awesome so tell us about I want to know a little bit more about like building it you know maybe not the technical aspects but like give us some of the logistics right like so you met
your co-founder, you start talking about like, okay, let's do this thing from that inception point to like a viable MVP.
What does that look like?
Especially working remotely and kind of Yeah, we basically had to figure out a way to productize what I've got going on for myself,
right?
And there there's a lot that comes with that and we decided to go with a boiler plate,
basically a starter kit to build like a web app.
So we don't have to start from scratch with all the user authentication and stuff like that.
That one got us off the ground really quickly.
And the first version was just super basic.
Like we couldn't charge for that.
The first version was just what you saw a minute ago but just for tweet ideas.
So you would get random tweet ideas and we were like okay let's get this into the hands of our builder friends and that are also posting on X,
right?
let's see if this is actually something people want because it's like looking back it's really hard to do three things at once really good instead of one thing.
So it would really like we would have moved way faster I think if we have just concentrated on Twitter or just concentrated on Reddit and by doing everything we also had problems to
market it because it's really hard to define like which kind of person actually has a use case for all three of those platforms right that's interesting yeah and yeah we got like the first
version done which was super scrappy so we hit up like all our builder friends that were also on Twitter and posting it and we're asking them hey can you test this out for we just need feedback and
then we got super harsh feedback and we improved the product a lot and then I think a couple weeks later we just said okay this is enough now we're going to
launch this and that's how that process went so we just took my workflow and asked ourselves okay how can we make this accessible for everybody so
basically building a good UI for it I want to go into if you're if you're open to it like those all those DMs you sent like the the people you were trying to get to use the product at the beginning.
So just this is probably more for me like you know I know we follow each other on Twitter and I've I've been in the process of trying to build my first thing which is almost ready and now I'm at a point where I'm like damn now I got
people have to see this.
Yeah, you know I have to actually share it with somebody and I feel like a mental block of like it sucks you know I know it sucks but I have to share it.
So, I don't know if I'm looking for advice, but just like what was bring bring us into that like how many people did you DM and it's probably hard to like remember the exact numbers,
but let's just say out of 100, how many people responded and what was some of that feedback and how did that like feel?
I think like because those were our friends.
I'm not going into that like they were down to test anything.
When it comes to like strangers and we had the first version out and we did the real launch,
so people were actually paying for the product.
We made like a post saying, "Hey, this is really like we made a no-brainer offer basically launching and we said you can get access for a year for I think let I think it
was like 50 bucks."
So, it's not even like roughly $4 a month.
A no-brainer, right?
So, what's the risk?
And that's what we got like the first 10 paying users the same day and then we just did two posts.
So, that's kind of a lucky shot.
Maybe the real work started after that like the next users that those were the real pain and I started to do stuff that like as they say that doesn't
scale.
So I actually I had I was manually researching accounts where I thought okay these guys are really active on Twitter they might need help with content.
So, I prepared a Loom video for every single one, highly personalized, where I actually shared myself being on their Twitter page and being like,
"Hey, I saw that you do this and this and you need like Twitter to grow your agency.
Maybe this is how you can create content with Puzzle."
And I did I did this I think just one weekend.
I did it over 100 times.
I think like a longer weekend.
And that was a painful process because most of them didn't get back to me.
But I actually could see something which was really important.
They wouldn't answer, but they still signed up.
That's something that made me go, "Hey, wait, maybe I don't even need the answers.
I just need need to get the link to our app into me as many hands as possible."
And it's up to them because I think the friction to sign up for something or the friction to actually get into the conversation with somebody,
those are like different frictions.
Yeah.
And like to get feedback, it was far easier to contact like the the already paying users and we got into like we had many video calls.
So I would advise like do a lot of posts and ask like just ask directly, hey, I need some feedback from people that would see themselves using this app super early
and maybe do like once like one post of these types every second day and then spin up the concept like sometimes just a screenshot sometimes a loom video
explaining it sometimes maybe a POV video of yourself using it to show the use case and then I would do like I would go into code dumps and That's one that one is really painful because you
can expect like depending on the how good the code DM is like I would say 5% answers for that mean means five people maybe answer from 100 and I think the
more if you're looking for like say systemized growth thing you want to get from those code DMs is actually more the feedback seeing which code DM script is working and then later on you can
systemize that and send out automated DM.
So that's that's that was the big learning just seeing okay targeting different people seeing how they respond and then seeing that they actually didn't that they sign up but they don't
answer.
So getting them to sign up is easier to get it than getting them on a talk or video call to to get like feedback,
right?
And we honest we wanted harsh feedback.
That's the thing we we are looking for.
Like every time people reach out to us and say like hey I'm super sorry actually I found this bug.
I'm always like, "Dude, you want to make this thing amazing?"
Like, "Never be afraid to hit me up."
Like every sign up, I like research them manually on Hex and I write them a code in case saying,
"Hey, I just saw you signed up for poster.
We're super happy.
Our mission is to make this like the best content creation tool for Twitter and later on other platforms.
If you have anything that's not working right, if you need help with anything, always free,
feel free to hit me up."
And those are like the little things that really don't scale, but they give like I've gotten a 100% positive response rate on those things.
Yeah, that's cool.
And that's great.
I mean, that's like it goes to show just how much I don't want to say manual, but maybe that is like manual work at the beginning you're doing,
right?
You're researching individuals, you're sending individual looms, you're sending individual DMs,
getting individual feedback.
And uh I don't know.
I think that's what like separates people, right?
Is like it's cool to build something and that's kind of where I feel like I am and then it's another level to be like let me go just like kind of do all this stuff that doesn't scale.
And I think that's that's pretty cool and I think it's like really good tactical advice I think.
Okay.
So you you do all these DMs, you get all this feedback, you start making you obviously make a few sales in the first day is what you said.
Maybe just briefly touch on if you can like how did you know like you should keep going?
So you're getting this feedback and people are people are saying oh this sucks or this works or whatever.
Did you have anything that made you seem say like okay there's this is feedback this is harsh but I think this can still work.
There are a couple things but in the early stages like 2 weeks after launch we still had like a really basic MVP.
We reached out to every user asking for like a quick video call telling basically we on the user call by offering value first.
We said,"Hey, we grew our accounts to this size in this time.
Let's do like a profile audit."
And that's how we got them on a call and the la like the last 30% of the call were like,
"Hey, let tell us like some feedback please about that.
What can we improve?"
Right?
So, one of those guys that got got like the lifetime deal basically, which was really heavily discounted.
And we he told us that this stage he's using it daily to come up with post ideas.
So he runs like a design agency and he had more followers at that stage than both of us and he was relying on he told us in the call he's
relying on the post to attract clients.
So that's really good.
That's a really good sign because for us it means we need content to to get like a business return on invest.
So yeah that's that's usually the better type of problem to solve like a not a that's a painkiller problem basically and not a vitamin problem.
and him telling us he uses he uses the product every day.
That was the big aha moment.
Then we got the same like not everybody falls into that category like you have some like the user activity just ranges from user user to user but we got more and more people
like that and some power users actually.
Then later on we use switch to post hog for analytics and we could see how long they actually spent in the app.
That thing was actually the moment I saw that one of the paying users spent like one and a half hours on average creating content and I was like,
"Hey, this is actually crazy."
And that was one of the final things also that made me go, okay, I actually have I'm in the best position to quit my job and to go full-time on this and try out to see,
hey, maybe I can make this big together with my friends.
Yeah, there might be something here.
Yeah, this is like in the early stages.
I think you're rather looking for signs to validate that you're solving a painful problem and not signs to validate your solution because rarely
do you build the the final solution.
Yeah, that's cool.
Cool.
Okay, that's perfect transition to quitting your job.
So, you were I was I wanted to pull this pull up this tweet.
You kind of had like a countdown going, I think, right?
Like, hey, ever x days until I quit my job.
Here's how I feel.
next day.
So, day one, day two, and you know, this one was just a couple weeks ago, day one of freedom.
I quit my job, blah blah blah blah blah.
This is awesome, you know, like so cool to see.
And I thought it was cool to wish I could could have found more of them.
And I sure I'm sure I could if I like kept looking, but the the days leading up to it.
So, maybe just talk us a little bit about I want to know about what was it like to have that countdown going.
Start here actually.
How did you know like this was viable enough to quit your job?
Was it like certain amount that was growing every day or every month?
Or was there a number you had in your head that was like, "Okay, if we hit this, there isn't like this one point where you're 100% sure,
but wanted to quit for a long time and go fulltime on something.
I just needed a mission and a clear goal and something that is already kind of working.
I knew if I go full focus on it, I can take it to that point.
It covers like living costs."
And we are we are in that moment where we grow this thing postal to that point.
I think on average we grow like 11 to 15% like week to week.
Meaning we keep up that average growth rate we will hit like 10k MR the end of the year.
That's a bit overoptimistic because of course it gets harder the longer you keep going right seeing that very clearly and seeing that people actually there were a couple things happening made me go okay let's
let's try it out.
like I'm 70% 80% sure there is something here and I want to see like I'm ready to risk it to see if it might actually work out.
And one of those things were like four weeks after the launch, somebody sent us via post talk like,
"Hey, I want to send you some feedback.
Here's my email.
Contact me."
I was like, "Weird.
Why don't you send like directly the the feature, right?"
So, I sent him an email anyway and was like happy that I reached out and he sent me a Loom video back going through the app and he was like,
"Dude, add this.
I would love to have this.
I love the direction you're going with this."
At the very end, he said something that blew me away.
And also like my two co-founders, he was like, "I love the product.
I love the direction you're going with this.
I would love to own a part of it."
It's like four weeks in after the launch.
Yeah.
And then we kept getting like two other people like say I would say they were serious about this.
They were like, "Hey, let's show me we can beat this one like a big competitor kind of and be down to show this my angel round.
See if we can like do an investment."
we that we attracted this type of attention from these people so early on and that we got users that spend so much time and that we already got like revenue because it's super hard
actually like many startups they never do revenue never do any kind of revenue or profit we're already here and it made me go okay you know what I'm going to quit and has been already in the works
like I've been saving up I've been living very very frugally the last three years ever since I started working I've been saving Now I've got enough cash runway for at least 24 months and I'm
going to leave actually Germany to live in Southeast Asia.
Just expand on that runway and I'm going to give basically sell everything I own, give up everything I own here and then I'm going to move there,
make it happen.
That's that's the plan at least on paper.
Yeah, that's cool, dude.
That that is super awesome.
I love kind of hearing a little bit of that.
And then I want to know just like what was that day like when you quit your job, you walk out presumably at the end of the day or maybe you walked out at 12:00 p.m.
I don't know.
Just just p personally what what did that feel like?
What were your thinking?
Like just bring us into that kind of moment.
Took me actually like I made the post like the I think I made the post on Twitter like last time clocking out or something.
Yeah.
Something like that.
this that's the moment where I was like okay now it's getting real and it was weird I felt like very relieved if you're building we have been building
this like since the last year I think we started to work on this and if you're juggling like a day job and then a startup this or a side project whatever
stage you want to call it right very mentally you're so split up like you're worrying about the work and then about everything else that you got going on in your life and then at the same time
about the thing you were building.
The moment I clocked out I gained so much free space mentally.
I was putting a lot of pressure away.
All the pressure is just basically doing what I love.
Like I from this day it didn't even take me like 2 hours I think after I clocked out I started to work on poster again.
Yeah.
Till till 1:00 a.m.
So you're like back to work.
Yeah.
Now like I so many people are doing it.
I don't know if you have seen that like the Tik Tok daily founder series.
Yeah, I've seen that.
Yeah, it's kind of taken off a little bit.
I've seen you I've seen you post about the those Tik Toks.
Yeah.
And I Let's see if I could pull one up as you're talking.
Go ahead.
I started to like I'm super camera shy actually.
Like I'm not person to be like in front of the camera.
I thought, hey, I quit my job.
One would make me actually go like out of my comfort zone.
Yeah.
Like so like this little series here.
Right.
And I had like it's now day 16.
So I started on the first day where I was actually jobless kind of and that's a nice like nice moment to start something like this just for fun to get a bit more used to speak in front to the
camera and those like having the freedom to do stuff like that makes you go damn I actually I'm actually free right now to do whatever I want and that's coming
more and more like the more time progresses from the moment I quit actually.
Yeah.
That's awesome.
Cool.
And then uh if anything here, but like what did your friends or family say as you're like building this thing?
And I don't know, may maybe they don't know.
That's that's cool, too.
Just I'm curious like that like they think that I'm batshit crazy to Yeah.
They're like you're making an app for Twitter.
They call it now X.
Yeah.
Germany is like not well known actually.
Yes.
So when I told my was actually uncomfortable when when I left on the last day like all the people were asking hey where are you going to work next I was like odd anyway
I can tell them the truth and so I told them I was like hey I'm I'm building this thing with two friends I've met on Twitter months ago and I'm going fulltime on this and they were like what
you're crazy man you have a you have a salary you have a benefits security right so it's like some people were like really supportive and the
other ones were like I get it.
Right.
Sure.
And I had the same stuff.
I thinking about quitting a long time, right?
And I already told like my friends family and girlfriend two months ago.
They know about my Twitter stuff and the stuff I'm building on the site that stage and they were like,
"Hey, yeah, yeah, let's just keep going on."
And then like some point I noticed I'm getting serious.
And it took a bit of convincing after like in the end they were like want you to succeed and I will support you this path.
Everybody in my close circle was like if you do like really do it focus your best.
I think if it doesn't work out in two years I will be still able to get a job anywhere to be honest I would just start from scratch like save up again and then at some point to go all in on something
again.
Yeah.
That's cool.
I I love hearing that cuz I feel like this is just me personally but I'm sure someone can relate.
Some people will look at you and be like, "What are you doing?"
Like that's get a stay in a real job.
But like you just said, there are also people that'll say seem to really like this and you should do it and if you're going to do it,
go for it.
And I'm sure that felt just so empowering and so just like, "Okay, I guess I got this."
And who cares what co-orker says or this person I kind of know says, my friends and family are like,
"Go for it."
Like, and you're right, you can always come back to another job.
And like you said, you you have the playbook a little bit.
save up, ready to go, and then take the leap again.
I love that.
Cool.
All right, my last question for you, Joshua, is just like um there's people watching,
kind of hearing your story, and you've shared a lot of cool advice, and I think that's awesome.
But what would you maybe say to yourself, you know, if you think back postal started what,
like months ago, less than a year ago?
Would you say to yourself back then?
piece of advice or one piece of advice you would sort of leave yourself right before you started postal actually say that just move faster and more be more focused and what
that looks like is for starting to work on a solution for anything I wished we have would have the idea or prototype of it you haven't even built it and you
just do like a trapdo test where you you basically launch or do like a weightless launch to see okay how much attention does sketch,
right?
This one can save you a lot of time you if you're not really sure what to work on.
And to be honest, I would wish we had Yeah.
just talk to more more users and get like be really close to the users so you're sure you're solving something actually painful to them and a problem for them
and then build fast like like get so many like as I said earlier right you're not building first thing you will build is going to be so far away from the
final solution that's going to look like product market fit in my opinion and get like go faster through this process like through all these iter erations and then
build systems around how you capture like user feedback.
How you basically take a like a single piece or unit of user feedback and spin up a feature around that and then get that into the hands of new users to get feedback for
us and then based on that.
Same goes for studying anything, read hitting anything, figure out a way how to get it into the hands of the users because you might end up like having bit invested a
lot of time into something no idea where your users are and how to reach them and that's going to make things really hard for us.
What it was was easy because we could just launch and all our followers right we had at that point with a really modest following like also posting on X and they're like hey let's give this a
shot.
We had like a free trial so no risk and that was a great way like we could easily get in touch with our users and that's key I think also talk to
users really tried but there's a reason it gets repeated by many many founders often I feel like I've butcher the same
like the simple advice is like simple for a reason or obvious advice is obvious for a reason and that's kind of exactly what you just said like talk to users is move fast.
Like it sounds simple, but you know that's like what matters or seems like what has mattered for your business at the at the end of the day.
So really cool, dude.
Well, thanks so much.
This was a really awesome conversation.
Appreciate you taking the time out of your Friday night to talk to me and talk to our audience and congrats on all the success and grow bigger.
Maybe we'll kind of do a full feature on you on our main channel.
So we we'll keep following you along and uh for you and thanks for coming on.
Appreciate it.
Dude, thanks for having me.
It's I think two years and I'll be on the main channel.
So, Friday or June 27th, 2027.
See you there.
All right.
See you.
Bye.