Today we will be exposing BTOC viral apps.
Apps that charge $4 a month, $10 a month, $20 a month.
You've seen these apps on Twitter X.
They're making millions of dollars.
How?
This week, we will be exposing the notso secret strategy that these apps use to print millions of dollars.
Without further ado, let's get into it.
Okay, so I got Gus here.
Gus is a researcher at Starter Story.
He's put together a massive list of BTOC apps doing this strategy.
We're going to go over a very specific example.
So Gus, if you want to kick us off.
Hey, so I was doing some research.
By research, I mean scrolling Twitter.
And let me share my screen and show you the tweet that I saw that really intrigued me.
So shout out to this guy, whoever he is, Gam.
And this was a couple days ago.
He said, "We entered a tick, we've entered a Tik Tok multi-accountled hyperrowth era for apps."
And then he lists all these different apps, some of which I've heard of.
like I've heard of TurboLearn.
We've obviously talked to the guy from Calai and then a bunch of others that I had never really heard of.
And he just lists the app, how much they're making, how many views they're getting, etc.,
etc.
And got a good amount of views on this tweet, right?
And so it als it reminded me of we recently published a video with David Park two.
I have it pulled up here.
It's the $10 million AI SAS playbook.
And if you haven't watched it, go watch it.
But in this he talks a lot about right how they grew Jenny Aai and he talks a lot about how they did it through all these Tik Tok accounts which I thought was super interesting.
And so when I you know when I was looking at this tweet I just thought let's like go see what some of these apps are doing,
how much they're making, what these Tik Toks look like cuz I I just kind of had to know.
Yeah.
So I just picked three.
So let's look to the let's look at the first one.
Yeah.
Maybe before before I jump in.
What changed and you know now why is everybody doing this?
That's a good question.
And I don't know if I'll we might cut this but I don't really know what changed.
I wonder if what changed is like some people started doing it.
I don't know who that some people are.
Maybe someone like Jenny and other apps like that started doing it and now all these apps are like hey let's let's try this too and it's working.
Tik Tok had a moment right where it was like going to be taken down in the US but it came back.
I wonder if people realized or in that you know couple days when it was offline or really one day we're like damn this is a really powerful tool.
Let's like max this out.
That would be like some that'd be some off the you know cuff ideas of that be interesting to see what you think or what people watching what they think.
But yeah that's kind of some thoughts there.
Yeah, my thoughts are like that it's just this idea has I guess something that can be gamed and it reminds me of like once once SEO was proven and a
proven strategy and because everyone's eyeballs were searching on Google then it became this thing where and this is a few years ago where you would just pay
for backlinks and you could game the algorithm to and just throw a ton of money at the algorithm and and just like stuff keywords into pages and that sort of And there was this just this moment
of time where you could just go bonkers on SEO just by throwing money at the problem.
This feels like that version of that for the Tik Tok era, but I could be wrong.
I don't know if this will last forever, but it's clearly working now.
Yeah, as you say that, it reminded me of like I just saw this tweet like it was like 2021 or whatever when there was all these like threads on on Twitter going around that were just like blowing
accounts up.
Yeah.
And that was another I think kind of moment in time like this where like people realized oh this work is working right now.
Let me let me do it.
I remember reading all these threads about people or business or whatever it was books and I think it's like Dicky Bush another guy that we you know you've interviewed on starter story he talked about he's talked about that
like that's when he started growing his account and so I wonder if this is like a similar this feels like one of those big moments in time where if you act fast you can rack up a lot of dollars
and also build a you know generational wealth type of business in a very short span of time.
Yeah, agreed.
Okay, so let's go into the first one then.
The first one I just picked from this list was Lockit App 300,000 MRR, etc.
So, just to show you what this app is, which all these apps are just so funny to me.
This is a essentially it's a friendship app where you can have a widget on your phone that has like a real time or updated picture of what's going on in
your life.
Uh, think of it kind of like a Snapchat.
And I you you showed me this actually but there's an app called or a website called sensor tower where you can kind of get some information on
these apps and according to sensor tower last month this app had a million downloads 300k per month you know number I don't I don't know how much this
matters but 13 in social networking and if you look at the like review store you can see like ratings it's like 400,000 ratings.
Holy smokes.
I've never even heard of this damn app, which is crazy.
Maybe I'm too old, but you know, there's like millions of people using this app.
My gosh.
It's pretty sick, right?
And their pricing, where did I find them?
Their pricing is like, it's like $3.99 a month or $36 a year.
Yeah, something down here.
You could see that.
Yeah, but you know, so going back to this tweet, it was like 20, but I just picked three.
So, do you want to see those first or you want you have any thoughts on this?
Okay.
So you're you're confident that they're growing their business through Tik Tok or I guess that that tweet said it,
but you went and found out.
Yeah, I went and found like I found their main account and then three other accounts.
Oh, so they're multiple accounts.
Yeah, multiple accounts that are affiliated.
I think that's the play is like these are these influencers that are posting about the app.
So let me just show you one.
I think it'll make sense.
So this one is a guy called Caleb's Journal.
Don't know who he is, but let's just look at the most popular ones.
And obviously actually that's I saw this interesting.
If you don't want locket content wouldn't follow, which goes to show this is what this guy's posting about.
So let's just look at one of these.
13 million views.
He says I'm crying.
Hold on.
Let me I'm crying.
My little bro asked me to get this when I moved out.
And sure enough, it's the Locket app that he's kind of showing off.
13 million views.
So that's one.
You think men are actually using this app or they like they think this guy's good-looking so they want to use it?
a little controversial, but I I would find it hard to believe that dudes are using this app.
Yeah.
I mean, I would go in the comments and and take a look.
This isn't relevant, but in the comments, you probably see all women in there.
Yeah.
So, this one, you move away from home and your brother asks to do this together.
Sure enough.
The Locket app.
Oh my gosh.
One more.
Let's just look at one more.
Leaving for college.
My mom made the whole fam get this.
What do you think it is?
The locket app.
And these are getting I mean I obviously started for the popular one but 13 4 million 2 million crying because my mom asked the whole fan to get this.
What do you think it is?
The locket app.
Same thing.
He just does his he flips his phone, shows his phone and does it and and it's kind of the same like I'm crying.
I'm emotional and I'm crying.
Literal tears.
It's almost like a bait and switch too is like by the time the fourth time you watch this you're like god damn it.
Lock it up again.
Yeah.
What the Cuz I lock it up again.
That's funny actually.
But so that's just one.
So let me show you just another one.
But there's this one.
Ka's Lens.
Let's just look at popular.
The app of the summer.
8 million views.
What do you think it is?
The locket app.
Not only is it the locket app, it's the same exact format where Oh yeah, you're right.
It's one line and then it shows the screen.
Yep.
So like it's perfect.
I wonder if these people are real.
That's another question.
But millions of views, hundreds of thousands of views.
My best friend did this.
Me something to do with their attractiveness too, right?
For sure.
100%.
And let me just show you the last one and then we'll comment on it again.
So this one, Morgs, Gabrielle, don't know who you are.
Attractive looking person.
How my life looks when this is another this the other girl was saying the same thing like you finally deleted Snapchat and downloaded this instead.
Constant updates.
Moved away from college.
Does that sound familiar?
We still do this every single day.
What do you think it is?
Lock it out.
And do they have a link in their bio or or how are they?
I'm curious how the affiliate interesting.
They don't.
Not this one.
Some of the others I'm going to show you.
Do either getting paid on views or or something because it'd be hard to track.
Yeah, these are just three of I mean I saw like 15 of these accounts that are more or less doing this influencer marketing thing for the
Locket app.
Oh my gosh.
This is I mean this is amazing research and yeah so back to the numbers right?
A million downloads a month 300k per month and number 13 social networking app on in the app store.
This is crazy.
I mean it just shows that there is no secret.
This this this is the best kept not so secret thing that's working for apps.
And every time I talk to founders I get on I'm getting on the phone doing a lot of interviews with founders.
They're always sharing this story.
I just talked to someone who I can't share who it is, but they got to 1 million in 90 days.
1 million MR in 90 or ARR in 90 days through a few strategic Tik Tok formats.
That's crazy.
So, I have this calculator.
Okay, so if you want to figure out how much a business is actually making, it's actually really simple.
You have to make some assumptions on certain things because not everything is fully researchable,
but it's pretty easy to get an industry standard.
So, did you This is my little calculator here, and you guys I'll put a link in the description so you guys can plug anything into here.
You can use this for your own app, your own idea, or just to test and check out what other apps are making.
Do you know how many views or impressions this app is getting?
That's a good question.
According to this tweet, it said 150 million views.
150 million.
So, I'll type that in.
150.
1 2 3 1 2 3.
And then, how many downloads were they getting?
You said it was a million per month.
Yeah, a million a month.
So that would be like.7 I think.
Yeah.
So if they're getting 150 million views, what percentage of those are converting to downloads?
And that's that number right there is actually.7%.
Not even one.
Yeah, less than 1%.
That makes sense, right?
How many people watch the thing and just scroll over and move on to the next one?
So, a low app download rate makes sense and also shows you, you know, you can back your numbers into this.
And if you wanted to build a business that made $100,000 a month, you can go and put your numbers in here.
Then the next thing that I look at is, well, what we know for sure is how much money they charge.
What was the number there?
$3.99 a month at 36 a year.
Some just 36.
3.99 a month.
So, let's say $4.
Oh, yeah.
A month.
Yeah.
$4 a month.
And then what we have to figure out is what their paid conversion rate is.
So if they get 1 million downloads, what percentage of those convert to paid users?
I actually don't know.
So I will go into chat GBT and I can search what is the typical conversion rate of a BTOC app in the iPhone in the in the app
store.
Yeah, I'll type that in and it'll give us a range probably.
App Store page view to install install the signup onboard user 1 to 5% often less than 2%.
So let's just be conservative and we will plug in that they are doing a conversion rate of 1% maybe 1.5 we could do and you can see how much money this
business is actually making.
So then the other one that I like to put in there is churn as well.
Churn is not that important for when you're first starting out but you can see how this business will grow over time.
So I'm going to actually ask what the churn is too.
What is the typical churn?
And churn meaning how long do they stay on at what percentage of customers fall off because it is a subscription app.
Typical monthly churn 5 to 10% good churn less than five excellent churn less than three.
So I maybe we'll say that there are six% churn.
So on 150 million impressions 1 million turn to downloads.
15 15,000 of those turn into paying customers.
I think that number could be higher if they had a certain payw wall, but that means that they get 63,000 in new revenue.
But that is not 63,000 per month.
That's 63,000 in new revenue per month.
So if you put it in this table here, because it is a monthly recurring revenue business,
you can see how much the MR grows each month.
So if you were to start this business today, and those were all to stay constant, by the 12th month,
you would have a $500,000 per month business.
Yeah.
And you can see what that looks like here.
By month 30, you'd have almost a million dollar per month business.
That's the power of a recurring revenue business.
As long as you can keep those numbers constant, that's not a guaranteed, but that's how I can see how much money this business is making.
That's wild.
Obviously, the the huge assumption is that this all continues, right?
that the attention and all that continues, but there's certainly a like period of time like we said at the beginning right now where maybe this is like really working.
Yeah.
And so it's like you're you're going all in on this if I'm that business, right?
Like hey, this is working.
Let's go like like push.
That's what David talked about I think in his YouTube video was like outreaching to as many of those people as possible and getting them to promote your stuff.
Yeah.
If you don't do it now, it'll be too late by the time you get it to work.
So the best founders are the ones who really make it are the ones who act with urgency.
But you know what I think is also interesting before we go into the next one is I think one thing that also changed too is that there's like more so a willingness to pay for something like
this cuz I I remember a few years ago precoid pre you know where we all work from home and and you know we're all digital and it's different generation for sure.
I remember when apps would be when apps would charge money, nobody would pay for them,
right?
Cuz most apps were free and people were just not willing to pay for digital things.
I just I just remember that like, oh, you paid for an app.
Why would you pay for something that is usually free?
Google's free.
All these things are free.
But nowadays, people are willing to pay for the locket app.
They're willing to pay for digital solutions, apps, and things like that.
And obviously, there's billion-dollar companies built on apps.
That's one of the bigger changes too when I think of what is the why is this working now is there's this combination of algorithms changing and consumer willingness to pay and that's like maybe
like the deadly combo right now.
Like we said it reminds me of the Calai guys, you know, that you interviewed a while back.
I think this was part of their strategy that I saw hiring a bunch of like fitness influencers to use their app and getting a bunch of downloads growing to however many millions.
Okay.
But well, before we on before we move on to the next one, I do want to share one little thing.
Shameless plug.
Uh but these Tik Tok examples, these businesses that are growing like wildfire, they're proof that the most important thing for your business is attention,
right?
Features don't matter.
Product doesn't matter anymore.
Attention is the name of the game.
By attention, I mean uh marketing strategies that get eyeballs on your product.
Sharing your product, simply sharing your product online and just testing your product in public and getting feedback and getting validation from real people.
When you get attention on your product, it solves all your problems.
It will tell you if you have a good idea.
It'll tell you if you don't have a good idea, and it'll give you the information necessary to either fix it or double down.
That's why at Starter Story, we have the attention database inside.
Dozens of examples of real world posts that you can use, copy and paste, to grow your business.
I've had me I've seen members of Starter Story use these templates get tens of thousands of views,
thousands of customers.
It works just like the examples we showed doing the same things.
Works.
Just head to the first link in the description if you want to get access to it.
Our team is adding more and more every day when we find stuff like we're talking about today.
All right, now back to the episode.
All right, let me show you the next one.
Yeah, so the next app is called Couple Joy and it's a relationship app.
I don't know.
Love tracking and long distance whatever.
Cute widgets, things to chat with your partner about.
8,000 ratings.
Let's look at the sensor tower data.
So, according to this, we're getting 500,000 downloads last month.
Similar revenue.
And it says 19 19 in in the lifestyle category.
The pricing on this one, where is it?
This must be different different types, right?
$12.99, 13 to 40 bucks a month.
I'm sure there's something about like the amounts of messages or whatever you can send.
So, similar to the last one, I found a list of, you know, 10 10 15 Tik Tok accounts and I just dug into a few that I thought were interesting.
So, it's going to be no surprise, but they're all going to be kind of similar.
So, here's this one.
Nessa and Ruby Couplejoy content.
And you we're talking about the link, right?
Couplejoy.app nessie.
Let's just look at these.
Just this is like crazy, right?
Like hand over face.
We found a secret way to get connected.
Let me guess what it is.
Nessie, it is probably the Couple Joy app.
Couple joy days together.
Blah blah blah.
There's that one.
Another one.
Hand over the face.
You're telling me I've been in a longdist relationship.
Oops.
I think I skipped it.
Two years.
Just found out this app lets me send messages to his lock screen.
What do you think it is?
Couple dry.
So that's like all these, right?
and so similar hand over face something shocking is happening.
But let me show you what the shocking thing I just found is and it's that app.
That's one example.
Here's another one.
This is this means like living a longdistance relationship and it's similar.
We'll see you tomorrow.
And this is actually a slideshow and it's the couple joy app.
Oh my god.
Three million views.
Million views.
Two million views.
And then the last one is I don't know.
Kenna Daily, don't know who you are, Kenna.
Sure you're cool if you're real but similar distance couple joy op/kenna pictures with my beautiful boyfriend millions of views thousands of
views another similar handoverface thing so you kind of you kind of get the point there right it's like all of these people are doing the same thing and
getting millions of views and in this case they do have a let's see what happens here yeah it takes them to download with obviously the reference probably or the the tracking link Yeah,
I mean that's a couple joy.
Clear this is clearly this is working.
The couple joy and the locket app have two things that I noticed that are the same is that they like to show off the feature where you can put something on your home screen customized,
right?
You know, that's a I think that's a newer feature on iPhones, too, by the way.
That would that's what I was going to say and like, you know, I I I share with a lot of the Starry members about,
you know, like how can you find a business idea that takes off?
It doesn't sound like a crazy change in the world.
But iPhone adding customization to the home screen enables new businesses.
Never before could that be done, but it's cool because everyone stares at their iPhone and pick up their iPhone 100 times a day.
That is the quote unquote killer feature that may enable these these apps have grown so fast.
I think that is actually something that you could probably do for anyone that's looking for business ideas here.
How could you do that for founders?
Could you put your revenue MR on your home screen connected to Stripe?
I've seen someone do that before.
Or let's say you are I don't know, put your net worth or finance or the other thing that I think that I want to mention if we can dive even deeper than just Okay,
here's a couple cool Tik Toks.
There's another thing I noticed about these two apps and their style is what I I tell starter story members about too is it the importance of intent.
So, a lot of people think, "Oh, I'll just go post on TikTok about, you know, what I have for breakfast that day or I'll post about even the problem that I'm solving."
But if you don't actually every single example you showed me that has millions of views and clearly what's working for them is they address the problem or they have some sort of hook or something like
that and then they switch it and they show the actual app, right?
Imagine if they did that without showing the app.
You wouldn't care about the app.
You just care about the person.
every single video they show you the actual app in use or being used or they're they're associating the problem that they're solving or whatever with the app.
That's really important.
I see a lot of people not do that.
So they'll create, hey, you know, me and my boyfriend we're doing long distance, but then they don't show the app.
Nobody's going to know about the app, right?
The intent is really important.
So if you just, you know, share with people what you're having for breakfast that day,
but you don't show them your product, then creating content, creating Tik Toks is pointless,
right?
Yeah.
No, that's such a good point, right?
Cuz you can go viral on Tik Tok or Twitter or whatever for some stupid you say or some hot take.
Yeah.
Which happens all the time, which maybe, you know, something crazy could get 20 million views or 100 million views,
but something with intent Yeah.
will get you more users.
That reminds me of like right on Twitter this week there's been the whole Have you seen this?
Like the fitness guy?
I saw this a little bit.
Saratoga or something.
Yeah, Ashton.
You're right.
Ashton Hall.
But there was no like intent behind this, right?
May maybe there was.
I mean, the tips for men, he did he did end up linking his his stuff here, you know,
got 6 million views there.
But I don't know.
My my point in bringing that up is just like the intent maybe of these Tik Toks is more direct than just like some crazy influencer posting his daily daily thing.
Yep.
Yeah.
Not that we're like in the business of giving advice or whatever, but like that people should do that people should be cautious of that.
Maybe doesn't maybe who cares like just go for it if in this world kind of thing.
Yeah.
I'm kind of torn by it to be honest.
Like I think there's something that's a little bit unethical about creating content that is purely designed to be algorithmic and is potent like some of the examples that you
shared have potentially bad intentions like you know if that person saying I'm going to college every day when maybe they're 26 years old and they graduated college four years ago.
I don't know if that's the case for that one, but I can see a world where that becomes more normalized to just create content for the sake of content.
It's a it's a different generation for sure, but there does something I do have a bad gut feeling about about doing that.
But at the same time, you know, short form content is entertainment at the end of the day.
So, you know, is this is this real or is this fiction?
If I watch a movie right now, it doesn't have to be real.
It's fake and I can still enjoy it and be entertained by it.
I don't know.
What do you think?
I think I was thinking about like Well, to answer that question, yeah, I think maybe it's just getting old where I'm just like,
h, you know, this is so fake and who buys this you know?
I'm looking at all these apps and I'm like, would I ever like download something off of this?
This is for a specific target, right?
I've I feel like I've been targeted for other things like there's an app I always see.
It's called Opal.
It's like a focus app.
And I've I've gone through the flow of like, oh, let me click this link from here and whatever.
So maybe maybe it's just like I don't resonate with these because it's not like my target,
but there's other I'm sure other apps and Tik Toks that I've seen that have totally gotten me.
Yeah, true.
But yeah, I think another part of this feels like uh and this is obviously on like me as a consumer or us on consumers is like these are just kind of spamming us in our face every day and like you almost
like don't even see it which is crazy.
Like you don't or I feel like I don't see like all the ads that I'm lowkey getting cuz that's kind of what this is,
right?
I don't know what to make of that.
That's kind of crazy to me.
It's cool, I guess.
But I think that's a good point is that these are just ads, right?
Have you ever gotten mad about advertisement?
Yeah.
When the commercial comes on and you yell at the commercial how much you hate that commercial,
that's okay.
That's just a commercial.
Like, who cares?
And like when you're right now, we're like hyper analyzing these guys pages and, you know,
we're going to their page and we're seeing that they're doing the same thing over and over again.
That's not the typical behavior of someone that's browsing Tik Tok.
You know, they're just browsing Tik Tok and one of those might come up and it may catch their attention and that's that's okay.
Really just an maybe it should they should be disclosing that it's an ad in some way or or eventually these social media companies will will do something about it and say that this is an ad,
but at the end of the day, that's just an advertisement.
Who cares?
Move on with your life.
Go touch some grass.
And none of this stuff is real, so you might as well do it if you want to build a business and make some money.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's crazy.
All right, last one.
This one is a study app, which you know, we see billions of study apps, don't we?
This one is called Einstein Homework Helper.
Nice.
Just ace your exams, some kind of study tip, etc.
Thousand thousand reviews.
Funny scam.
Do not pay.
Saved my GPA.
Wait, wait, but it says scammed.
Yeah, I guess so.
That's funny.
Okay, so according to this one, Sensor Tower data again, 70,000 downloads last month,
so a little less, 90K revenue, 93 in education worldwide.
There's actually a couple of This doesn't matter, but there used to be like a a different app called Fineman.
And now this one's called Einstein.
But let's go into their Tik Toks and find some people that are promoting this.
So we got StudyB Princess and dog over there.
Yeah.
Can you hear her?
Sorry.
Yeah, I'm getting a delivery.
She doesn't like anybody.
Sorry if you could hear that in the background.
I was trying to ignore.
Okay.
Study B Princess.
They are low-key promoting this app.
So, you know, it's it's the same playbook, right?
The the the difference here is like they're they're kind of like it's almost like there's these informal like what did you get on your exam today and what did you use to study?
I got 68.
Did you study a little bit?
The one that did get an ace.
What did you get or what did you use?
Does it come up that fineman?
Where's another example?
How to use Einstein AI?
What's your GPA?
So, that's one example.
Let's look at nurse bunny notes.
When someone says they use chat GB study, I don't use that.
What do I use instead?
Einstein AI or Yeah, Ein Einstein AI homework helper.
What did you get on the exam?
Blah blah blah.
Einstein AI is what I used to study.
And then, you know, let's just look at one more.
Same girl.
No, you're right.
It is the same or similar girls.
No, no, that girl is the same.
I have I'm I'm a super recognizer, so I recognize faces.
That's the same girl.
Oh, yeah.
That's funny.
On two different accounts.
There you go.
Right.
No, I think so.
I think so.
Yeah.
So, it's fake.
I mean, but they're like pretending to interview people in the street, but Yeah.
And then this is the playbook, right?
Just over the shoulder looking at my exam.
Wow.
Promoting promoting Einstein.
I like this one because it's a little bit of a smaller one.
I mean, I see 70,000 downloads, but number 93 in education.
That's by no means small, right?
But if I plugged that into my my revenue generator there, bring that up.
Yeah, let me pull that one up because, you know, the one that we showed was so big it was crazy to lock it up.
Like that's like pretty sick.
But I want to see what the for someone who's watching this who might, you know, be able to build an app with AI in our AI build accelerator,
which you should check out.
We'll put a link in the description.
What can you do with 100,000 views, right?
So, how many impressions did that one get?
Let me share my screen here.
18 million views.
Okay, that's 18 million views per month.
So that's a little smaller.
That's like about 10 times smaller than the one we talked about first.
I'm guessing that the app download rate is higher cuz you know when you get to really big scale says 70,000 views or downloads.
70,000 downloads.
That's actually quite low.
So I just going to get it to that point.
70,000.
Let's say maybe point4 72,000.
And what was the I'm guessing that the conversion rate on that one is going to be high because people want to ace their test,
right?
Yeah, just to be conservative, let's do a 4% conversion.
And what was the pricing on that one?
Pricing was $12.99 13 a month.
Okay, so that's more expensive than the $4 one.
So I take 13.
And the churn on that one is probably pretty good actually because you know they're in high school or whatever.
So and they need it for multiple tests.
So yeah, the MRR on this one after it looks like they're probably adding 37,000 in new revenue per month with just simple Tik Tok strategy.
And then I always like to look at my little growth chart because subscription businesses grow.
Let's see at month 12 they're doing 346,000 per month, which is about a $5 million business.
Maybe just just a little less, but crazy.
That's just helping people.
It's an app for high schoolers, right?
Yeah.
high high schoolers or probably anyone.
In in school, education, middle school, college.
Yeah.
Huge market.
Those are three examples there.
You know, the takeaway for me is just like they're just running the same playbook.
And we see that so much.
I feel like we've talked about that before here.
Find something that works and just repeat it over and over again until it doesn't.
Yep.
And that's something that, you know, we can talk about how it's unethical or, you know,
a little bit scammy maybe, whatever.
But at the end of the day, this is what's clearly working.
It's getting views.
The algorithm is a lot, you know, is serving people what they want to see.
And I was talking to David Park, who started Jenny AI, which is like a AI writing tool.
They they do this kind of strategy for people who want to write their papers in college.
And he kind of said like, well, people are actually just creatures of habit, right?
I like to watch tennis matches over and over and it's the same players and to someone who's not interested in it,
it's really boring and it's the same thing over and over again, but it entertains me and I would have no problem someone putting tennis content in my feed like that,
right?
We're creatures of habit and you know it even goes to the top like think about yeah sports like I mentioned or for example Saturday Night Live or the Tonight Show.
They all have formats that work and they've done it over years and they're really popular.
So maybe that's a way to think about it too is like if that's working, it's really not.
Creativity is really not.
These aren't artists doing this, you know, clearly business.
And that's okay.
Yeah, you're right.
Yeah.
I think uh there should be like no shame in in posting stuff or or getting people to post your stuff because our attention spans are so short and just like just go for it.
Yeah, that's kind of my takeaway is like in terms of getting attention on your product or whatever,
if you're going to use these avenues like Twitter or Tik Tok or whatever, it's just being shameless about it.
I think the last thing that I I'll say is just like it was interesting to see how cuz these are only like three examples for each of these apps.
I could have shown you 15 and so that's interesting to me like the multiple accounts.
Yeah.
All kind of shilling the same thing.
I couldn't tell you what that does to the algorithm or whatever, but there's got to be something there where it's like if it's just one or two,
maybe it won't show you as much, but if there's 15 or 20, yeah, there's something else there.
I didn't I don't know what to make of that, but yeah.
Yeah, I think there's something there.
Yeah, David Parkana maybe a little bit had a little bit of a conspiracy going that they looked at like your SIM card to see if you're legit and like these accounts get deleted and banned sometimes.
So, if you lose one of them that you have others to help back you up.
So maybe it's a little bit of a hedge.
That's actually interesting.
I didn't think about that.
Yeah.
Cool.
And like I said, those were just three.
I could have shown you 20 examples like this.
So a little went a little bit of a rabbit hole and it was kind of fun in terms of like seeing just what these folks are doing apps are doing.
Crazy.
Well, I hope this is helpful for people who are watching this.
Thank you, Gus, for going and doing the research for you guys.
Let us know in the comments if you like this format.
We really dove deep into kind of like tick tock formats and short form formats which you know it's crazy to think about how much economic value is
driven through just one format right you we saw one format locket app format get used across basically that format borderline created millions of dollars
of value one simple video it's kind of crazy to think about how a company can be built off of content where it used to be the other way around so that was Cool.
What should we cover next?
Let's see what I find on Twitter this week.
Let us Yeah, let us know in the comments if you want us to cover other marketing strategies.
I thought I thought that was really interesting.
And uh we'll be back next week with another episode.
Thanks for watching, guys.