Today, I want to see if I can make $1 with AI in less than 24 hours.
Well, that's at least how I thought this video was going to start out when I came up with the idea over a month ago.
Then, if you've been following, you know that I haven't published anything in over a month.
But, as part of the challenge, I didn't give up.
And technically, it just didn't happen in 24 hours, but it happened.
And this video is going to be about the crazy story of how we got there.
So, just to remind you what I'm doing here, I am doing the 100K build challenge where I'm going to try to make $100,000 using only AI.
As you may already know, there are three rules.
I can only use AI tools.
I must document everything as I go.
And number three, I'm not allowed to give up until I make $100,000.
Here's how much I've made so far.
And I know it's not a lot, but this video is special because I feel like we're at a turning point.
I have that feeling inside my gut that I've sort of cracked the code.
And for this video, I wanted to fully document that feeling and how we got there.
As you can probably tell, Bernie is a lot older and a hell of a lot bigger than the last time we recorded this video.
But technically, this is day nine, a really episode 9 of the 100K build challenge.
Thank you guys for following along.
I'm really excited to do this video.
Let's go.
So about a month ago, I was hot off the presses with my last tool that I built, the AI business name builder.
And I had also talked about my plan to be launching a new tool every single week.
I was feeling pretty confident and I had even found the next idea that I was going to build.
So let me explain this idea because it's important to the story.
Well, the app was called Build in Public.
And I had gotten the idea from this AI resume generator that I had found online.
This was an app that was making $20,000 a month.
This is a really cool app.
Seems pretty easy to build.
How can we copy what worked from this app and apply it to a different audience?
So, I got really excited about this.
What if there's an app where you could put in all this information about you and it would pop out your first 30 build tweets?
I was really, really pumped about this idea.
I went and bought the domain, gobbuildinpublic.com.
I started building and I was feeling really, really good about this app because I knew I could build it in a day.
And the premise of getting 30 tweets done for you that might generate a few thousand views,
I think was worth it, especially if you had a pretty low price point.
So, I went and started building this and honestly, I did it in like a day.
Cursor built it all out and it seems like cursor is getting better and better by the day because it is still is working even better than it was when we started this challenge.
So, I basically built out the entire thing in the course of like a day.
I mean, I didn't get all the way there, but probably like 90% of the way there with just a few more things that I needed to fix.
So, the app was pretty cool.
You signed up.
I created this whole onboarding process that asks you what your name is, what you're trying to build,
what sort of challenges are you facing, and just a bunch of other stuff.
It felt really boutique.
It felt really cool.
Once you click generate, it created a whole strategy for you, and then it generated your first 30 tweets.
The AI was was pretty good and I was really kind of learning a lot about how to prompt something like this and how to make it good.
I knew it wasn't really perfect yet, but it was honestly something that was really cool.
I'd even sent it to a few people and they thought it was cool as well.
But then something happened that I didn't expect.
I think I'm going to call this the excuse zone.
Let me explain.
So, the app was done and I started making excuses of why I wasn't ready to actually launch it into the real world yet.
And one of the reasons is that I was about to go through a period of change.
My wife was graduating residency and we had a ton of family visiting, coming in and out and I told myself,
hey, if I launch this, it's going to be really successful and I won't have time to work on the app or do support or anything like that.
So, I put it off to next week.
And then the next week, I was moving across the country, driving from Florida to California,
and I told myself, I'll do it the next week.
I won't have time to work on this.
And then sure enough, that week went by and I realized that I had a vacation planned.
I was going to Europe and surely I couldn't launch this thing because I wouldn't be able to work on it while I was on vacation.
So, I just told myself, I guess I'll wait to launch it when I'm really ready when I get back from all these excuses.
It's now a month later and I haven't launched anything.
We can build things, we can code them up, we can make them really, really good, but often times we create these excuses of why they're not ready yet.
If you're watching this, you might be able to relate.
Sometimes we think you don't have enough features or you're worried about if you launch it,
what your friends, family, what your boss will think and you just say, "Okay, I'm just going to put this off.
I'm going to procrastinate this."
And when I really look back, I was procrastinating something way different.
I knew that my product wasn't right.
It wasn't actually ready for the real world.
Something was wrong with it, which is what I was about to find out.
Okay, so finally, I get out of the excuse zone.
I'm moved in.
I'm ready to go.
I'm ready to build.
I'm ready to launch this thing.
It's been a month, but I'm putting the finishing touches on it.
And it's basically done.
So, I'm getting ready to launch it.
I'm nervous.
I put out the first tweet.
I don't think it's going to be a huge thing.
I don't think it's be crazy, but it just I want to get some people on it.
I want to just get some early feedback.
And I put out a pretty simple tweet that just has a link to it, explains what it does,
a small video about what it does.
That's it.
And I sit there and I watch this tweet and it's not really getting a whole lot of likes.
It's getting like a couple views and I start to get the feeling kind of in my gut that something is wrong with this idea,
with this product that I've built.
Finally, a comment comes in.
Someone leaves a comment.
I'm really excited and it says something along the lines of, "Oh, great.
More AI slop in the world."
And okay, you know, I've had bad comments before.
Then another comment comes in, something along the lines of, "This is despicable.
Now I get to see more AI garbage in my feed.
Great."
And look, people leave a ton of negative comments on my videos.
You guys have probably seen in a lot of my videos and on the Starry main channel.
I'm pretty used to it and it doesn't really bother me.
But there was something different about this is that all of the comments that were being left on this and it was just a couple were all negative.
There were no positive comments at all.
And this didn't feel right.
I was also having a really day and I was just kind of fed up with a bunch of other things that were going on.
And I just had this feeling that I did something wrong or there was something in the water that day.
So I decided to take down the app and basically I threw in the towel.
I was done for the day.
I was demoralized and I knew something wasn't right and I really just didn't want to deal with it anymore.
And this is when I kind of started getting pretty negative.
You know, it was kind of hitting me right now that I had spent the last month kind of putting off this app launch and then it going horribly,
horribly wrong.
and maybe I had some confidence around that this thing was going to work when it clearly didn't.
And I could have learned that a long time ago.
And I was thinking about all the wasted time going through the Starter Story build channel and seeing everyone asking for updates about the challenge.
And this is one of those moments where again I wanted to quit the challenge.
I was going, "Okay, what is the point of continuing to do this when this is so hard and this feels like this is never going to work out?"
But it was a Friday.
I think I was really tired and I had talked to my team at Starter Story about it and some other people getting some advice.
They told me, "Hey, just shut it down for a bit, try to sleep on it and just try to give it another day."
So that's what I did.
I decided to shut it off, have a good night, go to bed, come back tomorrow and hope for a better day.
The next day, I woke up feeling a little bit better.
I felt like I could look at the situation a little bit further out.
Yes, the internet response was harsh.
People were very critical and I felt maybe a little bit unnecessarily negative.
And my initial reaction from that was frustration and just almost like feeling annoyed by the whole thing.
But after zooming out a little bit more and I realized that they were probably right in some way.
I think I had rushed the product.
It wasn't ready yet and it wasn't really something that I truly believed in.
I still had a lot of conviction around the idea and the problem that it was solving,
helping people build things in public because I really do believe that that's something that I can genuinely help the world,
help people out there do a little bit better job of and I think that AI is an amazing resource to help them do that.
So, I thought, what if I changed the positioning of the app?
Instead of it being something that's like a done for you service, what if I used kind of a lot of the same tech and a lot of the same stuff that I already built,
but I made it into something that was more like a tool, more like a platform, almost like an AI coding tool,
but for marketing, maybe almost like a vibe marketing platform.
And so I'm sitting here the next day and now the gears start turning in my head again.
I'm getting excited about this app.
I think it just needs a few minor tweaks.
So, I go back into the cave.
I start rebuilding the entire app.
And around this time, Claude Code is getting really popular.
I see a lot of people talking about that online.
I start learning that tool, which is an amazing tool, by the way.
And basically, I have it build this entire thing.
I'm having fun.
I changed the positioning.
I changed up sort of the whole UI.
I made it feel bigger than, you know, just something that will generate a few tweets for you.
When it really started getting exciting for me was when I realized that like, damn, this is something that I would actually use for my own tweets,
for my own posts.
I could see even my team using something like this.
So, I was sending to them.
They were getting excited.
I was saying it to a few people.
People were getting pumped up about it.
At this point, I feel like, okay, I'm on to something here.
I was feeling like on top of the world now building this.
Feeling really, really excited about it.
And when I look back at the build and public app, I didn't really feel that way.
But I'm also appreciative because I wouldn't have gotten the idea for this app without that app and the sort of kind of mediocre launch that it had.
So now I feel like I'm sort of just scratching the surface.
There's so many things I want to build with this app, but I know that I just need to get something out so that I don't run into the same issue before where I'm just making excuses not
to launch yet.
I've rebuilt the app.
I'm getting ready to potentially launch it and now I got to figure out how I'm gonna actually launch this thing.
So before I talk about the launch of this app, well really the second launch of this app,
I just want to show off what the app is, what I sort of changed about it and how it works.
So this is the app right here.
It's called MoAT.
And I really like the idea behind the name of moat because I read this somewhere or I saw this somewhere online which is said basically distribution may be the final
moat.
You know as AI takes over there's really no mode is really like what's your competitive advantage?
How can some competitor just come and steal your business and cut undercut your prices?
Well, if they can, then you don't have a moat.
And maybe distribution.
Well, really, brand marketing, a personal brand, building in public, these things can all be moes.
If you have an audience and you're marketing and you're building, that may be your competitive advantage and it may be one of the final competitive advantages as the AI starts to take over.
So the idea behind this app is that if you're building cool stuff, if you're actually trying to build an app,
build a SAS, whatever you're trying to do, you're doing really cool stuff, you're shipping every single day,
but the hard part is actually marketing this app.
You're already doing the hard stuff.
What if we built something that will help you do what I think is somewhat easy part,
but I know that a lot of people struggle to actually market themselves, put themselves out there,
do marketing every single day.
And this app sort of tries to solve that to automate part of that process and and solve some of those problems.
And that's sort of the angle that I wanted to go for is like this is for people that are actually shipping stuff.
And by default, if you're doing that, then it's actually pretty easy to build an audience and bring people on board to what you're doing.
So that's what the tool does.
I'll kind of show it off real quick and I'll just say like,"Hey, I'm I'm launching my app today."
You can put that in.
It's kind of like an AI coding tool, but for marketing, like VIP marketing, right?
So, I'm going to plug that in there.
What I think is really important when it comes to sharing stuff online is not just doing some AI generated BS thing.
Like, that's not never going to work, right?
It's like AI slop.
You're never going to get any likes on that.
This app asks you for more context, right?
I'm telling it, I'm launching my app right here.
It needs to know more so that it can help you create a a really good piece of content.
So, it's asking me here, what problem does your app solve?
If you type that in, it continues to ask you for more and more.
This is context, right?
I think context is really important when it comes to creating stuff that can really perform on social media.
Then it gives you a bunch of ideas here and these are in proven formats that work.
This is actually trained on real data from a bunch of tweets and a bunch of posts online that could potentially work for what you did that was already cool.
So, I mean, that's the really important thing and that's really the positioning change that I created was like this isn't going to work if you aren't doing cool stuff.
I'm just going to help you share that cool stuff that you're already doing.
What's even cooler is that we're going to have LinkedIn posts and even potentially Reddit posts.
I know that there are like basically proven formats that you can sort of share on different subreddits.
I want my app to be able to help with that.
It's not there yet, but I think that's really cool.
So, yeah.
And then you can click into something and you can continue to give it context on what you're building and try to create something that performs.
All right, so this is kind of the beginnings of the app.
It's really sort of simple right now, but it is pretty useful.
I've been using it to create some of my own tweets that have been performing.
My team's been using it, and I actually have proof that someone doubled their followers based on a tweet that was generated or partly generated here.
Okay, so that's that's generally the demo.
It's still early, but I do think it's cool.
But I what I do want to talk about is the actual launch.
How did I actually make my first dollar off this?
I knew that what I did before probably wasn't going to work where I just put it out there and hope for the best and then maybe get some negative backlash because the product wasn't fully fleshed out at that point
and a bunch of other stuff.
So, I thought maybe I would kind of rethink that strategy.
And instead of just putting it all out there, I decided I'm going to take this one a little bit slower and instead of just hoping people
pay for it, what if I just had a few core people use it first, try to make it a lot better through their feedback and to get the results that they really want and then I can make it bigger after
that.
So, I started with just two people and that's kind of where I'm at right now.
And that's sort of like I guess more of a beta testing strategy is I want to find the people that really really really need this app first.
The people that want to go from zero to 100 followers or 100 followers to a,000 followers,
drive customers, drive initial customers to their app.
If I can help one person, then I know that I can help 10 people and then 100 people and then thousands of people,
but I have to start there.
And the app is actually live now.
I mean, you can go and use it technically if you're looking at my screen right now and looking at the link,
but it's not something that I'm actively like trying to blow up right now.
Just not totally ready there.
I'm getting closer.
But I believe in this product.
I have conviction around it so much that I know that I can take it a little bit slower.
And this thing could be a lot bigger than just, you know, one project a week type of thing.
And I want to talk more about this beta testing strategy.
And I hate to be a tease, but I'm going to save it for next week's video because I'm actually sort of still in the middle of it.
And I want to make sure that what I share is something that actually worked.
Yes, it's sort of working already.
I've already gotten a paying customer out of it, but I want to make sure I make the right video around that.
And I also want to get back on schedule with the recordings and the videos.
And there's a lot of stuff I want to share around that.
I'm going to be breaking down the entire thing in next week's video.
But I'm sorry you're going to have to wait a little bit for that.
But I'm really, really excited to share it.
So, that's the update right now.
That's the app.
That's how I launched it.
A much much smaller micro launch, if you will.
And I'm even building up a nice little weight list as well based on the strategy.
going to be talking all about that next week.
That's where we're at.
It feels a lot better.
It feels a lot more right and I'm excited to keep working on this.
So, the title of this video and at the beginning of the video, I posed the question,
can I make $1 with a new project in less than 24 hours?
And the answer is obviously no.
I couldn't do it.
I failed.
It took me over 30 days to generate a single dollar, which is borderline hilarious, right?
I'd be better off driving for Uber or doing Instacart orders, right?
I can already read the comments coming in right now.
But I wanted to share the real truth.
This story is about a regular guy building projects, life happening, things getting in the way,
moving across the country, and all the other excuses that I made up.
This is the real story.
This is what I wanted to document in this video.
And although I only have one paying customer of my new app, I'm actually feeling really,
really, really good about it.
But that's just how I feel in this moment.
And I'd be lying if I told you that I knew this was all going to work out, and this app or this idea was going to eventually get me to the $100,000 mark.
All I can do right now is keep shipping, keep showing up every day, keep putting these videos out every week.
Hopefully, I get to learn something that will help me grow as a person, and also learn something that I can share with you guys on the 100K build challenge blogs.
So, yeah, that's it.
I'd love to hear you guys thoughts in the comments.
I know it's been a long time.
This is the real raw story and I love to get your feedback, your questions, your comments and of course I love to see what you guys are building too and hear that you're getting inspired and trying to ship stuff and
build stuff.
I see all your comments.
I see all the stuff you guys are building and that's honestly the coolest part.
If you're still thinking about getting started and building stuff with AI, well definitely check out Starter Story Build.
It's our platform where in just a few days you'll come up with an idea, build it with AI tools,
and ship it to the real world.
Check that out.
I'll put a link in the description or you can just keep watching these videos for free,
building your own stuff and hopefully getting inspired.
And that ends episode 9 of the 100K build challenge.
I will see you next week.
All right, Bernie, you like that?
You're ready to get out of here, aren't you?
>> Later.