SEO is dead especially for anybody building an online business and today I'm just going to jump in and walk through a bunch of stuff to show you why I think that why that's the case this is
from Real uh data I'm going to show you from my own business and anecdotes from a lot of Founders that I've talked to and a lot of people that I talked to and what I truly believe is going to happen
right I do not have any skin in the game for this right now I I even had an SEO course many years ago SEO is how I grew starter story to be uh a million I Dollar business I believe that it's
pretty much done at this point and I'm recording this to just be honest and tell you why in this video I'm going to tell you the three reasons why I think SEO is dead I'm going to show you a bunch of examples and then I'm going to
show you what you can do about it and what we've done about it and what I think everyone should do about it and who's building an online business who's building stuff online so you don't waste a ton of time and your business
doesn't fail and you work on the right things um this is just from my own personal experience um SEO certainly still works in a lot of different ways I'm going to show you specifically where
it doesn't work and what you shouldn't be focused on so when I say SEO I mean a couple things I mean specifically Google and I mean specifically as a growth strategy or a way to get customers for
your business or more specifically for your online business so anybody that's building anything SAS apps uh digital products any of this sort of stuff that is where it's really dying I think I
believe that websites that get a lot of traffic uh will die a slow death from a three-pronged approach number one competition anybody can use AI to out rank you number two regular normal
people will use over time will choose to use chat GPT and other AI tools over Google and number three Google generally will prioritize Gemini in the Ser this
is the death by a Thousand Cuts where it's not dead doesn't die tomorrow but it will die a slow death and if you choose to build in that I believe it's just going to be a lot harder to be successful and to do that so let's get
into it I'm just going to be going through this ad hoc this isn't planned out or anything like that I don't have some script I'm going to read to I'm going to show you some real so first thing I want to show you is it says this post is unavailable that's cuz
this was uh quoted it was deleted I wonder why it was deleted big Google is is hiding this right okay this is what uh was the graph that was quoted and this right here tells me so much
this is hub spot a billion dollar company who basically built a multi-billion dollar company off SEO they did this such Smart Genius stuff
they took this growth tactic not a growth tactic but this is where they really grew their business search Google search specifically and you can see here this is the last 10 years they went from
2.5 million they've been doing it for a long time and uh over the course of five years they got to 5 million traffic or users per month and then they got to 10
million up in 2023 and then it dropped look at this drop right here this is scary right here here this is business destroying stuff right here 10 million to 2.5 million I'll share
another anecdote that I can't share who shared this with me a very very uh prominent person in media specifically digital media who works for one of the biggest digital media publishers in the
world everyone would know about this this but I can't share cuz it's confidential they showed me very very similar numbers this is scary guys this is crazy right now and uh I'm just calling I'm calling the red alert
on this right now 7 and half million people stop searching uh on Google Search right Google still shows that that numbers are going up this goes to show you that Google is changing their
algorithm and that is resulting in less people going to websites or going to other websites and that is a scary thing right there we're going to dive a little bit more into those numbers number one
my number one thing for business owners specifically the first reason that I think that SEO is going to get crushed is that competitors can use AI to outrank you in the longtail
this is what we're seeing at starter story is 5 years ago when when AI didn't exist you used to have to hire content writers you used to have to hire editors you used to have to pay real humans to
write this stuff and it was really hard there was a big barrier to entry right that's what made uh SEO worth doing because you knew that there wasn't some
kid out there who could just easily outrank you without writing anything right well that is all changed right now I'm going to show you with a specific ific query in Google uh in Google that I
that we used to rank for in starter story which is business ideas for golfers starter story talks about business ideas and lots of stuff like that right we used to be the only person who wrote about business ideas maybe there was one more other one you can see
here's starter story right here but now you can see all these different bu uh articles about business ideas for golfers the yardstick golf.com sounds like a cool website I'm sure that's cool
they were able to they're just more easily able to create an article like this that ranks and outranks us right that is just a very very small thing that just eats away at SEO traffic for
us but it gets worse and that is I know that sounds like a simple example but I'm going to explain why it's especially bad in a minute but first let's just show you how easy it is to create this
article business ideas for golfers write an article for me that goes over for my
website that shares 20 ideas okay check gbt open AI you are pretty good all right now they have this new uh UI where
now you can like write your article and like give it feedback this is how easy it is to create an article it has been 30 seconds and I already have an article that's pretty good and this is what I also mentioned here is that this is the
longtail right business ideas for golfers is is a pretty Niche article right it's a pretty small article you can win in the longtail as a small business as an online business but it gets a lot harder when there's no
barrier to entry to start so now I can go and say hey okay um this looks like a good article but can you beef up each section now it's going and it's rewriting My article now I don't even
need an editor and dude this these are the simplest one-hot prompts of all time like imagine if you were you put like a sick prompt in there that had a bunch of stuff like I'm an editor for the New York Times blah blah blah right that
would just be even better so this is how easy it is to write this and this is just going to eat away anybody doing SEO it's just a small example of that but I I really do think that because there's
no barrier to entry you get crushed but I actually think it's more Sinister than that look ranking high in SEO is more than just writing a good article you really have to write a truly great
article you have to get backlinks and that sort of thing but I think that all that stuff doesn't even matter and that's just purely AAS to the bottom why because AI has already created a fundamental issue with people who are
searching on Google which is a lack of trust because the barrier to entry of writing articles is so low anybody can do it anybody can get on Google now everybody going on Google will not trust
any article that they read unless they truly trust the source think about it if you were to go on Google and look for an answer to something you're not sure if something is is AI or not right and
knowing that why would you ever read something unless you fully trusted the source you wouldn't but that's the point of going on Google is people can find you who don't know who you are but why would they trust you this is why when
you go search business ideas for golfers we don't rank number one anymore Reddit does and why is that because people don't trust articles anymore and Google is telling you this right now this blows
my mind and it's true why is Reddit ranking so much higher because people believe that that's more trustworthy because it's real people and it's not just AI generated whether that's true or not but any smart person who saw this
who let's say they had a golf related business or something like that the first thing I'm any smart person would say okay I'm not going to create articles I'm going to go create Reddit posts I'm going to go comment on Reddit
that will be a way that I will grow my business right that tells you everything you need to know and we're going to talk about stuff like that Reddit stuff in a second if you were smart and you were starting right now and you're trying to grow your business you would go on
Reddit and start posting things on Reddit and this is exactly what we're seeing at starter story and this is what we're seeing with Founders who are just starting out right now this is starter story right here and this is our what we call our attention earing database this
is what's specifically working for Founders right now who are getting their first users on their business or making the first revenue and getting their first users I will click through this is a list of a bunch of ideas that you can
do specifically and the top one that's coming up right here is Reddit I'm going to click into this right here and I will show you that this is from someone inside St inside our starter Story
community who's trying to grow their uh this is from someone in the starter Story community that's trying to grow their uh productivity app they are not creating content on SEO they are posting on Reddit this is part of one of our
accelerators at starter story where people are building businesses and growing their businesses uh that you you should join by the way but check this out this guy created a post in the subreddit called r/ productivity apps
it's a smaller subreddit has 54,000 members but you can see here that this has 40 uploades 23 comments and this is how this person is actually getting users they are not creating content on SEO they're creating content on Reddit
why because that's what we know is actually working when we go here we see people actually posting on Reddit so if you want to do something similar like this do check out starterstory.com I'll put a link in the description you can
join if you are you have a product that you've launched and you're ready to grow it you can join and we do a bunch of cool stuff like give you a bunch of templates you can post on Reddit and basically get you traction on your product in weeks we have a bunch of examples of how people actually grow
their apps I love if you join but no worries you can also check out our attention earing database number two people are already starting to use chat gbt over Google more and more you go
online and you look for the data on this and I still think it's too early but what I like to do in situations like this instead of what the early adopters look people like me me and you are probably already using chat gbt more
than Google I know for certainly for coding uh I never use Google anymore when I used to use it all the time but that's beside the point I want to know what the regular people are doing what the normies are doing and when I think
normies it's important because those are your customers right these are people who are actually going to buy uh your products and not just the early adopter type people usually this I believe is happening sure it's not going to change
overnight but I believe a lot of people are already using chat gbt and once they use it there's really no going back so I'm going to share a stupid example this
is my dad and he is in his late 60s doesn't know how need how to do anything with Tac he doesn't have social media he doesn't have anything he asked me a question about something and I didn't
know the answer to it so I showed him how I can talk to chat gbt and get answers the moment I showed him this he basically stopped using Google completely it's right on his phone and
now he can just simply use chat gbt to get all the information that he needs for pretty much anything and for my dad to take on any sort of new technology that tells me everything I need to know
about uh how useful how chat gbt adoption is going to be so I I just wanted to send him a message because I said I might use it for some content remember when you told me that using
that you like using chat gbt over Google why he told he texted me back and he said chat gbt gives me a way more comprehensive answer and is just intuitive Google just spits out the
facts right in so many words he's saying chat gbt gives me a better answer and that is a crazy thing because Google's big thing is about giving the Searcher the best answer possible chat gbt is
winning and for my dad that's crazy okay this is a stupid example right uh people are just going to use chat gbt instead of other tools but okay they say oh chat GPT it doesn't give you news it doesn't
give you recommendations well okay that stuff is all going to get solved over time and I just want to share one specific example that chat GPT is not necessarily what's going to replace
Google it's going to get replaced by everything tools are all going to replace search and I'm going to show you a very very simple example of an app called cursor if you are programmer you
probably already know what cursor is but let's um go and actually use cursor so so this is starter story's homepage and I want to make a change to it I want to
make this button black instead of green what I could do is go on here and search uh how to make button black
HTML um and I could get there okay it's going to tell me that I should do in the code I should put background color black okay I could search that that's cool that probably gives me the right answer
but imagine there was a tool that I could search for it without using Google which I could do right here this is that right here I'm going to change this code this is that right here I'm going to
change this code make this button black uh override Styles instead of searching it it will just do it and I'm going to hit save on that I'm going to reload and now I have a black button so that
actually replaces the entire search Loop completely and I think that this is going to happen I think that this is going to happen in all sorts of tools so instead of having to go search Google for let's say I'm working in a
spreadsheet you will be able to have the thing just done for you inside the spreadsheet and that is going to replace a lot of search and as AI gets built into all sorts of user interfaces that
is going to replace using uh Google and SEO okay here's the last one Google will prioritize Gemini in the ser and this is the other thing when people continue to
realize that chat gbt is a better product uh you can't really trust any articles on the internet Google will continue to prioritize Gemini in this Surf and and Gemini is just Google's uh
AI its own AI thing and when you search things for example I search the benefits of meditation here now I basically get the same article right there uh in the Ser so people may still be so Google
will often give um I think Google will often give data of what PE that people are still searching for a lot of things but where I think it's really going to screw over businesses is that people would get their answers and then they
leave and I think that will continue to happen more and more and that was still happening with my business ideas for golfers right not only is Reddit stealing from me Gemini right here whatever you call this the Ser thing is
also stealing from me so that is the third reason where it will just also continue to screw you enough of why it's going down here's what you can actually
do number one is build a brand right A lot of people want to go and create SEO content that has no no no face or no brand or anything like that and that they can just rank with that brand is
everything now so if I go to I'll show you an example here if I search for the best wired headphones again Reddit has builtup Brand and people believe and
people associate that brand with humans therefore it ranks high I think the other one that I really think is interesting too is wire cutter by uh the New York Times people trust the New York Times and people are familiar with wire
cutter because they are known to have some of the best reviews on the internet that is called brand right I'm going to trust wire cutter more than I'm going to
trust um let's go to page six I'm going to trust it more than I'm going to trust detector prospector decom right that's just default so build number one is
build brand and build a brand over the longterm that doesn't happen overnight but that is the first thing to do the second thing you can do is if you're trying to look for places to actually get customers actually just find out
where your customers hang out and how they search for things and how you can get in front of them now to give you some data about starter story is that I realized that SEO was going downhill for
us it is how we built a million dooll business at starter story but I saw the writing on the wall a couple years ago and I realized that video is the next thing because I realized that everyone is hanging out on YouTube they're hanging out in front of the social media
algorithms on Tik Tok and all these other places I'm going to go there and get in front of them because I know search is going to die once I saw AI I had a feeling that search was done or will be done over time so I went on
YouTube I started creating on YouTube I started creating video content I made that content have my actual face in there nobody can replicate our content because this is ours it's not just some
random article that could be written by an AI and you don't necessarily know number three study what winning Founders are actually doing right now you can first do that by simply watching the
videos on our Channel and you will see that a lot of people are winning with social media with creating video content and all those things and then you can also do that by going to starter story
and reading our 4,000 case studies about how people actually built businesses Ordinary People built million-dollar online businesses and exactly how they did it what were the marketing strategies they used and uh what was
actually working if you're serious about actually building something and you don't want to waste time working on SEO or um you know maybe SEO might work in very specific cases you can learn that on starter story especially by looking
at similar businesses in your Niche or businesses solving similar problems as you and see how Ordinary People built businesses that change their life I'm a big fan of just seeing what's actually
working and then doing that all right I hope you guys enjoyed this video about how SEO is dead see you in the next one peace