Hey guys, welcome back to the $1 challenge where I, a complete beginner, do my best to build a mobile app using nothing but AI coding tools like ChatGpt and Cursor.
First off, wanted to start by saying thank you for all the awesome comments on the last video.
I loved your responses, your tips.
Uh, thanks for all the followers on X and all the DMs.
I think my biggest goal with this challenge is to try to inspire absolute beginners like me,
maybe like you, to test out these AI coding tools that everybody's talking about these days and try to build something for real.
I've never built anything before in my life.
And so this feels like a really big task.
But um hopefully you'll learn by watching what I do.
Maybe I can learn by watching what you do.
So if you're building anything, please leave a comment um to what you're building or maybe if you have a YouTube channel or something,
leave that in the comments as well.
On today's episode, you're going to watch me go through a little bit of debugging hell.
So, you'll see errors I made last time that led to the bugs that I encountered this time.
And then you're also going to see a couple of things that I tried to do differently so that the building of the app could go a little bit smoother this time than it did last time.
So, anyway, um it was a little bit of a doozy.
Uh my brain is fried from going through all that stuff to try and just get a basic, you know,
MVP out there.
I'm still not quite there.
I'm not exactly where I want to be, but I'm a little bit closer.
Anyway, thanks for watching.
Like, subscribe, leave a comment, follow me on X, show me what you're building, and join the challenge yourself.
All right, guys, let's do it.
As I said in the intro, I was just in in debugging hell, but I just want to show you all the pictures of all my errors.
So, let me share my screen.
Here's all I honestly don't even know what they all meant, but if you open them all up,
you know, you're going to see this error, error, error, error, error.
So, you you get the point.
And I'll show you my chat GPT thread.
So, I was just like, hey, I'm getting this error.
And it was like, oh, restart this thing.
Copy this prompt into cursor.
And it did actually help me a little bit figure out like, okay, where am I going wrong here?
But at the end of the day, I ended up just saying, and maybe this is part of me being a beginner,
but I think I said like, hey, I got this after running all the prompts, of course, another error.
I feel like I need to start over.
And it was like, yeah, some native code or dependency that's crashing silently at this point.
Yes, maybe it's cleanest to restart.
With that in mind, I'm going to start over.
So, I found this guy, actually, I found him on the Starter Store YouTube channel, but he is the creator of an app called Code Guide.
So, this is not sponsored by by any means, but it's a companion.
And one of the things he says, and I'll find him here on Twitter, is I don't know, it could be just his app or whatever that he's promoting obviously,
but he's like, "If you don't follow all this stuff, you're not going to make it."
And honestly, that's kind of where I felt like I was.
I felt like I was at a place where if I would have just kind of kept plugging in all the errors into cursor I I was just like turned around and so I feel like I just needed to start over.
So yeah, obviously this cost money thing was like I paid the yearly price 200 bucks.
So obviously I can pay that and I feel grateful to be able to do that.
But it's actually pretty cool.
So I won't go I won't like spill all the secrets on his app, right?
But you basically fill out a questionnaire and then it generates all these product requirements for you.
And when you start to read through it, it it it really helps it helped me think about,
okay, what are the components I want in my app?
Do I want it to sync on all these things I would have probably never even thought about?
It helped me think about.
So shameless plug for code guide.
I think the guy's awesome.
Go watch that YouTube video if you haven't seen it.
I wanted to start here because of all the mistakes I made that you didn't see and show you a little bit more precision maybe.
So, let's get into it.
So, I guess you don't even need to all know all of this, but there are some cool things in here like the flowchart,
you know, kind of if you look at it here, it's like app launches.
Here's the navigator, things like that.
So, let's see how far I can get in this video.
I'm going to close a bunch of stuff here and let's open up cursor.
So, I'm calling it walking buddy 3 just cuz I've done this a couple times with with a lot of errors.
So, I'm just going to pull in the documents.
So, let's go to my desktop step counter flowchart.
And the code guide is cool cuz it kind of shows you a little bit of this, but let's put it into cursor.
And then I'm just going to speak out and say these are the project requirements for my app and so I want you to explain everything as we go.
Okay.
I'll help you build the step counting app following the provided blah blah blah.
Okay, so it's installing some stuff.
The point is that it's reading a lot of this stuff and it's starting to create things.
Okay, this is awesome.
So, I think what I like appreciate about this process is that it feels like I'm going to go kind of step by step.
Okay, let's go.
Great.
We've successfully created we've used blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Okay, now let's create cursor directory and set up our project tracking.
Sure.
And per usual, you know, because I'm not exactly sure how this is going, I'm just gonna keep working this and obviously eventually open up chat GBT to be my co- co-pilot.
Okay, we completed phase one.
Great.
We have the basic expo project set up.
Let me explain all this stuff.
Would you like to proceed with phase two?
Yeah, let's proceed with phase two.
And remember, just one step at a time.
And it's what I like is there's like a phase, it goes in phases like so phase one was just like setting up the environment.
Phase two.
Now we're in front-end development.
And I'm sure Yeah, we're gonna This will get more and more complicated, but again, I like that it's just kind of guiding me steps to the way.
So, okay.
And I love again a quick hack in using cursor if you're beginning.
I I said, "Hey, I'm a beginner, so explain everything as we're going."
So, here it is explaining it to me.
So, reusable components, navigation, custom hook reactions, blah blah.
I can't I can't say I know what all this means, but it is helpful.
Okay, we need to install some dependencies.
Blah blah blah.
Let's install.
Okay, sure.
Let's run this.
Okay, let me explain what we just installed.
Core navigation.
I've created our first screen component.
Let me explain.
Defines our navigation.
A simple welcome screen uses our design colors.
I don't even know what color this is.
Okay.
Would you like to proceed with setting up?
I'll explain each part as we go.
Okay.
I'm going to accept accept the file and let's say All right.
Let's keep going and keep explaining.
Thanks.
I don't know why I say thanks to the AI.
Okay, so let's see what the next step is here.
It Let's set up our navigation structure.
Let's create a navigation component.
So main tab navigator.tsx.
So I'm guessing that lives in here.
You know, again, I don't know what all this is, but root navigator.
I'm sure I could have it explain it to me, but for now, I'm just going to keep going.
So let's create our root stack.
And finally, let's set up our main app tsx.
So where does that live?
App TSX, where are you?
I don't know.
Okay, that's okay.
Let me explain what we just set up.
Navigation types, main tab, navigator, root navigator.
We now have a basic navigator.
So, let me run.
And we're starting the project.
So, let me accept all.
Okay, let's see how this looks.
So, this is sort of a super super v1.
Again, let me take a picture of this.
I'm holding up my phone so you can see or so I can see.
Okay.
Welcome to Walking Buddy.
Track your steps.
Okay.
So, let me pull this up on the screen here.
What I learned from the comments the other day was that you can actually leave this app running so I don't have to refresh it all the time.
So, did it come over?
Where are you?
And here it is.
So, yeah.
I mean, once again, is it like, you know, perfect or beautiful?
No.
But it made this.
Track your steps, build healthy habits, and achieve your fitness goals.
Sure.
I mean, I may not that may not be the copy I have at the end of the day, but it built it.
I don't mind the colors.
Get started.
Nothing happens when I click get started, but that's okay.
Now we have you can test it by running.
Okay, I'm going to say great.
This looks is looking good at least for the first screen.
Let's keep going.
Okay, what you're watching me do here is just letting cursor guide me.
It's really helpful to have the project plan that I used in code guide.
That way I can continue to just press next or accept or just letting it letting it tell me what to do.
So, just wanted to speed through this part uh because all I'm really doing is pressing next or yes.
Sure.
Let's test this thing out.
See, I'll help you test the first app.
Let's make sure we have explo installed on your device.
Run.
Oh, okay.
So, once again, we are running into some errors.
So, I'm going to send this over back to cursor and say, "Hey, I got this error.
Please help fix it."
So, here here we go again.
Hopefully, this is not another round of just errors.
And just to be sure, I'm going to open up chat GBT.
And I wonder if I can load the documents in here as well.
So, let's go to I have a folder called Vibe Coding Projects.
And I'm going to give it a new chat here and say, "Hey, I'm building a mobile app with Cursor."
And I want you to be my coding co-pilot because I'm a complete beginner.
I'll give you the details of the app next.
I bet I can feed these documents into Cursor as well.
Okay, you got my back.
Thanks, man.
Okay.
So, let's go.
Let's give this the cursor.
I don't even know if it can read it, but let's I don't need to copy it.
Okay.
I'm say, okay, here are all the product requirement documents I created with a with a lot of other things that might be useful for you to know.
So, I just want you to like understand it here.
First, your app in a nutshell.
You're building crossplatform step tracking app.
You've already covered app flows.
What that means, translate all this document to code.
Okay.
So, let's just let's let's just say I'm going here.
this common issue that expo health pack cannot be resolved because expo health is not maintained.
Uninstall expo and expo permissions.
We don't need them.
Install the correct packages.
Okay, sure.
Let's let's run this.
Okay, so what I'm doing here is just letting cursor continue to guide me until I maybe run into another error.
I'm just following the plan.
That's the big benefit of using something like code guide.
It just is sticking to a plan.
I'm creating different screens.
I'm just proceeding.
But you're going to see me run into another error in 3 2 1.
Let's run the app.
I need to restart the server.
Okay, run.
Unable to resolve.
Okay, so I'm going to bring this to my screen here.
Man, I just cannot get out of debugging hell.
Okay, so before I give it to cursor, I'm going to actually give it to chat.
So I'm going to say, so we started building the welcome screen and the onboarding flow and we ran into this error.
I need a prompt to help fix this.
Unable to resolve.
This means that module is not installed in your project, but you're trying to import it like this.
Here's a cursor friendly prompt you can paste directly to install the right dependency or reload your app,
but it doesn't exist anymore.
That's funny that it says here's what you should do, but don't do it.
Since you're following the original product, here's a correct prompt to run.
Oh man, I don't know.
I'm hoping to run this in Expo Go.
Can you just give me like a singular prompt that I can give to cursor?
So hopefully this video does not turn into just debugging.
Let's give the prompt here.
What is EAS build?
I noticed that at the bin.
If you're not using a custom dev client, you'll either switch to manual or you'll eject using EA as dev build.
I don't even know what that means.
Before I kind of give it all this, I'm going to just do it one more time where I try to scan this.
All right, let me say I'm just going to add this to chat.
I got this error when I opened up the app.
What does it mean and how do I fix it?
So, I just cop what I did there.
Instead of copied and pasting the, you know, the image, I just copied the line here.
So, let's see what it gives me.
Your code is still trying to import expo health, but we already uninstalled that package and it's not compatible.
That's why the builder can't find it.
How to fix.
Remove all the imported code.
Here's what you should do right now.
Open quick fix so you can run the app.
Comment out or delete all the code.
Save the file.
Replace with the placeholder.
Once you do this, your app, let me know if you want me to up the file for no or try.
I definitely want you to update the file for me.
It's funny that it said, "Do you want to try to do it yourself or let me do it for you?"
And the answer will always be, "Let me do this for you."
But let's see what happens.
Okay, I've updated here.
Restart your Expo server.
Open the app and Expo Go.
You should now be able to go through the onboarding screens.
Okay, so let's see if this is still open.
Expo Go.
Let me refresh.
And boom.
Okay, we are in.
I don't know if this is great for the long term, but we're in.
So, it says you should be able to get started.
So, you'll see here it says get started.
Access health data.
Okay.
And boom, welcome.
When I click get started, it takes me there.
Allow full access.
So, sometimes I feel just so insane because all I did was like create two screens.
And I feel like there's there's like there's got to be an easier way, but I I truly don't know yet.
So, when I click allow access, like obviously nothing happens yet because we haven't done anything.
Okay.
So, I'll say awesome.
The app is running.
I see the welcome page and the health data access page.
Let's keep following.
What's phase two?
Okay.
Create the dashboard screen.
So, as this is building it, I wanted to just quickly say if you are a beginner vibe coder,
just know even though what you're watching me do is like I'm struggling.
I'm going to chip.
I'm taking screenshots.
Blah blah blah.
It still feels really fun.
kind of learn how to do this because I've never done it before and it's totally accessing like a different part of my brain,
a different way of thinking.
And so I think it is discouraging to get stuck in this sort of circular motion of like what am I even doing?
But if I take a step back, this is something I just would have never done before.
And what I think is cool about cursor and chip and things like this is that it gives me some creativity to try and bring this to life.
So, just a quick I don't know what you want to call it, intermission as I'm going through this debugging hell.
Okay, so we created the dashboards.
Next steps, connect this screen to your main tab.
Test the flow.
Would you like me to connect the dashboards to main?
Let's just continue to follow the plan.
If that is the next step we should take, then yes, and just explain why.
So, this lets you test the full onboarding flow.
Okay.
So, basically what I'm doing here is I'm just proceeding.
I'm still getting errors.
So, I'm still just talking to cursor, letting it guide me.
For some reason, it's unable to resolve.
So, I'm just continuing to ask it to explain to me what the heck is going on.
And at this point, honestly, I'm a little worried that I'm about to be just stuck in debugging hell again.
And the tough part is that I'm not exactly sure what the errors actually are.
And I guess this is part of the downfalls of my coding.
But let's see if some of these errors got fixed.
Okay, here we go again.
I don't believe this is going to work.
Let's see.
It's loading.
Oh, I'm shocked that it worked.
Okay, so let's see.
Welcome screen.
Get started.
Access to data.
Hopefully, this is where people say yes.
But when I click continue without health data, it lets me move on.
I'm assuming that because nothing can happen when I click allow access.
That's why nothing's happening.
So continue without health data.
And now it takes me to this page.
So let me screenshot this so you can see it as well.
Man, this is tough.
Okay, so what this looks like is like this.
So, I get to part of the the idea for my app.
I want three components.
I want like those three big numbers that I've kind of been talking about where it has the daily step count,
the weekly step count, and the monthly step count.
But then I also want like a habit tracker kind of thing.
I really like this app called Habit Kit where you see kind of your habits laid out in like a hub style grid.
And maybe I'm just too into the indie hacking world, but I feel like a visual like that would be cool to track like on a daily basis,
have I hit over 10,000 steps?
And if I do, I get the little square.
And obviously, if you don't, you don't.
So yeah, it says set set your track your goal.
So 10,000 steps.
I'm going to hit confirm.
Okay.
So I think that's fine.
It I I can't when I click confirm, nothing happens.
But I think that makes sense because there's nothing to confirm.
Okay.
So, I'm going to talk to cursor and say great, I see the health data access screen.
But nothing happens when I click allow access.
But if I click continue without health data, it takes me to the daily step count slider and steps and confirm.
And then when I hit confirm, nothing happens.
I'm assuming that's intentional as well.
So, that was a long prompt there, but let's see if that understands what I just said.
[Music] So, let's see if that works.
Reload.
Okay, I got a ton of errors.
Gosh, I think that's what's so hard about this live coding thing is it feels like sometimes when you make one update,
it just like kind of messes the whole thing.
So, I'm just going to copy these to the chat and say, "Hey, I got these errors.
What does it mean?
And how can we fix them?"
And this is where someone in the comments might say, "You got to stop chatting with cursor."
and you start you got to start chatting with Chad GBT or cloud.
But let's see.
Would you like me to update your dashboard screen?
Let me ask.
I don't think we've built the daily, weekly, and monthly views yet.
Have we?
I think this is where I'm going to get lost.
Sure.
Let's Let's fix it for now so I can see what it looks like.
Okay.
So, even though what I was saying earlier was this is fun because it is teaching me how to do something new.
Sometimes it does feel like just banging my head against the wall and may you know sometimes I'm like is it the fact that I'm trying to build a mobile app that is making this
complicated?
Like would it be easier if I was building a web app?
I'm well I guess I don't actually know if the answer is yes, but I'm assuming the answer would be yes.
Like I'm assuming part of what's making this complicated is the fact that it's like I'm trying to build something that will go on your phone on iOS or on Android or whatever and allow access to health data.
Yeah, I just don't feel like I'm getting a win here.
Okay, your dashboard now uses Okay, let's see if this actually worked again.
Okay, so gonna shake this to reload.
Boom.
Shagalaka kind of.
So, I don't want this.
So, right now, what the desktop looks like is this.
Or not the desktop, the homepage looks like is this.
I get welcome to walking buddy, allow access data, and now I've got my three photos.
So, I have my what this looks like daily, and I have this nice little circle, which I like.
But then there's a button that says weekly, and it takes me over to this screen, last 7 days.
This is how many steps I took.
And then monthly, but I actually want it all to appear in one singular page.
Here's what it looks like.
I'm going to say, give me a prompt that I can feed into cursor that would simply and easily as possible make it so
that the three numbers can appear on one page.
Oh, this is going to be tough cuz I feel confident that this is not going to work.
But let's see.
Nice progress.
It looks really clean.
Thank you.
Okay.
Update the screen only one step count at a time.
Stack them vertically.
Sure.
Okay.
So, that looks like a good prompt.
Let's feed this over.
Okay, your dashboards will now display all three summaries.
I'm going to accept.
I'm going to refresh.
And it already did actually.
Okay, not bad.
This is cool.
Let's share this onto my screen here.
And so you can see what that looks like.
And boom.
I mean, this is totally not centered, which is fine.
Yeah, I think I want them to shift down.
There's probably like more I can put in here, but this looks fine for now.
So, I'm gonna feed this over to chat and say,"Okay, after your prompt, this is what it gave me."
I think I'll want to redesign it at some point, but this looks like okay for now.
Honestly, for a V1, this is great.
Little do they know, I've tried to do this like three times, but whatever.
Okay, you've got a clean layout, blah blah blah.
When you're ready to redesign, here's some upgrades.
Add sparkline charts.
Add subtle dividers or cards.
Okay.
add motivation.
I don't know about that.
Add a user's name.
But again, okay, I'm going to say, okay, this looks good for now.
I'm going to want to redesign it at some point, but for the sake of building the MVP,
let's keep going.
Okay, great.
You have a working dashboard that shows your an excellent milestone.
What's next?
Following your implementation plan and the app flow, the next major feature is the habit tracker screen.
This is the GitHub style grid that allows you so at its core, it's visually motivating.
It's a separate screen tab.
Okay, that's fine.
It will make your MVP feel feel more complete and unique.
Build the habit tracker screen.
Next, what we'll do create for the last 30 days.
Yes, let's create it.
Assuming I can get it to work.
This might be the last feature I've built for this video.
This is hard.
I know I'm just thinking and I'm now I'm just like talking and pressing send, but it's hard.
Like, you really have to get into a mindset when you're doing this or a zone.
And, you know, it's 4:30 p.m.
for me here right now.
I'm feeling a little bit of the pressure to like be done.
I have a few things to get it done around my house and so yeah, I see the benefit of like really kind of trying to carve out time.
Anyway, so let's let's see how this goes.
Okay, your habit tracker is not created.
Okay, as I was yapping away at you, it created it.
Shows a 7x5 grid represent next step.
Let's connect the screen.
Okay, let's follow the next step.
Let's go.
I don't want I don't even want to open my Expo Go app because I'm afraid that it's gonna be,
you know, not working in there.
Let's see how it looks.
Refresh.
You better believe it.
Okay.
Boom.
I don't hate this.
Done.
Now the habit tracker screen is connected to the bottom tab navigator.
You can access it by tapping the habits at the bottom.
What to do next?
Blah blah blah.
Okay, so I have if I look at the habit tracker.
Okay, I need to I do need to make some changes to this, but it's not bad, dude.
It's not like horrible, you know?
So, this is what it looks like.
Boom.
Oh gosh, so many screenshots here.
This is what it looks like.
So, yeah.
Like, I almost wanted to say like, did you get 10K steps?
Did you hit 10,000 steps?
And I mean, I think it's kind of obvious.
Yes or no.
I wish it was like more of a calendar view like Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, like Monday with like the actual dates.
So, let me let's see what chat says.
How if there's an easy prompt I can get into there.
So, this is the habit tracker page.
I think this is a good start, but there's some changes I want to make and I want your help building a prompt so that cursor can easily make the changes.
And then, let's see.
You're on the right track.
Prompt for cursor.
Update the habit tracker with the following.
Add a clear explanatory headline above the grid that says each square equals 1 day.
Green means you hit your goal.
Label the columns by weekdays.
Show the current month name centered above the habit grid.
Sure, let's copy this over.
I'm going to bet so much money that this totally messes this up, but hopefully Chad GBT is clean and good.
And hopefully cursor is also clean and good.
But let's see.
And this will really I know I've said it a couple times now, but this will really be the last thing I do.
But it's it's making the edits.
It's working in the background.
Dude, I can't imagine what like and this is totally like a noob mindset or a beginner mindset.
I saw this tweet one time that was like what were people doing before coding by hand and you know I'm I'm kind of like this looks pretty cool.
I mean it's not perfect but but it's perfect to me.
No, I'm just kidding.
But it it's not perfect but it's not bad.
So I wish there's so much more that I wish was in here.
Okay, come on, dude.
Share.
Share it.
Boom.
Okay, let me show you what it looks like.
So, here's the original and here is the current.
Much better.
Each square equals one day.
Green means you hit your goal, I'm assuming.
Yeah.
Darker means like So, this is this is cool.
It's like no, yes, yes, we did it again.
No.
And then it kind of gets darker.
Okay, that's cool.
So, let me feed this back into chat and say, okay, I think these updates worked.
Of course, there might be other changes I eventually want to make.
And then I'll ask you, what do you think?
This is a solid base.
Clean, minimal, better than a lot of shipped fitness apps.
The grid is consistent.
When you're ready to take it further, that would be cool.
That'd be cool, too.
But right now, blah, blah, blah.
I'm going to say I need to pause again for now.
How do I make sure that I can cleanly close cursor and then start up next time?
Stop your dev server.
Commit your changes.
I haven't even done that.
Cursor autosaves.
Okay, so I'm going to kill the server.
Server stopped.
I'm going to ask cursor, too.
I need to take a break for now.
What do I need to do to make sure all this saves?
Okay, I have not set this up in Git yet.
So, this is the final step.
Actually, I do have a GitHub account.
You can see the very little I've done in here and the little I've shipped, but let's see where did I live off at.
Initialize Git repository.
So, get in and add your files to Git.
Run get add dot make your first commit.
Run.
And I think we're saved.
So I I know this because all this is blank on the left side.
Saved it to GitHub.
We're good, I think, for now.
So I created some more things.
I'm I'm going to just post it on X again.
So I feel like this is the only way to keep people interested or maybe even keep myself interested.
So let me share my screen and I'm going to say let's post something and let's let's put some photos in here.
They're going I bet some people are going to say, "What the hell are you doing, dude?
Like you're just kind of running around in circles here."
But that's okay.
I'm gonna say now I'm just in debugging purgatory.
Lol.
That feels stupid to say.
I was able to get out of the error loop and build just a few more slight features.
It still feels like I'm crawling, but today I was 1% better.
Boom.
I'm going to put this at the top cuz that's been the style.
Day 0.03.
Next greatest.
Have a nice weekend.
Okay, that's it.
That's all for today, folks.
Thanks for being here.
If anything, again, I'm hoping that you're seeing this is what it's like to vibe code as a beginner.
I don't know what I'm doing.
I feel like I'm building features and not actually launching anything, but I'll get there.
Subscribe, like, comment, give me some advice, follow me on X.
Yeah.
Thanks for being here.
See how this goes.
Bye.