All right, everyone.
Welcome to the Starter Story podcast.
Today, I wanted to bring on someone pretty cool, someone from inside the Starter Story community who had a crazy idea.
His idea was to build 30 apps in 30 days and document the entire process on YouTube and X and build in public.
Honestly, when I first saw this, I thought it was ridiculous, but then he started doing it,
posting every day, gaining followers, getting traction, and shipping apps.
So, I said,"Screw it.
Why don't we bring him on the channel and ask them, is shipping 30 apps in 30 days a genius move or is it stupid and you're just going to end up building 30 projects that go nowhere?
So, that's what we're going to be talking about today.
Welcome, Alex, to the channel.
Thanks for coming on.
If you can just let everyone watching know who you are, a little bit of your background,
and what you're doing with this challenge, uh, stoked to have you on here.
>> Sweet.
Thank you, Pat.
Thanks for the intro, and yeah, really cool to be on on the show.
Um, so yeah, my name's Alex.
you mentioned that I am indeed shipping 30 apps in 30 days and we're through the first week and we haven't we haven't failed just yet and so we got we started off strong.
Who am I?
Um so I'm based in the UK.
Um I had a big background in web flow and no code and I did a bunch of building in that space and then I went on to work at a startup for about four years called V.
So I joined there about employee number 15 and joined the rocket ship and that grew like mad to near near 200 people now and about 40 mil ARR.
So I wore a bunch of different hats, learned a lot.
But last year I left and I've been riding this vibe coding wave ever since.
And yeah, been building a bunch of products, been doing some challenges, been doing some content and having a bunch of fun and here we are now uh 5 days into this challenge.
what made you decide to do this challenge to ship 30 uh to ship 30 apps in 30 days like what's the motivation behind it?
So last summer after I left I did a six products in six weeks challenge and that was you know a bit earlier on in my kind of vibe coding dev journey and that was a lot of fun learned a lot very quick
shipped a bunch of apps but I kind of they were more like demos they weren't fully out there and since then I've worked on some bigger projects like I said sometimes that take months uh and
I've been doing content but what you know the dream for me is to to build these apps to get them out there to make a living from these products Now,
the problem with me is I have a list of hundreds of ideas and I love building and that is a bit of a problem as well because I've built many many apps to 80 90%.
I've spent weeks, months doing it and then I talk myself out of actually get getting them over the line.
I think they're not good enough.
I think they need more work and then it ends up just fizzling out and nothing comes of it.
So, I wanted to give myself a challenge.
I wanted to kind of break that shipping curse and really challenge myself.
I talk a lot about how easy it is to build nowadays, how you can build anything.
So, I'm kind of putting my money putting money where my mouth is.
Might have to edit that out.
>> Yeah.
>> Um kind of putting it to the test and um yeah, seeing if we can do it.
So, as of this recording right now, I think you're what four or five days in.
Most people probably would have quit by this point, but I think it seems like you're actually doing it,
which is cool.
How far are you in right now?
How's it going so far?
Yeah.
So, day five today.
Hoping it's not going to be a midnight scramble tonight.
I'm in a good place with today's product.
Um, but yeah, when I started and when I announced it, I thought, you know, the day before I I kind of got this rolling,
I said to a mate of mine, I said, "Talk me out of building 30 apps in 30 days."
Cuz we'd been, you know, nerding out a bunch and claw code and stuff.
And he said, "You've got to do it.
That's what you got to do."
So, I thought, "All right, go on then."
And, you know, the more I spoke about it, the more I saw that people were kind of quite interested in that.
And I thought, you know, there could be something here.
I launched it.
I announced it.
It went down a lot better than expected.
A lot of people paid attention, got a lot of engagement.
And after that, I was like, I've actually got to do this now.
Um, you know, >> so then I was like, oh, hold on.
I hope I can deliver.
And, you know, not only on the building, but also the content because, you know, I kind of did this launch video that was was a little bit polished.
And every day I've been trying to not only get that app shipped, but also make sure that that I've got a fun video to go along with it,
kind of documenting the build, adding a bit of drama to it.
So, that's been fun as well.
>> Okay.
Well, we're going to get all into that.
How you're actually doing this, what's the day-to-day look like?
But first, I want to do what we call haters corner.
And uh I just invented this right now.
I went on your post that you shared, uh, your ex post that kind of blew up, and I pulled up some of the meanest retweets and meanest comments,
which if you're doing anything cool online, this is bound to happen.
So, I want to go through maybe one or two of these and get your opinion on them because I'm sure that you saw them and uh,
the haters, they'll always be there.
So, the first one is from this guy Neil Doss, and he says, "Don't do it.
Focus on one or two good ideas and talk to users.
Use feedback to improve your original ideas.
Right now, you are playing a lottery and even if you win, you will never know that you had the winning ticket.
What do you think about that?
>> Yeah, thanks for this haters corner.
It's quite fun to think about these.
Um, so yeah, for Neil, I think he has a good point and I think, you know, there's there's something to take from all these comments.
So, focus on one or two good ideas and talk to users.
Very valid advice.
Hard to argue with that.
Like I said, this year I've spent a few months on a couple of different projects being really deep in the weeds.
For me personally, what sometimes happens, like I said, I kind of fizzle out.
I get I lose motivation, you know, I start talking myself out of things.
I start doubting.
So really, like this challenge isn't just about finding the right app, you know, getting the lottery ticket.
It's about exercising that shipping muscle, which for me, like I always I was always frustrated with myself.
I know I can build things.
I know I can market and sell, but it's just getting things over the line, putting it out there.
Yeah.
strengthening the muscle.
And I think as well on the lottery thing, it's an interesting example because I saw a tweet the other day that a guy analyzed a bunch of product hunt launches over the last few years and he said that only 3% of them are still
alive and making money.
And I've heard this from a few people.
Levels says about it, you know, long list of products.
Pat, yourself, I've seen your long list of projects that haven't haven't worked.
So, in a way, you could position it that yeah, maybe I am speedr runninging that list of projects and we'll be able to see at the end if there are any uh hot ones.
But, you know, if all else fails, if all apps do nothing, at least I've exercised that that shipping muscle,
I've I've built a lot of skills up and all the content and fun along the way, you know.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
I mean, I see it the same way is like you do this for 30 days, you ship a bunch of projects.
There's two scenarios that might happen.
You have one thing that really takes off or you find some sort of thing that like, oh,
this could be it.
You find that thing or you come out the other side with nothing but 10,000 followers,
an audience, right?
and I don't know if maybe it's 10,000, maybe it's 100,000, maybe it's 5,000, whatever it is,
you're creating content, you're doing something cool, and then you can always transition that to more products and that sort of thing.
So, that's what I think is really cool.
I have some more ideas on that for later in the episode.
But the next hater corner take, which I think is also interesting, is this one right here,
which is hot tick.
This isn't actually that hard.
You can come up with ideas with an LLM and use lovable to build early prototypes by a domain.
This guy says, "It's not actually hard to do 30 products in 30 days.
You've been doing it for 4 days.
So, you let me know.
Is it has it been hard?
How has it been?"
>> Yeah, I like this one.
And my reply to this guy was simple, not easy.
And that's what I think.
I think yes, it is.
It is simple.
It's simple.
You can put into an LLM.
You can oneshot an app in Lovable.
And as I said in my launch video, everyone talks about how easy it is and simple to get these apps out,
but I don't see the apps.
I've not been using any of these apps.
And I do the same thing.
I talk to everyone.
Ah, you could build this and that.
Okay, where is it?
Is it on production?
Have you got any paid users?
What traffic are you getting?
The cost to build is really low.
You can get really far really quick now, which is incredible.
So, what this guy is saying like, yeah, if you're listening, you know, you can get started super easily now.
What a time to live.
The hard part that shipping muscle that I've spoken about, actually getting it out there,
doing it every day, and also doing it in public, not to mention doing it alongside with the content.
So, you know, I think I've done challenges like this before for tweeting or blog posts or videos.
It's not hard to write a tweet.
It's not hard to write a little blog post.
What's hard is that consistency and just putting the reps in.
100% agreed.
The two things that are really hard.
It's easy to get 90% of the way there.
It's really hard to fix all those little bugs and do the O and get payments integrated and that's where most people fall off.
The second part is, as you said, anybody can build stuff, but then there's a mental block or maybe a little bit of imposter syndrome when it comes to actually putting it out there.
The 30 apps in 30 days with the content alongside of it forces you to do that and it's more mental than it is technical.
Okay.
Well, that finishes up haters corner.
I'm sure if we'll bring you back on the channel, you will have we'll have some more haters cuz you're doing cool stuff.
Now, I want to ask you just about your routine.
You are building an app every day.
You are creating content around it.
You're tweeting around it.
You're trying to get customers.
What does the daily workflow look like for you?
Are you doing anything other than building and creating content?
What does it look like?
>> Well, I'd love to tell you that I have a very well disciplined Casey Neistat daily routine where I get up at 5:00 a.m.,
I go for a run, and then I edit my video.
It's not been quite like that.
I've been very reactive a good few times.
I've been up late at night, you know, meeting that midnight deadline.
Um, I finish, I go to sleep, I get up, I need to edit the video, which always takes longer.
And then only once you've edited, you've got to package it, thumbnail, content, tweet,
you know, by 1:00 p.m.
I'm kind of haven't eaten.
I've shipped the video.
I feel good.
And then straight straight back to building again.
You know, >> straight back on the wheel.
So then I'm building, you know, hopefully if it's a good build, I can can do it a bit quicker,
but a lot of the times it expands and goes straight up to the deadline.
Um, and then repeat the same the next day.
>> Yep.
That's the grind, man.
But it's only 30 days.
Anybody can do anything for one month.
And I think that's cool is how you just can bunch it up all into 30 days.
>> The next question I have for you is on stack.
Give me your stack that you've been using.
You know, you probably have been trying a bunch of stuff.
What's been working for you in terms of your tool stack?
>> Yeah, good question.
I could talk about this all day.
I think one of the things this challenge is I want to try out a bunch of different stacks.
And that's what I said to myself.
Oh, I'll try out these different builders, these different author systems, different payments.
And then I tried something new the other day and I shot myself in the foot because, you know,
it came up to the deadline and or completely broke.
I have to strip it all out.
So, part of me now is kind of thinking I need to stick to what I know and what works.
So, that's something that I've been trying to do.
So, what is that stack?
First of all, I'm a big Claude code guy.
I I do love the lovable, the vzeros, the bolts, and I use them a lot just to get started because what what happens if you use those tools to start your project is it kind of creates a bit of a boiler plate
from the infrastructure side of things.
So if you then download that onto your local machine, it's got everything set up there.
You don't have to worry about bunch of different dependencies or databases.
So for me really it's about how quick can I get to actually the fun part, the building,
the creative part of uh vibe coding.
So I I like to use as well like the nextj starter templates that allow me to just deploy straight away and and just get to building.
And even with those easy systems, you still run into a bunch of stuff.
So you really want to make it as easy as possible for you.
>> The next question that I have, and I think a lot of people would appreciate this and have gone through this,
when you sh are shipping something every day, do you feel like the products are good enough?
>> To be honest, Pat, even if I work on something every day for 3 months, I still will will tell myself that it's not good enough.
Um, and Sean Puri put out a good post.
It's called the taste gap, which is where you have an idea of what something is in your head and what you actually,
you know, your first draft is never going to be what you think it should be.
>> So, you've always got this big, big gap, but that shouldn't, you know, demotivate you.
You need to keep moving.
You need to put it out there.
If I build for 3 months or if I build for the day, I'll tell myself it's not good enough.
And that's why it's been hard every day because I've been putting out the products.
I think someone going to, you know, shipping in a day, you're going to have a few bugs as well.
It's not going to be perfect.
It's the same with my videos.
I have to make the video, I have to speed edit.
So, I can tell myself all day that it's not going to be good enough.
But, you know, a lot of my learnings from just doing these challenges that force you to get stuff out is even if you think it's not good enough,
it's still going to, you know, can still achieve those goals that you would hope it would.
I know it's early and it's been, you know, just a few days of shipping, but I want to understand what you've learned so far,
but the first question I have around this is has anything about the challenge so far surprised you?
Like anything you didn't expect that would happen?
Yeah, a lot of surprises so far.
I think one of the big ones is even if you plan to build something in a day, you're going to pick something quite simple,
something quite small in scope and you'll tell yourself in the morning, we can definitely do that in a day.
And then as that day goes on, the hours pass by, you lose a few couple hours here, a couple hours there,
suddenly, you know, you're you're scrambling for the for the deadline.
And if you watch any of my videos, you'll see how that can happen.
So, I think even if you scope down, things can just grow.
And then it I kind of realized to myself if I give myself a month to do that then every every single small thing in there that I think is small scope within the month that will grow and that will just compound to to where you know
you can end up spending 3 6 months on one product before even getting it out.
>> What do you think so far has been the biggest lesson for you uh in terms of you've now shipped four or five products now?
>> I'm trying to learn the most efficient way to get the infrastructure and stuff up.
So making sure that I'm using the right starter kits using tools that I'm familiar with.
I still haven't got a good way to get or payments just like done in half an hour.
I'm trying to find that.
So I'm just trying to remove all that complexity so I can just focus on the build.
That is my biggest learning so far and I'm still learning it.
>> Yeah, maybe there's a product idea there or something like a boiler plate you could build that solves that problem.
That could be an interesting app that you ship in your series.
>> Yeah.
Well, I think as well like hopefully by the end of it I have a very rigorous way that I build that gets me up to speed really quick but also gives me the power of claw code and next.js.
>> So if that you know maybe that's a good reason to come along to the channel.
Um hit subscribe and when that when that drops you'll be able to check it out.
>> Yeah.
you're g you're going to have a lot of your own problems that you go through while building really painful problems which you are right now which could then potentially turn into a cool product that would also be useful for anyone who's watching your content as
well who wants to do the same thing.
So that's >> 100% and I have a long list of ideas but I'm actually getting those ideas pushed down by things by trying to solve my own problems.
Today's product if you're trying to name a a product every day and find a domain for it takes a bit of time.
So today's product I'm building a kind of smart business name plus domain name finder trying to find some good.coms for you which then I will use every day uh to to find a good name.
>> And if you're watching this he will have already shipped that plus like two more projects cuz uh it will take us a little bit to uh put this video out.
So that's cool.
So go and check out his channel and see how that product came out.
I think that'll be interesting.
Okay, let's go into the building public side of things.
So I mean one element of your challenge is you're not only building something uh every day but you're also creating a video around it,
you're sharing it publicly.
What's been the impact of building in public in terms of getting users, getting feedback and making revenue?
>> Yeah, it's a good question.
I think building public used to be a bit more of a unique thing where people would kind of share behind the scenes.
I think a lot of people caught on to it and like anything on social media or attention,
you know, there's a new thing, people go and do it and then it kind of mellows out a bit.
So, I've been been trying the building public thing for a long time.
And what is really nice about that is if you're by yourself, you're posting, there are people who are interested,
who you can learn from, and who can learn from you.
Well, I think for this challenge, it's a bit different because that challenge is a little bit more mad.
So, a lot more people are paying attention.
So, my building in public before was maybe five or 10 people engaging with with each post.
Now, it's a bit more.
I'm building very much more in public.
Um, especially with the videos.
And I think the videos people really like.
I think people like to see the systems and workflows and you know the planning you know the full thing rather than just hey here's here's the finished outcome and people struggle to know what to write about you know building public world what what am I
going to talk about and I think with something like this people say if you do something cool then you have content already talk about and it's kind of a natural flywheel you do something you get content and then you know it builds from there you know if you're looking to
do more building in public then actually doing something interesting to talk about is a very good first step for it >> that that's exactly What I think is you're already doing something really cool,
which is building a product every day, and you're documenting how to do that.
And I was watching one of your videos on YouTube, which I think had over like 3 or 4,000 views now,
which is just you showing off how to build what's how did you come up with the idea?
How did you act, what tools did you use to build it?
What are some, you know, of your thinking processes?
These are things that I think is super underrated, especially with video.
I mean, a lot of people can tweet, "Hey, I built this,"like you're saying, but you're actually showing the behind the scenes build.
And not many people are actually doing that.
And I think that's one reason why your challenge kind of blew up is that you're just taking people behind the scenes of that.
And there's a huge opportunity there.
I would also add, I'm a big believer in this kind of a bit more authentic content creation side now.
So, we kind of went through the era of very polished, everyone kind of just talking about the successes and it's the same on YouTube,
very high production videos.
I think we're seeing a bit of a swing shift now.
A lot more raw content is is performing better and people want something they relate to.
Not to mention the sea of AI video content that's that's flooding our socials.
>> Well, I think maybe you can speak to that a little bit too cuz I've been watching your videos and they're not like super high production.
Was the production process cuz I know you're somewhat new to creating videos and and being on YouTube.
Was that surprising to you?
Like how simple your videos could be or >> Yes.
And it's kind of by design because I just don't have time to to add a bunch of production to it.
I try and add as much as I can and you know this morning I was working on a fancy intro and you know that's 45 minutes of time burnt and I'm like do we need to do that?
And it goes back to the apps right?
It's the same thing content and apps.
You're putting stuff out there.
You could spend a bunch of time doing it.
If I gave myself 3 days to edit these videos I could do it in 3 days.
If I gave myself a morning then I need to get it done because there's an app waiting to be built.
And yeah, like I said, I've sent some videos to some friends and they've said half an hour or I did a vlog a couple of months ago that was like nearly an hour long.
People said, "What?
That's crazy."
But actually, again, going into that authenticity, people have a bit of a hunger for a bit more in-depth content,
a bit more follow along, you know, sit alongside you whilst you're building.
And and yeah, I think I think there's hunger for that now.
>> Yeah, it's cool that you can sort of just record a loom and that can get thousands or even potentially millions of views in today's I like that.
I mean, that's that's great for all of us is that authenticity just works now.
So, that's super cool.
Okay, so what we posed in the beginning of our conversation, which I really want to get down to the brass tax on this one,
is shipping so many apps in 30 days actually going to move the needle for you to help you build a successful business eventually,
or is this just a waste of time to get a bunch of clout?
>> Yeah, it's a good question.
A quote I really like from Tim Ferrris.
He said,"How can you do something and even if it fails be a success?"
And we spoke about that a bit earlier, but you know, even if I get no audience from this,
even if no one uses my app, then at least I've shipped 30 things.
So my not only is my building muscle stronger, my design, my product sense, um my content,
everything is, you know, 30 reps there and I'll have more apps live than I've ever shipped in my life.
So to me, that's still a success.
And >> is that genius?
I don't know.
Um, the other thing I think a lot of people are wondering how to get into the vibe coding game,
how to get building.
I've had people ask me, hey, like what what should I read, what should I watch to learn how to do this?
And my advice is always the same, like just build something.
If you take something and try and build it, use whatever tools you feel comfortable with,
whatever tools you've maybe used a little bit, and then you'll actually have to work out how to use those tools.
And that is by far the best teacher.
So, I'm doing that every day.
Like I said, I'm still working out the best ways to do this.
best way to get my products looking good, best way to take payment, best way to deploy the apps,
and you know, every day I'm stacking up those skills >> 100%.
I mean, I was skeptical.
Uh I I know that we also worked a little bit together.
You had kind you were in the Starter Story community and you had kind of posed this idea of this challenge to me.
I gave you a little bit of feedback on it.
Um I was honestly skeptical that it was going to work out.
I was also skeptical that you were going to show up every single day and actually do it.
But you are, which is super cool.
And I think what you said earlier is is the truth is that you are condensing what may take people three,
four years to learn all these things.
You're condensing it into a 30-day sprint.
You're running as fast as you can.
You're probably not hitting the gym as much as as you'd like.
Life is probably not as balanced as it could be, but this is a 30 days of going into the cave and learning everything,
specifically how to build products, how to design products, how to get the skeleton of the app set up so that you can just be faster in general.
You're learning how to grow audience.
You're learning how to create content.
You're learning how to create video content.
Even if you don't come out of this with a big audience, which is also something that maybe maybe you would have posted this challenge and it didn't take off and you didn't get the audience that you wanted to,
you will still come out of that with skills and you can't lose.
Uh even even if that happened, you still wouldn't have lost.
I think that momentum is the number one thing uh for a lot of people probably watching this right now is like just moving forward every single day,
sitting down, doing that deep work, adding those skills, stacking those skills.
Like you said, I don't want to give people advice on to do this or do that.
The only advice that I would ever give someone is just to get momentum, to put one foot in front of the other.
I know it sounds cliche, but that's exactly what you're doing here.
And you're just condensing it down to a really, really short timeline, which if you do that over a bunch more times,
then you are set for life.
So, I think it's super cool.
>> 100% 100%.
And yeah, even in the first week, I've had some pretty surprising results in terms of number of users coming to these projects,
some really good feedback.
And yet, at the end of the 30 days, I'll be able to kind of look at all those different projects,
look at all the analytics, look at feedback, and then that will be a really strong springboard for me to say,
"Okay, well, let me let me give these two or three things a lot more focus."
And I'm pretty pumped about that.
What I think might happen is you will maybe on day 15 something will finally click and you'll realize like oh my projects are all starting to go towards that direction
and then all of a sudden your projects start to all sort of complement each other too.
So maybe you build that the domain tool and then maybe you build a another domain tool or something like that but it does it differently but it's still in the domain space.
I don't know.
I'm just making something up right now.
your projects are going to start sort of having synergies, for lack of a better word.
And by the time you get to day 15 and then day 30, you'll have you'll be very clear on what to do next.
And I think clarity is something that you probably don't have a whole lot of right now,
but every single day things will get more clear, which is super cool just because of that momentum.
The last question that I have for you is after 30 days are over and you're finally out of that content grind,
what are you going to do?
>> Yeah, it's a good question and I think I touched upon it there.
I think I'll kind of take a step back.
Look at what worked really well.
Look at what got attention.
Look at what's maybe still getting users because even like I released a blog post tool the other day.
It's still getting usage.
I can see like the metrics and I think, you know, building on what you said there, I'll be able to see some different themes.
So, I've got plans to work on, you know, some a bunch of AI generation.
Well, you've got image generation, video generation, voice, all things that I see all these tools available and it's the golden time to be building with these tools.
um loads of different ideas.
So, I'm pumped to build all those out and see, you know, what what I enjoy working on,
what people find useful, what solves problems, and yeah, I think I as well I'll try and um try and uh take a look back at what we've built as well and enjoy that and hopefully get some rounds of golf in
that I've been missing out on as well.
>> Cool, man.
Well, thank you for coming on to the channel.
I think what you're doing is awesome.
Shameless plug, but you can definitely do similar things with Starter Story Build.
It's our programs that will help you find ideas, build them with AI, and ship it to the real world just like Alex is doing right now.
Alex, hopefully you keep doing really, really cool stuff, and I'm going to keep following,
and we can hopefully bring you back on the channel.
If you're watching this right now, put a comment if you want to see Alex come back on the channel and what questions you want me to ask him next time.
Um, I imagine even in a week from now, you're going to be a completely different person with hopefully a million-dollar app and,
uh, you'll have made millions of dollars by that point.
Uh, but we would love to have you back on the channel and um, thanks for coming on.
I know you're really busy, so I appreciate you.
>> Awesome.
No, really fun to jump on and I'll be in the comments as well, so if there's any ideas you want to send my way,
I'm listening.
Uh, yeah.
So, let me know.
>> Cool, man.
All right, we'll get back to building.
>> Awesome.
which is