All right.
So, if you're on X or Twitter lately, you've probably seen this crazy thing that's going on,
which is these vibecoded web-based games where you fly planes around and uh drive boats around.
And like some of these are crazy.
Some people call it vibecoded games.
And some of these apps are making 70 80 grand a month.
I mean, just search it right now on Twitter and you'll see hundreds of different games that are being shipped.
Why are people creating these?
Uh, and what's the whole point of all this?
Uh, some look cool, some look honestly pretty questionable and pretty stupid.
But honestly, I saw this stuff and I couldn't stop thinking about it.
It got me to ask the question of is this just another ridiculous trend or is this the start of something bigger?
That's what we're going to talk about today.
Let's get into it.
Gus, my researcher at Starter Story, tell me about Vibecoded Games.
Okay, let me share my screen.
Um I if I'm on Twitter all the time for better or worse and I've been seeing this trend vibe coding games.
So let me share my screen.
If you just look up the search term vibe coding games you're going to see all these little games that are being built.
Um and they look kind of stupid.
So this kid this guy is like he built a game for his kid.
There's this like shooting game.
Um there's a bunch of stuff you can find.
Sometimes when I click into here, I kind of think I'm about to get a virus uh when I start playing these games,
but you know, just I don't know.
I don't know what it is.
Just guy walking around.
Um whatever.
But uh the background on that if you don't know is this guy named Peter Levelvels who uh maybe most people know but in case you don't he started this
trend or he kind of started this trend uh because he built a game called Fly Peter or something like that.
Um he he vibecoded this game that's a flight simulator app.
So, um, if if you go to his his profile and or go to fly.pater.com, can you just explain what that means?
He vibe coded it.
So, uh, what I mean by vibe coding is there's there's another trend right now, uh, of these AI coding tools like cursor or wind surf that are building,
you know, helping people learn how to code and build different apps.
And vibe coding is essentially where you oneshot prompt, meaning you put into the put into cursor like build me a game.
That's all you do and you let the AI kind of think for itself and build for itself.
I actually did this yesterday just for fun.
And it created this like writing app thing for me that I was like it's it was insane like how how good it was.
Um from all I said was like build this.
Here's an example.
Go for it.
And so that's kind of what uh levels Peter supposedly did.
He and he's a he's a programmer so he has like experience with this stuff but you know he says here I asked make a 3D flying game more or less that's what he that's all he did.
AI was able to uh build this build this for him and the so that's that's part one.
Uh part two is that he's already making this has gotten a [ __ ] ton of attention.
Like if you look at here, you know, million views.
Uh this is like all he's tweeting about all the time right now.
Part two of this is that he's making a [ __ ] ton of money from this app.
Um so if you look at his his website here or his Twitter, he says he's making 87,000 a month from it.
He started this like four or five weeks ago.
The way he's making money is when you play the game, and I I'll go into the game in a second.
You can advertise your startup on his game and you can advertise for on a blimp or on something for $5,000 a month.
So, let's just like go into the game quick.
Wait, who was paying $5,000 a month?
A bunch of people.
Um, so let's see.
Let's see if we can show you.
So, so you come into the game, you put in your name, it's free to play.
You start, you know, going and here are all these Ads die shift.
This is awesome.
[ __ ] Charge box.
[ __ ] I'm going to die.
So, you're saying he built that without coding?
Well, that's what he says.
Um, he he he says that he he built it really just through a couple of prompts.
It clearly he's sort of developed this a little more.
I don't know a lot about Peter.
I know I know you do, Pat, but I know he's like a programmer.
He's built all these different things.
So, he has experience with it.
But I think it started off as like just build a game told cursor whatever programming language he uses to build a game for him and and it it just did it.
Well, that's the thing with these AI tools is that there's the AI can really build anything,
especially if it's, you know, I don't want to say that it's simple, but building a game is,
you know, there's lots of code examples on GitHub and all these other places that the AI can learn from to build basic 3D games.
And I it does make sense that AI coding could do this.
Yeah.
I think he probably did build it.
He does know how to code, but uh I'm guessing that the AI coding tools helped him like not have to learn all the random stuff he'd have to learn about,
you know, 3D modeling and stuff like that.
Like it it abstracted away all that kind of complicated stuff.
And kind of like I said, um I don't I'm not a programmer, so like I don't know what the hell I'm talking about,
but I asked AI to build something for me the other day, and it like let me see if I can just find my own Twitter here.
Um it did like a pretty decent job.
Let me find myself.
Gus Tiffer, give me a follow.
Appreciate that.
Um I don't know.
I I do a lot of writing for Starter Story and there's this copywriter named Gary Halpert that's like I don't know,
famous dude.
And in cursor, I just said, "Build me a writing app that will off of Gary Halpert that will uh critique my writing."
And I copied something in there and it gave me like a score.
I didn't ask it to do this or anything like that.
Uh well, you built an app that does this.
Yeah.
Wow.
Just yesterday.
And all I did was All I did was say, "Hey, I like uh there's this other app called Hemingway.
It's this like writing editor app."
I know this one.
Yeah.
Uh, all I said was,"Hey, I like Hemingway, but I like this copywriter.
Build me an app that critiques my writing and make it in the style of Hemingway editor."
It's kind It was kind of crazy.
So, I bring that up because when after Peter, you know, started tweeting about his game that he
built, a bunch of other people started also building AI games.
So, like I found this website called uh that's called aibbuiltgames.com and these are all games.
I shouldn't say all.
I think it's like mostly games that have been built after like levels kind of started this little trend.
So, you can look at any of these.
Let's just play one.
And uh and these are exactly like the controls that you know Peter created in his game.
And it's just like I don't know what this is.
Just going around and guess I'm shooting [ __ ] Um, and you can find you can find a ton of these.
So, he started this trend.
Yeah.
He started like random cool ideas with vibe coding and now like everyone's doing it.
Exactly.
Yeah.
A bunch of people have started like vibe coding uh these games.
Feels like that's about to be like the new cool math games.
Like kids are just going to go on that site and just start playing like all these different games.
For sure.
Yeah.
We can we'll talk about like other trends I think a little bit later.
But so that that's a little bit of the background of of these vibe coding games that are like exploding on on Twitter right now.
Yeah.
This has become such a trend that levels decided to do this like competition on vibe coding games.
This kind this doesn't matter like too much.
But the point the point I want to make here is like so many people started building these vibecoded games that there was enough demand for Peter to create like a competition all around
like hey show off your vibecoded game.
The only requirements is that it's mostly written by AI.
There's a bunch of other like little requirements here.
Submit your your game on this Google form.
And if you look at some of the quote tweets here and some of the search queries on it,
you'll see a bunch of these games that people like have started building.
So this guy built this stupid ball game in two hours.
This guy's building I guess this world game.
There's a bunch of other stuff.
This like uh playh highseas.com.
I saw this one.
I saw one that was a boat.
It looked really cool.
Like the graphics were crazy good.
It looked like almost like PS3 graphics for sure.
Yeah.
I mean, I've been vibe coding this retro arcade game.
It's that's like pretty cool, right?
My question for this is are any of these making money or is this just a trend, you know,
is fun?
That that's that's my big question.
And like I know we kind of talked about how he's making money, but is there a business idea here or is there a business here or is this just fun?
Yeah, that's the question.
Um, I don't know if anyone is actually making money off of this.
Uh, my guess is no way.
All these people are like have really small audience.
Um, I think part of this competition is going to be levels sort of like sharing the whoever the winner is like sharing it out.
And one of the critiques which we can get into this is that level so Levelvels is making money off it,
right?
he's making 87k a month through these advertisers.
But one of the critiques is you're only making money because you have an audience.
So there's this other tweet that I found or a couple that I'll pull up.
There's this one, this guy John Young Fuk, I don't know who he is.
Some of the conversation happening on Twitter is like, "Yeah, I would love to build like a 87k a month project if I only had the same audience as as Levels."
Obviously Levels has mill thousands of followers.
guy on Twitter who's never shipped an app.
Yeah.
Another one and I'll pull this up and then see what you guys think is uh this guy good,
you know, Level Levels has been updating saying, "I'm making this much now.
I'm making this much now."
And this guy said, "Good for Peter."
But guess the lesson is just like have an audience.
If if I only had an audience, then I guess I'd be making money, too.
Yeah.
I hate seeing the people that say, "Oh, you you only can do it if because you have an audience."
The reality is that you got an audience because you actually ship stuff and you build stuff.
Everybody starts with zero audience, right?
That's something you build over time.
And any business in order to be successful, whether it's a vibe coded game or, I don't know,
a billion dollar company like Apple or Tesla or whatever, starts with an audience.
You have to have an audience, otherwise you would never even have a single customer,
right?
The idea behind building something and then just hoping that it takes off is it does work.
It does happen from time to time, but everybody starts with an audience.
Even if it's just an audience of one.
If you do have an audience, may not be as big as Peter Level's audience, but you probably have an audience of 100,
audience of 500.
And that's where things start.
Build something, ship it to there, it will get shared to other people, and then you're building your audience.
And some people have really big, massive audiences like Peter.
And some people have smaller audiences, but there's nobody that's built anything with no audience.
Yeah.
And that's where I think that, and don't get me wrong, I I feel like I've been on that side before where I'm like,
well, that's cool that you make a bunch of money, but I have 600 followers.
You have 16,000 or whatever or more.
But this line right here like really gets me, right?
Like a guy on Twitter who has never shipped an app ever, whatever.
Like people sitting on the sidelines being like, "Oh yeah, if only."
But like you just said, like you start from nothing.
The only way you grow to something is by like doing stuff.
Yeah.
And I think that's where a lot of the critique comes from, but also it's coming from people who like haven't done anything.
I mean, Peter Levelvels, he's if you go to I think maybe it's his pin tweet or something else is like how many failed projects he has.
It's not like he doesn't have failed projects, right?
People are paying money for this, which means that there is some sort of value there.
You whether it does have part of his audience as part of it for sure, but look at all of his failed projects.
For example, I know Peter, he's always shared with me this thing called like airline list or something like that.
It's like a directory where you can see like popular airlines.
Yeah, this one right here.
He's built this.
He built this.
I don't think this is making $87,000 a month, but this is something that he shipped.
He built this probably even gave him somewhat of he got maybe into he's into flying.
I know that he's into flight simulators.
He wouldn't even had that idea if it weren't for a bunch of the stuff that he shipped and probably didn't,
you know, go crazy.
But would he have had the idea for the flying game if he didn't go and build airline list and like 80 other things and see what what doesn't make any money and what does make money?
And I think that's like an interesting insight.
Yeah, it reminds me of um there's a tweet we've done for Starter Story that's like 90% of my projects failed or something like that.
Similar idea like most things he probably made suck.
Yeah.
Or didn't work.
and the only way he got to 87,000 or and any more of these is by, you know, building stuff that didn't work first.
Another thing that's kind of been being shared is like that this vibe coding trend is like stupid and won't last.
And so here's here's a couple more tweets.
Clearly I'm on like Twitter way too much.
uh this other tweet that I saw that's like um this guy he built this thing um shared it on Twitter and now he's getting like hacked a ton and one
of the things is that so here's another Reddit post here's a Reddit post that's like cursor [ __ ] up 4 months of my work and some guy commented doesn't it terrify anyone else that there's an entire cohort of new engineers who are
getting into programming because of AI but missing absolute basic bare necessities the the point being like there's a bunch of like noobs who are using cursor and don't actually know what the hell they're doing and this
there's no way that this is going to last.
Yeah, I mean that's total cope because I'm a software engineer.
I have a software engineering background.
I'm not a very good one but my website has been under attack many times and I didn't vibe code my app right and you know cyber security is a huge problem in any business.
So just because you built it with cursor or not doesn't mean that your app is less or more secure.
It may maybe it would it would tend to be less secure if people that don't know programming are building stuff.
But you know if you did want your app to be more sec more focused on security then you can just vibe code your way there like go on chat GBT and ask how your app can
be more secure and it'll give you those things and you can vibe code and until you figure those out.
So I think that's a that's a really shitty argument and uh you know this is just classic like software engineers who want to gatekeep and you know that think that their
knowledge is so proprietary or you know you know they probably just are worried about losing their job at the end of the day.
So I guarantee if you go to some of these people's profiles they're, you know, haven't again haven't shipped anything in you maybe like contemplating,
you know, their one line of code for like 16 hours when the vibe coders just write like a thousand lines of code in an hour and then figure out the security stuff when that's needed.
Yeah.
It seems like it's one of those things you just kind of fail and then learn, which makes the most sense.
Like if you don't know how to just learn from that mistake, then what's the point of it?
Yeah.
And if you if you if it's a plane game, then who cares, right?
Yeah, if you are storing uh bank account information or something that's really sensitive,
then yeah, you probably shouldn't be vi coding your app or you should maybe contract out someone who can help with that side of things.
You know, if you're building a plane game or a directory or a job board or something like that,
then security really isn't that important until maybe you're at a bigger scale.
So, so yeah.
So all this is like a little bit of the background right of like the trend that's been happening with vibe coding games you know levels is flying game and all these other you know arguments for
or against like vibe coding but I I can't I think one of the main questions I want to ask is this just like an one of those other trends like drop shipping
like no code like NFTTS or is this something that that will become something else?
Yeah, I think that's what everyone wants to figure out is if this is really like a trend that's here to last.
Should they get into this?
Should they start vibe coding?
Should they start building games?
And I don't really have the answer to that.
But I always think that there's something there when you see such a mass amount of people doing something and you see with the hackathons,
like the contest that he launched, there's so many people doing it right now that there's something there.
Surely flying games aren't going to be a billion-dollar business in that exact form that it is now,
but there's something there with uh so many people doing this in this moment.
It's going to transform and and change, but there's something there.
I mean, I'll start with that, but I don't know what you guys think.
It certainly is like a shiny new thing, and and I think that's like always really interesting.
Like, it's fun.
Like I mentioned the app that I built.
It was fun just to do that and be like, "Oh, like I can make something."
I non-programmer now have some additional skill or something I can put into the world.
I think that's cool.
Some of the conversation online has been like some version of like this is just like another way to like build something and some of the other fundamentals still like matter.
Marketing, distribution, you know, finding customers, solving problems.
And I know you talk about that a lot, Pat.
Maybe this is overblown, but it feels like a trend that's like really like different than the others,
different than like newsletters, different than like drop shipping.
And I don't know what to make of that really to be honest, but it does feel just like a little different.
I like what you said about fun because I think that is how a lot of like big trends start too is like it's just fun and there's not like Yeah,
that thing does make money, but most of them don't and that's okay.
I mean, it reminds me of when I think Peter Levelvel's launched.
I don't remember the exact name of it, but it was a AI images generator thing where you could turn your uh Twitter profile headsh shot into like a cartoon image and make it look all badass.
And I remember that was like right when the uh stable diffusion or one of those early image generative models came out and it really wasn't that good yet.
So people were just levels is really good at finding that kind of early alpha and just building something fun and creative and cool with that and then like a year later or two
years later you see like entire you see like billion-dollar businesses get built off of it.
I'm not sure about billion but you know maybe he was one of the first people to do the headshot thing and now there's like professional head shot service where it's not like just a fun creative thing anymore.
or it's like something that actual that solves an actual painful problem of having to get your photo shoot done,
right?
So, that's how I like to see is like in this current iteration right now, this plane game is whatever,
but what is this going to be in 2 years?
What is this going to be in 3 years?
This whole vibe coding thing and games too.
I think there's something interesting uh with games is will people be playing more games?
Is this a sign that games will be more popular?
I think the games thing is really big, especially because, you know, people have always played games.
I like how when we were talking about it's more of like a fun thing.
It seems like it's very art and like expressionary right now.
The fact that you don't have to have like a AAA studio anymore or like this big studio with a bunch of funding to make a game and you can just launch something quickly and kind of get
people playing it is one thing that's really interesting and that could turn into something really big.
If some person like this can just spin up a fun little game, it gets traction and then you could figure out ways to make money from there.
I think that could be really big.
because yeah, the barrier to entry now is just getting lower and lower, especially for games.
Yeah, there's there's two tweets I wanted to show quick to kind of to kind of I guess share what I think.
One by I think this guy started Indie Hackers.
Yeah, he says, "Vibe coding is on a trend.
It's simply the best way to move forward, blah blah blah.
The people embracing it are the innovators and early adopters who envision huge potential.
They're willing to fight through the bugs, cobble together, etc., but everyone else would rather wait."
And so I I think it's it the point of me sharing this piece is like um it might be a trend that goes or you know lives or dies,
but I I do think like you said earlier Pat there's like it does feel like a really significant like new wave of people being able to build stuff and so your choice is kind of like do I play around
with it or not?
you know, for those who do who kind of fight through all the the the shittiness of the the how shitty it is right now in five years are going to be people that I don't know are just 5
years ahead of anyone who starts later.
And then there's second one here.
Um, if you feel the new trend like vibe coding is cringe because everyone is saying it,
it means it's going to be around for a very long time.
Cringiness is a marketing bull signal.
Cringe equals noticeable.
I think there's something to that too where it's like I don't even know who this guy is.
You know, he's some some kid.
But I think there's something there of like if you're willing or able to oh, I don't know,
like fight through some of that cringiness of what that feels like.
Um, are they saying the cringe is like because the games are cringe?
They're just it's not like Yeah, the games are cringy.
They kind of suck.
They're probably not going to make money, but you're putting it out there, you know,
getting some attention, learning to play around with these tools, feeling stupid, maybe doing it.
I'm sure like I mean I felt like I I keep referencing the that example.
I felt dumb being like, "Hey, cursor, can you build this for me?"
Um, but if I continue doing that, if any one of us continues doing that, we're just going to be light years ahead of other people.
Like I had a friend the other day, literally like on Sunday, he was like my age.
And he was like, "Oh, I just learned about this thing called Chad GPT."
I was like, "What?"
Like I use it every day.
I can't live without it.
Uh, maybe that's bad.
Um, but it just goes to shows like it's so early.
Yeah.
I think the cringe thing is actually pretty interesting.
Like maybe another take on it is like it's people who are willing to go and build silly vibecoded games like Peter,
you know, he has a big audience, but he's willing to go put like a silly game up there.
It's like it's like a maybe not as big of an ego around what they build.
And I think that like when you start having egos around what you build, then you're less likely to build uh things that are going to fail,
potentially going to fail.
Uh you're less likely to build silly things.
There's a famous article, I wish I could find it right now, about how like most big things start as games or they start,
sorry, it's called toys.
Let me find this real quick.
So this is a famous article.
It just it just came to just reminded me is that this guy Chris Dixon, I think he invested in some huge companies,
but um the title is the next big thing will start out looking like a toy.
And that's kind of everything you need to know about this article was written in 2010,
right?
And I'm sure there are some examples in here.
Skype uh started out as a toy and lots of lots of examples.
I wish I could read through this a little more quickly, but um there's another famous quote something around like what people work on on the weekends for fun today ends up being the billion dollar companies of tomorrow.
So just like fun egoless stuff is always a good sign that um it's going to be something big in the future.
It's going to look way different than it does now.
Removing of the ego and embracing the cringe.
People like view their startups as their own baby and that sort of thing.
That's that never works, right?
It's always just like trying something new and that like random thing you try on the 15th time takes off.
You didn't expect it.
That's like what usually ends up working out or like those are always the classic startup stories that you hear about.
Yeah, that's such a like good point of like the low ego to essentially be being be willing to like build dumb stuff or shitty stuff
first.
Yeah, I think is a good point.
So yeah, I think um I think that's you know why I like levels so much is that he is kind of the pioneer of like silly proofs
of concepts and you can see it with a lot of his past stuff is like you know for example Nomad List that was like his OG startup that he did that was kind of at the time I think somewhat of a new
idea and then how many communities and online communities and directory type apps came from that then there was the AI and all the stuff that came from that when he's doing something I'll usually
and it's working then that's usually a good sign of something.
I mean it's possible that this thing completely dies but it kind of also reminds me somewhat of no code.
Everyone doubted no code for so long and when no code came out all the engineers got mad that it's never going to work and that sort of thing and yeah no code where like zap year and that that it never really worked that
great.
It definitely solves some good problems, but what came from that was AI coding tools and now what I guess is kind of called instead of no code,
it's called Vibe Code.
Who knows what the next iteration of that is going to be, but I think it's something big.
So, you know, I'd recommend anybody that wants to that that is asking this question of is this people just shipping trash and making money and it's just a get-rich quick scheme.
I don't think so.
I really do think think that this is the beginning and if you want to go and my advice would be to just go and start playing around with it.
Start playing around with the tools.
See what happens.
I mean Gus is a great example of how you launched your own app in a couple hours.
That tells me everything I need to know about it about how it's going to be powerful.
So yeah, I don't know what you guys think, but that I'm feeling pretty excited about it.
I like it a lot.
It feels like one of those things too where the people that are building and playing with it now are going to really see the benefits in like two years if it actually does really take off and then it's going to be one of those things
where you have a bunch of people popping up because maybe they built a really cool game or vibe coded a really cool app because they were spending time doing the work when nobody else is doing it.
And then, you know, you're gonna have a bunch of overnight success stories pop up of people building really cool [ __ ] or something actually takes off and works because more people are coming on to it,
more people are seeing it.
So, that's how I feel like it's going to end up playing out.
Seems like it's a really cool opportunity.
Yeah.
And it feels so like I mean it's so cheap.
Like Cursor is 20 bucks a month.
Yeah.
You know, um I spend more on stupid [ __ ] you know, than that.
And so the the barrier to entry or whatever is like really low.
And so why not if you if you're aware of this, why not just build?
Why not just try?
Why not just mess around?
Uh it may lead to nothing.
It may be like a side quest that sucks, but I do think you'll like I've learned a lot playing around with it that I would have just never known before.
Um, so like for the people watching this, it's like you're so early, so you might as well like start playing around with these tools.
Yeah, it's like worth your time and and not expensive.
It does remind me a little bit of like, man, when I wanted I I really wanted to build a business.
I wanted to build stuff, but I didn't know how.
And this is over 10 years ago before I learned how to code.
And there wasn't, you know, vibe coding tools or anything back then.
So I what I decided to do because I wanted to learn.
so bad how to actually build things and turn them into real life apps and projects is I went to like a coding boot camp and when I got out of that it was took three months which was really short
at the time to learn something but when I got out of that I felt so empowered to build stuff that I just started building things I start I built like a small side project I built a Chrome extension I just started building all these things I went and worked as a software engineer
and then I started building startups and then I built starter story if you want to learn how to build stuff too I recommend just checking out these tools and just learning them and seeing that how you feel when you start using them
and seeing what's possible.
Sometimes I just see people do this and they catch the bug right away.
It's like, "Oh my god, I just built that thing.
I'm never going to stop building stuff and I'm only going to get better from here."
If you do want to learn how to do vibe coding and build stuff, we actually have a program dedicated to this.
In 12 days, each day you're actually going to build something.
You're going to come up with an idea, you're going to build a landing page, you're going to set up the O,
you're going to set up the database, you're going to build the features and do everything.
This is our AI build accelerator and it's something that we're really excited.
You'll be using lovable which is actually probably the best tool right now for doing this thing.
Imagine what you could do in 12 days and after those 12 days what else you could build after.
Uh this is something new that we've been running which has been really successful and some of the apps that people have built have been super awesome.
So check the first link in the description if you're curious but otherwise keep building and enjoy.