All right, guys.
Welcome to the Starter Story podcast.
I have a very special episode for you today.
Gus is finally back to give an update on the app that he's been building.
Gus went away.
He had a baby.
He's still been building stuff and I haven't heard from him in a while.
So, I want to get his update on everything that he's been doing, how much time he spent on his app,
how it's been doing, how many users he's gotten, and how much revenue he's truly made from this.
I think this conversation was awesome because Gus is in a very interesting place where he's still trying to figure out is this the right app to be building.
Should I pivot?
Should I go build something else?
I think this conversation would be really useful for anyone who's building anything is really in this kind of phase of you don't really have product market fit yet,
but you sort of have something working.
You've been building and shipping stuff.
This conversation was awesome and I hope you guys enjoy it.
Let's get into it.
All right, so Gus, it's great to have you back.
Congrats.
You birthed a child.
Um, you're you're not I >> My wife did, but I watched.
>> You birthed a child and you birthed an app and you're going to birth hopefully some more apps.
I just want to get an update from you.
I think the audience wants to hear an update from you, too.
You now have, you know, an app in the wild.
You've learned a ton in the process.
Now, you're back ready to go grind in the the great lockin of uh 2025.
Yeah.
>> So, I think the audience would love to hear an update from you, where things are at,
how much revenue you've made, everything.
>> Cool.
Yeah.
Happy to be back.
>> Yeah.
So, for if you're kind of the first time you're tuning in, seeing this, obviously, we have I have a whole playlist here on this channel of me going through the process of building this first app.
Um, but if it's your first time, I I uh essentially used uh cursor and cloud code to build my first ever app.
I don't have any really developer experience, anything like that.
and we sort of devised this idea of a a mobile app that's like a step tracker.
I can probably talk a lot more about whether that was good or not, but that's kind of what I built.
Let me just show it to you in case you uh in case you haven't seen it.
This is my my actual phone here uh that I have pulled up.
And so I built a step tracker that essentially just tracks whether or not you've hit 10,000 steps today or not.
I have like a helpful little widget sort of tracks here.
I have a new like history view where I can see uh you know over time how much how many steps you've taken,
your monthly average, if you've hit your goal and you can sort of toggle backwards to see like if you hit it or not.
>> And I just opened it up here on mine.
>> It looks like you showed a bunch of updates to it too.
>> Oh yeah, >> you got a little payw wall on there.
That's nice.
>> Yeah.
Go ahead and hit restore at the bottom.
That should take you if you've already bought it.
I've had so many issu so many challenges like setting up a payw wall.
That's like a whole another like way I could take talk about this.
>> That's the thing that they don't tell you about how easy vibe coding is is you know setting up Stripe integration or or these things.
So like you know of course you ran into issues there.
>> Yeah.
Like how to and then just like how to price it, what's you know what's interesting, what's not.
So yeah, that's what I built.
You know a quick reflection is like it was really hard for me to build it.
You know it was the first time I ever did anything like that.
So I went through a lot of trial and error of like do I do it on Android or just iOS?
You know, how do I build the features?
You know, how do I fix these bugs?
I kind of went through a whole process which you could again you can go back and watch,
but it's live.
It's in the app store.
It's working generally speaking.
So that's kind of the update there.
Now, in terms of like some numbers or some where I'm actually at, I actually pulled up kind of my app store connect page.
So I'll share my screen again so you can kind of check it out.
So, you know, Apple gives you a lot of like kind of data on like how many impressions your page has gotten,
stuff like that.
So, probably the big number here is total downloads.
I've gotten 73 total downloads.
That doesn't obviously equate directly to, you know, revenue or proceeds, but in total,
I've made about 40 bucks.
>> And we we started doing this um we started this process way back I think early June,
about three months ago, something like that.
and say over the last three months I've made um $40.
And there's a part of me that's like I guess stoked about that because you know I've never built anything and had anybody pay for it.
So it's kind of awesome.
Uh there's another part of me that's like a little disappointed and this is probably the you know the naive part of of this whole thing is like this is again my first project and um maybe I
had like these grand dreams of like this is going to be the hit you know >> course >> and I think I think I had a little bit of like dopamine dopamine in like how I was building in public on Twitter.
I had a lot of sort of people following, people commenting, people messaging me about,
you know, how cool it was or, you know, cool to see me doing this, uh, etc.
And so, I think there was a little dopamine rush of like, oh, people are excited about this that's going to lead to whatever downloads,
revenue, success.
So, I'm sort of I'm feeling those those two things of like this is this is actually kind of successful for me cuz I the original challenge was like the dollar challenge and I made 40.
So, >> 40x that goal.
>> Yeah.
Um, but the other side of me is like, "Oh, this is like I feel like I'm a little bit in the losing steam a little bit of like,
okay, what?
This is this was cool and now it's live and now I don't know what to do."
>> Well, before we get into a bunch of that stuff, I mean, how long have you been building this app for?
And how many hours you think you spent doing it?
>> Yeah.
So, if I started probably like June, like early June, what's that?
Like about three months now.
Yeah.
Going on going on four.
>> Yeah.
I probably work on it like an hourish a day realistically.
Of course, I've missed time here and there especially having a newborn so probably a little under like 80 hours probably total time total time that that you know that includes obviously building it and then a lot of the stuff I've been
posting about and I started a Tik Tok page.
It's another kind of thread we could pull on um a little bit but yeah just time spent.
you only spent 80 hours building this, you know, that actually I would have expected you to say 300 or 400 hours.
If I'm thinking of 80 hours, if you were doing this full-time, >> that would be 2 weeks.
So, maybe that's an interesting way of looking at it is if you were doing this full-time and you made $40 in your first two weeks,
you'd be pretty stoked, right?
>> Yeah, I think so.
>> Let's talk about that because it doesn't seem like you're that excited about the $40.
I maybe I can give some things in perspective of >> Yeah.
Yeah.
>> you making your first dollar.
I mean, I talked to a lot of people.
There's a lot of people inside Star community trying to build apps.
There's also a lot of successful people that we talked to that are making thousands of dollars per month.
And I don't have the numbers in front of me or anything like that there, but I would say that like making your first dollar within the 3 months,
first three months of starting is actually like really impressive.
If I even look at my own story, I didn't make a dollar for at least a year uh when I was building stuff.
And even when I started Starter, there's stuff before starter story, but even when I started Starter Story,
I think I made three bucks because, you know, the app was free when I was first starting.
I think I made my first like $3 or something like that two or three months in.
So, first of all, maybe you're going on social media too much and talking to successful founders because that's you help us create videos at Starter Story,
too.
So, >> that's something I I do want to just reset on that.
Maybe give me some of your thoughts on on that.
Yeah, that's a really good like perspective honestly because you're probably right.
I'm I'm like chronically on Twitter.
I get a lot of stuff of like mo people building mobile apps because that's what I am doing.
And um there's so many just like look at this thing making x amount, look at this making thousands of downloads and I'm just like I got 70 downloads.
I made 40 bucks.
I feel like I'm sort of it's easy to feel behind maybe.
So that's a good like perspective I guess is like it takes a long time.
I I think I am getting sort of like FOMO or whatever whatever word you want to put there.
That's like I'm like behind and I should maybe I should just do something else because like this clearly isn't >> you know clearly isn't working >> or like I've tried everything I I know I haven't.
>> We'll get there.
What what you should do but first I still have a few more questions for you.
So when you look back at the last three months even maybe sometime before that let's forget about the numbers.
Let's forget about the revenue.
Let's forget about all that stuff.
Tell me what you've learned and how you've changed and how your thinking has changed through building this.
>> Well, I think the biggest thing I've learned is that I can build something.
Having not been from any kind of technical background and having followed all these people for a long time who are building stuff and feeling probably jealous like,
"Oh man, how could they do that?"
Now I can or now I know how to.
Like if I was going to redo this again, I would cut that time in half.
That's one thing I've learned.
Second thing I've learned is like we've talked about this in other podcasts about like building in public is just like the the process of sharing what you're doing and like kind of building a little following and audience.
I mean when I started this I think I had like not that it's all about followers but if we're counting that as like a metric I think I had like I don't know 6 or 700 followers and now I have like 2500 or something like that
all from just like sharing my building process.
And so learning like how to do that online, how to share earnestly and in a way that's relatable,
in a way that feels true to me.
I mean, I've learned a billion things about like how do I price this, how do I even set up an account,
how do I, you know, do all this stuff that I think will serve me, whether it's for this project or the next one.
Yeah, I just feel like I can cut it all in half now.
>> Those are amazing things that you've learned, especially like the mindset stuff.
But let's also not even forget about just the hard skills that you learned.
You learned how to come up with a decent idea.
You learned how to build an app.
You learned how to ship something to the app store.
You learned how to design apps.
You learned pricing.
You learned payw walls.
You learned building a public.
You learned what makes good content.
And the list goes on.
Maybe you have some other things that you've learned there in the span of three months.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
I mean, when you put it when you sort of put it like that, you're like, "Oh, yeah.
You've kind of come a long ways, I guess."
I mean, the like I said, the original goal was like to make $1.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, it's funny how like the goalpost move.
And that's the thing that one thing that I noticed from a lot of successful people, especially people that are building software and apps,
is this mindset of learning over earning.
And it's like kind of like a cliche statement, but I think what you're learning and exactly how you said,
if I were to start over, I could cut that time in half.
That's actually more valuable than just some revenue, right?
Those are your own assets, your own skills, your own abilities that you can apply to more startups next time.
So that when you do see those people online and like they launch something and build something in like five minutes and it makes all this money,
that's because they have the skills building, coding, designing and they have the insights of what a good launch is,
of what good pricing is, of what a good idea is.
So actually you're getting yourself closer to that point even though you didn't make as much money as you wanted to or it wasn't a home run out of the gate.
>> Yeah.
I mean, yeah, of course.
Like I think that's going to serve me in the long run, you know?
It's just I'm gonna be able to like replicate this again hopefully faster or like yeah just faster,
better, cheaper, all that stuff.
>> And that's that's always the story of every time we I talk to a founder is, you know,
they have that overnight success or or that really big app.
We don't always cover this in our YouTube videos, but if you go ask them, they usually have 10,
15, five, whatever ideas before that in some long time span.
Sometimes it's a year, sometimes it's five years, sometimes it's even longer of failed projects where,
you know, it's not because they just got lucky.
It's because it was that combination of luck and skill and timing and then they just kept going.
So that would be like when I when I look at your transformation, you can go back and watch the old videos on this channel of when you were just trying to come up with an idea.
you know, it was like a touch grass idea and you know, I can't remember exactly what the ideas were,
but you are completely transformed from that point.
So, let's make sure that we level set the >> Yeah, that's a good reminder.
And yeah, I think that's kind of the the downside of building in public or sharing online is like you see all this other stuff and you're just like I feel like behind or I feel like I don't know what I'm doing or it's someone else has a secret or something.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't got it.
>> Is good.
It's there's good pros and cons.
I I've read this somewhere, but like the sort of anxiety that you feel when you're first starting is actually can it's a it sucks because it's anxiety and it makes you not feel great,
but it also it creates urgency, creates action out of you that that anxiety that you feel is important when starting out.
I don't know like super chill guys that like build really cool stuff.
It's usually most of the founders, most people watching this are smothered by anxiety,
including myself.
And that is it's an important driver in building stuff, I think.
>> Yeah, for sure.
That's a good point.
Yeah.
But I think to like all the founders we interview on the main channel, Yeah.
they all kind of have this like little I don't know, little time ticking inside them that's like >> Yeah.
Yep.
>> kind of pushing them urgency.
Yeah.
Those are good reminders.
Um but yeah, that's kind of where I'm at.
Yeah, that's that's kind of where I'm at.
Yeah.
>> Let's talk about that.
You kind of seem to be in this point where you're not really sure what to do next.
Are you going to build a new app, you know, or are you gonna keep working on this?
Tell me about what you're kind of going through day-to-day.
You now have an app.
It's made some money.
It's not up to your expectations.
How does that feel right now?
What's the day-to-day like?
And what are you thinking about?
The day-to-day is trying to figure out like how do I get more like eyeballs on this thing?
That's kind of the first thing I'm kind of trying to figure out.
Uh a lot of a lot of people in mobile apps are talking about like how at least on Twitter talking about like there's a combo of you know you build it and then you try to like share it or like make a Tik Tok page or something like as a
short form page and like just share stuff on there.
So I've been doing that a little bit for the last month or so.
I started a Tik Tok page and I'm doing like I don't know right now on Tik Tok there's a lot of like slideshows or whatever.
Um, and so I started this page, you know, I've gotten x amount of views on on my thing and I use a tool called real farm.
Uh, it's like a help helps you make Tik Tok slideshows and stuff and just sharing like different ideas.
And so here's an example of one and if you slide through it eventually you kind of see my app and the idea is like people would look at it and then be like,
"Oh, I wonder what that is."
Download it or or check it out from there.
That's one thing I've been trying to do on a regular basis is sort of just share share my app.
I posted a few times on Reddit that's been like not as successful as maybe I wanted it to be so far.
I'm sharing more on Twitter, you know, just about my process, less about like the app itself,
more about like thinking about it, some of the results of Tik Tok and stuff like that.
And then doing like some tweaks, you know, I when I first launched it, it was just like you had to pay a buck or whatever to download it.
and they're like, "You should actually make it free to download, do like a trial and then make it,
you know, a payw wall or whatever."
I kind of [ __ ] that up a little bit with just like when I like made it and it kind of messed some things up and so backtracked on that.
So those are some of the things I've been doing like on a daily basis for the last more I I probably it took probably took me like two months to like get it live and then for the last month or so I've been kind of just doing a lot of this stuff.
I mean, my my gut tells me that it just seems like you feel uncertain about things and maybe potentially that is affect Walk me through how you're
feeling about the app and you know what the next few days look like.
It doesn't seem like you have like a big plan or anything like that.
I probably feel like the app is like super basic or I feel like maybe uh insecure about how basic it is and like why why would anyone like pay for this when there's like other similar types of apps that are like
really really well built out and stuff like that.
So I think I feel a little bit insecure there.
I think I feel just a little lost on like like what do I do now?
you know, like kind of sharing on TikTok, but I don't know if it's really working.
Posting on Twitter and Reddit and I'm kind of like I don't know what I like it's it's like I don't know what to talk about,
you know?
>> Yeah.
>> And so I think that's a struggle I'm going through a little bit right now.
And I think we've talked about this before too is like building is fun.
Marketing is like it's not fun.
>> Yeah.
>> Or it doesn't feel as fun, you know?
making like small tweaks to my app is not that fun as like the come up and like making it come to life.
You know, just changing a few things on the page or on the on the screen is like not not as fun as like the initial sort of design of it.
And so I I just kind of feel this sense of like just losing steam I guess probably is what it feels like.
It's like yeah just losing steam like losing the excitement of it, losing the momentum maybe I had.
So kind of working on this app kind of feels like a chore more than excitement every day to work on it.
>> Yeah.
Some days.
Yeah.
>> For sure.
And so that's why I've been I mean I posted a little bit on Twitter about this.
It's like what do I what's like the move, you know?
Do I do I keep spinning my wheels?
Do I just build something different?
I get mixed sort of comments.
You know, some people are like it takes a long time.
Someone looked at my Tik Tok page and they were they said something like they were like hey I appreciate you these thoughts but like you've posted like 10 Tik Toks you know >> and I was like yeah and some someone
else was like get you get you know you get mixed results so it's I'm not like just kind of following what the crowd says but other people are like just kill it and do something else you know depends on what you want to do and I'm like okay and others are like just you
know you've made some money that means some people paid for it like go talk to the users and I'm like oh yeah I guess I should do that too >> and I've seen you've been posting about talking to people and some other folks online and I'm like,
you know, to be honest, I haven't talked to anybody about it.
So, maybe I should do that.
So, I don't know.
There's just like lots of different directions that >> and and I think because of all those directions,
I'm like feel a little frozen.
>> Yeah.
>> On what exactly to do.
I mean, it's impossible to say what you should do.
>> You know, there's no right or wrong answer to any of this.
The first thing is it's less about the idea, more about you.
So, this idea that you have now is good.
Clearly, it made some money, but it's probably not going to be a millionoll business idea that changes your life.
But that shouldn't stop you from continuing to work on it or or even continuing to work on other things.
I I saw some comment on your ex.
It was something like the only important thing is that you don't give up.
It's not that you don't give up on this idea, but you don't give up on building stuff and building useful products,
products that make money.
That's like the most important thing is that you just don't give up.
And I see a lot of people give up on themselves but not just give up on their idea.
And that's like the worst thing that could happen is that you give up on yourself.
The second thing that I do think is interesting we should dive into is motivation.
If you were more motivated around the idea and also if it was working a little bit better,
I think you'd probably wake up every day a little bit more excited to work on it.
Specifically, you mentioned the Tik Tok thing, how you only have 10 Tik Toks that you created.
If you were truly excited about this idea, not necessarily just the idea, the problem you were solving and the customers you were working with,
then you would post three Tik Toks a day and it would would it would feel effortless.
>> Not saying that Tik Tok is the right thing to do or whatever.
>> Sure.
>> But you mentioned you really enjoyed the building aspect.
You really enjoyed some other things of it.
Maybe there is a way that you can do more of that stuff and still grow this app or build ideas,
try things around that thing that you're really excited about.
I'll give you an example.
When I was doing the 100K build challenge, which people who are watching this have probably seen it,
I started with a YouTube thumbnail generator.
And um I hated that idea.
The moment I shipped the first MVP, I couldn't even get myself to ship a single feature after it.
Only I had some customers asking for a couple things, so I did it.
But even fixing bugs, it felt like so draining just to sit in front of it and do it.
And then when I found the idea that is sort of working now, Moat, I'm so excited about that.
I just build stuff all the time.
And I I'm so busy right now.
I can't find like a lot of time to build these features right now.
But like I cherish those extra hours I have on the weekend to sit down and get into cloud code and build a new feature or you know make the app better.
So like I don't know what you think about that but I feel like motivation is like maybe one of the most important things especially as a solarreneur.
>> Yeah.
I mean that's kind of like I think that's where I've been a little like cop con between is like do I cuz I do like the building pro.
I have more ideas of things I want to like try and make, but I feel like if I do that,
I'm kind of giving up on this.
I do still feel excited.
I mean, I I personally use this app every day cuz I cuz I like it, but I feel like if I started building something new,
I would just sort of like get distracted there and then maybe one day that that new thing would die out and then suddenly I have this like graveyard of like different ideas that I kind of like started and never like took to the end,
you know?
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
>> So, in terms of the motivation piece, like Yeah.
Do am I like stoked to like talk about hitting 10,000 steps every day?
I don't know.
Kind of.
>> Yeah, >> person I personally like try.
Is that like what I want to be known for?
I don't know.
I'll just say I like the process of like making the the content and stuff like that or like kind of creating the videos and that's like really fun.
I don't want that to be the only thing.
I don't know.
One thing that I think is sort of interesting that I think about sometimes Mark Lou,
you know Mark Lou, he has um really successful product called Shipfast and he sort of decided that if I go and work more on Shipfast,
like the actual product itself, it actually won't make more money or or you know grow.
Shipfast itself is intended to be a simple product.
Even if he if he goes and works on the on the product and makes it better actually makes the product worse because it gets more complicated.
It just it's okay as it is maybe needs a few enhancements every now and then maybe and now he's working on you know his analytics app and that's more of his focus now.
Shipfast still provides a lot of value to its users still makes a lot of sales still is interesting.
It is a useful product and it stands on its own.
I I don't want to say that about the about your current app, but it is a valuable app.
I use it.
I check it every now and then and I see that oh, how many steps I got done.
That's cool.
That's useful.
You mentioned you don't want to have a graveyard of uh, you know, failed projects.
I think the real worst case scenario is you have a graveyard of unshipped projects.
>> But you shipped this, you marketed it, you put it on TikTok, you you did all these things and the results weren't truly product market fit.
And you haven't experienced product market fit before, but it is one I saw a couple comments on your ex post about this too is like when something hits,
it hits and everything makes sense and there's ultimate clarity.
>> So I've I've experienced that a few times in my life and when it happens it's it's amazing and it makes you rethink all your previous projects before.
There's a healthy balance of like actually shipping stuff and like knowing what it's like to not have something that really hits and then have something that really hits.
So, you still have to ship things and put it out there.
But, I think it's okay that you have a really cool app that you build.
Maybe you make a little tweaks on it and improvements.
You add the pay walls just like you're doing now.
You talk to users.
You do all these things.
But, it's okay to try some other things, too.
>> Yeah, that's really good.
Yeah, I think I think this all this is like first timer stuff.
I think that's what I feel is like I really feel like a beginner still even though I I uh you know,
made a lot of progress and whatnot.
Yeah, everything you're saying is like really helpful.
just like maybe I make a few tweaks and do something else or maybe I what you said there about like it's not a graveyard of products.
It's unshipped stuff and I think that's I think that's a really helpful way of putting it cuz I've done that before too a little bit.
It was like I made some stuff when I was just playing around with cursor and stuff and I never published it.
I never shared it.
I just kind all these folders of things that I kind of half made.
So yeah, I think that's a good way of saying it.
And that there's an interesting point that I mentioned there as well is if you never ship it,
you never give it the time or the space or the breathing room to take off.
But because you shipped the walking app, you got it in the app store, you did app store optimization,
you added pricing, you started creating Tik Toks about it and this whole thing, it's okay to just shift your focus to something else for a little bit.
Let that breathe.
People will still use it.
It's still valuable.
They'll still share with their friends.
It still may grow slowly.
It's kind of like SEO, like you create the articles and then maybe it takes six months for them to rank.
You're still giving it that breathing room.
You still have it in your bio on X.
People still use it and love it.
And then maybe it just needs a little bit of time away in your head where you can come back to it,
but it's still alive.
If it was unshipped, that would be a real problem.
But because it was shipped, you got that learning.
You experience, oh, this was good about it.
This was bad about it, but it's still out there.
And I think that like that's nothing to be ashamed of.
Even if you have lots of projects, there's just every single time you ship one, you actually ship it.
you give yourself another chance to see what truly product market fit feels like.
>> That was a free therapy session brought to you by Pat Walls and Starry.
>> I don't have I don't have all the answers.
Uh I can only just share from personal experience and and you know, we talked to a lot of founders on the channel.
I see this a lot and I talk to a lot of people that are still trying to figure it out.
So hopefully it's helpful.
Take some time to think about this, but walk me through kind of what you're thinking about next steps.
What what are you going to try next?
What does the next month?
What does it look like for the rest of the great lock in of 2025?
>> Yeah, first I need to lock in.
So, second is um yeah, I think I'm probably going to I want to make a few more tweaks that I kind of have in in process and then put it leave it at a place where I feel like really good about it.
And then I think I'm going to continue making Tik Toks.
It's like not that hard to make that's just like lowkey promoting it and then um like you said,
I think like let it breathe a little bit.
I think I probably need that personally just to get a little bit out of my head with this and then start thinking about the next thing,
you know, the ne I have I have so many ideas of stuff I want to build and I kind of want that like feeling again of like,
okay, we're doing this again, bringing something to life, making content about it.
I think I want to spin off my own little YouTube channel just all about like building and my process of that.
So, I think that's what's next.
Let letting this live a little bit and see and creating more stuff, you know, creating a more more portfolio of like my shipped apps and stuff.
I like mobile.
I like building in mobile.
I don't know, maybe it's just cuz it's the first thing I did.
I feel like a little bit that's kind of what I want to keep doing.
I tried to build some web web stuff and I feel super lost in that for some reason.
>> Um, so maybe I'll stick to mobile for a little bit, but we'll see.
>> No, I think I think mobile's cool cuz most >> people in our space are shipping web apps.
It's definitely a more advanced skill actually shipping in mobile.
So, I would definitely keep doing that.
You built up those skills.
The last thing that I would I think is a cool way to think about things is like you creating Tik Tok videos even if it's about an app that you failed or whatever uh is still
valuable to the Gus world, right?
You have this brand that you're building.
You're creating content about shipping apps.
You're doing all these things.
You have this this app that you've already shipped.
This is all building into something bigger.
When I think of Mark Lou, like he's got all his apps, he's got his brand, he's got his YouTube channel,
he's got all these things.
Even if you create some Tik Tok videos, it's still building up this kind of world and this,
for lack of a better word, personal brand for you.
And I think that that's that's the right way of thinking about things.
How can I ship an app and create an app, but also create audience at the same time?
So even if this app fails or doesn't work out or doesn't isn't this huge success, I'm still building value through audiences,
mobile apps, like you said, like this is the right way to think about building things in 2025.
Building in public, sharing everything.
You're doing everything exactly right.
just not going to happen overnight, >> man.
Pat, I want to I want to be overnight success, man.
I got bills to pay.
I got a new kid at home.
I need like a million bucks tomorrow.
>> Well, you should try drop shipping.
That could be good for you.
>> Thank you guys for watching.
This has been the Starter Story podcast.
Put your thoughts in the comments of what you think Gus should do.
There's no right or wrong answer.
U should he keep building his app?
Should he build multiple apps?
Should he just create content?
I don't know.
Put it in the comments.
Let us know what you think.
Thanks for watching, guys.