Welcome to the breakdown where in just 6 minutes I will break down a real app that made $90,000 in its first year.
What's even crazier is that this app was started by a solo developer from India with zero funding.
This app right here shows the power of building software and apps and AI right now.
And I found this in the starter story database and I really wanted to share it because I think the story is awesome and there's a ton we can learn from it.
So welcome to the breakdown.
In six minutes, I'll cover one, the idea, two, how they validated it, three, how they built it and how you could do the same,
and four, how they grew it and scaled it to thousands of users.
So, stick with me for the next 6 minutes.
We're going to learn a ton.
Welcome to the starter story breakdown.
This is infography right here.
It was started by this guy named Manoj from India.
And this business made $40,000 in 5 months and then made over $90,000 in its last year.
And I have the proof right here.
Manoj sent me this on X, a screenshot of his revenue, $94,000 in the last year with this business.
What does this app do?
You might be thinking, well, this is an app that turns a blog post into an infographic.
Really, really cool idea and quite simple, but you can check it out for yourself.
So, number one, how did he find the idea?
Let's go check that out in the starter story case study right here.
He found the idea by solving a personal problem.
And what's even more interesting about that is he found this idea while building another business.
He was building a business.
He was struggling to get marketing working.
Then he did an infographic.
It sort of worked.
And then he realized that that was actually a better business than the business he was working on.
He experienced a painful problem in his original business and then he pivoted to build a solution that solves that problem because he knew that lots of other businesses could probably use that solution.
That is the first big takeaway of why I love this story is that a lot of people are looking for ideas.
They want to search for ideas or have someone on YouTube give them a bunch of ideas.
Well, the best way to find ideas is to actually just go and build something and experience problems and you'll probably find tens if not hundreds of ideas by
doing that.
Go build something, see what happens and I guarantee you'll find something interesting.
Okay, let's go to step two.
Validation.
How did Bonoj validate this idea?
Well, I have this right here in the case study.
And I think this is a super great lesson right here, but he validated it with a weight list.
To validate this idea, Manoj created a weight list and shared it on subreddits, receiving substantial feedback and interest.
And here's what's especially interesting about this.
We haven't talked about how he built this and then validated it because he didn't actually build it.
He validated it before he built it.
And I did some digging and I found the actual Reddit post where he validated this idea.
Is this product worth building in the r/startup idea subreddit?
Hey there, I'm building a tool blah blah blah.
Would love your help to figure out if it's something you'd find valuable and use and maybe even pay for.
Check out the details below and join the weight list for early access.
By doing this strategy around a few different subreddits in a few different places, he was able to get 1,400 page views within 24 hours and
over 150 users joined the weight list.
Then he even added a pre-order option to his weight page and some people even started buying the product right there before it even existed.
That is the power of launching with a weight list before you actually build something.
I have this post right here that has a bunch of weightless examples.
It's simple.
You put your title there, what you're building, name, email, and have people sign up.
That is a way to validate your idea before you even build it.
Three, the build.
How did actually build something like this?
Well, admittedly, I don't know exactly what tech stack he used, but I will show you how you can build something like this and how it's relatively simple.
So, here's the app right here.
You just dump in a bunch of text.
You click generate and it gives you an infographic.
To prove to you that this is relatively simple, I like to go to chat GBT and just do the same thing.
So, I'll dump a whole blog post into ChatgBT, ask it to give me an infographic, and boom,
here you go.
These are pretty good and honestly really good.
The reason I wanted to do that is to show you that an app like infography is really just an AI wrapper.
It uses some sort of LLM API.
It makes these calls inside of a web app.
It gives you a place to save them, generate a bunch of them, and hopefully with a little bit of prompting wizardry.
It makes the infographics better than what you get at a chat GBT.
That's why people would pay for it.
This is something that you could definitely build with AI tools, for example, lovable and is definitely something that you can build inside the starter story build AI accelerator where in 12 days,
you'll come up with an idea, you'll build it with AI tools, and you launch it to the real world.
An AI wrapper like this that does image generation, has a database, a few other things is definitely something you could build inside the AI accelerator and we'll help you do that.
Number four, growth.
How did Manoj grow this product?
Once he built it, how did he actually get customers?
Well, I have three things to share with you.
The first one right here is a Product Hunt post that got 634 upvotes and lots and lots of comments.
Product Hunt is a great place to launch your business and get in front of early customers.
I'm not sure it's going to lead to thousands and thousands of dollars, but it's a great way to get early feedback on your product.
What I also thought was interesting is that they had multiple product launches.
They had a V2 and a V3.
And the second marketing strategy that I noticed was affiliate marketing.
I went on their website, there was a link to become an affiliate.
Basically, how affiliate marketing works is someone sells or promotes your product and they get a cut of that.
The third marketing strategy that I thought was pretty interesting was this lifetime deal that they did.
They partnered with this platform called lifetime.com where basically they have an audience where they sell lifetime deals of the infography software.
So you don't have to pay monthly.
You can buy it for one-time price and you're able to do a bulk amount of sales and make a bunch of sales by going through this life platform because typically they have subscription pricing.
This is a great way to get cash infusion of the business.
Okay, that's it.
That was the breakdown.
In just a few minutes, I showed you how one simple AI app made over $90,000.
And we went over how they found the idea, how they validated it, how they built it, and how they grew it.
If you enjoyed this new format, let me know in the comments.
I hope to be doing a bunch more of these.
And if you're looking to build something similar, check out Starter Story Build, where we'll help you come up with an idea like this,
build it in just a few days, and ship it to the real world.
See you next one.