Okay, welcome to another episode of the Starter Story podcast, which comes out every Friday.
In this episode, we talked about our challenge projects.
Gus is working on the $1 challenge, where he is documenting himself building an app with the goal of making $1,
which we talked all about, and I'm doing the 100K builder challenge, and I'm documenting the process of going from zero to making 100K using only AI tools.
In this episode, we talked about the challenges of building in public, how scary it is to actually launch something,
and we gave a bunch of updates on our projects, what's working, what's not.
I think you guys are going to enjoy this episode.
All right, let's kick it off.
I know you've been on a little bit on vacation coming from sickness.
Yeah.
But yeah, I thought it was a good time to get some updates on how this stuff is going.
So, yeah, I started sort of my what we're coining so far as like dollar challenge, which feels so like small,
but it's been kind of interesting and fun.
So I'm I'm excited to talk about that and then obviously hear hear how things are going on your end.
Yeah.
Well, let's hear I mean you have posted Yeah.
on X.
You started building in public on X.
You probably got some followers there and you posted a pretty big video on YouTube.
So tell me how what you did, how far you are.
Yeah.
Let me jump into let me just share my posts.
So the the first kind of reflection is just like I'm stopping and starting honestly like feels like I got some momentum.
I stopped for a while.
had some stuff happen in my life, so I'm kind of ramping up again.
But the first thing I posted on Twitter got probably more views than I usually get.
I have a pretty small audience there.
So, let me share my screen and share this post here.
I'll share a few of these.
So, this first one I a couple weeks ago, we talked about some other folks that are building in public that we admired and I was like,
why not just like copy their format?
And so, I did like a day one post.
I was like, "Hey, day one, I'm building this thing."
I try to be a little honest about like, "Hey, I don't know what I'm doing.
I'm asking Chad GBT to blah blah blah."
And then a little hack that I probably got me more views than I expected was tagging some people.
I tagged you.
I tagged Jack Fris.
I tagged this other person that was Well, not to stop you there, but we just did a a video with someone who runs a business that makes $6 million a year,
and that was his first strategy, right?
Oh, you're right.
for his post, his day one post, he tagged like different AI tools.
Yeah.
And he also tagged like some people in the space and he said that like we're like, "Okay,
how did why did this blow up?"
And that was like his number one reason.
Yeah.
I didn't even think about that, but you're totally right.
And so that's an easy way, I think, to like I don't know, it's it's maybe it's a little cheap or cheating.
I don't know how you want to call it, but an easy way to like, hey, someone with a bigger audience than me might see this and might repost it,
which you know, in this case, you did.
And I think Jack commented as well.
Well, that's the thing is I have, you know, over 100,000 followers on Twitter.
I'm probably I kind of mostly have blocked Twitter, so I don't really look at it that much,
but I will always get a notification if I'm tagged in something.
And honestly, I don't get tagged on a whole lot of stuff.
So, if I get tagged in something, even if you have one follower or zero followers, I'm probably going to see it.
I'm probably going to like it.
And if it's cool and if it's good, I'm probably going to retweet it.
And then that could be the real game changer, right?
Yeah.
Yep.
100%.
So yeah, I think that really helped obviously get this.
I mean, it only had like, you know, 1,200 views, but you know, I don't even have 1,200 followers.
Nice.
And got some cool comments, you know, hell yeah, you know, it's awesome.
How far did you get?
Let's go.
You know, pretty pretty like cool thing.
Some bots, you know, obsessed with the journey.
But I would say like the feeling I had after posting this was like I mean it was kind of twofold.
It was like this is exciting.
It's cool that that's kind of the probably the like hit of whatever adrenaline or something that you get when you get some attention on stuff where you're like,
"Oh, this feels good."
Like people are commenting.
People think I'm cool.
How many times did you check it?
Oh, that's that's funny that you asked that.
Let's just say embarrassingly amount.
We're just like, "Oh, let me see the little blue dot, the little notification tool.
It's a little hit, right?"
I think the other side of it was just like feeling like now now you're like, "Oh, man.
Now I have to do this."
Yeah.
And so it's like this two and it's not like oh man cuz I want to do it but it's just like oh are there people watching?
Are there people expecting it?
Blah blah blah.
So I can probably say more about that.
I'm sure you can too.
But it's just more it's this feeling of like oh dude like now it feels like I have to live up to this and am I I don't know what I'm doing.
Like people shouldn't be following me in this stuff.
That's kind of how that feels now.
You it feels like you're on the hook.
I think that that's like a little secret tactic to shipping something.
It reminds me of when I first started Starter Story many many years ago is that just the idea of having a newsletter and saying,
"Hey, I send out weekly updates on Tuesday."
I had to get more content means I got more ideas for features or whatever.
I had to get sponsors and then all a sudden it's snowballing and I and I've sent 52 newsletters in a year or more.
or what I don't remember the numbers but then I had a business like and that's all because I said hey I'm going to commit to this thing which is posting every
week or whatever for sure and I think that's like what I want to do but you know so let's let's go to my second post this was on May 17th and this is it's now June 2nd this was on May 20th you
know I still had some momentum and I was like hey you know I'm building this thing and then basically the thing I built was just shitty I I I uh I talk about a little bit and we'll talk about
it again when I bring up the YouTube video, but this is like a mobile app I'm trying to make and I'm just like clearly lost,
you know, and this guy commented,"This is the MVP of the MVP.
This is going to go."
So, and and you know, it's funny.
I'm hooked.
Can't wait to see more.
And you're comment where's day three, you know?
I'm just like, gosh, like keep going or whatever, you know?
And uh at this point, I'm still feeling like a lot of momentum.
I'm feeling like okay, I think I can do this.
I think let's see how this goes.
And then, you know, just stuff happened in my life that really paused me from being able to like,
you know, get some stuff done.
So, this is May 20th and then next thing I know, I'm going to scroll up a little bit.
It is June 2nd and I like posted two later.
That's okay.
I mean, yeah.
Yeah.
Two weeks later is look.
And did that get did I get some likes?
Yeah, a few.
Got 150 views.
Not as much.
Got some comments for some people, including yourself.
This guy, I've been following this guy.
He's he has decent following.
And I was just like, "Okay, I'm starting over."
You know, day 0.01 of building blah blah blah.
I'm starting over.
Here we go.
Yep.
So, the app looks a lot cooler.
Yeah, it looks a lot better.
Drew some inspiration from some other apps that I can talk about as well.
That's the building in publicish right now.
You feel like you're on the hook.
Like even though life happened and a bunch of crazy stuff happened, you still came back 12 days later and posted.
It wasn't every day.
And that's okay.
you, but you probably felt some sort of like nagging like like, okay, I got I got to post that thing.
Okay, I don't have time today or the next day.
I got to show up and I got to do it.
Maybe that's the secret to why building in public works for so many people that if you didn't have that,
it could have been years.
Totally.
Yeah, that's that's a great point.
Yeah, I did have a nagging feeling of like, oh man, I should really update this.
I should really do this.
I should really work on this.
I should blah blah blah, which is why I came back to it, you know?
So, yeah, I think that's a great point.
That's like the pro I think of building in public if if that's something you want to do is you're going to feel this like accountability of sorts.
Yeah.
So that's kind of that's where that's at in terms of the building in public so far.
Cool.
Yeah.
The second thing I wanted to touch on is and this is fresh hot off the press.
So if you're watching this go watch that video.
Let me go to that channel first.
We I you know on the on the star on our star story build channel this very channel.
I just posted a new video.
It's already got some views.
Yeah, it's got some views.
35 minutes ago, 250 views.
This is me looking feeling awkward kind of giving a little intro.
Really good on camera, I thought.
Yeah.
Thanks.
It felt a little a little uneasy, but yeah.
So, we just posted this video.
You know, obviously we're talking in the a couple videos ago, we talked about the you challenging me to build and so I was like,
let's create let's do a video, you know, and uh started getting some comments, things like this.
One of these made me laugh.
I can lend you the dollar.
Like, thanks, dude.
You can always count on some troll in there.
Yeah.
Any this guy, thanks for being realistic.
Pat should have started off with the $100 challenge.
Apparently Gus is the smart one.
Thanks.
You know, rising the ranks here.
But anyway, I think the the idea or the brief thing I want to talk about here was like that it was I mean,
in a similar way, like posting this now feels like, oh, now I got to do a day two, you know,
or an episode two and eventually three all the way up until, you know, whatever thing happens next.
I don't actually know where it's going to go.
Yeah.
And so, yeah, I think you're right.
And that trick you can trick yourself on for building in public is to, you know, post publicly,
feel that accountability.
Even if it's realistically who's watching me, probably not that many people, you know,
I have 800 followers on Twitter.
That's about it.
Yeah.
But there there still feels like a twinge of like, okay, I should do this for maybe there's one person out there,
maybe just for myself to like complete this challenge.
Yeah.
got to have some sort of motivation like in all aspects of life whether it's like I don't know even going to college like not flunking out you're motivated by impressing your parents or your peers or
whatever to actually finish the exam and pass and all these things when you're building online you have to find that motivation because I think a lot of people there is no public accountability
if I fail nobody knows and that feels good but that actually will lead to like almost like a 100% failure Right.
Right.
Oh man.
Yeah.
I mean the amount of times that I've over the years have been like I'm going to do this,
I'm going to do that and just sort of worked on it by myself or whatever.
You know, I have a graveyard of things that just never took off or never went off the ground or domains I bought that never went anywhere because I I I didn't I felt like,
okay, I guess I could just let this go.
It's just me anyway.
Yeah.
Whereas here, you know, we're on this channel.
We've been building this channel up, you know, trying to build online presence up, etc.
This feels a little more like, okay, there's some stakes now.
Yeah.
You got you got to have that.
You got to have like even Michael Jordan like when he was the best in the world.
He had to like make up reasons to want to win, right?
Like that famous like you would find like waiters that like pissed him off or something like that and that would be his fuel to win.
Like you have to have something.
And a lot of people build in silence and there's nothing, right?
Yeah.
And even talking about this, right, when this episode comes out, I'm going to be like,
"Okay, now I got to continue."
And next week or two weeks from now, another update.
And you're like, "Okay."
Yeah.
Got to keep going.
That's kind of where my project is at in terms of the actual app itself.
It sucks.
Let's see.
Somewhere in this is somewhat working on your phone like you have it at or even a prototype or something or No.
Yeah.
So, I guess I'll go back to this which I the prototype is like this.
I don't, you know, not that I'm getting too technical at all, but you can load the app on cursor.
You can take a, you can kind of make it run on a server and then you can see kind of how it's working.
Yeah.
So, like kind of Yeah.
It's not like actively tracking my steps right now, things like that.
But I think I'll get there.
Yeah.
There's a lot of, you know, there's more I could talk about, I'm sure, but it's just like it feels good to to post about this and talk about it.
And it also feels a little like, oh you know, now I got now I gotta post about it and talk about it,
you know.
So yeah, that's kind of that that's where that's at.
I can't wait to see day two or whatever day you are on on whatever platform.
But uh I'm excited to see it.
Yeah, I mean me too.
But yeah, so that's kind of that's where my projects are at.
I hope I hope more than anything for for my version of this challenge is that there's people out there that are watching that are super beginners,
you know, that follow people online and they're like, "Oh, I can never do that."
That they'll get a little bit of like, "Oh, that seems like a normal dude, and I really am."
And so maybe that'll hopefully push them to do it, too.
Yep.
Yeah.
So that's the $1.
You only have to get one customer.
So, I think it's I think it's good to do the $1 challenge because once you get that $1,
you're going to upgrade to the 10K and then and then that'll be the next step.
That's a big jump, Pat.
One to 10K.
How about 100?
Okay, we could do 100 and then I'll do hunch challenge.
Then I'll do the 500.
We talked about that in the last building in public episode, I think, which was yeah,
just keep upgrading the challenge and because you always want to keep bringing people along to the journey and one to 100 is there's different things you're going to need to learn.
100 to 1,000, you're going to learn different things and etc.
So, I'm I'm I'm trying to figure out how to go, you know, from the 100K to a million,
wherever we are.
If we're talking about starter story or we're talking about this app, there's always new things to learn in every journey,
which I think is cool.
Yeah.
So, that's my What about you?
All right.
Well, if you're watching this today, I've kind of come out and announced kind of or not announced,
but I'm kind of changing up how I'm going to be building stuff.
Going to be building a lot more.
I want to learn how to use these AI tools to build way faster and kind of automate the build process.
I think in in the age that we're in right now is you can just build stuff so easily that yeah,
why not just build as much stuff as possible?
And I think eventually in a few months or a couple years, I'm going to be able to have AI agents that are like shipping features for these apps,
too, which is super cool idea.
And I just want to like get in there and like learn all this stuff about AI coding.
I've learned a lot through the challenge, and this has been cool.
But I guess, yeah, if you're watching this by now, I've already shipped my second product in the 100K challenge.
You can go to Startertory Labs, labs.starterstory.com.
I actually created like a dashboard where you can see the progress so far.
Doing a little bit better than the $9 that I made with the thumbnail app, which is it's starting to grow.
I starting to get customers.
Made over $100 now.
So, I'm feeling good that that's going to keep growing.
I don't know.
What else do you want to know?
I want to know.
So, every time we've posted a video on the YouTube channel, we got a mix of comments,
right?
Some are like, "This is awesome."
Some are like, "This sucks."
And others are.
It's all over the place.
After releasing that video, how that felt.
I was on vacation at the time when the video came out.
And I was like super nervous to release that video because it was like the first unveiling of like the the failure or whatever or the you know you have the
ambitions to make 100k.
It's so exciting and you think you're going to get there and people following along like how is he going to do it and you come out with the video that it made $9.
And I sort of expected that that was going to happen as I continue to develop just knowing like okay this is going to be a lot harder than I thought.
Yeah, but yeah, even when the video was coming out, I was on vacation and I was checking the comments on the YouTube video.
And I hate that I did that because I was like way too concerned with, you know, what people were going to say.
And I'm My whole the whole thing with this challenge is that I'm trying to document the real process and not take shortcuts.
Yeah.
That will either piss people off or like have to delete comments or like do something fake like Yeah.
So, I h I knew that I was going to fail.
I sort of expected I was going to fail and I wanted to document that failure process completely even though it could you know the objection will be like why the hell
would I join starter story or you know build stuff if you not even you can do it right I knew that people were going to say that but I'm not trying to be one of those like influence like this or
people building stuff online that would never do something like this because it opens up the the reality of what it actually takes to build stuff online and how you can't just build a project in 5
minutes and have it make money.
Like everybody knows this.
There's a lot of people online selling business models and these sorts of things that make it seem like you can do that.
So then that's like this content is showing the real truth versus this other content I can go watch and I can see this person make a million dollars overnight or whatever when that's all fake.
Yeah, for sure.
I do want to prove it.
I know that I'm going to prove it.
And one of the rules of the challenge is that I can't give up until I make 100K cuz that's one of the big way I I know that will be the way that it gets proven.
is by not giving up, not by some, you know, genius idea or something like that.
It's like just going to take time.
And if you watch the theme of that video is around patience.
And that's actually like the big learning is okay, I made basically nothing.
When I first launched the product, I opened up my Stripe a week later, depressed, not even thinking,
and all of a sudden I had a bunch of sales.
I had like over 10 sales in the app, and I was like, "Oh, right.
It doesn't happen on that first tweet, right?
Some I posted, someone probably thought about it 10 days later and they came and they signed up for the app and they tried it out,
right?
Every single Starry video that we've done with people like that, it's always this sort of like it takes time.
It doesn't happen overnight.
And like I think the kind of the point also of building cooler small projects like this is that they grow slowly.
Like SEO is a good example of that.
Like you can build something, you can launch it, you can almost completely forget about it and then all of a sudden it can start getting sales 6 months later.
I think we've talked to a lot of people.
I don't think we ever talked to someone that's like, "Oh, it's an overnight success."
It's more like it's cool to like build something and then it can it just kind of slowly it's a compound.
It's a compound interest, right?
It's like invest investing by putting in your time and building something and spending hours building something really cool and you've already put in that work.
You put in that time.
now go work on something else and kind of just forget about it because if you are if you're impatient about it and then you just shut it down and oh,
it's never going to work.
Well, you may have given up that opportunity for it to make money a little more slowly,
right?
For sure.
Yeah.
No, I Yeah, I think that's I mean, going back to some of the stuff I was saying, I feel like Yeah,
it feels like for the in the past when I've given up on projects, a big piece of that has been because I didn't wait I didn't like try long enough.
Yeah.
Yeah, you know, like or I tried for whatever, you know, probably less than a month, but let's say a month.
I was like, "Oh, it didn't work and I'm just going to shelf it, you delete it, delete the project."
And I don't know.
I think that's a little bit different than what you like the antithesis to what you're saying,
which is like build it and like kind of let it let it play out a little bit, you know?
And that's part of the thing that also works when you start if you want to and what what I want to do is I want to build a lot of different things,
but they all sort of build on each other, too.
So let's say I have the the business name generator that just came out.
Now I may go build the let's say I don't know like a logo generator or something like that,
right?
Like literally the business name generator can link to the logo generator which drives customers but also it may use a lot of the same code or I may have learned a lot about you for something like that.
So I can reuse that.
So they're all building on each other to a it I can do them faster.
I know the customer better, but also they can actually send customers between them.
That's like, yeah, you can go build a bunch of random stuff, but for you, maybe you build the walking app empire where you have a walking app and then you have a running app or you have a walking blog.
Like these are like if there's compounding there, too.
But also, if you're someone like like us where it's like you don't really want to like pick one thing,
you want to like work on that's why I like starter story as a media company.
You get to work on different videos, get to talk to different people, you kind of have this ADHD around building things.
Yeah, that that can work if you do like building lots of different apps but in the same space can really work I think.
Yeah, that's a funny way of saying it.
Just like kind of and I think I feel like a lot of people relate to that.
Just like sh like not it's not a shiny object syndrome exactly, but it's a little like I want to do multiple things and I feel that like I want to do not just one thing and uh yeah so it's like a balance
right of like not jumping too fast but also like just knowing yourself and I want to try bunch stuff like it's more interesting for me keeps me interested.
Yeah.
The key though is finishing I think and that's what a lot of people miss.
Okay, you can try a lot of things, but if you aren't finishing anything and putting out into the world and getting some feedback,
then the feedback you're never building at that point, right?
And that I think a lot of people watching this could could relate to that.
Let me ask you this question.
Did you finish it?
Did you finish that app?
Is it live in the world right now?
Did it get some users?
Can be just one user.
That's fine.
If that's not the case, then you can't be working on different things.
Yeah, that's a great point for sure.
And I'm probably more on the camp of where like I just never finished it, but I want that to be different on this one.
It is.
Yeah, it's gonna be different this time.
Hopefully, it will be.
But but yeah, so that's kind of that's a cool update and I'm excited to see I'm excited to see how far this goes.
You know, I do feel like there's some momentum in terms of like the community and stuff like that of people that really like this stuff.
I hope that like they can pick it up too.
Yeah.
And that's the other thing is I'd love anyone watching this, if you're this far into it,
if you want to build stuff or you're already building stuff and documenting the process,
which we can potentially talk about the challenges that come with that in a second, but I would love to be a like maybe we start like a group chat with people that are doing this sort of thing because I want to see more people do it.
Yeah.
Yeah, for sure.
Cool.
Well, you heard it.
So, P.
Walls headstarterstory.com.
If you've watched this far, you know where to catch them.
Yeah.
Cool.
Well, that's kind of everything I want to talk about, I think.
Thank you guys for watching.
Hopefully, you enjoyed this update on the dollar challenge and the 100K challenge.
Let us know in the comments what you want us to cover next.
If there's anything any specific topics around where we can kind of go back and forth on on our experiences building these apps from someone who's a little more beginner and someone who's,
you know, I already have a successful business, but I'm still doing this.
So, there definitely different perspectives there.
Yeah, that's pretty much it.
Thank you guys for watching.
I hope you enjoyed this episode of the Starter Story podcast.
We'll see you next Friday.