All right, we are back for another episode of MicroSAS ideas.
I got my drink here.
I'm ready to go over a bunch of ideas.
Last time we went over three micro SASS ideas.
Today we're going to go over seven.
We're going to do them even faster and we're going to do it a little bit differently.
As you guys know, I love looking at successful businesses and seeing if there's another idea we can remix off of these ideas.
So, that's exactly what we're going to be doing today.
We're going to be looking at successful businesses and then we're going to be using AI to remix these ideas and give you ideas that you can walk away with today.
By the end of this video, we will have seven ideas you can go build right now and I think you'll learn some cool things about how to potentially find more business ideas based on what we're going to go over today.
All right, without further ado, let's jump in.
This is the Micros database inside starter story.
There are hundreds of ideas in here and we are going to start jumping through them right now.
So, I don't want to waste your time.
Let's go to the first one right here, which I like, which is Live Tourney.
Let's click that.
Okay, this is Live Turney.
This is a side project that makes $36,000 a year.
It's not a bajillion dollar business, but it's probably a pretty cool side project that we can learn from.
So, let's check out what this thing does.
First, let's just click on the link to what they do here.
We'll just click live tourney right here, and let's check it out.
Run golf tournaments with live scoring.
And this looks like a SAS for Oh, I think this is really cool.
This is a SAS that golf courses can run to run tournaments, let's say on the weekends or something like that.
So, this helps them potentially drive more revenue by having a tournament with lots of people coming and playing and buying stuff.
And then also, it saves them a bunch of money because they don't have to manually run this with spreadsheets.
It gives them an app and an easy way to run these tournaments and easy easy way for people to sign up for these tournaments.
This is a really cool idea.
I have a suspicion that's making a whole lot more money than $3,000 a month.
But let's check out the pricing and just understand a little bit more about what this is set up.
Oh, interesting.
Okay, so $2700 per year.
That means they probably have about 10 customers at the time that we interviewed them,
which was just over a year ago.
I'm guessing they're they've grown a little bit hopefully.
But 10 to 15 golf courses around the world use this software.
Hopefully they also charge per event, which is pretty cool, too.
That's kind of a smart strategy.
And that's a lot of money, right?
If you think about it, that makes sense because the customer here, this is kind of what's smart.
The customer here is golf courses, which have more money to spend.
They know that if they run tournaments, they're going to make X more dollars.
And they probably only have like one guy running the the pro shop there, so it makes sense.
So, his life is easier, and they don't have to have extra people on hand to help out with their tournaments.
That's cool.
But, I assume you guys probably don't care that much about golf.
If you do, that's awesome.
Let's go take a look at this idea and let's try to remix this idea.
So, I got this little feature here in Starroid called idea remixer, which is really cool.
You can open this up and basically let's try to find what makes this idea successful and and try to remix it and see what kind of ideas it will give us.
So, what I think is interesting about this one is that it's niche down to a specific sport.
So, uh it's not a tournament software for, you know, all sports facilities, right?
It doesn't do everything for Rex sends or something like that.
It just does it for golf.
So, I'm just going to let them know that and say I think what's cool about this is that it's niched down to just golf.
Any other sports this could work for.
And we're going to put this into our AI.
And what's cool about this is that this is taking all the information that we have about this case study,
actual founders submitted data about why it worked with growth channels and all these sorts of things and also is taking place from other sources as well.
Looking at all of our case studies, this is really cool.
So, here's some ideas.
It's going to give me probably like three, four ideas.
We got one for pickle ball.
We got one for hoop score.
I'm guessing uh basketball tournaments.
We got one for eternity esports.
I like that one, too.
That's really cool.
Fortnite, right?
That seems like it could potentially work.
Uh the f the one that I want to just go look at and we'll talk a little bit about here.
Uh obviously you can go uh try this on your own too is pickle ball because that's the first thing that I see cuz I'm a tennis player and I know just how big pickle ball is getting.
That's peing my interest right now.
Why could it work which I really like here?
Pickle ball is exploding in popularity especially with older demographics underserved by tech and with more money to spend.
I actually went to a pickleball tournament I think last year even though I don't even play pickle ball uh regularly.
This stuff is happening everywhere.
There are tournaments all over.
This could be super useful.
So, this is just one way to remix this idea.
There's lots of different ways you could potentially remix this idea.
I think it's cool to look at certain niche sports.
Again, these are micro SAS ideas serving one customer with a very specific solution.
Tournaments for pickle ball.
I think that's a cool idea.
And that's rapid fire.
So, we're going to go to the next one.
All right, let's go to our next idea.
our second idea.
I'm back on the MicroSAS ideas database, which you can click the link in the description if you want to get this.
Let's go for a little bit bigger revenue.
I'm seeing we're in the around 20,000 per month, which is pretty goodiz business at this point.
I like this one right here, data fetcher.
I just hear data fetcher.
That's kind of cool.
Makes me think there's like some sort of API or something like that.
And I'm seeing connect air tableable to any app or API with no code.
I like those words, no code.
I like the word API.
I'm a developer, so that's cool to me.
I want to learn a little bit more about this business.
Let's see.
Okay, so this is data fetcher.
How I built an air table plugin that lets users manage their data better.
Makes $270,000 a year.
That's a pretty good business right there.
One founder, zero employees.
I like this.
I like what I'm seeing right here.
Let's learn a little bit more about this business.
Let's go see what they do.
Data fetcher.
And um this is connect any API to air table without code.
Okay, that's cool.
Data fetcher and I just like to read through this and understand who is the customer here.
What does it do?
Data fetcher is the no code solution for importing API data into air table.
Connect any REST or GraphQL API.
Okay, cool.
The first thing I really like to see here is this is a product that's used by Amazon,
Harvard, Stanford, blah blah blah.
These are real big businesses using this.
That's always a good sign for a microSAS is that it's an app that serves businesses.
And that was what we said in the last one, too.
I'll go to their pricing and see how much they charge here.
It's $30 a month or well, I guess it's $50 a month.
And then they also have annually there.
Cool.
I think that that's a cool little business.
One thing that I think makes this business successful is that it's built on Air Table,
which is a platform that companies use for their first party data.
So, let's say that in Amazon there's some department and they have all their data on Air Table.
that's where all their whole team is going in and out of and updating things, but they want to be able to connect that to something else.
I think that's one of the most important things that this is a platform where the firstparty data is hosted.
So things like notion, Google Sheets, these sorts of things, I think that's important.
So when we go to try to remix this, let's go make sure that we ask it that.
So, I'll go back to my data fetcher here and I'll open up my idea remixer and I'll just let I'll just say that I'll say what I like about this
business is that it's built on air table where bigger I say bigger
businesses use this to manage their data first party
uh what other platforms MS are big businesses
storing their data for their teams to access.
Let's see.
So, that's kind of the the premise of this is where do big businesses store their data for team access?
Because I'm thinking, okay, how can I build something that has a,000 customers charging them $30 a month and that's a really,
really good business right there.
Right?
So that is okay.
We're getting lots of cool things here.
These are all really, really big.
I would probably jump over Google Workspace Google Sheets cuz everybody uses those, but also that could be,
you know, a sign that that maybe is something good to use.
I think building on top of Microsoft could be interesting there.
But again, I want to give you just one specific idea to be able to walk away with here.
And the one that I personally like is probably monday.com.
We actually had partnered with them on a previous video.
They are looking for developers to help build apps on their platform and they are huge.
So let's dive into that real quick.
monday.com uh tell me some more of the numbers on
that and is it under served in terms of
apps?
Um, could I build this
there?
Okay.
And that's what's cool about this uh idea remixer is you can have it dive deeper and deeper into try to really get curious about this idea.
Money.com has 180,000 paying customers and their customer base is 20% enterprise, 42% mid-market.
What that means is big companies are using this.
that potentially could be even more powerful than something like notion, right?
It's just more corpo, which means you can make more money from it.
So, this is actually a really good idea.
I would dive deeper into potentially remixing this idea on monday.com's platform is really not changing a whole lot.
I know based on some information that monday.com is trying to build out their developer ecosystem.
They want more apps.
They want more developers.
And that's where I think there could be an opportunity.
So, that's the second idea.
Let's go to the third idea.
Let's keep going.
Here we are doing these stupid rapid fire.
I see another one that I kind of like here which is app store spy app market intelligence.
I always love stuff that's kind of like based around like yeah intelligence or databases and that sort of thing.
And that kind of reminds me a little bit of what we do at Starter Story.
So I'm going to click on that and see what this app does.
My SAS makes $8,000 a month and helps apps spy on their competitors.
That's cool here.
So u this is cool.
Seems like okay.
Yeah, they take a bunch of apps and they get you a bunch of data on these apps.
Let's go check out what this does.
Find your next big app idea with real-time data from over 15 million apps.
So, they go through the iOS uh app store and the Play Store and they get a bunch of data.
How many reviews?
How many downloads?
How much money are these apps making?
This is a cool idea, especially if you're a data nerd like me.
Let's check out the pricing.
This is $19 a month and $99 a month.
Seems like you don't get a whole lot on that one.
I'm guessing, you know, whenever an app has it highlighted uh as the the most popular uh plan,
that's what they're trying to get most people to to buy.
So, this is cool.
Um I feel like this business is probably making a little bit more money.
We interviewed them almost two years ago.
I bet they're a lot bigger now.
Uh and I'm seeing that they have pretty good traffic here when I checked that out.
So, they are growing and I think that's really, really cool.
Let's figure out what makes this successful.
I don't really know what makes this successful.
And this is another cool thing about our idea remixer is that Starter Story knows we don't necessarily have to know.
So, let's go to our idea remixer.
Let's open this up.
And I don't really have anything to say about this.
I think it's a cool idea.
Uh, go for it.
I'm just going to say, is there anything?
Yeah, it's asking me, should I just get working for you?
Go for it.
Let's see what it has.
And let's see if there's anything cool um that comes up here.
Okay, this there's a couple cool things in here.
I kind of like newsletter spy, but I also I would want to build on a growing platform or space.
I feel like newsletters, just in my opinion, they're maybe not growing as fast as they used to grow.
What's really growing right now, I think apps are really growing right now.
They'll always grow.
But what also is growing is different local markets.
And that's the one I like about this.
This is the remix angle on this one is geography.
So, it's the same idea, but instead obsess over emerging markets because I bet there's a bunch of apps that are growing in Latam,
Africa, and these sorts of things.
So, um I will potentially just ask it and I'll say,"Hey, I like I like idea number four.
What is the fastest growing uh geography for apps right now?"
That's what I want to know.
and India.
That's super interesting and makes a lot of sense.
700 million smartphone users, which is two times bigger than probably the entire US in terms of actual population.
So I imagine that is a really really hot place to build an idea like this.
So not everything needs to be remixed into a different category or whatever.
Sometimes it can just purely be a geography remix and AI coding tools and all these new tools that are coming out right now is making it possible for an actual business to be successful that
just niches down.
Yeah, they have uh you know big apps like App Store
spy or sensor tower which is another big app that gives you uh intelligence.
But what if you just did it for India?
And I think that that could be a kind of cool idea.
Okay, we are back to Microsde ideas.
Let's go to idea number four.
This app is making $10,000 a month.
I like this one here.
Software for sports facilities.
Similar to the first idea we covered.
I love sports stuff.
And especially if you're passionate and have a hobby or something like that, it's cool to build.
You know, building the apps app intelligence thing for India is cool if you're super into data,
but maybe you're into sports.
So, let's check out what this app does.
This is the Swift app right here.
And this is three friends turned a fun side project into 120K per year SAS for sports facility owners.
Okay, what does this thing actually do?
Uh, let's just go check out their website because sometimes that's the easiest way is grow your sports facility on autopilot.
Spend less time on the phone and more time growing your business.
Okay, I see.
Cool.
Industries.
Let's see what kind of industries they cover.
Okay.
So, I see you have a baseball facility or a soccer facility, you know, a rec center or whatever these things are.
This is going to help you manage your memberships, your upgrades, your events, and all these things.
Let's go check out their pricing, which doesn't seem to be on the page.
They don't show their pricing, which is interesting.
I guess you can book a free demo and then potentially go further from there.
Does seem like their traffic is picking up.
It's growing.
And you know, this is a cool SAS.
This is a cool micro SASS that serves clearly small businesses.
I can go and look at, you know, a lot looks like a lot of baseball.
I'm seeing a lot of baseball, maybe batting cages and things like that.
That's so that's pretty cool.
Okay.
I think there are two ways you could potentially remix this before we go into the AI.
One is to go like this is very horizontal.
So they cover baseball and softball and hockey and ice rings.
Those are very different.
You could go niche.
Maybe just build a better hockey and ice rinks one or potentially you can go find a different category that's outside of sports.
Let's try to find that other cate category cuz I'm kind of interested.
What could that be?
Let's go try that.
So, we'll go to our idea remixer right here and we'll say like it seems this business serves lots of sports facilities.
What types of other local facilities or small
businesses could use a platform like
this?
I like this already.
Okay, I like this here.
First one that I kind of like is this kind of kids indoor playgrounds and family centers.
I don't know a whole lot about this cuz I don't have kids, but I imagine that daycares or just any sort of kids facilities.
It's kind of similar to Swift app because they're also serving like you know sports facilities which often is a lot of kids.
But what could be different is this kids indoor playgrounds or family centers.
So, um, party booking, kids gym and trampoline parks and play cafes and, uh, lots of things cuz look,
there's ever people that have kids, they're always looking for things for their kids to do to keep them busy,
whether it's daycare or just, you know, going out to different events or things like that.
So, I'm going to have a dive a little bit deeper on that one.
Let's see.
Um, I like this one right here.
And let's see.
Okay, so I I had to dive a little deeper on this play care one because I really want to know a little bit more about this one.
And we got some really cool stuff here.
I won't go too much into it, but this is the core concept right here, which is a modern booking and management system for indoor playgrounds,
trampoline parks, party centers, and soft play cafes.
I never heard of a soft play cafe, but maybe that's some sort of growing thing.
I would look more into that.
It handles reservations, birthday party bookings, time slot management, parent coms,
digital waiverss, upselling, and all these sorts of things.
It's very similar in nature to what uh Swift app covers.
And I think that could be interesting.
And what's cool about here is also we got a distribution strategy.
This is all based on what worked for this business.
You could potentially go and do it for something else.
Okay, let's keep going.
I told you we're going to do lots of different business ideas here.
Let's go over another one here.
Let's look through this here.
I see.
Okay, this one's cool.
Okay, this one's doing $145,000 a month.
So, this is nearly $2 million per year business.
It is music data analytics.
Let's take a look at the case study here.
How these friends bootstrapped a million dollar per year business out of their love for music.
And I like this sort of stuff because I love to see businesses that aren't just like,
you know, totally boring B2B type things.
This is like built off of a love for sports or music or art and things like that.
I love that sort of stuff.
So, super cool to see people winning in that area.
But let's go check out what song stats does.
Song stats is real time music data and analytics for artists and labels.
And you know, it's kind of similar to the app store idea that we saw is like you just get lots and lots of data.
I love businesses that cover data.
Um, let's see what their pricing is.
Um, it's a little confusing there, but it's €20 per month after the trial.
So, it's a little cheaper than people looking up the app store thing because maybe these are artists.
These are people that are trying to grow their plays on Spotify or or whatever it is.
So, I really like this business.
Let's go take a look again a little bit more at why they were successful.
Uh, interesting.
So they integrate, they give you insights across Spotify, Apple Music, YouTube, Tik Tok,
Instagram, Shazam.
So I imagine that.
Wow.
And they have over 6,000 customers subscribe to Songstats uh and doing over and they're approaching a million dollars in annual recurring revenue.
That's awesome.
We interviewed them about two years ago, so I imagine they're doing even more.
I mean, the first thing that I would look at is their traffic.
Yeah, it's growing and they're doing almost half a million in monthly visits per month.
This is a really cool business.
Let's go and remix it.
So, I kind of like this one because it is a little bit lower market.
It's not just for businesses.
It's for uh artists.
I think that's somewhat interesting.
Music.
So I don't really have crazy thing about what's interesting about this, but I don't really know exactly why this works.
So I'll ask it.
Let's see.
Explain to me why this works and some other ideas uh it could work for.
Okay, so this is cool.
Instead of giving me a bunch of ideas, it's kind of explaining a little bit more about why this thing worked.
And this is the thing that I thought was actually really interesting here.
Visibility is everything in music.
Timely data leads to smarter promotion and career moves.
Songs made it low friction and actionable.
I'm going to plug that in and see what other ideas can be built off of
this.
could capture this truth.
Okay, that's cool.
I got a lot of cool things from here.
Again, the podcasting thing comes up, but I don't really love that idea.
Uh because podcasts are one of those things that are kind of like harder to grow.
Uh but one that I do like here, it's a little bit more niche because there's probably less authors in the world than there are musicians.
However, there are a lot of similar things uh mentioned here is visibility is everything in music.
Timely data leads to smarter promotion and career moves.
Song stats made it low friction and actionable.
So, this is kind of cool.
The other thing that I thought was interesting about uh song stats was that uh there's lots of different platforms where it wants to get all of its data.
with this idea is kind of cool because you could track uh features, reviews, everything about all about your books across all different
platforms, Amazon, Goodreads, Wattpad, and so on and so forth.
Why it could work?
Indie self-pub authors struggle to see their growing impact as data is fragmented.
This is like a Fitbit drive smarter promotion, celebratory moments, and fan engagement.
So, I really like that one.
If we can if you can niche down and do something similar, but for authors, this is all data you can get across of all other places.
And I think this could be a small little niche way to carve out that same idea.
Look, that's not a business that's going to become a million dollars overnight, but it's a cool SAS business that I think will grow for a long time.
There will always be authors and people writing books, and it takes advantage of that visibility is everything,
which is really, really important for authors, especially big ones.
And for the final idea, I thought we were going to get to seven ideas today, but that might have been a little too ambitious.
So, we're just going to do one more idea here.
I'm going to scroll through this.
Let's find a big daddy.
Something that is making a bunch of money.
And let's see what we can find here.
So, this one looks cool.
Pre-render.io io allows search engines to crawl SEOfriendly versions of React, Angular,
and JavaScript website.
This makes $220,000 a month.
Crazy.
That's huge.
2.5 million a year nearly and $0 to start this 86 solarreneur score.
This is badass.
This one is awesome.
One founder, four employees.
That is a very, very profitable business.
This case study is a little bit old, but I wanted to share this one because I think why this works actually is the most important thing.
So, pre-render.io, if I go check out what this thing does, get your JavaScript website crawled,
indexed, and found.
Basically, what this does is if you have a website built on a JavaScript framework, Google struggles to crawl your website,
which can hurry your SEO.
And this is a no-brainer solution that businesses will pay for because uh SEO is really really important.
Do I think you should copy this business now or remix this and do it for a different language or something like that?
Probably not.
But I think the reason why it was successful is actually the reason uh of what is actually what we can use to find another idea.
Again, I'm going to go to the pricing on this one.
They're charging $290 a month and they have usagebased pricing.
Super smart.
But let's go and remix this idea.
So let's check this.
Here we are remixing pre-render.io.
And I'm going to just say that what we said is what I think is interest what I think made this
successful is that was built on a growing trend.
JavaScript frameworks and it solved a new problem that these frameworks created.
Now I want you to analyze it in that
lens.
What is the big new growing trend in web technologies and what
problems could be solved with similar businesses?
Okay, there's some cool ideas here.
And actually, I think this one is really, really cool because it hits on a pain point for me.
So, this is the remix angle of this is a different is carving out the audience and a feature and building on the growing trend,
which is AI.
So, the oneliner behind this app is that it's a plug-and-play firewall for web apps that use LLM.
So, chat bots, AI forms, this chatbot that you're looking at right here could use this.
It monitors prompts.
It blocks abuse and it logs user and AI interaction.
Right?
Just as uh single page apps needed SEO fixes.
Now, every site is slapping on AI features, they're potentially exposing their keys or they're getting their their bills run up like crazy.
This happened to me the other day when I didn't have certain rate limiting feature on my app and I got charged $100 because I have an online presence.
they wanted to troll me and make me spend a bunch of money on an LLM when they weren't actually using the feature.
This could be a really cool idea and I think it does hit on, hey, we will save you money because we'll prevent people from abusing your app and we'll give you,
you know, you'll save money.
Maybe you pay $30 a month for this or $100 a month for something like this, but you'll save a lot of money.
This could be super actually useful for this crazy growing AI trend.
I think that is a super cool idea.
again because the thing that made this grow was that the JavaScript frameworks were going crazy.
There's a lot of growth there.
I don't even need to explain how AI is, you know, the big next growing thing, especially in development,
web development, and that sort of thing.
I think that's a cool idea.
Again, you can go on here and you can remix it in different ways.
I think that's super cool.
So, that's it guys.
That is six Micros.
Hopefully this gave you some ideas how to look at successful businesses and see if they can be remixed in different ways.
There's remixing it for a different niche.
There's remixing it for a different geography.
Went over we went over a bunch of those things.
Hopefully you learned something from this.
If you're looking to build anything in here or you have an idea, please check out Starter Story Build.
You'll take your idea, build it, launch it in just 12 days.
We have our 12day AI build boot camp.
Our whole program is built around it.
You can see the whole syllabus right here if you're serious about building.
I think this is awesome.
The stuff that people are building in here is amazing.
Thank you guys for watching.
I'll see you in the next one.
Peace.