Hi, my name's Pat and this is episode 11 of the 100K build challenge where I'm trying to see if I can make $100,000 using only AI tools.
Quick update for you guys.
My app has now made over $2,500 and I think I might be on to something.
And I also think it might be because of one tough decision I made when starting this project.
And that's what I'm going to be sharing with you today.
But before we get into that, let me remind you of the rules.
Rule one is that I can only use AI tools.
Rule two is I must document everything right here on this channel.
And rule three is that I cannot give up until I make $100,000.
So without further ado, let's dive into episode 11 where I'm going to be sharing with you the dirty little secret I learned the hard way about what it might actually take to build a successful
product online.
Okay, so this story starts a few weeks ago when I was trying to figure out pricing for moat.
How am I going to price this tool?
$5 a month, $10 a month, $30 a month, $10,000 a month.
I honestly had no idea.
So, I did what any smart entrepreneur would do.
I decided to look at the data.
And as you guys might remember, my very first app from the challenge all the way back to episode 1,
well, that was the AI thumbnails generator.
And man, it just gives me PTSD bringing up these dashboards.
But what I wanted to know was what was my conversion rate?
Well, let's dive in.
For people that visited the site and then clicked just to the signup page, that was only 2%.
Which is quite bad.
But then actually, people that subscribed and paid, well, that was 0.1%.
Not 1%.
But onetenth of 1%.
0.1%.
Ouch.
That is not good.
And to make matters worse, it wasn't like the AI thumbnail generator was expensive.
It was $9 a month.
So, what do I do now?
Do I price it even lower?
Do I price it higher?
Do I do yearly subscriptions?
I did not have an answer for this.
And honestly, this was really demotivating.
But everything changed when I got on a call with this guy named Devon.
He's built a cool business that makes over $20,000 a month.
And I was interviewing him for the main Starter Story YouTube channel.
And over and over, he kept talking about this one thing, Lifetime Deals.
And immediately that got the juices flowing for me.
What if I didn't charge a subscription at all and I did a one-time payment lifetime deal?
Would that solve all my problems?
I started looking into this and honestly, I got mixed results.
Some people say they regretted doing lifetime deals while others said it changed their business and it was the best decision they ever made.
There are certainly pros and cons to a strategy like this and honestly, I was a bit skeptical.
Here were my main hesitations.
Number one is that because my product uses LLM APIs which cost money, what would happen if a customer costs more than I actually make from them in terms of revenue.
My second hesitation was if I make all the revenue upfront from then I will lose all future revenue that I can make from that customer as well.
And my third hesitation was regarding support.
As you guys know, I'm a one-man show.
So what if these customers take away all my time from me and bombard me with support and questions?
I wasn't sure if this was the right move.
and I had a lot of thinking to do.
So, I went on a long walk with Bernie and I weighed my options.
And by the time I got home from my walk, I said, "Screw it.
What's the worst thing that could happen?
Let's give this one a try."
So, that's what I did.
I priced my app at $19 for lifetime access.
And within hours, people started buying.
The conversion rate compared to the AI Thumbnails maker was even more staggering.
It skyrocketed.
It was seven times higher than it was in the Thumbnails app.
That's like over a thousand% increase.
I was super excited about that, but I was still unsure how it would impact the business.
Would it still be profitable?
Would I be drowning in support?
Am I shooting myself in the foot by doing this?
Well, over the next few days, I learned and realized a few things that changed my mind on this whole lifetime deal thing.
So, in terms of time, my big hesitation was, how will adding a lifetime deal impact my customer support?
Can I afford to spend 20 hours supporting one customer who paid $19?
Well, then I realized early on that's the wrong way to think.
If one person buys your product and actually uses it, that's gold.
You're not losing 20 hours.
You're investing 20 hours into learning what customers need, fixing their problems, and getting your product closer to product market fit.
In fact, the scarier situation is the opposite.
someone pays you or never pays you at all, never uses the tool and quietly leaves.
That means no feedback, no retention and no growth.
At the beginning, you should want people who use the product so much that they need your time and support and ask you questions.
The second hesitation was around costs.
What if a customer ends up costing me more in LLM API usage than the $19 I made from them?
Well, the truth is that very few customers will ever use it forever at 100% capacity.
Most lifetime buyers just want to tinker, try the tool, or use it for a single project.
And over time, usage naturally drops off just like with any product in the world.
Devon, the guy I talked to, he said that only a tiny fraction of his lifetime customers are still active.
That's not a failure.
That's just how lifetime deals work.
Think of it as a one-mon subscription paid upfront with some people sticking around longer.
The economics usually balance out.
The third hesitation I had was around revenue losses.
If I take lifetime payment upfront, I'll lose all future subscription revenue from that customer.
Well, the truth is I realized that I wasn't locking myself into lifetime forever.
The priority right now is not in maximizing LTV.
It's about getting momentum with this product, getting users feedback, a little bit of cash,
and social proof.
Later, I can switch to subscriptions, raise prices, and change the model.
Sure, those lifetime buyers will get grandfathered in because without them, I probably wouldn't have been able to get this product off the ground in the first place.
Right now, it's not about the sales.
Customers are giving me feedback.
They're telling me what they like, what's broken, and what features they want next.
That feedback is worth way more than the few thousand dollars I've made so far with the project because I know I'm building something for the long run.
Something that will make tens or hundreds of thousands of dollars per month eventually.
And I want to get there by building a great product.
And I will not get there if I don't get feedback from actual customers.
So, with all of this, I realized that a lifetime deal for me right now is actually the move.
I tried it.
It's working.
So, I'm going to keep doing that.
And here's my plan.
I started with lifetime deals to validate and get momentum.
And as I add more features, I will slowly raise that lifetime price over time.
And then eventually, when it feels right, I will transition the product to subscriptions.
But right now, $19 is a no-brainer buy, especially considering other products cost more than $19 a month.
And with Moat, you get a database of proven social media templates that you can use right now.
That makes that $19 price a no-brainer.
As I continue to get feedback and at the end of the day, I realized just because other people are doing subscriptions,
that doesn't mean that I have to do it.
I dropped my ego and realized that lots of other businesses do this lifetime thing, so there must be a reason for it.
That's why I tried it.
It worked and I'm going to keep doing that right now.
So, if you're building anything or planning on launching anything soon, consider starting with a lifetime deal.
Get a few people to pay you something and use that momentum to keep building and build something great.
This has been episode 11 of the 100K build challenge.
Thank you guys for watching and let me know in the comments what you think about lifetime deals.
Would you buy one?
I'll see you in the next one.