Let's be honest, nobody really cares about your project or what you're building or what you're doing online.
So, the question is, how do you get people to care?
The best answer that I can give to that is build in public.
You've heard of this before, but you probably see people talking about on Twitter that have huge audiences.
What about the people that are starting from scratch right now, building public the right way?
The people that don't have huge audiences, they're building simple things and they're figuring it out along the way.
That's what we're going to be covering today.
A couple people who are crushing it, building in public right now that you have never heard about.
We're going to be going over their posts, what's working, how they do it with basically no audience so you can copy them and do the same to get attention on your products,
make money, and build a business that changes your life forever.
Welcome to the Starter Story podcast.
Let's go.
Cool.
Well, welcome back.
I was um I've been following these two people, which is why I wanted to talk about it today.
um that I think will give you whoever's watching this like some really good examples of if you're building something how to like get attention on it.
Something you always talk about Pat is like uh just because you build it doesn't mean they're going to come and I think that's a big thing that new founders need to hear.
So I have two examples that I think are really cool and a little bit of shout out to them for building something cool and sharing about it online.
Awesome.
So this first one, let me share my screen.
This first person, her name is Sherry, and she's building this tool called uh Peak Money.
We're not going to really talk a lot about the app itself, but just to get into it a little bit,
Peak Money is essentially a finance app that I think their unique angle is like it's not just like a tracking your budget.
It's like you can chat with it and it'll give you some insights about your spending.
Um, yeah, I think it's pretty cool.
uh someone who is always looking for new finance apps.
Uh it's kind of I think it's a unique take.
I think it tells you like you spent this much this week is well here's your goals blah blah blah.
Nice.
But I think what I and the reason I've been following her, what we're going to talk about here is like this this build in public journey that I think has gotten her a ton of attention on her product and spoiler like she recently hit like
number one on Product Hunt, which is a cool goal or a cool accomplishment.
And I kind of wanted to walk through a few examples of her journey and then tie it back to like this is why building in public is so important or so cool,
especially when you're starting.
So I um she's been doing this like almost daily updates where she says like day 1, day five,
day 10, and then gives a little update on how her app is going.
So I went I went all the way back through through her Twitter and found day one of her building Peak Money.
So, here's the first one, but it's just like day one building the next big personal finance app,
blah blah blah.
Doesn't matter.
And the thing that I found most interesting is day one has only 500 I probably just added one.
556 views on this post.
Yeah.
And one comment that is literally herself.
Only four likes.
Four likes.
One comment.
One bookmark.
Wow.
And um this was when was this?
This was March.
So like so not about a month ago.
Yeah.
I mean the first thing I see on this is you know no offense to her but this isn't a very interesting like I kind of like when I s first saw this tweet I was like uh you're building the next big personal finance app.
That's cool.
It's not really that interesting to me and maybe that's potentially why it didn't get like a whole bunch of engagement.
But it's still day one, right?
This is day one.
This kind of shows and I'm guessing it spoiler alert probably that she's going to start getting a she's going to do day two,
day three.
Let's see what happens.
But I like I mean it's cool to see that it started with only four likes and probably that's from people that went back,
you know, so it probably had zero likes and that's and that's kind of like what people are afraid of,
I think, when they want to share something like this, right?
Yeah.
Getting zero likes.
Totally.
Yeah.
And that's kind of one of the first themes I wanted to riff on a little bit is like,
and this is something that's held me back from posting or whatever online in my in my past is like,
what if nobody cares?
You know, like what if I have this big announcement or I put this all this work into this video and then literally no comments,
a few likes, and uh basically crickets.
Yep.
Um, so I think I think that's kind of like the most the first thing that like stood out to me.
So this is day one.
I think she posted this first one at like 9:53 and then this next one.
Oh, this one was actually first 9:48 on March 5th.
So she posted those five minutes.
Yeah, five minutes.
Yeah, that's interesting.
I feel like most people would just post once.
She posted this one was even before the previous one and clearly this one did performed a little bit better.
Another thing that people are afraid to do which is like okay yeah the first thing that you post or the second thing or whatever it may not be the one that hits try different things right she posted that other one which got 500
views this one got 1,200 views.
Okay that is a 120 140% increase in views.
Clearly something about this post was better and she didn't care.
She knows that anybody who sees this day one probably isn't going to see the other day one post even though that's like,
"Oh, why would you post two day ones?"
Kind of say the same thing.
So, she's trying one with the link.
She put the link in there and then she's trying one with with no link.
Okay, that's a little bit like an AB test, right?
To see what works.
This is what smart people who are building public do is let's just let's just throw the wall and see what works.
The faster I can get that feedback loop of this works and that doesn't.
do more of what works and do less of what doesn't.
Let's see what happens if she keeps going.
No, that's a really good point.
I didn't even catch that the first time is especially for newbies, and I I consider myself a newbie.
Like I said, you kind of think like everybody's watching you are going to someone's going to look at this and say,
"Oh, you're you're so dumb that you posted this twice in a row."
Yeah.
But that's that's like that's like not true, right?
And nobody's watching you.
They're they're just they mostly just care about themselves.
And yeah, the manifestation of that is they're just on the feet.
They're on their feed.
They're scrolling.
They see that post.
They're not going to go look at your profile.
They're not going to go think about you.
They may not ever think about you ever again, right?
This is people think that, oh, if I post this, they're going to click on it and then they're going to,
I don't know, dox me or whatever.
Something bad is going to happen.
But in reality, they see it, they say, oh, that's cool.
They move on.
They see it.
Oh, that's not that cool.
They move on.
That's you.
That's 99.9% of the time is what's happening.
Okay.
So, these are day ones.
Let's fast forward to day 15.
Still, you know, this is like almost a month later.
1,700 views.
Nothing insane, right?
Right.
Um, but I think I noticed it was like the first one was like, hey, this is what I'm doing.
And this one is a little more like, you know, whatever.
Day 15.
Here's some like information.
Yeah.
Downloads, conversions, wow retention.
I don't even know what that means.
A screenshot.
Modest amount of views.
She only has like 7,000 followers now.
So, I'm sure it was even less back then.
10 comments, couple likes, couple bookmarks, blah blah blah.
What I like about it is it says the same headline or the same title, building the next biggest personal finance app.
It may be slightly different than what she had on day one, but again, she's reminding people,
hey, I'm doing this thing.
Let me remind you that I'm building the next biggest personal finance app.
She's done this for 15 days.
And that's another like thing is like that kind of goes back to your point is nobody cares about you.
Nobody remembers you.
You have to remind them what you're doing, right?
I Hey, just a reminder.
I'm that sherry person that you see on social media and I'm big and I'm building the next biggest personal finance app.
I think that works for a couple reasons.
It's like, hey, I'm doing something big.
I'm setting out for a big challenge and obviously just I'm reminding you what I'm doing cuz you just saw this without the the reminder,
you'd be like, "All right, what are they doing?
I can't really remember."
Oh, that's cool.
Whatever.
This is like a little bit more bold, maybe.
Yeah.
No, that that's a great point.
And we might talk about this a couple times, but you know, we're doing the, you know,
you're doing the 100K challenge and I remember something you said as we were kind of producing it is like like,
oh, we have to remind people at the top every single time cuz it might be the first time that they're like seeing that piece of content and being able to be like,
hey, this is what I'm doing.
Here's like a overview.
And it I guess when you first said that, I was like, why are you you know, why are we going to do an overview every single time?
And it just the point you just made is like you have to remind people what you're doing because again they're probably not like fall paying as close attention to it as you are.
It's like um a TV show.
Why why do they do the intro every time?
You know why do they do the same intro?
It's like it's just to remind you, you know, what this thing is about and to get you into that mood and that vibe and whatever.
Okay, it's day 15.
Mo a bit a bit increase.
Yeah.
500,700.
Okay, this is day 22 and this one couple things obviously longer blah blah blah.
Terms of impressions 54,000.
Wow.
Okay.
54,000.
That's a big increase there.
Yeah, big increase.
A lot of more comments, blah blah blah.
And you know, if we were obviously going to like super break down this post, which I don't know if we necessarily need to.
One ob obviously visual thing is still the like, hey, I'm built reminder.
Yep.
And then just like a ton more information.
I mean, yeah.
again.
She's day 22 building the next biggest personal finance app.
They need to ingrain it into our heads that that she's doing that.
That's obviously working.
And then I don't know what what do you think made this one blow up.
Um there was this let me see if this opens.
I don't know if we've talked about this, but there was this this other post that kind of blew up right around the same time about like this guy posted I want to find an app that says XYZ things.
Obviously, this clearly got a bunch of views and it almost like coincided perfectly with like hey,
I'm building this too or PS like I'm doing this.
Yeah, she tagged that person.
So then maybe he gave it a like or a retweet and then like show just I also think she shows off more of the app here.
Well, that's like a random side tangent is like um God, I don't remember the quote, but like she by doing this every day,
she started doing this series of posts before that tweet that you just showed went viral.
If she hadn't been doing that before, that wouldn't have she wouldn't had the chance to go viral.
It just kind of a lot of times like people I don't want to say she's lucky, but you get lucky.
Something happens.
You see this viral tweet.
Oh, actually, I've already been building this.
Let me reply to your tweet.
I'm already doing it.
I don't need to go do it and and figure it all out.
I'll just retweet this, tag them, whatever, do a reply tweet, and then all of a sudden,
you blow up, right?
So, that's like it's like a luck thing, but like if she wasn't putting in all that hard work and doing every day and documenting every day,
that wouldn't have happened.
So, you know, as she as she continues to build every single day, her probably feed and algorithm,
she's being seen as the next big personal finance app.
Someone sees that tweet and then tags her in that or whatever.
that wouldn't have happened if she wasn't building in public.
You know, nobody would even have known her as the building the next personal finance app person.
So, that I think that's a cool little tidbit.
Yeah.
The quote is luck is when preparation meets opportunity.
There you go.
That's that's the quote.
She was prepped and then the opportunity came with that viral tweet, right?
Yeah.
No, I totally agree with all that.
Um I saw even I saw that tweet and I was like,"Oh, you know, I think you're right.
When people see that they're like, "Oh, I should go build that."
and she was able to easily say, "I am building that.
I mean, let me let me build that feature or whatever."
Blew up.
I'm sure she got a ton of followers from this and maybe more interest, profile visits,
etc.
Okay, so that's day 22.
We're going to fast forward here, but to her now her Product Hunt launch.
There's a whole series on like how she was launching on Product Hunt and she congrats to her like hit number one on Product Hunt,
you know, 93,000 views, you know, people commenting like congrats on the momentum blah been following blah blah blah.
And I think this one's more of like a payoff of like I've been doing this for the last April,
past two months.
It's sort of like validation of like people saw this, I've been sharing about it, they liked it.
Yeah.
And now I'm number one.
Well, let's go back.
Go and pull up that first tweet again because from day one.
Yeah.
Let's put it into perspective because this is what can happen in basically one month.
I think it was a month and a half or something like that when you start building if you build in public.
Look, there's a lot of people influencers online that are talking about, hey, you got to build in public.
Hey, look at me.
I have a million followers and it's so easy to build in public and then people go and try to do it and nobody likes their stuff.
This is what we really want to do with this podcast.
What I think you did a great job researching is finding people that are relatively new.
She does have some followers, but not a whole lot.
And I'm sure she gained a bunch in the last 30 days.
I wonder how much she had in the beginning.
But this is an amazing example of what can happen in 30 days.
And and you kind of mentioned that it seemed like, oh, 2 months will be a long time.
I think this is insane.
Her life essentially is changed forever from the perspective of building in public and building a successful app or whatever.
30 days.
Imagine if you could change your life in 30 days like this.
I'm sure everybody would take that right now.
This is the prime example of it.
March 5th, 2025 to April 15th or 23rd, 2025.
Not even two months by just showing up every day and just writing a little bit of what you're doing.
Yeah, that's pretty cool.
This is such an amazing example of that that I hope that I mean the goal of this of this video we're creating today is to show that like why aren't you doing this,
right?
Why aren't you building in public right now?
Like turn this video off and go start your day one or like we're doing on YouTube right now,
100K vibe code challenge.
Start your day one video and just just put it out there.
And look, we showed you what happens if you get zero likes, which literally was her example.
Why don't you do it?
What's What's the worst that could happen?
Nothing happened to her.
Nobody even cared.
Only 500 people saw it, and it was probably people that were going back in time to look at it,
right?
So, I just think that like that's crazy.
Yeah.
It's super cool.
And I I think that's why I wanted to talk about her.
I've been just following and like low-key rooting for her as she's like building this because I'm like,
"Oh, this is a cool story."
Like, I remember seeing this back a couple weeks ago and now look at this blah blah blah.
Yeah.
And I think people like that, too.
I I think maybe there comes a point where that turns, right?
There's always the like you like them when they're rising and then you hate them at the top,
but she's not really there yet.
Yeah.
But I think right now people are like rooting for her because they if they've been following from the beginning they could be like man this is awesome.
And and you said a key word there which is rooting for people want to root for the underdog.
Right.
If you see your buddy go put himself online and say he's building something and he's starting from nothing.
There's no success yet or anything like that.
You're always going to root for that person.
It's like maybe like part of our biology or something like that where we want to root for the underdog.
Um that's another just reason for you to go and do this right now because if you do this,
if you share what you're doing, people are going to get in your corner.
They're going to message you and say, "Dude, I love what you're doing.
I want to do it, too."
All this stuff will happen.
And it's actually, like you said, way better when you're a nobody, when you're an underdog and you have nothing to lose,
right?
when you start getting to the top and you know that's one of the reasons why we don't share our revenue anymore.
I don't share how much money that starter story makes anymore because you know relatively it's been some time now and you know usually people come kind of attack you at the top a little bit but that's a story for another day.
This yeah this is awesome.
And so the last thing I want to point out to her and this is what I think is really interesting in terms of a format.
We're always you're always talking about like what's the format that we're going to share about.
She is basically like starting again.
So now that she's got this whatever product hunt momentum she got to launch and now she's starting again our path to 10k downloads in 30
days.
Nice.
And so so now she's on the journey again till we get 10K.
And I bet it there there might be a who knows, right?
You can never like predict how something's going to work or not.
You can bet that she's going to take what she's learned over the last 20, 30, month and a half days and apply it to like this next mountain for her.
And how did this tweet do this one?
10,000 views.
Yeah.
I mean, she knows what she's doing.
The Yeah.
Setting a new challenge.
It kind of reminds me of the 100K build challenge that we're doing on the Starter Story build channel.
When you complete the previous challenge that you set out the day one, the next challenge is to get downloads.
So the first challenge for her was to build.
The next challenge was to get downloads.
That's actually pretty powerful to kind of start over again, right?
She built it.
She did it.
Now she's focused on growth.
And then when she finishes this challenge, I don't know if Yeah, it's a 30-day challenge.
Go do make your first dollar challenge.
After that, go make your first 100K challenge, right?
She's just continuously doing this.
Is actually really, really smart.
I haven't seen anybody really do this like this before.
I like it.
Yeah, it's pretty cool.
And it's something I think anyone can like copy.
You know, you're if you're just starting your first thing like, okay, for the next 30 days,
I'm going to commit day one, day two, day three.
Maybe no, maybe you'll get crickets.
Maybe you won't be as successful this person.
Yeah.
But you certainly will learn something.
Right.
By yourself or your product or whatever.
That's something I always try to explain to people, too, is there's always someone there's always a big group of people out there that are trying that are a little bit behind you.
So, you're learning this thing, which is building.
There is a huge group of people that want to learn building.
Now, she's learning growth.
there's people behind her that have built but are also trying to learn growth, right?
Someone said this somewhere, but like in any sort of built in public or anything like that,
just try to help people that are 6 months behind in terms of where you are.
When she goes and does the monetization one, she'll go and help people that have already figured out growth but not monetization.
There's always going to be a huge millions of people online that want to learn what you've just learned or what you're currently learning right now and that that will never end.
Yeah, that's a really good point.
Um, and I think that's part of what makes even, you know, shameless plug for Star Story,
like I think that's what makes it interesting to people.
That's why I started following initially was cuz it's like, oh man, they just did that and I want to learn from what they just shared or what they just posted about or video came out,
whatever.
Y um I think people like that stuff.
There's always something to learn, even if they're not millionaires.
That that's what I've always believed about Starter Story is that you don't have to be a billionaire to learn something interesting.
You could have just made something that gets users or you could just have made something.
There's always something that somebody can learn.
So, Sherry, congrats, Sherry.
Hope we I'll keep following you and if something else crazy happens, we might talk about you again.
Yeah.
Or maybe we'll even have you on the podcast someday.
Um Okay.
Okay.
So, next I want to show you uh a different guy that I've been following.
His name is Matt.
And um it's it's a little bit of a different it's not like I don't have posts that are like about his journey.
These are just like five different examples of five different build examples that I think you can copy or you can like look at and and take and twist in your own way.
Yeah.
So um here's Matt.
I've been following him following him.
Cool stories.
Obviously a little bit of a bigger audience than Sherry had, but I've seen him kind of grow recently.
and he built a tool called Real Farm.
We're not obviously going to talk about the tool, but it's this like automated short form videos,
AI short form videos.
Say what you want about like AI, this kind of stuff, but that's what he's doing.
But like I said, the main thing I want to touch on is like what are the types of things he's been sharing about his product that you can like kind of copy or some examples.
So, let's go through five of them.
The first one I think will feel similar to what Sherry was just sharing.
So, this first one, this is from December 2024, so not that long ago.
About 3,000 views, and it's just a post that's like, "Hey, I launched this thing.
Does anyone want to use it?"
Yeah.
Kind of thing.
Uh, you know, a couple comments, blah, blah, blah.
And really just like a screenshot.
Yeah.
Tool.
And that's like that's literally DM me if you want.
Happy.
Yeah.
I mean, I think what's cool about this is that you went and did the research and found like a bunch of like different posts that he did.
And for anyone watching right now, the reason why we're sharing this right now is because these are all formats that you should just steal.
If you're watching this, you're definitely building something, an app or a service or something like that.
Literally take this tweet right now, replace real farm with your app, change the photo,
and that's it.
It's not stealing.
It's This is This is what everyone should do, right?
This is like talking to customers, getting beta testers, just putting your thing out there and seeing if you can just get one person to care.
You should steal this, right?
And if you do this, and we're going to probably show a couple more examples here, too.
Try to do at least one of these a week or a day or whatever, and you'll be building in public and you'll be able to do what he did.
So, yeah.
Um, yeah.
Yeah, I was going to say the exact same thing like copy paste this for your thing.
Probably the scary part.
So representing all the new beasts here is like if someone did DM him then he has to like test it and I think that's like for for a new person that's probably the first scary thing is like it there was
just like a I don't know exactly know like where I got it from or story or whatever but it's like sometimes when you're on the journey like you're kind of enjoying the journey more than like
the destination.
That's not like the quote.
I'm totally screwing that up.
But it's almost like what if you get what you want?
what he wants his users and what if he gets it and then it's like,"Oh now now this thing has to work."
Yeah.
Right.
People are scared of success or Yeah.
Yeah.
No, I could see that.
I mean, but it's okay.
Like, I mean, what's the worst thing that's going to happen if the thing doesn't even work and you still send it to them?
They will tell you, "Hey, this didn't work."
Or they may say something else like, "This did work."
Or, uh, there's this other thing that's kind of confusing about your website.
You should probably fix that.
Like, these are things that like is okay.
And like what's the worst thing that happens is someone like clicks on it and goes like I don't know what this is and then they just don't respond to you.
Like that doesn't sound that bad.
I think I think you I think we're going to be all right.
So um but yeah I I could see that.
Next example.
We've we've probably seen this a million times and this is you know he's a little bit more successful here.
So we're skipping ahead a little bit obviously.
But you know a month later or so 130,000 views I used to pray for times like these.
10k MR in 35 days.
and the the the classic I've seen a billion of these posts, right?
And they always get a lot of views.
The classic like Stripe dashboard or like MRR dashboard obviously a little harder to like copy and paste,
right?
Because you have to like actually have revenue.
But I've seen people post this with like their first $100.
Uh I think people still will see this and be like, "Oh, that's cool.
Let me see how much you're making."
Yep.
People are attracted to that kind of stuff.
Yeah.
No, obviously this someone watching this might go, "Hey, okay, cool.
Well, I don't have 10,000 MR, so I can't share this, but exactly what you said.
You should share.
First of all, the Stripe screenshot, I don't need to explain why that works.
When you get your first $100, you should share that.
When you get your first $10 payment, when you get your first payment, you should share that.
If you attempt to get your first payment and you don't get your first payment, you should share that.
Say, I failed.
I couldn't get a customer.
I got a 100 people to visit my website and nobody paid for it.
Share that.
Show show the Stripe screenshot that says zero dollars, right?
It's obviously not going to get a million views like this did.
But I was talking to someone the other day and he was like, "Well, I don't want to create this video unless this app that I make makes a hundred bucks or a,000 bucks."
I was like, "Well, if it doesn't make money, still try to have it make money, and if it doesn't,
just change the video or the the packaging to be around how you failed."
And that's still potentially equally as interesting as you being successful.
So, I think that um first of all, you can temper it down to be less money or you can just make it about how it didn't work,
right?
This is content and failing would be relatable to me.
For sure.
Yeah, that's a great point.
Like, yeah, you don't have to wait for a certain milestone.
10K is easy.
You know, a lot of people that's like the round number people like, right?
Well, that first that's an interesting point because a lot of people think that they need to wait for a certain milestone because I follow Pat and he's making X money.
I cannot share anything until I make that amount of money.
That's like comparison is the um joy, right?
But instead of comparing yourself to someone, compare yourself to compare it to yourself yesterday or the week before.
you're starting from zero or everyone starts from zero.
So if you make a hundred bucks the next month, share that because you're just make you're doing better.
You're improving, right?
I sound like a motivational person right now, but when it comes to creating content around that,
that's something that I did when I first started is when I made my first dollar, I shared about that on on Twitter.
And then my next month I made $100 or $200 or whatever, I shared that.
I didn't really care about like who was going to see that or like that or whatever.
I was just like I was so excited that I had done better than the previous month by I I had done 100% better,
right?
It was I did 2x what I did the month before, but if you look at the whole numbers, I did $100 in the whole revenue.
A lot of people would be afraid to share that because it's not what someone they compare themselves to,
but if you compare yourselves to yourself, then you have unlimited content as long as you just get a little bit better every day,
you know?
Totally agree.
And I like this comment here.
How'd you do it?
And he's like, I have no idea.
Just pressing bunch of buttons in the right order, I guess.
Yeah.
There you go.
That's funny.
Okay, next example.
This one is less of like a You can copy this for sure.
And I've seen a lot of videos like this that actually take off, but it's just like, hey,
this is what I'm building right now.
I think people like this.
It just it's a cool angle.
It's showing him on his computer.
We do a lot of this obviously for some starter story stuff where you're like on your computer showing what you're building.
But I think it's some things that stand out like
hey showing him what does it look like when I'm building a business like this is what it looks like.
Authenticity.
Yeah.
The I mean I what I like about these examples that I'm really stoked you found this guy and you're showing he he's trying a lot of different things,
right?
He's got a video.
He's got an MR screenshot.
The first one, what was the first one again?
It was just a screenshot of the website.
Yeah, he's trying a bunch of different things.
And what I think is cool about this one is visual, right?
This is something that I think about when we create content is like he could say a real farm is one person business and there's no photo or there's no there's there's no media associated with it.
That wouldn't get any likes.
He could show a photo of him doing the same exact thing from the top down angle.
Probably wouldn't get any likes, but he did this little video which is interactive.
it creates a little bit more engagement.
You know, this is this is really smart actually and clearly it worked.
So, yeah.
And there was um I I can't find it, but that one tweet that I showed about the guy who said,
"I want an um finance app that did these three things.
There was a guy who got he like showed himself building it kind of like this sped up thing and his video got like a million two million views or whatever and he started this other finance app or whatever."
This is like a style that I've seen.
Yeah.
Quite a bit.
Um, that probably takes like z zero effort to like I mean it takes some effort to like set up the camera,
think about the angle, etc.
But you got to go and put up a camera up on your ceiling and point it down and then go get the shot and do a time lapse and then go and edit it.
This is it takes work to do, but this is worth it, right?
This got 22,000 views is helping grow his brand, probably driving people to his website.
This is this is what you have to do to stand out.
And um you know, maybe this didn't work and it was just a good cool thing to try out,
but it worked for him.
I bet he's done it a bunch more times.
Yeah, for sure.
One other quick thing here, side sidebar, is like I noticed that he like comments on a lot of like he responds to the comments.
I think that's another like little thing that I've seen people do is like they'll post something and then they'll actually you've said this before.
You say something like sometimes like sales or whatever like will happen in the comments or in the DMs and I I think that's something I've noticed about him.
Not not I mean I showed you a little bit on this post.
I also saw it on a few others that I that I was looking at.
Especially when you're starting out and you have 12,000 followers like he has.
I'm sure he had much less is like you're making friends when you are responding to you're building connections and those connections can often lead to sales or just people retweeting you or just you
know they're in conversation with their other buddy and he's like hey I want to get into TikTok and like well follow this guy Matt Welter.
He actually replied to my tweet that one time and we had a conversation and I actually think you should use his product.
It's stuff like that.
is like when you get so many followers and it gets hard to respond to everything then it's just you know it's just a time thing but when you're starting out should respond to every single comment unless it's you know AI
generated or something like that uh because this is where you make friends right this is everyone's kind of hanging out and yeah always ends up being that you know the same people kind of that
coming in and out of your comments all the time so you're kind of building that relationship digitally asynchronously uh on Twitter So,
I I used to respond to every single comment and for anyone starting out, I would recommend to do that because those people are now like huge people that have big followings and
we're, you know, kind of we we know each other through the internet.
Yeah, that's pretty cool.
Okay, a couple more examples.
This one is a different format.
Not a ton of views on this obviously, but what I noticed is he did that he does this all the time.
This is one example of like 20 I could have pulled.
Yeah.
It's just like a video update of the the product.
So, obviously, we're not listening to it or whatever.
It doesn't really matter, but he's just walking through like Whoops.
He's just walking through like this is what I'm building.
This is how it works.
You know, this is the strategy.
He talks all about like short form strategy.
Yep.
And so, again, not like a ton of views.
It's not really about like this post.
It's just that I noticed he did this.
It does this a lot.
Yeah.
Where he just jumps on I don't actually know what this app is.
Probably like Loom or whatever.
Yeah.
And just like, "Hey, this this is my app behind the scenes.
This is kind This is why this feature is cool."
Y and I'm sure I'm sure some people watching this are like, "Oh, that is like a cool feature.
Let me go check out the app."
Now, even though it has 16,000 views, this media or content or tweet or whatever, it's directly showing off what his app does,
which means that there will be higher conversion or higher intent to try out this app.
So, anybody that's watching this will be like, "Oh, it does this, it does that, it has this feature,
has that feature."
Those views are more valuable than when he's just sharing that top angle of him building a business cuz that doesn't have any intent around the business he's building.
Like if I'm looking at that tweet, I'm like, "Oh, I want to start my own business."
If I'm looking at this tweet or this video, I'm more like, "Oh, well, I kind of want to use that software."
And so that's why like views are like a vanity metric.
I always try to tell people is like views are cool.
Um, but what's more important is the intent behind those views.
You can have a million views and not get a single customer or you can get 16,000 views here and maybe this drove a,000 MR for his business.
I don't know if that's the case for here, but there's a lot more intent around this sort of thing.
And that's probably why he's doing it a lot is even though, you know, it's probably not going to make a billion-dollar business,
but it may drive an extra customer or two, which if you do it, you're already building the app anyway,
you're already adding features.
Why not just record a quick Loom and post it?
So, I think that's awesome.
Um, and like I said, he did this he's he's done this like a billion times as far as I can tell.
Okay, last one is more of like a personal thing, but it's certainly a format that you can steal or use.
It's just like a long update.
So, he says,"Real Farm made 100K revenue in 100 days.
Here's some lessons I learned."
And, you know, we're not going to read all of it, but, you know, boom, boom, boom.
Here's three lessons.
Here's another little screenshot of a little bit less.
You know, you can see that uh too 36,000 views.
You know, nothing crazy, but it's reminds me a little bit more of like what a little not really exactly,
but like what Sher the past example was doing that it feels more like personal.
And my my quick takeaway here and then I'll give it back to you is like this is like a little fluffy whatever but it's like reminders that like hey I'm I'm like a regular guy that's just like doing this thing online
and here's like some things that I'm learning and I think people eat that up.
I like reading this stuff.
I'm like oh cool reflections or like what can I learn from this when I quit my job blah blah blah you know.
Yeah.
I mean, I think it helps that he made $100,000 and he has a stripe a stripe screenshot in there so that it's like,
hey, here's my authority on doing this thing, making money online or whatever.
Now, I'm like, okay, now I probably want to see his takeaways because he did it, so he probably learned something.
So, I do think that's important.
But going back to my previous example, he could he could also have failed to make 100K in 100 days.
And that still might be interesting if he did this tweet differently.
And the Stripe screenshot said, actually, I know a lot of I can't pull the examples up right now,
but I just I've seen a few people that do this.
It's like, make the Stripe screenshot zero dollars or maybe $100, whatever it is, and make the headline,
I failed to make X in X days or whatever.
Here's what I learned.
Maybe it doesn't go as viral as this did.
Um, but that's still interesting, right?
So, um, I think that it's not the right word isn't transparent, but like being okay with going out and saying,
"I failed.
I screwed up.
I did this wrong.
Um, I didn't hit my goals.
Whatever it is, people really like that.
I think that's powerful and sometimes can be even more powerful than, hey, here's how much money I'm making.
Here's what I learned.
Hey, here's how I failed and I'm willing to share this with the world.
People can people like that, too.
Yeah.
I think it comes down to like relatability.
And when you see something like that or something like this Yeah.
Like I mentioned for the other person, Sherry, it's like I'm rooting for, you know, I'm rooting for this guy.
I don't know him.
You know, I've DM'd him a couple times, but that's it, right?
I'm just It gives you like a personality and that people want to root for.
And maybe that'll turn to users, maybe that won't.
I don't know.
Um, but I don't think it hurts.
Maybe is my my thought there.
So, yeah, these are the two folks uh that I want to talk about today.
Yeah.
No, this was cool.
I think I think what hopefully people will like about this is that we shared people that you've never heard of.
My goal is that our goal was that you haven't heard of these people.
Um, and this is what you can do starting today, right?
You can go and do your day one post now and you can these are real live proof of what happens if you just start building in public.
Yeah, I agree.
And like I said, that's why that's why I brought these people up because it feels like sometimes you'll see I don't know,
for example, in starter story interviews where it's like, oh, I did this 3 years ago and that's awesome.
You know, I think some of that still works, but it's really cool to see like this is like last week.
Um, you can do this like right now.
I think that's a little bit more interesting.
So yeah, if you're watching this and you enjoyed us covering some kind of smaller people uh that are just getting started,
what's currently working, right?
Our goal is to share the most freshest content that we could possibly have.
You know, we're not going to bring some influencer on here and talk about something that worked 5 years ago.
Our goal is to find the most like freshest thing that's actually working right now.
So if you like this, please put a comment in there to let us know if you want us to cover something different or more or maybe cover even smaller creators.
let us know.
Um, but yeah, that was cool.
It was really cool to go through those examples and just see people that are on the come up today.
Everything things are always changing, but also things kind of always stay the same.
So, I think that's cool.
Thank you guys for watching.
Um, I meant to say this earlier, but you can check out the first link in the description.
We have a link to our attentioning database, which is like different posts that you can basically copy just like the ones we showed here and use for your own product.
If you're building something like the day one thing, I launched my thing or here's my Stripe screenshot or whatever,
we have a whole database of templates that you can download, um, which is free and you can check it out.
I put the first link in the description.
Otherwise, check out Starter Story Build where we have boot camps where you can build cool stuff with AI,
real projects.
And other than that, thank you for watching the Starter Story podcast.
We will see you in the next one.
Peace.