all right so here's a question I want to figure out can you go viral get users and get paying customers without a personal brand my team and I spend hours every week researching what is actually
working right now for online businesses and one thing we keep seeing is people are using these really simple templates to get their first customer and sometimes even generate tens of
thousands of dollars super simple stuff that really you can kind of just copy and paste so in today's video we're going to be breaking down four these examples of this kind of viral content
specifically a single tweet that generated $30,000 with zero audience a real that got 880,000 views using something a little different an Instagram post that
led to a, 1400% increase in traffic and an example of what you should and should not do when posting on subreddits we'll go over why they work and how you can do it too
so if you're looking for Content ideas that are working literally right now you're going to love this episode as always leave your feedback in the comments and tell us which idea you like the most and you could see yourself
trying out let's go all right let's get into it uh I have four examples today let's do the first one I'm going to share my screen this is an example from
Twitter it's this guy named Eddie um this is a launch announcement post that got three million views and what it is
it looks like it's an app that simulates If your tweet's going to go viral or not so if you're looking at this obviously there's a lot going on here but there's two versions of a tweet
and sort of what it's simulating supposedly is how viral one version Will Go version a versus version b and a couple things that I think are really interesting about this particular post
good hook on Twitter what works is like short Snappy this one like really just tells you in one sentence what this does build an algorithm that simulates how
thousands of users react to your Tweet so you'll know it goes viral before you post that's one thing I found interesting we see a lot of like call to actions or I see you know it's always like sign up for my email list sign up
for this lead magnet but his call to action was like you can get access right now by joining this Google meet which I've never seen before and maybe you have or not I don't know I thought that
was like a really interesting thing to see there's like a concept not to get too heady but there's a concept of a called like purple cow from some marketer named Seth Goden that's like do
that's like different and this is very different and the last thing before I'll pass it over to you all is according to this tweet this other tweet said he made 30k in 24 hours selling
through Google meet after one viral tweet 30,000 I actually went through the process of uh the product is called um
crowd test AI where you can kind of inut your Tweet here you know input it over here and if you you know want to predict it takes
you to a sales page oh th000 bucks per month nice this is so smart oh my gosh yeah yeah that's just like some initial
thoughts I have some other stuff but num go to some of the engagement numbers how many com wow so 3.3 million
views almost 10,000 likes over three 350 comments that's crazy and how many followers does this guy have uh right now I wish I could see at the time of is
posting 19 19,000 followers wow yeah so he's not like a super big account and probably he got like 10,000 followers from this and does does it say I see
here it says he's 17 years old yeah nice I mean seems like a pretty cool idea I have no idea how that actually
works and I it's a really cool idea and it's smart that he's charging a thousand dollars for that like really like that's just gonna attract a
um probably more like Enterprise and B2B just by charging a lot more for something kind of crazy and uh if you yeah if you did 30 30 customers times
thousand that's how he got to the 30,000 probably and that's a that's a great start for a for a product I think the really interesting
about this thing about this is like the the live selling aspect yeah and I feel like this is is going to blow up even more because I've been seeing a bunch of people kind of talking about it I know
Gary ve had mentioned something about it with like you know they're doing it on Tik Tok the live selling and that's just like e-commerce products and I think Daniel dalan had made a tweet too saying
the same thing of in China live shopping is like really huge so the fact that you can kind of do this with SAS too and make you know put on a live demo of your
product and maybe even answer questions in real time and basically come over objections for people that's kind of insane and I feel like that's a huge
play just to even close sales instantly it's kind of nuts yeah it creates like a fomo you know it's like there's no way to place to put your email in or anything like that and this feels like
this new shiny crazy product that doesn't exist yet so people want to get on there and you know you get on a call and before you knowah you've handed over your credit card and you even thought about it right
yeah I think a post like this this obviously it's cool it's like it's interesting good good hook good video like we we've seen this a million times but I think what in my opinion makes it interesting especially for like a space
like Twitter or anyone building online is you really want to go viral I feel like that's just like a desire that people building online
want and so this is like a perfect product to be like well yeah I need I need to go viral or I'll spend a thousand bucks once to try Tred out for
a month to I think it just hits this like deep desire or like this like really desire that people want to go viral be famous get attention there's
two things here that I think are really great I mean one is a little harder to do it's proof this is proof that his app actually works because he did it for his
own app like if you look in some of the comments there it's like did you do it with this post and he's like yeah we iterated through like 50 different posts to get this one and this has 3 million
views so already you just have proof right there in in your face you don't need any social proof or proof that this actually works this is like you know built into the actual marketing itself
which is really smart but the other thing that I think that probably doesn't get talked about is retention and this is something that you know people talk about on YouTube is like if you can get someone to stay till the end of your YouTube
video then you know YouTube's going to show that to you know a million people or whatever this is a small little Twitter hack and Twitter has changed their algorithm to be about retention so
basically I mean I don't know exactly how the Twitter algorithm works but I do know one thing is that they track likely track how long you stay on a post so
right now they're tracking how long you are hanging around on this post and seeing uh how much you hang out or keep scrolling and what's really smart about
this is it has this one line it doesn't over share too much it doesn't say hey we built this thing this is how it works this is how it does blah blah blah blah
blah all this stuff they just say hey I built this and that's it it's one sentence doesn't even have a period in the sentence and then they have the video that you watch it and you see
something happening which is like what the hell is going on here it's very Snappy video and it's getting you to stay and likely I saw this post before and I watched this post like five to
maybe 10 times replay over and over so I could like kind of understand what was going on in this post and that signaled to the Twitter algorithm that this is a
post that people want to learn more about and is interesting ra rather than just scrolling through so this can be done in a lot of different ways on Twitter obviously this is an extreme
example where you get three million views but that's something that we do when we post stuff on starter story is yeah you could write a book but people are like I don't want to read that book right now or you could just write one thing
and give a video or um a photo or something like that that you know it's like when you go on Twitter and you'll see someone post like a screenshot of
let's say like a bunch of bullet points like here's everything that's going on in open AI news today or something like that that works because people click the screenshot they look at it they sit there for a few minutes and that tells a
Twitter algorithm this tweet has retention right you probably can find an example right this is a good example right here is like yeah people are going to sit there and read that and Twitter
likes that and that goes for all the algorithms or platforms LinkedIn you know all that stuff is going to be like that so yeah that's a little hack that
can probably double your impressions all right so if you like this example I think you're really going to like this this one example is just
one of our million dooll attention ideas database our team spent weeks researching this stuff and putting it all into place you can download all these right now 50 plus social media
ideas that you can basically copy and paste right now maybe throw into chat GPT throw a little details about what you're building and voila yes it might need a little bit more work than that
but these work because they are proven templates if you think getting lots of Impressions on social media is about luck well I dare you to try these out because these work based on all the principles that we talked about today
retention Hooks and all that stuff so if you really want to try some of this stuff out like the stuff we're talking about today check out the first link in the description and you can download all these get access to them and get started
growing your business all right let's get back and let's talk about some more ideas all right next example this one's from Instagram I have a couple from Instagram it's an Instagram account called poor boy coffee I've been
following this guy for like the past year different obviously than some of like SAS products and apps we usually see he's building a coffee shop in San Francisco or outside of San Francisco
Isco and um you can scroll through this but one of the things that he's done for the past year is do these types of posts where he sort of shows off the revenue
and a little bit more behind the scenes stuff of his coffee shop so in this example he's doing a you know number of Cups sold Revenue gross revenue in week one gross revenue week six and then
total revenue at the bottom there's a couple things that I think are really interesting about this one is we were just talking about like that retention having the numbers behind a Post-It note
to reveal like makes me want to stick around and see like okay what it like what is the revenue I want I've always been curious about how much it cup of coffee cost or whatever so that's one
thing that I find really interesting and then the second thing and then I'll turn it over to you guys is I think people really like these kinds of posts that sort of reveal the numbers or the behind
the scenes stuff we see all that always on Twitter feels like those pop off and then something like this I think is is another example of that where people are really interested in like what are the
actual numbers going on behind this business I've always been interested to know what people want to know how much you yeah people want to know how much do you make and and like how does what's the breakdown of that so yeah I think those are two things immediately a pop
out to me what do you guys think I love this format I think this works in like a bunch of other niches too like you guys said just the interest around the numbers of the business business and how
much it cost to actually start it just gets almost anybody interested because you know somebody might be watching and say hey I could actually start a coffee shop because I see the cost now and I
see that the investment is actually not that bad so I think there's like natural interest in that and um I saw it in the golf Niche the other day some guy did
the same thing for like Golf and how much it costs to actually play uh a tour pro golf tournament and he does it Ross a couple different things like how much
it it how much it cost to be a pro golfer and I think it's just kind of cool because people are just always interested in how much things cost nowadays really interesting format gets a pretty broad audience too to come in
and watch it both of these guys are basically doing the same thing he's using the Whiteboard and all that seems like something that anybody can do if you're running any sort of business just list out how much it cost to run your
business and do it in a kind of cool way like that go buy a whiteboard at Target or something like that and and just write that down that's just like so easy and that having that prop I think is like makes it easier to like
have a visual and obviously a place like Instagram is such a visual medium so I think that really helps too yeah like he could go and put those all those numbers
as Graphics but I think people are like kind of tired of the heavy graphical stuff like just give me something authentic and put it on the Whiteboard like I'm like I'm in school like it's nostalgic I'm at school right now and
the teacher's writing on the Whiteboard or you know I'm in the meeting room and we're using the Whiteboard rather than you know some fancy Graphics or something like that the one thing that I think go re reload this page real quick
this this really really small thing that happens see what happens when he sit like right when it starts he sits down he could have started the filming this this is a small little hack for anyone watching this to get a little bit of the
sauce he could have just started filming it and when he has started sitting down but there's this little movement thing like reload the page right now and watch what happens in the very very first
split second he sits down right there that creates movement if you watch any Mr Beast uh shter anything like that everything starts with movement it's
like hey quick let me sit down something like that and that's just a little tiny hack that you'll notice all great this guy's a really good content creator you
can clearly tell yeah all they all do this yeah yeah that's funny that you say that because there was a uh a meme kind of going around and it was how the
different age Generations start a video and it was like gen Z does like the kind of like Snappy thing where you fix your camera or something like that and um
yeah like the Boomers just press record and then make sure like the first thing is just them sitting and it's kind of like awkward interesting I never saw
that yeah it's funny because gen Z kind of already knows like we know how to keep attention and make things interesting so that is it's a really good hack yeah I know what you're talking about it's like the pause
Millennial pause yeah yeah the millennial pause I've never heard of this yeah it's funny yeah the idea is like she starts with sort of the shaking versus
Millennials will start with like fres play okay yeah that's kind of interesting too this next one is uh another Instagram example it's from a
guy in the starter Story community named Dan gorby this one's different than the last one the last one was a video maybe you're not comfortable like doing video stuff you can totally be comfortable posting a picture in this case a
Carousel and this is a sort of launch announcement for his app that he built I think we've talked about it before in other places it's called the focus app and so obviously you see the copy here
on the side you know I made an app blah blah blah blah and what's cool about the graphics I think here are you know it kind of announces what he does a little
bit of like my story how long it took me to build this thing some like kind of addressing some of the doubts and then sort of an advertisement for his app
finishing with like Hey try it now and I think this is a cool example like I said already of a different kind of uh Instagram post to kind of announce what you're doing or like what you're
starting um so this this was something I thought that was that anybody could like anybody could do this uh which which is I think the thing that I'm taking away from it it doesn't have that many likes
but I'm curious are there any numbers behind this because he's in our community yeah yeah what he shared was he got 2,000
views 71 likes 31 comments and probably most interesting 1, 1400% increase in traffic since that post wow so drove
people to the focus project his his app the focus pro.com that's the big thing right there right is it may not seem like a lot of views or a lot of likes
but 14, 1400% increase to zap the focus project yeah I mean this is you know it's I I like this example because it's so simple it's not three million views
or whatever the problem here that I see that you know and why I like to show this one is that so many people are afraid to even share on their own
personal Network that they're starting a business or that they built something or that they did something a lot of people um you know for a lot of reasons want to just you know kind of build in silence and hope I can you know get users and
then get successful and then I can share them doing this thing but I think that man if if you're not willing to go and you know post on tell tell your friends tell your family post on your own
network then I'm not sure if if if you if you got it if you can make it sure there are examples of people that that did it without that but even if it doesn't really have some crazy results in terms of you know revenue or
something like that that is a mental or psychological step that you have to take to become someone who builds something and eventually you know becomes an
entrepreneur and makes build something that makes money and all that is that something that you guys ever thought about too like because I I you know some people are like afraid that people are going to hear about it at their boss is going to hear that they're starting
something that that's the one big objection that I get I mean yeah 100% I feel like I've heard of people who are like who start like different accounts on like Instagram or Twitter things like
that so that they can feel like they can share it a little bit more like in stealth but anyways yeah I I do feel that for sure where I'm like what are people going to think what is my friends gonna are they going to judge me are
they going to think I'm stupid which yeah has held me back for like a long time I think that that when you I know Pat you talk a lot about like attention and all that stuff and that's such a like um it seems easy feels like it
should be easier than it is yeah and in some ways it really I mean it is like this is not we're not talking about crazy complicated things here it's just more about willingness to put yourself
out there which is like probably the hardest thing in all this yeah it's like not afraid to be scrutinized by people yeah definitely the most difficult thing like I remember
when I first started just making videos like podcast Clips online I had like a 100 200 followers on Twitter and I was afraid to post just like a podcast clip that I did because I was just like you
know people are going to be like what is he doing blah blah blah yeah and you kind of go through all those emotions but it's not really that big of a deal at the end of the day yeah no I mean I remember feeling that way too and I mean
the reality is that people are probably maybe they won't say it to you but they are probably thinking it you know maybe you got some like buddies that you know you went to high school or or college with and they're kind of doing their own
thing they see you do doing something new they're probably gonna you know give you a little crap or you know whatever that's just that's just life um but I think people when you do put yourself
out there and like Gus if you can share your screen and pull that up there because I think that there's that one line that's really important in that post which is I finally did it and it
shows you that like I have the balls and the courage to build my own app and tell the world about it everybody secretly
wants to be an entrepreneur have Financial Freedom build a business at least there's some desire there I think for for everyone I can only speak about myself but I do think that a lot of
people behind the scenes will tell me like man I really want to do what you do and that sort of thing only maybe 5% or even L do this and and tell the world about it and that's that's half to
battle even if it doesn't get a whole lot of you know likes or whatever I think it's amazing I I think it's like a
huge hack to leverage this right here to be able to go and your business starts with zero customers go to your network
your Instagram following your LinkedIn following your friends family Network whatever that's where you can get your first customer customers or that's when you can get connections to your first customers you're at a huge disadvantage
if you decide you want to do the faceless thing or whatever so if you want to do it the hard way do that but I think that this is just like such a great way to get people in your corner
and then get over that psychological hurdle of putting yourself out there I feel like with all the like AI stuff and like AI generated comments and posts and
things like that and Advantage is you know putting yourself out there being real yeah people like like to root for that kind of stuff yep let people root
for you yeah yeah I think you just also you you attract cooler people that are doing cool stuff online when you put yourself out there yeah like you're always going to have somebody that's
hating from the sidelines I feel like most of that is just cope or like a jealousy because they don't do it themselves yeah but then in reality when you put yourself out there you end up getting cool opportunities talking to
really cool people that are probably much more like-minded so this last one is also from Dan Corby this uh this is a a post he made
on Reddit that got let me see my notes that got 753 th000 views 714 up votes
179 comments uh in the first 48 hours after he posted it and so just to quickly run through what this is um it's sort of a a little bit of like behind
the scenes of what I built um he talks a little bit about his story talks about his project the focus project some lessons he learned from it um and then
some like kind of examples showing off like what the project actually is and so um a couple of things that I think are interesting about this post are
like one it's um I don't know it's like a just sharing from experience it's not like an ad uh
or a straightup ad for his for his project um something people can comment on and learn from Etc but then you know the subtext of that even though what I just said was that it's not an ad is
that it's kind of low-key in ad you know if if this gets a lot which it did gets a lot of views and attention there's probably a certain percent I don't know what the percent is you know maybe in the one to three to
five percent of people that are going to say Focus project I wonder what that is and copy and paste That Into You Know search and go to the app and you know a
lower percent maybe sign up so yeah that's that's this one what do you guys think about this so Dan is I mean I think what's cool about this is that Dan Corby the guy who created this and
created the focus project he's part of the our growth accelerator which is basically like kind of what I talked about earlier is we give you a bunch of ideas you go and post it in a bunch of
places post on Reddit post on Instagram there's a bunch of templates you just go and post it but you know put in your project and all that stuff and see what hits uh when something starts hitting do more of that go to different you know
let's say Reddit starts working go to different subreddit so for anyone watching who's you know sick and tired of building stuff and not getting any users you know this is proof right here
that the growth accelerator is the is a way to to get users and honestly it's it's only for people that are serious about doing this you know you got to be able to put yourself out there but I
think this is such a great example so yeah Shameless plug on that but I really do think you know this is this is just such a great example of someone who's getting users and making it happen and doing it in just a few days
there's another example in here that I think actually because I talked to Dan about this and you I was like holy man you got 750,000 views and then he told me he was like yeah that's cool but
I actually got more users from a different post and I really wanted to show this because you know it's cool to get a million views you got
almost a million views on that on that one but views don't mean without inent right or action to be taken after
so this post right here if you scroll down uh I think I don't have the numbers exactly on how many views it got but if that got 40 upvotes what did the other
one have uh 714 that means it probably got 10% of the views let's say that this post here got
maybe 50,000 views or 30 to 40,000 views Dan told me that this post um got more users than that other
post and that's like a little sauce right there which is like attention doesn't mean anything without intent you can post on Twitter about what you have for breakfast and it gets a million
views but you won't get a single person to sign up for your app if you do that and that's why everyone talks about oh but you have an audience you know you can do anything when you have an audience that's right you got
to have an aligned audience and you got to have a good product to fit for that audience and all that so you know why why this makes sense is it's actually where it was posted so in the growth
accelerator we tell you to go and try different subreddits this is posted in the r productivity apps subreddit his project is a productivity
app right that makes sense yeah so what was the other subredit that was his was in chat GPT coding that's a bunch of people who want to build a business they don't give a about your
productivity app right go post it where your Target customer is and the in intent to sign up will be way higher and I think that's just such a great example of you know views don't
mean right it's all about users and that's that's the the metric you should be looking at when you're trying to see what channels work yeah I have a question Pat any like anecdotal stuff on
like cautionary tales from posting on Reddit kind of thing for like for example I've posted some stuff and sometimes it'll get like taken down by the mods and I'm like God damn and and like you can learn from that and figure
out like what does or doesn't work and I'm sure it's not like blanket advice but like what do you think what do you think about that for Reddit specifically I guess yeah well I was actually
like Reddit was the channel That blue starter story up so the very very I I was doing the same thing as Dan gorby this guy here I was posting on basically
every channel possible to see okay can one of these things work I was posting on quora I was posting on Instagram I was posting on Facebook you know back then Twitter and you know things were a lot different back then but then I had
one Reddit post that got I think 400 up votes and it was high intent like I was kind of talking about earlier thousand people signed up for my uh newsletter at
the time and that that was like the inflection point for the business I went from kind of not feeling good about this business idea and thinking okay maybe I'll go start something else and then that was the moment where starter story
was truly born even though it was months after actually building it and that's why I'm so you know excited about the growth accelerator because my goal with the growth accelerator is to help you
find help you experience that inflection point where all of a sudden you find something that works and you just do it over and over and that's what I did with uh Reddit I just posted the same content
over and over and over and I extracted the users from Reddit into my app onto my website into my email list and that's the other thing with getting attention
you know if you don't convert some of that attention to becoming customers then it's also worthless but yeah man Reddit is a tough place you got to go on there and have a thick skin you're probably going to get banned you're
probably gonna get Shadow banned yeah this is this is the petion right is that funny I think about this one so petition
to B Star Story so like I I just you know I this was this is the end I had milked it dry for everything it was worth at by this point
and uh you know there was it was so controversial starter story was so controversial because I was providing such valuable content that half the people were like okay like that's fine
you can promote your thing because this is so good and the other half were just mad about the promotion thing so it would if you read you know some of these comments in here you can see that people
like you know lowkey kind of supported yeah and that sort of thing but you know the mobs are crazy man
yeah that's funny right it's crazy I got two things I think one if I mean the cool story about that is we've made an actual video on the main YouTube channel
about that that's true so go check that out if you are interested in that full story two I think what's sick about this is Pat you did this so long ago like the
Reddit thing yeah and Dan Gorby's using it now and it just shows like the strategy is still working like I bet some people are probably like oh this is outdated you know this is not the move
anymore but it's literally proof that this still works it's just the method is probably a little bit different yep um but I think that's really cool too is that these things don't really die out
they just you just have to adapt to what works on it now yep yep yeah man it's crazy there are just millions of people hanging out on all these platforms you
just got to go get in front of them and there's it's not just Reddit you know you can do it on Tik Tok and all these other places and it's just waiting for you all you got to do is just try and eventually something will work all right
so uh thanks for guys for watching I hope you guys enjoyed those examples I mean uh go out and just try a couple of those things there's something you could potentially do and just a few minutes
obviously put some work into it don't just copy and paste it but doing this could change your business it could be that inflection point and I just really wanted to record these today to go over
them why they work and hope you liked it so it's cool to learn about these examples but now it's time to take the step to just put them into action if you have a project if you started things if
you're building features and you want something more then I think you should join the starter story growth accelerator we have a new accelerator starting at the beginning of the month and in this accelerator we will
challenge you to stop building features and start sharing and promoting and being Shameless and getting users getting paying customers and changing our life in the accelerator we gamify it
we incentivize you to do the actual marketing you'll do marketing every single day and it'll feel fun and once you start seeing the results you'll get addicted to it dozens of people are
seeing results in the accelerator every single month that we do it they're getting users they're growing Their audience and they're making their first dollars online and growing their businesses so if you're ready to work on
stuff that actually matters click the second link in the description and you can put your name in the Hat to join the next starter story growth accelerator thank you guys for watching and we'll
see you in the next one peace