Hey guys, welcome back to the dollar challenge where I, a complete beginner, do my best to build something with AI,
market it, and make my first dollar online.
In today's video, we have a pretty big update.
Uh, and so I'm I'm nervous.
I'm excited to tell you guys, but first, I'll tell you how we got there, what I learned along the way,
and what's next.
All right, let's go.
All right, so how did we get here?
So, in the last video, if you watched it, you saw me posting a bunch of stuff on Reddit,
all these different Reddit communities.
I'm just gonna be honest and say that did not work.
I think I got a few downloads from my posts, but really nothing more than that.
And so, um, I had to figure out, okay, what do I do next?
And the platform that I know the best, the platform that I'm on the best, and and just know how more or less how it works is X.
And so I decided, okay, I'm going to start posting more stuff on X about my building process and what I'm learning and things like that.
And so I want to share a few of my posts here.
But my my building public strategy is is very simple.
It's one just to share what I'm doing, two to share what I'm learning, and then three to be authentic about it.
I think for a long time, I struggled to figure out what to even post on X because I wasn't doing anything.
And the the easiest solution to that that I found is to build something.
Now that I built it, I have something that I can actually talk about.
So that's my strategy.
I'm not saying you should follow that.
I'm just saying that's what I've been doing and it has been working.
And there's lots of people that I follow online who I've learned this from.
I just want to shout out a few of them.
So I'll share my screen and and kind of give them a little shout here.
You've you've heard about them before for sure.
One guy is this guy named Rob Hollum.
he shares and he he was just on on the podcast last week.
He talks a lot about his building journey, where he's at now.
He he's building this super cool app, but before that, he was doing a bunch of stuff that didn't work.
So, I'd recommend following him.
Second, there's this person I follow, Sherry.
She we I've also talked about her on the Starter Story podcast.
She's built Peak Money and she just always shares her metrics, her app, what she's doing.
Now, she's doing these little videos.
That's really awesome.
And then one more who you all will know is Jack Fris.
I don't know if you all know, but a lot of you will know him.
He shares a lot about his app he's building PostBridge and other things obviously, but I love the way he talks about how his building process,
what he's learned, things like that.
And so those are a few people that I draw a lot of inspiration from.
A post that worked for me specifically and I think drew a lot of attention was this one here.
It's probably like the prime example of how I like to quote build in public.
You can go ahead and read it kind of on your own time, but you know, I just talked about how seven months ago I had heard of this thing called cursor,
but I kind of thought it was throughout.
You know, I saw all these people posting about it online.
Um, and I don't know, I just didn't believe that what they were talking about was true and still until I started really doing it myself.
And that's kind of how I built this app, one step at a time.
You know, my app was not yet approved.
More on that in a second.
But this post drew about 20,000 views.
And I I really love this line that I ended it with is my only regret is that I didn't start sooner.
And that's just one other thing that I've learned in this whole building challenge both here building online learning about how things work with cursor and claude and all that stuff is that I think I just
sat on the sidelines for so long.
I was so nervous to start.
I felt like I don't have an idea.
I don't know what to do, etc.
And the best thing I ever did was get started.
And I think the best thing you can do is just get started as well.
Now, let's talk about just the app store approval.
So, I think in the last episode I just had the test flight.
A lot has changed since that.
I mean, I feel like I'm making so much progress here in just a few days, but I had not yet got approved.
And just let me walk you through briefly what that was like.
So, putting stuff on the on test flight is not terribly hard, but it, you know, it's not super easy.
And so, my first submission I got, hey, we noticed an issue blah blah blah.
What I had to do was I had to resubmit kind of a video on how the app works.
Even when I did that, I got another message that was like changes needed.
I don't even remember exactly what the issue was or why it didn't get approved.
But again, at this point, I was feeling pretty discouraged.
I was like, what the heck is happening?
Like, why is this process so hard?
It was hard enough just to build this.
Now, I can't even get it freaking approved on the app store.
What's going on?
I I asked actually asked Claude or Chad.
I kind of ran it through some of the messages that it was that the app store was sending me and they helped me sort of fix it essentially.
And eventually I got to a place that said congratulations.
And this was awesome.
This was such an awesome feeling to say, hey, your app has been approved for distribution and some other,
you know, probably terms and conditions or stuff that I needed to know.
But but my app was approved.
It was an amazing feeling and yeah, I think a quick reflection on that is just it's probably nothing I would have ever thought was possible.
You know, when Pat challenged me to do this about a month and a half ago now for the purposes of this YouTube series,
like I I guess I thought I would, but in the middle, I was just kind of lost.
What this app turned into is kind of nothing that we talked about in that first episode.
If you go back and watch, that's probably a fun one even for me to rewatch.
probably feel and sound so naive in that episode.
But yeah, it's it was crazy to not only build it, but just go through the process of publishing it.
And let's see if I could quickly find this tweet.
I was like, I feel so stupid being nervous to press this button, submit for app review.
And yeah, I think there there's a big difference between building something and actually publishing it and shipping it.
And I finally got that feeling.
And uh for everyone out there who's watching this, who's gotten this far and is currently in the process of building it,
that's obviously an amazing accomplishment, your next step is to ship it.
So just press submit, press live, share it online.
Obviously easy for me to say cuz I'm at the other side of it.
In that moment, I was really scared, but yeah, that that'd be certainly something that I really urge you and push you to do.
And so when I finally published it, I posted this tweet, which to be honest, I thought was a banger.
You know, I thought, man, I'm going to post this and I'm going to get 20,000 30,000 views.
I'm on a roll here.
I only ended up getting 3,700, but I I just said, "Hey, you know, point of view, your first mobile app got approved.
I'm nervous."
kind of this try to I was trying to be authentic and I I tried to do this thing like I'm giving away 25 free downloads to the app.
Thought that was like an interesting poll.
So, I kind of posted this video and some more some more like screenshots of me like showing off that it's live on the app store.
I linked this U form which was a form that I thought I could collect emails on and then you know send them free codes.
I think at the end of the day I only ended up getting like 10 or 11 which you know that's not nothing more than my Reddit post but I thought I thought I'd run out and I didn't.
And then I also did this thing where I linked my actual app besides the U form in case there were people that wanted to find it.
And to my surprise, all right guys, I just got back from my short walk.
Um and I just wanted to share like three quick lessons.
Not that you're looking for lessons, but um I've learned a lot in this journey that I think you could benefit from.
So, first lesson really is that you just have to get started.
It sounds so simple.
Uh but for months, I sat on the sidelines watching other people build stuff with cursor,
watching other people make a few bucks online, and I was so skeptical.
I was so skeptical because I thought they must have some secret sauce.
They must have some uh big advantage that I just don't have.
I'm sure in many cases that is true.
Um, but I learned probably 10 times more from Pat challenging me, going into Claude and Chat GPT and just typing in and saying help me build this
using cursor to, you know, the full extent that I know to actually make it work.
And so that's one of my biggest lessons is to just get started.
The second lesson I've learned is to uh share your learnings online along the way.
I think a big thing that I've benefited from in my, you know, sharing and sharing in public,
building in public, is that I feel like I'm trying to be authentic.
You know, I'm not trying to be this guy who knows it all and I'm I'm just a 30-some year old dude who's trying to use these tools to build stuff.
I mean, obviously I'm biased to my story, but I personally think that's way more relatable than some 18 or 20 yearear-old,
and no no shame to them.
they're building awesome stuff, but um I feel like I I represent more of like a regular perspective and I'm sharing that authentically online.
And so as you're thinking about building stuff, I really encourage you to share it online,
whether that's Twitter or Instagram or somewhere else.
Um there's lots of examples of people that are building in public um that I think you should follow.
And my last lesson, this is a shameless plug, uh, but for starter story build, uh, we have a boot camp called the iOS boot camp where Roz,
he's the instructor, he guides you on how to not only find an idea for a mobile app,
but build it using cursor and then deploy it to TestFlight and a bunch of steps after that.
I watched a lot of those videos and I learned a ton uh, just how to get even get it live onto Test Flight.
I don't think I could have done it without some of that stuff that I learned in that Starry Build program.
So again, shameless plug.
I don't want to, you know, feel like I'm just shilling something, but I really do believe in that,
especially if you're a beginner, especially if you don't know where to start.
Um, it's a powerful tool and program that can help you essentially just take the right steps to get started.
So, I really encourage you to check that out.
We'll leave a link in the description, obviously.
Awesome.
Okay, let's get back to the video.
Sorry to leave you on that cliffhanger.
So, where was I?
I was saying that I had posted this link that, you know, if someone wanted to download it,
they could.
and people downloaded it.
So, I got this first message that said, "I have your code running on my phone now."
That was crazy.
This guy I've been following online, Yonyi.
He's awesome.
Definitely go follow him.
And I was like, "Oh my gosh."
Like, that is such a crazy feeling, you know.
Congrats.
Someone else posted that they had downloaded the app.
I I hadn't sent him the code or anything like that.
And a few other people DM'd me that they had sort of downloaded it.
And yeah, if you look in the my Apple developer account, I've made today, as of this recording,
25 bucks.
And that's not, you know, that barely covers the cost of cursor for a month, but that's okay.
You know, I think the the biggest thing and and I think on on on that sale, I think I posted this on the 12th of July.
Yeah, on July 12th.
The 12th I got one sale.
On the next I got five, then three, then three, and I think from here it's kind of gone down.
This was sort of the the rise of my post.
And it's it's not a lot obviously, but it is just such a cool feeling to know that I like,
you know, I I created this just out of not out of nothing, you know, like obviously a lot of this people have done this before,
thousands of times before me, but it's not something that I honestly ever thought that I could do.
If I think back to where I was at the beginning of this challenge and even when I started kind of getting to know Pat and and more about starter story,
it's just not I would have never thought that I would have actually built something in the world and shipped it and that people would press download and not only press download but press buy,
you know.
And I I posted this on Twitter just just today actually where I said let let me actually just pull this up where I said I posted this like nice picture that I took on my fancy camera that's back
there.
I said, "This feels bit better than any bi-weekly paycheck I've ever gotten."
And to be fair, I prefer the amount of money I get in my paycheck.
This is 25 bucks, and I won't even see all of it cuz Apple takes a certain cut.
But it feels better because it's mine, you know?
It's 100% mine.
It's something that I put out into the world, try to create a little bit of value, and that people whether they just did it cuz they followed me or they wanted to be supportive,
I don't really know.
But the point is that they they bought it and and and this is real.
That's such an awesome awesome feeling that I I hope you get to feel someday.
I'm not saying it's easy.
And I usually hate these sort of like, you know, guru success stories, you know.
I don't know.
When you watch these on YouTube, you're kind of like, okay, that's cool.
But you had certain things going for you.
And certainly I did too.
I have this channel.
I work with starter story, a proven brand.
There's all these like benefits that I have.
But yeah, I just I hope that you can get this feeling of of putting something out there into the world and and one person buying it.
Will this be a, you know, 10,000 per month business?
Probably not.
Actually, for sure not.
Well, I guess I shouldn't say for sure.
You you never really know.
But I think it's just something.
It's a starting point.
And and that's that's the best feeling I I can have.
And that's the biggest lesson I can take away from from my story, if you've been following,
is to challenge yourself, set a date before yourself or something, and get get your idea live into the world.
And so that brings me to the last question, which is what's next?
I I'm not sure, you know, I I can't say I knew exactly that I would get here, but I think my goal from now is just to continue sharing updates.
And so I'm going to continue to share what I'm doing.
I'm going to share, you know, more and more images of my app, you know.
So, what I love about my app is that it, you know, it challenges me and forces me to get outside and go on walks and I can,
you know, somehow easily, you know, show it off.
You know, this post doesn't get a ton of views, but it's something.
And I think I'm just going to continue to share online about all the different features I'm building.
So, what's coming, this one got a lot of views, too, actually, is I'm building widgets for my app.
I think this is going to be really awesome.
I'm going to ship that soon.
Here, there's some other features that I'm hoping to build.
notifications, maybe just a longer term like tracker, you know, habit tracker, things like that.
Who knows, you know, how far that'll get, but I want to run I want to run this all the way to the end.
And I I'm just going to continue posting online, sharing my wins and losses, sharing what works,
sharing what doesn't.
And that's I think that's the best I can do.
I'm sure there's other hacks short form or on Reddit that I can get better at, and I'll probably come back and do a video on those things.
I'm going to probably want to talk to some users, get some real feedback.
I actually had a guy DM me and say, "Hey, are you taking some feedback on this app?"
And I was like, I don't know.
I guess I am.
Sure.
So, I'll probably, you know, create a video about that.
What kind of feedback I'm getting and and different features I'm building.
But for now, the dollar challenge has been completed.
And I want to say thank you.
Thank you for supporting this journey.
Thank you for being part of it.
This isn't over.
This isn't a goodbye, but I'm proud of where I've landed.
I'm proud that I've made this dollar and maybe next is 100 and maybe after that a thousand and after that.
All right guys, thanks for being here.
I really appreciate it and we will talk soon.
See you.