all right guys today we're going to be answering the question can you replace your salary with a website that does one thing whatever you want to call it simple business ideas is what we're
going to be talking about today I got this database right here there's a bunch of simple business ideas real business ideas how much money they make just researching them thinking about why they actually work how they get traffic and I
think you're going to learn a lot from this so the first one I have here is Excel exercises so I'm just on starter story right here I'm just going to open this up in a new tab here so I don't really know what this does Excel
exercises sounds cool Microsoft Excel I'm guessing this guy makes $6,000 a month teaching people how to use Excel and I know that $6,000 a month is not that much but this is a single page
website so let's just go check out the page real quick um this is Excel exercises.com.au
like simple but we're going to talk about why it works so let's just like play around with it for a second cuz I just like to see how these things actually work so I'm going to hit get started and then boom they're putting me
right into a course on how to use Excel I haven't logged in I haven't done anything but now it's just saying format a number as a currency by holding control shift and hitting the dollar
sign I don't know how to use Excel but I just learned holy nice it gave me 15 54 points this could be all built with AI tools I feel like an AI could do this really easily there are so many
skills out there that people need to learn hundreds of thousands maybe even hundreds of millions of people use Excel every single day and they want to get better at it I want to figure out how this thing makes money right because I haven't had to pay any money yet so I'm
going to go back to the starter story case study on this and he's saying that the website brings in $4 to $6,000 a month okay cool it's not a whole lot of money right but I quit my job when
starter story was making about $4,000 a month then I got back all my time that's what's cool about Excel exercises right hundreds of thousands of people go to
this website and doesn't cost any money or time to serve them what I'm curious about is how did he get initial traction how did he get his first users I woke up
one day shortly after getting everything working and saw an email from stripe notifying me that somebody had paid for the annual subscription at first I thought I had made a mistake so he accidentally got his first Customer because he set things up on strip and
because he took money I think that's one thing I see people get wrong is they're afraid to charge money for their product just put the pay wall up you can create a stripe checkout Link in like 5 minutes
and if nobody buys it that's fine if they do cool what I'm also curious about is how this business makes money let's try to figure that out well where do they get customers and how do they make money what was the gross strategy for
Excel exercises and how do you scale the site grew a lot during covid people were bored at home they're wanting to teach themselves they looking for new jobs and trying to improve their computer skills that is the thing that I'm looking at
right there people are looking for new jobs or working on improving their skills that is never going to change think about what skills people want to improve now maybe it's not as much Excel
but maybe it's AI they want to get better at prompting they want to get better at using chat GPT they want to get better at llm text generation or photo generation that's the big thing
right now people are trying to upskill they're trying to improve so they can get a job right that's never going to change that's what I really like to look at in these cas studies but I'm going to do a little bit of Internet sleuthing on
this guy one of my favorite things to use is similar web it looks like his traffic is actually growing in yeah in November December maybe less people are interested in learning Excel by January
people are looking for new jobs the new year and his website gets 80,000 visitors per month which isn't a whole lot but I'm looking at some of the keywords Excel practice so people want
to do excel practice exercises I think that's pretty cool I wonder if you could build something something for coding practice exercises or AI practice
exercises or maybe even something that's more Niche that is like specific to finance or something like that I think that's cool and it reminds me of this really cool business boot dodev similar
type of business which I think is really cool but it's for coders and it's gamified exercises that you do in the browser that help you become a better
coder which I think people are are willing to pay for because it will help them get a job help them get a promotion just like the Excel exercises this is a case study worth checking out and the
money is crazy $236,000 a month is just crazy to me okay let's go back okay we're going to move on and show you more the simple website number two is called bank
statement converter this business makes $12,500 a month let's go check it out this is Bankston converter.com easily convert PDF bank statements for
thousands of banks into clean XLS format okay this is a onepage website this website right here makes $12,500 a month but why does this make $12,500 a month so let me I'm going to
go download a random bank statement online let's save this as and let's see novelty bank statement let's try uploading this so I'm going to upload
this here see I got to convert it to PDF which I don't even know how to do let's try PNG to PDF PNG to PDF here's another onepage website that
probably freaking crushes it right now I'm actually just finding this so this website right here PNG to PDF this website PNG to PDF gets 1.8 million
visitors per month and I'm guessing that the guy or the gal who created this has a bunch of websites PDF to PNG JPEG to PDF right they probably have a bunch of
domains like this oh you have it right here here we go PDF F to PNG doc to PDF look he's got all these things here and each of these websites probably does a
million depends on how popular that keyword is but they just running this keyword if you look you'll probably find that there's some sort of way that this is monetized oh look they've got it all
here this is crazy sorry this may be going on a tangent here uploading this PDF and let's see what happens it was lost in The Ether it seems anyways we all understand what this does right this
is going to take a PDF and give it to you an Excel format there's really no service that will do this for you even maybe some AI tools we'll try to do this but I'm guessing this website does it
really well let's go check out their traffic Bankston converter.com let's confirm you're a human it's not a chair okay bank statement converter.com gets
62,500 visitors a month that are just simply converting their bank statements but how do they make money that's what I want to figure out okay my name is Angus Chang and I built a bank statement
converter BSC he calls it it's used by accountants and small business owners so that is his cooler thing and I can see that being useful let's say for an accountant that would typically be
taking the PDF and retyping it over to excel this probably saves them multiple hours per week maybe even tens or 20 hours per week is is something that
they're doing constantly it's a really Niche audience but it's something that is used by actual businesses right at least small businesses which I think is cool and it looks like it's a recurring
Revenue model people are paying for this over and over again each month what I want to know is how is he getting traffic for this I tried a few things to attract customers the first one is cost
per click advertising for the first six months I spent about $1,000 USD on Google search ads sadly it brought in a lot less money than I spent on ads so that didn't really work and he turned
them off and this is what I like about reading starter story case studies is you get to see all the different things they tried so you don't have to make these mistakes yourself supporting more Banks BC works by identifying where a
bank statement is from and then running specific code for that bank uh if the conversion results aren't good often a customer will tell me and provide the PDFs they uploaded a side effect doing that was likelihood a user subscribed
increase massively which makes sense if you upload a statement and it doesn't convert properly you won't subscribe so seems like he tried a lot of things but actually the thing that worked for him is just simply making his product better
so if you supported more Banks if the result of the free generation just actually worked then people were really likely to subscribe because oh my God this is going to save me hours and it
actually works things actually working is half the battle right especially with a free tool like this you're going to get a lot of traffic it's got to actually work and that is unfortunately
something that I see a lot of people screw up it's pretty easy to just make something that actually works and a lot of times people just don't give a and and I think that's important to to point out he says he has 11,000 monthly
visitors and his business is doing $122,000 a month now he's doing 60 so multiply that by six it's not going to be that exact multiplier but let's just
say multiply it by four this business is potentially doing 440 to $50,000 a month $40 to $50,000 a month is crazy how can you do
something similar to this website I mean I think that this is like super cool right PNG to PDF we looked at that this is PDF to XLS but even more Niche right
it's just for bank statements imagine all the different types of things that people still need converted and actually this will be a lot easier to build now
with AI tools like this is actually like making me want to build something right now because his bank statement converter was actually really hard to build because he I think I believe he started
this before AI was really there I would go to chat gbt right now I would paste in I would take the entire case study copy this whole case study say I have a
case study I want to share with you I'm going to plug the case study in there I say what I think is really cool is that
it is Niche even more Niche than just a PDF converter it is a PDF
converter specifically for bank statements what other Niche ideas for conversion could
you come up with give me some ideas I'd love if it served high value clients
like accountants lawyers Etc let's see what I can come up with okay there's already a lot of cool stuff in here so it's pulling out four Cs and professionals I'm just going to read a
couple ones that just I see real quick tax document extractor that is actually a really cool idea if you can upload a W2 or 1099 which is these government forms are never going to change and
convert that into structured data boom that's huge right there that would be so good let's talk about lawyers and legal professionals so let's look here let's look at legal case PDF to structure data
convert court case PDFs into structure data for case management software court case PDFs that's the niche thing right there I'll just ask chat gbt are the
most popular case management softwares for lawyers okay boom so Cleo Cleo is the leading cloud-based platform for
centralized case management so boom I'm going Court caset to cleo.com right court case to cleo.com and this is my potential business idea look I don't
know if it's going to work but I think that's really cool okay last one we're going to go through the last simple website let's check out online soliter I like this one cuz it's going to be a little different as you guys know we try to interview people when they first
start their businesses on starter Tory but often times these businesses grow so this case study when we interviewed him and and learned about his business he was just making $11,500 a month which is
dope that's that pays your rent but now the business is doing $155,000 a month and actually I just caught up with this guy and is doing even more now let's see what this business does online solitire
I think it's pretty self-explanatory what it does boom you can play Solitaire dude who doesn't like Solitaire right every single kid m old people my age grew up playing solar on their computer
and I can just play it's exactly what you think it is like this is good this is really well done I like this a lot okay guys let's figure out how this thing makes money I'm going to go to my similar web which they're blocking me
out here but that's okay let's plug that in and I want to see how much traffic they're getting and also want to see where they get their traffic from okay online soliter holy this thing is
getting 441,000 visitors per month to play Solitaire and the average visit duration is 12 minutes and 48 seconds let's look at traffic
growth looks good it looks like 61% is direct that means that 61% of people are just generally just typing in
online soliter on their browser and then 31% organic search so let's try that out let's see online Solitaire he's not even
the number one result which that I think that makes it even cooler you don't have to be the number one result for your own domain to play solitire so let me just
look up play solitire right and he's not even in the top page onlin solitaire.com oh look you can play it on Google now but I bet it sucks and this is another
thing that I hear people talk about is okay Google will just take your product but this isn't as good this sucks this
is so much better right but let's go back to the number one keyword that they rank for solitaire is searched 8.6 million times a month that is
mind-blowing oh my God okay this is cool let's learn how he actually built the things building the product the initial design was an app so you can see it doesn't look as good a big surprise people thought there was something wrong with the game so I turned it into an
optional feature so how does he get customers users find soliter games by searching for them I've been optimizing my pages for moz's on ph optimization tool the site is not ranking super well but it's still getting around a th000
clicks a day from Google dude he's doing way more than that now he's doing 500,000 uh visitors per month so way more than this so it just grew naturally
I think that's really cool let's see how he built it uh the app is built in react with Firebase being able to handle users and database related things I made a downloadable version to desktop okay
let's talk about how you can make money on something like this I'm guessing it's almost fully ads so we go to starter story and let's see now it's makes $200,000 per year that's in
22 but I'm looking at another one of the case studies cuz we've interviewed multiple times as he spiled the website which I think is super cool I initially started the website as a side project and a bit over a year ago I implemented ads on the site and have steadily grown
the revenue from $1,500 a month to about $10,000 a month today and I think he's doing even more than that so let's go back to our chat GPT and say what are some highly searched games that are
maybe not as big as solitire but are popular and I just past it in let's see if chat can figure it out Hearts mind sweeper sodoku maang pyramids solitire Wordle I would go and look for old games
actually I want more data give me these in a table with the most active users in the world let's see bat gamon play Bat
gamon online let's look at this 247b gam.com let's go check this one out this is 247 games is not that great what I like about the solitire one is that it's a nice web based game right this is crap
but I'm guessing that this has crazy traffic 1.9 million visitors per month that is a freaking joke man okay by that
logic if that guy's website was making 400,000 and my guess is that he's probably doing close to $3 $40,000 a month it means that this bat gameing
website might be making a million dollar a year I would like to get some more data on that I'm going put my little notes so that we can get that sort of stuff but damn that's pretty crazy crazy
okay those are the three ideas I want to show you but there's tons of more I don't want to waste your guys' time and I cut I'm cutting this down look onepage website usually starts as one page website that's how you get the users and then you figure out how to monetize them you can monetize them with ads you can
monetize them with a backend product you can monetize them with courses or there's so many different ways to do it I think that building something simple is huge and what's cool is you can just
build it now and then over time it'll grow things like SEO or other things that people search for help it grow but it's not going to just going to happen overnight that's why I think it's cool to do little simple things and try lots
of different simple ideas see maybe this one will hit more than the last one and I think that's really powerful that's it I hope you guys enjoyed it you should definitely join starter story where you can download all this information look
up all these ideas and how all these actual real business ideas make money and do it yourself so come join starter story that's it signing off hope you guys enjoy it hope you guys like this
format have a good one