AI won't replace your job, but somebody using AI probably will.
At Starter Story, we study thousands of business ideas.
No doubt the biggest shift happening right now is AI being used everywhere.
In this video, we're going to break down the new memo by the CEO of Shopify that basically says if you're not using AI,
you're fired.
In this episode, we're going to talk about why that's such a big deal, what this means for you if you work in tech or really work at any company right now,
and how you can get started today tinkering and learning with the tools that will be the greatest skill of the next decade.
I think if you watch this video, you'll be even more optimistic about what's going to happen in the whole AI world.
So, please watch this through the end.
I think we talk about some really cool stuff.
All right, welcome to the Starter Story podcast.
Let's dive in.
I got Gus here.
Gus is a researcher at Starter Story and uh he looks at all sorts of business ideas and trends and things that are happening right now and we talk about them.
So, what do you got today, Gus?
Okay, so I was doing my usual scrolling on Twitter and I came across this post that you probably have seen or maybe even saw if you're online at all.
Let me just share my screen for a quick second here.
It it's this tweet by the CEO of Shopify.
Don't know who he is.
Toby Thuti probably pretty famous or whatever.
It's an internal memo that was getting leaked online and so he decided to just post it.
And so we're not going to I don't think we'll read the whole thing, but the main sort of takeaway that I had and we'll you know we're going to talk about this is he's basically telling his company AI is now
a fun fundamental expectation.
AI must be part of your I think GST means get done.
And then this last one we probably won't touch on this too much but before asking for more headcount and resources basically see if AI can do it.
Yeah.
And I found this really interesting because it's not that I think you know here at Starter Story and some of the people I follow online like on Twitter at least like a bunch of people are using AI to hack these
projects together to vibe code stuff to to build little tools.
But it feels like one of the first times that we've I've seen like whatever talking head big head CEO say like hey AI you got to use it
now in your everyday life.
Yeah.
I think what I used to hear from employees or CEOs and I'm not really in this world.
It used to be like if you use AI you're going to get in trouble because you are faking your job or not doing the work.
This is the first big shift I'm seeing where it's like actually you should if you don't use this then you're actually not doing good work.
So that's really interesting and maybe that's because the models have improved, you know,
from 2 years ago they've improved so much that now it's, you know, it's unquestionable.
For sure.
Yeah.
And so like my perspective is so I still work full-time.
I work for a big tech company and I remember at the beginning maybe a year ago or whatever we I heard of some people that were getting sort of little slap on the wrist for logging into chat
GPT or like you know there were sort of this sort of boundaries of like don't use it because whatever we can't trust it or it's not ready or it doesn't feel
real.
Yeah.
And that's kind of it's like obviously so different than like this memo.
I think what what was actually pretty interesting is is that one one of the last points that you mentioned from the memo is that instead of hiring someone,
you should try to just do it with AI.
And I don't think people would have said that before.
Maybe a lot of CEOs probably don't even have the balls to say that because that kind of implies don't hire hire bots over AI.
But I think that's kind of cool like if you are working in a company or you're building a startup or whatever to be able to have the skills to be able to use I think a lot of people might not
even know what to do.
Can we use AI to do this?
Yeah.
Okay.
You can go log into chat GBT or whatever, but how do you actually do that?
Yeah.
It's funny cuz like I have some friends that I chatted with a while back and he works in like I think he works for the state.
He he made a comment to me that was like, "Hey, have you heard of this thing called Chad GPT?"
This was like a month ago.
I was like, "Of course, dude.
You haven't?"
And he was like, "No, I just found out like it writes like pretty good emails."
And I was like, "It does way more than write good emails."
But yeah, it's kind of like this this idea that it's like changing everything, you know?
And so I kind of have like three main points I want to riff on, I think, when it comes to this memo that that I was thinking about.
So the first one is like this idea of like don't put your head in the sand.
Yeah.
And I think like I mentioned a company I I I worked for.
I think that was a little bit of the approach at the beginning and I would say eight out of 10 people in my everyday life kind of still think that AI is Yeah.
a silly little tool.
Yeah.
To play with like it's not serious.
I mean, thinking back to when I was working, I just remember like how excited everyone was when I would show them a spreadsheet with a pivot table because they didn't know how to use a pivot table and it was like this
really kind of scary hard thing to do because Microsoft Excel is not userfriendly.
I feel like AI is that like times 1,000 where now you can go to your co-workers or your boss or whoever and be like,
"Hey, look at this pivot table."
But actually, it's like doing the work of an entire team, right?
is before you couldn't cut the data.
You know, the pivot table solved that or whatever.
Now, this is, hey, I just automated this thing that, you know, we spend all these meetings about and it just does it or I just improved this process by 10x because,
you know, I automated whatever.
If you have those skills, you're going to get promoted.
You're going to get raises.
You can start your own business.
And that it's actually funny because I just remember I had talked to this guy who he he started his own company while he was working a full-time job.
He built a GPT rapper.
It was all AI based thing and he was working full-time job and his boss pulled him into a room and this actually happened to me too when I started my business.
So I I felt those emotions.
He's like you feel so scared like that you're going to get in trouble.
You know what?
You're going to get fired.
And his boss said, "Dude, I saw what you built.
That's awesome.
and can you help us do AI projects here cuz we really really need help for all the same reasons we just talked about earlier is that it can
you know cut costs, improve workflows, make more money and these sorts of things.
So this like you said if you're putting your head in the sand and just saying oh okay maybe I'll use chat GBT like when I need it.
No, go and start playing with these tools.
See what's possible.
still so early and you'll probably find like 10 things that you can improve at your company that your boss or the CEO like of Shopify will be like,
"Dude, thank you for doing this.
Like, can I give you more things to do?"
Yeah.
I kind of feel like there's, you know, it's not that simple, but like two types of people,
right?
It's like people that are putting their head in the sand and saying like, "This is stupid."
And then if you're probably watching this, hopefully you're not like that cuz how did you land on this podcast?
Like not not knowing about AI tools.
But yeah, the second type is like someone who's like, "Let me just go see.
Let me just go play around with it."
Like, yeah, it's not that expensive to do or, you know, not that expensive to learn.
Yeah.
Just like get things like done in a more like efficient way.
And I still think I'm using like 1% of what I could actually be using it for.
So, I feel like yeah, that's kind of the way the world's moving for better or worse.
And yeah, that's sort of like one of my first things.
Yeah, this trend is is different.
You know, it's like often these different things will come up.
the no code trend and the crypto trend and all these different trends but this is different because there for those that we are changing our culture to do you know whatever the NFT or whatever it is
this is actually you know changing everything and it's still early too you know it's still like very very early days I saw Toby's response or the the
CEO of Shopify had a response to one of the comments on Twitter and it was saying like what do you actually use AI for and his response was basically mostly internal stuff.
That's that tells me like that AI is good.
It's getting there.
Eventually, it'll do a lot more, but right now it's good for like a lot of internal things,
which if you're working in any sort of company or anything like that, that's like that's lowhanging fruit,
right?
So, that this is where it starts.
It's only going to get crazier from here.
Almost real like it's actually him eating spaghetti.
And the point was like, what is it going to look like in 700 more days?
Yeah.
Like, and that's how fast these things are moving.
That's that's the difference.
There's that famous line that says this is the worst it's ever going to be.
Yeah.
And that's kind of it's borderline scary to think about it that way.
It's only going to get better.
And the difference now is it's actually use unlike crypto and all these other trends.
It's actually useful and being used and it's only just going to get more useful.
And yeah, it's kind of a crazy thought.
Yeah.
But yeah, so that kind of leads to my second point is which we already started touching on is like if you're watching this like you're you're so early.
Like you it's it's almost hard to especially for someone like me, I'm like really on Twitter a lot.
I'm seeing all the stuff that people are building.
It's easy for me to look at some of that stuff and be like, man, I'm like way behind.
I haven't built necessarily my own app.
I haven't launched XYZ thing.
All the ideas are taken.
We talk about that a lot and and they're being taken every day even faster because people are building with AI.
But like I mentioned a little bit ago, like my friend who just discovered Chad GPT a month ago is my age.
I talked to most a lot most people in my life don't use AI on like a regular basis.
A question to answer or talk about is like how can I start using this now because it is still so early.
Yeah.
What I think is interesting is like when you go online it can be kind of scary because everyone's using all these buzzwords.
So there's, you know, we know of chat GBT, we know how to use it.
you just go online and you do it.
But there's all these buzzwords.
There's AI agents, MCP, blah blah blah.
All these things.
It's all right?
It's all people just trying to, you know, sell you something or over complicate something.
This what software they do in software engineering too is they have all these over complicated things.
But when you actually just start playing with these tools, you realize that they're actually really simple and they are designed so you can really do anything that you want.
And also what you realize is like a lot of the it's it's it feels like it's too late when you go in there and there's all these big terms and all these scary things and like the AI agents is one example of it is like you go in there and you realize that the AI
agents they don't actually work.
They are just an idea for the future of where it's going to get and it's going to eventually get there but they don't actually work right now.
Even chat GBT's operator which is like their big AI agent you know it's got to go it can't get through captions as if it screws up all these different things.
And I think if you just start going playing with these tools now, you'll see how early it is and you'll realize how early you are when right maybe if you're looking at it from outside it feels late but you go in
there and when you see this is my favorite thing is to go in there and see how everything is broken and I'm like oh actually like I'm so early to this right now.
All I need to do is just show up and I am ahead of 99% of people.
And when it gets to the point where it's like actually working, I will get that massive raise or I'll be able to start a company or whatever.
It's so early and that's actually the time where you want to be in there because you can just ride the wave,
right?
Totally.
There's this massive AI wave that all you need to do is just get on and do basic stuff.
It's like if you were on the just learning the word processor or Microsoft Excel, right?
All you needed to know was how to do a filter and you were God, right?
Or how to do a pivot table and you were God.
You didn't need to know macros or, you know, all these different things.
All you needed to know was how to set up a AI agent or something basic like that.
I think we've this is more like heady, but like things move so fast nowadays that it's easy to that things like AI building with AI feels like almost old
news.
It's still not.
It reminds me of I think I've referenced this before, but some podcast I listened to where it was like 10 years ago where the host asked another guy like,
"Is it too late to start on YouTube?"
Like, and imagine imagine asking like, "Is it too late to start on YouTube?"
Like 10 years ago.
And I think it's hard for me and people in general to have like that kind of time horizon kind of thing,
you know, like what is this going to look like in 10 years?
Nobody knows.
Yeah.
But it's pro it probably won't look like it looks like today.
But it I think like you said this is something I think that's here to stay.
Yeah.
In in different than any other like recent trend we've seen.
And so you should get into it.
You should start using it.
You should start playing around with it because in times that by 10 years Yeah.
it'll be like you'll be 10 years ahead of everyone who's saying we'll see what it looks like then.
Yep.
I mean it's going to look a lot different in 10 years but and it's moving really fast.
like you know what was some popular thing in AI last year is different now but AI solves a real business problem and there's no ever getting around that
so it's like if you're just hoping that it's going to you know eventually phase out which most of these trends do it's not possible for this to phase out because it helps people be more be more
productive which saves costs and generates more revenue and there's no ever getting around because it's capitalism you know get on the wave or or get the off you Yeah,
for sure.
Shameless plug.
I think it's a good time to pull up our starter story build.
I mean, we're talking about AI right now.
I was talking about how this is the most valuable skill of the next decade.
Whether you work in a company, you're building internal tools or you want to build a side project that cash flows that right now is doing anything in AI
and you'll be set for life, I think.
So, we have launched our new product, Starter Story Build, which is an entirely new product that helps teach people the most valuable skill of the next decade,
which is wrangling these AI tools.
There's lots of different tools out there, but Starter Story Build is focused around project-based learning.
So, you go and build one specific thing over the course of about 12 to 15 days.
You have an idea, you come up with the idea, you build it, you launch it, you get it live,
you get a real thing.
So you go in there with an idea and you come out with a a project or a product and you also come out with the skills to build anything you ever want.
So you can go to your boss and you know tell them about some internal tools you can build or automate a process or build more startups and you know change your life.
So for example we have the AI app boot camp where you will learn tools like lovable subabase github open AI APIs and you'll do that over the course of 12 days.
We have our resident expert Lazar who has built 50 product projects in lovable.
We have office hours where if you ever get stuck, you can get unstuck and over the course of 12 days,
you'll build something awesome.
So, I think it's amazing.
Promise that you will come out of it with a real product if you follow the steps and and do it.
And uh yeah, I think it's awesome.
So, check that out.
We'll put the link in the description.
The AI app boot camp, which is a part of our new product starter story build.
I think you'll love it.
All right, let's get back into it.
Awesome.
So my last point is just maybe some takes, some like optimistic versus pessimistic takes of like this whole AI thing.
I saw this LinkedIn post which I thought was really interesting.
You know, I'm not so on LinkedIn, but I randomly went on there and let me share my screen again.
It's from this guy and I feel like I know him from somewhere but I couldn't place it.
Okay, my screen's up here.
Shopify CEO to 8 8100 employees.
Show me why AI can't replace you.
34% couldn't.
they're gone.
Calling it like a PR spin for layoffs.
I don't know.
I think that's a pretty negative take on the situation.
And you know, it's always more complicated than that.
Yes, Shopify has had layoffs.
Yes, AI is essentially taking jobs from certain people, but you know, there are AI pessimists out there for sure.
Like, there's definitely always going to be AI pessimists out there, and they're not wrong.
I mean, think about it.
There's certain jobs that are are gone now.
People that write papers for you in college, there's people that will write your papers for you.
That is gone or at least those paper writers are now using chat GBT as well to do it.
So AI is going to take jobs for sure.
It's definitely going to take away jobs from people that are don't want to use it or are against it or whatever.
There's no going back on that.
If you want to work in corporate America or or do anything, the focus is on productivity always,
unless you're doing art or something like that, right?
So, I think that if you're pessimistic about it, that's a bad place to be.
I don't know.
What do you think?
Yeah.
I mean, my my pessim my most pessimistic take is like I work in tech and I work more in the like customer supportish side of things.
So, my pessimistic take is like I'm screwed.
Like that's what it feels like.
Like when AI can sound like a human, write like a human, talk like a human, do it faster,
know everything, all that all that stuff, you're just like, "Well, shit."
Yeah.
I'm done.
You know, and I imagine like there's people watching that are in that same boat.
They have like a full-time job that or like, you know, do a certain thing that you can sort of if you if you see the future,
you're like, "Okay, this is going down a route of this probably won't exist in 5 years."
So that so, you know, if I expand that out, you're just like, "Oh, yeah."
the pessimistic viewers makes people lose their job.
But my question for you is okay, if you have that that that's the pessimistic side of that take.
What's the optimistic side of that take?
Like how would you how do you see people inside your company navigating that and you yourself too?
Yeah, my company right now it does feel like there's those two camps like there's people that are just like I'm not going to pay attention to this.
What happens happens and those are the folks that are just going to for better or worse maybe get left behind on some of this stuff.
I I think that's probably like a majority if I'm honest because there's just like not a lot of folks that are talking about like how they're use it still feels like a bad word.
AI still feels like a bad word.
I don't know what that says about my company or people there.
It's just that's just what it feels like there's a few people that are trying to use it in a way that makes them like more productive.
I think for me my like most optimistic take on this whether that's inside this my company or like outside of it is like that it's going to open avenues that you know like right now a big trend that we've been talking
about is like vibe coding or whatever.
Not saying I'm going to go build an app or anything like that.
Maybe I will, maybe I won't.
I can.
Yeah.
Like if I put if you put your head down to it, you you you probably could.
There's stories you're seeing every day, people are talking to that are doing it.
people inside our, you know, the Star story build boot camp that never coded a day in their life that are like building stuff.
And so I think there's those opportunities probably my my last thing is like because there are people who are still like slow to adopt AI,
you could probably use that to your advantage.
So for example, like you mentioned the paper writers that are out of potentially out of work.
The optimistic take of that is like there's still millions of people that are going to resist using AI and are going to want to hire paper writers.
you can just use it then do it faster for more people and you know make more money or or or work less or whatever.
So I don't know something like that those are some of the things I think about.
Yeah.
I mean I just like as a hiring manager someone I hire people at starter story and you know assess productivity and that sort of stuff.
I think at first I was annoyed when people were using AI with stuff because I could tell for example if it was copyrightiting or something like that I'm like this is done by AI and it's not good.
So, I think there's like a there's like this class of people who are using AI as a lazy shortcut,
but then when I hear someone like you, you working on some stuff and I know that you use AI in your workflows,
but it comes out better.
And that's the same way that I personally use AI when if I'm doing something is like I'm using this to be better.
And as long as you can do that as someone who hires people, fires people, promotes people,
and that sort of stuff.
If I see that you're doing that and you're being more productive, then I'm happy.
And if I if if he take if it's taken to even the next level which is you know this has been automated or this has been removed eliminated or you know we we 2xed it or
whatever and you used AI to do that then I'd be even more impressed and like that other guy I was talking about where you know he didn't get fired he got basically promoted.
I'd be looking for people to lead AI projects because my boss, if I had a boss is wanting me to increase productivity or,
you know, increase the profits or, you know, hit my goals or bonuses or whatever.
So, that would be I think the optimistic take on it is I think my last point, the optimistic view is like it's kind of fun.
Like I do think there's an element of that like it's cool to be able to make things run faster or or create things that just would be take longer,
be harder, you know, maybe more impossible to make exist.
And like I don't know, I I do think there's like an opportunity there to like bring something to life that you probably or maybe wouldn't have done as fast by using something like AI to make that happen.
That's it.
I mean, I remember working in in corporate and if you can be that, you know, young kid or whatever that comes to the meeting with,
you know, the AI agent that is solving the problem.
It's just like coming with the pivot table from 10 years ago.
It's like you're going to impress everyone.
It's fun.
People are excited.
They and that will probably open up, you know, more excitement about AI in general because,
oh, hey, this can do this thing.
Or even maybe it's something as simple as, hey, after the meeting's over, here are all the notes.
I put together this notes thing.
And like basic stuff like that, I'm sure is like, whoa, this is actually really helpful and this is awesome.
This is when you get the promotion.
Like building cool internal tools.
That's like my like if I was working at a company, I would always be like excited to,
you know, try to automate something or improve some sort of process or, you know, just impress the folks around me because I was more of the tech guy or the tools and technology type of person.
I didn't really care as much about the sales or whatever.
I was like, let's like build a cool app that can help us do this or let's build a small process that could improve this.
I think a lot of people watching this probably feel similar to that is that they like building things and like if you can just do that at a company that's pretty cool.
Awesome.
Well, yeah.
I hope you guys enjoyed the this episode of the Starry Podcast.
We tried something a little bit different talking about this kind of groundbreaking new press release from this CEO uh of Shopify about how AI is going to change everything.
And why we wanted to talk about it is that I think that this does affect everyone.
If whether you work in a company, whether you're starting your own business, whether you're running your own business and you have employees,
this is the beginning of, you know, the end as they say.
So, I'm just I'm super nerding out right now on AI tools, cursor, lovable, playing these tools.
We have the AI build accelerator where you actually build something.
And like I said, it all feels kind of scary and crazy right now, but in our AI build accelerator,
you will build something in 12 days.
And yeah, it doesn't really work that well.
You know, you have to kind of maggyver the prompts and do all these kind of like door stuff,
but as we said earlier, this is the worst it's ever going to be.
So, if you can kind of learn how to, you know, finagle these things now when other people can't,
that's what the real value is.
So, I think it's early.
I'm excited.
That's why I wanted to make this podcast.
And uh hope to see what you guys build with AI.
Thanks for watching.
We'll see you in the next one.
Let us know in the comments what you thought about this sort of new format, but otherwise we'll see you in the next one.
Peace.