Oh mighty gods of open AI, I come to you a humble vibe coder.
Please, I need GPT image access in the API so I can make content for my YouTube channel.
I'll do anything.
You call Sam Alman.
It's you.
Please.
I need GPT image API access.
I need content.
I need thumbnails.
I need views.
Without it, I'm nothing.
H I could grant you access, but only under one condition.
Anything.
I'll do anything.
You must sell me your soul.
Oh, I already did that.
You did?
Yeah.
Yeah, I already sold my soul because I'm launching the GPT40 image boot camp.
In 2 weeks, you'll build exactly what I'm building, a real life production web app that uses the GPT40 image API.
You'll build side by side with me.
Daily videos, daily projects, live office hours.
You'll come out the other side with a real life app and you don't even know how to code.
Oh, that's pretty cool, actually.
Can I join?
Sure, you can.
The link is in the description, but you'll have to sign up quick because I might only run it one time and I'm going to keep it very,
very limited.
But please, please, you need to give me access so I can do it.
Access granted.
Granted.
Wait, really?
Let's go.
Yeah.
Woo!
[Music] Woo!
If you're new here, I'm doing the 100K build challenge where I will attempt to make $100,000 using only AI.
This is how far I am.
And if I'm being honest, this is turning out to be a lot harder than I thought it was going to be.
Before we get into that, let me remind you the rules of the challenge.
Rule number one, I will document everything on this channel, so please subscribe.
Rule number two, I can only use AI tools.
And rule number three, I will not stop until I make 100K.
And I'll probably have to try a lot of different things along the way.
I'm not going to give up on this.
And that is my one big promise to you.
Things are starting to move really fast in the challenge right now.
Lots of good things are happening and even more bad things are happening.
And we're going to get all into that in today's episode.
This is episode 4.
And in this episode, I'm going to talk about how I build and how I focus in even super distracting environments like being on an airplane or being around Bernie,
this crazy dog right here.
In this episode, you're going to see me set up Stripe and monetizing my app to take payments.
You're going to see again lots of feature building, feature prioritization, scoping things down,
and removing a feature so I can get to launch.
You're also going to learn my super secret trick to forcing yourself to launch on a specific date.
And spoiler alert, it's not what you think.
And lastly, unfortunately, you're going to see me bang my head against the wall in so much frustration and nearly give up on vibe coding forever.
All right, this one has a lot.
It was super fun to put together.
This is day four of the 100k build challenge.
Let's go.
Okay, so I had to wake up really early, like 5 in the morning and get on a 5-hour flight across the country.
I was going to my best friend's bachelor party.
So, I got on the plane and I said, "Fuck it.
I'm going to buy this Wi-Fi and I'm going to try to see if I can vibe code on this plane,
which worked surprisingly pretty well.
It worked better than I thought it was going to be.
But unfortunately, I couldn't narrate and kind of bring you guys along for exactly what I was doing because I was sitting in the middle seat and there was like an older lady sitting
next to me.
She kept asking me uh that I could fix her her Wi-Fi and I was trying to kind of remain a little bit more incognito while I was coding.
But I was able to record my screen and I'm going to walk through everything that I built.
Uh some parts are going to be kind of fast forwarded through cuz the Wi-Fi was really shitty.
But this was my build session.
Let's jump in.
All right.
So, right now I'm just adding my to-do list and my little handy dandy notepad right here.
This is just Apple notes.
And you know, I know that I have a couple hours on the plane.
So, um I know there's a lot more to do, but these are the things that are just coming to mind right now that I need to do and I'm just writing those down so I'm not kind of questioning what I need to do next.
And I look, I wrote get payments set up twice, which I didn't even realize I had written at the time.
I just know I need to get stuff done.
And look, I don't need to write down 100 things.
Just need to get the next things done.
And as I remember more things, I'll just add them to my checklist as I go.
So, the first thing I decided to do is let's just get payments set up.
I want to use Stripe to be able to take payments because this is an app that's going to cost money because it's hitting um you know,
different API or AI models that cost money every time I run them.
I know I'm going to charge for this app from the get- go u because I want to make money with it and not lose money.
So, I'm just setting up Stripe, which you know, you need to do all the basic setup stuff on Stripe and get your API keys.
And um this is a brand new Stripe account getting set up right here.
So, hopefully this Stripe will have some money in it someday.
Uh at at this moment, I'm just using the sandbox environment, so the test environment cuz I'll be able to use fake credit cards just to test that payments will actually work so that when the first user comes in and decides to
pay for it, um they can.
Again, my goal with this whole vibe coding series is not to write a single line of code and get everywhere I needed to go with only prompts.
So, I'm writing in here, I would like to add a Stripe integration.
Um, I'm telling it exactly what I did, right?
I'm I just created a new account in Stripe, and I don't really know what I'm doing, but I think this is what I need to do.
I'm telling it, hey, I'd like you to use Stripe Checkout, which is, you know, a very well-known uh basically way to way to use payments.
This is a very known well well-known way to use payments without having to code up a lot of stuff.
It'll just go to Stripe's pages, but it feels like it's still on your page.
And then I'm telling it to uh require the user to pay $5 to then what will happen after they pay the money.
So I sent it that prompt and let's see if it can figure out what to do.
So it's going and you know Stripe has great docs, great documentation on the internet of how all their code works.
So, it's using the amalgamation of all the different code samples online on how to use Stripe and all the open- source uh code repositories that it's
finding.
And I have a good feeling that it's going to be able to implement Stripe potentially on its first try just because there's so much good code uh so much good documentation out there on how
to implement Stripe and uh this hopefully taking payments should be one of the easiest things we have to do in our app.
So, this is a bug that I ran into right here.
Uh, I'm basically just taking the bug, pasting it back into cursor, and seeing if it can figure out uh what how to fix that bug.
So, it ran into one bug, and it's giving me some ideas.
And now, it's implementing that bug.
Okay, so I think I fixed the bug.
Now, I want to test that I actually fixed the bug.
So, I'm uploading a file, and I want to see if it actually asks me for payment once I click generate thumbnail.
[Music] Um, it looks like I think the internet was so crappy on this plane Wi-Fi that it was holding up for a second there,
but I think it's going to work.
Just give it one little second here.
This is Stripe Checkout working as advertised right here.
It's asking for $5.
Oh my god, this is amazing.
This is pretty cool where you don't really have to write any code, but you can take payments for your app.
You can charge for subscriptions.
They can cancel their subscription.
They can upgrade.
All this can be done with cool tools like Stripe Checkout.
Stripe is an awesome company.
Obviously, you would probably know this if you're watching this, but super easy to integrate.
Obviously, free to use and um you know, I'm going to test it right now with my credit card,
which or the Stripe fake credit card, which is 4242 42 4242.
You do 42 on everything.
And let's see.
And boom, it took us to localhost 3000/stripe/success, which is a page on our website with a giant check mark.
Doesn't really work.
Um, but I basically got payments working with two prompts.
I wish I could have done it in one prompt, but I did it in two prompts, but that's okay.
And um, that's pretty amazing to be able to get all your payments working with two prompts.
And hopefully that's helpful for someone watching to see how easy it is.
So I can see that my test payment went through on Stripe and I got my five first $5 payment even though it's fake money.
It's not real money, but I can see that it works so that when this eventually goes live,
it looks good.
Okay.
So at this point, I've decided to change up how my app's going to work.
And instead of asking them to go to chat GBT to put the prompt in, I decided and spoil spoiler alert uh by the end of this video,
you'll see that will change again.
But basically what I'm doing here is I'm changing it so that um we will do our image generation on the back end while we wait for the hot swap.
And it's all not really that important to go through all this here, but um basically I'm just asking it to change up how it works.
and it's doing a really good job of that.
I mean, um, these are pretty big changes that would take a while to do if I were writing them with code,
but Vive Coding is actually making it pretty easy and it's doing a lot of the busy work that I would have to do before if I was writing all this with code or using,
you know, more clunky noode solution or um, you know, yeah, some sort of website builder or something like that.
This is like pretty amazing how fast it's making these changes.
Again, I'm just running into bugs here and saying, "Hey, I don't want to see the Stripe checkout link until you um click the button that says order your
thumbnails."
Now, I want to move over to some design stuff because I know I want to make my landing page look a little bit better.
I'm still not super happy about my landing page.
So, what I'm doing here is my buddy Danny Postma has a really cool uh service or business that you does AI head shot.
It's a little different than YouTube thumbnails, but basically I just love his design.
I'm a huge fan.
And um what I want to do is I want my website to look a little bit like his cuz I know that he does a bunch of testing on his website,
a bunch of AB tests, and he's really really good at conversion.
So, I said, why don't I just kind of steal a little bit of his style from his page and let's see if Cursor can um kind of take his style
and do it for YouTube thumbnails cuz I think that will save us a lot of time if we do that.
And at this point, I'm just really not happy about how my website looks.
So, I took a screenshot of this right here and I'm just going to pass this to cursor and let's see if it can make my landing page look a little bit better.
Okay.
And now I'm just asking it, hey, I want in my landing page specifically, I want to add a new element with that has a bunch of social proof cuz social proof is that one thing that I really want to make sure uh I
think it's really important for landing pages or marketing in general is saying like,
hey, here are real examples of thumbnails, how they looked before, how they looked after,
and here's how many people are using our service, and here are the successful people that are using our service.
Obviously, my service doesn't exist yet.
So, the really only social proof we'll be able to do is my thumbnails for my YouTube channel or that I've actually created using the service,
which doesn't exist yet, but I still want to get the template set up so that I can just kind of go and replace it.
Basically, I want it to look good.
I want it to look potentially good and then go and replace um the placeholders.
And there it is.
Right.
This is my new social proof element of my landing page.
Obviously, it says logo one, logo two, logo three, example one, example two.
I'm going to fix all this and change it so it makes sense.
And obviously 2,943 AI thumbnails were not created with our app.
So, we're going to have to change some of that eventually, but starting to like how this looks.
And I know, okay, if I can make this look good, then that's half the battle, right?
It's got to look good.
It's got to look professional.
I'll fill out the data later.
Um, but I'm starting to like how it looks because I want someone to land on this page and be like,
"Oh, oh, wow.
This is legit."
Like, people actually can make nice thumbnails with this.
And because my again, my number one goal is not to get something that works.
At the end of the day, I need it to create good thumbnails, right?
So, I first want to show that you're getting great thumbnails.
This is worth your time, and it will help your YouTube channel, help grow your audience just because you have better thumbnails.
Okay?
And now what I want to do is I'm trying to make the homepage look cool cuz right now when you look at it,
it just says choose file.
It's not really clear what the thing does.
So what I want to do is I want to have like a big fat thumbnail right when you land on or at least just like a blank canvas because the our thumbnail maker is all
about drawing on a blank canvas.
Um and just getting the user to just be able to immediately start drawing and messing around with stuff right when they land on the page.
So I want that to be present.
So now I'm prompting cursor to go in and um make that look cool right when you land on the page.
And now what I'm doing is, you know, I just realized that, okay, I'm getting pretty close to what I wanted to get done in this session.
Now I know there's a bunch more things that just came to my mind of things that I want to add and clean up.
And I'm kind of in landing page mode right now.
So I wrote down I want to remove the pricing because that's not really going to be important.
The login, there's not going to be a login for this.
Um remove the language thing.
Like why is this English thing here?
Um, I'm trying to really kind of simplify things down and cut things out right now because the AI created a bunch of um,
you know, links and buttons and this sort of thing.
Well, I got to remove those.
So, I'm just putting those into my to-do list as I go.
More will come, but I just wanted to remind myself to do that.
Now, what I'm doing is I'm adding basic authentication to my app.
And by basic authentication, I mean, I want anytime that someone goes because my app is not ready yet and I don't want someone to like steal my all my API credits,
my open AI credits to spend a bunch of money on my account.
I'm just setting up username and password authentication so that when you go to my website right now,
it requires a username and password to see anything because I'll take that off eventually when it goes live.
But yeah, and now I'm reading your guys's comments right now because uh you know, sometimes the cursor takes so long to load and I was on shitty airplane Wi-Fi that I love to
read you guys' stuff.
So please, if you're watching this right now, leave a comment, give me some advice, give me some feedback,
tell me what you like, tell me what you hate.
I love I love reading every single comment in there other than the software engineers who think I suck at software engineering because I do.
I do.
Okay.
Now, I'm adding my domain.
This is one thing that I wanted to get done is make hook up my domain name, a thumbnailsmaker.com.
I think that's what it is.
And I'm hooking that up to my namecheep account and my Cloudflare and getting everything to work and hooking it up to Heroku.
You guys probably don't care all that much about this, but it has to be done.
Now, I'm just trying to log in.
It was the the Wi-Fi was so the Wi-Fi was so bad that it was almost impossible to do this stuff.
That's why it's like going so slow.
Uh but yeah, now I'm just asking chat GBD how to set up name servers.
You know, this is stuff that I don't really do that often and I usually screw it up and then it takes 24 hours and I screw everything up.
So, I just want to make sure I do it right.
So, I'm just asking ChatGBT exactly what I should do in my situation and it's giving me an amazing step-by-step tutorial,
which I think is super underrated.
Um, tell me exactly how to do it and I'll be happy.
Now I'm just committing up my codebase up to GitHub.
Uh which it already forgot that I had a Git repository.
And I know all that software engineers that have been in my comments saying you don't even know how to use Git and you don't even know how to deploy basic things.
Well, yep, you're right.
I guess I'm a fraud and I don't know anything because I didn't memorize every single Git command.
And this isn't something that I personally someone as someone who's been building products for a while.
It's not something that I think about.
It's just literally just a way to save my code and I don't think about how to commit stuff.
I just think about I just have I just know like the three commits I need to do to commit it up.
But I just want to make sure I do it right because it's a new repository.
Okay.
So now I'm just doing more cleanup stuff like I am removing a lot of the unnecessary buttons on the page and just trying to just kind of remove stuff that the AI
kind of erroneous erroneously added.
Um I'm trying to add that that big canvas on start creating your thumbnails.
And I'm just prompting this here on exactly how to do this.
And I think at this point the Wi-Fi uh completely went to and I just gave up.
I got really impatient with it and I closed my laptop for the rest of the flight and I just said screw it.
I'll I'll figure this one out later.
And that was pretty much the beginning of my first plane session.
The Wi-Fi was better.
I would have been happier, but that's it.
And at that point, I landed in Southern California and got on my merry way off to the bachelor party.
So, I just arrived here in beautiful Los Angeles, as you can see by the many clouds in the sky,
and I am walking into the bachelor's house right now.
The soontobe married man.
I I haven't seen him in a while, but I know he's been watching the vlogs, so I actually have an idea.
LA.
All right, we are on our way up to the bachelor party.
Uh the soon to be married man here and soon to be married man's brother, Daniel Lron.
All right, so dude, you know this new challenge I'm doing, right, with the vlog?
I'm building an app with vibe coding until I make $1,000.
$1,000.
Until I make $100,000 and uh you know, like 100,000 people watched the first episode and now I'm like that's crazy.
I'm like pretty nervous about it.
I thought that nobody was going to watch it and now there are like thousands of people waiting to see it when I actually ship and like I'm actually really nervous and now I feel like it has to be perfect.
Oh, you got this.
Classic Pat.
Exactly.
But I I have an idea to give myself a little bit of accountability.
Why don't I make a bet that if I don't launch this by the end of the month, I will pay you $1,000.
Wow.
Can I get in on this, too?
Yeah.
Sounds like a good deal.
I'll pay you a thousand.
Oh, wow.
Wow.
Double double or nothing.
$2,000 on the line.
Let's see what happens.
This may be the dumbest or smartest thing I've ever done, but I guess we'll find out.
Back at Firebirds.
After I made the bet that give my friend $1,000 if I didn't launch by the end of the month,
if I'm being honest, I didn't get a whole lot done for the rest of the weekend.
I mean, how are you going to vibe code when you're at a bachelor party and you're hanging out with a bunch of old friends?
After that wild and crazy weekend shooting guns, going on hikes, going clubbing, hanging out with old friends,
and having a great time, I felt refreshed, ready to get back home and ready to ship this damn thing.
And I continued to put the finishing touches on the app until it was at a place where I think it was kind of ready for testing.
It wasn't pretty, but it was pretty much there.
But right when I got home, something crazy happened.
My phone started to blow up.
I was getting messages.
I was getting texts from all you guys, comments on the videos and everything.
Oh my god.
Open AAI just released their new image model through the API.
This was the moment we'd all been waiting for.
So, I realized it was time for the infamous hot swap.
So, I went down.
I went to sit down and implement it for you guys and do it and do it live on camera for you.
But you'll never guess what happens when I attempt the hot swap.
Okay, welcome back.
We are going crazy today.
Last night in the middle of the night, I got a message that the GPT or that OpenAI had opened up the image
GPT4 image access in their API.
I'm so mad that someone sent me this because I couldn't sleep.
Literally last night, I got like 5 hours of sleep, 4 hours of sleep because I was so excited to go in here and build this.
And honestly, I'm just feeling overwhelmed right now because I know I need to build this yet I continue to checking YouTube and Twitter and everything and and this is
killing me.
It's like I know I need to build this right now and yet I'm procrastinating it.
So my goal here is to show you how I ship.
I want to document the whole process and I want to show you one cool thing that I think you should install.
It's 100% free to use but it is called self-control.
This is not for the faint of heart.
If you want to stop going on freaking X and YouTube and all these things and just get building,
this is an app you can install that you that you can block all websites and and a bunch of other things and you can't unblock it for a specific amount of time.
I want to try to get this done in the next hour.
So, let's do my 1 hour 1 minute thing here.
Start block.
And I'll put my password in there.
And now I can't go on a new website.
So, if I try to go to x.com right now, it loads, but it doesn't actually load anything.
I got to do the hot swap.
Everything has changed now.
I got my app right here, and I made all these cool changes to it.
But again, this is kind of what I was talking about in the last episode was things change.
You got to adapt to these changes.
That's the cool part about vibe coding is that you can make these changes with hopefully a couple prompts.
So, guys, I have no idea what I'm about to do.
Again, as promised, I'm not going to write a single line of code.
I'm going to do it purely with prompts.
You guys have watched me the entire time.
I have only done things with prompts.
And I promise to always do that.
So, let's figure it out how we're going to do it.
All right.
So, this is the hot swap.
And this is my to-do list.
You guys like my fancy fancy to-do list.
This is how I like to do things.
What I want to do is well, first let's just go look at our app cuz I got to remember everything it does.
So, what's going to change now?
So, I'm going to upload this.
I'm going to draw on it.
Hey, I want some mountains here.
Blah blah blah.
Okay.
I'm going to hit generate thumbnail.
What needs to change?
Well, I like this modal, but I is it necessary?
I'm trying to think right now because this model costs money.
I need to make sure that they pay before I do any sort of generation or something like that.
So, this is kind of cool.
It says it's processing your thumbnails.
I'd like this to eventually look like, hey, I'm processing your thumbnails right now and then I'd like to order them.
I think that works.
What I want to do is I just want to test it here.
the I want the real deal to be tested here even though it's going to cost me money so that I will potentially move this to after the payment.
So, let's go and actually figure it out.
Here's what I'm going do, guys.
I have no idea how I'm going to do the the image API.
I don't even know how this API works.
So, I guess I'm I'll click try and playground, too, just in case.
But I log into this.
Okay, this is actually a good way to test it.
So, I should be able to get all the API details if I send this add mountains to the background.
I don't know if the playground's going to work this way, but let's ask chat GPD in the open AI image playground.
Can I see the specific API call?
That doesn't look very good.
Why do I look like that?
The weird ass teeth, man.
That's all right.
It's not bad.
Actually, it did give it to me.
This is the images.
GPT image one.
This is the whole thing right here.
Oh my god.
that I can look at it in Python and in curl.
This is the whole API right here.
So I I'll really just have to paste this in.
And I guess this is where's the image input here.
So I'm going to Okay, so I'm going to say this looks like my I actually think I found it here.
But I'm curious because I pasted I included a file upload with it.
Can you tell me how that works?
This is cool, guys.
I mean, this is breaking down the API call itself, which I think is actually really,
you know, if you're on here and you're not a coder and you don't fully understand APIs,
well, oh, that must be it right there, huh?
Okay, the image.
This is the uploading of a local file from your machine.
The f flag tells curl to use multipart form data, which is necessary for file upload.
So, that's where it's getting it from.
Actually, it's giving us some cool stuff in here.
So, let's figure out how to actually hot swap this into our app.
So, I mean, the first thing that I want to do, I know I want to do a lot with this, right?
Look, it would be cool if there was a huge playground where you could do all these different things and you can reprompt it and blah blah blah.
I just want to get the what I call hello world working where when I click this, it sends the photo and it puts it right here in the first one.
I'm not going to have it do multiple images.
I'm just going to have it do one image and I'm going to give it as much information as possible to get that one image.
So, let's go and prompt it.
Okay, so I want to implement things simply first.
Here is the API call as a curl method.
I'm going to paste that in.
Please do this with once the user clicks and I got to remember what they even they click.
So excited I don't even know what I'm doing.
Generate thumbnail.
It should send the sketch to open AI.
get the result and put it on the first image of the modal.
Okay, I already know that there's a million things are going to go wrong here, but that's okay.
So, when we hit generate thumbnail, I want to go there.
I think it should be able to figure that out.
I don't need it.
I was going to send it a screenshot maybe.
Yeah, I don't think we have an open AI key or anything set yet.
So, but let we'll get to that error when we do.
Look, the size is going to be wrong because we want a thumbnail size.
That's all okay.
I'm going to say from the OpenAI playground.
So, just to see you, you'll probably need to change some things.
Let's see what it can Can you implement this?
Okay, the hot swap.
Let's go.
Oh, they want the Open AI gem.
I already don't like that.
I don't like the gems.
Okay, we'll try it.
We're going to do what it says.
I have a feeling that I don't like want to use the gem, but let's try it.
Ooh, we got that thumbnails controller.
Whoa, cool.
It's making changes to the thumbnails controller.
Ooh, it's adding a route for generating thumbnails, which we never had that.
Interesting.
Okay.
And if you guys, if we have the cursor GPT40 boot camp ready, I'll be explaining more about how all this works,
but you don't need to know it.
Technically, you can do this without it.
You can just vibe code it and figure it out along the way.
You can always also ask chat GBT, hey, what is this actually doing?
Anyway, so it wants me to do bundle install.
I'm going to run that.
And guys, I haven't written a single line of code as you know, and I will not for the entire challenge,
I will not write a single line of code.
This is probably going to break, but let's see.
I've implemented the OpenAI image generation.
Okay, let's see.
Set the Open API key in the environment variable.
Guys, I'm going to move this out of the way, guys.
I'm going to move this out of the way so I can set my key without you guys stealing my key.
Okay, so now it should be okay.
Well, I already lost my thing here.
Okay, added Ruby OpenAI gem.
Created a thumbnails controller.
Added the route.
Modified the front end.
To use this, you'll need to set the open API key environment variable.
I did that.
Would you like me to add?
Yes.
No, I already did that.
Add image validation pre-processing.
Make any adjustments.
Okay, that that's cool.
More stuff, but no, I'm just going to test it out first.
So, let's see.
I'm going to restart my server as I always do.
And guys, if this works, I will eat my [ __ ] shoe.
Okay, this is my thing here.
This is our first big error, guys.
Let's check it.
It seems that first of all, I'm going to copy this.
The first thing I do, guys, is and I would probably know this more because I've done some coding before,
but I'm just This is the server errors right here.
It looks like a bunch of gibberish.
I have no idea what's going on just like you.
I have no idea.
I'm just seeing that it's giving me this error.
And now we're going to go and debug this just like we do.
See error.
And then I'm also going to copy this.
Let me add some debugging fix.
Now, let's update the front end code.
It It would take me longer to do this with regular code.
This is how I debug like when I'm working on regular stuff.
like okay it's something to do with image data it says my guess is that it's turning it into a file instead of sending the base that that isn't important but basically it wants a file
it doesn't want a wo it's doing some crazy stuff okay in the front end it's doing that let's also make sure we open a I already have that I already have the key okay so let's accept the changes
accept that file review the next file accept that one oh did we ever run the bundle install let's make sure we run that bundle install okay that's already running but let me just restart I'm Always restarting my server,
guys.
That's one thing that everyone should do.
Okay, reload this.
We're reloaded.
Let's try it with our guy here.
And text mountains.
I'm not going to waste time doing this cuz I know it's going to break 15 more times.
Okay, it's not broken yet.
Calling OpenAI with prompt.
Make this look professional and eye-catching.
Hey, it looks like it's working.
This is the API call.
And obviously, it takes a while, guys.
You know when you go on chat GBT and it takes like 15 minutes.
Oh, something happened.
Oh, it doesn't look like it did anything, but it worked.
Oh my gosh.
But it didn't make any changes to the result.
I just want to make sure that it actually worked.
Is it something with the prompt?
Cuz I know we didn't do anything with the prompt and I feel like the prompt is important cuz I'm looking at the prompt.
It says make this look professional and eye-catching.
That is a prompt, but I'm going to ask it this time because I'm just generally curious.
I don't know what it's actually doing.
So maybe it'll give me a nice explanation of that.
Okay, let's debug this first.
Let's check why just not seeing the visual changes.
I'll modify the controller to add more logging in front end.
See, that's good.
Logging.
This is what all tool edit file not found.
Try switching to agent mode, whatever that means.
I see it's trying to make maybe I should just keep it on agent mode.
Let's try let's try doing that on agent mode because it's getting pretty smart.
The open AI image edit API requires both a source image and a mask image.
We're only sending the source image.
The image format needs to be specific size and format.
square PNG with transparency.
Let me modify the code to handle these requirements.
Okay, let's go take a look at this controller.
Thumbnails controller.
No, I think you're calling the wrong model.
Can you reference this, please?
Because this is such a new model.
It probably was trying to go and reference old, you know, stuff it's finding on the internet on how to do this.
But this is clearly needs to be updated here.
Okay.
Now, I imagine this is going to break some things.
But now it's doing the right image, the right prompt or the right model.
GBT image one.
And let's see.
We're going to load it.
We're going to restart our server, which we always do.
And we're going to reload.
Not that one.
We're going to reload this one.
I think I had it at desktop, maybe.
Yeah, this is my tester one that I like.
Okay.
It's working.
Please work.
It's going to take some time.
If it's taking longer, that's a good sign.
That means it should be hitting that new API that's slower.
Need the hot swap.
You know that song.
Come on.
This is a good sign that's taking a while.
And guys, this is obviously not going to be ideal.
Whoa, here we go.
A hot swap works, guys.
I've been waiting for this moment all my life.
Wow, guys.
It looks like somehow it kind of got my hair kind I don't have a hat on in the original image.
That looks pretty good.
It put my text on there.
That's not very good, but we could just prompt it better, right, to get that.
Okay, now I just feel the hot swap is done.
There's a million more things that need to happen for this to be working, right?
It still needs to be behind a um thumbnail style.
So, let's try to do a couple of those things.
I may fast forward through this section, guys, just implementing more of the features and it's going to go fast.
But, this is working, guys.
How freaking cool is this?
Wow, this API.
And then there's going to be a bunch more APIs that come after it, and it's going to get better and better.
I really think a lot of people can make a lot of money.
I'm not I wish I could go faster on this project because there's so many business opportunities or ways to,
you know, headshot generators, thumbnail generators, Gibli style cartoon generators.
These are all going to open up so many ideas to make money.
Let's go see how much this actually cost us to run.
So, I'm going to go to my OpenAI thing here and and let's see how much this actually cost because I'm curious.
One image, 36 cents.
I think I did.
Yeah, one image for 36.
That's my costs.
So, if I do four images, that's going to be a $125, $150, something like that.
So, that's not great, but we just have to price it properly to do that.
Okay, cool.
All right, let's go build the rest of the features.
So, now this is kind of how I'm building features.
I'm going, okay, there's probably aboutif there's probably a hundred things that I want to implement right now,
but that's a bad idea, right?
I still don't this idea isn't fully validated yet, but a couple things need to happen for it to just work and be decent.
The number one thing is that the responses are good, right?
Like that's not good enough for your thumbnail.
We got to do some work on the prompts and it still may not be good enough after we do the prompts,
but that's okay.
The models will get better and thinking about the competition.
This is, you know, what's the alternative?
This will hopefully be as good as it can be.
So, here's the first one.
Let's have it, what I need it to do next is like be clear to the user that it's uploading.
just feel like it because it takes so long.
They need to be able to come back to this page and check it out later.
The next one is I need to put it behind the payw wall, which it's not set up that way right now.
I need the thumbnails to be actual thumbnail size.
The text thing needs to actually work.
I think that's most of it.
So, let let's have it do four images first.
I want to do the pay wall first, actually.
So, let's figure that out first.
Move that up.
All right.
Put it behind a payw wall.
Okay.
I'm just going to ask it because there's a lot of ways to do this, but I need to make sure it works.
Okay, so the open AI call is expensive.
I want it to only happen after the user has paid.
So, slashstripe/success.
Do your magic.
There's a lot of things that need to happen I already know, but let's just see if it can do it.
I'll help you restructure the application to only make the OpenAI API call after successful payment.
We'll need to store the image and prompt temporarily.
Okay, cool.
Well, it was going to do that.
I I knew it was going to need to do that, but I didn't even tell it.
Right.
Redirect to Stripe first.
Only generate the thumbnail after successful payment.
So, oh, cool.
It's storing it in the session, meaning in your cookies.
It's adding a thumbnails process after payment.
I don't understand that, but that's interesting.
This isn't the most ideal way of doing things, but it's okay.
Finally, let's update the front-end JavaScript to handle the new flow.
Would you like me to make any adjustments to the implementation?
Okay, let's try it.
We're going to upload this guy here.
Error generated thumbnail cannot read properties of null class list.
Okay, I'm just going to tell it what I did.
When I clicked generate thumbnail, but what it should do is go to Stripe and get the errors occurring because we're trying to access a loading spinner element.
doesn't exist in the HTML.
Okay, so it's kind of going it's starting to hallucinate a little bit.
Why would it do this weird spinner thing?
But I don't know.
So let's simplify the code.
Again, guys, you just paste what's happening.
Just as long as you know the places where to look where the errors are, then that's half the battle.
Okay, now I'm getting that.
Okay, so now it it's going to do a little debug session here.
Let's to fix the issue and then go running terminal command.
So I'm running that.
It's doing something here.
That's taking too long.
Maybe it's waiting for me to run it again.
Let's try it.
I don't know what it's doing there.
We're gonna go and pull it from the Okay, it's trying to do more stuff now.
This is gonna probably go into hallucination crazy mode.
Like I don't think that's going to fix it there, but we're going to find the issue and we're going to solve it.
And I'm going to show you how maybe this is helpful for you guys to see how to debug something like this.
Okay, it's being slow.
Let's just keep testing.
Let's keep accepting.
I don't know why it's trying to make more changes.
Let's just see if this fixes it cuz I'm I'm in a rush, guys.
I got to go play some tennis.
Nope, didn't fix it.
Okay, let's get a little smarter.
I'm going to reload.
If I hit generate thumbnail there, let's see what Okay, this is the whole thing that's coming up here.
We're getting a cookie overflow error because we're trying to store the image in the session,
which is too large.
We need to change our approach to store the image data temporarily in a different way.
Let's use active storage instead.
Guys, I don't really know what this is doing, but sounds like it's something that we have to do.
It's creating our whole database, which is absolutely just crazy.
So, I mean, what this is, I I I really kind of I do understand what's going on here,
but basically, it's saying, "Hey, you need to put this data in a database.
You're going to need a database when you build anything."
And that's another kind of shameless plug to the the build accelerator.
We'll teach you how to use databases and how to do all that with AI tools.
So, let's see it working.
Wow, it's creating the whole database right now.
Oh my god, pending thumbnail.
That is too cool.
Oh my god, I can't believe it's doing this.
So, basically, it's creating a table for thumbnails, and then it updated the controller to use all that and do all that.
So, I doubt this is going to work, but let's try it.
Let's go and reload.
I'll probably restart my server just because I've been around the block a couple times,
guys.
But, we'll reload that.
Let's do this here.
Okay, it's asking for our payments and I'm going to pay my five bucks and let's see what happens.
This is a fake credit card, obviously.
And now it's loading something.
It's taking a while to load and that's okay, but we're going to want to have to fix that.
But that's pretty interesting.
Yeah, this is running thumbnails controller process after payment.
So, let's go check this out here.
I see.
So, basically, it's doing the API call, which is this is it right here.
That's not right, but it worked.
Okay, so guys, I have to pretend that I don't know how to code.
So, this is what it did.
Let's fix it.
I'm going to send this to OpenAI and say this is what it did, and it took a while to load.
So, I'm going to say, okay, that sort of worked.
So, I I put the image there.
Okay, that sort of worked, but it took forever to load.
And it looks like this.
I need to see the actual thumbnails, please.
Guys, this gets me so pumped up on AI coding.
Like, I just think about the people that can just vibe code.
Obviously, this is like pretty hard right now, but it's only going to get easier, right?
To be able to build a thumbnail generator will be something that we'll be able to do with vibe coding eventually.
Right now, we're trying to kind of wrangle all the tools.
But yeah.
Okay.
It's doing some crazy stuff.
So, let's keep let's let it keep loading.
And guys, I'm going to have to probably fast forward a lot of this because I can't make a 4hour video right now.
And again, we're going to restart our server.
It ain't my first rodeo.
Okay.
And I'm going to pay my $5 of fake money.
Oh, please come to me.
Lord, Lord, have mercy on me.
Okay, it's processing.
Let's see what it's It's doing something.
Please work your AI enhanced thumbnail.
I will not bore you with this waiting.
This is beautiful.
Oh my gosh.
All right.
Oh, we got to do I got to add something for I'm not gonna have time to do it today, but just reminds me is I got to be careful with the security thing,
right?
Another shameless plug for the AI build accelerator is you got to have good security and you got to also it's important because someone can go and find get your API key or just hitch
your endpoint for your API.
I have to I'm going to prompt it with some security stuff later, but yeah, security and make sure I don't spend 1 million.
Okay, just adding that as a potential to-do.
Got to do it later.
I'm not going to do it now.
Oh, I can even download the thumbnail.
Kidding me.
This is so cool.
That's not even that bad, guys.
This is so sick.
Okay, we got it working behind the pay wall now.
That is too cool.
Let's go check out our costs.
Still says one image, 70.
So, maybe I've done two images now.
I can't remember how many I've done, but whatever.
All right, let's br that.
Okay, that worked.
Great job.
Can you have it do four different images?
Well, how are the images going to be different?
That's actually a feature.
Let's Let's ask Chat GBT about this feature because I don't even know what I would really want to do.
Hey, I'm building a thumbnail generator for YouTubers.
I want the generator to give me four options, but I guess I'm not sure how to differentiate them.
Should I prompt them differently?
Let's see.
Cuz I don't really know what to do here.
Yeah, it's a good idea.
You might want four distinct thumbnail options.
Method one, prompt variations.
YouTuber pointing to use the same core scene but vary the style composition or emotion of the prompt.
Method two, style presets.
Ooh, this is cool.
Vary focal points.
Let's try this.
I like style presets.
This is getting a little bit more kind of crazy, right?
Cuz I'm actually giving it like product ideas.
Okay, that worked.
Great job.
Can you do four different images, but I would like them to be different styles and have presets for these.
Here are the four presets I'd like to start with.
That's 1 2 3 4.
I'll probably just put one
two three four.
I'm going to have to end this stream soon.
It's getting too long.
I don't even want to let users choose.
So, I'm just going to do the style presets.
Then, I would like all four of these generated thumbnails on the page.
Guys, this already got me excited just looking at like the OpenAI playground and seeing like look,
this is the very first version just generating a thumbnail in my app.
There's so much more we could do.
And you know, one thing that people will say is like, why don't you just do this in OpenAI?
Why don't you just do this with Chat GPT?
Well, we're going to create it in a way so that it's got bunch of like built-in YouTuber stuff and then it's just going to be easier.
You can do this, save time.
It's only going to cost you a little bit more money to do and but that's after I do the MVP,
right?
So, I don't know if this is going to take off, but I think it's a good start.
Okay.
Wow.
So, it wants me to even start doing seating the database.
That's cool.
All right.
So, it's creating the styles as an actual This is cool.
It's doing all this database stuff, which I just think is freaking epic.
Okay, I'm going to stop it here.
It was at this moment I thought I had made it.
I had got the API to work, and now it's just a matter of tying up all the loose ends and getting it ready for production.
But boy was I wrong.
I proceeded to spend the next four hours in a death spiral trying to get this app to do exactly what I wanted it to do.
I'm fast forwarding through this right now, but and I will spare you all of this footage because it's almost impossible to go through all of it.
But this is the honest truth and this made me so angry that I literally wanted to punch my computer screen in the face.
It was demoralizing.
Every single prompt was adding more code, more complexity.
It continued to hallucinate and do things that I was telling it not to do.
It continued to use the old dolly model.
It would just go back and forth and change the code and change the code and change the code.
And then basically hours later, I hit a breaking point.
Oh my god, I can't do it, guys.
I can't do it.
Vibe coding.
I'm I think I think I'm over vibe coding.
I think I'm pretty sure VIP coding isn't going to work anymore.
It's easy to start the project.
It's easy to create the UI, but the moment you got to do something new or complicated,
we're talking about background jobs, I'm ripping my hair out right now and the AI is going over and over and over and over again,
and it can't fix it.
I don't really even know how to code this.
there's like a new API that it keeps referencing and it keeps going back to like old API documentation even though this API just came out.
And guys, I don't think the hot swap is going to work.
And um man, I'm feeling like this challenge might be over.
This is really, really frustrating.
And although I was super hyped up on vibe coding to start this, I still believe it's possible.
And look, it's never going to be easy.
But right now, I feel stuck.
For everyone in the comments, maybe you were right.
Maybe vibe coding is not going to work.
I just I think about people who would go and start vibe coding and they don't know how to code.
How are you going to create something real doing this?
Once your app gets complicated, what are you going to do?
How are you going to fix it?
I know that I could build this without vibe coding, but I don't feel that it's possible to build with vibe coding.
Look, I mean, I'm going through all this right here.
Look at all this code that it's created, right?
It's so much.
And I have no idea what anything is really doing.
It's going off the rails.
It can't go back and fix itself.
I'm sure there's a way to do it, but I just feel so demoralized right now.
There is so much going on here right now that you can see my prompts here.
I've been prompting this over and over and over again, trying lots of different things,
and it's just not getting there.
This has been a couple hours now and I just don't feel that there's any way out.
So, I got to step away, give this 24 hours and see if I can come back and what I'm going to change to fix
this.
Um, I told you that I'm never going to give up.
I'm gonna find a solution, but I need to go take a break and come back tomorrow with a fresh fresh head,
a fresh mind on this.
And let's see what happens.
But that's all I have for you guys.
I'm sorry this isn't the ending that you want, but yeah.
Okay.
I'm sorry, guys.
I'm signing off now.
base.