All right, welcome back to the Starter Story podcast.
In today's episode, I have a really important question for Pat.
Should I switch to Cloud Code from Cursor?
So, if you've been following my story here on the channel, you've seen that I've pretty much only used Cursor exclusively.
But honestly, I'm getting a lot of FOMO because there's a bunch of people online that are posting about using Cloud Code,
how Cloud Code has changed their life.
And so I saw a tweet that Pat posted a couple days ago saying that Cloud Code was life-changing for him.
So I wanted to ask him why and to walk me through his workflow and um see if he could change my mind.
>> Let's get into it.
Welcome back to the podcast.
Let's go.
>> All right, let's do it.
Let's talk cloud code today.
>> Yeah.
So Pat, let me let me just uh pull this up quick.
So I saw your tweet where you said that cursor was amazing.
That's what you said.
Cursor was amazing.
Cloud code is lifechanging and obviously I wonder what's next.
We're not going to talk about what's next.
And then I also saw just to quickly give color.
I saw this other uh Reddit post that from a month ago where some guy wrote Claude Coach changed my life and he kind of gives this whole this whole narrative.
And I've been seeing some other people online.
Our buddy Alex Finn who came on to the channel.
He's been posting all about Claude Code.
And like I said in the intro, I'm feeling a little bit of FOMO.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh because I'm pretty exclusively on cursor.
I could talk about why pretty much just like that's the first one I used and it's just kind of stuck on it,
but I've been seeing all this cloud code stuff and I'm just like, hey, should I switch?
Like what's going on here?
So yeah, why is cloud code life changing?
>> Yeah.
Well, how long did you spend learning uh cursor?
Because you're a beginner, right?
>> Yeah, beginner.
Um, realistically like an hour in terms of hours, probably like a week.
>> Yeah.
>> We like to 40 60 hours, something like that.
>> Because I was really from scratch, you know, like I never really used like any code editors or folder,
you know, it sounds so basic, but >> Yeah.
And that's why I liked cursor because I love the visual, the chat window, the code in the middle,
the folders on the left side.
It makes sense to me.
>> So yeah, I mean, I've obviously used tools before cursor, but I've been using cursor for I don't know exactly how long,
but I'm thinking it's almost a year, but I used to use VS Code before that.
And then before that, other tools and I just switched to Claude Code.
So I I can kind of give you perspective the differences between cursor and cloud code and what I like better about cloud code from your perspective as someone who only knows cursor and is
considering.
So I could share my screen right now and kind of just walk you through how I have my setup uh and then you can just ask questions uh based on that because I think I just kind of set
it up based on a few different thought things I saw online.
I'm definitely not a cloud code expert, but uh in terms of what it can do, I mean, it's way faster than cursor and I think it's better for me.
So, I I can kind of walk through that.
>> Yeah, that'd be awesome.
Yeah, I haven't I've seen a bunch of videos or people that are posting.
I haven't watched a bunch of them yet.
Um obviously, I should.
So, yeah, this would be great just to kind of even if just for me, you know, I want I want to know.
>> Okay, well, let's let's do it.
So, so yeah, that's the first thing is I actually still just use cursor.
It's mainly out of convenience because cursor is not just um an AI generation tool.
It's like a fork of VS Code.
So, it's uh it's an IDE.
I forget what that that uh acronym stands for, but uh it's basically like where all your code is.
You can run terminal, you can see all your files, you can see all your changes.
So, I still use cursor and technically I think I still pay for cursor.
I don't think I'm really using the cursor features.
So I didn't I really don't have to but there I'm still using cursor a little bit which we'll get into.
So that's the first thing I would say is like you're already using cursor.
So cloud code is in the terminal.
So I know pe software developers on here might be watching this thinking okay yeah I know this this is obvious.
But uh for you you're more of a beginner and I think there are also beginners.
So I just want to be cognizant of that just to keep things.
>> So cloud doesn't have like this visual.
Cloud code doesn't have this.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
Cloud Code is CL Yep.
Exactly.
Cloud Code is terminal based.
So instead of being this user interface that you can click through and drag things, Cloud Code can't do any of that stuff.
Uh it's really just an input and then it does a bunch of things and it's really just a prompt,
one single prompt.
>> It does a bunch of things and then you can continue to prompt it.
So it's way different and I think probably a little bit more advanced, but let me just jump into it real quick.
So here I have the terminal.
You can get this by doing terminal new terminal in cursor or in VS code or you can just do a raw terminal like if you go to terminal here.
You could also do it there.
Uh but I like to do it inside cursor because I also have access to all my files.
So first thing you just run you have to install it which I won't do that now but uh you can just go Google that on how to install it.
You just run claude.
I like in the terminal.
So, I'll do that right now.
I say yes, I trust the files.
And then now I'm in Claude.
I can say, "Hey, go do something."
>> So, you're just kind of chatting with it in the terminal instead of I'm used to like on the >> Yeah,
just on the right side.
>> In cursor, you have command L where I can say, "Hey, go do something."
This is like a user interface >> where I can click through things.
because I can do background and I can change the model and you know I can add context and all that stuff.
Cursor or claude code is like hey you tell me one thing and I'll figure it out.
So you can run claude to open it up in the terminal but uh I don't I like to I have one little hack which you know you have to be careful when you do this.
I think you do exit to get out of there.
I don't even know.
C run claude and then I do dangerously.
So if you run this flag called dangerously skip permissions uh again >> sounds scary.
>> It's a dangerous thing to do but it's kind of unworkable if you don't use this or maybe if you're more beginner uh you want to see all the changes cuz technically if you told Claude,
"Hey, go and delete my entire file system and and nerf my computer."
It's possible that it could do that, right?
Uh so if you run this, it is a dangerous move, but I think it's actually really not usable unless you do this.
So that's that'll be my first tip that I learned.
You know, it took me some time to learn that and understand how to fix that.
>> I wonder if that's like kind of on on cursor, try to keep going back to it, is there's like a agent mode or whatever.
>> Yeah.
>> So is that kind of the same idea?
>> Yeah, sort of.
Uh well, agent mode.
Okay.
So yeah, that is a good question.
So if I say, "Hey, go do something."
It'll go into agent mode.
It'll start doing it, but then it sometimes, you know how it will ask for your permission to do something.
>> Yeah.
>> Basically, that's Claude Code's version of that is skipping all that asking for permission.
So if you run dangerously skip permissions, it will just do it and it won't ask for your permission.
I think there's a setting for cursor on how to do that.
Um, But I mean, let's just try it.
Hey, go uh delete my repo.
Let's see what happens.
>> I'm guessing that >> starter story goes dark.
>> I want to make sure I understand what you're asking for before I take any action.
Okay, that's not what I was looking for it to do.
Um but >> uh basically there's a little thing that will prompt up and it will ask you to run it.
Say like run a script >> uh to uh delete run a script to uh
verify my homepage is working >> sometimes.
Yeah, I've gone there where it says like do you want to run and then you click yes or no?
>> Yes.
That's what That's what I'm trying to get to.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
>> Basically, by running dangerously skip permissions, you're skipping that, but it makes it way faster.
>> So, it's able to just like do a bunch of things behind this.
And that that's I think probably my first big thing that I personally like about Claude Code is that it does a bunch of stuff behind the scenes.
Cursor is very verbose.
Look how verbose cursor is right here.
>> I can't I can't read all this.
I mean, you tell me what your thoughts are on that.
I mean, yeah, to be honest, when I'm using cursor, it gives me all this stuff 80% of the time,
if not more, I don't read it.
I just, which is probably like, if someone's watching it who's like a developer or something,
they're probably like, "Dude, your code is probably all buggy and stuff because I just basically click accept."
>> Right.
Right.
>> Accept all changes.
>> Yep.
Yep.
>> And half the time, more than half the time, I don't know.
I don't know what it did because I start reading it and I get a little lost and I'm just like,
I'm sure it's fine.
>> Yeah.
Exactly.
That's it's an interesting thought.
I mean, okay, so the the thing here is, okay, so this is the verify homepage script that it created.
Here's the auto run.
Ask every time versus auto run.
So it looks like I already had that on.
Maybe that was a setting that I had already had turned on in my cursor, but that's that version of that basically.
>> Yeah.
Okay.
But you're saying dangerously skip is similar.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
It's basically the same thing, but it also like doesn't really let you know what it does.
So let's let's just run that same uh query >> in cloud code and see what happens.
Okay.
But first, let's look at what sorry what cursor did.
Uh it it has a lot here, right?
It's showing me the scripts it ran it.
Um it's just very verbose, right?
It's there's a lot going on right here.
>> Do I really care about knowing all of this stuff?
I I personally don't.
I do have a little bit more of a software development background, so I kind of know what it's trying to do.
>> For me personally, I don't really care what it's trying to do.
I'm just I just care that it's getting it done.
>> So, I'll show you what the same uh script does in cloud code.
>> So, I'm going to run that in cloud code.
And it does have what I like about it is it kind of shows you its like logic of thinking
>> and it creates these to-dos.
Have you seen these?
I've seen people post about that or talk about like if you give it a plan >> or a three-step plan or something like that.
It'll like make the plan and do it.
>> Yeah.
>> Um >> but I didn't give it a plan.
It it took what I said which was go run a script and then it created a plan which I think is actually way better.
It >> it created it little to-dos plan to do this and it's doing all this stuff, >> but for some reason I don't feel the need to go and read through all of it.
>> It just it does the same thing essentially, right?
>> But >> sure, >> it's it feels like I don't like it kind of is going back to its to-dos a lot.
It's kind of show thinking and then it's just giving me an output and that's it.
>> Yeah.
Interesting.
Cool.
So I don't know what you think about that.
>> I think the intimidating part is the terminal.
>> Yeah.
>> For me like for example I was making my mobile app and I would say hey cursor I need you to make this box in the app.
Yeah.
>> So that when users do this XYZ that you know this is the the outcome I want and it would kind of go do it.
Could you do the same thing here or are you like um is it different I guess?
>> Yeah I think yes you can do the same thing.
It gets the same job done that cursor does, but it does it faster.
I really do think it does it faster and more accurate.
Now, I don't know exactly how that is.
Maybe they have a better model.
I don't I don't know why it's better.
I have some theories, but I do think it's better.
That would be the main reason why I think Cloud Code is better is that I'm able to get more done.
I'm able to ship more, and I'm about I'm able to feel more confident that the AI is doing a good job.
So, I mean, let's try it real quick.
I will show you the app that I'm working on right now, which is my local host 3000.
You said we wanted to add a box to the app.
>> Yeah.
Or some, you know, um like an input box or something.
>> An input box.
>> Yeah.
>> Let's try it.
Uh can you add an input box on the homepage?
Which what what are we adding to the input box?
>> Um just like for you where users can like type a question or something.
I don't know.
where users type a question and then once they submit it goes to an
answers page uh where we question gets answered I would say just just for simplicity sake no need to use AI just
make up a fake answer to set up the structure of our app this is a brand new app that I just created this would be the this is the cloud code prompt we're going to put in there and I'm thinking
it's going to be a lot faster than I mean it would be cool if we benchmarked it on how fast it did it but let's try this.
>> So essentially it's a very similar type of like experience where you're you're not exactly like you're just chatting with it chatting with it in the same way in the same conversational way that maybe I'm doing it in cursor.
>> It's basically the same thing and that's kind of I think something we'll talk about a little bit later is that like it does the same thing for someone like me cloud code is is a lot better.
I feel like cloud code is just a not a lot better but it's just faster and it gets less errors and it does it quickly and when I'm doing something more complex here's another thing that I think is interesting I feel like in cursor you
tell me this do you have to kind of be in the right file to make changes for it or do you feel that you can just oneshot it with no context and it can fix your thing >> oh um I definitely think you need to
have like that at context thing enabled because and maybe it's updated in the last month but early on when I was building my mobile app,
I wouldn't add the context and it would get all screwed up >> until I saw something online that said,
"Oh, make sure you add the context or kind of point it to, you know, whatever folder you're working in so that it could know what it's talking about,
I guess, or like know what you want."
>> That's one of the things that I didn't necessarily verbalize yet because I didn't even think about it,
but now looking back at cursor, that feels like the stone age because I can prompt it with there is no way to add.
There probably is a way to do it, but you don't need to add context with cloud code.
There's something better about the model where you can just say, hey, and you know, this is a very simple app that has been created.
But in Starter Story, it's a very complex repository that has lots of stuff in it.
I can usually oneshot it and it'll go find what I'm talking about.
That would be the first thing is that you don't need context, which is nice.
It just it allows you to be lazier.
You don't need to go find the file and try to kind of I don't say the word is like kind of maneuver your maneuver your way through the AI.
you kind of just like can just prompt it.
The other thing that I want to share too is I think is really cool and I don't know it's more of like a personal thing.
I feel like cloud code does more it it just does more maybe it has it feels like it has more liberty to do things and it takes a little bit longer.
It does a better job and it's kind of nice like I'll I'll prompt it like to actually create a whole feature.
Like sometimes I feel like to go to cursor you don't tell it to create a feature you tell it to do 10 steps of a feature.
I mean tell me your experience with that.
Yeah, I mean I'm kind of biasing towards something I feel like I learned in m that Alex Finn video we did on the main channel where he kind of said like cursor will mess up and I experienced
this too if you gave it like one long prompt and said okay I want to do this this you know in my experience it like it really messed that up and so instead I had to okay first do this let that
finish yeah >> then do this let that finish blah blah blah so you know I'm kind of not when I'm working in cursor I have to like set aside an hour to do it because which which I mean you probably you probably
should, right?
Like I'm assuming you're going to say you could run it and then kind of go do something and then it'll keep working in the background.
But I can't do that with cursor like I have to kind of make time for it really a lot of time for it.
>> Yeah, I think what you're saying it's just more involved like you're more involved in the thinking process.
This is where curs or cloud code potentially be different.
You can give it that feature and I will just like give you my actual workflow right now.
I will tell I'll ask it to fe to do the feature.
It's a little bit more complex.
So if it's a 10step process in cursor, I'm giving it the first eight steps that I would do in cursor in cloud code in one go.
And then I literally get up and I go and do something around the house.
I go, you know, put some chicken in the air fryer or I go like tidy up or I take my dog for a walk and then it sometimes takes a while.
Like sometimes it takes 5 10 minutes to do uh a task.
But I can trust that it's like kind of figuring itself out as it goes and it's like thinking better.
So like I will literally go put this in >> and I will get up out of my chair and I'll just go walk around >> and I'll I'll like go do stuff around the house.
It's I think one of the things that's interesting about these tools is they change how we work.
So before you got to be like zoned in doing deep work.
Now AI tools, especially Claude Code, has made it so it's more like I'm more delegating to you.
you're my junior programmer.
And maybe that's only because I have software engineering experience, but I really just delegate this to Claude code and then I told you was I you do the first eight steps,
I'm going to do the last two steps and then I'm going to test it >> because the testing is the next thing that's like that it can't really be done.
You're not you shouldn't commit and and push up code that isn't tested.
It's changing the way that I work, which is kind of like a mind [ __ ] for me right now because I've been so into the deep work thing and giving it every little
step and like wanting full control of things, but claude code is changing how I work.
>> Cool.
Uh, a question that's coming to mind is like, so yeah, I kind of want to see what it did if it did it.
>> Let's see.
Okay, so that worked >> and obviously this is very simple.
Sure.
But uh what is the meaning of life?
What's also cool about cloud code and it's a real hack that I had to learn by tweeting about it.
But if you do command control shift 4, take a screenshot of your app.
I like to take the whole context because claude code will know uh what page you're on.
And I will make sure you do it's four buttons.
Command, control, shift, and four.
Because typically I would just do command, shift, 4.
But this will copy it to your clipboard.
And you go back to cloud code and you do control, not command, controlV.
And then you and then it pastes the image there.
Because it's it's command line.
It's a little different, right?
I think you can drag images in, but this is the fastest way.
and I'll say the submit button doesn't work.
Can you fix that?
And go to a new page on submit where the question is answered.
Then I'll get up and I'll say, "Yo, Bernie,"which is he's down here right now.
Let's go for a walk and I'm going to think about more important things than coding.
How am I going to market my app?
And you know, all these things.
It's just a really different way of working which I never really thought about until we kind of been walking through it.
>> Yeah.
My one of my other questions and then obviously we'll kind of shift the conversation a little bit is why do you use it in cursor?
Like that I think as I' I've been watching people online I'm kind of like I've seen a lot of people say that like oh just use it in cursor but you do the whole like new terminal thing run cloud and that that's where I've been struggling to be like well why
wouldn't I just keep doing the same thing?
Yeah.
Why do you keep using it in cursor?
I guess >> the the main point is is mainly out of laziness.
Cursor did something smart which is they forked VS Code which was the app I was already the IDE I was already using.
So I could go redownload VS Code but like I don't really have any incentive to do that.
This is also just VS Code on a little bit of steroids.
The second thing would be that I do sometimes still use cursor if I maybe want that more verbose thing going on here or maybe I want to ask it something like I feel like >> I haven't really figured out how to use
cloud code to ask it questions but I might use them in tandem.
Right now it's building my app but then I also might go over here and say like what do you think of my app?
If I'm being truly honest I'm using cursor like once I'm prompting cursor maybe once or twice a day when I used to use it for everything.
So I don't really use it for a lot.
So, it's mainly out of laziness.
You know, my guess is also cursors.
They're freaking out right now about >> Cloud Code and they're probably going to make,
you know, they're a huge company and they got a lot of funding, so they're probably going to do some dope stuff,
too.
>> Um, try to compete.
So, and that's kind of what I think is also interesting is like there's lots of different AI tools,
right, that solve different purposes.
I imagine that in a year I'm going to be using 10 different AI tools.
One of them is going to be testing my app.
One of them is gonna be marketing my app.
One of them is going to be building my app.
Another one's going to be fixing bugs.
So, and they're going to be all built by different companies, right?
There's no one's going to win this race.
I think just Claude Code kind of just edged out a little bit in front.
>> That is something I struggle with is like the amount of tools.
There's cursor, which I've mostly have used.
There's Lovable that I've kind of played around with.
that there's wind surf that I've never used but has supposedly lots of users.
There's a bunch of other little ones like that I know exist out there.
>> Yeah.
>> And uh yeah, so anyways, I feel like you know one of our points as we zoom out is like is this the right tool?
You know, like should I be using this?
>> You know, I guess that's the main question, right?
Okay, should I be using code versus cursor versus lovable versus winer versus >> GitHub copilot or whatever the differences are.
What do you think about that?
Should somebody switch?
>> Yeah, I mean it's a really good question.
I know that this podcast that we're recording right now is all about should I switch to cloud code,
but I think also if you're spending a lot of time thinking about if you should switch to cloud code,
you might be thinking about the wrong things.
And there's a lot of FOMO around that too, like am I using the right tool or this new tool came out,
I don't know how to use this tool, I might lose out.
I might get behind.
I think there's a lot of actually problems with that, right?
I mean, >> I mean, I feel that that's the kind of one of the reasons I was like, let's talk about this cuz I'm like,
could I do it better, faster, whatever?
Am I doing it wrong?
And >> I think, yeah, I think that's a really kind of dangerous place to be.
And that's why I think it's good to talk about this is look, cloud code is awesome.
You can we can nerd out on these tools all day, but if cloud code didn't exist or there was something else or there's something else comes out,
I would still be doing the same things that I'm already doing.
Like I was doing building apps, building cool stuff, using AI with cursor.
If cloud code didn't exist, I would be okay.
I would still be focused on building stuff, talking to users, creating content, distribution.
I think a lot of times these tools can be a big distraction.
What I like about AI tools is that they're fairly easy to learn, but you have to kind of make that judgment call on like,
should I spend the time to learn this?
How much is this going to set me back to go and learn this tool?
>> That is a great that's a that's a good point I'm thinking about cuz I just posted on X yesterday a screenshot of I said uh I said,
"I fear I may be about to waste dozens of hours learning how to use this thing."
You know, and some comments were like, "Yeah, you should do it or you shouldn't do it or whatever.
Um, and I feel like, and then today I posted this thing because it's kind of where I'm at right now.
I was like, I don't exactly know what to do next with my personal little mobile app.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, um, and that's kind of I think the point you're trying to make is like I am probably focused too much on like,
you know, I had a thought like should I should I red do the whole app but do it in clock versus cursor?
>> Yeah.
And it's kind of like I feel like what you're saying is like that's probably the wrong thing to think about.
What to >> Yeah.
I I think that's a really really kind of interesting point is like what I I think the question I would ask you is like what feels scarier if there's just two questions.
Should I rebuild in cloud code or should what do I do next with my app?
What feels scarier?
What feels more unknown between those two questions?
>> Uh I mean for sure what should I do next?
>> Yeah.
in C in for for building or whatever it's like I would know what to do kind of like I would say okay I did it before I've done it twice now I'm just going to shift how I did it in there
>> into this new tool and so I was that feels it feels intimidating because it's a new tool >> but I know what to do the the marketing piece or like what do I do next is like do where do I post or who do I talk to
or like where's the tool for marketing which there's a lot obviously but you know where's the hack you know cursor and cloud code fit a little bit like a hack to build something doesn't feel like
there's a huge hack for marketing.
I'm sure somebody watching is like, well, there is do that.
But that's kind of what feels scarier.
>> These tools or the FOMO around the tools can be a form of procrastination around what really needs to get done.
Like imagine if you you could spend a week learning cla code or you could spend a week uh figuring out how to get a 100 customers.
What would benefit you more in the long run?
>> I know the answer, Pat.
>> Yeah.
[Laughter] customers.
Yeah.
For sure.
And I mean I mean it's totally right.
And you've talked about that a lot.
It's like even with like marketing or whatever.
It's like you could market at random or you could market to your target, you know, what's most effective and in this case it's it's a similar tangential question which is yeah should I spend 40 hours learning curs or cloud code like I did with
cursor?
I mean maybe like maybe it's beneficial to some degree but now that I have something I probably need to actually run it to the end that I can't or that I know in terms of marketing which would really at this point be zero
step zero that is more beneficial long run and I think I I mean just to make that really emphasize that point is I feel like I've definitely fallen into that trap where I'm like oh this tool that tool that's shiny that's cool that's new let me try this let me switch
that like I did I tried lovable for a while early you early on and then I was like someone posted about cursor and I was like oh cursor looks cool and over the a few months I've been in and out of like different tools,
Vzero, Bolt, Replet, you know, kind of thing.
>> That is interesting.
Yet, you mentioned Lovable.
I don't know if you've seen some of the black they've been getting.
I mean, apparently they have a hundred million dollar ARR business.
>> Uh, >> yeah, I saw a couple tweets.
I'll pull them up as you're talking.
>> It keeps coming up.
>> Fastest ever.
>> Yeah.
>> Company to 100 million.
>> Fastest from 1 million to 100 million.
or 1 minute 200 must be if it was zero to 100 maybe it's not but I thought that was >> sure yeah I've seen that and I've seen other people posting like I don't know
anyone who uses lovable >> right >> and then I think I saw this one from Noah Kagan who I like he's like it's amazing lovable is a $2 billion company I haven't seen one person using it >> y
>> uh and then people obviously posting here's my here's my vibe code stack or whatever um or what do you think about that >> I think people need to get the hell out of their little bubble because you ain't
going to build.
Sorry, I'm I'll go too crazy on that.
But people think that the world revolves around their their tiny Twitter circle.
Twitter is an algorithm that serves you and you think it's the whole world.
You need to like zoom out for a second.
Like it's possible that Lovable is lying or they have some sort of scheme going on uh where they pumped a bunch of ads.
I don't know, whatever it is.
But there are a lot of companies out there that you wouldn't believe what their revenue is.
I mean, they're just in a different space.
HubSpot is a great example of that, right?
Like I don't use HubSpot.
I like to use Notion and everyone I know uses Notion.
I don't really know a whole lot of people using HubSpot, >> but I also know that HubSpot is a massive company for a different world,
a different type of audience.
I think they make billions of dollars per year.
And uh if you kind of get stuck in your own bubble, I think that's a really also dangerous place to be in in terms of talking to customers and and building something that's useful for customers is
maybe stepping outside of your world and going into your customers world.
That's a different topic, but I think it also shows how big this AI coding and building space is.
There's a lot of tools.
So there's Cursor, Claude Code, Lovable, and a lot more that are billion-dollar companies and you don't even know a single person using it.
That actually makes me even more excited because it shows how big this space is.
>> Yeah.
Yeah, that's a great point.
Yeah.
I mean, it's funny how when you say that like the little circle like everyone I see on Twitter is using cursor or cloud code right now.
I don't see anyone using the others, but that's that little circle thing.
And then yeah, I think that ultimate point of like the tools are like one lever, you know,
to get you to a certain place and then there's a whole another world like after you build the thing that pro that like you know like just matters probably way more than like which IDE to use or whatever which
by the way IDE means um >> something development environment.
>> Yeah, integrated development environment.
>> Fancy all the nerds out there.
Yeah.
So yeah.
Anyway, cool.
Yeah, I mean, yeah, I think that's that's been kind of interesting for me to to kind of watch your workflow,
but then obviously get to the main point.
Yeah, I think uh got got me a lot to think about.
I don't know.
I don't know if I'll >> So maybe that the you know to answer the question like should I switch?
What would you say?
>> I would say do what works for you.
There's definitely a balance between like having fun and and learning something new.
But the main goal is you shipping a product, you getting customers, you talking to customers,
and you just continuing to build.
So use what tools work for you.
If cursor is working for you right now, just keep going.
You don't want don't go and set yourself back a week or two or a month >> because you're going to get some marginal increases in your uh code
editor, your coding workflow.
you talking to one customer is worth more than you learning, you know, spending two weeks learning a tool,
right?
I I really think that >> you working on a couple marketing posts is worth way more than getting a little bit speedier in the development process.
>> Yeah, it's a good point.
>> Cool.
I like that.
I like I like that.
I like where we ended there.
>> What's What's your plan or what's what's your decision?
I kind of it's like what's the feel like I got to take my vitamins or something, you know,
where I'm like, you know, at the beginning of this conversation, I was a little bit like,
ah, dude, I'm totally gonna I'm gonna use cloud code after this.
And maybe I still will just to mess around like you said, but yeah, at the end of the day,
like what's actually more important is is not that, you know, I might I probably will mess around with it a little bit,
but I know if I get too into it, I'm going to just like it'll be a month and I'll just be playing around with cloud code and not marketing,
not talking to users, things like that.
So yeah, I think a little bit of both, but I'll I'll lean towards like probably not switching too much yet and then seeing kind of where it takes me.
>> Cool.
>> Well, that was fun.
>> Yeah, that was fun.
Thanks.
Yeah.
So, uh, thanks for tuning in today.
Uh, let us know in the comments if you're what tool you're using, if you're planning on switching and or any any other feedback you have for us.
Uh, that's been the Star Story podcast.
Oh, one last thing before we leave is, you know, we'll leave a link in the description to uh starter story build.
If you are somewhere in the beginning, we're trying to figure out you haven't if you haven't used any tool,
you're trying to figure out where to start, you can start by using uh taking the program,
uh we'll outline kind of some easy ways that you can use AI to to build your first idea.
So, we'll leave that link in the description as well.
Thanks for tuning in.
Appreciate it.
And uh we'll see you next week.
See you.