Hey, welcome back to the Starter Story podcast.
Appreciate you tuning in today.
You are in for a treat.
I just got off with Rob Hollum.
He's a guy following X.
He just launched a an app called SuperX, which is a a Twitter app that helps you ship better tweets.
But I think if you stick to the end of this episode, you're going to hear one, his whole story,
which is pretty awesome.
But two, I think you're going to learn kind of a lot about what it takes to actually build something successful.
A lot of people online will tell you or you might even see online about overnight successes or I built this thing in two weeks and it's making X amount of money.
Sometimes that works, but for the majority of people, that's just not reality.
And Rob is a great example of somebody that took a lot of steps to finally make something that is just starting to take off.
And so, I hope you enjoy this episode.
Leave your feedback in the comments.
If there's anyone else you want us to bring on, leave that in the comments below as well.
Thanks for being here and welcome back to the Star Story podcast.
Rob, welcome to the Star Story Podcast.
Excited that you're here, man.
Appreciate you coming on.
I know you have a lot going on right now.
Just launched an app, things like that.
And I'm excited to hear more about your story and have you share that with our with our audience.
So, thanks for being here.
>> Appreciate you, Gus.
Thanks for having me.
>> I love story.
So, >> yeah.
Thanks.
Cool.
Well, we're all big fans of you and thanks for being a fan of us.
Okay, I want to start here which is kind of starting a little bit at the end and then we'll kind of work our way back to how you got here.
I think that's like a there's like a movie director like Quinton Tarantino who like kind of sometimes starts at the end.
So that that's what that's what we're doing here.
We're starting at the end of all the spoilers and then we'll figure out how you got here.
So over the P I'm on your Twitter account.
Nice by the way.
>> Good place to start.
Thank you.
>> And I want to start here.
You just launched your I don't know if it's your first SAS but one of your first SAS called SuperX.
Like literally I've been following over the last 24 hour 24 48 hours you know successful launch day X you know amount of R MR this is a really
cool post like what a launch day etc.
Cool picture you look super hype here and the app is called SuperX right so let's show it off a little bit here.
>> Yes sir.
>> Super super X is well how about you tell us about SuperX.
What what am I looking at here?
>> So, SuperX is well, it was originally a Chrome extension.
A lot of people will be familiar with SuperX being a Chrome extension to track your analytics across X,
but since Tibo and I partnered up, we've been working on the SuperX web app, which is what just launched.
We're calling it soft launch because we have a lot more things planned after we get a couple weeks of feedback.
Uh, and then we're going to go more hard launch with more videos and and cool stuff and hit product hunt and all that that kind of stuff.
>> Okay, cool.
>> But yeah, SuperX basically helps you grow faster on X.
That's what it So it's like a tool that kind of I'm looking at your obviously your video here like tracks engagement your retweets.
So it's okay.
So it's a way to help you grow on X.
Awesome.
>> Exactly.
Which is cool.
>> And the web app is that like helps you write content, helps you come up with content ideas,
>> schedule it, plan it, all of that stuff.
>> Awesome.
Okay.
So I wanted to start there.
You know, obviously congrats on the success.
I'm going to stop sharing for a second here and I want to get to how you got this idea,
what the launch has been like, but let's go way I mean we don't have to go way back.
I I we don't need to hear about your childhood or anything like that, but let's go back to the beginning of your kind of building journey.
What's like where did where did it all begin?
What's kind of the the origin story for you building stuff online?
>> Yeah, so I had a very traditional path for a very long time.
I went to university in the UK.
I studied computer science and I graduated and I became a software engineer.
I became a software engineer in a video conferencing company.
I was very like lowlevel in the trenches fixing bugs in their protocols etc.
But fundamentally I didn't enjoy it.
I never have been a coder by heart personally.
I'm not like a deep programmer.
I love other stuff.
I've always been creative.
I've always loved things like music.
Not to say that people who code don't like music and stuff, but I've always loved the arts outside of like logic and technicality,
if that makes sense.
>> Sure.
>> So, I felt kind of like an imposter in this like just coding, software engineering environment,
you know what I mean?
>> Yeah.
What What were were like a lot of your co-workers kind of longtime developers, like lifeer,
9 to5 lifers?
Yeah.
>> Yeah.
Yeah, they loved it and I didn't I didn't love it and I was like something's wrong because the people around me seem like they're genuinely excited to start the day and I'm I'm just thinking,
oh god, like I've got more bugs that I've got to fix and that's all I've got today.
Just more bugs.
>> Sure.
Yeah.
A little bored, maybe a little like restless.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
I just didn't feel like I was going the way that I wanted to go in life.
But fortunately for me, it was around the time of COVID layoffs and I was caught up in that co layoff sort of period of time.
So you got laid off.
>> Yeah.
I was laid off.
Basically paid to leave two months in which for me was perfect.
And >> that's funny.
That's funny that you're like for me was perfect cuz for for me and maybe lots of people maybe watching would be like oh [ __ ] Like >> that's not perfect.
>> I had some people join at the same time as me and they were devastated and I was like I totally understand it.
These people who were like loving their job.
>> Yeah.
I felt for them.
But for me, I was like, yeah, like you say, secretly celebrating, thinking, what am I what can I do now?
You know, the doors opened up and I have some runway now as well to play with.
>> So I You've got like a severance package or something.
>> Exactly.
>> Yeah.
Nice.
>> Exactly.
So I had like a few months to play with and I was thinking, okay, what do I do?
And I had a friend reach out to me after he he found out in a crypto startup >> and so I basically within a month learned basically everything that I use nowadays.
Nex.js, Node.js, JavaScript.
I didn't code any of that that kind of stuff.
Before I was doing like low-level Python stuff.
Now all of a sudden I was learning JavaScript next.js and I joined.
>> How did you learn which is like videos courses?
>> So my friend was like hey there here are the things that you need to learn to to come and work with us and yeah I just went on YouTube and I looked up next.js course.
I think it was one of the first ones that comes up when you look up how to code next.js.
>> I add new programming obviously which helps with fundamentals.
But yeah, I looked up No.JS course.
I went through like 20 videos, nextJS, 23, 20 videos, etc.
Tailwind, that kind of stuff.
>> The old days where you had to actually learn stuff.
>> Yes, the old days.
Now you just go and claude or cursor >> build it for me, do it, make it better.
>> You just need to know next.js.
That's all you need to know.
The name and then >> Yeah, that's awesome.
Cool.
So you're so you talk to your friend.
He's like,"Hey, come learn how to do this."
And you're starting to learn.
Cool.
>> Yeah.
And so yeah, I worked with him for nine months on that startup until eventually they went bust.
But I learned so much in that period of, you know, I don't know how it is.
You're building an app yourself doing the actual thing.
It's so much better than just watching YouTube videos.
>> Oh, I I personally have like for months and years probably, especially on Twitter.
Like I'm somehow ended up on the like build in public indie hackers Twitter.
I have no idea how I got there cuz that's not my background really.
But yeah, watching all of them and being like that looks cool or like there's no way they're making money or like just a lot of skepticism around it.
And then but yeah, when now that I've started building my own mobile app and other and learning the the new way of of building with like cursor and things like that,
it's so fun.
>> Yeah.
Has made stuff so fun nowadays.
Yeah.
You're just like, "Oh, I mean, you're just like, oh, I made that and that works.
That's cool."
Like, "Oh, that like it works on my phone.
How does that exist?
And so yeah, that's pretty cool.
So you were kind of like feeling that excitement like this is cool.
Awesome.
>> Exactly.
There's something about building web websites and apps like you're building your app.
Something about the Totally.
So much better doing stuff.
>> Sure.
Yeah.
Awesome.
Okay.
Cool.
No, I agree with that.
It's it's so fun and it's it's it just like there's a I don't want to say powerful, but there's just like a maybe I'll just say like powerful feeling of like I made this and like it came from my head and
onto a screen and that's kind of how we interact with the world a lot these days obviously.
So that's awesome.
Okay, so so that that startup goes bust, right?
>> It does.
End of 2023.
>> Okay, so then what's what's next after that?
>> So then like we just said, I'm absolutely addicted to building websites.
I love it.
And I'm starting to use X, use Twitter for the first time, like properly.
And I see this guy called Mark Lou and he's got like 5,000 followers or I think it was 10,000 followers.
And he he's doing this live stream on YouTube.
And it's like he's building this app.
I forget I think it was called HeroIT.
He was doing this live stream to build this app called Heroit from scratch on YouTube.
One of the first guys to do it.
And I joined it and there were like two people in the live stream.
I was like, "This is awesome.
This guy's awesome."
I sent a couple messages.
I think Mike replied and then like that's awesome.
And then I come back and I'm using X for the next few days and all of a sudden he's like launch this new thing ship fast in a few days or a few weeks boom he blows up >> everywhere and makes hundreds of
thousands of dollars >> seemingly overnight right obviously it wasn't overnight but it seems like it and I'm like what is this?
>> I think most people were like where's this there's that much demand for like for boiler plates for building websites using Nex.js.
>> Yeah.
So for people who don't know what what's like ship fast.
So shiftast is a nexjs boilerplate.
So it's a set of code basically and instructions that Mark a guy who who's on X and Twitter and everywhere basically >> launched that basically helps you make
websites and software very very quickly.
>> So and he was extraordinarily successful with it and has made quite literally millions of dollars off of that and his course codefast as well.
So very inspirational I think for a lot of us.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
So you saw that you're like whoa what the heck is this?
Yeah, literally in real time.
And this is like August 2023.
And then in September 2023, this was literally as I was being laid off, well, not laid off,
it was the the company was going bust.
And so I I was like, I need to build something.
And so I flew out to where my my buddy was because he was the one who I worked with in the crypto startup.
He's in Egypt.
So I flew out to Egypt.
I was like, okay, I'm going to spend a month in Egypt with him.
And we just grinded it out.
We just like next to each other, sat down, just ordered meals online, and just basically tried to build a startup.
It was called Coach Miro at the time.
We're trying to connect like coaches with coaches if you're anywhere.
We built like a landing page.
>> Let let me pause you for a second.
What's kind of like I want to get back to like the Egypt and building that and where you go.
I'm curious just for one click like what's kind of your family or friends saying as you're doing all this stuff.
You know, you're you get laid off, you go work this crypto startup, you fly to Egypt,
you're kind of building online.
Do they even know about it or is that even like a really big factor for you?
If if not, that's fine.
But I'm just curious what that what kind of people are saying people around you are kind of saying as you're pursuing this.
>> That's a really good question.
I am very very lucky to have always had very very supportive parents.
>> Awesome.
>> My parents have always been incredibly supportive of like whatever I wanted to do.
Obviously I had the financial runway.
They have always sort of trusted me because of the the corporate company.
I had the financial runway.
So they they knew I wasn't struggling financially.
They were like okay we understand you have the time.
As for my friends, my friends were doing this kind of stuff.
The friend was the friend I flew out to Egypt with.
I had another friend who was building a similar sort of startup back in the UK.
And yeah, I think it's I don't know about you, but I feel like you start to >> as you get older and you leave environments like school and university,
you start to drift towards the people that mesh your values more.
And so people who had problems with it or didn't believe in it or criticize me, I just drifted away from.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
>> You know, so yeah.
and I had that sport network in the back that I'm I'm very grateful to have have had and have.
>> Yeah.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
And I just ask because you know I don't know my my perspective sometimes is this road can be a little like out of the norm,
you know, like what you're doing is not the traditional thing and so it's I feel like it can be hard to pursue that path and and obviously it's awesome to hear that you have supportive family and
friends etc.
But yeah, I still think there's a little bit of a you're like you're not taking the normal route.
You know, the normal route it would be would have been I got laid off.
Let me go find another job.
But instead, you were like, I got laid off.
This is a mindset thing.
Not that this is like a guru podcast or anything like that, but for people watching like that's there's like a subtle difference there.
And I it took me a long time to start to figure that out.
So, I think it's cool to hear like the support you had and things like that.
>> Yeah, thank you for highlighting that.
I completely agree.
This is the thing I always believe in.
Optimists will always win.
So if you can see the the most optimistic outlook outcome, like I said, it's not a grow podcast,
but if you can be as just as optimistic as possible, I think >> it served me till now at least.
>> Yeah.
Okay.
So you fly to Egypt, you try to build something, it doesn't work.
Yeah.
Tell like are you at that point are you just trying to like just trying a lot of stuff like testing a lot of things or what's that like?
>> Literally.
Literally.
So I think just before I left to Egypt, I tried to set up an agency, a software agency with my with a couple of buddies called Tech.
So I didn't go anywhere.
And then Mustafa and my Mustafa and I my friend, we were in Egypt together and we were at the same time building these other things to coach Miro,
posting on X about it cuz I was so inspired by Mark and I was posting and I was seeing that there was actually quite a big community.
And so I was like, the only thing is I keep randomly coming across a new person every single day.
I would love for a place where I could just like have an like an index, a directory of all the people who do this indie hacking,
which is the term people were using at the time.
And I was like, I want to I would love for this.
So I was like, hey Mustafa, what about an index for indies?
And we're like, index?
So we bought the domain, index.app, and within like a few days, we shipped it.
I think I in terms of validation, I posted a tweet and I was like, "Hey guys, what would you think about somewhere to see all the list of India hackers and it got like 2,000 views,
which for me I was getting 20, 30 views on each post?"
>> Sure.
So, you were like, "Oh, there's something here."
>> Exactly.
>> So, I was like, "We got to build this."
So, in a few days, yeah, we built an MVP.
>> It is.
>> If you go to indidex.app.
>> Do you want to show it off just for fun?
>> I can for sure.
Let's do it.
Let's share my screen.
Share.
It's a Riverside's a little funky for sharing that work.
>> Can you see?
>> Okay, cool.
Yeah.
Indie decks like Pokedex.
>> Exactly.
>> Okay.
Yeah.
>> So, you see it the full screen or >> it's just like people >> Exactly.
It's an ind It's It's exactly what we say here.
It's an automated list.
So, we were fetching the profiles from Twitter, but also allowing people to opt in.
You'd press C and then you'd be able to look if you were on the on Twitter.
I think it still works.
Maybe not.
X always changes their like so I think it's probably broken.
>> Sure.
That's fine.
Yeah.
Cool.
The point is you had like some validation more more than the other stuff you were doing.
This is pretty cool actually.
>> Exactly.
Like finding people go to their profiles like Danny and this used to work.
This used to show your ex followers.
It's really funny because we're basically doing this but way better on SuperX now.
So >> yeah, that's kind of interesting.
Kind of the the threads connecting a little bit there.
Okay.
Yeah.
Let's stay let's stay on that just a little bit.
The like validation thing >> for the other stuff you built.
I'm sure there's other stuff that you know that you tried that didn't work.
>> Yeah.
And this one obviously it's not like this took off but you got a little bit more validation on it because views and obviously people signed up for it etc.
What was that?
Maybe just say a little more about that like trying to validate something like I'm sure there's people watching that are like I don't know like I'm trying a bunch of ideas maybe stuff's not working etc.
How do you validate?
>> Yeah it's an interesting one.
A lot of people have a lot of opinion of a lot of opinions on validation.
I think fundamentally it comes down to are well I think there's two types of validation.
There's interest validation and there's like monetary value validation in that are people interested in it.
People are going to look at it and click on it versus are people going to give you money for it.
And this was a problem I had when it came to building early stuff.
I I don't know if it was imposter syndrome or the fear of just using stripe.
I just didn't monetize anything and so I wasn't making any money.
And so for instance with Indidex it was very popular.
We got number four on Product Hunt, but that said, we didn't make any money from it and I don't think people were willing to pay money at the end of the day.
So for me, what has always worked in terms of a validation strategy, obviously maybe I'm biased towards X,
but I think X is an amazing platform for it.
That said, you should go to where your customers are, for me, Index, it was on X.
The indie hackers were on X.
>> So you go to where your customers are and you just got to speak to them and you got to ask them.
For me, it was posting a tweet out and saying, you know, are people interested in this?
Or you post maybe a teaser of it and see how much interest it gets, you know?
>> Sure.
>> You see these nowadays, people are like, I built cursor for something and it goes viral.
It's such a an interesting thing and it's visual.
So >> cool.
Yeah.
No, that's that's helpful.
To kind of not like pre-validate, but like just figure out what people are willing to pay for versus what they're just like interested in.
And so that's a good example for indie decks where it was like something people were interested in,
but maybe not not enough to pay money.
And obviously at the end of the day, you're trying to survive at least.
>> Last thing I would say about that is people saying that they would pay money doesn't mean they're going to pay money.
The best way to determine if people are going to pay money is by putting a buy link on your >> SAS.
If they pay you money, then they'll pay you money.
You know what I mean?
>> Yeah.
>> You like, yeah, I pay for that.
It's like when it comes to to putting the money where their mouth is, then >> sure >> it can often be different.
So >> yeah, I can Yeah, I can relate to that as a beginner more beginner.
Like there's fear around fear maybe is is this worth paying for?
or am I like it's a more of a selfworth thing maybe of like am I willing to put myself out there you know what if they don't pay for it and it's like that feel that feeling of rejection like looms a little bit
>> if you've never had that before then it's completely understandable it's like there's no confidence confidence is you have a track record of doing certain things but if you have never earned a dollar online then it's like some mystical beast you know
>> yeah you're right when you see when I see people online I'm just like how are they doing that how is that real and it's just like and I don't know they just put a buy button on it.
I feel like I saw a Peter Levelvel's tweet that was like he he he always he often like will repost people that say like oh I'm going to build this and his thing is just like put a landing page put a buy button on it see how it happens and that's kind of the validation piece.
Yes.
>> Cool.
Okay.
So you're you build that so that so stuff's not working.
Index gets a little bit of traction.
Are there other projects that fail or or kind of what happens after?
>> Yeah.
So this is over a period of months.
I took a few months off to travel during this period.
I was I went to Southeast Asia after Egypt basically and I went to Bangkok and I did Bali and Cambodia,
Vietnam, all this kind of stuff and I got a little bit carried away for a couple months but around March 2024 I was like okay I want to get back to this and that was when we shipped Index to product hunts because Index was like an MVP but nothing
special.
So I came back I locked in and I shipped Index.
Index went to number four on Product Hunt.
it got a bunch of visitors slowly like tippled off and I think that what that came down to was we weren't monetizing it.
So there was no incentive.
It was like is this just an endless cycle of building stuff for the sake of building stuff?
>> It's like I I I don't have infinite money to be doing this like I'm slowly burning my runway.
I need to make some money.
So at the same time I I had a a family friend reach out or and he basically reached out to me and he said,
"Hey, I'm an ethical hacker, a pentester.
I've noticed there's a gap in the market for a platform for an a directory again another directory of pentesting tools ethical hacking tools that ethical hackers can go and look at they just dump them on GitHub all over
the place they share them in forums there's no one place so >> well what is ethical hackers what is that >> so ethical hackers are basically people who will hack systems to find vulnerabilities and you pay them to find
these vulnerabilities then you can go and fix them >> so interesting they get in there before the unethical hackers do >> sure you know >> that's cool makes sense though it makes it makes like so much sense.
Yeah.
>> Yeah.
So they they basically have like engineers they will have or like plumbers I guess they have their toolkit of all their tools and they can go in and they can use a tool to you know poke at certain websites etc.
And they will make their own tools and they're constantly shipping their own tools and scripts and stuff like that.
So they he wanted somewhere to to centralize this.
And so I was like awesome.
Okay.
Well from Index and Coach Mirror and all these other things I built up the technical skills.
I built up a little bit of the distribution when it comes to Twitter to X posting.
I also think I was at about thousand followers, something like that at this point, 900 followers.
I was like, "Okay, I'll get a little bit of traction and I'm lacking on the monetization."
So, okay, what are we going to do?
What's the monetization monetization plan?
And he and we chatted and we were like, "Okay, we're going to get enough viewers on this site so that eventually we can charge ads."
In hindsight, it's a little bit naive because it takes often a lot of time to build up enough traction to make money off of ads.
>> So, you can sort of see the way that this was going.
>> Yeah.
>> I built the MVP in two weeks.
I shipped it.
I learned a hell of a lot about SEO at this point.
So that was another distribution angle.
And yeah, I put it out into the world.
Has made a single penny of money.
But that said, it does about a,000 and 1.5k visits a month now.
Like 50 visits a day purely SEO driven.
>> Nice.
>> So pentest list.
Okay.
So that's your next project that starts getting eventually getting a little bit more traction.
But you're I feel like now the difference I'm hearing and obviously I'm just kind of psychoanalyzing a little bit is uh link stuff because people ask for it or there's like some even if it's
a little bit some demand which is I think obvious like it's it's like a duh of course like build stuff people want >> it's not easy it's not
>> when you're in the trenches.
>> Yeah, >> for sure.
>> Because you got to you got to be motivated right?
You got to be motivated yourself.
So you have to have things that other people want, but also something that you want enough to go and build it,
right?
>> Yeah.
>> So it's like people want it, but it's so boring or you're not sure or you're nervous or hesitant.
And it's like, so it's often I find that's why we we get drawn towards stuff that we find cool cuz it's just like,
well, we want to build it, you know, and then later on you find oops, no one else wants it.
So >> yeah, >> got to start again, you know.
>> That's funny.
Yeah.
Yeah, for sure.
Okay.
So you you build this, it's you haven't really made money.
Obviously, we're building towards your eventual recent launch, but yeah, what's kind of the next step or like what happens after?
>> Yeah.
So, that was the last time I was like, this is the last time I'm shipping something and spending weeks on it or months and not making any money.
That's it.
>> So, I was like, okay, I need to upgrade my life.
I need to change your environment.
I don't know about you, but when I feel stuck somewhere, the easiest way to get myself out of it is to change my physical environment.
So, I was in Kosamui in Thailand and I was like, okay, I need to move.
So flew back to the UK and spent about a month at home living with my parents again.
I was like, "Okay."
So I posted this tweet and maybe I can get it up.
>> Yeah.
>> It would be really I can probably use SuperX to try and find it.
>> Shameless plug for SuperX.
>> Shameless plug.
How long ago it was?
Oh, it was Yeah, it was almost a year ago.
It was August 2023.
And basically Yeah, this is it.
Boom.
Found it.
Let me share screens window.
Can you see this?
Yep.
So, basically, I posted this tweet at the bottom.
You can see you've got the little selfie that always works because people want to connect you.
I always say this, if you're posting a tweet and you want to get traction, you want to stand out amongst the AI slop,
>> post yourself.
I understand the resistance, >> but it's it's if you want to connect with people amidst like this the the massive text,
>> face to face content is the way to go.
I posted this this selfie and I wrote this long tweet that basically said, "Right, it's time to be honest.
In the last 11 months, I've made a whopping $0 off savings.
And I was like, look, I just wanted to be as as open and honest as possible.
I went and I listed the four failures.
Techia that I mentioned, Coach Miro, Indidex, Pentest List, shared what I learned each time.
So like Index Product Hunt, 100,000 impressions on launch day, 250 users, no monetization.
Pentest List, we got 10,000 SEO impressions in 2 months, 600 followers on a on a Pentest List X account,
but again, no monetization.
M >> so I basically said look guys the ends are open I have experience I' look I'm looking for an opportunity >> and I'm not going anywhere and then I think this was my first interaction with levels IO I saw him reply he replied to
this thing it's very levels ioesque >> said 26 more failures and you're statistically at a likely winner >> and I saw this and I was like damn levels IO Peter levels like one of my inspirations replies you there among
like amidst a sea of other guys >> and one reply stood out I don't I'm not sure if I I'm going to find it here I think I will cuz He's at the top,
a guy called Ian Nuttle.
I don't know if you're familiar with him on X.
>> I don't know who that is.
Now, >> this guy, he posts a lot about coding with AI now.
And he said this.
He said,"You should start an MVP service.
$2,000, $5,000 to ship an MVP app extension, whatever, and then optional monthly retainer.
We'll give you cash and time to figure out what your next product will be."
So, I said, "Thanks for the idea.
I'm going to take it forward."
Literally in 24 hours.
I don't know if you can see this.
>> Yeah, I can still see it.
Yeah.
>> I launched this site, Liftoff.
It wasn't as fancy as it looks now.
Or not fancy.
It's not fancy, very simple, but like we didn't have the logos, for example.
>> Sure.
>> And I shipped another tweet and this other tweet converted into my first client basically reaching out and saying,
"Hey, I want to work with you."
And I signed literally in about a week from this post an MVP deal for building an app someone for $3,000.
>> Cool.
>> That's awesome.
From there.
>> Yeah.
Cool.
First of all, that's super cool to see almost the you know, and obviously it's it's not magic,
but like you said a few days later or whatever, a week later, you got your first client.
And it's like I think that's like a such a huge like lesson.
I think even for me listening is just like it's not it's almost like it's not magic.
It's like this manual grind of a work, you know?
I think that's like that's pretty awesome.
Okay.
So, cool.
Cool.
Go ahead.
>> I I agree.
It's it's I you know this phrase the the more you do the more you find out.
There's a more explicit version of that you mess around the more you find out.
>> This holds true I think in in every avenue of life.
>> Yeah.
>> The more you do the more problems you find or maybe the more replies you get the more opportunities you get and then >> you just follow a lead from there.
You know the more you it's like buying more lottery tickets and then you just pick one go with it.
For me, that was like Ian's Ian's but also levels I replying gave me motivation as well,
validation that like I wasn't crazy.
I just need to do 26 more and then I was likely to succeed.
>> Yeah.
So, I think for people who are like struggling and and being stuck, just pick something.
Just do like do more.
>> Yeah.
>> Pick up something that you never thought you'd pick up, you know?
>> 100%.
Yeah.
And I' I've totally resonated with that because for years I kind of just watched people online do it and again I haven't done anything.
I haven't like accomplished a lot, but in the last two months of trying to build something,
I've learned way more than like tutorials or videos or just like comments on Twitter.
Yeah, that's pretty awesome.
Okay, so liftoff, get a client.
I'm assuming there's like >> lifts off, you know, >> I was going to make that joke as well.
It literally >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
I I I did this uh strategy where basically you post every sing and this is something I'm I'm so bullish or so uh a believer on not only the face content but post everything post your wins your
losses stuff that can resonate with people emotionally >> because people will will resonate and get inspired by your wins but at the same time just like this tweet your losses are going to resonate with a with
a heck of a lot more people and your wins you know what I mean they're just inspirational >> but the the the losses the struggles most people are in in on that side,
you know.
Yeah.
>> So, if you post and you share about that, and that's something anyone can do.
It could be like, "Look, I'm I'm struggling with this right now."
Obviously, >> you want to write about it in a way that is is >> and genuine.
Yeah.
Just brain dump.
Think about the the structure of it.
If you're writing tweets, for example, this is what I did.
So, across a period of four or five months, I posted everything.
Every time I signed a client, every time something went wrong, I was hiring for someone.
when I when I hired my first like employee or contractor if you want to call it that liftoff >> every single thing I posted and it just compounded compounded and compounded because I got one the first client was
for $3,000 next client for $5,000 I think I got a couple for $5,000 the next one for for $6,000 and then in the span of I think it was back to back back days
I signed two clients that were combined worth $18,000 four months from signing my first client for $3,000 I was signing $18,000 of clients like back to back.
>> Nice.
>> So, it like it scaled super super fast.
>> Yeah.
And you're just driving it from Twitter from Twitter posts >> 10,000 like completely.
I They were reaching out to me.
All of them reached out to me.
The best thing about it was they would come on the call and they'd be like either my son followed you on on X and he he told me about you or my colleague told me about your journey or
I saw you myself on on X.
It's really awesome.
Let's work together.
It wasn't they already knew my story.
They they'd seen my wins and losses.
They'd seen the social proof.
if they seen the, you know, the evidence.
>> Yeah, that's cool.
>> They were already sold.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
There was a guy we interviewed on the main YouTube mainst story channel and uh he talked a little bit about that.
Like one of his pieces of advice was like he's like I'm more likely to want to work with you or hire you or whatever if I just like essentially see evidence of all the stuff you've done.
even if it's not worked, even if you know it's not growing a ton, you're showing me that you've built stuff and I can I feel like I can trust that more than somebody that's like and the opposite not or like
not sharing.
So, I think that's awesome.
It's like a huge lesson.
Yeah.
>> A really nice analogy.
I'm a big fan of analogies and there's this really nice analogy that I first heard.
Cody Schneider, you know Cody Schneider?
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah, he did a podcast with someone, I can't remember who it was, and they talked about this concept of digital gravity.
If you think of your personal brand or your Twitter account as a little planet in the solar system,
every piece of content you push out there is adding on a bit more mass to your planet.
>> If you know basic physics, the more mass you add, the more gravity you get.
If you think about customers, instead of a typical funnel, which is they go in one end and come out the other,
instead it's going to be they're going to be orbiting you and they're going to orbit you two or three times.
And the stronger your gravity, the more people you're going to pull in and the more likely they are to orbit you >> and they orbit you and they look at your content,
maybe they'll come back and they'll do it five, six, seven times and then they'll crash like touch down over time and that's a like basically what you're >> describing.
That's cool.
That's a cool little analogy.
I like that.
I haven't heard that before.
>> Awesome.
Okay.
So, you you get some clients, you know, this is taking off.
What's that like or what's next?
Yeah.
>> So, that took off.
I the the there was a moment where I was making all this money and I sat to myself and I was like there were problems going on with the agency clients complaining about certain things.
I was having issues with my with my contractor.
So I was like okay December 2024 when these client projects finished up and I received the final payment not taking any on any more clients instead.
And this is the transition into SuperX.
>> What I realized at one point I had a call with another MVP agency owner who's very successful.
He still does it.
He still is extremely successful and I chatted with him and I was like how do you write your tweets?
your tweets are doing very very well like you we're both of us were growing our agencies through the tweets and he's like I just have a long chat with Chad GPT like a long chat history and like Chad Gypt knows me now so I just say I want to write a tweet
about this and it writes me a tweet at the time I was writing all my tweets manually >> yeah exists I'm coding with AI why don't I just write my tweets with AI >> there is the argument that when you write tweets with AI it's going to be
lose its authenticity and this is a very very understandable argument and this comes into the whole AI slot thing my stance on this is always AI is a very very good tool to turn good ideas or
good writing into great writing.
>> What a lot of people do and where I think the AI slop comes from is when people are taking bad ideas or just no effort >> or what I say bad ideas and trying to turn that into good stuff and it's just padding and AI just starts to create
this this fluff.
>> Wow, that's great.
You know, >> just don't say anything.
You have nothing to say.
AI just that's AI slop in my opinion.
>> Yeah, sure.
And so AI is a brilliant tool to augment what you already have and make it so much better.
If you come in with nothing, it's you're going to leave with nothing.
Garbage in, garbage out, you know.
>> Yeah.
Yep.
I get that.
>> So, so I was I I I heard him say that he was writing his tweets to AI.
I tried it.
I had a few tweets go viral after I tweaked them.
But AI made it so much easier for me to to do so much more.
And so I get the reps in.
This is something I'm also I also talk a lot about.
get the volume in, get the reps in, and then you're you're you're much more likely to succeed or go viral at some certain point.
And uh I was like, damn, this is awesome.
What if I could productize this?
>> Yeah, >> cool.
>> I'm doing this all manually.
What if I could take this concept of putting your brain in chat chat and wrap that into a product?
Like, let's do this.
I was working with my clients, my last few clients.
I was like, end of this month, I'm going to close these clients.
Like, that's it.
And I'm going to pivot to this thing.
So, I bought the domain.
>> Brandcast, broadcast your brand.
That was the idea.
Smart.
Sounds good.
>> I still have the domain.
It's never been published on anything.
I think I bought the domain and I didn't do anything with it >> because that's clever.
>> Yeah.
So built it.
I built the UI was quite messy.
Kind of worked, but it was very niche to my use case.
>> And the same time I saw this uh I was obviously looking at competitors.
I was looking at type Twenter, these kinds of guys.
And I reached out to Tibo, one of the co-ound one of the co-founders of SuperX.
And I was like, "Yeah, it would be awesome if I could get a a private beta access."
And I was like, "Yeah, sure."
And so I had a look at it and I was like, "Okay, it's very janky.
It like barely holds together.
There's something here."
And I was like, "I think what I can build is much better."
I was like, "Okay, build Brancast."
And and at the same time, I think it was Christmas, New Year's, January 2025.
I was like, "Okay, a few things happened.
First of all, I was like, one of my New Year's resolutions is I'm going to start vlogging."
So, I shipped a vlog, very basic vlog of me going to the gym on YouTube on X to January 2025.
I was like, "Okay, I'm going to start doing this."
I bought a DJ Osmo Pocket 3.
I was like, "I want to do this."
Then about a week after that, I saw TBO post online that his collaboration with the former co-uilder of SuperX was coming to an end and he was looking for a new
technical technical co-founder.
>> Like, I am literally >> I was like, "Okay, it has an existing user base.
It has existing validation in terms of the Chrome extension, right?
They had an incredible amount of data and an incredible uh structure.
And I was like this, I can take what I'm doing with Brancast and whack it into SuperX and make this amazing.
All of a sudden, like the my light bulb was going off.
I was like, "Boom, I can do this with this."
>> And so I reached out to Tibo.
I sent him a a screen recording, a loom.
Basically told him, I was like, "Hey, so last couple months I've been building this app.
if we don't work together, I I'm gonna compete with you if I share my ideas.
It's like negotiation.
I was like, yeah, like I'm building this app.
And I think I was probably the only person who probably reached out to him and was like,
hey, I've been building this thing that basically does what you're doing for the last 2 months.
And this was when everything blew up.
I'd started collaborating with Tibo SuperX, the SuperX web app.
I had booked my flight to Rio Janeiro in Brazil.
So I was like, let's go somewhere else, baby.
You know, I've did Southeast Asia last time.
dropped on Africa.
Let's go to South America.
>> There's a whole another podcast we could do.
Personal life just like tell us about the places you've been, man.
Cuz you you just been dropping like this place, that place.
I mean, that sounds awesome.
>> That's for crazy stories for sure.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I I and I posted this tweet and that's the one that's pinned on my profile.
I was like, I'm leaving my home.
I left my job, my my agency.
I'm living on savings again.
I was making good money from the agency, >> but I was unfulfilled.
I was stressed.
I was unfulfilled.
It felt like I was just on a hedonistic treadmill, you know, >> this this constantly I was making more money and then it was going up here and then like here up here and I was always levering myself up
>> in terms of satisfaction in life.
>> Yeah.
Sure.
Yeah.
I a lot of people uh heard people maybe it's something Pat has said to me or else it's like like MVP services or like an agency is like a really good some people obviously it's a good lifess but it's a
really good start starting point, right?
like you're you're always making money if obviously if it's working, you have cash coming in,
but you're still trading time for money, you know, or like projects or whatever.
So, and it sounds like since you since the start of this conversation, you said you were looking for that sort of freedom.
>> Exactly.
>> Yeah.
>> So, exactly.
I wanted the freedom.
I wanted to have my own SAS.
So, I built it in a week.
He was blown away by it and we we collaborated from there.
>> Cool.
Um, and that was the beginning of our SuperX collaboration >> for the last 6 months since January 2025.
Now it's July 2025.
We have been working on SuperX.
I've been handling the the development side of it, witting about it.
>> And yeah, I've been doing everything I can to make SuperX the best tool to grow on X.
taking my ideas from Brancast of being able to my my dream my goal with SuperX is to have something that understands you so well that the UX is is such that you can just speak into it
and say I have this tweet idea that you know like I'm really struggling right now I don't know what to do you know do a tweet maybe some images generated for it or an instruction to take a selfie everything is managed for you and then
you click a button and boom it schedules it to a time that your audience normally engages with your tweet tweets app so you don't have worry about when to schedule it.
>> Sure.
>> And on top of that, maybe you come in and you don't have an idea.
So you go to SuperX and you see trending articles, trending media, and you can get inspiration.
Maybe it will write you a tweet or it will give you a prompt and it will say, "Why don't you write about this?"
You know, or you can chat with the content strategist >> and you can say, "Man, >> you know,
I I feel like not getting momentum on Twitter.
What can I do?
What can I change?
Look at my analytics.
Look at someone else's analytics I'm inspired by.
You know, what what is the difference between us?"
basically an omnipresent overlord of of X that can tell you what you're doing right and what you're doing wrong and help you get there,
you know.
>> Yeah, that's awesome.
>> This is where we're taking SuperX.
>> Yeah, that's cool.
And so what where where is it at right now?
And obviously I was just showing at the very beginning of this conversation like where you're at,
you know?
>> Yeah, you kind of had a little bit of a launch launch release.
Yeah, if you're comfortable sharing like kind of where where are you at?
>> Users.
>> I share everything so I'm not hiding anything.
Only the only the the code that's what I would share.
But everything else is is open season.
So we grew over the last 6 months to $1,600 monthly recurring revenue in private beta.
So I think we had about 30 active users according to post hog of our web app.
So 30 people using it actively in the private beta.
And a lot of people ask me how did you get users for private beta.
Basically what I did is I screen recorded certain features or I screenshot certain features.
I shared them and I said, "Hey, reply super X if you want early access."
Some people replied.
I DM' them with a link and that was it.
These these private basers were also paying.
It was AI server AI costs, server costs, etc.
>> It was all covered by that.
And so we grew to $1,600 MR in the six months.
>> And during that time, I was shipping loads of features to the Chrome extension and the web app.
There was one feature I shipped called the AI shield because I saw levels I were talking about how there was AI slot on Twitter.
>> Yeah.
>> So I was like okay solution to that would be we can use what we've already got in SuperX which is Chrome extension.
>> We can fetch every single tweet as it appears.
Send it through an AI system to evaluate certain typical trends of what looks like AI content like m dashes overly optimistic things like that >> and it will give a score based on 0 to
10 how likely it is to be AI generated.
Then you can press a button and it will remove all that content above a certain threshold if you want or you can just label them.
So in terms of money now launched the web app days ago >> Wednesday I think.
Yeah.
>> Wednesday the 9th.
And my strate strategy for this was it's just a soft launch.
I'm going to post a tweet and I'm going to do what I always do which is follow up with progress updates,
wins and losses and just post like selfies along with it so that you keep the momentum going.
>> And I did this.
This is my launch strategy.
This is all it is.
I made a very quick video.
I screen recorded something.
We had an old video SuperX extension.
It's on our landing page.
So, I clipped the start of that with a screen recording demo of me doing it.
Glued them together.
Did it in Da Vinci.
Put a cool song on it.
Posted it on Twitter and it went semiviral.
Not really viral.
It was like 30,000 views.
>> Sure.
>> 100 likes.
But in the span of 24 hours, we got 50.
So, that's 50 free trial signups each for $29 a month.
Conversion rate is about 50%.
24 36 hours.
If it converts, and it hasn't converted yet because obviously they're doing the 7-day free trial,
expecting a growth from like 1.6K MR to about 2.5K something in the region of that.
>> Yeah.
>> Maybe more, maybe less.
We'll see.
But I'll be posting about it.
>> Yeah.
Well, I'll be excited to follow along.
That's cool, man.
Yeah.
I think that's uh such a good like I think my take away from this is like you've been doing this for like a long time and and it could superX,
it could have been probably anything else.
you've just kind of are seem to be finding a little bit of a lane.
We'll see obviously how it goes.
You've like a thread there, right?
I think the thread is like sharing updates, good or bad, like sharing online, good or bad,
kind of building it public.
And that's kind of what you're doing again with this launch.
And I think it's I think what I already said my takeaway, but my other takeaway is just like that it might just take a couple shot a lot of shots on goal.
I think that's super underrated but probably super valuable skill to have is that ability to like take a shot didn't
work let's take another shot you know I'm I'm sure there's millions of examples of people that have tried two or three times failed then said escort I'm going to >> sure >> this isn't fun anymore and and they
might have a valid reason for that but for people who like if this is like what they want to do like that you know like level's response to you is like okay just 26 more failures then you're almost there.
Sounds like a lot.
>> It is a lot, you know, but it's like it's a good reminder that it takes time.
>> And the only thing I would add to that is I completely agree with everything you said.
Only thing you need to make sure is as you're between attempts, revise, go back to yourself.
>> Go like, what went well?
What went wrong?
Can I improve it next time?
>> Yeah.
>> And I think if you don't do that, then you might do a hundred shots and none of them work.
>> Sure.
because you're just doing, you know, you won't learn from the the lesson until you've learned from the lesson.
The lesson will keep repeating itself until you've learned from it.
>> So, that's a good point.
>> Me, it was distribution.
Oh, I need to work on distribution, SEO, and Twitter.
Okay, >> now it's not making any money.
Okay, now I'm going to put a buy button on it or I'm going to run an MVP agency to make money.
Okay, that gives me the financial runway.
Now, you know, and you're adding on an extra you go and then eventually you have the boulder.
>> Yeah.
Cool, man.
This has been awesome.
What's kind of like a to summarize kind of the biggest lesson into one final sentence or two?
What's kind of the sendoff here before we wrap?
>> I would say is this homozy quote which I really really really like.
It's not guruesque.
I it resonated with me so strongly.
How it goes is figure out what you want, clear out all your distractions.
Do so much volume that it is statistically improbable that you will fail.
And I think everything that I have learned has come down to these three things.
You figure out what you want.
Do you want to build a SAS?
Do you want to make money?
Do you want to ship things for the sake of it?
Figure out what you really want and then clear out all the distractions.
So your signal to noise ratio needs to be like on on point.
There is so much distraction in 2025.
It's great because it clears out a lot of the competition because they're on Tik Tok.
Problematic because Tik Tok is also there.
Your phone is also there.
I use Instagram reels and stuff.
I still swipe on it.
But it fries your brain.
You know, you're looking also at what other people are doing and all you're doing is scrolling on X and you're consuming and you're not creating also so much noise that you do not need.
Need to look at how successful someone else is doing cuz you don't know the full picture >> so you can't know,
you know.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
>> Clear out that signal to noise ratio.
Just focus on the things that you can actually do something with that are tangible and do so much volume that it is statistically probable that you'll
fail.
So by that I just mean post post ship ship ship keep going just just >> it will take potentially longer than you want it to
>> if you really want it you got to keep going and and and the last thing I would say about that is thing to keep you going your why people have financial wise for me there is the financial why
tied to it but it comes down to and I I did this in one of my daily videos I I spoke about it me it's supporting my family being able to to they've always been incredibly supportive being able to support them back in the future.
Also to remove any kind of like health worries.
The phrase man, a healthy man has like many wishes and dreams.
A sick man has only one just to be healthy again.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't want to have that stress.
So, um, if you have your why and you know what your why is and it's personal enough,
you can keep revising on it.
Then you can keep doing it.
Then you can do the volume.
It's everything I've learned basically.
>> Thanks for coming on the channel, man.
This was really fun.
excited to see where SuperX goes and uh hoping it grows and then we'll we'll bring you on to the main channel for like a a huge feature.
So, let's see where this goes and uh congrats on the success so far.
I think this is this is awesome.
>> Appreciate it, man.
Thank you a lot.
>> Hey, again, thanks for being here.
I hope you enjoyed that conversation with Rob.
Leave your feedback in the comments.
What's kind of one thing you're taking away, your favorite part of the episode, or if there's any other feedback for us,
please leave that as well below.
And while you're there, check out the first link in the description for starter story build.
A theme I think you heard in this quick episode with Rob was that he built a lot of stuff in order to finally find the thing that's starting to make some money.
And if you're someone maybe like me who didn't exactly know what to build or didn't know where to start,
I would really encourage you to check out Star Story Build.
It's our program for helping you use things like Cursor or Lovable to find an idea and build and ship your first app into the world.
Now, are you going to be rich overnight?
No way.
But the first step to building anything successful, I think, is to actually build something.
So, check that out if you're interested.
It's that starter story build.
But besides that, thanks for being here and have a nice weekend and we'll see you next Friday.