Hi, my name's Pat and this is episode 10 of the 100K build challenge where I'm setting off to see if I can make $100,000 using only AI tools.
And quick update for you guys, my app is finally getting traction.
And I actually made more money this week than I've made in the entire challenge so far.
And that's the story I'm going to be sharing with you today.
But before we get into it, if you're watching this for the first time, the rules of the 100K challenge are simple.
Rule one is I can only use AI tools.
Rule two is I must document everything here right in this channel.
And rule three is that I cannot give up until I make $100,000.
This is how much I've made so far.
And these are all my failed projects so far along the way.
Quick random note, you can follow all this in real time at labs.starterstory.com.
But if I'm being honest, this challenge has not been easy.
If you guys have been watching, you know I've nearly given up multiple times, but I keep coming back.
Mostly thanks to everyone in the comments who keeps cheering me on.
My goal with this challenge in this series is to show you the real journey with all the ups and the downs and hopefully inspires you to build something and ride this insane AI wave that's happening
right now.
So today's episode is all about a huge breakthrough I had.
And it all starts just a few days ago.
So it starts at this point where I finally have an app that has some potential.
It's really at the MVP stage.
But what's cool is that I really believe in this idea so much that I find myself lying awake at night thinking about it,
which I think is a good sign.
Or maybe I'm too attached to it.
Honestly, I'm not sure, but there's only one way to find out.
I'm honestly so excited about this idea that I've been waking up every day at 6:00 a.m.
And I'm not usually a morning person.
I have my coffee.
I take a I finally get to my desk and fire up Claude Code.
And then I take a look at my to-do list and it has like a hundred things that I want to do.
Features, bug fixes, world domination, and I want to get it all done today.
So, I start prompting Claude Code and I feel productive.
But all of a sudden, I look up at the clock and it's 1:00 p.m.
And what did I get done?
I'm honestly not really sure.
And this is when I start spiraling.
The uncertainty, the self-doubt, and then the imposttor syndrome.
All of a sudden, I'm doomcrolling social media, comparing myself to all my competitors.
And then I look up again.
It's 8:00 p.m.
and Bernie is barking at me because I still haven't taken him on a walk.
This is not productivity.
This is not a good place to be.
There's something wrong with my routine or workflow, but I'm not really sure what it is,
but it's late and I got to go to bed.
I wake up the next morning with a clearer head.
I fire up Chat GBT looking for a solution this time.
Hey chat, will you be my startup coach?
Sure.
What's going on?
I explained the whole situation.
Chat, I just feel overwhelmed.
Young Patrick, the answer is simple.
You must talk to users.
Why?
Talking to users will help you uncover what they actually struggle with instead of guessing what features they need.
And users will tell you how they describe their problems, which will help you write better copy for your landing page and pitch your product idea more clearly.
If you have these regular conversations, they'll help you ship, test, and iterate quickly,
which is the key to actually building something that works.
And then it hits me, oh, duh.
All these features I've been building, they're worthless if I don't even know if anybody wants them.
So, here's what I do.
I pull up Gmail.
I start crafting up a draft to anybody who even signed up for my app.
It says, "Hey there, you're getting this email because you're an early user of Mo.
I know the app is early and it has issues, but thank you for being an early part of it.
Then I told them about new features that we launched.
And at the end, I added a line that says, I want to chat with you.
I put a link to book something on my calendar.
And then I sent it off.
Within 2 minutes, I had a call booked on my calendar.
Oh my god, what?
This is crazy.
I'm already nervous for this call.
And you probably won't believe this, but I'm actually an introvert.
I just want to sit behind my computer all day and play with Claude Code.
And all day I'm anticipating this meeting with nervous energy.
And then finally the call starts.
I'm waiting.
Nobody's coming on.
This guy is going to noshow.
And then all of a sudden a boo joins the call.
A software engineer from South Africa.
I'm feeling awkward.
What do I say?
But I keep it casual.
And I ask him what he does.
Where's he from?
And then all of a sudden he tells me he loves what I'm building.
He loves my app.
I couldn't believe what he was saying.
this thing, this app I'm building is borderline broken.
It's super early, but he tells me he sees the vision and he shows me tweets that he's already created with the app.
We chop it up for almost an hour and he tells me about his app he's building, PRD pulse,
and how he's trying to build in public and get out of his introverted shell as well.
I ask Abu all sorts of questions that I got from this awesome video by Eric Mijikowski on how to talk to users,
and I'll put those in the comments if you want to see them.
At first, before the call started, I was nervous and it felt awkward, but by the end,
I realized that he's just another guy like me, a software engineer trying to build his own things and ship them.
It was so much fun.
It was so cool meeting one of my users, and it felt amazing after I got off the call.
But more importantly than any of that, I got off the call with a renewed sense of clarity.
This one quick conversation with my target customer felt more productive than all the features I had been building in the last few weeks.
I now knew exactly what my product needed.
I knew exactly who my target customer was.
And I just had so much clarity, which gave me even more conviction about how this idea can be huge.
So, I know all I got to do is keep doing this, talking to customers, building what they want,
and talking to customers again.
So, what's my big takeaway this week for the 100K build challenge?
Stop hiding behind your code.
Talk to your customers.
It doesn't have to be over a call.
It could be an email, a Twitter DM, or even in these YouTube comments right now.
One customer conversation might be worth hundreds of hours of coding, and it honestly could make all the difference.
Thank you guys for watching the 100K build challenge.
This has been episode 10.
I'm really excited about this idea, and I'm going to keep going with it.
So, let me know what you want to see me cover next.
I hope you guys like this new format.
I'll see you in the comments and I'll see you in the next one.
Peace.