99% of Founders make this exact mistake when they're starting out they think if you build it they will come no no no this never works after getting millions
of views on my content hundreds of thousands of users for my product and building my own business to over $1 million a year I'd like to think that I've cracked the code a little bit but here's the thing you don't need a crazy
idea you don't need funding and you don't even need an amazing product you just need to Master One skill attention this is usually the difference between
successful and failed Founders so in this video I'm going to share with you my three-part framework for getting attention on your business on your product and getting users I teach this
method to members of the starter story growth accelerator and many of them have gone on to go viral get their first users and some of them even making more than $10,000 a month after doing this oh
and stick to the end because I'm going to be showing you a real world example of a business built-in starter story that's now making $112,000 a month this is the million dooll attention Playbook
let's go so before we dive into the whole Playbook uh this session was part of the starter story growth accelerator the accelerator is designed for people who are serious about building and
getting attention and taking their business or product to the next level some of the strategies and tactics I'm about to talk about today are part of the accelerator that's all for now let's dive in let's talk about the power of
attention this is I like to preface before we go into the framework or anything like that I want to just share a little bit about my story this is the original starter story landing page stories about Millennials starting
businesses this was the business that I thought that was going to be successful if I just built it and then people would show up there was already some similar businesses out there that were doing something uh similar making some money so I built this put it out there and
just hoped that the thing would just get users get traction and then be able to monetize it and all that stuff so I hit publish on the website created the Facebook page created the Instagram page
I even emailed some people about it and I was just now waiting for the success to happen right looking at the Google analytics screen and hoping that you know people were going to show up
because you know I had this business I think that was going to be successful there are other successful people doing it and I was like okay that's that's all I got to do and then sure enough nothing
zilch NADA no users come to the website obviously hindsight is 2020 I should have marketed it I should have put it out there and I just expected uh um to
be successful because I saw what other people were doing and just copied them so I go looking for Solutions how can I solve this problem and over sure enough
over a long long enough period of time I realized that after studying lots of other Founders and lots of other stories and actually reading into it if you
build it they will not come and you know sometimes you'll hear if you build it they will come every founder realizes at some point sometimes it takes weeks
months years or even decades if you build it they will not come good products are built on distribution attention and you can have an amazing product and have no users or you can
have a product with pretty good marketing and you can have customers and that's probably something that you guys have noticed when you go and look at trying to start something or you're looking at competitors or you're looking at other people in the space ah these
guys products they're really not that good like this doesn't work this thing doesn't work like this is a huge bug this is a huge problem yet they still have make all this money and doesn't really make a lot of sense this is how I was kind of what I was realizing and
this is my aha moment when I realize the secret to making money is not about having the perfect idea or the feature or building on the right Trend or or all these things it's about attention and distribution so I go into deep work mode
trying to figure out how can I get more eyeballs on starter Story how can I get more eyeballs on my thing and after months of work what it felt like or at least months of work a long time I eventually create one piece of content
and this wasn't the first piece of content I created but I was creating lots of stuff I was like how can I get more people to see this thing that I created and I created this Reddit post right here and certainly wasn't my first Reddit post but it was the first one
that actually took off and this Reddit post got about 400 upvotes which isn't crazy it didn't go viral it was simply taking one of the stories from my website which I was building a media
property a blog a website that would be monetized by potential sponsorship so you know eyeballs was the name of the game and tens of thousands of people viewed this post and this was the piece
of content content that created the inflection point for me and this changed everything I doubled down I did more Reddit posts I started posting in other places online I started using like Reddit comment strategy and this is how
I got thousands of users hundreds of people talking about my product followers and people telling me that they love my product and it was useful for them and it inspired them and this was the inflection point right this is
when I found a channel I doubl down on that and I just kept doing more of it and this is what led to starter story becoming an actual business that had actual users where people were emailing
me that to sponsor the website for thousands of dollars all because I focused on attention and distribution and the reality is I've talked to thousands of Founders you guys have
maybe watched some of the YouTube videos and we have thousands of case studies you'll realize when you read all these case studies is that reddit's not the only distribution Channel there are hundreds of distribution channels out there and there are thousands of
different ways to exploit them the way that I did it on Reddit was just this very kind of specific thing and a very specific subreddit and it worked and there's lots of other subreddits and there's lots of other
ways to do it and you'll read in our case studies in on starter story is every single founder will talk about their Channel their thing that worked for them every successful business I
know at least especially in the solopreneur and solo founder bootstrapped space is all built off of attention distribution and a good
Channel you don't need a life-changing idea you just need attention on your idea if you understand this concept I think you can turn any idea into a million-dollar business but there is one
caveat it's important to say that attention can't turn any idea as it stands into a million-dollar business but attention will give you the information and data necessary about what needs to change if it's not going
to be a million-dollar business and and that's actually goes for most products if you have a business that's not going to be a million-dollar business because you can't scale in this way or has this one hole in it that is okay and the only
way to uncover that is through getting attention on it and finding out that it's not going to work and there's another element which is actually talking to people once you get that attention that will help you uncover
that so if you feel skeptical about your product being successful or your ability to scale or whatever you're building that's normal and that's good attention
will solve that problem this is what I'm quinting the the bat framework which is really really simple so my goal is to keep this framework super simple so that it will also work for virtually any
business I think okay this is the bat framework build attention talk b a build attention talk B build the product a get attention on it t talk to potential
customers that come from that attention it's really as simple as that but I'm going to dive a little bit uh more into it build attention talk you have 24 hours in a day 7 days in a week you
should be spending 20 20% of your time building the product 40% of your time getting attention on the product and making sure that you convert that
attention into users that you talk to which you be should be spending 40% of your time talking to those users getting feedback taking that data and that information from talking to those users
and funneling that back into the build this is overly simplified on purpose but the first thing that's important is that it's 8020 so you are spending 80% of your time marketing and talking to users
and 20% of your time building this is overly simplified you can't have one without any of these others you can't just build and get attention and not talk to users and you can't just get attention and talk to users and not
build anything right I believe if you can do all these three things in a somewhat balanced way generally at the same time you will win it won't happen overnight but you will win if you can do all these three things over time you'll make more money than you can ever
imagine but it doesn't happen overnight so I'll explain this with an example it's really really simple example but hopefully it will help clarify things so B you build a landing page a simple
landing page just a onepage landing page whatever you share it with your network a that's a 10 you already have people that follow you on LinkedIn or whatever that already trust you that is like the most highest leverage form of getting attention for
you right now maybe not not you specifically but for most people that don't have an audience or something like that from that attention from your network from those posts or emails or whatever you do capture those emails and
you get on interview calls you DM and email these people relentlessly that's talk that's talking to customers then from talking to those customers you take that feedback and you make changes to your product your copy your offer based
on what those those people told you and the data that you got from those people not necessarily data from like surveys or something like that data that you got in your in your gut from talking to a
few people and seeing what those Trends are then you go and try to get more attention you go and do a Reddit post ay attention that attention gets converted
to emails and further calls or DMS or whatever and then uh you talk to those users obviously let's say a 100 people give you attention on it three people
you end up talking to that's that's okay that's just the that's the the attention funnel right then you take that feedback again you iterate you make more changes to the product you add a feature you remove a feature you change your copy
whatever then you go and get more attention let's say a piece of data you got from those customers was that oh yeah I browse this other subreddit that's information that you got from that interview or customer interview or
talking to that customer you go and take that and do more Reddit posts so you take that information not only to the build but also the marketing you'll give more attention you do a few more smart cold emails or Reddit posts if those
worked or if you got information about those and then you talk to those users and you funnel it back so you're it's like attention flywheel right you're talking uh getting attention talking to
customers and then funneling that back into changing the product and this is what happens this is not something that happens in a month this is what we've been doing at starter story for years this is what I I believe is like
generally what uh companies with product Market fit do right it's just improving the product maybe it's not as much as build but it's improve and that always comes from getting attention talking to
customers okay stop there real quick before we continue if you've been struggling to get users on your business attention on your product I want to invite you to join the growth accelerator over the past seven years of
building starter story I've learned firsthand that attention and distribution are the most important parts of any business you can have an amazing product but if you don't get attention on it it means nothing that's
why I built the growth Exel Ator it's a 28-day Sprint where you get the operating system I've used to get hundreds of millions of views on your product and thousands of customers so if you're ready to get traction on your
business head to the first link in the description and check out the growth accelerator if you're serious I hope to see you in there but now let's get back to the video okay let's go into each one into more detail so let's go into the
build phase let's dive into build real quick we're going to go through each element of the bat framework build attention talk so generally speaking 20% of your time should be spent building the product iterating and making changes
on it and a lot of times that is really just adding features or removing features which is one of the most elusive things is that I see is people adding features that shouldn't be added
so just by default 20% of your time is spent building it not 50% and definitely not 80% building is necessary but it I don't think it's all that important
obviously you need to have a product but by first principles a product will not generate attention users you can build something put it online and it can never ever get visited by someone ever and
that is the harsh reality of a lot of products and a lot of things even just being on an app store or something like that doesn't guarantee anything some rules for the build phase I want to keep this simple is avoid building
unnecessary features if someone didn't tell you they needed this do not build it right if you have this feeling in your gut that you need to build this one feature or customers won't like it don't
do that you didn't have someone tell you is the point of building something if no one tells you they wanted it avoid building if your product is starved for attention if you don't have any attention don't build there's no point
in building if you don't have attention avoid building if you haven't talked to users or customers and gotten data and specific feedback right anything that you build if you really only had 20% time you'd only have time to build the
things that people actually asked you for so avoid building unless you actually have that data and avoid even if you do have that data avoid building something because one person told you they needed it not all feed back is created equal it may not be your
customer they may be unique build things based on multiple insights and we're going to talk about the power of talking to more and more people because that will make that part a lot easier okay some tips if you inherently love to
build things you still got to build things instead treat building as a reward so reward yourself for building after you do some attention earing and after you talk to some customers I like
to save my build time for the shallow hours so don't do build stuff during deep work because you're probably already really good at building and you don't need that deep concentration to
write that piece of copy and make it perfect that's a deep work activity or um working on you know a strategy thing
or you know just something that is hard new scary that is the Deep work stuff what I like to do because I really like to build stuff is like okay we we got to build that thing but I'll save that for
the weekend when I have those couple extra hours and I'm just kind of chilling and I'll build that part so I like build on the weekends attention and talk on the weekdays Jacob said I need to make a rule that I cannot open my
code editor during deep work I just wrote this on my reflection Doc and realized how my perspective has changed in the last month and Jacob is an awesome example of someone who's building something really cool and really focus on attention he got like
millions of views on Tik Tok for his uh his service okay so if 20% of your time is building 40% of your time should be spent getting attention to your product and making sure that you convert that
attention into users a percentage of that attention into users so you can have an amazing product but without attention you won't get a single customer we kind of talked about that
that's a fact right just by first principles there's no way that you could get a customer without attention so by the same logic I believe the more attention you can get on your product
the more chances you have to get customers and the more attention you get the more data you can get on why your product sucks and What needs to change so like I said earlier you may not have
the million dollar idea but attention will get you to the million-dollar idea some rules and tips for the attention phase attention doesn't mean viral you do not need a million views or followers
you do not need an audience you simply need to get in front of more people so 10 potential users is an order of magnitude better than one potential user
and a 100 potential users is an order of magnitude better than that right 100 potential users May convert to five actual paying users so that's all that really needs to happen it doesn't need
to be a million with starter story it was I don't know a thousand people on my email list before it was monetized and that wasn't a million right it was a couple Reddit posts that got me there
it's better to have a small amount of really passionate users than a bunch of not passionate people that's especially when starting out you don't need you you only need one customer right you'll know
there will be more in the future that you can get with attention there's no silver bullet or perfect Channel that I could tell you right now you have to try a lot of things you have to look at what's actually working for other successful businesses right now that
Reddit thing that is 7 years old right I posted that six or seven years ago that's probably not going to work now but there's I guarantee you there's a million other things that's working what what are we doing as starter story right
now we're doing YouTube right I'm going to practice what I preach here is that we are going where the attention is and this is from studying other businesses and looking at Trends and seeing where
people where those eyeballs are for your specific customer so that means trying a lot of things and and doing research when things work do them again do them differently but do them again and just
do more of them that's important too you should never automate or use AI for the attention process because this is very much like trying to find product Market fit if you go and just ch uh generate
something with chat GPT and put it onto LinkedIn it's not going to get likes it's not going to work people can see through that kind of thing and it doesn't work at this at this point it's
about doing the absolute best because is such a small amount of people it's got to you got to do it right to get it to see if it could potentially work is important to get attention from the
right users I kind of explained this before if you made a like say an Instagram reel about what you had for breakfast and it got a million views that's not going to lead to a single customer for a SAS app right that's less
valuable than 100 potential customers seeing a Reddit post they have the money they'll pay you so think about intent when itur uh comes to attention and then this is important but you must actually
to capture a percentage of that attention right you get a thousand people to your website I hope that you can convert 1% some some percentage of that two people that you can actually
talk to this is usually done by collecting emails but it's not the only way to do it but it's important to capture attention because if you get attention but you don't talk to those users you don't learn from them then it's useless let's go to the talk
section and we'll go through this one all right so it's not a perfect number but I think about 40% of your time should be spent talking to users getting feedback making sales taking all this data and building your customer
knowledge asset which I'll talk about and funneling these insights back into the build phase and the attention phase of of the flywheel so just like building is nothing without attention attention is nothing if you don't talk to these
people and understand uh their needs pains wants desires so one way I like to think about this is that these people that gave you attention that watched your Instagram reel or read your Reddit
post these are real people with real problems and they are your potential some of them are your potential customers and isn't that crazy it's like you're almost there you have these
people on the hook now all you have to do is reel them in right if you talk to them and this is what I think is amazing you almost have them and if you talk to
them you will unlock the secrets that will lead them to handing over money to you the gold m is sitting right in front of you and all you have to do is dig your hand in and do the work right and I
want to repeat this one again because I wrote this and just it really felt powerful to me especially looking back on all the mistakes that I've made and what hindsight if you talk to them you
will unlock the secrets that will lead them to handing over their money to you they won't do it right away but you will unlock the secrets that will lead to them doing that 99% of people who launch
businesses they don't talk to anybody a lot of Founders are introverts and you might be too I am as well it's scary to talk to people you might get rejected people might um not show up up to your
calls they might tell you your product sucks they might just say no these all all these things suck and but they're part of the process all you have to do is be curious ask questions and let your
potential customers tell you about their problems and just let them talk right you'll be amazed at what happens if you simply do this and I'm just going to keep going on this now because I think it's so important it doesn't matter what you're building if you're building an
app that's a $5 app you still talk to customers what is the value of talking to customers I think that one I if I could put a number on it one IRL in real life
conversation where you got to sit face to face with your potential customer I think it's worth $1,000 and that money on the scale so like yes one of them might not be worth
that much but you may have a $10,000 conversation with someone right this money represents if you do enough of them this money represents the insane
information that you extract from them and this information is nowhere to found to be found on the internet packaged in such an easy to consume way sure you can find on the internet but there's so much
information out there that it's hard to parse what a c what that customer would say or what they wouldn't that is the power of conversations and I like to think of every customer conversation
that you have adds a notch in your belt that represents the N the full nebulous knowledge of your customers what they need want and desire so think of the
knowledge of your customer like an asset you don't know that much much about them right now maybe or you know a certain amount about them but every time you talk to them you learn new things and
you become empath more empathetic to that customer and what they need and if you serve decide you want to serve the same customer over years then this really builds if you do this over a long period of time for example this is kind
of what we do at starter story we know who our customer is and over time we've gotten better at understanding what that is but there's still so much more that is the asset that is a million dooll asset you can't put a price on it but
your knowled of the customer is what you can turn into million-- dollar businesses over and over so that's how powerful it is it's not just one business it is an entire customer segment right and this is when you why
you see the same people launching the same businesses over and over they sell their business and they go start another one which is very adjacent or they have multiple businesses that all kind of serve that customer they're not building multiple businesses they're building one
huge business that all serves the same customer my favorite example of this is this guy uh Tom he built a business selling AI children's books it's called self and I asked them I was on a call with
them and I asked them hey are you worried about like AI or chat gbt like just replacing your business like stable diffusion just launching your features and taking your business and I loved his answer because he was so confident about
it and he said that he wasn't in the AI business even though his business is one of those AI businesses right he told me that he wasn't in the AI business he was in the business of children's gifts and
children's gifts will never go away right he sells like basically gifts that Grandma mothers buy for their children grandmothers will always buy gifts for their children and they will always have
similar pains wants needs and desires that will never go away AI is just the vehicle for him to do that right now and the growth tactics he used those will come and go but giving gifts to children
will never go away and over time he will know his customer better than anyone else and he's not in the AI business he's in the children's books business right that's thinking about it from the
customer so talking to customers has three massive advantages number one these conversations build up your customer knowledge asset we just talked about number two these conversations
give you the data on what you need uh to build what you need to change or even what you need to Market differently so just having these conversations gives you very valuable data and potentially
one of maybe just like a nice little extra icing on the cake is these customer these these conversations these talking to customers is a form of sales these people will likely buy your
product or back you as an entrepreneur through Word of Mouth you know they want to get in your Camp they are early adopters and they want to buy your thing and they want to tell people about your thing and they want to evangelize uh
what you're doing so those are three huge things but that is basically the bat framework the bat framework thanks for coming guys I'm excited to see what
you guys do and get your feedback and yeah see what happens