What's up, guys?
It's Pat here.
I got my dog right back there enjoying a little Florida sun, but I'm here to declare that I'm about to do the AI build challenge.
No team, no plan, just me in a wild challenge that I'm setting for myself using AI tools.
Lately, it feels like we're living in the AI gold rush.
Every week, there's a new tool, new technology.
Someone is launching something and getting to like a 100K MR in like 2 weeks, and I want to get in on it.
So, here's the challenge.
I'm going to try to make $100,000 using only AI tools.
I have no idea how I'm going to do this, but I'm going to start with an idea and a prompt and see what happens.
But before we do that, I do want to set a few ground rules.
Rule number one is that I can't work on anything unless I film it.
No secret progress.
Nothing goes undocumented so that you can watch it here on this channel.
Rule number two, I can only use AI build tools.
Yes, I know how to code, but I will prove you can do this without knowing how to code.
Rule number three, I will not stop until I make $100,000 or completely flop trying a bunch of different things.
I will be sharing everything right here on this channel.
So, please subscribe and please watch these episodes.
This is episode one.
We're going to start with the idea and see what happens.
Let's go.
All right, let's get started.
In this episode, I'm going to see how far I can get by writing down my idea, trying to write down the problems it solves,
what I'm going to build, get the app working to then see if we can make some money from this.
So, let's get started and let's see what happens.
All right, so I have an idea and I'm going to be as honest as possible with the idea.
It came to me literally while I was sleeping last night.
I was dreaming about this idea and that's always a good sign.
And uh sometimes I would say like, you know, probably should go write down a bunch of stuff about the idea and how it could be successful or whatever.
But this is [ __ ] vibe coding.
I'm gonna vibe code until I make 100K.
I'm gonna build cool stuff and see what happens.
So, I'm just going to write down quickly what the idea is going to do, but that's about it.
And I kind of want to go in a little bit blind with this idea and just see what happens.
And let's see how fast I can do this.
So, all right.
I like to do my docs.new.
You guys know about docs.new.
It's the best.
Create it.
It's that's like an actual domain docs.new and it creates a Google doc.
I'm sure everyone knows that and I'm just a boomer over here, but let's try it.
Okay, so my 100K idea, this is something I think you can make 100K doing.
Also, it could be a total [ __ ] flop.
Like, who cares?
That's what we're here to build.
And I want to show that it's possible.
And I'm not just a YouTuber who talks about successful businesses.
I show you that I can actually build this [ __ ] So, all right.
So, here's my idea.
YouTube thumbnail generator where you can generate a thumbnail based on a drawing, some uploaded images,
and some text.
This is my idea.
And I'll show you the tweet that I found this on.
Oh, wait.
It's on my Twitter.
So, I don't love to go find business ideas based on tweets because, you know, there's probably a bunch of other people building this already.
But what got me intrigued about this is a couple things.
Number one is the problem.
I think I write two things.
It's problem and my edge.
So, I like two things.
Problem is having a great YouTube thumbnail can quite literally make or break a video and a YouTube channel,
but creating them is costly.
I just paid someone $50 per thumbnail and it was pretty basic stuff times four for a video.
That's 200 bucks, right?
Imagine I could spend less and get a better result.
That would be crazy.
I just pay someone $50 per thumbnail times four for a video.
That's 200 bucks.
And that's generally what we pay for videos.
It also takes time.
Often we'll do tons of reference shots to get the right one.
I'm going to show you right now.
Here, this is for a thumbnail we're working on.
Look how many these are real photos that we took.
These are actual real reference shots and we probably spent 30 minutes doing thumbnails.
That's time, money, effort, right?
What's my edge for this?
I like to say this too because I think if somewhere else someone else were to go and create this thumbnail generator just like if you were watching this video and you went to copy me like why why would I
win over you or why would you win over me?
I have a YouTube channel with 500,000 subscribers and I need this tool myself.
I'll be motivated to make it better than the rest.
I also have an audience of people who want to create on YouTube.
I know people watching this be,"Oh, you have an audience?
This is so much easier for you."
Like, you can do this.
You don't need an audience to do this, right?
If I go to Lane, I don't know how big this guy is.
He only has 8,400 followers.
And this tweet, and I know that maybe sounds like a lot, but this tweet got 1.9 million views.
Imagine if you actually had a a reply in here that said, "Okay, try out my software."
You would get 10,000 MR literally from that.
If you think about conversion rates on that, right?
[ __ ] crazy, right?
This is what's changed in this world.
Like, you got to get building now because you can have a smaller account.
Maybe he had 5,000 followers when he tweeted this and you can get 2 million views.
This is the one time in history where this may be possible.
Start building.
I'm going to link to the AI build accelerator right now in the description.
If you want to build something like this in 12 days, shameless plug, this is the this is starter story build and you can go to our app accelerator right here and you in 12 days you can build a real app
using AI using only AI tools like this the one like the one I'm using here.
But I'm I want to prove that it's possible so you can go and do it too.
Anyways, okay, let's go back.
This is my idea and I I call this like the one pager, right?
this is if I spend five minutes just writing down my idea and just some of the ideas of what it could do,
then I'm going to feel more motivated on to get it done.
Look, anybody can probably create this tool, but when you get to the end and you know,
you got to fix those bugs and you have customer support and you have all are you going to be as motivated to to do this if you don't actually experience the same problem?
This is why copycats never work, right?
Look, there's a lot of ways to approach this soling people create thumbnails.
What I think is cool about this is just a small widget toy app almost like a proof of concept.
It only needs to be useful.
And I think that that's cool.
That's like the idea of like micro SASS, right?
Here are the features I'm going to build.
And this is helpful to put together because now I know what I'm going to launch with and I don't have to question that.
So onepage feature that allows you to draw the thumbnail, upload some reference shots,
and write a prompt.
It results in five thumbnails that are YouTube ready.
Look, I could do more.
I was like, "Oh, you can go and prompt it again to get more ideas."
That like, let's just get the proof of concept going.
And that's it.
Okay.
Then I'm also going to put a Stripe payment link or checkout link to validate that people will pay for this.
And some people might not like this, but I'm not going to allow any free thumbnails.
Maybe maybe I'll change that, but I don't want to lose money on a bunch of people just trying it out.
I'm gonna have like a free to sort of try.
Maybe you can get one but not all of them.
You could there's a lot of ways you could approach it, right?
You could do like, oh, they get a low res one and not the high-res one.
Look, this all these sort of things don't really matter.
The best way to do it is I just want to put a Stripe payment link on it and see if somebody pays for it.
And if they do, then I can explore other ways of monetizing and that sort of thing.
But the simplest way, the one line of code type of way of doing things will be to ask for payment upfront before they can actually use or before I lose money by
hitting Open AI's app or API.
So, how much will I charge?
I'm going to charge five bucks a month.
I want to make it like so I will raise this price, but let's just try five bucks a month.
It's a simple toy app.
And you know, thumbnails are like that cool little thing.
is like, okay, if I could save if this is 200 bucks for one video and I could do five bucks a month and plus my team is going to love this too that I don't have to hire designers and to do that whole headache,
right?
All right, I'm probably missing a bunch of stuff here, but I feel like this is cool.
And like the other thing I'll say is like I like this.
You see, we have this video with Nico on our channel who dude, I just love talking to founders and like hearing what works for them and not.
Well, go watch this video.
It's awesome.
He built 17 apps and sold two of them for 265,000.
He did locked himself in a room, taught himself how to code.
And one of his like biggest lessons, which I think is like probably people will overlook it because they're looking for the growth strategies or the tactics or whatever.
His was to set himself a hard deadline saying like I need to launch this by the end of the day or the end of the week or else.
So I'm going to set myself a hard deadline of launch in 4 hours.
I think I can actually do it faster.
We're going to be doing this with cursor and from scratch.
You guys get to follow along.
Okay, I think we're ready to get started.
We need a name.
Duh.
Name.
You don't have to have a name when you start, but I like to have a name and a domain name.
Maybe it would be cool if we did like I like to do like a domain name.
What are people actually searching?
So, let's go to create thumbnail.
Generate clickable thumbnails with AI.
AI thumbnail maker.
Free AI thumbnail maker.
I want to make free AI thumbnail maker.com.
Let's see if that exists.
Okay.
So if someone searches free, so this is what this is my mode of thinking for this.
If I search free thumbnail maker, then Google will like if my domain is the same as the query,
if that makes sense.
So I'll say freenailmaker.com.
It's available.
Wow.
Okay, let's try a This is crazy.
AI thumbnailmaker.com.
It's not actually free, right?
We're going to make it cost money.
So we got to do something that's actually real with it.
Let's let's search.
I like AI thumbnail maker.
I don't love AI because eventually people won't even care that it's AI.
It's just something that makes thumbnails for you, right?
That's like thinking long term a little bit.
So maybe thumbnail creator.com 2,800.
That's too expensive.
16 AI thumbnails maker.
I like that one.
I'm going to buy it.
It Let's buy it.
I don't know what C means.
I think mean Canada or something.
Okay.
Confirm order.
Domain registration.
Hey guys, we're doing the thing we're not supposed to do, which is buy a domain first,
but screw it.
AI thumbnailsmaker.com one-year subscription.
I can afford a $16 that's Canadian.
I don't know why they're charging me in Canadian.
They think I'm in Canada.
But anyways, I just want to buy the domain now so I don't forget it later and this video gets published and then someone steals my domain name.
So, it's purchased and okay, we have our domain name.
Okay, name AI Thumbnails Maker.
I know it's very clever.
This is exciting.
We have a business idea built on a simple premise, a single feature.
I like to call this a pointy feature, right?
It just does one thing.
It's only going to do one thing.
That's going to make it really easy for me to launch this and maybe get a few hundred people to use it,
get a bunch of feedback on it, make it better, see if people are willing to pay for it.
I could do it in 4 hours.
And I got a name for it.
I got a domain name.
And now, let's start building.
Okay, this is the part that's going to be fun.
I'm going to go through the whole process of building this with cursor.
It's been a while since I created a project, but let's try it.
I got cursor here and I want to start it totally fresh.
So, I'm seeing a couple things here, but I don't actually know what to do right now.
Do I open a new project or or I don't know.
So, I'm just going to go to chatbt and ask it.
And this is like how anybody if you want to build anything and you just don't like know exactly where to start,
go to chatbt and just ask.
So, I'm about to create a project and I'm going to use Ruby on Rails because I know that and I know it'll be good for a little project like this.
I'm I'm going to create a project with Ruby on Rails, but I want to do it with cursor.
I don't have a repo or anything set up yet.
I downloaded cursor, but it's asking me to open a project.
So, what do I do next?
Okay, you're going to love cursor for RailsDev.
It's slick.
Step-by-step startup project in Rails new my project name.
Oh, and I'm going to stop it real quick and I say I want to deploy it.
Oh, before you keep going, I want to get it live on a real server so anybody can visit it and I want to do that right away right when I start it because I don't want to develop it locally.
This is like more just like software engineer perspective from what learning to code.
I want to get it deployed live first so I don't have to worry about the headache that that causes later.
Okay, create a Rails app.
Okay, we're going to start Rails new my app.
This is what we do.
So, I'm just going to copy this.
Well, I'm going to change it because I need to give it a name.
So, what do I do here in your terminal?
Okay.
So, I'm going to actually go into it's asking me to go into the terminal.
So, I'm going to pull up terminal and I'm going to do rails new.
Well, first I'm going to go to my code repository cdcode.
You don't have to do this, but I'm going to do it because it's just an organization thing in my computer.
And I'm going to do Rails new my app database Postgress SQL.
Let's do we're going to call it Rails new AI thumbnails maker.
Okay, I ran that and now it's running things.
And this is where everything usually goes wrong, but that's okay.
Seems to be working so far.
And then I'm going to CD into it, which is just basically going into that folder.
So I I called it CD AI thumbnails maker.
Yeah, I'm in there.
Okay.
Then it's saying to create a Git repository.
literally just copy and paste this stuff and it's not that important yet but we will learn about why this is important but you don't need to know it to you don't need to know how to code to do it okay it's done I just
copied and pasted it all okay in cursor click open project and select the folder my rails app okay let's do that I'm it's in my code folder and there it is right there so I'm going to open that and boom
we have a code repository this is look I think the lovable app is cool but I think that this is more of a better long-term solution Even if you don't know how to code,
I'm going to show you how to use this without knowing how to code.
It also doesn't charge you.
I think the pricing is probably better on this, too.
So, it's worth learning, I think.
Okay, now you're in business.
Cursor will index the Rails app and give you AI superpowers.
Nice.
Okay, let's set up the Heroku first.
Brew tap Heroku and brew install Heroku.
That's already done on my app, so you can do that, but I don't have to do that.
I'm already logged in.
So, now I'm just going to create my app.
I already use Heroku, so it's easy.
But I'm going to pull up the terminal here and I'm going to do Rails Heroku create AI thumbnails maker.
It seems to like the dashes so I'm going to stick with that.
Okay, that was easier than I thought.
Step four, prep prep for Heroku.
Add a proc file in the root of the app.
Okay, here's a good example of I would know how to do this because I know how to code,
but also I realize that someone watching this may like, okay, what does that actually mean?
Add a proc file.
Can you explain how to do this?
Rightclick the top level.
So, this is explaining.
I I know how to do this because these are like buzzwords.
But if you don't know, just chat gbt it.
In cursor, right click the top level folder of your app.
You should see folders like app and config.
Create a new file proc file.
Okay.
Inside the file, paste this line.
So, I'm going to copy this and I'm going to paste it.
Cool.
And I click save.
I'm just hitting save.
Cool.
I did that.
All right.
So, now let's go back to the step by step.
What I like about Chad GPT is it gives you this very very simple step by step in gem file.
Make sure you add this in production group gem file.
Okay, this is if I do command T in cursor, I can type gem file and I want to make sure that these gems are in there.
Again, if you don't understand what they're asking for here, then you can just go and ask Chat GBD what they're talking about and add ask for more info.
I think it's cool to ask Chat GBD about like why it's doing certain things and to explain them to you as who you are.
Maybe you're not a software engineer and even though it may take longer to do it, it's it will help you in the long run.
And that's that's the big pain with these AI tools is yeah, you can get started and you can create things easily,
but when you need to make changes, you could run into a bug that that's sends you down a rabbit hole of two weeks,
right?
If you do take things a little bit slower, which I'm going to again shill the AI build accelerator,
which is over the course of 12 days, you build an app and you take it maybe a little bit slower,
but you learn about important things like O databases.
This is what I think is going to change the world if people can approach AI tools like a little bit more like a software developer,
a little bit more thinking, setting things up for success.
So for example, we have the initial setup where for the whole day, but for that specific day,
you create a bunch of documentation about your product that about your project that allows you to more easily prompt the AI and have it do what you want.
If you don't do this, you might fail with building with AI tools as they exist right now.
This is just one of those things that has to be done right now to kind of maggyver these AI tools.
Anyways, so I'm going to make sure that this I guess this gem it wants.
So rails 12 factor.
Let me see.
I will just search this.
Is it here?
No, it's not.
So make sure you add them in the production group, the regular group.
So I'll just add it here.
Okay.
Then I do bundle install.
And look, man, if you learn this stuff, you can do anything.
It's pretty cool.
Okay.
Let's deploy deploy to Heroku.
What this basically means is we're going to take our Hello World app and just see if it actually works.
And then actually we didn't even start it.
So I'm going to I want to get it to work locally first.
So I'm actually going to ask it before we deploy to Heroku.
I want to get this working locally.
And I'll explain this too.
Okay.
So it's saying in your app folder run bundle install.
We just ran that.
So we need to do db setup.
What that's doing is setting up the database.
Every app needs a database basically.
So we're going to run this and see what happens.
Okay.
It looks like it wants us to do a bin DB migrate.
So we're going to do that too.
And that worked, I think.
Cool.
Okay.
Now, let's start the server.
Do bin rails server.
Let's see if it works.
And that says it's working.
And basically, if you just read, sometimes it's just important to just read things like you can,
what I like to do, too, is just let's paste this into chat GBT.
This is I started the server and this is what it said.
Like I don't really know what this is telling me, but I can ask that means that everything is working.
Yes.
And your app is running locally at localhost 3000.
Oh, hopefully this isn't your first time hearing about what local host is.
But this is basically a way to test your app that your app actually works locally.
This is not on a server.
This is on your computer.
So you can test, you can make a change on your computer and then you ship it up to production,
which is cool.
So that's working.
Okay.
But I guess what I want to first do is go back to our plan.
Uh I want to deploy it to Heroku before I even make any changes to it.
This is cool.
This is working.
I want to get it live on a a real server.
So, let's try it.
I'm going to do j get checkout b main.
And hopefully I'll run into some issues, but everything seems to be good here.
So, I'm going to split this terminal and have a separate one here.
Okay.
Branch name main already exists.
So, here we go.
This is a I don't know.
Actually, I don't even know what this is.
I'm just going to I'm going to say I'm trying to do step five deploy to Heroku.
And this is the error I get.
Oh, no worries.
That means you're just already on a main branch and you created it before.
So, step one, switch to the existing main branch.
So, I'll say get checkout main.
Okay, cool.
I'm already on main.
I'm going to say get push Heroku main.
Okay, let's try it.
Oh [ __ ] it's working.
No way.
Okay, so what it's doing right now is it's deploying to the server and it takes a minute again.
I'm just watching it here, hanging out, and it's saying 44 not found.
So, that's interesting.
The page you're looking for does not exist.
Seems like something's working, but I'm getting a 44 not found.
So, I'm going to ask chat GBT about that.
I'm going to say, okay, I deployed to Heroku and it was successful.
But live, I'm now getting this error.
And actually, I'm going to switch it up too because one thing that I wanted to do that I forgot to do because I just don't even have that.
But I want to actually have cursor do this for us.
So, I'm going to actually do command L.
And I totally forgot about this, but cursor has this agent feature.
So I'm going to actually ask cursor about it.
So I'm going to say so I deployed this to Heroku and it was successful but on the server it gives me this message and I'm going to ask it to
do it as an agent and that means I think it just does it for you which isn't always the best thing to do but let's try it.
This is so it's kind of letting me know this is a common error and this is actually just a little better because you don't even have to go to chatb anymore.
You don't have to use Google to figure out the issues you can just ask cursor itself.
So, let's do that.
So, I think that's cool because I showed you guys, hey, you can do this in chat GBT,
but you can also do this in cursor.
So, you actually don't even need cursor if you don't want to pay for it, but I I recommend using it.
So, it's telling me my what I'm doing wrong.
Let me check your proc file.
Okay, let me also check your routes config.
I can see a few potential issues.
It's saying that I don't have a controller.
And look, I'm not even like really reading all this right now, which is maybe for better or worse a good thing.
But it's still telling me stuff and I'm waiting.
So it looks like what it did is it's creating controller.
It's drawing new routes and it's doing all the things that I would do that I had to spend years learning as a software engineer and it's doing it.
And now it's also going to actually push it to Heroku.
You guys, if you're doing this, hopefully you're doing this alongside with me or at least trying it out.
This is crazy.
It's going to run all this and I just say accept all.
Would you like me to help you run any of these commands or yes?
I say yes.
make the file changes and run the commands.
Let's see if it can do it.
Let's commit and push the changes.
Okay, so it wants me to actually run them.
Get add.
Okay, it wants me Oh, it's doing a commit for me.
That's pretty cool.
Run command.
Wow, it made all the changes and it's actually just committing it up and making the changes.
So, in simple terms, I told it a problem that I had.
It made the changes and it deployed the app automatically.
I just had to click okay, okay, okay, and it did it.
This is really like the beginning of AI agents.
It's really not truly there yet.
It could make a mistake and like there's more things that need to happen.
But this is truly crazy.
Let's see if it actually worked because basically I told it, hey, what I'm seeing here in the in the app is a 404 not found.
I want to see like something that I can change and modify.
So, let's see.
Now, let's restart your dynino to make sure.
Oh, okay.
It wants me to restart it.
So, let's hit that.
And it says it's done.
Okay.
So, let's let's test it out.
There it is.
Welcome to AI Thumbnails Maker.
I didn't tell it to write that.
I just told it to get something on the screen.
So, I mean, just to show you, let's try something again to say, okay, just just to do that again because I think it's just so cool.
Can you center This is just basic.
It's obviously not what we're going to do.
Can you center the text on the homepage and add a bunch of copy about why people should use my tool?
Let's try it.
Let's see what happens.
Sure, I'll update the homepage with center text and compelling copy about your thumbnail maker tool.
And just to show you there, I mean to show you that this is like real, we're going to go to I think it's home index.
Yeah, this one here.
This is the actual code that says, "Welcome to AI Thumbnails Maker.
Your application is now running successfully."
It's going to go make some changes.
Look, it already made all these changes.
Whoa.
My god, this is crazy.
It's making all these changes.
Let's see if it'll push it up live.
And guys, we're going to get into making the landing page and actually building the app,
too.
But if you set things up, right, then everything just becomes really easy, right?
So, wow, it's giving me all this here.
So, I'm just going to run this.
It's deploying it.
Okay.
If I reload my basic app here.
Oh my god.
This is what it's going to be.
It's not live yet.
This is localhost 3000, but that's not bad.
I It's not great, but we're going to make it look way better here.
And I hit nothing happens when you hit get started now.
And now we're deploying this.
It's It takes a few seconds to do it, but once it does, let's see if it's live and actually works.
Okay.
I didn't have to hit accept all, but okay.
Let's reload.
Let's see if it got it.
Boom.
There it is.
This is live.
This is crazy.
Okay, let's go back to our our our plan because we need to actually build this thing.
So, let me go back to my everything that I wanted to make sure that we do today, which is nailing the idea,
branding the problem it solves, and creating the Hello World app with cursor, Rails,
and Heroku.
Those are the main things I wanted to do today.
And I wanted to do it quickly to show you how fast we could do this.
Obviously, I could have done it faster if I wasn't explaining things.
And next time I do this, I could probably do it in 5 minutes.
This is the power of AI tools.
I'm going to stop here and we may put more into this video.
I may jump back in after I take my dog for a walk as he needs to go to the bathroom.
But the next thing we're going to do is we're going to actually add the basic feature.
We're just going to get it to work with a feature.
We're not going to have the domain set up.
We're not going to have the landing page too fancy or anything like that.
Just going to do the one feature.
That's what we're going to build next.
And then this should be done pretty fast.
I'm going to try to get cursor to do this, but I will save that for the next one.
And I hope you guys enjoyed this vibe coding until I make $100,000.
Let's see what happens once I actually build this.
Get it look good.
Get it work good.
Oh, that's not what I thought was going to happen.
Ash GBT, please help.
It worked.