Over the next decade, AI coding is going to change the world.
Eventually, in minutes, there will be AI agents that can build you anything you want,
and you won't even have to write a single line of code.
We're not exactly there yet, but we're pretty close.
And in this video, I'm going to try to prove that.
I'm Pat Walls, the founder of Starter Story, and I'm a traditional software engineer.
And I'm Lazar.
I'm not technical.
I've never written a line of code before, but over the past few months I've learned how to leverage the power of AI.
Lazar is a subscriber of Starter Story.
He has a day job working ops at a startup, but at night he's turned into a vibe coder,
and he's built over 50 different projects in the last 6 months, all with AI tools.
To give you a little context, I've spent over eight years, thousands of hours, written tens of thousands of lines of code,
and committed to my code pace over 7,000 times.
And Lazar is going to challenge that and try to clone my business in under 60 minutes using only AI tools.
So, Lazar, you think you can do it?
Yeah, I think so.
But before we get started, I do have to explain what Starter Story is.
It's a customuilt web application built on Rails that has these core features and elements.
The first one is the design.
It has its own custom design and its own look and feel of the site.
The second one is the actual case studies.
These are breakdowns of successful businesses, how they got started, how they came up with the idea and how they grew their businesses.
Then there's the ideas page that has all the resources, lists of business ideas, examples,
how-to validation, etc.
Then there's the academy which is our course where you can take action, submit milestones and build the business that changes your life.
Then there's the community.
We have a whole community of founders where you can sign up and go hang out with other people who want to do this crazy thing which is build an online business.
There's also authentication, the ability to sign up, log in, reset your password, etc.
So, for the purposes of this experiment, I want to see if you can replicate all of these features and let's see how far you can actually get.
Okay, I'll get my timer out and I've started it right here.
Let's get started.
What's your general plan?
The plan is start off with an idea.
I break it down into smaller pieces.
Based off of that, I will create some project documentation that I will be able to reference throughout the build.
I'm going to build out all the pages.
When I'm done with the UI and the user experience is satisfactory, we're going to replace the mock data with the real data connecting the database and building the authentication part.
And that way circle the whole the whole project and finish it up.
Cool.
Sounds like a plan.
Let's get into it.
All right.
I just go in to chat GPT.
go to explore GPTs right here and just type lovable base prompt and they will find it.
I usually what I would do is I would say I want to clone.
We're building the base prompt.
So now that we know what we want to clone, right?
That we've specified it a little bit.
Case studies, resources, community.
All I got to do is run this prompt.
And then it will ask me usually a few questions.
Why and what am I building?
My answer to is I want to prove path walls that I can clone his
website in under.
And as you can see, loves the energy.
We're kind of trying to do this real fast.
What parts are musthaves?
I will say all of the above.
As with any other idea, I want to know who am I building this for?
So, I always define the target audience, whether it's going to be web, mobile, and anything design related.
You mentioned design being the big thing of yours, right?
So, I like to replicate the design.
If I'm cloning it, let's clone it for real.
I'm going to go to starter story and I'm going to go to your homepage and I'm just going to take a quick screenshot of it,
right?
Just so that I have something that chat GPT can reference.
And then from there I will just go back and say I'm basically trying to feed it with enough context about what's your business about even though it obviously knows a little bit about
it.
And as you can see the base prompt itself when you're using AI should pretty much be tailored like this.
You want to have the basic concept of the project.
What are you building?
What is going to be the name of it?
Target audience.
What are the core features and pages?
Right.
So now that I got a base prompt, my next step is preparing the project documentation.
It's not just about, oh, I'm going to dump this in, do a single shot prompt, as you mentioned.
It's about structuring it properly.
And the way I structure it personally is I divide all the documentation and all the PRDs into four different documents.
And all I need is just this base prompt.
I literally just copy paste it in and it just basically tells me, okay, I'm going to build these docs for you.
Yeah.
So we got the master plan and then as I mentioned we got the implementation plan.
The big difference between these two is that master plan is like I'm building a house sort of but the implementation plan is like how am I building the house?
Then you have the third layer which is the design guidelines which is how am I going to paint my house and then the last bit is sort of like app flow kind of pages
roles like in this case of again construct of a house you have an engineer you have a foundation builder you have a landscaper you have like you have to assign different roles and make
sure that lovable understands all the concept and all the bits and pieces of the project.
We're just going to go to lovable.
So use it as my full stack tool to actually design the UI and the UX.
I will also use it because my database of choice is Superbase which natively integrates with lovable.
So that connection will be made super easily.
And again we have the base prompt.
So all I got to do is just put it inside of it.
Press enter.
It is starting to build the files.
As you can see it's following very closely the instructions we gave it.
We got the name correct.
Right.
It's founder library.
Real stories, real founders, real growth.
So it copied us and it gave you a new name.
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah.
100%.
So we love it.
These copycats are going to go crazy on me, man.
Case studies, founders, industries.
We got some case studies that are featured.
First step that I always do with every project, see that there's this little GitHub icon right there in the top right corner.
I transfer the project to GitHub.
I want to own the code so that I can manipulate with it so that I can play around with it,
right?
I just go in, click to add file, create a new file, right?
And then because I want my docs to live in a centralized folder, I usually go to the name of the file and I just go to docs and then I do the forward slash so that I can build it as
a folder, right?
And then I go back to GPT, right?
And then we, as we recall, I had a master plan built out first.
I just go in just copy all this and then I go inside here and then I just name it
um master plan MD.
Then I just click commit changes.
I'm uploading all of this stuff so that I can reference it along the build to make lovable follow the implementation plan.
It's like giving the project a brain.
Yeah.
Exactly.
And then I do that for all of the other files.
Now that we got everything created, I'm going to go ahead and move into my prompt library right now.
And then in my AI library, I got a bunch of stuff.
And one of the big things for me is having this first lovable prompt.
I do want to make sure that a lovable understands what it's supposed to do.
And I'm just going to click copy prompt.
And then I do really important thing here.
I switch from the default to chat mode.
And about 80% of the time I will spend time in chat mode, not the code mode because I want to talk to it.
I want it to understand what I want it to do.
Right?
And then I'll just paste my prompt which makes it read the docs and tells me if it understands the plan and gives me the the first phase of it.
Just tells me, okay, this is where we're going to start off doing things.
As you can see, it's reading my documents and then it's telling me that it has a clear understanding of what we're building right now.
We're building a founder library with real case studies, educational resources, and supportive community.
So, what I would do next, I want it to revise the road map according to the timeline.
So, you're telling it right now, hey, I don't have a whole lot of time, so you need to cut some stuff out.
Oh, yeah.
I'm The more context you give to these tools, the better.
All right.
Before we keep building, I wanted to share something.
These AI coding tools are really powerful, but we're still in the early days.
In a few minutes, you're going to see Lazar troubleshoot some pretty bad bugs and errors.
And this isn't the first time because I've seen tons of people quit or give up as soon as the vibe coding goes crazy or gets complex.
Look, learning these tools can feel overwhelming, especially if you don't have the right system or framework to follow to build.
That's where Starter Story Build comes in.
Starter Story Build is your roadmap for learning how to build with AI.
Our boot camps are designed to take you from zero to a real life production app in just 12 days using only AI coding tools.
We've had hundreds of people join, launch their first app, and every time I'm just blown away to see the type of stuff that people are building.
Here's what's even cooler.
The expert that will help you build along the way is this guy, Lazar.
Not only will you learn how to use AI coding to build, but you will also get the structure and accountability to take action,
get it done, and ship it.
So, if you've been sitting on the sidelines and wanting to build with AI, this is your chance.
Head to the first link in the description to check out Starter Story Build, I can't wait to see you in there.
Now, let's get back to the video.
So, as you can see, it's building a road map for me.
So what I would do next is I usually take this copy it and then basically say okay let's
proceed with and then I just paste it and I just say break it down into small
steps and wait for it by just because lovable tells you it's going to do something doesn't mean that it's But I always love to do this type of
stuff where I'm like, break it down.
Let me read what you're how are you going to make a case study.
Oh, okay.
So, this is the page you're going to build.
It's case study detail, right?
Detailed founder section, key metrics, QA, related case studies.
Okay, I like that.
Then I copy it into the chat.
What I'm going to do here, I'm going to switch over from chat to default.
Very important.
Otherwise, it's not going to write code.
I would just go and and say proceed.
So, you had a little meeting with it, add it with it, and then Okay, time to get started.
And that's all I do.
We got a a bug.
Usually, when I see it, I always try to do try to fix it on your own cuz it reads the code base.
It knows what it's doing.
Now, there are situations where AI can mess it up to a place of where you're going into this whole loop.
And in those cases, what I like to do is I'd like to go to another GPT that I built,
which is specifically designed for debugging purposes with Lovable.
And I can show you that real quick while we're fixing this.
I just take this, I go to Chad GPT, and I'll go to my debugging prompt wizard.
I don't even say anything.
I just dump the the error code, read it, right?
and it's searching its knowledge and based on the knowledge builds everything up tells me what the cause is,
how to fix it.
Why do you think this will work?
And a lot of times it will admit that it doesn't.
Right?
And it's like, oh, now you got me thinking.
And as you can see, it gave me a full prompt.
You take this, you copy it into the chat, you paste it inside, and then try to get it to work.
But it's obviously not.
Sometimes no matter what you do, it just don't want to debug itself.
A good hack to get lovable into shifting gears a little bit is this suggestion to refactor.
We will likely see the error code again.
However, it will be in a smaller file.
It's a syntax error.
All I got to do is flip a small switch, find the file.
It's line 64.
So, all I got to do is instead of what's I'm going to say what is.
And then all you got to do is refresh the sandbox.
And if that error was fixed, it will work.
Yep.
Yes.
Oh, nice.
So, we're working on case studies, right?
That was our first thing that you wanted me to replicate, right?
So, as you can see, I got about nine of them in here.
Um, and as you can see, we got the founder, the metrics, the location, the related case studies.
This is very close with the metrics on the right.
Yep.
And that looks really good.
Yeah.
One issue there is that I know we told it to do case studies.
We told to do ideas academy and community, right?
Academy community.
But there has something there called founders.
I don't think we told to do that, right?
No.
No, we didn't.
But with tools like these, fixing those mistakes is super easy.
There's a couple ways that you can do it.
Again, we switch over to the chat mode, right?
We want to talk and be like, "Hey, why did you build the founders page?
Go back and read the master plan."
Right.
Yeah.
That's why we have those docs uploaded.
So, you're yelling at your programmers right now.
Yeah.
I'm basically going like, "Hey, man.
You've done something that I never asked you to.
Can you go ahead and please reread what we talked about?
Please read the docs.
And correct your behavior, your plan.
Okay, I just said read the docs.
It knows what docs, right?
It's again reading my stuff and again it confirms that I'm absolutely right and apologizes.
So, we'll forgive it.
I think we got to be forgiven.
So again, phase one, phase two, academy, guides, videos, courses, founders page d.
Okay, I want you I want AI to revise the plan, create a page for ideas, but I wanted to follow an example.
We can go starterstory.com and then go slash ideas and make a screenshot real quick and just say it can do this to
categorize them, right?
And then I will go to another website.
Just any website you want, but I've used idea picker in the past.
And I just like how it's outlined.
And I'm just going to take a quick screenshot of it.
Upload as many screenshots as you want.
And then I also want when I click on an idea, I want to be able to see it broken down and validate it almost,
right?
like what's the target market, what's the revenue potential, all the all that jazz, right?
I really want to make sure that a reader of my website gets the benefit of really understanding what the ideas are about.
And I can even go further and say image number one represents the main category page,
image number two will represent the ideas within a category.
And image number three is an idea broken down.
And then it knows, oh, okay, I got everything that I need, right?
Okay, I got to switch back to default mode.
So now it's coding the ideas page, as you can see, not the founders, right?
It's it's making that change right now as we speak.
And now when we go to the new ideas page, we can see the library, right?
We got the AI, business ideas, micro SASS, solarreneur, like let's go through AI and see,
okay, wow, we got an AI copy assistant, AI power tool, right?
Estimated revenue 32K.
Let's let's look at it, right?
Oh my gosh.
The pain point.
This is the idea source, right?
We can find who mentioned this uh being a problem.
What is the business plan?
Okay.
Uhhuh.
So, this is a tier subscription model.
It's going to take me three or four months to build.
And then later I can save it on the list of ideas that that I want to build.
So, we got the ideas page.
The next logical step would be the academy.
So what I would do is I want to say I want to reference the plans, reference the docs and be like okay I need the academy next what do you have in the plans about this page and as you can see it reads the
ideas page cuz it's just built it design guidelines app flow components nav everything now academy as a concept is very unique like you've built something
that I don't know that that many people built so far so I don't expect it to know exactly how it's supposed to do it so what I would do is I would feed AI AI with what the academy should look like.
So, we can go again to Starter Story Academy and I'm just going to take a quick screenshot of it.
This academy feature Yeah, this product took hundreds if not a thousand hours to build.
So, I'm curious to see if you can actually replicate this.
I I just feed it with uh screenshots, right?
And then I'll just gave it screenshots and a task to really try and replicate this, right?
Adjust the plan that it gave me cuz it has a really good plan.
has a solid plan was to have resources mock academy like it it really has a structure that it it made up.
Well, I mean, okay, I love it.
Let's adjust it a little bit.
Let's tweak it a notch.
Right.
I'll give you these screenshots.
You try to figure out how do we merge the best of both worlds.
Let's see what it did.
Okay.
So, you said you spent That's real.
Yes.
You said you spent hundreds of hours or whatever.
We just I spent so much time on this, you wouldn't believe it.
And now we just got to connect it all together.
And the best way to connect everything together is by building a community page.
Let's say, can you I love to the fact that we're cloning things, but I also want to add a personal touch to it,
right?
I don't want to be a copycat, right?
So, like when we do the community page, I'm going to show you something.
I got a trick up on above my sleeve, even though my sleeves are a bit shorter today.
And yeah, as you can see, we built the community page, right?
Wow.
What the members say, join the Slack community.
But I want a unique twist, right?
Right.
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to take this, right?
I'm just going to copy this headline.
I'm going to head over to the this cool website called 21st Dev, right?
21st Dev is one of the most popular libraries today.
So, in my case, cuz it's your communities all over the world, right?
The word that comes to mind is global, right?
So, let's see what we have on that end.
Like when I search global, right?
I got a globe here, right?
So, we're going to take the globe.
Oh my gosh.
And I'm just going to click copy prompt, but I'm going to say change the headline.
Join our community of founders.
Right.
I'm just going to click copy prom.
Oh, it's going to go here.
And all I got to do is just paste this in.
And we're going to have our globe.
We can see that the element that we wanted to build.
So the globe is inside there.
Now I just took that looks so good.
Yeah, I took the globe.
You can do anything really.
There's a bunch of libraries there.
There's a bunch of stuff that you can do, right?
This kind of puts us where we want to be, right?
We set the foundation, right?
We got all the pages up that we talked about.
We got the ideas, the academy, we got the case studies individually.
This is cool.
You did a bunch of HTML and CSS, but what about the back end?
What about working with APIs?
Can you show me what you could put together?
Yeah.
Uh, in terms of that, well, to think of it, I do have an idea of what we can do right now.
Right.
You know, as you said, we're going to have to store these case studies somewhere, right?
And in the beginning, we talked about Superase.
We mentioned it as a native integration with Lovable, right?
Right.
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to use the back end to actually take Open AI's API and build an AI assistant,
for example, that's going to take one of the ideas and tell me how to build an actual startup.
That's funny cuz that's actually a feature that has been requested for a long time.
So, I want to see you do it.
I actually had time to build it.
So, let's So, yeah.
What I'm going to just do is I'm going to like I'm going to go ahead and I have my own databases,
whatever.
And I'm going to create a project in Superbase with one of them.
All I got to do is go to Superbase.
The project's going to be founders, right?
And then I'm just going to put in any password, whatever.
And just going to go ahead and create the project.
It's going to take maybe a minute or or two, right, to do uh until that's done, you know,
like again creating an account in Super Base is like super simple.
So, all I got to do is go back to Lovable, see that the founders project is there and I just got to click connect over here and I just
connected the back end in two clicks.
Wow.
Yeah.
So, you you got a working database.
Yes.
Right.
Now that I got a database, I'm going to need an API key, right?
So, I'm going to go to my account again, platform.openai.com, and I'm just going to create a quick secret key for founders.
So, you're creating an API key so you can communicate with chat GPT API.
Yes.
So that I can leverage it to build that assistant, right?
Okay.
So, not only are you building with the AI, you're building something that has an AI feature.
Yeah.
Okay.
Wow.
Now, let's build.
This is a new part of the plan because it's new.
It's it hasn't been broken down into chunks.
Lovable has no context of it.
I just want to make sure that it knows number one what I'm building, what is the function,
when does it trigger, and how it should do it.
And now AI should in its right mind say, "Okay, give me the API key.
I need it to build the edge function."
There it is.
Right.
And then I just paste it.
All right.
So we built the edge function as you can see lovable gives you the prompt to take you right then and there.
So it has this ability of like taking you to check the edge function logs right if you click to edge functions it created it and if you go to secrets it
actually stores your open AI key in a hidden way right so like we didn't do any coding and this is already in the back end right at all.
So, let let's see if it if it's running properly.
We're going to go to the homepage because that's where we told we want it to be triggered.
As we reach the footer, right, it didn't trigger yet.
So, maybe there's a there's a few kinks here and there, but that's all right.
That's This is the assistant.
So, let's say I want to clone starter.
And just to let the audience know, he coded this.
This isn't like a lovable feature or something like that.
You created a chatbot.
Yep.
which I don't we don't even have after thousands of lines of code and thousands of hours.
We don't have a chatbot.
It's working and it gave me a full business plan, SWAT analysis, analyze competitors,
monetization, what's the market size, what's the proposed solution, what's the solution fit.
Now, the last bits and pieces left for us to do really like how do we get the memberships done and how do we get to that part of like getting some people to actually uh sign up.
So right now we're all I'm going to finish it off with is say build a memberships page.
So we're going to just go again to starter story, right?
Really and I'm just going to again I just like your designs a lot.
So I'm just going to rip you off completely here and I'm just going to take everything the way it is and ask Lovable to follow the screenshots but also
follow the design guidelines cuz again it's a little bit different, right?
There's a unique twist to my page, right?
And I'm just going to ask it to build that memberships page.
Wow.
So, it did this.
Yeah.
We got the membership page, your prices, everything.
We're pretty much there.
I think this is as as much as it can be built within such a short time frame.
Great job.
By the way, uh we didn't exactly hit in under 1 hour, but most time we were just waiting for the AI tools to finish.
But this is amazing.
I mean, these are features those were built over the course of years.
And I know for people watching this, you know that this isn't going to instantly be a million-dollar business,
but I do love the idea of getting inspired by other businesses and essentially kind of copying another business that can help you get started with yours.
Cuz I think when I started my business, it was really just a copy of another business.
I put my twist on it, you know, and built it and got eyeballs and trust like you said.
But what are some of the important things to think about when you do start VI coding?
When I post my projects, people are like, "Oh, you should learn how to code."
The way I think of it, if we're talking about it from of a perspective, where is this headed to?
By the time I become a mediocre code writer, AI will be so much better than what I am.
So, if anybody watching this is like, "Oh man, I should learn how to code."
I think you should learn how to vibe code, like, which is like learn how to use these tools cuz they're faster at coding.
They're better.
Yes, they're not there yet today.
Yeah.
But like six months, a year from now, they will be ahead of any competitive or non-competitive coder that ever worked in this particular
industry.
Learn how to use these tools.
You know, build a lovable create your lovable account.
Learn how to prompt really is what I'm trying to say here.
Cuz you got to learn how to talk to it.
You got to learn how it communicates.
Um and that is probably the first step for anybody watching this.
Yeah, and that's why you should definitely check out the AI accelerator led by Lazar here.
In about 2 weeks, without knowing how to code, you ideate, build, and launch a reall life production app using only AI tools.
We've been running this program for a while.
We've seen a ton of great results.
People shipping stuff really fast and I'm just blown away with what's possible.
Today's session is proof of that.
And you also get to walk away with skills that I think will change your life.
These are the skills of the future.
And what's also cool is we also have office hours.
So weekly Lazar gets on, I get on, and we answer your questions.
We help you get over obstacles and roadblocks to help you actually ship that idea.
So if you're curious about building an app like Lazar, an app like this, or even potentially more complicated stuff,
please check out the AI app accelerator.
You can find the link in the description.
I think it's worth checking out.
Thank you, Lazar, for coming over.
Thanks for having me.
And uh we're going to have to do this again, but even faster.
Oh, 100%.
We're going to have to take it up a notch next time.
I look forward to it.
Cool, man.