If you're new here, I am setting off to do the 100K build challenge.
Challenge, make $100,000 with only AI tools and document the entire process.
Rule one, document everything here in this channel.
Rule two, I can only use AI tools.
And rule three, I cannot stop until I make 100K.
Here's how far along I am in the process.
And this is day two.
Okay, now that I got all that out of the way, guys, holy smokes.
63,000 of you watched the day 1 video.
I am blown away.
I did not expect this at all.
And if I'm being completely honest, I'm nervous.
I'm excited, but I'm mostly scared because I'm not really sure if I'm going to be able to pull this off.
Making 100k is not going to be easy.
That's the point.
And that's what I really, really want to share in this series.
that your first idea is not going to be your best, but it's better than no idea because you get to fail.
And what you learn from those failures is what you then turn into the $100,000 idea.
And that's what I want to show off in this series.
What it actually takes to make a h 100red grand and how many different pivots and changes of direction I'm going to have to go through to get there.
I want to document all of that.
And that's what brings me to my bigger realization is that this challenge is way more than just me or this channel.
I want to get you, yes you, involved in the 100K build challenge.
I want to see you do it.
I want to create a movement and I want to see a lot of people watching this video also give it a shot.
In this video, somewhere in this video, you will find what I call a Bernie break.
It's basically an intermission where I take my dog Bernie for a walk and share a little bit more about how you can get involved if you want to do this,
too.
So, make sure to watch that part if you're curious.
All right, this is episode two.
I think you're going to like it.
I don't really know what's going to happen next, but let's get into it.
Let's go.
Okay, guys, let's get into it.
So, as a reminder of where what we've done so far, we came up with the idea.
We created our codebase and we bought our domain name and we got everything set up on our local server and then also we pushed it up to production so that we
have it running on our real life server.
That's what we did last time.
Let's talk about what we're going to get into today.
So today I really want to focus all on design.
Really how to make the thing look good and how to not spend too much time on this.
How to do it quickly because probably if you're watching this you're not an expert designer.
I'm not an expert designer, but I've learned a lot through my years of working on different projects.
And I want to show you how I would approach design and how you can do this in like, you know,
20 30 minutes, which is going to be the length of this episode.
Okay.
So, in today's episode, we're going to be going over design principles and how if you set these up,
it can make your life 10 to 100 times easier.
Number two, we're going to talk about design stealing.
We're going to go and hopefully steal a design from an existing proven product and copy that over to our idea so we don't have to spend a whole lot of time coming up with a brand new design.
Number three, we're going to talk about refactoring components so that your project doesn't become a complete mess.
And lastly, we're going to get into the weeds.
We're going to do some debugging when cursor starts really screwing up.
I have this way of approaching it, which is getting a second opinion.
And I'm going to show you that in real time.
So, and finally, before we get into it, shameless plug, check out the AI build accelerator if you want to do something similar.
I'll put the link in the description right now.
All right, let's get building.
Let's go.
We went over the idea on one pager.
So, I'll pull that up here.
But we have our Yeah, our one pager, which is just not even one page, it's half of a page,
which went over exactly what our thing's going to do, the problem it solves, why should I be building this,
is my edge, and then the scope of what we're going to build in the first one.
We gave ourselves a deadline to launch this in 4 hours.
We about 30 minutes into it right now maybe.
And we got a name and we got a domain name, right?
I got to add that.
We got the domain name, too.
So, we started with our idea on one pager.
That's done.
Then we did the basic setup.
I got everything set up in Rails cursor.
I show you guys the exact step by step to do that and how to prompt to figure that stuff out.
If you're getting stuck, we bought the domain name a thumbnailsmaker.com and we got it live locally.
This is our local version right here.
This is all prompted.
It's not very good right now, but we're going to get there.
We got it live on Heroku.
What are we going to do today?
That that's that's all day one stuff.
I like to use this little Apple note.
There's no, you know, complex productivity system here.
So, I think what we should do today is for this session, and I'm breaking this up into little sessions,
is let's get it to look good, get it work good.
So, I'm not going to talk about anything like that.
Let's just get it look good.
Get it work good.
and we already know what we want to build.
I'm going to prompt J chat GBT to show you what I would do if I was building, but I also want to confirm that.
So, I'm building a small micro SAS micro project that does one thing.
I don't want to spend a bunch of time on the design.
I don't think it matters.
I'm using Rails.
What's a good framework for design?
Okay, cool.
So, Tailwind CSS.
I was kind of expecting it to give me that, but I wanted to check and I wanted to also share one thing that I think is really helpful when building apps and maybe something that you wouldn't necessarily know if you're
just starting out is design is a problem that's generally been solved unless you have this crazy design first app.
You should always I think you should use a framework like Tailwind to make your app just look good without having to do a whole lot of work.
Or I can just search Tailwind.
Basically what it does Yeah.
If you go to this here, it gives you like pre-built components.
So like here's a pricing section built with Tailwind.
Like that's pretty nice, right?
Like that you can do this by just basically copy and pasting this code.
You can copy this code and you can paste it into cursor to build what you want to build.
So I think we should use that.
I want to do something a little bit different than what you might see so that we can save us some time here.
So basically I'm going to go to chat GBT.
I'm going to say, "Hey, I'm building an app."
And well, let's just actually go back to our original one.
Okay, cool.
I want to add a design guidelines prompt to add to my readme file that the AI
cursor can use before making changes to the app.
Okay.
Yeah, that's what I want to do.
I'm going to say do it in markdown and I'll explain what I'm doing here.
The guidelines should be use Tailwind.
Don't do anything crazy out of the box.
As far as colors, use this color palette.
Okay, now I'm going to go look up color palettes.
Basically, I want my thing to look like somewhat good.
Pools.
Let's see this.
I can go in here and pull out some color pal.
Let's start the generator.
What do we like?
Okay, I'm going to get a seizure looking at this.
This is pretty cool.
How do we go to the next one?
Oh, here we go.
What do I want to do with I have an AI thumbnails generator.
What do I think is a cool color scheme?
I'd say maybe YouTube colors.
I want that YouTube red.
So, maybe I can How do I give it YouTube red?
I want to give it a specific color.
Generate color palette from photo.
That's cool.
Let's try that.
So, let's go to YouTube.
I don't want to I just want to go to the one.
So, let's take these color.
I mean, it's really just the red, right?
So, let's take that and we're going to upload that to cools.
Man, what about the red though?
Oh, yeah.
Then you can go in here.
Cool.
Let's try that.
I don't know if this is going to work, but open in the generator.
Cool.
So, this is the colors that I'd like to try.
I'm going to copy these.
How do I copy these?
Just want to copy ffo.
I guess we'll just write them down here.
FF32.
FFA.
That's really it.
Not very good looking, but I like the red.
So, let's go and add that to our chat GBT.
Okay.
Let's see what it gives us.
Let's try this.
I actually have never done this before, but I know it's good to like give it some guidelines.
Okay, and then it's saying what the primary ones, etc.
So, let's copy this.
And then I'm going to go to my agent and say, "Hey, first I'm going to accept the file changes.
I'm going to say, hey, can you add this to my markdown to my readme
file?
And then I'm going to just do something.
I'm going to look up something in cursor like how can I get cursor to reference that anytime they design something.
Cursor question.
I have some design guidelines in the readme MD file of my project.
How can I get cursor to reference this when it's writing code every time?
Custom context.
Cursor lets you pin files as context.
This lets you tell AI to always consider those files when generating or editing code.
Open the readme file and cursor.
Click the pin icon in the top right of the file tab.
Okay, cool.
So, I'm going to accept those changes.
And there's a pin icon.
Is it top right of the file tab?
Pin.
Okay, that's it.
Now, anytime you ask the AI to help with code, automatically include the context of your readme in the prompt.
Okay.
And then I'm going to clean this up and take this out.
We don't care about this.
We want to make sure that we pin just that and accept all.
Okay, cool.
So hopefully that works.
All right, so now I'm going to go and try to make this look better that I also want to do like cuz right now the UI is really quite simple.
It's just AI thumbnails.
Very very basic thing.
Let me see if it's currently using Tailwind.
Uh yeah, it is using Tailwind, I think.
So cool.
It's already working.
Okay.
Yeah, bank statement converter.
This is the one.
This business makes $12,500 a month.
And I think their website was really simple in terms from a UI standpoint.
I don't want to reinvent the wheel on this.
I just want it to look and feel similar to this because I know that this makes money.
So, it's totally different.
It's a bank statement converter.
We're creating a YouTube thumbnails thing.
So, it's not like we're stealing.
But, here's a couple elements of this page I think are that we need to have that we don't have.
I'm going to zoom this all the way out to get the full thing.
I'm going to take a photo of it and I should be able to feed this into cursor and have it build it.
So, let's do it.
Okay, cool.
So, now it knows the guidelines and now I want to build this.
So, I'm going to command A on this whole thing.
So, this is the whole file, right?
This is just just so we're clear.
This is this is the uh the homepage.
So, if I do AI thumbnails maker, that's the name of our thing by starter story.
Let's just put that in there to show you that this is what we're editing.
This is the index which is the homepage.
So if I go back and I reload, this is AI thumbnails by starter story.
So I'm editing this page.
So I'm going to copy the whole thing.
I'm going to do command L and I'm going to turn into agent and I'm going to say, hey,
here is a photo of the user interface I want to replicate.
I'm going to upload that there.
Can you take the general structure of this and replicate it for our app?
Obviously, I'm just talking to like a human, right?
Obviously, our app is different.
It's a thumbnail maker, but this but I like the structure.
Okay.
Then I'm also going to say, please use placeholders for certain features.
E the actual thumbnail creator.
A placeholder is a I'll show you what I mean.
Hopefully, it can figure this out.
But a placeholder is a gray box with an X through it with the proper dimensions.
Okay, let's try that.
What I love about AI is that it's probably going to screw some things up, but you just keep yelling at it and it does it.
Okay, so look.
Oh man, it already referenced the design guidelines.
Thank you for using Tailwind, incorporating the same structural elements, but adapted for your use case.
And now it's making some changes to index.html.rb.
So, let's remind ourselves what we're doing.
We're in the get it look good.
So we did the design guidelines.
Now we're doing the UI structure.
I'm not an expert at this guys.
I just am just trying different things.
So this is just to prove that AI is so powerful right now.
And I think it's going to change the world especially when it comes to building software apps and yes it will,
you know, add a lot of competition.
Anybody can build apps now.
But actually, I think it will just make apps better and it'll be more niche use cases where now before you had to hire a developer to go and build something and it just wasn't like cost-effective because I this app isn't
going to, you know, I have to have a team of 10 developers working on this like niche app.
Now you don't need that.
So more things can be built, more useful things and that's why you see these, you know,
apps making millions of dollars that do very simple things right now.
It's possible to do that.
Okay, they're doing a lot here.
I don't really know exactly what they did, but they're telling me they created a header section.
Cool.
They did a main conversion area.
They did a feature section.
They added the pricing tiers and a need more section.
They didn't do a footer, but we'll see.
And we can ask it to do that.
So, I'm going to hit accept.
And I should see this reload.
And we're Oh my go way.
You're kidding me right now.
Okay.
They didn't get a header, but it looks pretty good, right?
It's got the same structure.
It's got the secure, professional, blah blah blah.
It came up with its own copy for Wow.
Click here to create your thumbnail.
Nothing happens.
Right?
So, now we got our basic structure.
I'm not building any of the features yet, but I want to build it so it looks like a legit website.
Right?
So, I'm going to get mad at it.
Not mad at it.
First, I'm going to say thank you.
Wow, that was pretty good.
But you forgot the header.
I mean, I'm I'm gonna look here and see if it did.
Can you add that?
But also, I want you to do something quick.
Separate the files.
You know, actually, I don't care about that.
That's like the engineer in me wanting to overengineer something.
So, I'm going to say no because I don't want to do that yet.
So, that was But you forgot the header.
Can you use a proven Tailwind header that looks professional?
And I say, "Oh, also add the footer as well."
So guys, in order to make this video fast, sometimes I'll probably skip through when it's generating because sometimes it takes some time,
but I'll go and, you know, go on Twitter while I'm waiting.
But this looks pretty good.
And let's see if we can get the header working and see what comes up.
Then we're going to get it work good and we're gonna work on building the feature.
So like working with the OpenAI API, we're going to do some cool stuff for sure.
But let's just get the header in there first while that loads.
I had a professional header with a navigation.
Okay, let's see what it looks like.
It still didn't do the footer.
Mr.
I told it to do it, but I guess I needed to.
Maybe it was still thinking.
Let's see.
Oh, it gave us a footer, too.
Header features logo with an app name using thumbnail icon navigation links, blah blah blah.
Okay, let's see what happens.
Did it do it?
We'll need to update some of these, but we're not going to have a login.
Well, we actually might need to do a login, right?
That's the thing is I probably won't do a login to just validate that this is something that actually works.
And we'll talk about that.
We'll get there when we get there.
And pricing obviously doesn't work.
So, you know, when you create something, it's like, okay, I see what this could look like.
I know I need to add those pages, but I'm not going to go and add the pricing page right now,
right?
I'm going to just build the thing.
I don't even know what my price is going to be.
I think I said it could be $5 a month, but we'll get there.
All right, it's time for a little Bernie break.
They needed a walk.
It's time for me to take a little break from the code.
So, while we're out here, I want to talk about something real quick, which is this challenge,
which I thought was just going to be me uh trying to build something to make $100,000 end up being way bigger.
I saw all your comments and how all you guys want to get in on the challenge and try to do it yourselves,
too.
So, I'd love for you guys to get involved and I got a couple ideas and a couple options if you want to get involved build something,
make 100K or just build to try for you guys to try to set the challenge for yourselves to make 100K using uh building with AI coding tools or if you just want to build with AI coding tools in general and learn this crazy skill
that I think is going to change the world.
I legitimately honestly think that these AI tools are the future, right?
This is just the very very beginning.
And it's part of the reason why I want to do the challenge because if I can learn these,
who knows what's going to be the next thing?
What's the next big thing?
And I can be on the cutting edge of those tools.
Bernie's leaving.
I'm I got to hold on to you here.
So So option one, I think if you're game, also do the challenge.
Set yourself this crazy goal of making $100,000 with AI coding tools.
Document your journey doing it.
Post on X, post on YouTube, and just try to do it with me.
It's okay if it doesn't work out.
It's okay if it takes a long time to get it done.
I love if you guys did it alongside me and uh we did it together.
You don't need my permission.
You can use my thumbnail style, which in the description right now, I will put downloads.
You can download this thumbnail style so you can do it as well.
We're going to create a movement on YouTube and all social media.
And I think it'll be really cool.
If you're doing this, please drop a comment below and I'll try to shout you out and potentially collaborate with you on videos,
talk about tools, projects, or we'll probably come up with something.
Option two is honestly a shameless plug, but it's for the AI Build Accelerator, which is a paid thing,
but I really, really think it's amazing.
If you want a little bit more structure and accountability on building with AI tools and learning these tools should definitely check out the AI build accelerator where you will learn how to use AI tools,
how to come up with an idea, launch a product and come out the other side with a real production product and the skills necessary to get there to build anything you want after that.
This is a part of Starter Story's bigger new project which is Starter Story Build where my goal is to create the best place to learn AI coding tools by building real projects.
So, I'm really really excited about that.
I'm going to put a link in the description down there.
You get a ton of stuff in there, but most importantly, accountability, structure to to take you all the way to the end to build something that you never thought could be possible to take that idea,
turn it into a real thing, and ship it.
Check that out as a link in the description and see if that's your vibe.
Or if you don't want to do that, that's fine, too.
Or you can do both.
You can come build with me in the accelerator and document your process along the way.
I'd love to see you in there.
Or if you're just here to hang out, watch and learn, and hang out with me and Bernie.
And uh hopefully we'll turn this Bernie break thing into an ongoing segment, then well,
enjoy.
Keep watching, subscribe, and let's get back to work.
All right, Bernie, you ready to go?
So, I feel like the UI structure is there, guys.
Look, it's not the most beautiful thing in the world, but that's not really what I care about.
I don't know what why we would have the English thing there, but the register thing could be cool,
too.
Let's get it work good.
Okay, so here's what we're going to do to get it work.
Well, what's the main thing?
I I wrote it down here in my scope is allows you to draw the thumbnail, upload some reference shots,
and write a prompt.
So, those are three things we're going to need to do.
So, draw, and this is just something I know because I know thumbnails is like, yeah,
you have to draw the thumbnail, but you also it's also going to need some reference shots of like what say you want to do a thumbnail of your face and you draw your face,
then it needs to know what your face actually looks like.
So, we're going to add the draw the thumbnail.
We're gonna add the reference shots and we're gonna add the writing of a prompt.
Okay.
So now what I want to do is I want to simplify out my code a little bit.
And this is something that more so I would know because I'm a software engineer.
But even if you don't know how to code, this is going to make sense.
So see this this file right here.
This is our whole file.
You guys know this because we can change AI thumbnail maker to be AI thumbnail maker and it will update that,
right?
So, we know that this is the whole thing, but this file is too long.
This file is confusing, right?
And I think for people that are coding with AI, it's like, damn, this is like a lot of this is scary,
right?
Because it's a lot of code.
Well, I'm going to actually tell the AI to fix this.
So, I'm going to do command L.
So, I I I'm going to highlight everything, do command L.
I'm going to say, "Hey, this file is getting too big, and I'm not a coder.
Can you please separate these out into different files so that it's easier for me to make
changes and wrap my head around all of this code?"
I'm going to say, "Feel free to please do this in the best way you think possible."
Let's see what happens if I do this.
I'm going to try it with agent.
I don't even know what that edit thing does.
I think that might be command K.
Maybe that's command L.
I don't know.
We'll see.
Okay.
I'll help you break this down into smaller, more manageable components using Rails partials.
Yep.
Okay.
If you don't know if you're not familiar with that, then first let's create a directory for our components.
Okay, cool.
So, basically what it's going to do is it's going to create a folder which will probably likely be an app.
It says it's an app views shared.
So, it's right there.
This is like shared components that you can use in different places.
So that's kind of nice because we may want to use that in on multiple pages.
So this is actually going to make our lives easier.
So you don't have to worry about too much what's going on here other than it's doing good work and that's going to take a minute.
So we'll let that load up and keep going.
And I want to make sure that this video doesn't get too long.
So let's see how far we get.
I do want to try to get the draw done and maybe the the first hookup to open AI, but it's okay if we don't because I want to keep these videos short and I also have to go
play tennis very soon.
So, but I want to make sure that I document everything on this from idea from zero to idea.
I'm making money with it.
Let's see.
Okay, so it is creating the header into a separate file called header.
And you can see that starting to get created.
And I hope this is helpful for you guys just to like kind of talk about what's actually happening here cuz it's actually pretty simple if you just follow along.
Then it's creating the hero.
So the hero is usually like this section.
I think that this is usually the hero.
Then it's separating the next part into I can be your hero, baby.
Okay.
And the features.
I think that's probably going to be these, even though they're not really features.
I guess they are.
And then there's the pricing and the contact.
So, basically, it's breaking this file into five files that are one after another.
That makes sense, right?
I think that's cool and that's smart.
So, I'm going to accept all those changes.
And let's hope it did it right.
Oh, now they're going to update the index file for Yeah, I noticed they didn't do that yet.
So, now the index file is going to be a lot simpler.
So, let's see what those Oh, wow.
Okay, cool.
So, see how much simpler this is?
Now, this is, you know, if you're not a software engineer, this is like hopefully I even though you potentially don't know how to code,
this makes sense and will help you when you use AI coding tools is like I don't know,
I think it might be called separation of concerns or something like that.
But, but now it feels a lot more approachable, right?
Oh, I want to go edit a feature.
I just go to that features one and I can go click it here and this is only 35 lines of code,
right, of HTML.
So, that is a lot nicer and now it feels a lot more approachable, right?
Hopefully that's helpful and you'll like that.
Maybe that's that one little thing that this video will give you and be helpful to you.
If you're a software engineer already, you probably are rolling your eyes right now.
But let's just reload and make sure it works.
It does.
Cool.
So, everything is the same.
We changed the code.
That's like called a refactor maybe.
I think that's hopefully useful because I think it's really important guys with when you're building with AI coding tools,
you are coding, right?
You can't just prompt forever and hope that things work.
You still have to somewhat start to understand the code.
And I guarantee you anybody who at least started with AI coding tools, who's making money and being able to ship features,
starting to use databases and these sorts of things, they've had to learn this, right?
And you can learn it all with AI.
You can ask it questions.
I could I could ask it a question and be like, "Hey, why did you do this?"
And probably give me an answer.
But we don't have time for that now.
Let's go and build the features.
Okay.
Let's draw the thumbnail.
That's the next thing I want is I want to add a thumbnail being drawn.
So, let's go to hero.
And this is our actual feature right here.
Okay.
So, now I'm now I only have 22 lines of code.
And if I say thumbnail creation area boss, just know that it should say boss, right?
Cool.
That is just, you know, showing how what we're editing right now.
We are editing everything from this point to this point.
So, let's go.
And what I wanted to do is I want to be able to draw what the thumbnail will become,
right?
Cuz that was the original idea was that uh here's with chat GBT.
This guy had to go and draw on a piece of paper.
I got to get a pen out.
I got to go write.
I want to be able to draw that right in the app.
That's why I think people could would potentially pay for this because they don't have time to take a draw,
take a photo, send the photo to their computer, and then make another change.
Like, that's really annoying.
This is something that I would actually use, right?
So, let's try it.
Cool.
How are we going to do this?
I don't know.
But let's see.
I'm going to ask chat GBT.
I'm going to say, hey, command L.
Okay.
So, I want to have a the section.
So, the section that we have in there is thumbnail creation area.
So, let's say that in the thumbnail creation area, I actually want that to be a drawing pad where you can draw somewhat similar to like whenever
you're I'm just going to try to give it as much details as
poss.
But let's just create the drawing tool.
Can you find a library online that is free and open-source and is the best option possible?
So, anybody who's a software engineer knows what this means, but a library is basically like I don't want to have to go write all this code myself.
I want to rely on a drawing pad library that developers have been working on for years that's works on all browsers and is super easy to implement
with one line of code.
So, I could go look that up myself, but I'm actually going to ask the AI to do it.
I'm going to say find it and implement it here.
This is a big moment.
If this works, I will eat my shoe because fabric.js because this I I don't even want to be a soft I feel bad for all software engineers if this works.
Okay, so this is what it did.
This imple implement implementation.
Okay, it did the canvas drawing area 600 by 300.
So, 600 width by 300 height.
It gave us a brush size slider slider and it says that it g there's a generate thumbnail button that saves the drawing.
No [ __ ] way.
Okay.
And this is how much code it was.
Not that much code.
Okay.
Let's see.
Oh my.
This is crazy.
Okay.
Doesn't actually work.
Oh my god.
But then I we lose it.
Okay.
That worked.
But when I start drawing, it doesn't stay.
All of the drawing disappears as soon as I click my mouse.
Okay, I'm going to do this as agent.
Okay, guys.
And I'm going to make sure that we don't go too over time on here.
So, probably got 5 to 10 more minutes and then I'm just worried that my screen recording software is going to bug out like it always is.
So, this is as far as we're going to get today.
Let's try to get it to the saved point, though.
I think that would be cool.
implement canvas with specific dimensions.
Okay, let me help you fix that issue.
The problem might be related to how the canvas is being initialized.
Let's modify the code to ensure my drawings persist.
I've made several improvements to fix the drawing persistence.
Okay, so it's a persistence issue.
Persistence just means like if you does it stay after you leave the page or can't can it be saved?
Persistence means just it's saved somewhere.
Okay, let's accept this.
I don't know.
I don't even want to read this whole thing because I just don't sometimes the AI bugs out like this and you got to go into debug mode.
So, this is a good example of like, okay, it doesn't work.
Let's figure out why it doesn't work.
And this is like what programmers do.
So, I don't know if it actually changed anything.
So, let's try it.
I don't know if it did.
No, it did not fix it.
Okay, now it's being weird.
So, I'm going to highlight it all and do command L.
That didn't fix it.
Did you actually make the change?
Can you make it if not because I don't think I made the change.
Okay, it's saying it made the change, but I don't see it.
So, it says edited 10 file.
No, this is all so far.
It's not making the change.
Okay, here we go.
Oh, there we go.
Let's accept that.
So, this is still not working.
Can you help me debug
this?
And then while I'm doing this, I might go into chat GBT because now I'm worried you can draw.
But the drawing immediately disappears when I uncclick my mouse.
Here is the code.
Please help.
And if you This is cool.
By the way, guys, I shared earlier.
Sorry, I'm go back.
The AI builder Lazar leads this whole thing.
He taught me this.
Ask CatchBT to give you a prompt to give to cursor.
Please help.
And if you please help and give me a prompt for cursor to fix it.
So, I'm I'm what they call Oh.
Oh, let's retry that.
And this is maybe what you call a second opinion, an AI second opinion, where I'm going to another doctor and I'm saying,
"What is the what is the issue?
Doctor, tell me and please help."
There we go.
Yes.
Well, we didn't need chat, GBT.
And this is clearly working.
Oh my gosh.
This is too cool.
Okay, we cleared the canvas.
This is too [ __ ] cool, guys.
Okay, cool.
Now, I'm going to do one more thing before I end the stream here because we're getting closer,
but I don't have enough time to build all this yet.
We're going to build this, but again, my goal is to build this in 4 hours.
We're going to do it over 4 hours.
I promise you, but I didn't get a whole lot of sleep last night, so I'm a little tired.
And I want to get it to a point where I feel excited about Okay, this is another little hack,
by the way.
That's not the great advice, but what I like is like I want to get it to a point where I'm excited about the next step and then I stop.
I go do other things.
So, I'm excited to get back and work on it again.
So, for me, I'm excited here, but I wanted to do one more thing that's really going to prove that this is going to work.
I want when I click this for it to just simply download the photo, not the thumbnail,
to my to my computer so that I know I can in the future when we when we do the next video,
I can send that to chat GPT because that will tell me, okay, now all I need to do is hit the chat GBT API and we're going to get a lot closer.
So, this is what I'm going to do here.
I'm going to prompt it to help me with this.
I'm going to say,"Wow, that worked.
I want you to download the image to my computer."
When I click the button generate thumbnail.
Okay, that should be enough.
I'm going to say as PNG.
And then the last thing we'll do after this is we're going to deploy this up to, but let's let's do this first.
Okay, here's a download link.
This seems I've updated the code to create a temporary download link element.
Set the download file name to thumbnail.png.
Set the link.
Okay, cool.
I'm going to Let's just see if it works.
And you guys know I'm gonna be drawn a on this, right?
Okay.
I might get banned from YouTube, but let's try it.
It worked.
Yeah.
Okay.
The last thing I'm going to do before we go to the next video is I'm going to I want to deploy this up to my server.
So, here's the difference.
Right now I'm on my local server here, but if I reload my Heroku server, which is eventually going to be a thumbnailsmaker.com,
we in the next video, we'll set up our domain.
So, let me let me do that.
Set Let me put a note in here.
Set up our domain.
Okay, I want to deploy this up.
So, I I honestly forget how to do this.
I'm just going to ask cursor.
Wow, that worked.
And I want to test it that it works.
This is another thing is like you should always be testing that it's working and remotely so you don't get solve those issues before they come become a real problem.
Well, that worked.
Deploy this.
Can you commit this up and deploy to Heroku?
Oh, and the other thing that I want to make sure that we do is just make sure that this is in GitHub.
I'm going to tell you why that's important.
I'm just letting it run.
This is not the right thing to do when you have a real serious app.
Just letting thing letting it do these things.
But right now, this is fun and nobody knows about this app yet.
Okay.
And guys, in a future video, cuz once you guys know this website, you're going to be able to go to it.
We're going to be talking about security, too.
So, that's really important.
I think with AI tools vibe coding, you have to be very careful about security.
This fine right now cuz this is just a fun app and nothing is going to happen.
But the moment I put my API key in there, my open API key, that costs money, right?
So, I need to be very careful with people abusing it.
And we're going to talk all about that.
That's another reason you should join the AI build accelerator because we talk about security.
We talk about those things and making sure that you have a basic audit going on before you get potentially a $5,000 bill from OpenAI,
right?
Okay, that says it worked.
So, let's see.
No, that didn't work.
So, what I think happened here is if I go back, I look at it committed one file, but it should commit all files.
Please commit all changes and deploy.
It wants me to run this.
Okay, now now we run it.
That should work now.
Let's hope.
And what's cool is while that's going, I think, is see this right here?
This is that whole signature pad thing is just one line of code.
We had to do some more code to customize it, but you can go click this.
Here's a little kind of cool thing if if you're nerdy about the the stuff.
Go and tag that in there.
And you can see this is all JavaScript here that is running that code thing or that signature thing.
So that's a cool little thing there.
Okay, let's see if this works.
There it is.
Okay, we got that.
Okay, sorry.
Just a reminder, this is locally now.
This is live on a thumbnailmaker.h herokuapp.com and we can do our little smiley face here.
I got some teeth going and generate the thumbnail.
And it worked.
There we go.
Okay guys, that's it for today.
What we're going to be covering in the next video is we're going to get it work good.
And I kind of knew going into it that we probably were going to get every feature and that's okay,
right?
There's a million features we could do.
We don't want to do all them.
We want to just get the basics working.
We still don't have this, but basically like the only thing that needs to change now is we need to send this to OpenAI's chat GBT model and potentially some other data too and then wait for
its response for the thumbnail.
I'll see you guys in the next one.
This is Vive Coding until I make 100 grand.
I screwed up big time.
I decided to start building without knowing if it was possible to actually build this thing.