Just about a year ago, Nathan Cvy decided to go from non-technical to [music] technical.
He started learning AI and used it to build and ship his ideas.
And within one year, without knowing anything about how to code, he launched a few different apps and even made a few thousand bucks in revenue.
So, I wanted to invite Nathan onto the channel to do a deep dive into his exact [music] tech stack as a non-developer.
What's even cooler about this video is that he's tested over 200 different tools.
And in this video, he shared with me the only tools [music] that actually matter when it comes to shipping.
So, if you're trying to find out the right tools to use from people that are actually building products,
then you need to watch this episode.
All right, let's get into it.
Welcome to Starter Story.
This is the full stack.
All right, real quick before we dive in, Nathan is going to walk you through the exact tech stack for building mobile apps in 2026.
And if you're watching this right now thinking, I want to build my own app.
Well, we put together a resource that will take you from idea to a real working app in the app store.
The link is right down there in the description, but more on that later.
Let's get into the video.
Nathan, amazing to have you on the channel.
I'm stoked to chat with you.
I've been following you on X for a little bit.
You've been building some really cool stuff.
We're going to talk all about your stack and all the AI tools you're using.
But first, before we do, show me some of the stuff you've built.
>> Yeah, this is EB.
This is actually the first app I ever built with a friend and it helps you focus on Mac.
So, it blocks distracting websites.
The next app I actually built was Harmony.
Harmony is an AI planning and goal app.
So, it has you put in a mission statement, like a vision for your life.
And then using AI, it suggests long-term goals, weekly goals, and tasks that you can do.
So, I just started building this like last summer.
I'm currently uh approaching $3,000 of ARR on this.
So, still getting started, but it's been really fun to build.
Well, let's dive into it.
I think I would love to see is for this app right here, this Harmony app that you built.
Could you walk me through your stack?
What are all the tools that you've been using as a sort of non-developer developer?
So, I literally over the last year since I started coding, I've tried over 200 tools really with my goal being which is the tool that gives me the most creative freedom
and also speed.
After going through all of this, testing all of these tools.
These are the ones I've landed on for mobile apps, and I call this the ultimate mobile app tech stack.
The one I'm going to start with first is Expo.
Expo does two things for you.
One is it helps you submit your apps to the app store.
This is actually a really complicated process, believe it or not, and Expo makes it a lot easier.
So, that's one of the main reasons I like to use it.
And the second reason is Expo has a lot of packages and tools to add features to your apps that you normally would have to code yourself.
And so it can save you a lot of time.
So if you go to like the Expo doc, if you go to the reference, they have like all these tools like calendar like if I want to integrate like calendar features into my app or camera features and they have all of these different things.
A mistake people make.
I've seen people out there recommend people to build native Swift [music] apps because people usually launch on iOS first and they'll build Swift apps which you have to build in
Xcode.
And I've just found it a lot more complicated.
You don't get to use coding tools like Cursor, which we'll talk about later.
With a tool like Expo, it lets you publish to iOS and Android.
But even if you're only thinking of doing iOS in the beginning, Expo is valuable in terms of speed.
And the only reason you'd ever need to do a native app like that is if you're building like a game.
But if you're watching this video and you're still trying to get more technical, you probably don't need to do a Swift app.
You probably should do an Expo app.
So Expo's great.
There's some really cool libraries or I should call them packages you can use with Expo.
One is Native Wind.
Helps you have really good styling.
Native Wind is great if you're familiar with Tailwind on web apps.
It just helps you like have consistent styling and create like a consistent colors and things like that and dark and light mode.
So like if you look at my app, it has like this consistent colors and rounded corners.
This is all with native wind.
So I only have to define it in one place in my app and then I can use it everywhere.
Also light and dark mode in my app.
This is because of native wind.
Definitely recommend that.
Okay, next let's talk about React Native Reanimated.
This is a package you can install with Expo where you can animate your app and it does it in a way that keeps your app performant.
Literally, Reanimated is in my entire app just in like the animations and how things open and close and just animating the whole thing.
Reanimated is like a basic building block of pretty much the entire app.
So, highly recommend that.
Okay, final tool for the front end.
Let's talk about Lahi files.
This is really cool.
I use this in Harmony to add confetti.
So these are lightweight animations and you can search for them and you can embed these into your app.
So super awesome.
So those are some things on the front end.
I think it's really important to have your app have really good UIUX and to be pretty.
And so these are some of the top tools I would recommend.
Okay.
To kick off the back end, I want to talk about Convex.
This is arguably the most important tool here out of all of these because your backend,
that's where all of your data lives, where all of your logic is, where the core of your app lives.
One thing I want to say, I often times see people get recommended, especially people that are starting out with coding.
Superbase gets recommended all the time.
And that's really popular with tools like Lovable and Bolt as well that are more like beginner friendly.
Superbase is a really good tool.
But when it comes to speed, once again, speed and freedom to do whatever your imagination says,
[music] Convex is the best.
This is my codebase for Harmony.
And as you can see, first I have my apps here.
So I have like a web app that has like my website and it has like a form that they can fill out that then takes them to the native app.
This is my native app or the iOS.
Um over here you're going to see convex.
[music] My entire backend is right here.
So when I'm using AI right here, I'm in uh cursor, which we'll talk more about later.
I can reference my entire back end and AI has context of the entire thing to make changes and it can look at the front end at the same time.
Thi this is huge because in Superbase it's actually fragmented like half of the logic in Superbase is in the code,
the other half is in the dashboard.
So you're constantly having to do this dance between them.
Convex, it's all in one spot.
Amazing tool.
They've got a great team.
and they're always making it better.
We could get more into Convex.
We could probably do a whole video on it, but in terms of speed, it's so good being used with AI.
Next up, let's talk about Clerk.
Clerk is what I use for O.
This is one thing I want to bring up real quick is a mistake I made when I first started building iOS apps is I thought I needed to build everything myself from scratch.
Like the first time I was building Harmony, I tried to build my own O solution.
And when I say Oth, I mean like logging in with an account with [music] like Google or with a password.
I literally tried to do my own one.
and I spent like a week straight trying to do it and I was running into all these problems.
This is something that you should just outsource and use [music] a tool.
So the tool I use is Clerk.
It's like one of the most mature, one of the best ones in the ecosystem.
It integrates really well with Convex.
So highly recommend Clerk.
Okay, our next tool is Resend.
Resend is what I use for emails.
Something that makes an app a great experience is when users get emails for notifications or an intro email or when they cancel,
you can ask for feedback.
So, Resend is awesome and once again it integrates with Convex.
If you look at Convex has these things called components.
So, they actually have pre-built code for a lot of tools.
So, if like I search resend, they actually have a convex resend component.
So, instead of me having to write all the resend logic from scratch, I can actually just install this and it makes using resend really easy within convex.
So, um that's what I use for the back end.
And then if I want to do any AI features, I like to use Open AI.
They have like pretty much everything that you want.
Honestly, I use OpenAIs over the others is because their platform is really easy to work with and it does everything I need and it's fast and it's cheap.
You know, I can compare and I could try Claude and stuff, but honestly, for the features I have in my app,
it works really well.
Yeah.
So, they have image and vision models, they have audio and speech models.
So, if you you can think about all the features you'd want in your app, you can do anything here.
Now, for marketing, the first tool we're going to talk about is having your own landing page,
which is easiest with Versel using Nex.js.
JS for SEO and also for people that are on web and it redirects them to the app.
This is a marketing thing and it's really easy to build these websites with AI.
So in terms of marketing things that have worked the best for me so far, even though my app's still growing,
it's still getting there are organic social media posts.
So I post on X and LinkedIn and I'm really active on those.
That's where most of my subscribers have come from.
X has gotten me the most impressions, but LinkedIn has been the best for actual paying subscribers.
LinkedIn also has like a lower barrier to entry.
It's like harder to get your stuff seen on X, but LinkedIn, a lot of people have subscribed.
My app kind of goes well with LinkedIn, too, because it's about like productivity and like planning.
So, I kind of it fits like that audience.
In terms of organic social, it makes sense to double down on the platform where you feel like your users live.
So, that's what I'd recommend there.
>> Cool.
>> One of the lowest hanging fruits with marketing is a tool called Apple Search Ads.
So, Apple Search Ads is great because you can catch the user in the app store, right,
based on their intent.
It's the easiest way to convert people because they're already thinking about downloading an app,
they're already in that mindset.
One of the top ones I run is one called it's just a weekly planner campaign.
So, when someone searches weekly planner on the app store, I a lot of times show up at the top.
And this has actually helped me get a lot of subscribers, especially if you have something really niche.
If it's something broad like dating app, that's going to be really hard to do a campaign for.
But if you have like a niche feature or thing with your app, it's really smart to run targeted campaigns towards that.
Another great marketing tool is called Screen Studio.
It allows you to record videos of yourself and you can actually plug in your phone and it will do screen recordings on your computer with your face and your phone and edits them and makes them look
really pretty.
There are a million social media scheduling tools out there.
I've tried like all of them and I think Pali is the best one.
If you like to post on a lot of different platforms at the same time, this is my favorite one.
Look, Nathan has done a lot of the dirty work here [music] right now for you.
Which tools work?
Which tools don't?
And he's been sharing everything you need to build a real mobile app in 2026.
But here's one thing I do know.
[music] A lot of people are going to watch this video, bookmark it, but not actually get started building.
And [music] I don't want that to happen.
So that is why I created the starter story build iOS playbook where you will go from idea to a real working app on the app store [music] without writing a single line of code.
In our playbook, we're going to walk you through everything.
How to generate app ideas, how to build it with AI tools, how to work with APIs, and how to get it submitted and eventually approved [music] in the app store.
We took everything we know about building mobile apps and put [music] it into this boot camp.
So if you're serious about building, just hit the link in the description to start your first app.
All right, let's get back to the episode.
Next, let's talk about payments.
So, authentication and payments are the two things do not try to build yourself.
In terms of payments, my favorite tool to use is something called Superwall.
So, they do two things.
One, they handle all of the back-end transactions for the inapp purchases for your app.
When people like double click on the right side and they can subscribe through like Apple Pay or whatever,
they handle that first.
The second thing they do is they help you build pay walls.
I'm just going to open up my super wall.
They let you do a lot of testing.
I actually haven't done like a lot of like AB testing yet with it because my traffic's still so low,
but they have all of these templates of like proven payw walls that convert.
[clears throat] It's super easy to get started and design these and then you can test all of them.
They give you analytics.
So, Super Wall I highly recommend.
I actually was using a tool before called Revenue Cat.
Revenue Cat is also a great tool.
I will say Superwall where they are superior is in terms of the payw walls.
They just have better pay walls.
They have better templates.
But honestly, you might want to look into RevenueCat.
They do have deeper integrations.
Overall, I recommend Super Wall.
But this is a great tool to make getting paid a lot easier.
[laughter] Okay, now let's dive into analytics.
First, I'm going to start with a hot take on analytics.
Don't get so obsessed with analytics until you have a great product that is at least getting some traffic and some conversion.
What happens is people do like premature optimization.
They start doing AB tests or measuring all of these crazy analytics before they've even got anyone to like download and use their app.
The most important analytics at the beginning are what you're going to get in Super Wall,
which is like the payw wall rate.
Paywall rate is what percentage of people that download the app actually end up getting to the payw [music] wall.
So, this is like to test if your onboarding is like too long or not.
And then conversion rate is of all the people that see the payw wall, how many of those actually end up paying.
Those are like the most important things you're going to want to look up up front.
But once you start to get more into the analytics, a tool I really recommend is Post Hog.
Post HTO's great because you can dive more into your data of like your daily active users.
With Postto, I created this onboarding funnel where I can see the drop offs of like where people are dropping off in my onboarding.
When you start to get more into it, once you have an app that's actually a good product,
it is valuable to start looking into uh using things [music] like this.
And Post Hog has a really generous free tier and they also have error tracking.
So really recommend them.
Another really important tool in terms of analytics, this goes into attribution as well,
but if you want to start running paid ads, like Facebook ads or Google ads for your app,
you're going to want to get something called an MMP, which is a mobile measurement partner.
There's a bunch of them out there.
One of the most popular ones is called Appsflyer, which is the one I recommend.
It's kind of going to look similar in terms of you're going to get a lot of the same stats you're getting from Super Wall and things like that.
The reason why an MMP like apps flyier is so important is for attribution.
So when I run an ad on Meta, I need to be able to tell Meta that someone downloaded and paid for the app.
I need to be able to send that information back to them so they can find more people [music] like that.
So you have to use an MMP to be able to send this data back.
Appsfly, they have a really good free plan.
It integrates really well with all the ad networks.
If you're wanting to get into paid advertising, then you need to get something like Appsfly.
with mobile apps instead of SEO, they call it ASO, which is app store optimization, and the leading software to help with this is called App Tweak,
and it's a little expensive.
I've done like their free trial and stuff and done research in it.
So, you probably don't want to use this until your app's bigger.
It's really good for trying to optimize your app store optimization and [music] showing up in the app store results.
That's a really good tool that I plan on using in the future when my app's big.
[laughter] Okay, now let's talk about another crucial area and this is development.
The number one tool in my repertoire is cursor.
Cursor is a Visual Studio clone.
They team forked that and basically injected it with AI.
And cursor is amazing because I have my code here on one side and on the other side I have an AI chat with an LLM.
And they have, as you can see from this dropown, they have all of the best LLMs and they update this like every day.
So when a new one comes out, they're going to have it like almost immediately.
And it has context of my entire codebase.
Cursor is an elite tool for coding.
It makes everything so fast.
It's especially powerful when you pair it with speechtoext tool.
There's two really popular ones.
One of the really popular ones, it's called Whisper Flow, but I actually like using one called Willow.
I like Willow because they have like a native app.
I find just the app in the UI like a little snappier.
I just kind of want to show you like what this looks like.
My project management is super simple.
I literally have an Apple Notes app with a to-do list.
Anytime I run into like a bug or like a feature idea, I put it here.
So, like for example, I have this bug that I listed right here.
When I reset yearly planning, it doesn't reset the state of the year.
So, I'd be like, "Hey, cursor, when I reset my yearly planning, it's not actually like resetting the state of the card.
So, can you try to figure out what's going on there and fix it?"
As you can see, like Willow is super snappy.
Like, it almost immediately translated that.
There was barely any lag.
So yeah, cursor.
Look at this.
It's looking through my files.
It's starting to make plans.
It's figuring out what's going on.
Another tidbit I'll just throw in is one of the best LLMs right now for coding is Opus 4.5.
When this came out, it kind of like rocked the coding world.
[music] So I subscribe to the $200 a month cursor plan.
And I max out on this almost every month.
I think you probably want to start out on like a lower plan, but as soon as you max out on that,
you can upgrade.
But honestly, it's like the main thing I use.
I'm building this app in like 20 hours a week.
Like this is like my part-time job.
And so because of something like cursor, I'm able to do this on the side from our problem it did before.
It looks like it found the bug um and it fixed it right here.
So it actually fixed it in the code.
So that's awesome.
Another really popular tool for coding is Claw Code.
And this has especially gotten a lot of hype in the past few weeks.
I actually use both.
I use cursor as my primary one because I like seeing the code and I like being able to look at my changes.
So like this is git.
I like to be able to look at my changes and I just like the look and feel of an editor.
So it kind of just comes down to personal preference.
But claude code it's a CLI.
So it's like an app built into your terminal and it works very similar to cursor.
And one funny thing right here is you can run claude code.
Right now I'm running cloud code within cursor which you can do which is funny.
But I can say like um design me a new feature that shows ro health in the app.
It works very similar to cursor in that it's a chat and it references your code.
The reason why people like claude code more is when you're starting out from scratch.
It's probably superior because it can run for like an hour without you doing anything.
So like you can go in on cloud code and be like hey design me this app from scratch.
These are all my features ready set go.
and it will go for like an out and it'll actually build you something pretty good.
Cursor doesn't do that as well.
And so I think cursor is better as you start to get more mature in your codebase.
Like my codebase is getting a lot bigger now.
The reason I use both is actually usage.
So with cursor, their $200 a month plan and with cloud code, these are subsidized.
They're actually giving you more usage than you're paying for because you're doing a subscription.
So, for example, I've already used in this cycle $234 worth of tokens.
I'm only paying $200 a month, and I'm not even close to hitting my limit.
I think last month, I don't know if it lets me look at it, but I think I ended up reaching like $400 or $500 of usage.
I would probably recommend trying both.
See which one you like more.
This might be another hot take.
Like, I don't design app screens in Figma anymore.
So when I'm like designing like new features and stuff, I actually just tell it to follow like the design system that I established in the beginning with Native Wind and I just have it create pages based on best
practices and stuff and I find it a lot faster.
However, I do use Figma for like assets on like the app store screenshots.
I use it for like so like social media assets and sharing on social media, but I literally just have like one big Figma board with like all of my brand colors and my fonts and logos.
I just build and design in the code.
Your designs change so much and so frequently that if you're using Figma to design stuff,
it's just going to slow you down.
Another thing I want to note with all these tools is they're very friendly in terms of pricing.
They either have a free trial, a generous free tier you can always use, or they're usage based so that you're only spending like a few pennies at the beginning.
Thanks for sharing your stack, Nathan.
Super cool.
It's pretty crazy that you were able to learn all this in just really one year.
Tell me about how that was even possible for you.
>> Yeah, I think number one is I don't know if you can see where I am right now, but this is like a little closet in my house that has no windows and no distractions.
I pretty much just locked myself in here, blocked social media, and just learned.
So, eliminate distractions in your life.
You can do a lot more than you could ever imagine.
So, some of my takeaways in summary would be number one, if you desire, you can become technical.
You really can.
You can dive into it and [music] can learn it pretty fast, especially now with AI.
You can become dangerous quickly and start building your own stuff quickly.
[music] Number two, I would say everyone talks about AI has made coding so much easier,
but the tooling around it is so good now.
We have tools like Expo that make publishing and building your front end like so seamless.
And then we have Convex on the back end that you pair that up with AI and you can build apps in your free time and make money.
[music] Number three, remember that your number one moat as a startup is speed.
Speed is everything.
That's the one advantage that you have over the huge company.
[music] That's the only reason why they can't necessarily just crush you.
So, make sure you prioritize speed in everything [music] you do.
And then number four, the motivation that has kept me going because there have been hard days and there will continue to be hard days as I try to grow my app.
It's to build stuff that you personally want.
This is a great way to build something that has a good chance of making money, but also it's a great way to stay motivated.
Because when you build something you want, you're motivated to learn.
You're motivated to make it work.
and you're motivated to do like anything possible to make it happen because you personally want that thing.
So, it's great to start with a hobby project and start with something that you wish existed.
Yeah, that's my invitation to you is to go start building something that you want.
Well, cool, man.
Thanks for coming on and sharing.
It's crazy what you can do in a year, especially with AI tools.
I also invite anyone who's watching this right now to just get started and see what happens and see what you can build.
So, thanks for coming on, Nathan and Sharon.
>> Thanks so much.