I talked to a lot of people who share the same struggle.
They say, "I don't know if this app idea is going to work."
Well, what if I told you that you could know if your app idea would work before you even write a single line of code?
>> If you reverse the process and first figure out how to sell the app, it's going to make it so much [music] easier.
>> I just talked to a couple founders who did exactly this.
They grew their app to $30,000 a month with this simple content [music] first strategy.
This is not some highle stuff.
This is a real life story that actually happened.
And I asked these two founders to come onto the channel and show their exact playbook for how they validated their idea before writing a single line of [music] code or building anything.
>> I always dreamed of being like an entrepreneur, but I always like was very passive about it.
I always just watched watched and then I decided to take action and now I'm here, which is insane.
>> So in this video, they're going to be walking through their three-step process.
Number one, how [music] to research app ideas.
Number two, how to know if your idea is inherently viral and worth building.
And number three, you're going to watch them come up with an actual piece of content designed to validate an app so you don't have to build a single thing.
Thank you to Alejandro and Mario, founders of Push Scroll, for coming on here and sharing the sauce that nobody else would be willing to share.
Let's get started.
I'm Pat Walls.
This is Starter Story.
Welcome to the playbook.
Welcome guys, Mario and Alejandro, founders of Push Scroll and creators of this awesome content first playbook.
First, before we get into the whole playbook, you guys just let me know who you are,
what you built, and why this is worth watching.
>> Hi, I'm Alejandro.
I'm one of the founders of Push Scroll, where I'm primarily responsible for marketing and design of the app.
>> And hi, I'm Mario.
I'm the technical founder, and I'm coding the app and optimizing our funnel.
The app we built is called Pusho, which makes you do push-ups or any other exercise before you can doom scroll on social media.
In just 4 months, we scaled our app to 30K MR and 300,000 downloads all through organic content we made ourselves.
On Instagram alone, we did just over 30 million views and probably around 40 million views on all platforms combined.
But we did this in a different way, creating the content before actually building the app.
>> In this video, I'm going to show you how we did that.
And by the end of this video, we're going to show you an exact process that actually turned our app into a $30,000 per month app and how we do it again if we had to start over.
>> Cool.
I'm really excited to go over this.
Guys, before we dive into the step by step and the exact playbook on how to do all this,
can you just give me the high level of what this whole process looked like and how it looked for push scroll?
There's three steps to this method.
First, you do some research.
Then, you come up with a viral idea.
Then, you create the content based on the viral idea you just came up with to validate if it's actually a good idea.
And if the idea didn't work out, instead of wasting thousands of hours, you just wasted one video.
And you can just start again day by day until it works.
>> Okay, cool.
So, let's dive into step one, which is the research process.
How do you guys go about even starting the process of finding a good idea?
I think a lot of people watching this or watching our channel wonder, how do you even get into a space where you can find an idea that could potentially make $30,000 a month like Push Scroll did?
So, the first step is going to be research.
Research and validation are extremely important.
If you choose a bad idea from the start, you will make your life 10 times harder when it comes to marketing and payroll conversion.
No matter how good your video is, if the app idea is not attractive, your marketing videos won't get any views or they won't convert.
At the end of the day, what matters the most is distribution.
So, if you reverse the process and first figure out how to sell the app, it's going to make it so much easier.
There's no definitive way to find a viral idea, but here are some tools and resources that you can use to find one in the next 14 days.
First up, you're going to warm up a new Tik Tok account in your niche.
Warming up consists on scrolling on your for you page and watching in full length content that is in your niche.
The problem is with your current feed that's only a reflection of your own inner desires.
If you want new ideas, you have to act as your perfect customer.
For example, you could create a feed for the looks maxing niche.
You will see what content goes viral and build your idea around that.
To start out, you would follow a bunch of people on that niche around 10 and then you search looks maxing and start watching every single video and understand why it works.
Use this as an opportunity to deeply understand the niche, understand the pain point that creators are already targeting and use the same ones to target your potential users.
So, here's a new feed.
For example, I would look for looks maxing and then go to one video and first of all analyze what makes this video viral.
In most cases, it's going to be the hook, but you also want to take a look at the content and how they do the CTA.
For example, this one is also promoting a product.
Hook is how to blow up.
Then, they give you a bunch of tips.
Here, they're probably going for either engagement.
There's probably going to be a lot of tips that people don't know.
So, they'll be asking like, "Hey, what's rosemary?"
or "Hey, what's head scrubber?"
And that generates a conversation that Tik Tok will boost.
And then at the end, there's the CTA.
But you want to look also at the comments like all this engagement that I was mentioning.
Here's where people talk about the actual pains that they have.
It also gives you ideas on what kind of content to create to have this engagement.
For example, people here are saying do I have potential?
Could be an idea for an app that tells you like whether you have the potential and then it gives you a score for your face for your hairstyle or another one rope explanation.
Like this is a a bit of a niche method and so you can use it in your own content to get people to comment.
In this case it's a carousel.
We did mostly actual videos, but it's a bit like similar style.
Just like look through the whole video, understand what makes it good and then try to like sort of come up with your own ideas.
So, [music] the way to find ideas from what I understand is I think that's pretty smart actually is to actually look at what people are saying in the comments and maybe translating that to an app idea.
So, this person saying, "Do I have potential?"
That's what it said in the comment.
And then the idea is maybe there's an app that tells you if you have potential.
Tell me a little bit more about why it makes sense to look at comments and why they could become app ideas that make money.
>> To get a viral video, people have to be really excited about this idea.
And one way to see how excited they are is comments.
Like if people actually watch a video and then it's interesting enough that they go like,
I got to share my opinion or I got to ask something.
That's a signal that the content is getting to them.
>> You're on to something there with the comments thing because let's say we put out a video and it has 100,000 views.
We may only get 100red comments.
And as you're saying, the people that leave those comments are the most passioned users.
Whether their passion is positive or their passion is negative.
Looking at those are people that are experiencing the most pain or the most excitement around something and that's where the app ideas could potentially be.
I think there's something there in looking at the comments for sure.
>> Yeah, exactly.
If you see in your feed like a video that does not at all fit to the niche, there's also a button in Tik Tok specifically where you can press it and impress on not interested.
And basically, you're trying to train the algorithm to show you more of the looks maxing videos.
You want to engage.
You want to watch the video fully.
You want to like it.
You want to leave a comment.
And it's also useful to do this if you later want to post organic videos because if you straight up post from day one,
your videos might get shadowbanned.
And it's super hard to get an account back from being shadowbanned.
So, that's also like useful for later than posting yourself.
So, not only are you getting more inside of your niche and understanding more about your customers,
but you're also warming up your account for the eventual content that you're going to post,
which is equally as important.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
>> In any case, you don't have to limit yourself to this method for finding ideas.
You can also try improving or working on other ideas or taking inspiration on them.
You can use proven viral ideas and adapt them into similarly big niches where there's a market cap.
One example is Quitter, which is an app to quit adult content.
So you could do quitter for sugar addiction which is what stopper did.
I can show the website.
You can see here that the main feature is the tracking and then stopper it's similar concept for a completely different niche.
They don't even target men but women.
Or one last method that you can try is taking an existing idea and making a huge improvement.
That's for example what Ki did by improving my fitness pal which is a fitness tracker with AI vision.
And the important thing is that they made it the main feature.
If no app has in that niche reached any significant revenue probably stay away from it.
They're called tarpet ideas because they sound like really good ideas to practice, but they will waste your time.
>> Let's talk about tarpet ideas for a second.
I think it would be really useful for the people that are watching.
Tarpet ideas.
The first tarpet idea that I know of that I see a lot is recipe generators.
I see a lot of people building recipe generators, but I don't really see a whole lot of very successful apps in that space.
What other tarpit ideas have you guys seen or even tried to build yourself?
Stay away from social media apps.
But to be fair, like social media apps, it's just like a different game you're playing.
With social media apps, you're trying to maximize for shares instead of revenue.
And so I don't think it's a tarpet idea, actually.
>> Probably a tarpet idea for bootstrappers like us.
>> Yeah, not even that.
It's just riskier.
I mean, it's going to take more time to take off because you need the high K factor.
You need high shares.
Initially, it's going to be slow, but it's going to be exponential.
But the thing is, I guess target ideas are just >> to-do lists.
That's another exact typical list or project tracker.
>> Yeah, I mean apps that are not viral are target ideas.
That's pretty much the definition of a target idea.
If you cannot market it, then there goes your app.
>> I think they also come from just staying in your bubble.
For example, if you have a technical background, you will probably do like a project tracker or like a to-do list or an extension for something like that.
And it's not until you exit that bubble that you see other ideas with a lot of potential.
>> Yeah, that's great.
And that's why I think what you guys say, which is going and curating your Tik Tok feed to be in some kind of random niche and unliking the ones that aren't in that niche,
can show you ideas that you probably wouldn't find.
Just hang out on X.
>> Exactly.
Just like go pursue your like childhood interest or like take a week to learn photography.
Speak also with people outside your bubble and you will have so many insights about like what problems people have outside of typical issues that you come across.
Always find at least one competitor which has a somewhat similar idea to your app who's doing significant revenue.
You can use sensor tower to check the revenue that the app is making.
For example, our competitor clear space was making around 60k in monthly recurring revenue when we were researching competitors.
That also give us a signal that we should be able to make money on top of going part.
And so here's sensor tower.
It's a database of popular apps.
For example, clear space is the example I mentioned.
They're making 20K a month and it's quite similar to the main product of our app.
It's really strong validation that it will be profitable.
Or for example, OPPO is a more generic screen time control app where you block apps and add scales and so on.
They're the biggest one in the market and they're making $600,000 per month >> and their app sucks because I used it one time and I deleted.
[laughter] >> Yeah, that that's true.
Push is a lot better.
>> It's a bit complex to use and so on.
>> But actually, I think the app was pretty weak when I used it and it made me think about how much opportunity there is just in even the doom scrolling space.
you your app might not be as [music] generic as Opal.
You maybe want to target a more specific niche.
But if the most general one is making a lot of profit, that probably means a niche can take a fraction of it.
>> And to be fair, those numbers are not super accurate.
If you're in touch grass level, it might be off by like 5 to 10K.
There's a lot of variance there.
But for like bigger apps, it's pretty like spot on.
>> The extremes are a bit off because like here like when you grow to the size of Opal,
your revenue doesn't just come from the app.
For example, they released a new program that's Opel for schools and they monetize in a completely different way.
So, they make even more than this.
>> Yeah.
I just remember like our numbers were a bit off.
>> Oh, yeah.
We can check actually.
>> Yeah, [laughter] this is very off.
>> Nice.
>> How much does it say?
You says you're doing 10K, but you're doing more.
>> Yeah, 30K and way more on like neck this month.
>> All right.
Well, cool.
Thanks for showing that.
Okay.
So, we went through most of step one, which is research.
But what I really want to do in this exercise in this playbook that we're going through is I want you guys to at least come up with a hypothetical app idea because I want to do this with like
a real app, a real potential app so someone watching can apply their app to it and see how their app compares.
So let's come up with an actual app idea which we will see if it's viral and then we'll also create an actual piece of content around it.
But what were you guys thinking for the app idea?
>> So if you look back at the comment we saw earlier, do I have potential?
That's pretty much what we're going to make with this idea.
We're just going to take this comment and transform it into an app idea.
And the idea is very simple.
You just take a selfie and then it shows you detailed stats about your current appearance.
Basically shows you how you can improve it.
To be honest, like this idea already exists, of course, it's called UMAX.
However, we will use this as an example to show the principles that go into a viral app and that you can really apply this to every app idea.
Okay, cool.
So, our hypothetical idea is a looks maxing app.
I can take a photo of myself and it tells me how I can look better by chiseling my jaw or shaving my beard or whatever it does.
It's pretty simple idea.
Obviously, this idea already exists and it's a very successful idea.
That's the point.
For anybody who's watching this, I hope that you are coming up with your own idea.
And what we're going to talk about next is going to make a lot of sense.
So, try to bring your idea to the table for this.
But now that we have our idea, what is step two in the three-step content first playbook?
First, we have to ask ourselves, what even is a viral app idea?
A viral app idea is any idea that will make your marketing efforts 10 times easier later.
And before you even touch your code editor, you have to verify that your idea can go viral on Tik Tok.
Because if you know your idea is viral, you can literally have the worst loweffort video known to mankind and you can still make millions of views.
If you have an idea, here are things you can look at to know if it has viral potential.
It doesn't have to have all of these things, but if it has some of them, that's already great.
First of all, your app idea should solve a fundamental human need.
Think of this parameter.
At the bottom, we have the most fundamental needs for humans such as food, clothing,
reproduction.
And only when you have that covered can you move up the ladder into for example safety needs or self-esteem.
Most big apps nowadays usually fall into the safety and security sector.
For example, you have health apps like Kelli, push hole, life reset.
And in our case, you could argue that looks maxing corresponds to the lowest sector on this pyramid.
So an app ideo in the looks maxing niche could be really fundamental if done right.
>> Is being lower on the pyramid better for an app or is it not matter as long as you're hitting anything in that pyramid?
>> The lower you can go the better because the lower you can go the more we actually need it.
>> But it's also why Alejandra said it doesn't have to cover everything because in some cases you can sacrifice a bit like maybe it's not the lowest one but the one before but there's a bigger market gap in there that you can exploit cuz after all everyone's going for the
bottom.
If it's just a bit higher that's also fine.
You can also make a lot of money with it.
>> Okay.
So our looks maxing app that I can take a photo of definitely hits that criteria.
What's the next criteria?
>> Number two is to look up the trend.
For example, on Google trends, you have to make sure your idea is in a growing market to see if a market is growing.
You can check this website.
So this is the popularity chart for doom scrolling on Google and usually represents whether people are worrying more about it or not.
You can see that doom scrolling is getting bigger and bigger as unfortunately it's affecting younger people more and more every day.
And here's the chart for looks maxing.
You can see that it only started to become a thing in 2023, but UMAX launched exactly at the moment where it started to rise like end of 2023,
beginning of 2024, it exploited also timing, which is something also really important.
So overall, right now, I would prefer doom scrolling as a market because it's going to keep growing.
But you can see how much impact the timing for UMAX had back then.
If the market is big enough, there's going to be room for a lot of players.
And that also means that you don't have to solve the whole problem.
you can just focus on a smaller part and that's going like targeting a specific smaller audience is going to make your life a lot easier and like how to approach them how to understand them and going for the whole thing and still
since it's big that's going to still be able to grow a lot and get over 10kr at least >> okay so the second criteria is seeing how big this problem is on Google trends
we looked at the doom scrolling which is definitely growing very fast and probably one of the reasons why push scroll your guys' app kind of took off as Well,
we looked at looks maxing which kind of peaked last year, but that doesn't necessarily mean it's not still a big market and there's still money to be made there.
And just one year is really not that long ago when you think about it.
But just to really understand there as far as our idea for looks maxing, this sort of hits that criteria that it's a growing trend,
not as good as looks maxing.
So let's say maybe we give us a half point for this one.
>> Yeah, exactly.
I would just give it half a point.
But if you look at the last 12 months on looks maxing, if you compare the first entry point and the last one,
it is slightly growing, but it doesn't have the same exponential growth that doom scrolling has,
right?
But it's still like that's still like solid.
I wouldn't discount it just because of this.
If it's declining, then that's a red flag.
>> Yeah, you don't want to do an app for newspapers.
>> Yeah, exactly.
That's a good example.
Like newspapers would be like a bad market to enter now.
I mean, it would be funny to search it up.
Newspaper.
Yeah, it's going down.
>> Yeah, it does not look good.
Yeah, that would be like a bad example for a niche you want to enter.
>> Cool.
I like that you guys showed that and what's good, what's medium, and what's bad.
What would be the next criteria that you would write it against?
>> So, your app should also be extremely simple and straightforward to explain.
So, people actually underestimate how brained people on TikTok and IG are because people scroll at their highest dopamine peak.
You're scrolling, you're on your bed, you don't want to think, and as soon as something is slightly complicated,
you just have to swipe your thumb.
That's it.
Therefore, your app has to be extremely easy to understand.
If we look at our app idea from earlier, it's extremely simple.
You basically just snap a picture of your face and it analyzes your stats and potential.
That's literally only two screens.
And ideally, you should be able to explain your app in three words.
If you look at Cali, it's AI calorie counter.
If you look at our app, push scroll push-ups before doom scrolling.
This is not only important for viral videos, but it also determines how likely it is for someone to share it with their friends.
And if we look back at our looks maxing idea, you could even do it in less than three words.
You could just say face analysis.
>> Okay, so three simple words.
Even our example here, looks maxing is two words, face analysis.
So that's a very simple app and that definitely hits that criteria of if this is something that could potentially go viral and make money.
What's the next criteria that you'd have?
>> The next one is, and this is probably one of the most important ones, your app has to be visual.
For example, Kaii, you just snap a picture of your food and instantly get the macro breakdown and you already know what the value is.
You literally don't need any explanation.
I mean, just look at this example here.
As you can see, just takes a picture of the food.
Boom.
Micro breakdown.
It's only very minimal captions.
And if you turn on the sound, it's just some music.
But you immediately know what the value is.
And that's what the power of a visual app has.
So, if you look back at our example, it already is extremely visual.
I mean, people literally take a selfie.
And to make it even more visual, we could add some sort of trading card stats.
So something like this where you see the face and you see all the stats, but instead of whatever this is,
it's your facial stats, the jawline, your acne.
And the overview here is extremely good.
Okay, so the app has got to be visual, especially if you're doing something that you eventually will be creating a video about.
If you can't visually show what your app does on a video, good luck having anyone even understand it.
So, our looks maxing idea definitely hit that criteria.
What is the last criteria to know if you have a potentially viral app or if there is potential in an app that can make money?
So, last but not least, it needs to be sharable.
And you can achieve this in many ways.
Contrary to all the advice we just gave you, you can literally make a pet rock app and it could go viral and you can make a ton of money.
Or you could also do just something that friends want to share to help improve your friends life like reset or push scroll.
Even our idea um shares especially on IG are a big part of the algorithm and they will boost views like crazy.
And you can achieve this by doing the did you hear about test.
Did you hear about the app that lets you track calories with just a picture cali or did you hear about the app that makes you do push-ups before you can doom scroll on social media push scroll?
Let's go back to our example in the looks maxing niche.
Our idea is very sharable since you want to help your friends become more attractive.
And you can also explain it very easily.
You could say,"Have you heard about the app that scans your face and shows it your potential?"
>> Okay, I like that.
So, whatever app you're thinking about and you're putting against this criteria, create that sentence.
See if it creates excitement.
See if it creates curiosity.
See if it's something you'd want to even say to a friend.
Maybe even try saying it to a friend or a family member or your partner and see if that evokes excitement or curiosity.
I think that's really powerful to show that there's something actually interesting here.
>> This question is going to be your hook in most of your videos as well.
The format that went viral for us was this guy's doing push-ups to unlock Instagram.
That's literally the same thing as did you hear about the app that makes you do push-ups before you want to scroll.
Okay, so those are the five criteria you want to analyze your app against.
Doesn't have to hit all these criteria perfectly, but if it does, there's probably a better chance of it being viral,
something that you should work on and actually end up creating a video.
So, I'm going to go over those again real quick.
The first one is how low does your app fit on the Maslo's hierarchy of needs?
The lower the better.
Number two is, is this a growing trend?
and is this a big market?
And you can look all that up on Google Trends.
Number three is, is your app really simple and straightforward?
Can you put it into three words in one sentence?
Number four is, is it visual?
Is it something that you could share on video, which is the number way to market and grow an app these [music] days,
Tik Tok, Instagram, it needs to be visual.
And number five, is it sharable?
Is it something that people are going to tell their friends about?
Is it something that is going to create curiosity and be interesting and have people share on social media?
So, thank you guys for sharing those five things.
I think our looks maxing idea is pretty good.
It probably gives maybe a 3.5 or a four out of five on this scale if we could give it a score.
Let's pretend that we're going to go with this idea.
We think it's worth creating a piece of content around that.
What is step three in the three-step playbook?
>> The only reason why we ultimately decided to build our app was because it went viral on Tik Tok.
We basically did a video trying to validate the idea and it got a lot of engagement and that was the sign for us to actually build the app.
So step three will be to just take this idea and you turn this into a video.
And this video then serves to sort of validate if your idea can go viral.
And I'm going to show how we did it and how you can use this as a template for your own idea.
With any viral video, the most important thing is the hook.
If you don't get the hook right, no matter how good the rest of your video is, it's not going to get any views.
So what makes a good hook?
Your hook has to be extremely clear to the point a 5-year-old can understand it.
There has to be a curiosity gap.
So, the viewer needs to have enough curiosity to stay for the payoff after the hook.
In my case, the 20 push-ups are the thing that created the most curiosity.
You want to know like what do the push-ups have to do with stopping doom scrolling.
It has to be novel and original, which is not a reason why my video went viral in the first place is because this app idea is pretty new.
And then you also need to put emotion into the hook.
I use the keywords doomscrolling addiction which are two very powerful words which evoke emotion and also bonus points if you can use visually interesting elements inside your hook.
So maybe in my hook I could have been doing push-ups while saying the hook.
So let's actually look at the hook we used for our video.
So our hook was what if you could stop your doomcrolling addiction by doing 20 push-ups.
And if you don't know where to start with your own hook, there are some tools you can use.
For example, this one.
This is a custom GPT I made.
You can enter your own video ID in here and it will give you a hook that has been tried and tested.
And when you start out with folks, you don't want to reinvent the wheel.
You want to use what already works.
And this GBT is trained on what already works.
So you cannot go wrong with this.
So once you have a hook, how do you actually showcase your app if you haven't already built it?
This part is very simple.
You just have to understand that people don't actually care how their problem is solved,
just that it's being solved.
So if you can show the perceived value of your future app, then you don't even need to have an actual app in your video to go viral.
And to do that, you can use visual elements from YouTube.
For example, for our app, we used an AI push-up tracker.
As you can see, that's just a video I found on YouTube, and it's pretty close to our actual app.
And if you can't find anything on YouTube, you can just use your editing skills to create an animation or some visual that can represent your app idea.
And when you showcase these visuals, try to keep it fresh every 2 seconds.
Show a new clip.
And also keep it brief and to the point.
Every second counts here.
Also, it's important to use fifth grade language and keep each sentence or line below 15 words.
One thing I want to mention for people watching, go check out the Tik Tok video that they created.
He sort of talked about this for a second, but you mentioned people don't care how their problem is being solved.
They just care that it's being solved.
So that when they watch the video, they realized that they could potentially stop doom scrolling and also get into better shape.
I remember when I had posted about this on X and people were all curious about what kind of video you created.
A lot of people were thinking that it was just showing off a demo of an app you already built.
When you go watch the video, you'll notice that you just filmed a YouTube video and you sort of edited it in a way that made it look like it already existed.
That way you didn't have to actually build the app and you didn't have to create a demo and it's really worth watching how you [music] guys built that together.
It's not about the app, it's about the benefit and that's a really important thing.
>> Yeah, exactly.
All right, let's actually make a viral video script to verify that the looks maxing idea we had previously is actually a good idea.
So step one, you need a good hook.
So let's go back to our GPT here.
So I already asked it some questions.
I started out by asking, I'm building an app that scans your face and gives you stats about your appearance.
The way I program this GBT, I give it an idea and it gives me hook suggestions.
But what I missed here is that this is for validating a video idea.
So I added this.
This is to validate my app idea.
And I ended up with this hook.
This is the one that stood out the most to me.
What if your phone could tell you your glow potential from just a selfie?
It's very similar to the hook we actually used.
What if you could stop your doomcrolling addiction by doing 20 push-ups?
And let's actually run through the checklist, right?
Is it clear such that a 5-year-old can understand it?
I would say yeah, it is.
Is there curiosity?
Yeah.
I mean, you want to know how you can look more attractive.
And that also ties into the fundamental nature of this app.
Is it novel and original?
Technically speaking, it isn't.
But if it was a new idea, which UMX was back in the day, this would be the case.
So, this is also check.
Is it emotional?
I would say yeah, it is because we're using the words glow up potential.
Those are very emotionally loaded words.
Now that you have the hook, you need to write the rest of the script.
So, we use this hook.
It starts out with this.
And then basically, you just explain the app as straightforward as you can.
So basically, you just take a selfie and then it will show you the current stats for every aspect of your face,
like your acne or your jawline.
And for every aspect, it will show you the potential you have for a glow up, but it also gives you a detailed guide on how to get there.
And then you have a call to action.
Should I build this?
Let me know in [music] the comments.
So, what's actually happening here?
We're using connector words.
This just makes it flow a bit nicer.
And each line is less than 15 words long.
You have to remember that the attention span is very short in Tik Tok.
And also what's very interesting here, if we take all of this and we put it into this hemingwayapp.com,
you will see this is grade two language.
You want to keep it below grade five language.
This is very important because as soon as it's just a little bit complicated, people are going to scroll.
What you're going to do after this, you need some shots.
You need some visuals to keep it [music] interesting.
So you just go to every line and you just put like sort of like a to-do list of visuals you need to record.
Try to have a new visual every 2 seconds.
You want to use different types of shots.
You want to use close-up shots, wide shots, POV shots.
You also want to add funny and unexpected moments.
For my app, you could do like a silly face in the beginning.
Oh, this is how you look right now.
And then you could do some Tik Tok filter.
This is how you could look like after using this app or something.
You want to keep it funny and unexpected.
And you just edit it on Cap Cut.
That's pretty much it.
You just do this every day until you get a viral video.
Well, that was awesome.
What I think is super cool about this is this is exactly what you guys did.
This is not like theory or anything like that.
You guys did this.
You created this viral video with a great hook and then it went viral.
It got a bunch of comments.
You built the app.
It started making money and look where you guys are at now.
So, this is a super cool process.
I think a lot of people watching this will hopefully change their minds on not the right way to build apps,
but a different way to build apps.
Instead of building the product and spending months on a product and then trying to figure out marketing,
what if you could just have all the marketing figured out before spending a second on the product?
So, this is super cool.
Okay.
Thank you guys for coming on, Mario and Alejandro and sharing this playbook.
For anyone watching this, hopefully you really enjoyed it.
There's a lot of stuff on YouTube about these different playbooks on how to, you know,
do Tik Tok and all these different things.
But what I think is really cool about this is this is exactly what you guys did.
You guys are making $30,000 a month with your app and you did this just in the last couple months.
So, this is fresh.
This works.
And the proof is in the pudding, right?
You guys have this really successful app called Push Scroll that anybody can go online and check it out.
Really successful.
Thank you guys for coming on and sharing all that when you didn't have to.
Putting all this together, I think it's going to change lives.
So, thank you for coming on.
>> All right.
Thank you, man.
Thank you.