We collected two and a half million
sales calls and studied them with a
machine learning platform at scale.
The big insight is that you're losing
most of your sales deals, not to
competition, but to indecision.
And that indecision stems from their fear of
failure. Dialing up the FOMO backfires 87% of
the time. They're not afraid of missing
out, they're afraid of messing up.
You just talk about how to actually leverage these
insights to improve your sales process. You have
something, I think you call it the JOLT method?
Yeah, JOLT them forward. The first thing is we've
got to judge their level of indecision. The second
thing is we've got to offer a recommendation.
The third thing is we've got to get them to start
trusting us and we call it limit the exploration,
and the T is we've got to de-risk the deal.
We've got to take some risk off the table.
Great segue to The Challenger Sale,
which is basically this on steroids.
Most salespeople are trying to figure out what's
keeping the customer up at night. The challenger
approach is about showing the customer what should
be keeping them up at night. What's a risk that
they don't know about but you do.
Holy moly, this is going to be the most
action-packed, high-density podcast episode we've
done. Today, my guest is Matt Dixon. Matt is one
of the world's foremost experts in sales, known
for his groundbreaking research into what makes
the best salespeople different from everyone else.
His first book, The Challenger Sale, was a number
one Wall Street Journal bestseller and has sold
over a million copies worldwide. His most recent
book, The JOLT Effect, builds on his lessons
and insights and will change how you do sales.
In our conversation, Matt breaks down what
you're probably doing wrong in your sales
process based on research, into millions of sales
conversations, and then how to tweak your process
to be a lot more successful. This episode is for
anyone that wants to improve their sales skills or
improve the rate at which they close deals.
With that, I bring you Matt Dixon and if you
enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting app
or YouTube. It's the best way to avoid
missing future episodes and it helps the
podcast tremendously. Matt, thank you so much
for being here. Welcome to the podcast.
It's great to be here. Thank you
for the invitation, Lenny.
It's great to have you here. First of all, a huge
thank you to April Dunford for connecting us.
She's a huge fan of your work. She mentioned
you a number of times on the podcast episode
that she did. She's great.
Yeah, she's very nice.
She's amazing. You basically spend your time
researching salespeople and digging into what
makes the best salespeople different from all
the rest, and then synthesizing these lessons
into these really actionable pieces of advice
so that anyone can become better at sales,
which to me feels like a dream come
true even if I'm not a salesperson,
even though many of us do sales part-time,
but especially if you're a salesperson.
First of all, just to give people a sense of
the work that you do, could you just talk a bit
about the research that went into the books
that we're going to talk about, we're going
to be focusing on The Challenger Sale and The
JOLT Effect. What is the research they did?
Yeah, sure. Just start with The Challenger,
because that chronologically came first. We
actually started that research study in,
I think it was in late 2008 actually,
and we published the initial results to, at the
time I was working for a company called CEB,
which was acquired by Gartner Group
in 2017, a research organization,
and then I was running the group that served heads
of sales, business, business heads of sales around
the world. We had five or 600 clients around
the world, and we launched that study in '08.
We published the initial results for our clients
in '09. We kept collecting some data and then
we published the book in 2011. The book was
published off a data set of 6,000 salespeople,
so we did an in-depth survey with 6,000
salespeople, as well as collected performance data
on those 6,000 sellers. It was a global, cross
industry, different types of companies as well,
product companies, services companies, large,
small, slow growth, fast growth, you name it.
Overtime, though, that research has been ongoing,
so we've collected data. I think to date,
on roughly a quarter million salespeople around
the world that we continue to go back and not
just validate the original findings, but look
at how things are changing and do cuts of the
data now that the data set's so big. That was
a survey based piece of research we did.
The JOLT Effect, we started that research in
2020, actually. It was actually in March of 2020,
which I think is a time that everybody
remembers with probably mixed emotions,
most of them bad. I think though, you remember
March was a time when people were getting into
Tiger King and baking sourdough bread. A few
months later, that got really old, but in the
beginning it was kind of surprising and weird and
this whole pandemic thing, but we actually thought
because we're huge nerds, that this would be an
interesting time to do a sales research project.
We had always been fascinated by what Professor
Neil Rackham did back in the '70s and '80s and
spin selling, and he and his research team
sat in on 30 something thousand sales calls,
physically sat in on these meetings and took
notes. They're a team of psychologists to produce
the research that went into spin selling, and so
we always kind of aspire to get, if you will, at
the coal face or where the rubber hits the road in
sales, which is the sales conversation when that
salesperson is sitting across from the customer.
The problem with that is it's really hard to
get people to pay for that kind of research,
that kind of undertaking, and then let alone,
getting invited into those meetings because a lot
of the really critical sales meetings took place,
of course, in the client's office. Until March of
2020 when that all changed and the entire sales
process for every company on Earth went to Zoom
and Teams and Webex and other virtual platforms.
We recruited several dozen companies across
industry and around the world into a large global
study, and we collected two and a half million
sales calls and studied them with a machine
learning platform at scale. That was a very
different kind of research project and honestly,
it's fun just as a researcher to look back on
Challenger and the manual survey-based approach
and the interviews and all this stuff to fast
forward to today, being able to take advantage
of large data sets and advance technology to study
millions of sales conversations is pretty cool.
Amazing. Okay, so the second book, the most recent
book, The JOLT Effect is based on these two and a
half million sales conversations.
Mm-hmm. That's right.
I love insights that come from tons of data, so
this is most excellent. This episode is brought
to you by Enterpret. Enterpret unifies all of
your customer interactions from Gong calls,
to Zendesk tickets, to Twitter threads, to app
store reviews, and makes it available for your
product team. It's used by leading product orgs
like Canva, Notion, Loom, Linear, and Descript,
to accurately integrate the voice of the
customer into your product development process,
helping you build best in class products.
What makes Enterpret special is its ability
to build customer-specific adaptive AI models
that provide the most granular and accurate
categorization of all your customer feedback and
also connect customer feedback to revenue impact,
to help product leaders confidently prioritize
things that will actually move the needle for
your business. If you want a custom model
built for your organization so that you can
automate your feedback loops and prioritize
your roadmap with confidence, get in touch
with the team at enterpret.com.lenny.
That's E-N-T-E-R-P-R-E-T.com.lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Webflow. We're
all friends here, so let's be real for a second.
We all know that your website shouldn't be a
static asset. It should be a dynamic part of
your strategy that drives conversions. That's
business 101, but here's a number for you,
54% of leaders say web updates take too long.
That's over half of you listening right now.
That's where Webflow comes in. Their visual
first platform allows you to build, launch, and
optimize web pages fast. That means, you can set
ambitious business goals and your site can rise
to the challenge. Learn how teams like Dropbox,
IDEO and Orangetheory trust Webflow to achieve
their most ambitious goals today at webflow.com.
Let's dive into the insights from The JOLT Effect.
The way that I understand is the big insight
is that you're losing most of your sales deals
not to competition, but to indecision.
Basically, customers preferring to do
nothing versus choosing something because
they are afraid of making a mistake.
Good summary. Yeah, [inaudible 00:08:25], if
you're busy, you said it more succinctly. I've
been doing this for a while now and you said
it way more succinctly than I can. Just to
back up for a little bit, I think one of
the data points I always start with when
I present the research on The JOLT Effect
is that our analysis showed that anywhere
between 40 and 60% of the average salesperson's
qualified pipelines, these aren't just leads,
sometimes bad leads that are thrown over to us by
marketing, these are qualified opportunities.
These are people we've met with, customers
we've pursued, we've engaged, they're in
the sales process, 40 to 60% of them will be
ultimately marked as closed loss, no decision.
That's actually, I think that number is actually
on the rise, especially in places like SaaS and
the broader tech sector over the past year and
a half, but that's a really painful thing.
If you think about as a salesperson, that for
46% of your deals, you're going to spend a lot of
time, energy, resources, a lot of your company's
money and their time and resources pursuing
these opportunities where you eventually just get
ghosted and you don't really know what happened,
just like the customer, the opportunity evaporated
on you, they ghosted you, they want radio silent.
You don't really know what happened there.
We decided to take this two and a half million
sales call dataset, which you could have
used to answer lots of different questions,
but we were really fascinated by this
question, maybe two, two questions. One is
why do customers make no decision? Because you
understand it's frustrating as a salesperson,
but it's also puzzling for customers to do that.
They go through the entire process to evaluate
a solution, and many of those customers
say, "Yeah, I want to buy," and then they
ghost to the salesperson and it's so puzzling.
Why would they waste their own time evaluating a
solution than doing nothing? Then, the more
important question is probably what are the
very best salespeople do differently? What have
they figured out to avoid that outcome?
Cool, and we're going to talk about that
latter part to help people understand why,
because it sounds like, okay, I guess this
happens, but help people understand why this
happens. Why are people nervous to make a
mistake and not make a decision at all?
Let me maybe take us a step back, Lenny. There was
a reason we actually even asked that question that
you just asked, and the reason was this, when
we looked at sales calls, if you think of the
typical sales process or buying journey, it kind
of moves through three phases. Phase number one,
is the customer in their status quo. It's
what they do today. They use your competitor's
product. Maybe they do use a homegrown solution,
maybe they never saw a need for a solution like
yours, but that's their current state.
Step two is we've got to get them to agree
that the current state is no longer acceptable and
they've got to move forward in a new and different
way. We call that agreement on a vision. We've got
to get their intent to move forward and to change,
and that step number three is you got to get them
to buy something. That's the action step where
they execute the docuSign, they sign on the line
that is dotted and they send the contract back.
It's a simple three step process, and what we
found in our analysis is one of the big places
where a lot of deals fall out of that process
is between intent and action. It's after the
point where the customer says, "Yeah, Lenny, this
sounds great. I'm sold. Let's talk." But before
the point where that actually deal gets sold, a
lot of deals kind of go sideways in that moment
and the way this comes across in sales calls is
that customers start, if you will, relitigating
concerns that they had asked and you thought you'd
address much earlier, like what might go wrong
and is this really the right answer for us?
These are things that are puzzling to salespeople
because it feels like this thing is slipping
through my fingers right before my eyes. I thought
we had this closed. I thought you said you want to
move forward and now you're asking questions that
we addressed three months ago, what's going on?
What salespeople tend to do, because they've grown
up in a world where they've been told, the only
reason the customer hesitates is because you
haven't put to bed their status quo bias. We all
know, we're all human beings, not just customers,
but perhaps especially customers, are guilty
of status quo bias, meaning we are prone to
laziness and doing nothing because it's easier,
it's inertia. It's easier to just keep doing
more of the same than to change behavior.
Change is really hard and salespeople have
been taught that the status quo is their biggest
competitor, and if the customer is starting to
get cold feet, it's because they still think
either what they're doing today is good enough,
what you are proposing is not a compelling enough
reason to change, or maybe it's just not a top
priority for them or their organization.
It's got to be one of those reasons.
What salespeople have been armed to do is go
out and dial up the FOMO and make the customer
sweat a little bit. The first thing they do is
they say, "Lenny, remember the demos and the
proof of concept trial, how excited you were and
those benefits, you got to pay for it. You're not
going to get all those great benefits for your
organization unless you sign the agreement."
If that doesn't work, I'll try to kind of
scare you into action by dialing up the fear,
uncertainty and doubt and saying, "Lenny, you
told me about these problems in your business.
You guys are really struggling right now. By the
way, did I mentioned, we're working with all of
your competitors and they're seeing tremendous
benefits from our product and you're going to be
left in the dust and those problems you brought up
with me, they're not going to solve themselves."
I'm trying to create that burning platform a
little bit for the customer and get them to
realize the cost of their inaction.
There is a cost of doing nothing,
and if those two things don't work, what most
salespeople go to is the 10% discount that's
only good this quarter. It's like the price
driven urgency. Maybe this will be the thing
you need to just get you over the finish line.
What we were so surprised by which led us to the
question you asked, Lenny, was that 87% of the
time when salespeople do that dial up the FOMO
in those moments, especially with a customer
who says that they're ready to move forward,
but they start to backpedal and waffle and waiver
and become hesitant dialing up the FOMO backfires
87% of the time. In other words, it increases
the odds, the deal will be lost to no decision.
If it weren't for that finding, we never
would've even bothered asking the question
about why do people end up, why do we lose deals
to no decision, why do customers make no decision,
but this was really puzzling because it flew in
the face of everything we talked about, including
in Challenger, to be totally candid. We talked
about how challengers are exceptional at breaking
the customer's status quo bias by showing them the
pain of same is worse than the pain of change.
Again, overcoming that inertia, that not just
individuals but organizations suffer from.
Challengers are really good at that. Here, we
see that the tactics that you might associate
with challenging actually kind of backfire,
which was, as the author of The Challenger,
still a little bit troubling to
me, but we'll come back to that,
but I think what we realized was we got it
right, but we got it kind of half right.
We went into the data and we asked a slightly
different question, which is why are deals lost
in no decision? What drives that? We found that
actually, there are a lot of deals that are lost
because the customer does actually prefer their
status quo. That is status quo bias. They believe
what they're going to say is good enough, what
you're talking about, it's not a compelling enough
reason to change or this is not a top priority.
Those are all status quo preference reasons,
but it turns out those are only 44% of the no
decision losses, 56% of no decision losses are
customers who want to buy but can't buy because
they're stuck in this no man's land of indecision,
and that indecision itself stems from their fear
of failure, which you put your finger on earlier,
and this is the part I found so fascinating,
so we dug into the psych research. We read
probably 30 years of cognitive psychology journal
articles, many of them from Dutch universities,
which I find very interesting, but
a fairly very big into this stuff.
A lot of the Kahneman and Tversky work around loss
aversion and prospect theory, et cetera, and one
of the big findings we came across is that
there's actually a more powerful human bias,
even more powerful than status quo bias that
rears its ugly head and causes indecision,
and that is called the omission bias.
The omission bias is, if you get down to it,
is the fact that people don't want to be blamed
for making decisions that lead to a loss. In the
human mind, there are two types of loss that we
think about. We all like to avoid loss, but not
all loss is created equal. There are losses that
happen when we do nothing, and then there are
losses that happened because we did something.
We made a decision, we picked a vendor, we
executed a contract, and then something bad
happened. It turns out that in the human mind,
people are okay with missing out. They are
not okay with messing up and being blamed,
and this is really powerful. It's even more
powerful than status quo bias, as I said.
The shorthand for salespeople is this, dialing up
the FOMO can be very effective to overcome status
quo bias, but knowing that every human being,
including all of your customers, who I include
in that definition of human beings are definitely
afraid of being personally blamed if things go
wrong. The FOMU actually matters more than the
FOMO. The FOMU is the fear of messing up or in
the not safe for work version of your podcast, I'd
say FOFU, but your listeners can figure out what
that stands for on their own, but this is really
powerful for salespeople, right to understand.
Look, if you are trying to scare your customer
into action, you're going to miss out on these
benefits. You're going to miss out on solving
these problems. You're just going to pay more
later if you don't say yes now. What you're
really doing is using scare tactics, but you're
trying to scare somebody who's already afraid.
The problem is they're not afraid of the thing
you think they're afraid of. They're not afraid
of missing out, they're afraid of messing up.
We've got to address that as salespeople. We've
got to help instill the confidence in the customer
that you're making a great decision. I've got
your back. You're going to look like a hero,
not like a fool and that's really what
The JOLT Effect is about. It's about
how the very best salespeople execute that.
It wasn't that we're wrong with Challenger,
it's just the story was kind of incomplete.
You got to break status quo bias. If you don't
do that, you're never going to have an indecision
problem, but even once you overcome the customer's
indifference and their status quo bias, you got to
second battle you've got to fight, which is you've
got to instill the confidence and make them feel
good about this. Frankly, leap of faith they're
about to take and their fear, you got to deal with
the fear that if something goes wrong, they're
worried that they're going to be blamed for it.
We're going to talk about this method you
developed for how to actually do all the things
you're talking about, but first, to make this even
more real, what I'm thinking about is an example.
Is a good example, maybe a CRM, like a better CRM
product, say someone has Salesforce installed and
now they're like, maybe there's probably something
better out there we should probably evaluate.
Then, I'm thinking from the perspective of a
startup trying to build a better CRM. There's
always this advice, you have to be 10 times
better for anyone to pay any attention. I think
that feeds into exactly what you're showing is
it needs to be so much better that this fear is
reduced. Can you just talk about maybe an example,
whether it's that one or a different
one to make this more concrete?
We encountered a ton of examples. It's so
interesting you mentioned startups and I think
sometimes, I was actually with a big enterprise
software company and I think when, and I presented
this research to some of their sales leaders and
one of the folks in the room said, "I'm really
glad we are who we are, that we are the 800-pound
gorilla, especially in a market like we're in
right now," because as the old adage goes, it
wasn't IBM, but the old adage is that nobody
ever got fired for buying from IBM, right?
This company is like the IBM of their space.
They're the 800-pound gorilla. They've got the
brand strength, the reputation, they're the safe
choice. This team felt kind of comfortable or
comforted, I should say by that fact, especially
in a tight environment where it's a battle for
deals and for mindshare and for wins out there
in the market right now, especially in tech.
What I said is you've got to remember though,
that may be true, and I would argue, and I
think you're right, that for a startup, yeah,
you've got to be 10 times better to get that
mind share. It may be even better than that
to get somebody to take a leap of faith with
you. There is inherent risk in going with the
unproven player, but I cautioned these folks and
I said, "Now, remember, what are the things that
drive fear of failure and indecision?"
It turns out there are three big ones. The
first one is have I made the right choice?
I know I want to work with this vendor,
but did I configure the solution of the proposal
the right way, the right contract length,
the right implementation, the right used cases,
the right integrations, all that professional
services or DIY, all those big questions.
The second thing that customers worry about
in their second fear of failure is that they're
going to learn something after the contract is
signed that's going to make the decision look
like not such a great decision. I'll give you
a really specific example about this. I spoke to a
tech company not too long ago, maybe a month ago,
and they landed their biggest deal of their
existence. It was an early stage company,
seven-figure deal, game changer for this
organization. Then, they beat out some big
established competitors. This is a huge win.
They went out. They celebrated. It was just
totally amazing, their first big enterprise
win and their first seven-figure deal and their
first victory against some of these incumbents.
Unfortunately, about two weeks after they won
this deal, the new Gartner Magic Quadrant on their
space came out and they were shown to be kind of,
eh, right? They weren't the leader, but
they were sort of middle of the pack.
All of a sudden, the client who signed the
agreement, the CTO just got crap rained
from everybody saying, "Did you see the Gartner
Magic Quadrant? It looks like the company we just
plunked down seven figures with was kind of seen
as so-so by the Gartner analyst? Have we talked
to these guys and those guys and why aren't we
going with the leaders," and blah, blah, blah?
They ended up backing out of the contract because
the CTO said, "I'm spending every day talking to
all the other key stakeholders trying to convince
them that yes, we did all of our due diligence,
but life is too short and we're probably going to
end up going with one of the big players. We're
sorry. I mean, that's such a painful story,
but that's the customer is like they're going
to keep doing research because they don't
want to be surprised when some new piece of
information comes to light. It's the second
big fear of failure driver or failure driver.
The third one is that the customers are worried
they're just not going to see the ROI. They're
not going to get the full benefits. You might
project for them a 5X improvement in sales
productivity. What if it comes in at two or three
X and my name's on the agreement and the CFO comes
asking why we didn't get the benefits we thought?
In today's environment, that's not just egg on
your face, you could get fired for that stuff.
This is the client who's really looking for that
vendor to have their back and to assure them that
they're going to see the benefits that are being
projected and promised through the sale. What
I said to this big enterprise tech company was,
"Look, you guys, yes, it's tough to be a
startup right now, early stage company,
there's a lot of risks there, but who's offering
more choices, them or you guys? You guys have
a partner ecosystem. You have 20 different
cloud products. You bought seven companies
in the past three years. You have a cornucopia
of options, which adds to the buyer's anxiety
that they haven't chosen the right thing.
Second, do you think there's more written about
you guys or about them? You could fill a football
stadium with all the coverage on you guys. I mean,
everybody's got an opinion about you because you
are the 800-pound gorilla and everybody's worked
with you before and they have opinions, good and
bad, and people want to leave no stone unturned.
Then, lastly, it turns out you guys are a lot
more expensive because you're trying to move
from selling simple products like these
ankle biters out there, these startups
into selling big enterprise solutions. You
guys are selling not seven-figure deals,
eight-figure deals, nine-figure deals to your
customers. That increases the customer's anxiety
that I really have to see return on this.
You, in many respects, are getting whipsawed
by these factors in a way that the startups are
not because they don't have as many choices.
There's not as much coverage about that. The
investment is lower, and so there's a little
bit less risk for the customer. You guys aren't
immune just because you're the big brand."
You're doing a great job making it clear why
it's so nerve-racking to buying new software.
There's just so many things that could hurt
you as a person at a company. April Dunford,
I think this is barred from your language that she
talks about how it's actually more stressful these
days to buy software than to sell software because
of all these things you've talked about.
Yeah, I think she's on point on that one. I
mean, your customers are, yeah, they're really,
really afraid of this not panning out. It was so
interesting, and salespeople can think of so many
different occasions where the purchase buying your
product, just made all the sense in the world for
the customer, it would make things so much better.
It would solve such big problems for them.
They're so dissatisfied with their
current approach. It's just a no-brainer,
and the customer will look at that and they
will agree with you and they still won't make
a decision because of the what-ifs, right?
Yeah. This is got to be very frustrating for
founders to listen to and be like, "Come on,
our product is so much better. What are you
doing?" But I think this explains a lot of
the challenges they're probably having.
This episode is brought to you by Heap,
the product analytics solution that shows
you everything users do on your digital product,
website, mobile product or other digital surfaces.
We all know a great digital experience when we
see it. It's intuitive. It anticipates your needs,
and it makes it easy for you to do your job. If
you're trying to build that kind of experience
for your users, you need up-to-date,
reliable information about what your
users do in your product and why they do it.
Want to know how your users behave across
platforms, what keeps them coming back, what
they're doing that you're not even aware of? Well,
I have some great news for you, Heap captures
all of this user activity for you automatically
and then gives you definitive answers to all
your questions about user behavior in seconds,
not weeks. With Heap, it's easy to prioritize
the product investments that improve conversion,
engagement and retention. Visit
heap.io/lenny to get started
with a demo. That's H-E-A-O.io/lenny.
It's a great segue to talking about how to
actually leverage these insights to improve your
sales process. You have something, I think you
call it the JOLT method?
Yes. Yeah.
Awesome. Let's get into it.
The JOLT, it's an acronym. It just
so happened it worked out that way, but I like
it because it's memorable, but it also speaks to
what's happening. Our customers' stuck in their
indecisive state. They want to buy from us,
but they just can't because worried about what
might go wrong. You got to JOLT them forward. We
got to JOLT them into action.
Beautiful.
How do we do it? The first thing is we've
got to judge their level of indecision,
we've got to figure out what we're dealing
with. The second thing is we've got to offer
a recommendation. The third thing is we've got
to get them to stop doing endless research and
start trusting us and limiting, we call limit the
exploration, and the T is we've got to the derisk
the deal. We've got to take some risk off the
table, and we establish that safety net for the
customer so they feel like we've got their back.
Maybe we talk about each of those. I'll start with
the J because it's first, but also I think the
way, while it's kind of linear, I would encourage
listeners don't think about this as a process
where it's like I do step one, two, three, four,
J-O-L-T. Think of it as it starts with the J,
and the J tells you what the next step is. Is it
the T? Is it the L? Is it the O? Is it the O, and
then we got to deal with the T. Then, we got to go
back to the O because it comes up again.
Think of it as sort of the dividing rod. How do we
figure out what's got the customer nervous? This
is a really, really, really tricky thing because,
and I've likened indecision to the carbon monoxide
poisoning of sales. It's everywhere, but it's
odorless, it's tasteless, but you need a carbon
monoxide detector, and that's what the J is.
How do we get fear of failure on the table?
The problem with this is that, and I think
most of your listeners will be familiar with this,
everybody, especially customers suffers and senior
executives especially, especially, suffer
from what's called the Dunning-Kruger effect,
which is they think they're better at things
than they really are and decisiveness is one
of those things that buyers will think they
will say they think they're decisive.
In fact, if you surveyed your customers, not that
they recommend this, and you add 100 of them,
if they consider themselves to be decisive folks,
like 99 out of 100 will say, "Absolutely, yes,
I make the tough calls. I manage from the gut. I
live on the edge as an executive making those big
calls," but the research tells a very different
story. It turns out that 87% of buyers in our two
and a half million sales calls we studied, either
showed moderate or high levels of indecision.
The folks who are not worried about fear or
failure were 13%. Yeah, those people do exist.
By the way, if you find one of those people,
you should sell them everything as soon as
possible because they're making the decision quite
literally on the dollars and cents and the ROI and
whether it makes sense for their business. It's
a rational decision for them, but for the rest,
they're dealing with a lot of emotion, and that
emotion is all wrapped up with fear of failure.
What's so tough about this is that it's not just
Dunning-Kruger like we think we're more decisive
than we really are, even if your customer knows
that they're indecisive or they're worried about
failing or how their boss is going to perceive
them, if this purchase doesn't pan out, they don't
like talking about it because it's embarrassing.
They don't want to talk about like, "God, I
got to tell you this better pay off because if it
doesn't, I'm already on thin ice with my boss. She
doesn't like me already. This is going to be the
last straw." Nobody's going to say that stuff.
How do we get on the table? One of the things we
don't think works particularly well are classic
open-ended questions like, "Lenny, do you
find when you go to the Cheesecake factory,
do you leave satisfied or hungry because
you can't decide what to order?" I guess,
it's not great approaches with customers, you'll
end the sale pretty quickly because again,
your customers find that kind of offensive. They'd
like to think of themselves as decisive people.
We found a technique, this is actually not in
the book, we found it after we wrote the book,
called pings and echoes that high performers use.
Think of the way a surface ship might detect a
submarine in the water using sonar. They send a
ping out into the water and they're listening,
if you will, using sonar for the reflection
back and the reflection tells them, is it a
friendly submarine, an enemy submarine? Is it
just a whale? Is it heading towards us? Away
from us? At what speed are they about
to torpedo us? All that good stuff.
We want to do the same thing in sales. The
way this works is that a salesperson will
try to articulate but in a non, not to out the
customer, but to get confirmation or refutation,
if you will, that what they've articulated
is actually a concern for their buyer.
Hypothetically, let's imagine we're talking
about a purchase and we've had a lot of great
conversations. I've shown you a lot of demos.
You guys have liked everything we've shown.
We showed you partner options. We showed you
different configurations. We did POC over here.
We did a pilot over there. You guys are just
eating it all up, but I'm kind of getting the
sneaking feeling that you guys actually don't
know what you want and we've shown you a lot
and we've probably made that problem worse.
What I might say to you is, "Lenny, I'm just
curious if we could calibrate here for just a
moment, and there's a reason I'm asking this,
which is a lot of the customers at this
point in our process of working together,
they get almost overwhelmed with all the options,
and look, I probably made this worse. We're very
proud of what we do. I want to show you, paint
the art of the possible, but I also know if we're
going to do business together, you told me right
away budgets are limited and you can't have it
all. You've got to decide what's nice to happen
and what's need to happen. I'm just curious,
are you and your team clear on what
would be in and out of the proposal?"
What's going to happen is one of two things, one
you might say, or a few things, you might say,
"You know what? No, we don't know and we have
liked everything you've shown us, but as you said,
we can't have it all. So, we'd be really curious
to know what do other companies like us start
with? How do we get going? What are the things we
can do without and we can maybe add later on down
the road," or you might get the customer says,
"No, no, no, we were just being polite. There's a
lot of stuff you showed us that we're not actually
that interested in. It's cool, but it's just not
for us. We are very clear on what we want.
So, let me share that with you now. However,
what I'm really concerned about is once we get
this kind of specked out and configured and
priced, I'm going to take it to the CFO because
I've got to get her approval on this and I can't
build our business case on the claim you guys
make about improving sales productivity by 10%
because she'll laugh me out of her office.
Help me get grounded in what's a believable
outcome for us so that I can sell it and I can
be confident we're going to actually hit it."
Again, it's not designed to embarrass the
customer, it's designed to get this on the
table so it can be recognized and dealt with and
contextualized. You're totally normal. Everybody
struggles with this. There's a lot of stuff we
throw in front of people and it ends up doing
some harm. They don't know what to pick.
Let me be of service and value to you.
That's the first thing that we point
to and that's going to tell us, okay,
is it a choice problem? They're overwhelmed. They
don't know what to choose, like that example we
just used. Is it that they're just doing endless
research and they feel like they haven't really
come down the learning curve yet around this
purchase or is it, no, I don't actually know
that we're going to get what we're paying
for here and we screw this stuff up every
day of the week at twice a Sunday and I don't
think it's going to be any different and then
I'm going to get blamed, so help me manage the
downside risk, but it tells us kind of where to
go next on that journey, if that makes sense.
Yeah. Awesome. The advice there is basically get a
sense of how clear they are internally on knowing
exactly what they want that'll help them make a
decision. There's kind of this moment of, okay,
let's just help me understand the question, the
way you phrased it, are you and your team clear
on what would be in or out of this proposal?
Yeah. That's just a one example. That's if I
hypothesize that you're really struggling with
what to choose. Now, my hypothesis might
be, you know what you want. You've done
plenty of research, but you're really worried
about the ROI and you're just worried you just
aren't going to be able to accomplish that.
That ping might sound very different. It might be
we've been having a discussion about, you've been
asking for multiple terms of the ROI calculation
and changing parameters and really trying to make
it bulletproof, but a lot of customers struggle
with that a little bit because that's a big thing.
You're putting your name against that. Maybe we
should have a conversation about whether that's a
concern for you. Is there a believability gap? Is
there an execution gap you're worried
about on your side or on our side?
Let's have a conversation about that so I
can set the proper expectations so you feel
really confident going to the CFO and lobbying for
investment here. That ping could go in, but it's
based on what I think is holding you up.
Got it. It's just like at this point,
many customers have this question...
Yes. Yeah.
... and that maybe comes from the thing that
you think is probably blocking them.
Yeah, I think that's perfect language.
At this point, most customers like you,
are thinking about this or they're worried about
that, or they're getting a little anxious about
this. Let's have a conversation about it.
Awesome. Okay, cool. Let's go to step two,
offering your recommendation.
Sure. Oh yeah. This was right with that example
we talked about before. Options are really a
double-edged sword. What we know from the research
is that options are great early on. If you're
meeting at the trade show and the customer's
swinging by your booth or you're doing a first
demo or first, let a thousand flowers bloom,
but if you want the customer to actually make a
decision, you've got to get the weed whacker out
and call it down to a manageable set of choices.
The science is very clear on this, that too many
choices at some point will overwhelm the customer
and it leads to a lot of bad outcomes. It leads to
the customer not making a decision at all
because they don't want to make the wrong
decision. I don't want to work with you, but you
put so many options in front of us. I don't want
to be blamed if I choose the wrong one and it
leads to things like post-decision dysfunction,
which is, I thought I made the right decisions,
but now I'm learning more and people are asking
hard questions and maybe I need to go revisit
this. Hey, Lenny, we're going to have to scrap
that agreement and start over because I
don't think we can figure this right way.
We have to, there's a time and place to offer
options, and there's a time and place to narrow
choices up. The simple guidance here for
salespeople is that you've got to shift
your posture from asking the customer what
they want and just diagnosing their needs,
to actually recommending to them what they
should do. Salespeople get a little bit
anxious about this, I find, because they don't
want to be seen as like, I told you to do A,
but you're like, I don't want to do that. I want
to do B and now I feel like we're at odds.
They worry about that. Salespeople have grown up
in this world that it's the customer's choice. The
customers always right, let me just guide them,
but they're the ones should make this decision,
but sometimes the customer can't and they
don't know enough about these decisions.
We know the stuff because we eat, sleep,
and breathe it every day as salespeople.
We work in this industry, they don't.
We are in a much better position to be
able to guide them toward, you know
what? You don't really need X, Y,
and Z. You can leave that out of the proposal.
Companies like you, they get started in this
way. Let me put three options in front of you.
I would go with the middle one because I really
think that's going to be the best for you in the
first year, and then we can expand from there.
Here's an analogy, I'll often tell people to
think about the last time they went to a fancy
restaurant and they looked at a menu with some
expensive entrees and everything looked delicious,
but they didn't know what to order, so you
asked the wait person what they recommend.
How helpful is it if that wait person says
to you, "Well, what are you in the mood
to eat tonight?" It's no help at all, right?
You're no closer to a decision. They basically
just dump the problem back on your lap.
But what a great way people do is they say,
"If you want my opinion, I love this dish and
I'd probably say it's our most popular. We
sell out of it every night. We've still got it.
So you're in luck. It's a lot of food though,
it's a big portion. If you're in the mood for
something lighter, there's a vegetarian option.
It doesn't get as much play on Yelp, but I love
this one. It's absolutely delicious. It's one
of our kind of dark horse favorites, if you
will, but remember, everything we make here
is delicious. If you don't like those choices,
you're not going to go wrong with any of them,
but those are just my favorites."
Now, what happens in that moment is
what psychologists call the delegation
effect, which is rather than the burden
of a bad decision being solely on the shoulders
of the decider, that burden is now shared. Now,
think about it, if you order the dish the
wait person recommended and you don't like it,
whose fault is it? Well, technically it's your
fault because you ordered it, but it's also kind
of their fault because they recommended it.
You feel like there's some safety in getting
that recommendation, that endorsement. It's a
really simple example, but it works in complex
sales as well. Customers are looking for somebody
to share in the risk and the burden of making a
bad decision and having that partner who's
guiding them toward what they should care
about and what they shouldn't care about, what
they should consider and what they should take
out of the proposal, is actually very reassuring
and comforting them and it increases the odds
of getting some kind of decision from them.
Amazing. This is a great segue to The Challenger
Sale, which we're going to talk about, but let's
get through the last two steps and then we'll talk
about The Challenger Sale, which is basically
this on steroids, this idea on steroids.
The last two, so L is about this customer
who's doing endless amounts of research. Every
salesperson has seen this customer, they're
never happy with the number of reference
calls or the amount of research they've
done. They want to talk to more and more
people. They're just in information overload
mode and/or what we might call analysis paralysis
mode because at some point, they're never
satisfied with, they always feel like all
the answers will be in the next white paper
they read or the next reference call they do,
or the next person on LinkedIn they talk to.
What salespeople need to do to stop that, you
got to understand I think why customers do that.
They don't want to be surprised. That is the main
reason, but they also don't trust the salesperson
to be forthcoming. They believe the salesperson
is paid to sell them more than they need, to
put one over on them, hide the dirty laundry,
only talk about the things that work in the
platform, not the things that don't work.
You're not going to get introduce any of
the customers who hate you. You're only
going to introduce the customers who love
you, and we know we're going to say great
things about us. That's what the customer thinks.
That is what is in the customer's mind. You've
got to actually shift, get the customer to stop
trying to be an expert and start trusting you as
an expert. There are two keys to that.
The first one is you've got to establish
some trust. I know that sounds like a
platitude, but we found in the analysis,
there are specific things that great salespeople
do very early on. They are brutally transparent
with customers about like, "Hey, I know you were
interested in this capability. I got to be honest,
we get mixed reviews on that. It's kind of an
early capability for us. We're still trying to
iron out the kinks," or "I know you are interested
in this used case, but I have to be honest, we're
actually not the best in the market at that. Our
competitors much better at that than we are."
These kinds of moments show the customer that
you're not here to put one over on them. You're
here to get them to a great decision. It kind
of makes no difference to the salesperson,
whether the customer buys from them, doesn't
buy from them, it buys from a competitor. You
just want to help them get to a great decision.
That's step number one is building that trust.
Step number two is you got to demonstrate
some expertise. What we see in so many
sales interactions, especially in tech, is
that salespeople will show up with the clown
car of experts, the subject matter experts,
the solutions engineers, the product people,
the executive sponsors, and then they
will just punt to these people.
What happens in that moment is dangerous for
the salesperson. The customer, it sounds like
they're loving it, right? They're loving that. I'm
talking to the people who really know their stuff,
but what's also happening in that moment is
the salesperson is actively getting delegated
down to the person they sound like. If they
don't sound like any more than a glorified
emcee or a coordinator, then that's kind of
all the customer will perceive them as.
What right or ability would you have to guide the
customer on what to choose if you've offered no
value or expertise? You don't have to be as deep
as the product people. You're not going to be,
you're a salesperson, you're not a product person,
but you do have to be deeper on than the customer,
and you do have to demonstrate that
expertise. Those are the keys, again,
the customer to stop trying to be an expert
and start trusting you as their expert.
Then, the T is taking risk off the table. Two
keys to doing that, I think the first one happens
really early actually, and that is resetting the
customer's expectations. Average salespeople love
when they get an inbound lead from a customer who
says, "Hey, I saw that case study on your website
of the customer who got the 10X improvement in
sales productivity, and we want that. That sounds
great." That company's in our industry, amazing.
That's a slam dunk business case for us.
The average salesperson's thinking like,
"If you're excited about that, I'm not
going to talk you out of it because that means
you're going to be excited to take in the CFO and
excited to sign the agreement and get going."
What great salespeople do though is they know
that while they'll stand by those claims, those
case studies, those proof points, they try to kind
of under-promise and over-deliver and they might
say something along the lines of, "You know Lenny,
absolutely, that is a great case. I was involved
in that sale, but what we also need to understand
is everything went perfectly. They resourced
it to the hilt. They had no integration issues,
no hiccups. It was beautiful and seamless. I
don't think you and I can think of many technology
implementations that happened that way.
What I'd rather we do is build your
business case around a 5X improvement in sales
productivity because we see that at least that,
in 100% of our implementations. Then, let's
set up to over-deliver against that because
I think we're going to do better than that
based on what I know about your organization,
easily 6, 7, 8, 9%, maybe even 10, but we don't
want you to just walking in and promising 10X
improvement sales productivity. If we finish
the year and we're at 7X, if the CFO is now
asking her questions when in absolute terms,
she should be thrilled with 7X, right? Let's
make sure we set ourselves up for success."
The other thing you've got to do though is
establish some safety net options. There are lots
of different shapes and forms. These can take
everything from before the deal is closed, pulling
the implementation team onto the call, or the
customer success team or the account management
team so we can start roadmapping, "Hey, as soon
as we get signature, here's how we're going to
spend our next six months together to make sure
you guys are getting all the value you expect, if
not more. Here's what we got to do. Here are the
stage gates, here are the owners, here are
the metrics we're going to monitor. Here's how
often we're going to connect with each other."
Instills a lot of confidence with the customer
because it feels like, "Oh, you guys have done
this before, right? You've been there, you've
done that. You've helped other customers like me
get value." Everything from that kind of stuff
to adding in professional services support,
especially like you think about a tech purchase.
I'm not saying give it away for free, but you
will find that high-performing salespeople
will also add on professional services,
but it is not just because selling more,
which they are because they're high-performing
salespeople. It's the way they position that.
They usually position it as an insurance policy.
"Hey, I know you guys want to DIY this. This is
one of the great things about our solution. You
totally can. You got all the training support,
all the videos, you got all the enablement content
you need, but I know this is a big priority
for you, and I think it would be really smart to
carve out a slug of professional services hours
that way our A team is lined up in case anything
slips and if it does, we get you back up on track
because the last thing we want is for you guys
to be upset that you're losing ground and you're
not going to deliver on the outcomes that you
promised to your boss. So, let's set that up."
There's lots of different ways we can create
those opt out clauses in some industries are an
option. Not very common in B2B, but in some
cases, you can offer those or specialized
contract carve outs for instance. There's lots
of different things we can do to create that
safety net where the customer doesn't feel like
they're jumping out of an airplane by themselves,
but you are the tandem skydiving instructor that's
going to guide them safely to the ground.
Amazing. All of this, especially this last
step, is coming from, they're probably not
going to decide on anything that that's
what you're fighting is help them...
That's right. That's right.
... be less worried about messing up.
Yeah, that's right.
I especially love this point about under
promising and over delivering because so much of,
and most of this is B2B SaaS software that you're
working with, right? Like B2B SaaS companies?
Our dataset cut across, I think that it might just
be that SaaS is the place where we're seeing the
most indecision these days, but it's not suggest
it's kind of an easy target, but it is rife within
indecision these days, and unfortunately I think
it's also rife with a lot of these missteps that
salespeople make that actually make things worse,
but we had data from manufacturing firms,
services businesses that cut across. This was
prevalent and consistent across industries.
With the under promising and over delivering,
I think that's especially powerful for where
most companies want to get to is net revenue
retention being higher than 100% where you can
expand larger within the org and it makes sense
to help them set up base, feel like, wow, this
is so much better than we even thought it was
going to be, versus...
Absolutely. Yeah.
... it's not delivering what we thought.
Amazing. Okay. Any last piece of wisdom to
leave listeners with around The JOLT Effect
before we move on to The Challenger Sale?
The only thing I would suggest is that for
anybody, I mean, I think just do it is this,
is that you should hit the pause button when the
customer, because the customers, we all know,
are going to get cold feet, often late stage,
and it can be very frustrating. The knee jerk
reaction for almost every salesperson
out there, this happened in our analysis,
75% of salespeople we studied, would
immediately go out to dialing up the FOMO.
Go back to doing that. You're not going to
get these benefits. You're going to be stuck
in this terrible state of affairs you're in
right now. Dial up the cost of inaction, or
let's try to use some price base or other delivery
window-based urgency driver to get the customer
to move forward. But just remember that if the
customer's already convinced that the status quo
is suboptimal, and you've already got the intent
that basically again, you're using fear on top of
a customer, selling into a customer who's already
afraid and you're actually making it worse.
Hitting the pause button and just reflecting
a little bit on what's really going on here.
Is it that they're indifferent
or is it that they're indecisive?
Those are actually two very different things.
Amazing. I know you have a meeting in 10 minutes,
so this is going to be the most action-packed,
high-density podcast episode we've done. We've got
10 minutes talk about Challenger Sale.
Sure.
First of all, how many copies of this
book have you sold at this point?
I think it's about a million.
Holy moly.
Yeah.
That's insane.
That's a lot, yeah.
Okay, so it's a legendary
book in the world of sales. I imagine many people
have heard of it, at least some people know the
teachings. Let's spend a little time there. If
I were to summarize the big insight of the book,
basically it's the best salespeople challenge
their prospects thinking and teach them about the
market and what they should be doing versus
just helping them get what they want.
Yeah, very well said. I think one of, just
like the FOMO, FOMU kind of shorthand,
here's a shorthand I'd give to salespeople
is most salespeople are trying to figure
out what's keeping the customer up at
night, right? It's classic solution
selling needs, diagnosis, et cetera.
The Challenger approach is about showing
the customer what should be keeping them up at
night. What is the thing you know that they need
to know? What is the way that other customers
are using your solution to generate returns
and benefit for their organization? What's
the risk that they don't know about but you
do because by the way, you're going to talk to
10 times more customers, or I say you're going
to talk to 10 of that customer in a week or 10
times more than a week than they will all year.
You are a window into the outside world for them,
and that's what challengers really understand.
It's not free consulting though, because if
you remember from the Challenger Sale, it's
not just about bringing these provocative ideas
that reframe the customer's understanding of the
world. It's about leading to your unique benefits.
What you're really trying to do is create a fire
and then be the only person in town who sells
the fire extinguisher that'll put it out.
Is there an example you could share
of a Challenger sale type of sale?
Yeah, we wrote a sequel to The Challenger Sale
called The Challenger Customer. In that book,
we talk about a case from a company called
Dentsply. Dentsply, as the name would suggest,
manufactures or produces dental supplies,
right? They sell equipment and product
into dental practices and dental offices.
Years ago, Dentsply had developed, we all know,
I think your listeners can all relate to this,
when you go to the dentist and the hygienist
is polishing your teeth or they're using the water
pick, or unfortunately, maybe the dentist is using
the drill. That wand has a very heavy power cord
that's attached to it and it's attached to this
power base and that it feeds water through there
and electrical current and all those things.
Dentsply had developed the world's first
lightweight, ergonomic, cordless wand
that drill bits could be attached to cleaning,
implements, et cetera and it was a total
breakthrough. Actually, when they unveiled it
was pretty interesting, they gave, you remember
the scene in Pulp Fiction where they opened the
briefcase and then it emanates like a light emits
from it. They gave all their salespeople
like this little aluminum briefcase thing
with this eggshell foam and a wand in there.
I can't remember what it's called. Let's call
it the XP-9000 Wand, but it had one demo
wand in there and they would go around to
dental offices and be like, "Ah." It was lit,
literally, it had blue lighting inside...
Wow.
... and it was really cool, the reveal and
they'd take it out and they give it to the dentist
or the head of the dental office and they would
hold it and be like, "What? It's so much lighter
and it's ergonomic and this thing is cordless?
It's amazing. It's a revolution." Then, the
first thing they would ask is, "How much is it?"
When they told them it costs like three times more
than the current old-fashioned wands they're using
with the heavy cord, they would gently put it
back in the briefcase, close the briefcase,
say, "Can you give me a price on new drill bits
or new like polishing attachments?" They couldn't
get anybody to want to pay for this thing that
was much more expensive than the old one.
They did a lot of work and they figured out, they
knew that this was unique. They knew this was a
unique product. Nobody else in the market made
this. They're the only supplier who had figured
this out, total innovation, but they hadn't given
the customer reason to want to pay a premium
for that innovation until they figured out the
connection between the equipment that hygienists
use and absenteeism and workers' comp.
It turns out that one of the biggest
professions that where you get carpal tunnel
syndrome, shoulder and neck and lower back
injuries is being a dental hygienist.
The reason is that they're standing,
holding that heavy wand being dragged down by
that heavy cord at an awkward angle all day
long. That's why dental offices really struggle to
keep hygienists showing up, not calling in sick,
not out for months at a time for reconstructive
shoulder surgery, not with exorbitant health
benefits claims and workers' comp claims.
They came in and they revised their sales pitch.
Now, when they come into the dental office,
they sit down, they say, "I'd like to talk
to you about your hygienist workforce. Are you
guys seeing higher turnover? Have you seen any
absenteeism due to carpal or lower back or neck or
shoulder injuries? What are you guys doing about
that? What's the cost to your business?"
They get the dentist talking and the way
they start talking about, "It is not just
the insurance and workers' comp costs,
it's stuff like when my hygienists get injured,
and it's a repetitive motion business and job,
when they get injured and they call in sick,
I've got to reschedule all these cleanings and
all these appointments, and that's a bunch of
upset customers who end up then going to the
practice down the street or saying bad things
about me on Google reviews or what have you."
There's all kinds of ripple effects for the
dentist. The cost of losing a hygienist is
massive and the market for hiring them is
very, very tight. What Dentsply does is
start the conversation there, and then they say,
"One of the things that we figured out is that,
based on our own independent research, one of
the primary drivers of all these bad outcomes,
absenteeism, repetitive motion injuries, is
related to the equipment that hygienists use.
It's because they're holding that old fashioned
heavy wand, attached to that big heavy power
cable at an awkward angle doing repetitive
motion all day, but what if you could solve
for that? What if that was no longer a problem?"
The dentist says, "Well, how would you solve for
that? There's no other technology." "That's
what we got. We've had the same equipment for
30 years. Let me show you the new XP-9000.
We're world's first cordless, lightweight,
ergonomic drill. We can show you that it
is far preferred by hygienists because they
don't get injured as often because it's much
easier to hold and it doesn't put stress on
the joints and pinch points, if you will, where
hygienists tend to experience these injuries."
It's just a simple example, but you see, again,
they're still selling a fancy wand, but before,
they were leading with it. Let me show you
this and talk about the features, benefits,
and that led to how much does it cost. Now,
they're leading to it. They're starting with
an insight and giving the customer a reason
to care about solving this business problem,
and it turns out the only way to solve it is
buying this XP-9000 drill from Dentsply.
The key lesson from this book, and I know
we don't have a ton of time to dig into it,
is start with an insight they may not be aware of.
Give them a sense of where the things are going.
Help them learn something about the future and
the problems that they need to know about that
they may not be aware of, and then transition
to here is how we can solve that for you.
Yeah, that's exactly right. Make sure those
connections are really tight, right? Getting
this right starts with answering the question,
why should the customer buy from you instead
of your competitor? It's not because you're more
customer-centric or more innovative and possible
to prove your competitors claim the same
thing. It's not that you're the leading global
solution provider of whatever you sell.
It starts with the product or the way you
deliver the product or something about your
service delivery that only your company does
you are only capable of. Nobody else can touch
with the barge pole. Then, the second question is,
what would have to be true for the customer
to want to pay us for that, to pay a premium
ideally? That's the core components, if you
will, of a challenge or a conversation.
Amazing. Matt, I promised I let you out
here in time. Final questions, where can
folks find your books if they want to dig in
further and how can listeners be useful to you?
Well, thank you for the offer. I love being
connected with folks who heard me on shows like
this one. If you heard me on the podcast, "Hey,
I heard you on Lenny's Show," shoot me a LinkedIn
invite. I'm pretty active there, love being
connected with folks, so please reach out to me.
If you want to learn more about JOLT Effect,
so we do a lot of workshops and training around
that methodology, visit jolteffect.com. There's a
ton of, there's also a lot of free tools on there
that you can download that help you put some
of these concepts into practice with your sales
teams or if you're an individual seller.
Then, of course, the books are available
everywhere. Good books are sold, which I
think is on the internet these days.
Amazing. Matt, thank you
so much for being here.
Thanks, Lenny. It was a blast. Thank you.
Bye everyone. Thank you so much for listening.
If you found this valuable, you can
subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.