There's this whole concept of SAFe,
basically Scaled Agile, right?
Scaled Agile Framework came out of the desire to
figure out how do we scale Scrum and different
processes. I do not recommend using SAFe. Every
single person I have talked to who likes SAFe,
found success with SAFe, they ended up ripping
it up and making it into something else.
You've been up close and personal with a lot
of companies working with product owners,
Scaled Agile, and all these things.
This product owner role did not emerge from
product management as we know it today.
It was a way to help the developers
prioritize what to work on. I ended
up going to a ton of Agile conferences
and speaking about product management,
and I started to learn that there
was this product owner role in Scrum.
It feels like it's growing. More and more
companies are adopting this as the way to work.
A lot of large companies turn to Scrum
or to the frameworks, and it's because
they traditionally didn't grow up building
software. When you look at agile methodologies,
what we're really saying there is we want
to be able to move quickly and deliver
great value to customers. If you embrace
those principles, you're going to do well.
Today my guest is Melissa Perri. Melissa is
a legend in the product management community.
She's the author of the foundational book Escaping
the Build Trap, and her most recent book Product
Operations. She's also the CEO and founder of
The Product Institute, which trains product
managers at all levels. She's trained PMs at
almost every Fortune 500 company at this point,
and in our conversation we dive deep into a
topic that I don't spend a lot of time on on this
podcast, product owners, Scrum, Scaled Agile, and
building product at very large non-tech companies.
Melissa shares the history behind these ways
of working, what she's seen work and not work
when companies roll out these frameworks, and
most importantly what you can do as a leader
at one of these companies and as a product owner
working in one of these companies to level up your
organization and yourself. I learned a ton from
this conversation and I'm really curious to hear
what you think since we don't cover this kind of
stuff on this podcast too much. If you enjoy this
podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow it
in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's
the best way to avoid missing future episodes,
and it helps the podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you Melissa Perri. Melissa, thank you so
much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Thanks, Lenny. Thanks for having me.
First, let me give a little context on this
conversation that we're having. I think
it's going to be a little bit unique. I was
doing a deep dive on the job market in tech,
and I saw something that was really surprising
to me that the product owner role was the
third-fastest growing role in tech, and this
was just in the US, the data I was looking at,
but I think it's probably true broadly. This
was extremely surprising to me because I've
never worked with a product owner, I don't hear
anyone in my circles talking about product owners,
I've never wanted to hire a product owner, and
it feels like it's just this very different
part of the tech ecosystem that you don't
hear a lot about on podcasts like this,
and it's clearly growing so I felt like it'd be
really helpful to spend some time helping people
and helping me understand this part of the world.
I asked you to come on to talk about this. You've
been up close and personal with a lot of
companies working with this way of working
with product owners, Scaled Agile and all these
things, so I couldn't think of a better person
to have on here to help us understand what's
happening here, and also just to help people
do this better. Melissa, thank you again for
coming on and helping us understand this.
Yeah, I'm excited to talk about this. I have
been really passionate about this topic for
many years and I've been talking about it in both
agile circles and product management circles,
so pretty excited for the listeners to
hear what else is going on out there.
This episode is brought to you by Pendo, the
only all-in-one product experience platform for
any type of application. Tired of bouncing around
multiple tools to uncover what's really happening
inside your product? With all the tools you need
in one simple to use platform, Pendo makes it easy
to answer critical questions about how users are
engaging with your product, and then turn those
insights into action. Also, you can get your
users to do what you actually want them to do.
First, Pendo is built around product analytics,
seeing what your users are actually doing in your
apps so that you can optimize their experience.
Next, Pendo lets you deploy in-app guides that
lead users through the actions that matter most.
Then Pendo integrates user feedback so that you
can capture and analyze what people actually
want. The new thing in Pendo, session replays,
a very cool way to visualize user sessions. I'm
not surprised at all that over 10,000 companies
use it today. Visit Pendo.io/lenny to create your
free Pendo account today and start building better
experiences across every corner of your product.
Yes, you want to take your product-led know-how
a step further, check out Pendo's lineup of free
certification courses led by talk product experts
and designed to help you grow and advance in your
career. Learn more and experience the power of
the Pendo platform today at Pendo.io/lenny.
I'm excited to chat with Christina Gilbert,
the founder of OneSchema, one of our
long-time podcast sponsors. Hi Christina.
Yes, thank you for having me on, Lenny.
What is the latest with OneSchema? I know you now
work with some of my favorite companies like Ramp,
[inaudible 00:05:22], and Watershed.
I heard that you just launched a new
product to help product teams import CSVs
from especially tricky systems like ERPs.
Yes. We just launched OneSchema FileFeeds, which
allows you to build an integration with any system
in 15 minutes as long as you can export a CSV to
an SFTP folder. We see our customers all the time
getting stuck with hacks and workarounds, and
the product teams that we work with don't have
to turn down prospects because their systems
are too hard to integrate with. We allow our
customers to offer thousands of integrations
without involving their engineering team at all.
I can tell you that if my team had
to build integrations like this,
how nice would it be to be able to
take this off my roadmap and instead
use something like OneSchema, not just to
build it, but also to maintain it forever.
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many
horror stories of multi-day outages from
even just a handful of ad records. We are
laser-focused on integration reliability to
help teams end all of those distractions
that come up with integrations. We have
a built-in validation layer that stops
any bad data from entering your system,
and OneSchema will notify your team
immediately of any data that looks incorrect.
I know that importing incorrect data
can cause all kinds of pain for your
customers and quickly lose their trust.
Christina, thank you for joining us,
and if you want to learn more, head on
over to oneschema.co, that's oneschema.co.
Before we get into the history, is there just
anything broadly that you think might be helpful
to share before we dive into the history of
the product owner role and all these things?
Maybe it'll help to set some context of where did
I see all of this start emerging as well. When I
started in tech, I was very much a product
manager, never heard of the product owner
role before in my life. In Escaping the Build
Trap I talk a lot about how we used Scrum when
I started working with this team in a startup,
and it was the first time I ever heard of it.
That was 2011. At the time, the person who
was teaching me about agile was very like,
"Hey, this is flexible. We're just going to break
things into sprints. We're going to sit there and
actually talk about the work. This is made for
us to actually get better at our jobs." We were
pretty sold on it and it was never dogmatic. As I
worked at other companies, I found that they were
being a little more dogmatic with their Scrum,
with their stand-ups, how we actually run things.
Then I started speaking at conferences, and
one of the first conferences I spoke at in
New York City was called Lean UX, and there was a
bunch of people from the agile world there too. I
learned that this was much bigger than what we
were learning in my company and what we were
doing in these companies. There's this whole
group of people out there practicing agile,
and I was like, "Oh, this is cool. I want to
learn how to do things better. Teach me about your
philosophies." I ended up going to a ton of agile
conferences and speaking about product management.
At the time, people were really excited to hear
more about it, and I started to learn that there
was this product owner role in Scrum where I was
talking more about how we traditionally talk about
product management, understand your customer, go
out test things, make sure there's a hypothesis,
don't just blindly build what you want to
build. I found out that that was not the case
in a lot of these companies who are adopting
Scrum and introducing a product owner role,
so I started doing a lot of trainings through my
school product institute and I'd get called into
these large companies, all these large banks,
probably around 2014, 2015, to help them learn
product management. I was really excited about
this because before, they didn't want anything
to do with it. They were like, "I don't know
what product management is. I don't need this."
I go in to train people and I found that
a lot of them had been going through an
agile transformation and they had all of these
new product owners where they came in and they
basically said, "Hey, you're a product owner
now. Your whole role has changed." They came
from all different backgrounds. Some were
developers, so a lot were business people
who worked on the banking side, a lot were
business analysts, some were project managers,
but they just collectively took a bunch of
people and said, "Tada, today you're going to
be a product owner because we're going to do agile
now." I will come in and help train these people.
What I found was that there was a really big
misconception about what those people should
be doing compared to what they teach in agile
and Scrum versus what we all consider great
product management. I've been trying to fill
that gap for the last almost 10 years working
with these companies here. Then I would go to
their leaders and at the beginning of these agile
transformations, I'd be like, "You can't just
do Scrum. That's not going to make you amazing
at delivering products. There's so much more to
this." The leaders didn't quite understand that.
I'm noticing this really big shift in the industry
where we're finally getting there. A lot of
companies are doing it well now. Capital One is a
great example that took their agile transformation
and started adding product management on it,
and they've really turned that around in the
card business. So many organizations are still
at the beginning of this journey and they're
at the place where I saw people 10 years ago.
I think there's still a lot of companies out
there. Maybe we take it for granted in tech or
in Silicon Valley about how many companies are
doing this and how big this scope is where they're
making these roles, but they're not really doing
product management end to end. That's where I've
seen all of these areas and I've been trying to
help organizations for the last 10 years really
set up robust product management practices. It's
not just one piece of development, it's
how do we actually build better products?
I love this example of Capital One. It can work
really well and you can get to a place where it's
actually really productive. There's a few ways
we can go about this. Do you think it would be
helpful to talk through the history of the product
owner role just like where it initially emerged?
Yeah, I think that's a great place to start.
I think it brings a lot of context too to
what's happening. People forget about the
history here. When I explain it to people,
I say we had product managers in Silicon
Valley, right? They were in Google,
they were in all of these companies, Amazon, and
they were born out of this business role. From a
software native company, your software is the
business, right? It's what you sell, it's what
you actually look at. Our product managers in
Silicon Valley, they're doing market research,
they're talking to customers, they're
working with developers, they're iterating,
they're doing the end-to-end product management.
What happened on the other side of things,
especially in large companies, is the
emergence of product management from Scrum,
from product ownership. That's usually the
first time these companies were introduced
to product management was from implementing a
product owner role and then going, "Hey, we're
still not meeting our goals. Are we building the
right thing?" Then they started thinking product
management. Where that role came from is Scrum.
If we go back and talk about the history of agile,
agile was a movement that got started by software
developers. In 2001, the Agile Manifesto was
written. A bunch of developers got together in
Park City, Utah, they were all skiing together
and they said, "Hey, we've been independently
all working on how to develop software better."
Some people were practicing Scrum as we
know it today. That was Ken Schwaber,
Jeff Sutherland. There were people who were doing
different types of agile frameworks as well,
Kanban, where you were moving it through a Kanban
board. There was behavioral-driven development,
there was feature-driven development. That was the
style of agile. There was XP, extreme programming,
that was started by Ron Jeffries. All of these
people found each other saying, "Hey, we've been
trying to push the boundaries of how do we develop
better software," and they got together and they
wrote the Agile Manifesto as we know it today.
The Agile Manifesto is really just a guideline
on how they're striving to not just be people
who code what people want, but building better
products. How do we build better products through
software development? The premise to remember this
is, and I keep saying it, but they're all software
developers. Nobody was a product manager who went
to that meeting. Nobody who wrote the Agile
Manifesto was actually a product manager. I've
spent a long time talking to these people as well
over the past 10 years just saying, "Hey, how did
this come about? Where did this come from?"
The one person who was really close to them
who was a product manager was Jeff Patton, but
he never signed the Agile Manifesto, he wasn't
at that meeting. He talked to them a lot, he was
able to see what was going on, but all of this was
a purge from how do we build better products from
a development perspective. That's really important
to know. Two of the people who signed the Agile
Manifesto, Jeff and Ken, as I was talking about,
they were independently coming up with Scrum
on their own in their different companies,
and they got together and started to codify
it and they said, "This is how I'm doing it,
this is how I'm doing it." They ended up writing
the Scrum Guide. The Scrum Guide is what a lot of
people base their agile practices off of today. In
the Scrum Guide, it outlines a bunch of roles that
you would do on the development team, and then
it says how you should be developing products.
Most people out there are working in Scrum
today, and what they say is, "Let's break
things down into two-week sprints." You can
change the length of your sprint if you want to,
but two-week sprints is pretty standard at the
beginning. We define what we're going to work
on in the backlog. It's the product owner's
responsibility to define what goes into the
backlog, write down the user stories for it, do
all that. Then the development team comes in,
they discuss it, the product owner prioritizes
it, they ask questions, and then the development
team commits to what they want to build
and they go out and do it. At the end,
the result is a potentially shippable product, not
necessarily shippable, but potentially shippable.
They're trying to break it down into small
chunks and build things instead of what they
had been doing in a lot of companies, which
was building stuff for three years and then
releasing it in a big bang. What all of
the people who signed the Agile Manifesto
realized was if we do it the other way, if we do
a waterfall type environment, agile waterfall,
that's where we go across, there's a lot of risk
because we don't test it with the customer and we
don't get feedback on it if we spend three years
building it and never show it to somebody. It
really approached a different way of building
software. It said let's chunk it down and try
to get feedback faster. Really noble intention.
In the Scrum guide though, it introduces these
new roles. We have developers as we know
and love them, we also have a product owner,
then we have a Scrum master, and the Scrum master
is in charge in Scrum of actually helping people
do Scrum better. That's literally their job. How
do I do Scrum better? How do I make sure that the
team is working well together? They host things
like retrospectives where at the end of a sprint
we say what went well, what didn't go well, how
should we actually inspect and adapt our process.
The product owner is where things get murky.
The product owner in general first showed up with
Scrum, and if you go and you read the first Scrum
guide, which I pulled up and started reading,
because I've been very fascinated about how
this is described, it says that the product
owner is responsible for maximizing the value of
work done, the team does the work. Interesting,
because now the product owner is not quite
part of the team. The team consists of
developers with all the skills to turn the
product owner's request into the potentially
shippable increment each sprint. The team
is usually seven plus or minus two members.
Then when you go further into the first version
of the Scrum Guide, it does say that the Scrum
master works with the customers and management
to identify and instantiate a product owner.
The Scrum master teaches the product owner how
to do his or her job in order to optimize the
value of the use of Scrum. If they don't,
the Scrum master is held accountable. Then
it's got another tip if we go deeper into
this. It says per commercial development,
the product owner may be the product manager.
For in-house development efforts, the product
owner could be the user department manager.
What's interesting is that that was the first
version of the Scrum Guide, and I get into
arguments about the Scrum Guide with people
all the time. 2013's version though, the more
updated one that you could go and find is the
one that almost every company has run an agile
transformation off of. It loses that thing that
says the product manager could be the product
owner. It doesn't say it anywhere in that guide.
This was the first version, and you can kind of
tell it was an aside. It's like, "Oh, by the way,
the product owner in Scrum doesn't need to be
a product manager, it could be the customer, it
could be a developer." It's usually the customer.
When they were writing this too, sometimes the
customer was an internal person at a bank or
somewhere where we were building software who
was asking for the software. They were like, "Go
build me an internal tool. Go do this." Now we're
just asking for requirements inside a company,
and that's where you can start to see how the
product owner role kind of evolved into somebody
going to ask, "Hey, what do you want me to build?
What's required here?," and then just listening to
somebody come back and say, "I need this feature,
I need this feature, I need this feature." Scrum
doesn't describe how to get the stuff into the
backlog, and it didn't in the 2013 manuals.
The manuals have all been a little bit better,
they've all kind of been updated since then, and
they do describe it has to start with the vision
a little bit more, you have to break down the
vision for the product and get in there, but none
of that existed in the early versions of Scrum.
When people got trained on how to be a product
owner, what was happening here is, and this is
the whole other world of Scrum over here, when
people get trained to be a product owner, it's
usually a two-day class where they teach them,
"Hey, this is how you break down a backlog.
This is how you do stand-ups with your teams.
This is how you think about prioritizing
work. This is how you manage your backlog,
prioritize it for the developers. This is how
you work with the retrospectives," but it doesn't
teach them about experimentation, it doesn't teach
them about market research, it doesn't teach them
about data, it doesn't teach them about any of
the things that we need to be a product manager.
Then what happened was we went into these agile
transformations at these companies and they said,
"Hey, let's adopt Scrum because Scrum was built
as a way to build better products faster." It's
literally the tagline. Everybody was like, "Yeah,
I want to build products faster. Okay, great.
Let's do Scrum." All these large organizations
back in the early 2010s, in the 2000s said, "Oh,
we got to be better at software. How do we do
this better? Otherwise, we're going to lose
when it comes to innovation." They adopted
Scrum as a way to build software faster.
Now, what happened is in order to do Scrum, Scrum
basically sells training. That's what Scrum does.
All of these agile coaches would come in and teach
the product owners, newly minted product owners,
took all those people, made them into product
owners, put them through a two-day class and
then say, "Go." That was the beginning of
all the agile transformations, and that's
where a lot of companies still are today. This
product owner role did not emerge from product
management as we know it today, it was a way to
help the developers prioritize what to work on,
but that was it. The product owner was
held accountable for making sure that they
were working on the most pressing things or the
highest value things, they do say that, but to me,
if you look at it from a developer perspective,
it's also the person where you can say, "Hey,
well, you told me to build that, right? We didn't
build it wrong. You told me to build that."
It almost gets into consulting territory
where you're like, "Okay. If the product
owner prioritized all this stuff for me and told
me what to do, I can't be held accountable if it
was the wrong thing to build." Some of that stuff
does come up in a lot of teams that struggle to
adopt agile, to adopt Scrum. I feel like there's
a big misunderstanding out there about what is
this role and what should we be doing, but the
premise of this is when we talk about Scrum,
it's just one piece of the puzzle,
and when people talk about agile now,
they almost always associate it with Scrum.
I was actually Googling agile methodologies,
and like I said, the other ones, Kanbans is an
agile methodology, XP is an agile methodology.
They don't have product owners, they do not exist
in those methodologies. There are four developers
to work on things, or teams to work on things.
XP would consider product managers in the teams
as far as I know it, but Scrum kind of sees
it as a separate thing. Agile methodologies,
everybody says, "Oh, they're Scrum now," so it
gets a bad connotation out there about what to
do with it. I think Scrum if you do it well is
bad, but you have to understand that it's just
one piece of building great products, it's not
the whole thing, and companies will adopt it like
it's going to radically transform everything. To
be fair, a lot of times it's sold that way too.
There's a bigger picture question that's coming
to mind as you talk about this. I'm imagining
founders listening to this and smaller companies
listening to this be like, "Why do we need any
of this?", especially Silicon Valley startups,
"We're just going to build stuff. We don't need
these frameworks, we don't need a Scrum master. We
just have awesome developers and product managers
and we're just going to build awesome stuff." I
don't know anyone that has worked this way that
has built amazing things. Can you talk a bit
about who ends up looking for solutions here,
where this even comes from, what companies need
help here versus, "I just don't need any of this?"
A lot of large companies turn
to Scrum or to the frameworks,
and it's because they traditionally didn't grow
up building software. They're looking at how do
I implement something that has rigor at scale, and
that's where you see a lot of Scrum come up. Now,
I've seen startups using Scrum. Some of them
do it fine, they understand that it's just more
about trying to get things out the door every
two weeks to test it with customers. I think
if you keep that philosophy, like I said, I used
it and we didn't have a lot of rigor around it,
that was fine. When we were doing Scrum, when I
did it with my team back in OpenSky, we got to
this point where we were like, "Two weeks is too
long. We're just going to ship things every week."
We just talked to each other, we skipped
stand-ups, which is sacrilege in Scrum,
but we kipped daily stand-ups. We didn't need
to stand around and talk about it, we talked to
each other every day. For me, what was amazing and
where I see teams actually thrive when they start
using Scrum is when you go and talk to people.
You're having the conversations about the work,
you're breaking it down, you're understanding
it, so the developers and the rest of the team
can go hit the road running and people can ask
important questions. If you're not doing that,
that's where I think things like a framework
help, but if you already are doing that,
you don't need a framework, you don't need
Scrum, you don't need to be prescribed to
this two-week sprint or anything like that.
As long as you have a methodology, it doesn't
even have to be a defined methodology. As long
as you have a way of working that gets things
out to customers, well, who cares? Who actually
cares? Where there's a lot of, I think, baggage
in the industry and where I hear product managers
get really frustrated and other people as well,
developers too, is that when you do Scrum by
the book or how people teach it and how they
write about it, it's a million meetings. I know
they were put in there so that people were forced
to talk, but when you already know what you're
supposed to work on, why do you need to keep doing
meetings? Shouldn't you just go do some work?
A lot of developers complain, a lot of product
managers complain that Scrum has too many
meetings and they don't actually get to
do work. That's where I think you have to go
back to the inspect and adapt part. A lot of
people who are very religious about Scrum will
come and yell at me about this. They're like,
"Oh, well, that's not how it's supposed to be.
You're supposed to inspect and adapt." Agree,
but a lot of people aren't doing it and
that's the piece where you go and you say,
"Is this serving us? If not, let's get rid
of it. Let's not do those types of things."
When you're a small startup, I don't think you
need a lot of this overhead. It's really much
designed for larger scale companies, and those
are the ones that you see really adopting it.
From what I've seen on the data, it's
also companies that are as you I think
alluded to at the beginning,
not necessarily software first,
product first companies. Feels
like it's very common in banks
and telecom companies and companies that
aren't product First and software first.
There are SaaS companies that do
Scrum out there and they like it,
and I don't think they're very dogmatic about it.
Got it. Yeah.
They do it for a reason of just trying to
provide some more context to their teams
about how to work together at scale. I've
also seen places where they don't prescribe
whatever methodology you want to work with for
the teams, but instead they'll spend a lot more
effort breaking down the road maps, thinking
about what are we going to do each quarter,
trying to set those themes, and then they just
let the teams run, and that works as well. I
think it really depends how they adopt it, but
I would say it's not a hard and fast rule that
no startups are doing this. Some are doing it, I
just don't know how it's going for them. To me,
it might be overkill if you're doing that with
a team that's pretty experienced in doing this.
What I was insinuating is less just
Scrum as a general idea and more very
structured rigid processes and also product
owners. Then there's this whole concept of
SAFe that we can talk about. Should
we get into that or should we talk
about product manager versus product owner
and just the challenges people have there?
Let's talk about SAFe because that's where
a lot of this started to get Confusing
Okay, cool. Let's go there. Yeah.
Scaled Agile Framework came out of the desire to
figure out how do we scale Scrum and different
processes and bring it to organizations at scale.
It originated from a more structured approach to
agile too called Rational Unified Processing.
Now, SAFe wasn't the first thing that started
at scale. There was also LeSS, which is a Scaled
Agile Framework, and then Jeff Sutherland who
did Scrum has Scrum@Scale. It's not the only
scaling framework out there. There's a lot,
there's actually a lot out there, but SAFe
was one that was marketed the best. The way
it's marketed is will tell you everything
you need to do, to do all of your agile
teams with Scrum and put them all together.
The idea behind SAFe was that Dean Leffingwell
came up with it. He wanted to really show how
you tie multiple teams together at scale in an
organization and how do you bring some rigor and
process to that. The executives at really large
enterprises, we're talking tens of thousands of
people, they love SAFe because it prescribes a lot
of an operating model of what to do when it comes
to development, but it also gets billed as like,
"Hey, this is the whole model for you
to go do software." If you look at it,
it's a big map that everybody kind of makes fun
of a little bit, and it describes all different
things on it if you look at the map. You can
click in and you can see the definitions and
you can see what's going on in the areas.
The SAFe image has gotten bigger and bigger
over time. I think, what is this? Version six.
I do know a lot of people who worked on SAFe,
so I know a lot of trainers and I've worked with
companies. The first time I was introduced to
SAFe was when I was working with a bank back in
2015. I came in to train their product managers,
I'm doing my training, we're setting them up
on how to go talk to customers, talk about
hypotheses, MVP, and somebody came up to me and
they said, "Hey, Melissa, all of this is great,
but I don't have time to go talk to customers
because I'm a product owner." I was like, "Well,
what are you doing on a day-to-day basis?
What don't you have time for it?", "I got
to write my user stories." I'm like, "Okay.
How many user stories do you write per day?"
This was for the developers to have a full backlog
so they could all work, right? She's like, "Oh,
yeah. I spend pretty much 40 hours a day writing
user stories." I'm like, "On what?" We're like,
"What are you controlling?" She's like,
"The login API for a bank." I'm like,
"Can you log in?" She's like, "Yeah," and
I'm like, "So what else are you working
on? Is there a new initiative? Is there a new
thing?" It's like, "No, I was reorganized into
a team where I became the product owner. I have a
product manager who goes and talks to customers,
but then she comes and she tells me what to build,
and then I write the user stories around it and I
put it into the backlog for the teams." I
was like, "What is this?" Then they said,
"That's SAFe. This is what we're working towards."
This was my first experience with SAFe, and then
I ran into another company that did it, another
company, same thing over and over and over again,
where all these product owners were just basically
trying to keep these backlogs full for developers,
and they were working on such a narrow level. When
a lot of organizations too I saw it reorganized
into agile teams, they did it by component.
Everybody was over every tiny little feature,
and these teams were massive, super huge scope,
and some of the stuff was just not prioritized.
It was done, you didn't need to work on it. They
were finding work to do so people wouldn't get
fired. That's how the product owners operated.
There was all this legacy baggage sometimes in
companies where they were all re-put on things by
component, and they're just making up work to do.
SAFe introduced this kind of split between product
manager and product owner, and if you look at the
map, the product owner is part of the agile
team where they sit with the Scrum masters,
which is a team coach that they call here
and the developers, and then the product
manager is sitting with a system architect and
what they call a release train engineer. What
SAFe does is they pull a bunch of agile teams
into a release train and you get on the train
when you're ready to ship things and you make
sure that it all goes pretty smoothly to get
to that potential shippable increment or that big
feature launch that you would be doing with SAFe.
SAFe's really good at prescribing how to do that,
they're great at describing how to do the release
trains, how to bring those teams together, how to
put them on it. Then they do this thing called big
room planning where they get the entire release
train together, all these teams, they put them in
a room and in every quarter you're breaking down
what we're all going to work on. Where I hear
frustration from teams every time I come in and
train them is that when you do big room planning,
a lot of times it's a commitment. You start at the
quarter, they haven't been doing good discovery
because remember, these people have not been
trained on good discovery so they don't really
know what they should be working on, they haven't
been out talking to customers a lot of times. They
kind of scramble, they figure out what needs to
happen. Usually they have a backlog of stuff that
does need to happen, it just has to get done.
They map it all out in a big room together,
they commit to it, and then that's the quarter.
They ask me, "When am I supposed to do discovery?"
I'm like, "Well before that ideally you should
have a vision. You should be breaking it down,
you should be putting discovery into that vision,
talking to customers, feeding that in there."
Then I hear, "We don't have time to do that
because we sprint back to back." I was like,
"What does that mean?", and they're like, "As
a team, we go and we basically do two-week
sprint into two-week sprint into two-week sprint,
and I got to make sure my developers are full. I
got to make sure they have things to work on.
If I go take time off to go talk to customers,
which also is not my job as a product owner, it's
my product manager's job, they'll feed me in what
the customers are saying, then I break those down
into features and I can work with the developers
on it." That's how all of this stuff starts going.
What happens in organizations that they don't
understand here is that it's not the most
efficient way to work. I see a lot of developers
out there become almost ... How do you describe
it? Reliant on the product manager or product
owner to tell them what to do. Even though you
build them this great vision and you explain what
needs to happen, they go, "Oh, I can't work on it
because the product owner hasn't prioritized it."
Then they asked me, "If I don't have enough
for the developers to do on feature work,
what are they supposed to do?" I said, "I
guarantee you there's a ton of tech debt
they could be working on. You don't have
to scope that out. Let them choose what's
the most important thing. They should be working
together as developers and architects to figure
out how to tackle some of that tech debt,
how to get into it while you're figuring out
is this the right thing to be building."
With all of this stuff, people feel like
they don't have time because they're in a
million meetings, and the expectations of
these companies is that every sprint, we're
delivering software towards these roadmaps
that we promised in the last quarter and
we're not checking to see if they're right,
we're not checking to see if they're actually
helping us move it forward, and a lot of times
the organizations are not set up with the right
feedback mechanisms, the right user research and
the right data to tell us if everything is
working so they can feed that in to the next
release planning. They're just planning, planning,
planning, breaking it down into sprints and going.
SAFe is not good at describing how you do all
that other work. In a lot of this stuff too,
there's pieces that they put onto this map of
SAFe where they're like, "Hey, you should do
OKRs," and it's like, "This is what OKRs are. You
should do a roadmap. This is what a roadmap is."
How all of that cycle works together where you're
balancing discovery and delivery and feeding it in
is really confusing in organizations. Then
what it's basically saying is a lot of the
discovery work goes into the product managers,
and the product managers, the product owners
report into the product managers. What I've seen
that doesn't work here is that you're basically
making these product owners order-takers. They
are extremely tactical, and then when it's
time to actually be more strategic, let's say
you want to be promoted to a product manager,
some organizations, that's not even the same
business line, not even the same career path. It's
product owners go over here and product managers
go here and they report into different people.
If you ever want to move from product owner
to product manager, a lot of times you don't
get experience with the strategy, figuring
out what customers want, breaking it down,
looking at the market research, determining
is this valuable, is this what we should be
working on. They're not even getting exposure
or a chance to do that because SAFe is like,
"No, that's the product manager's job. Your job is
to go really deep and work with the developers."
Wow, okay. A lot of this sounds quite absurd as
someone hearing all of the details and looking at
this image. That being said, many companies are
adopting this. It feels like it's growing. More
and more companies are adopting this as the way
to work. I imagine the incentive is we just want
to build great software and we don't know exactly
how, and there's this process we can plug in and
it'll help us do it. I guess thoughts on that,
and do you find it can work or often works or
often doesn't work? What is your experience
with people adopting this and how it goes?
I know a ton of companies that adopted SAFe
about eight years ago and have gotten rid of
it. Capital One just came out and said they
got rid of all their agile roles, all their
Scrum roles. They were early adopter of SAFe, they
don't do it anymore. They wrote about that in the
newspaper. I've seen it happen more often. Now, in
a lot of our organizations too I'll see parts of
them do SAFe and other parts not do SAFe. It
could change business line to business line.
I don't think though that people grasp how much
it's still out there. I get questions on SAFe
every single day on the podcast. Everybody asks
me, "Why are we still doing this?" It's for what
you said, executives buy SAFe because it's the
only framework out there that basically draws
them a map and says, "Plug and play, do this."
That's why everybody's so excited about it because
it's the only thing that specifies things to this
level, and they went, "Oh, it's something I can
understand, it's something that actually
has definitions around it." To be fair,
that was a great thing for SAFe
to do as a marketing tool. Bravo,
they created this thing that everybody wants,
a good product to sell, but it's overkill,
and that's what I keep hearing from organizations
is it's basically taking the responsibility away
from leaders to go figure their stuff out
themselves as well. If you are a new leader
and you've just been dropped into this role,
I have tremendous empathy for them because
yeah, where do you get started? How do
you try to run a technology organization?
Somebody came and told me, the CIO came and told
me I'm in charge now. I'm in charge of all of the
developers, or I'm in charge of all the product
managers. Now, where do you start? I can totally
tell why people adopt SAFe because you're like,
"Oh, I've been looking for the handbook. I've been
looking for something to do here." The problem
is it's only solving a little bit of the puzzle,
which is bringing those teams together.
People do say it does really strains well,
but it doesn't tell you also how to do your job
as a leader, it leaves it all out. They talk about
portfolio visions and portfolio management
and SAFe there too, but more often than not,
I come in and I find everybody above product
owners and product managers, let's talk about
directors of product, VPs of product, they don't
know what they should be doing as a VP of product
or a director of product. It's like, "What's
my role? What should I be feeding in here?"
SAFe doesn't even have that in there, that's not
even a role. Product manager going up into those
levels is not really there. What do you
do when you own a whole product line in
an organization? What you do when you're the
head of product for a credit card at a bank,
right? What's my job? Doesn't say that. There's
a lot of people out there in these organizations
that I've been working with who I'm like,
"You are supposed to be doing strategy,
and this is how you do strategy. This is how you
go out and talk to customers. This is the patterns
that we have in software. Are you doing a platform
strategy? Do you need APIs? How do you think about
your app strategy, rolling it out? How do you do
this here?" All of that stuff doesn't quite come
from ways of working, which is what SAFe is doing.
It's about how do you do your jobs in those areas?
A lot of organizations who adopt SAFe don't
realize that you need a head of product, you
need somebody to actually be feeding that vision
all the way down and make sure it's breaking up
around the teams and controlling that portfolio
vision and doing all of these things into it.
I have not seen SAFe slowing down by any
means out there for people adopting it,
I see more and more organizations adopting
it. I think we take for granted too in Silicon
Valley how many people are just starting on
their journey for digital transformation.
There's a lot of pharmaceutical companies,
banks, insurance companies, they outsource
their development or they had an IT team, but
they never had to really think about it before
because digital wasn't as important. Now they do.
Some of these companies, most of these companies
are Fortune 50 companies, right? Fortune 100
companies. I think a lot of the ones I see,
at least banks, realized early on, "Hey, when
it comes to apps and how people interact with
our stuff, software is important," but there's
a lot of companies that did not catch that train
and they're just starting, and then they
turn to things like SAFe because it gives
them a guideline. "Hey, I've never done this
before. I've been in this bank for 40 years.
All I know is waterfall type development. What do
we do?" Then we'll go, "We'll go look at SAFe."
I love that we spend time on that because I think
it's really important. You can be cynical about
all this and be like, "What the hell are people
thinking? This is crazy," but as you described,
people just have a problem to solve, they've
never done this before, they look for solutions,
they find something that seems right, they see
other people doing this and like, "Okay, let's
try this thing." What you've seen is it rarely
actually works out the SAFe specific approach.
There's a few ways I think we can help folks.
One is someone trying to do say an agile
transformation or a digital transformation, your
advice for how to actually do that better. Then
I want to talk about say you're a product owner
or a PM within an organization that works like
this. What can you do? Maybe let's start with
the first. Say someone's trying to figure out,
"We need to build better products. Something's
not working right." SAFe is an option. Your
suggestion is don't maybe do that. What
should people do? I know you're not going
to have the answer in a short answer, but
generally, how should people approach this?
Yeah. When I've worked with companies
on digital transformations, you want a
development operating model. That's where a lot
of these agile methodologies came out of. You
have to understand that's just the development
operating model, that's not actually going to
help you with go-to-market, with launching your
products and with product management. What I
advise for companies to do is first sit down
and say, "Hey, how do we think about building
our operating model?" When I think of product
operating models and what I do with companies
is we break out how do you determine product
strategy? Do you have a good product strategy?
You look at your organizational design.
How are we actually organized around our
products? Do we have good coverage of
product managers and do we have skilled
product managers up and down the organization?
Then we want to look at product operations. Do
we have the infrastructure in there to help
support these teams? Can they get the data
to make decisions? Can they actually be in touch
with customers? A lot of these large organizations
haven't actually thought through many of those
steps as well that enable product managers and
development teams to be successful. They don't
have ways for them to go and talk to customers.
That's why they're not doing it. I have a lot of
empathy for people in these organizations as well
who can't do product management well because of
the bureaucracy or the things around it. Leaders
need to solve that, right? They need to understand
what the role is and they need to open it up.
Then we got to look at our culture and incentives.
Are we just rewarding people for shipping as many
things as possible, which is like, "Hey, just
put everything you possibly can into that release
train or that backlog," or are we coming back and
saying, "Hey, is this valuable? Is this tying it
back to our business?" Many organizations
do not have a great product strategy,
many large organizations that I've worked with,
and it's that tying it back to the value piece,
tying it back to, is this going to reach our
company goals? If you are a huge organization
and let's say making billions of dollars a
year, and your goal is expand geographically,
what are you doing in your portfolio to actually
enable that? What products are you building to
expand geographically? So many organizations don't
have the transparency to actually even see that.
One crazy thing, a lot of people give large
organizations a lot of flack for, and I know Marty
does this too, for focusing on processes. I don't
think processes are the enemy here. For example,
if I hear somebody really worried about getting a
roadmapping tool in there or something like that,
I'm like, "Yes, you need that because you have
no idea what your 4,000 teams are doing." If
they're actually coming back to the business
goals, you have no infrastructure in there
to be able to see that transparency.
Those types of blocking tackling is
absolutely necessary for a transformation
for a organization to be stood up around
software product management. You have to have
the transparency to actually see those things.
You do need to have enough process so that you as
an organization can be efficient in getting things
out the door, and that's what I think SAFe was
trying to do, but it's not working because it's
not solving the problems of the product management
and it's not solving that problem of connecting
the value back to the product teams. Instead, it's
seen as a role that almost babysits developers or
tells everybody what to do. Where's the discovery?
Where do those things come in? I know with the
SAFe image that we got over here, they try to drop
things like Lean UX in there, which Jeff Gothelf
thinks it's hilarious, but it's not really pulling
it all together of how do we do this on a cadence?
How do we help people go out there and actually
talk to customers? How do we enable them to do it?
If you're starting a transformation, it's not
just thinking about how do we build the product,
but you should also be thinking about how do we
launch the product and how do we make sure this
is the right product to do. That's the big pieces
of it, and that's where all that product strategy
comes in. You should also look at the career
paths. This is what really bothers me about agile
transformations and what bothers me with Scrum
and SAFe is that when we organized in these large
organizations into agile teams, we made all these
new roles called a product owner, and so many
organizations don't have a career path for them so
they email me and they go, "What's my career path?
What do I do next? Where am I supposed to go?"
I've been saying for 10 years, this is not a team
role, it's not just a team role, it's a business
role and it rolls all the way up to helping you
further your business. You have to make sure
that people on teams can be promoted to running
multiple teams, can be promoted to running an
entire product line. To us, that's so simple
in Silicon Valley native software companies, but
it's still unheard of in other organizations. What
happens too, and this is where I think leadership
and C-suite needs to really pay attention,
because we're transforming in this way of working,
what happens is some of the roles that we had
before do not serve us now. Maybe we don't need
a million project managers, maybe people in the
business who decided what we're going to build,
are they the right people to bring with us on
this next phase into product management? Can they
learn? Can they grok software? Do they understand
those pieces? That's what we have to ask.
Organizations are so afraid sometimes to
put these career ladders in because it kind of
overhauls their traditional ways of working,
and then they've got people who've been in these
organizations for 40 years and now you're saying,
"Hey, you're actually not in charge of that, the
product manager is in charge of that," and that's
scary. A lot of them get in the way because of
that. If you really want to transform though,
the C-suite has to be like, "Hey, we're going
in this direction," and just put it down because
I've seen it run by a lot of middle managers, a
transformation run by tons of middle managers,
and those are the jobs that are usually in
most jeopardy when you start transforming
and you have to re-skill and you have to figure
out what to do, and they don't want to do that.
They're not going to be the ones who jump
up and down and say, "Hey, let's do this."
There's a lot of people out there, I think,
pushing organizations to try harder and to
internally as well. I've worked with a lot of
people who run these transformations who just
really want it to work, and I think they do it
with the best of intentions, but the C-suite has
to understand this is not just a transformation
project, this is a whole new way of working,
and if we want a whole new way of working,
we have to really rise to that occasion.
This episode is brought to you by Coda. I use
Coda every day to coordinate my podcasting and
newsletter workflows, from collecting
questions for guests, to storing all my
research, to managing my newsletter content
calendar. Coda is my go-to app and has been
for years. Coda combines the best of documents,
spreadsheets, and apps to help me get more done,
and Coda can help your team to stay aligned and
ship faster by managing your planning cycle in
just one location, set and measure OKRs with
full visibility across teams and stakeholders,
map dependencies, create progress
visualizations, and identify risk areas.
You can also access hundreds of pressure-tested
templates, everything from roadmap strategy
to final decision-making frameworks. See for
yourself why companies like DoorDash, Figma,
and Qualtrics run on Coda. Take advantage
of this special limited-time offer just
for startups. Head over to coda.io/lenny and
sign up to get six free months of the team
plan. That's coda.io/lenny to sign up and get
six months of the team plan. Coda.io/lenny.
There's a few things I want to pull out from
what you just shared. One is, just to clarify,
you recommend not using SAFe, you
don't think that's a good approach?
I do not recommend using SAFe. Yeah.
Great.
There are people who like SAFe. Let me just
say this, there are people who found success
with SAFe. Every single person I have talked
to who like SAFe found success with SAFe,
they ended up ripping it up and making it into
something else. It's not actually SAFe by the
book. If you do that, fine, that's any process.
If you ended up adopting SAFe and you want to go
back and look at it and say, "Actually let's just
get rid of all the stuff that's not working and
keep the stuff that is," fine, but being open to
understanding this is not the way that we do good
product management. There's not a lot in SAFe
about doing good product management. That's the
stuff that we have to understand. It could help
in certain areas, and I do think it does help in
certain areas, bring some rigor to things, but
if you take it too far, it will destroy things.
There's actually a great story about a water
company in the Netherlands and they decided to
adopt SAFe, and this was on the news a couple
months ago. They decided to adopt SAFe in their
IT teams and start working with it. They
ended up going bankrupt, and the reason
they ended up going bankrupt is because the
teams were learning the processes for SAFe,
they were taking so long to deploy their new
invoicing system and payment collections that
they couldn't collect payments from customers
because they got so caught up in the process.
That's what I see happen a lot in these
organizations. Instead of talking about
what's really important, which is, "Hey, how are
we serving our customers? How are we winning in
this market? How do we stem churn? How do we do
all these things?", we're talking instead about,
"What stand-ups are we doing? Oh, how do
we do this release planning? Oh, my God,
you guys didn't sprint back to back, you did
it wrong." We're talking about work about work,
but we're not actually getting
into what are we achieving here,
and that's the part I do not like about
rigid processes when it comes to this.
That touches on the other theme I wanted
to bring up is it feels like the stuff is
a kind of replacement for skilled, talented
people, a product leader that understands how
to do these things and has product taste and
has organized teams to build great product.
It feels like people are just, "We don't
have that so we're going to create this.
This process is going to fix all our problems."
Can you talk about just the importance of that,
the people you hire to run these
things as key to this, if that's true?
In a lot of organizations, the people
who buy SAFe, they have not run large
scale technology organizations before, or
they're new to this way of working so they
adopt SAFe and they hope it works because
it looks like a nice plan, like we said,
to go out and do things. When you're doing
a transformation, a lot of companies are
pulling people into these roles for the first
time. I've said since day one that I've been
working with companies, it's okay and I think
it's noble to want to train people and put them
in different roles. Cool. If you're going to
spend money upskilling your people, do that,
but you also have to intersperse people who know
what they're doing. I think at leadership it's
really important to bring in somebody who knows
what they're doing to help run this type of thing.
There are more people out there and more
leaders who have done this before because
we've been doing this for 10 years. There's
Shruti Patel, she's chief product officer at
US Bank for small business banking. I just had her
on the podcast. She worked at Shopify, she saw how
great teams worked, and then she was able to come
and help apply that at a bank. She's experienced,
right? She's an experienced product person who
comes in to help. Melissa Douros is the CPO of
Green Dot Bank and she had worked at Discover
Financial leading the transformation there,
did all that work, and then could bring it to
Green Dot Bank. She can see what needs to happen,
what needs to actually go on here.
We've got more and more people out
there who have done this before who are looking
for these opportunities to do it in the bank,
and I think it's important for C-suite to bring
them in to actually look at that. Where I've seen
transformations be the most successful in all
these organizations is when you do that mix,
you keep some of your people, but you also
bring people in to learn. I get hired all
the time to come in and train. I've worked with
almost every Fortune 50 company at this point,
fortune 100 company too, and I get in, I
come in to train a lot of product managers.
We do it through Product Institute and we'll train
everybody. What used to happen about eight years
ago is they train everybody and they would say,
"Go." Where do you go after you bring in the
consultants to do training to keep learning? How
do they watch other people in the organization do
great product management if there's nobody
in the organization who's done it before?
Luckily I think a lot of organizations are
realizing that, so more leaders are out there
who are saying, "Hey, I've got to actually
intersperse skills here. I need to bring in
some more directors who are experienced here, some
more individual contributors who are experienced
here." Those organizations I think are wildly
successful because they recognize it and they say,
"I've got to make sure that people can learn
from others." That's how you keep developing,
that's how we all keep developing, it's not
just doing all external classes. That's where
I think these things become powerful. You
could do that at all levels. You don't have
to just do it with the teams, you could do it
at director level, you could do it at VP level.
That's how we should be thinking about this.
Now, there are some CPOs out there and some VPs
of product in these large organizations who are
new to this way of working, but they've committed
themselves to learning and to trying to figure
out how to do it best. They're not saying, "Hey,
I'm just going to adopt SAFe or I'm just going
to do whatever is over here," they're actually
saying, "What don't I know?" I'm watching them
go out to talk to other CPOs, do all these other
things. They usually have great market knowledge,
great business knowledge, and they're fantastic
at strategy, and then they hire people underneath
them who are great at the other pieces like the
execution and getting the software at the door.
I think those people are successful in it as well
because they notice their skill gaps and they
hire for it just like any great leader would.
In these organizations, I do see sometimes SAFe
for something being a crutch for people who don't
know what they're doing to bring in. If you really
think about, "Hey, how do I make this better?",
and have that continuous learning mindset and that
way to want to propel this forward, I think you'll
consider other options and start to think about
broader than just SAFe, broader than just agile,
what do we need to make this successful?
The key part of this too is recognizing
that product management is not just this
role in Scrum. I say this in my talk too,
I say Take Scrum away. You still need product
management, right? Product owner doesn't exist
without Scrum, that's not a thing, but you still
need product managers and that's why all product
owners should be product managers, they should be
fundamentally product managers. That's why I do
not like these career trajectories that keep them
separate. Sure, if you want to have a principal IC
product manager like they do in a lot of large
Silicon Valley companies, perfect, let people
keep working on those things. They don't have to
go into management, but that doesn't mean they're
different. Between an IC product owner and an IC
product manager, it shouldn't be different there.
Perfect segue to where I wanted to go next,
which is say you are a product owner today
listening to this and you're like, "Man,
this is exactly my life. What can I do?",
what's your advice to folks in that role right now
about how to potentially become product managers,
build the skills they need to not just be stuck
in this career path that doesn't go anywhere?
Yeah. I think the first thing is bringing
awareness to that your role is more than
just working with the developers. A lot of leaders
argue with me that we need product owners because
it just doesn't scale. You've seen massive
companies at scale where they don't have any
product owners. I do not understand that. It's a
weak argument to me, it's a very weak argument. It
just means you don't know how to distribute the
work evenly and give a little bit of strategic
guidance to product owners so that they can gon,
or product managers, on a team so that they can
go and build visions and cut down features and
stuff like that. If you're a product owner and
you're like, "Hey, I don't have the opportunity to
talk to customers, my product manager does that. I
am just working with the teams. I want to be more
strategic, I want to think longer term," I'd say
try to take some ownership over that and push
back on the things that are being given to you.
I was doing a workshop for Mind the Product
back in the day, and I had a product owner
in my workshop and she said, "I don't think that
things we're working on," they were doing SAFe,
"are the right things to work on." I said, "You
should bring this to your manager," and she was
like, "I don't know. I'm going to get fired.
I don't think it's the right thing. What am
I going to work on if we're not going to work
on this?" I'm like, "Well, this is the beauty
of product instead of project, we stay with the
product." Just because your project ends doesn't
mean that you lose a job. She put together this
whole thing, went and said, "I don't think we
should be working on this," and they promoted
her. They were like, "Fantastic." She took this
leap of faith and went out there and started
saying, "This is more. We need to do more."
I think if you're a product owner
and there's no career path for you,
start asking leaders what your career path
is because it's going to make them go, "Oh,
great question. What should the career path
be?" There's a lot of literature out there
about how we make career paths, so you can start
there. Ask what's next for you after this product
owner role. I would ask the product managers
if they're doing all the customer research,
see if you can do some customer research with
them. Go sit in on this. A lot of them will say,
"I don't have time. I don't have time to do this."
Strip back all the user stories you're working on,
stop thinking about it as a quantitative metric
that needs to just go up and up. Instead,
really think about the value you're delivering
with your team. Is this the right thing?
When you talk to leaders and when you
present your case, you say it in a way of,
"Hey, I'm working on X, Y, and Z feature.
What's the goal here? When we release this,
what do we hope will happen?" I think that's
one of the best questions anybody can ask if
they're worried their company is not
focused on outcomes. What do we hope
will happen when we release this? What
metrics are we going to change? How do
we instrument it to make sure that's true?
Then we can go back and actually see if it
changed. One simple question to get alignment
on it, and then you can start to say, "Oh,
that didn't work or this did work." Great. Why
did it work? You can open up those conversations.
I'd say there's a lot of things you can do to help
move your companies forward, and I have seen in a
lot of these organizations too, a groundswell of
product owners and product managers saying, "Hey,
what's next for me? What's going on?" That makes
the organizations go and figure it out. I was
working with one Fortune 10 company not too long
ago, their C-suite, I've been working with them
for a very long time and they're finally like,
"Hey, we're going to codify the product manager
role and we're going to have it all the way up and
down our organization, we're going to make roles,
we're going to make responsibilities." To me, that
was music to my ears, but the reason they were
doing it too is because they noticed there was
a lot of churn in the organization in that role,
and they also realized it's a critical role.
They're losing good people because people from
the outside are coming because they want to
work for this great big organization that's
doing super well, fantastic, but they get in
there and they go, "Where's my career path?
What am I supposed to do? Where am I supposed to
go?" A lot of leaders are out there now realizing,
"Hey, we do have to get our stuff together," and
the only reason they're coming to this conclusion
as well is because they're looking around seeing
other people doing it and they hear it from the
teams, they hear it from the product managers.
I don't want people to think, "Hey, I have no
power. I'm in a 10,000 person organization." The
more you bring this up, the more your leaders will
respect it because they don't want to lose
you, they don't want to lose good people.
If you want to be great at your job and you
need more support there, speak up, speak up.
At a certain point, I do tell people this.
If you feel like you can't do great product
management in your organization, try to find
another organization. I know that is hard to
say and I respect people are tied to insurances
and it's hard to change jobs, but if you do have
the opportunity to look for another organization
that does it well, I would go there. I would also
say in large corporations too, I've seen certain
business lines and certain divisions do it super
well and then others not. If you are in a large
corporation, maybe think about moving internally,
laterally to a different team and seeing if
you can work there. I'd find the leaders who
know what they're doing and go work for
that. That's usually the best move here.
The point you made about how a lot of companies
don't have any product owners and have scaled
very wide, just to reinforce that in the
data dive that we did on job market trends,
no tech company has a product owner basically,
no top tech company. I know there's an important
distinction here. These are tech, software first,
product first businesses where their business
is the software they're building, and a lot of
the companies we're talking about here are not
that. They're banks and telecoms, pharmaceutical
companies. I get that it's a very different world,
but I think it's important to highlight, "You
can become very big." Google has no product
owners as far as I know, Amazon, Microsoft,
Netflix, no company you've heard of that's
a tech company has a product owner. They're all
product managers, they're all product managers.
Yeah. I don't want people to think that there
aren't people who build great software in
these large corporations too because there are.
There's pockets of people who are doing it super,
super well. If you are one of those people who's
been pushing the boundaries, doing great work,
and your title is a product owner, what I always
tell people on your resume, if you're looking for
your next job so that you're not pushed out, let's
say, of these large corporations like a Google or
somewhere like that, and that's where you want
to work in a tech firm, make sure you describe
how you did your job from a value perspective. Do
not talk about your agile cadences. Get Scrum out
of there. Talk about what value you brought
to the users and what metrics you moved,
and that's how your resume should be laid out.
I do read tons of resumes to hire people,
and also chief product officer, same thing. If I
see immediately implemented Scrum processes across
the organization, I'm like, "No, that's not what
I need. That's not what I was looking for." I was
looking for what are you going to do to push the
strategy in that part of the organization? What
are you going to do to actually build better
products for customers? Then when you get into
the interview, you can talk about what things
you did to do that, but you want to make sure
that you're focused on really understanding the
customer and translating that into great products,
and the outcomes that we were looking for when you
do it on your resume, I think that's important.
Okay. I want to spend more time here because
this is so important. This is highlighting
here's the difference between a product owner
and a product manager. If you want to move
into product management and become a great PM, if
you're a product owner today, even if you're not a
product owner and just want to get into product
management, can you again just highlight here's
the big difference and here's the skills that
people value most in a PM versus a product owner.
Yeah. When I see product owners write out
their resumes or describe their job functions,
they always approach it from a process standpoint.
I prioritize the backlog, I worked with the
developers to break down the work, I checked the
developer's work and did the acceptance criteria,
I wrote the user stories, all those functions is
what I see over and over and over again in product
owner resume. What you want to do instead is say,
"I led the," we can even do the login API,"I led
the work around the login API. The problem
that I was solving around it was trying to
enhance security for our login protocols to meet
regulatory requirements. I interviewed a bunch
of users, I got up to speed on the regulatory
requirements, I worked really closely with our
legal teams and our compliance teams to translate
that into something that was going to secure our
bank, and when we launched, we were able to meet
our compliance, save our bank a couple million
dollars, and we smoothly transitioned into these
new security requirements without disrupting any
service for customers for four million customers."
Way different story than I prioritized backlog and
I shipped it off to developers. Take it a step
further. If you're working on customer-facing
things, who are your customers? Did you
go out and talk to them? By interfacing
with customers and understanding them, I was
able to solve XY, and Z problem with them,
which resulted in a measurable amount of XY
and Z metric going up for the business. I ran
this function, I ran this feature, I launched this
feature, I watched it through, I iterated on it,
I did the stuff that was needed to make this
successful. That's what I want to see on a resume.
Even if you have a product owner title, I'll still
read the details and everybody else will too,
but I will say there's sometimes a poor
connotation when you have that title
unfortunately because of the baggage that's
associated with agile. Even just on resumes,
I would say do product owner/product manager
in there just to let people know that I know
how to do this and I've been doing this
well. If you do that in your bullet points,
that shows up as well. There's also this whole
concept that we didn't even get into about
certifications. People keep asking me if I want
to transition into product management, should I
get a certification, an agile certification?" I
feel like these were bigger a couple years ago,
but they're still big. If you ever see somebody
with a CSPO on the end of their profile,
which you probably have seen on LinkedIn,
it's a certified Scrum product owner.
Now, one thing to remember, and this is about all
agile stuff, is we call it the agile industrial
complex, agile coaches and agile trainers,
the whole Scrum team, scrum.org, Scrum Inc,
SAFe, everybody, the way they make their money is
through consulting to teach you these processes
and by having people be trained to get these
certifications. They come in and they say,
"All your people need to be certified Scrum
product owners. Give me 2,500 bucks per person,"
and then they get a certificate at the end of
a two-day class that says they're a certified
Scrum product owner. It doesn't necessarily mean
they could do the job, it doesn't necessarily mean
they could do product management, but let's think
about when we're talking about too should we adopt
SAFe in general, should we adopt these things,
think about how these organizations make money.
They're selling certifications. Of course they
want more and more people to adopt it. That's the
idea here. They're selling you this dream that you
just certify all your people and then you could
be working on it. They take all these people,
they put them in two-day classes or whatever,
and they turn them out and then they say, "Go,
you're a completely new role." It doesn't work
that way. That's not in the best interest of your
company, that's not really what we're looking for
here, and that's why all of this stuff needs to go
deeper. If you've done a CSPO class and you have
that certification, it may help you get hired at
another large enterprise that is adopting Scrum
and SAFe. That will probably help you there.
If you want to transition into tech and go into
the companies that we talk about, they're
probably going to look at that and say,
"This person doesn't know what they're
doing. This is not here." If you do know
what you're doing and you did that for a reason,
because some people need that to get promoted,
some companies actually require it, which is
crazy, but to get promoted or be that thing,
I have tremendous sympathy for that, but you're
going to have to do a lot of work explaining in
your resumes and stuff as you transition that
you know more than that. You're not just a CSPO
with a two-day class, you have done the work.
That's where all of this building up on your
resume becomes really, really important.
It's not just about getting certified.
I had people ask me, they're like, "Can you
just certify product managers?" I'm like,
"No. If people take my course, I give them a
certificate of completion and as a completion."
You finished a course just like any other course,
but I will not certify product managers because I
do not think you can ever say somebody is prepared
and able to do their job from a short class. Now,
there are some agile agencies that do a lot more
training where you have different levels, and what
they would do is they would train people, but then
they would make them go do work and they had a
coach that they worked with, and they go back and
forth and they could demonstrate that they could
do the work over time to get to the next level.
It's almost like the PMP, the project management
certification where you have to have time
actually doing the job. That's different,
that's a different type of skill, it's a different
type of certification, but if you see any CSPOs,
it's typically a two-day workshop that they
went to and then got certified. That's the
difference with this. I would say be careful if
you are a product owner wanting to be a product
manager of just certifications. All the large tech
organizations I know too, they're not looking for
certifications in product management or product
ownership to hire people, they're looking for
experience, but the organizations that might
not know what they're doing, they are looking
for CSPOs, they are looking for that.
If it's required by your organization,
you might have to ask, "Are we all well set up
here to do our best job? Is this the place where
I'm going to learn how to be a better product
manager?" I also feel bad though for people
because it's hard to be a product manager,
it's hard to get your foot in the door.
I'm so torn on it because there are organizations
that hire people with a CSPO and they require it,
so of course if it gets your foot in the door and
it helps you do it, but if it's not going to help
you and it's not going to put you on the career
path you want, I don't think it's worth money.
I think one interesting thread throughout
this whole conversation is rarely is a
plug-in play-ish easy solution going
to be the answer to your problem,
whether it's plugging in SAFe and it's
going to help us build great software,
taking a class helping you become a great
product manager, be skeptical of that.
Yeah. There's no quick way to doing any of this,
there's no fast track. You don't get
to skip over all the hard things.
Yeah. Bummer.
Yeah. I wish.
Yeah. One question I wanted to clarify. When you
come into an org and they have product owners,
do you encourage them to get rid of
product owner as a title and role
and make them product managers
or do you keep product owners?
I say that we should have a hierarchy. You
would have all product managers on a team,
they would be an IC, individual contributor, so
they're either an associate product manager and
that's if they don't have all the discovery
experience or maybe they know basic Scrum,
totally fine, you can be an associate product
manager, but if they don't know how to talk
to customers, digest what the customers are
saying and turn that into a feature direction
and a backlog and this is how we're going to
work, all that stuff needs to be in there.
If they don't know how they should be measuring
things, you're not quite a product manager yet.
Associate product manager, and then product
manager, and then a senior PM. A senior PM
can work on a Scrum team as well or a
development team. I do encourage them,
I say, "Get rid of these two different titles
because it's confusing everybody." I help a
lot of people with career paths too. I've
seen companies with 47 different titles
for product managers because somebody in this
organization is called a product associate and
somebody over here is a product manager and
that person is a platform product manager,
and that person is a platform product owner,
and this person is an API product owner. You
can have product manager, senior product
manager, all that stuff, but I would not
confuse people with the two different titles
of product owner versus product manager.
But importantly, there's a bar for who
is called a product manager because
if you take a product owner as you've
said, and say you're a product manager,
they're going to be a terrible product manager.
Your advice is make them an associate PM, and then
once they reach a certain level,
they've graduated to product manager.
It depends. I don't say this as a hard and fast
rule because there are product owners out there
who've been doing their job very well. Just
because they have a title of a product owner
doesn't mean that somebody can't do the job of a
product manager. There are plenty of people out
there who were just named this because a company
names them that and they know what they're doing,
so don't look at that hard and fast. When we
do this, we typically will say everybody's
got product owner on their title, change
it to product manager, but we will go back
and look at what is the actual skillset.
When I've come in to work with companies
on transformations, what we typically do,
the way I get introduced usually is we come
in and they're looking for some kind of
training for all of their product teams,
and then we bring in Product Institute and
we do our online training, Then afterwards
I work with the organization, I say, "Now that
everybody's been baselined and trained, we have
to figure out who is going to be a great product
manager and who's not," so there's an awareness.
You know what's interesting? Once people figure
out what the job's about, a lot of them opt out.
When I did the transformation at Athenahealth,
we had 365 product managers and they all had
different titles too, product innovation, all over
the place. We turned them into product managers,
we trained everybody, we gave everybody the
opportunity to learn, which I think is great,
and then we gave them opportunity to
practice their skills. What happened
is at the end of the training, a lot of
people raised their hand and said, "Oh, no,
no, this is not what I wanted to do. I thought
it was very different. I did not realize how
much people work it was. I have to go influence
these people, I have to do all this stuff. This
is actually not really what I wanted to do."
We found other roles for them that were what
they wanted to do or they decided to leave.
That was up to them, we didn't cut anybody,
but we moved some people into operations because
they wanted to be a little more heads down to
find process. That was their thing. We moved
people into data roles who were good with SQL
and were good with data analysis. We moved
people into user research roles because they
wanted to talk to customers, but they didn't
want the responsibility and the accountability
that came with the product management piece
because they realized it was so intense.
I've seen this happen a lot in large
organizations. You baseline everybody,
you show them what the role is and then you
let them go practice it, and then at that point
some people will opt out and then you have to go
back through your people and say, "Okay. How do
we level-set now? Who's doing really well? Who's
not doing so well? Which teams need to have more
experienced people on it because they don't have
anybody to learn from?" That's where we would say,
"Hey, let's hire some ICs over here or a director
of product management who can help train these
people and help them keep growing." That's been
super successful. I've seen people bring in
some more directors, scattered them around,
and they've leveled up these product owners
who were not necessarily doing great product
management and now they're doing fantastic.
I've watched fantastic leaders in these
organizations that are not software native or
doing these transformations. Bringing the right
person, you can make amazing product managers.
Give them a year or two and completely
turn it around. It's totally possible.
It's totally possible to take people and
train them, and I firmly believe in that,
but you got to get them exposure
to what good looks like. If you are
in an organization and you cannot
see what good looks like anywhere,
that's a red flag. That's where leaders
need to look at their organization and say,
"Do I have people with these skills interspersed
around so that everybody can start to learn,
so that everybody can actually be on the uptake
of this and make sure that we are well-balanced?"
That was an awesome nuance and addition. I'm just
looking back at all the things we've talked about.
We've covered so much ground, the history of
agile and Scrum and SAFes and product owners,
we've gotten into all kinds of advice on
how to do this better as a company leader,
as a product owner, as someone thinking about
even moving through product management. Is there
anything else that we have not covered that you
think might be helpful to touch on or wrap up on?
I think I would tell people to remember
that when you look at agile methodologies,
and if you look at it with small agile, what
we are really saying there is we want to be
able to move quickly and deliver great value
to customers. If you embrace those principles,
you're going to do well, but if you think
of agile as just a defined super cut and
dry process where you have to follow
every single little step here and there,
that's not going to serve you because you're
not getting back into why are we doing this.
There are some great agile coaches out there.
There are first principle approaches to doing
great product work and doing great development
work. They're there because they are not just
selling Scrum, they are there to make people
better. Those agile coaches I think can make
great fantastic teams, and I've worked with a
lot of them, and I think they are really there
to just make it a better environment for the
people who are working and to help the company
produce better products. That's their whole goal.
Then there are people too who are wedded to this
is SAFe and you will do it by the book. This is
Scrum, you will do it by the book. I'd be very
skeptical of that because what's the end goal?
What's their end goal? Like I said, a lot of
people out there get paid by certifying people
and by consulting on these processes. McKinsey
made a huge division to do this, and a lot of
SAFe was actually introduced to organizations
from McKinsey and from large organizations,
consulting organizations like that. They came
in and they said, "Yeah, this is what you do.
I'll teach you how to do SAFe, I'll teach you
how to do Scrum." They have been building those
consulting agencies off of agile transformations.
We always laugh when I talk to other people who've
been doing transformations and coaches. I go,
"Why is McKinsey always coming in here
and doing this?" I've followed them into
so many organizations and I've been like, "Oh,
wow, they screwed this up. Let me go fix it."
There's always a saying that nobody gets
fired for hiring McKinsey. McKinsey's big,
people trust their name. A lot of the people at
McKinsey haven't done this before, they've never
been inside the organization trying to transform
it and stay there for a long time. That's why I'd
be really skeptical of who's selling that.
If you approach agile from a perspective of
I want to be agile because I want to release
things quickly and get feedback from customers
and make sure that that's great, look at
all of your processes like that and say,
"Is that serving the best interest of our company
and our culture and our customers? Is this making
our customers proud of us? Is this helping our
customers receive good value?" If your processes
aren't, fix them, change them, inspect and adapt,
ease a lowercase agile principle. We should be
looking at every process we do and saying, "Is
it working?", and not be afraid to change it.
I think it's important to highlight this can
work. There are ways to reorganize the way you
build product at a very large company where you
can actually deliver great product consistently.
You've seen that happen a lot. Anything
you want to add there to give people hope?
Yeah. The biggest pushback I hear from large
organizations, especially ones that are not
software native as banks or insurance companies,
whatever it is, is that we're not like Google,
we're not like SaaS companies. It's true, you're
not a SaaS company. The way that you do it is
going to be slightly different than the way that
Amazon runs or the way that Google runs. I don't
see many companies actually run the same, and just
because it works at Google doesn't mean it's going
to work at an insurance company that's a hundred
years old. That's okay, but you could still learn
from people who've been producing software at
scale for many, many years. You can still learn
what makes them successful, and then you could
take some of those principles and apply them
to your organization and then figure out where
we need to adapt. That's what I would look at.
I see software strategies and digital strategies
becoming so intertwined into the strategies of
companies in general, whether you're an
insurance company or a bank or anything.
They're becoming so heavily entwined in the
C-suite strategies. The first thing I would say,
and where I see a lot of companies struggle with
this is you have to make sure that it is thought
of at the C-suite. What some organizations do is
go, "Oh, no, that's IT work. Let me push all the
software strategy down." If you're doing that,
you're missing out on innovation, and this is
where the product role comes in and where I think
more organizations need chief product officers
because they're the person in the C-suite saying,
"How can software enable us to be 10 times better
and crush our competition, whether we're a bank
or insurance company or a pharmaceutical company?
What can we do with our software that's
going to put us ahead of the competition,
that's going to put us ahead of the market?"
If you're not having those conversations when
you're thinking of your long-term
company strategy, you're behind,
you're behind because that is what every small
high-growth startup is doing that's coming out
to try to disrupt these big companies. The
big companies are successful, they have a lot
of money so they don't have as much urgency as
sometimes these smaller companies do to change
or somebody who's failing to change. That's why
things are going so slow, but at the same time,
if we don't pay attention to that and we're not
considering it, that's where the danger comes in.
I imagine people are going to have a
lot of questions and hope to get even
more advice. A couple of final questions.
Where can folks find you online if they want
to ask more questions along these
lines, maybe get your help on some
of this stuff? Then finally, how can
listeners be useful to you, Melissa.
You can find me on LinkedIn. If you go search for
Melissa Perri with an I, P-E-R-R-I, you'll find
me there. My LinkedIn is /melissajeanPerri.
I'm happy to connect with people there. My
school is called Product Institute, so if you're
interested in doing product management training
or getting help with some of this stuff, go to
productinstitute.com and reach out to me. I run
a podcast too called The Product Thinking
Podcast. We answer questions every week,
and a lot of them are around SAFe, agile
and all these topics, so if you have a
question and you're saying, "Hey, how do I do
this?", definitely reach out and let me know.
Awesome. Melissa, I learned a lot. I feel like
a lot of people who listen to this podcast,
they're like, "I had no idea about any of
this, and now I understand all these terms
that I kind of hear occasionally." Thank you
for coming and sharing all of this with us,
especially the advice for folks
that are in this world right now.
Yeah. Thanks for having me.
Bye everyone.
Bye.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to the show
on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.