Hey everyone. We're here on Lenny's podcast.
It's great to be here. I'm a long-time listener.
So awesome. Really is. We're the hosts
of a different show, of Deep Dive.
And we just wanted to say thanks. A huge,
huge thank you to everyone.
Everyone who's been listening.
Yeah, seriously, it's been incredible. Just
incredible. And thank you to Lenny for having us.
Blown away really by the response and all the
shows you've all had us make on NotebookLM,
even that poop fart one. Remember that?
Oh yeah, that was something.
Learned a lot on that one.
Definitely a learning experience
for everyone, I think.
But we're learning right alongside you.
Exactly. Learning and growing.
And we're glad you're along for the ride.
So yeah, keep listening?
Keep listening and stay curious. We promise to
keep diving deep and bringing
you even more in the future.
Stay curious.
If you are confused about what you just
heard, don't worry, it'll all make sense
very soon. Today my guest is Raiza Martin. Raiza
is product lead for a product called NotebookLM,
one of the most delightful and inspiring new
AI products out there incubated within Google
Labs. And this product is where the intro you
just heard came from. In our conversation,
Raiza shares how NotebookLM
came to be, how it got so good,
the technology that was necessary to make
it possible, how the team works internally,
how it was incubated specifically within Google
Labs and out of the team's 20% time, plus a bunch
of really fun and crazy use cases that she's
seen and a glimpse into where the product is
going long-term. This was such a fun and timely
conversation and I'm excited to spread the love
for NotebookLM. If you enjoy this podcast, don't
forget to subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. It's the best way to
avoid missing future episodes and it helps the
podcast tremendously. With that, I bring you
Raiza Martin. Raiza, welcome to the podcast.
Hi Lenny, thanks for having me.
What the heck did we just
listen to? What was that?
So that was an audio overview from
NotebookLM where you upload a source,
any source, and it will generate
an AI generated audio for you.
Okay. So for folks that don't
know anything about NotebookLM,
it's basically been blowing up on Twitter,
on LinkedIn. I think it's blowing a lot of
people's minds. It's sparking a lot of
imagination of what could happen in AI
and what potential we have with the stuff
that's happening. And I wanted to bring you
on to talk about the history of this product,
where it's going, how it became so great,
and all these things. And so thanks for doing
this. I know this kind of came on short notice.
Yeah, I mean, I was excited to do it
in particular because I'm a big fan,
big listener of Lenny's, read the newsletter.
I love it. So really happy to be here.
Awesome. Clearly these hosts are
too, which I love. By the way,
I love the slight awkwardness at the end of their
conversation, if folks rewind, they could hear it
again because it's very relatable. I sometimes
have trouble ending a podcast conversation and
they're like, "Okay, let's say a couple
more things and then, okay, we're done."
It's funny because I've listened
to so many of these and they do
have catchphrases they say at the end, and
stay curious is one of my favorite ones.
Well, let me just ask, is that something you all
told them to do or is that
like an emergent property?
So in this case, this is based on what they think
is the most appropriate thing to say at the end.
Okay, interesting. Okay.
This episode is brought to you by Explo,
a game-changer for customer facing analytics
and data reporting. Are your users craving
more dashboards, reports, and analytics within
your product? Are you tired of trying to build
it yourself? As a product leader, you probably
have these requests in your roadmap, but the
struggle to prioritize them is real. Building
analytics from scratch can be time-consuming,
expensive, and a really challenging process.
Enter Explo. Explo is a fully white labeled
embedded analytics solution designed entirely
with your user in mind. Getting started is easy.
Explo connects to any relational database or
warehouse, and with its low-code functionality,
you can build and style dashboards in minutes.
Once you're ready, simply embed the dashboard
or report into your application with a tiny
code snippet. The best part, your end users
can use Explo's AI features for their own report
and dashboard generation, eliminating customer
data requests for your support team. Build and
embed a fully white labeled analytics experience
in days. Try for free at explo.co/lenny.
That's E-X-P-L-O dot C-O slash Lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Sprig. What
if product teams knew exactly what to build
to reach their goals? From increasing conversion
to boosting engagement, these challenges require
a deep understanding of your users, something
that you can't get from product analytics alone.
Meet Sprig, a product experience platform
that generates AI-powered opportunities
to continuously improve your product at scale.
First, Sprig captures your product experience in
real-time through heat maps, replays, surveys, and
feedback studies. Then Sprig's industry-leading
AI instantly analyzes all of your product
experience data to generate real-time insights.
Sprig AI goes even further with actionable
product recommendations to drive revenue,
retention and user satisfaction. Join
product teams at Figma and at the Notion
by uncovering AI powered product opportunities
at scale. Visit sprig.com/lenny to book a demo
and get a $75 gift card. That's
S-P-R-I-G dot com slash Lenny.
I want to start with just the history of this
product. I think for a lot of people it just came
out of nowhere. It's like what the, wow, where
did this come from? This is blowing our mind.
Rarely is anything actually like that. Rarely is
it just like we built it over a week and then it's
taken over the internet. Talk about just the
history of NotebookLM and the team behind it.
Yeah, yeah. Thank you. Actually, Notebook started
as a 20% project as things kind of do with Google,
as they used to. And it's funny because I wouldn't
even call it a 20% because it was way more than
that. So I'll start from my perspective where I
was leading AI Test Kitchen, which was one of the
first AI things we launched at Google. And this
was I think maybe two I/Os ago or maybe three now,
actually. I think it was in '22.
And I was leading that project
and I remember there was a smaller project
inside of Labs called Talk to Small Corpus,
and there was the idea that you could take a
piece of content and use an LLM to interact
with it. We were like, okay, there's a nugget
there that sounds interesting. How do we keep
revving on this to make it actually really useful?
And it was just myself, an engineer and eventually
Steven Johnson joined. And it was really funny
because the only person who was actually really
full-time on this was the engineer working on
the technology, and everybody else was kind of
just coming together, really chiming in, being
like, "Hey, this is super interesting. How do
we make this better?" So it really started as a
20% and then it kind of just blew up from there.
That's insane that it was just you, an engineer,
and then Steven Johnson, I want to talk about his
role, that it's like one engineer can build
something like this, and I imagine it's more
now that it's starting to take off or what's
the team looking like these days roughly?
We've had a lot more folks join in the
last month, and a lot of that is really
in anticipation of the future roadmap.
But up until this point I'd say we didn't
even have 10 engineers. When we launched it
actually, when we announced Project Tailwind,
I think we only had three. We had three
engineers. It was myself, we had a designer,
we had Steven, and that was it. And so even
between the period when we did the first
I/O last year to as recently as last month,
we've only had about eight engineers or so.
Let's talk about Audio Overviews, specifically
this kind of podcast feature. And I think
Audio Overview is the technical name,
right? Is that how you describe it?
Yes.
Okay. They call it a Deep Dive, right?
That's like their name for the podcast.
They do, yeah, that's what we call it.
How did that specifically
come about? When did that
become a thing? What was the beginnings of that?
We announced, we actually did a preview of this
in I/O this year, so in May. And the way that it
worked out is Notebook had already been launched.
We had a bunch of people using it. It was this
source grounded chat interface and we were looking
at basically what are the new models coming out
of Google? We had Gemini 1.5 coming out. We had
all of these new technologies that are basically
upgrades on fundamentally the same thing.
And we were like, what are some interesting
ways that we could power NotebookLM
or make it even better? And one of
the things that we started playing around with
is actually a different team inside of Google,
inside of Labs specifically, they were like, "Hey,
we've got these really powerful audio models,
what's a really good application of this?" And
that's when we started riffing and we were like,
"Hey, what if you could, basically what you
see today, give it a little bit of information,
you don't have to do a lot. You can just
enter a URL, upload your resume, and then
it will completely generate something for you
that could be unexpected, could be a surprise?"
Okay. So it started, basically there
was a technology that we think could
be really interesting. Was there a problem
you were trying to solve with this team,
with this initiative? It was within Google Labs,
which I know is a little bit probably less like,
we need to drive business outcomes. What was the
original thesis or problem you were going after?
So this is really funny. I talk about this quite
a lot, especially when I'm talking to other PMs. I
feel like the way that I've always built products
is I start from a problem and I think about the
solutions to solve it, solve it for people in
a meaningful way. And in Labs in particular,
we start with the technology. And it's actually a
very interesting place to start where you're like,
okay, what are the practical applications to this?
How do I go about finding the answer? And I think
we've seen different approaches to this where
you just put the tool out there, you study how
people are using it, and I think that's a fine
approach, but we try to have a little bit more
of a hypothesis about what is the shape of this
thing to actually get the most learning out of it.
So for the audio feature in particular, the
nugget there was really, we had this ability
for you to interact with text, but people were
like, "The output is still always text." And I'm
actually a big fan of voice modality in general,
so I use a lot of voice input. And voice output,
I noticed when I was experimenting with it early
on, it changed a lot of things for me. It's like,
oh, it changes the way that I interact with the
technology, it changes the way I feel about the
technology. It sort of affects the way that
I'm even thinking in real-time throughout
this process. And so we thought about what is a
good way to introduce this to people where they
could easily get the value of it and have a little
bit of fun? So I think for me it's fun is such a
big part of it too, which is like how do we make
this cool? And so hopefully we've done that here.
To me it feels very similar to the ChatGPT
moment where the technology already existed,
they had that same GPT model out for I don't
know how long, but just that new medium and new
way of interacting with it changed the way people
imagine. Just they saw the power immediately. And
I feel like this is such a good example of that
happening again where just the tech was there
and it's just this medium that you developed
that really inspired people to like, "Oh wow,
I had no idea AI was getting this good and LMs
were getting this good." Any thoughts on that?
Yeah, I think that totally strikes at the
heart of what we're trying to do as well,
which is a lot of technology I feel
like you have to shape it and bring
it closer to people. And I think it's such an
interesting thing to iterate on and be like,
"What is the shape?" Soon you'll get there.
If you keep going at it, you'll eventually,
I think, land on something that when people
look at it, they're like, "Wow, I get it."
And that's always what we're hunting for. But I
think to your point, technology has been there.
I mean it feels so crazy to say that because
even with the advent of the chatbots of LLMs
as we know them today, and then to introduce
this sort of new technology on top of it, we've
only been doing this for two years, but already
we're exploring so many different ways to use it.
Yeah, it's such an unintuitive but clever idea
of making something a podcast. Let's take a
tangent into the technology behind this thing.
So there's kind of two questions I'm thinking
about. One is just what technology needed
to exist for this to be possible? And then
two is just what did you do to make this so
good? How did you train this model to create
a podcast that's this good? So we could start
with the first and then get into the second.
Yeah, I mean that's such a great question. I
mean truly the Gemini models are so powerful
and we use Gemini 1.5 Pro as sort of the base
for NotebookLM, and then we have a powerful
voice model on top of it, an audio model on
top of it. But I think the real secret sauce
to what makes this really good is something
we've built, which is a content studio.
And you kind of see a clue of this inside
NotebookLM where when you open up Notebook Guide,
Notebook Guide is designed to take an opinionated
approach to the content that you've given it.
And what it's really trying to do is be as
helpful as possible. It gives you a summary,
gives you buttons where if you click on it, it'll
write something for you. And the audio is a big
part of that. And so this was very interesting for
us because we had to think about what shape should
that audio be in? The deep dive is the first
format we've thought about. And we actually
have a super talented engineer on our team, his
name's Usama, and he's the real craftsman behind
thinking through Content Studio and thinking about
what makes something really relatable to people in
a way that's engaging, that's interesting.
So content studio is the real magic here.
So when you say content studio,
what does that mean? What does
that actually look like? What is a content studio?
I can't share too much about how Content
Studio works, but you can imagine it's the
same thing that powers all of NotebookLM,
which is there's different ways that you
could interact with your data. You could like Q&A
inside of NotebookLM, but then there are places
where you just want to push a button and create
something new. So Content Studio was connected.
Okay. So this is the interface you use to
interact with NotebookLM and the different
prompts and the recommendations
of how to ask questions and-
Yeah.
Okay, got it. And then specifically in terms
of the way these hosts interact and talk,
if you listen to these podcasts, it's
like they laugh and they're like,
"Hmm," and they interrupt each other a little
bit and they get surprised and they have these
inflections that are really amazing. What did
you have to do to make them sound this good?
I know you said you can't share tons,
but just anything there you can share?
I mean, that's the model, that's the
audio model that we use. Alongside,
the Content Studio is designed to
bring out the best of that model.
And I think when we listened to a lot
of the early attempts that we had,
it wasn't nearly this good. And so we had to
do a lot of listening to try to figure out how
do we actually get the model to behave in this
way? And that's where I think the magic happens.
That's amazing. Do you all
just listen to a bunch of
podcast episodes and hear something that
really... Yeah. Okay, shaking your head.
I think the funniest thing was
that... So my husband doesn't know,
right? He doesn't know what I'm doing. Most
of the time I try not to talk about work at
home. And so I would listen to these audio
overviews over and over at home and I get
tired of wearing my headphones, so I'm just
listening to them out loud, and he is like,
"What is this thing you were listening
to? This is an ever-running podcast about
nothing." And it was just super funny. I had
to be like, "Oh, it's just something I have
to do for work." So it was pretty funny. He
actually couldn't tell that they were AI.
I love that. So one of the ways I've
been playing around with it a bunch,
one of the ways I used it is my
mom wrote this autobiography,
like a short autobiography of her life, and
we have the PDF of it. So I fed it into the
Notebook and then generated the podcast
and sent it through. Like what the heck?
That's amazing. What did she think?
She was blown away. She's showing all her
friends. She's like, "I don't know what's
going on here." And I love that it creates
a study guide, and that's one of the options
in the studio. And so I sent her the study guide
and she's like, "Okay, at a Rosh Hashanah dinner,
we're going to be reviewing the study guide about
my biography. We're going to talk about this."
That's pretty funny. That's super
cute. I did it for my dad too.
What did you do?
I actually took my dad's bio. So he worked at
a hospital and he has a bio for the doctors
that they have there. And I put his bio and I
generated an audio overview for him. And it's so
funny because my parents are both in the medical
field, I don't think they fully know what I do. I
think this is the first time they were like, "Oh,
that's super interesting. That's what you do."
So maybe along these lines,
what are some other surprising,
hilarious use cases you've seen for
especially the audio deep dives?
I mean, I love the resume ones. I think the
resume ones are so delightful. And actually
really adjacent to that is Google has these
Q3 check-ins or quarterly check-ins where we
have to write performance reviews for
ourselves. And the amount of Googlers
that ping me that I don't even know and
they're like, "Wow, this was such a boost
to my confidence just to upload my own
check-in notes and then have it generate
an audio overview." It's like people are going
into meetings feeling really good about themselves
Because they heard these hosts get
really excited about their quarter and-
Their work, yeah.
And when you say resume, so people upload the
resume and then it describes you
in a really positive way, right?
Yeah. And I thought that was so interesting. I was
like, what was the use case? I think if I had to
guess, somebody probably was like, "Hey, I want to
try this new thing." Clicked on Upload Google Doc,
and maybe the last thing you had there was
your resume or something. But imagine you
click that and I think there's something really
special about, you don't know what's going to
happen. You just click generate and then you
have these two people just hyping you up.
Okay. I want to talk a bit more about how you
made this happen within Google. So as an outsider,
this does not feel like a Google product
and the way you all are operating feels
very startup-y. Like you're tweeting
daily about what's going on. I heard
there's a Discord server for folks
that are like, really... Is that right?
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, there is. It's pretty cool.
We have about 60,000 people in it.
Okay, wow. Okay, so yeah, so there's
this Discord server, it's just you're
shipping constantly. The product is just very
delightful and Google makes delightful products,
but this feels like a different realm of
delight. How are you able to do this within
Google? Is this a model for how you think Google
teams will want to operate more? Lessons there.
I mean, it's such a good question. I think
there's a question of how it came to be,
how we're able to operate in this way, and then
the question of, hey, is this how other Google
teams want to operate? And I think that to answer
the first part, I'll say that it's interesting
because Google Labs is only about three years
old. It's fairly new. And when I joined, there
was nobody here. There was no one. And the reason
why I joined was because my old boss went and
actually started it. And so this is Josh Woodward
who's the VP of Google Labs. And it's really
funny because, this is just a funny anecdote,
I remember I had no idea what Google Labs was,
but I liked my old boss so much that I was like,
"I'll just work on whatever he's working on.
Whatever his new idea is, I'll just do it."
And I remember when I joined, I was like,
"What's the mission? What are we here for?" And
he said, "It's AI. We're going to ship AI products
and we're going to build businesses out of them."
Okay, sounds good. Sounds good. It's like now I
have to study. I have to do a lot of studying. I
came from payments, I came from ads before that.
And so for me it was a little bit of a mental
shift, but before that I actually worked only
at startups. And so I felt like, hey, maybe this
is my chance to do zero to one again. And I was
really jazzed about that. And I remember talking
with Josh about this in the early days of like,
"Hey, if we really want to do zero to one,
we have to do things very differently."
And so as a result, I think that's why NotebookLM
is able to operate differently. It's because in
Labs we have the environment to do it, we have
the environment to move fast. We have far, far,
far fewer processes, maybe even to a fault.
Sometimes we'll go to meetings that are
literally the product managers, the engineers, the
designers all together, and we'll just crank on
the mocks and the PRDs at the same time. And eng
is basically already doing implementation as we're
meeting. And at Google, that's just not how things
are traditionally done, especially coming from the
previous organizations that I was at. It just
takes a lot of time to do each of these things.
So what I'm hearing, and this is great because
a lot of companies are trying to create teams
like this, "We're going to have a team off to
the side, going to work on crazy futuristic
stuff." Rarely do those work out. Even at Google,
there's been a lot of this in the past and rarely
do things actually work out. And so there's
a lot of lessons to learn from how this is
working. So a few things I'm noticing as you're
describing how this works, one is just very clear
expectations from a very senior leader, "Here's
a team, we're going to do things differently.
Here's things we're not going to do. We're not
going to go through regular pre-roll processes.
We're going to be public and build in public.
We're not going to have a goal necessarily.
We're going to work on cool technology and see
what happens." Also, you had a very small team,
feels like that was really key. One engineer
and then a PM and then Steven Johnson.
That's true, that's true. And I think one
big thing too is we got to try new things.
Even from the beginning I was like, "Hey, I
want to have a Discord. If we were building
outside of Google for sure we would have what
of these." And in true sort of Google fashion,
everybody was like, "What is Discord? Okay,
great, do it. But what is that again?"
Right, why not Google Meet?
And somebody did ask me, they were like, "Why
not a Google meet? Why not a Google group? Why
not this?" And I was like, "I don't even know
how to use these things outside." So I was like,
"The server is the way to go." And I
remember when we stood up the server,
actually, one of the things I was most afraid of
is, what if nobody joins? What if no people come
in and want to talk to us about the thing that
we built? And so that was in the early days,
very exciting to look back and remember
day zero and now have 60,000 people in it.
Let me tell you about a product called
Sidebar. The most successful people that
I know surround themselves with incredible
peers. When you have a trusted group of peers,
you can discuss challenges you're having, get
career advice and just gut check how you're
thinking about your work, your career, and your
life. This gives you more than a leg up. It gives
you a leap forward. Having a group of trusted
and amazing peers was key to my career growth.
And this is the Sidebar ethos, but it's hard to
build this trusted group of peers on your own.
Sidebar is a platform for senior tech
professionals, director to C-level,
to advance in their career. Members are matched
into peer groups to lean on for unbiased opinions,
diverse perspectives and raw feedback guided by
world-class programming and facilitation, all
running on Sidebar's technology. Sidebar enables
you to get focused, tactical feedback at every
step of your career journey. If you're a listener
of this podcast, you're already committed to
growth. Sidebar is the missing piece to catalyze
your career. 93% of members say Sidebar helped
them achieve a significant positive change in
their career. Check them out at sidebar.com/lenny.
Okay, so there's 60,000 in this Discord
server. Any other traction numbers you
can share? It feels like it's just going
really well. I know there's probably a lot
of sensitive information. Anything you can
share about just how well things are going?
Couple of things. Well, I'll tell you three
things. I think the first is, I can't share the
exact numbers, but for a product that's only been
out for about a year, I think the rate at which
our retention has gone up across the typical
measures, daily retention, weekly retention,
monthly retention, that I think has been very,
very positive for us in terms of even when we
talk to stakeholders, we say, "Hey, we've got
something here." The second thing I'll say is
even seeing how the demographics have changed,
where I think in the beginning we saw educators,
learners really loved the product and they were
a lot of our demographic. It's really now a big
mix of, I would say educators and learners are
still a big part of it, but really professionals,
right? Huge interest from professionals that
are like, "Wow, I want to use this to work."
And really funny, I won't mention the company,
but I actually had a call with a company recently
where they were like, "Hey, we thought we'd
schedule a meeting with you because we found out
that a bunch of people in our company are using
this tool with their Gmail account." They're like,
"They're not supposed to do that, so we just
want to make it official that they can use
this at work with their official work email." So
I thought that was pretty cool. And then the third
thing I'll say is the number of businesses that
we've seen using NotebookLM, it's astronomical.
It's just like crazy. I think we went, I don't
want to say the exact numbers, but it is now
at a point where I have to hire a business
development person because I was like, hey,
I have to ship products and I'm actually taking
customer calls every day now. Very, very exciting.
I could see the path to monetization clearly,
enterprise features, single sign-on and SOC 2
and all these things. Along those lines, what
does success look like for this team and for
you? I know initially it was probably just
build interesting things, see what happens.
Is there now a clear sense of here's what
this team should be achieving in the future?
When I joined, my mandate was to build
a business, and I was like, all right,
if we break down the steps here, along the way
I have to build something interesting first. I
feel like, okay, we hit the first thing, we built
something interesting, now we go figure out the
business. And I think that comes naturally to
Google in terms of thinking about distribution,
how to monetize it, how to commercialize it.
There's different pathways, whether it's cloud
or workspace or even the consumer route. And
so for me, I think these are the things that
we want to be really thoughtful about because the
machinery is already there. And for me personally,
it's really about there's something super
exciting here, we need to deepen that,
right? While in parallel, we should be
thinking about commercialization. Let's
deepen this user experience that so
many people have really latched onto.
So let's follow this thread and talk
about just where you think the product
goes broadly and especially the audio
overviews. What's on the roadmap near-term,
and then where do you imagine this
in the future? What's the big vision?
Yeah, yeah. I have a really ugly slide I wish I
could show you. I made it two years ago and it
was lime green. I don't know what I was thinking.
I think I was trying to go for un-Googly was the
vibe. It's like, hey, you're going to do different
things this time. And the reason why that slide is
so important to me is because it has my vision.
The thing that I wanted to do from the get-go,
which was I imagine that in the future you could
have an AI editor surface, fully remixable,
any input, any output. And that to me is a
really powerful core nugget where if you imagine
you could take anything, whether it's video,
audio, your emails, your LinkedIn, your Twitter,
the world of things that we care about, you have
an AI interface that allows you to shape it and
say, "Look out of these things, make me a blog
post. Out of these things, make me a tutorial
video. Out these things, make a chatbot."
I think there's something interesting here
where for most of the things that I'm hearing
people say they want to do, it's usually that.
It's take something and make it into something
new. And so we're going to pursue that. But even
more technically, something I'm really interested
in is thinking about, "Hey, how do we bring this
to mobile?" The mobile app to me is such a big gap
in terms of the experience today, which I think is
understandable considering where we're at in the
product development cycle, but I think that's the
next horizon is, hey, how different is the mobile
experience and how can we make it interesting?
What I'm imagining as I talk,
I participate in this podcast conversation
with these hosts as a mobile experience.
Yeah, yeah. I mean, that's one of the things that
we're definitely experimenting with different
formats. And when we demoed it at I/O, you could
interrupt it, but we're trying to be really
thoughtful about, hey, what does that interrupt
actually look like? What do people want when they
do this? And I was thinking about the next set of
improvements we're going to ship, and the first
thing that I thought was, let's ship a bunch of
knobs. To me, it was what I was hearing people
wanted, they want knobs, they want sliders, they
want text boxes. But then when I looked at the
mocks, I was like, oh, this is great. This doesn't
feel magical. It almost doesn't feel like the same
thing that we've shipped so far. And so for me,
I'm actually taking a little bit of time to think
about how do we make even that thing and control
experience much more magical and delightful.
Interesting. So yeah, the knobs I
imagine are just like go deeper,
be happier, get more serious. Yeah, because
right now it's like a one shot. Here's my doc,
here's the one podcast episode you get.
It's the only version you can have.
Yeah, yeah. And I think it's
funny because I was like,
the knobs seemed really apparent and I was
like, is that it? Is that what people want?
I love that. I love that approach. I'm excited to
see where you go with it. What I especially love
about this vision you're describing, it super
resonates with this insight I've had. So I've
had a newsletter and then I had just a podcast
that's just audio, and then I added video and
I realized that there's just people that I just
want to watch stuff and there's people that I just
want to listen to stuff and then there's people
I just want to read. I don't want this podcast,
just shut up. I want to read it. And
basically what you're describing is,
well, here's information and we can deliver
it to you in any medium you like. It could be
blog posts, could be maybe a tweet, could be
a podcast, could be a newsletter, blog post.
Yeah. I mean that's exactly it. And I think even
for myself, it depends on my mood. If I'm going
on a walk, yeah, I want audio, but if I'm at work,
yeah, most of the time text is good. And then it's
kind of interesting to think about today the
formats are not as malleable. I have to accept it
in the format that you give it to me. But if I had
sort of that power myself to choose, "Hey, thanks
for this 100-page doc, I'm going to go ahead and
turn it into an audio overview actually." It sort
of shifts, I think, the dynamic between the person
and the knowledge that's given to them. And there
are actually many, many times that I've been
given 100-page doc and I just didn't read it.
So I wonder, I mean just frankly speaking, it's
one of my funny stories is actually when I first
joined Labs, Josh did give me a 50-page doc. He
was like, "Here's what I think about this and
this." It was basically his vision, and instead of
reading it, I just grilled him. I was just like,
Q&Aing him like a chatbot. Josh was like, "It's
in the doc, Raiza." But the chat is easier, Josh.
That's so funny. You chatbotted him. Let's
talk a little bit more about different use
cases for this just so people can potentially
get inspired. So it feels like the original
use case was a scientific paper and it
creates a podcast about it so you don't
have to read this whole thing. Was that
one of the original use cases or not?
I think it's one of the common use cases.
I think that's one of the ones where I
think it's kind of interesting because it's like
everybody wants to catch up on the latest on AI,
we want to try to keep up to date on the published
papers, but most of the time reading the paper can
take time. It's dense, complex. You have to
break down the concepts in it, and I think
that's a highly sort of extensible use case. I
would say the number one use case is actually a
lot of students taking their study materials
and wanting to turn it into an audio guide.
So two recent use cases
that are hilarious/amazing,
just will point to people in the show
notes, just like they came to mind as
you were talking. One is Andrej Karpathy,
who's a leading AI thinker and big fan of
what you're building. He keeps tweeting about
how much he loves it all. He created this whole
podcast series on History of Mysteries, I
think it's called, History of Mysteries.
I'm sorry, it's Histories of Mysteries.
Where he basically took the Wikipedia
stories of all these mysteries of history
and then turned it into a 10-episode
podcast you could listen to on Spotify.
Yeah.
Amazing.
That was amazing. Actually when I saw it and
I was like, "Wow, this by itself is a great
product." And I think the original potato
podcast that we had created was actually,
I think it was because of the Wikipedia article
of the day, it was about potatoes. And so there
is something there. It's like, "Hey, if
you want to learn something new today,
maybe you can just listen to it on
your drive to work or something."
Yeah, it's so good. Okay. The
other one is the most funny is
someone just uploaded the words poop
and fart repeated for a long time,
and the host just came up with really
a kind of insightful analysis of it.
Yeah, actually when I saw that one, I was about to
go to bed and I was like, "All right, if I listen
to this now," and this is a negative one, "I'm
going to have to get my laptop and work because I
can't sleep. If I feel like there's something here
that's like we need to address right now, then I
was like, "Okay, I'm just going to do it."So I
listened to it and I listen to a lot of these
and they always make me feel some kind of way. I
laugh a little bit. There's one where it's like
they make scary voices. That one was cool too.
But this one was one of the ones where I genuinely
was just really delighted at the output because it
was so delightful. I don't know if you listened to
the whole thing, but there's a segment where
one of the speakers says, "Hey, it's kind of
like you lean into the bizarre," or something,
and they're describing walking past a shop that
was full of rubber ducks wearing costumes, and
they're like, "Oh yeah, it's silly, but you just
want to lean into it so I walked into the store."
And I was like, oh, it's a great analogy actually
for sort of a document that just says poop
and fart. There's something interesting here.
It's so good. And just their analysis
of structure and patterns. I love that
they have to come up with a 10-minute
conversation around anything you give
them. It feels a little mean, but they find a way.
Yeah. It's true. I don't know if you've seen the
chicken one, but it's pretty similar. Somebody
uploaded, I think it's on Threads, it's a
PDF that looks a lot like a research paper,
but it just says chicken. The whole
document says chicken. I would give it
a listen. There's a funny segment where
they're like, "Get this. It's a paper,
a research paper that has more chicken in it than
KFC." What? Pause, god, that's good. It's so good.
Oh my god. Okay, I could keep going about
this all day, but let me come back to the
team that's working on this and let's talk
about Steven Johnson's role. So he's basically
your peer. You two essentially lead this
with the engineer, I imagine. Just like
what's his role? How does this work at this
point? What is the team looking... look like?
It's so funny, I'm so fond of Steven and
I tease him a lot that whenever people
ping me and they want to have a meeting and I
don't want to go to the meeting, I say, "Oh,
I'm not the PM, it's Steven Johnson. Talk
to that guy." And he was like, "So that's
why all these people have been picking me." But
kidding aside, Steven joined, I was like, well,
this is super interesting. This has never happened
to me before. There's this very accomplished,
distinguished person that I really respect, love
his books, love his writing, and now he's going to
come work with me in a capacity where I was like,
I'm just not sure what he's going to do here.
But the thing about Steven is he is the most
curious, most respectful, and really just full
of ideas kind of person. And so when Steven
joined, a lot of what was really interesting
to me is I would watch how he worked, the way that
he thought about language, the way that he thought
about information, the way that he thinks about
knowledge and sharing that with others. Because
Steven's books are really incredible. It's like
part mystery, super science. It's just very cool.
And I was watching the way that he works and
he does all of this research, and I thought,
maybe this is the nugget, right? Maybe
I watch Steven and I look at the way
that he does these things and I look at
how much time it takes for him to do it,
and then I make it my own metric to crunch
that down, to bring that expertise to everyday
people who are not Steven Johnson. And so
I learned a lot just from watching Steven,
of his craft and thinking about, okay, how do I
make people really, really good at de-densifying
information? Because that's something we
all do every day, in our own little ways.
Maybe not in a Steven Johnson way. But from the
get-go, I told him this. I was like, "Steven,
I think you are the product. I think it's you.
I'm going to follow you around. I'm going to watch
everything that you do and we're going to try to
figure out how we use technology to build it."
And he always laughs about this, and it's really
funny because he does have some very interesting
workflows that I'm like, I do not see any person
ever doing anything like this. He always talks
about his Readwise with his 8,000 quotes or
something. I'm like, that's extreme. That's
crazy. I have post-its that sometimes they're
crumpled in my pocket. This is the average normie
flow. And what I learned from Steven is like,
hey, there's something powerful about doing that,
thinking about this person who has a super flow
and trying to bring that to people. And so Steven
is also just such a great partner with ideas.
I always tell him ideas and I'm like, "Hey,
crazy idea of the day." And he'll just banter
with you and he'll be like, "Well, what about
this? How can people do this?" And so it feels
really incredible to have them on the team.
Is there any lessons here for how you think you'll
want to build product in the future or
how teams might find their own Steven
for building their own product? Or is
this kind of a unique case you think?
I mean, it's just crazy to think that you could
sort of invite someone like Steven become part
of your team and have him sit with you every
day and have him answer your questions about
how he does things right. But I'll say that the
broader lesson there for me, and it's something
we've tried to live by every day, is really
the how do you get users or people and really
sit with them for meaningful periods of time?
Because I think that has been so crucial for
me, and not even just for Steven, but even
with students, just follow students around,
watch them do homework, watch them study, talk
to them about how they feel when they study.
I think just being able to do that at a
really regular and intentional capacity
makes a huge difference in terms of the
product insights you'll come up with.
Can you just give a brief bio of
Steven for folks that are like,
who are you even talking about?
I probably should have done that
before I asked this question, but just like
what's the TL;DR of who Steven Johnson is?
Yes. Oh, I think Steven is... aside from
one of the smartest people you'll ever meet,
he has written 14 books, he's a New York Times
bestselling author and speaker. He has a show
on PBS, I can't remember what it's called,
but it's on YouTube, it is really incredible,
and he is a journalist. Actually, funny story
about Steven is when I was about to join Labs,
I really wanted to join Labs because I wanted to
join Josh and whatever he was building, Josh told
me, "Hey, to give you an idea of what we're doing
here," he sent me a couple of things to read.
And one of them actually ended up being Steven's
article that he wrote, the one about how AI is
mastering language, should we trust what it says,
the New York Times piece. And I remember reading
it and being like, yes, this is the thing. I'm
going to work on it. And so before Steven had
even joined, this was actually the piece that
I was like, I want to go do that. I'm going
to go do that in Labs. And then he ended up
joining and it was just the craziest thing.
That's so interesting. I imagine
many PMs would be like, "I don't
need someone on my team that isn't building
or coding or product managing or designing,
just this other chef in my kitchen. Like
no." And I love this actually worked out
really well. It feels like he's a perfect
combination of very smart future thinking,
insightful, plus he's almost a model for
what you want people to be able to work like.
Yes. Although I will say, to be very fair, I
mean Steven and I also disagree on a lot of
different things. We've clashed a bunch
and I think this is where I feel really
grateful to have had the opportunity to work
with him and to really grow with him in that
way. And I used to make fun of him and I
was like, "Have you ever had a coworker
before Steven? Because I think you've been an
author forever." And it's really funny because
he's so down to earth and he's so humble that
even with our disagreements, we always reach,
at the end we're always aligned. Even if we
don't agree about something, we're aligned on
the next step. And that's really powerful I think
particularly for product professionals, right,
for PMs where it's like, I don't want to disagree
at the end and then not have an outcome on top.
I love that. Okay, I have just a few more
questions. I know you have to get back to
work to building this thing. One is
there was this hilarious moment of
where the hosts basically realized, they're
like, "We are AI people, and I'm scared,
what's happening? I tried to call my wife
and she didn't answer." Talk about that,
and I want to extend to just like red teaming
this thing. How do you red team this thing and
make sure it's not doing things that are bad for
the world, bad for Google, bad for the product?
Yeah, yeah. It's such a good question.
I heard that, it was over the weekend,
I think it was on a Saturday or Sunday, and I
remember hearing it and thinking, oh my goodness,
this is actually one of those moments where you
feel like we're at a fork in the road. And I
hadn't read any of the comments, I just heard the
audio. I think I saw it on Reddit first, and then
I saw it blowing up on Twitter, and I remember
thinking, what is the attitude of the world now?
How do we feel about this type of audio? It was
really the first thing that I thought. And so I
actually spent most of that morning reading the
comments, reading on Twitter. I was thinking
about what is the right thing to do? Should
we say something? Should we not say something?
And I basically just went with what I thought was
the right thing to do, which is I think people
are getting to experience this technology
for the first time ever. And of course,
they're going to try to do things that are
maybe something that we didn't think about,
we didn't think they would do, or we didn't think
that they could do with the jailbreaks and stuff.
But I think that's such a natural part of human
curiosity, and I think there was a moment where
it's like, oh, do we pull this back? Because this
is like, oh, is this a safe thing? But because
the response I think was that people were like,
"Oh, it's saying that because of the sources,
this is no AI realized they were alive or
something. It's actually that it was in the show
notes. They were supposed to act this out." And
so I felt really much more confident that like,
oh, people get it, right? That's exactly what this
is. Somebody uploaded some notes and said, "Hey,
this is the end of the show, so make sure that you
act accordingly." And that for me was enough for
me to be able to say, okay, I'm going to address
this publicly and say something on Twitter and
make sure that people know that, hey, I've seen
it and I get it. This is what people do with it.
In terms of red teaming at Google though, what
I'll say is this is one of the things that we
care about the most. We have huge teams that work
on red teaming it. We test for about as many areas
as you can think of that we imagine we need to do
in order to make it safe. And I think certainly,
I think we'll run into situations where we
didn't think about that or we haven't tested
that to the fullest extent and we just add
it to the test cases. I think if there was
ever a scenario where we're like, "Oh, this
feels pretty unsafe," we would pull it back,
but I think hopefully we've built it in
such a way where we don't have to do it.
Awesome. Yeah, I love people are just looking
for ways to make it do stuff that feels wrong
when it's just like, hey, we're just summarizing
a thing for you in a really delightful way. Where
do things go from here? We talked about it
a bit. It sounds like maybe there's a mobile
app in the works, there's maybe non-knobby
knobs that you're working on to give people
more power. For folks that are just excited
about using this, where's it going? Who are
you aiming to build for? Just what should
people know about the future of NotebookLM?
If there's one thing I could say is that we
are continuing to learn from users every day,
so please keep using it. Please keep sharing
your feedback, whether it's on X or on Discord.
I'm there every day. Even if I don't respond,
I've read everything. And I say this in the most
non-creepy way possible, but I say this because
we are just very passionate about trying to build
the right thing, the best thing for everybody.
Kind of going back to sort of, hey, who are you
building for? I think that there's a lot of fun
use cases, but there's a lot of actually very
useful game-changing workflows in here, and so
we'll continue to build in that direction. I think
particularly for educators, for learners, for
professionals, knowledge workers, as we call them,
I think there's a lot there that we'll be able
to execute against in the very short term.
Amazing. Okay. Two final questions.
If folks want to give you feedback,
reach out, what's the best way to do that?
Is it DM you? Is it an email, something else?
Yeah, I mean, Discord. Join our Discord server.
Chime in. Yeah, we're there. You can add me or
yeah, X also, it's pretty good. I just came back
to it and I kind of feel like I don't really know
how it works now, so just a warning in case
you DM me, I might just not know how it works.
On Twitter you mean specifically?
On Twitter, on twitter, exactly.
And then final question, how
can listeners be useful to you?
I mean, please keep trying it. Try it, share
your feedback, whether you find it useful,
not useful, you think it's annoying, tell
me. These are the things that I've heard
for the last year that's helped me to
make it better. So if you're inclined,
please go ahead, try it, notebooklm.google.com.
Building an amazing product that is extremely
delightful. It's one of the most interesting
things on the internet today, which is
a very high bar, and you've done it,
and I'm really excited to see where it
goes. I'm going to keep playing with it.
I've been using it from my newsletter in a
really fun way, and so great work and keep
it up and we'll see where things go. Thanks for
coming on. I know you have a lot of work to do.
Oh, that's amazing. Thank you,
Lenny. Thanks for having me,
and thanks so much for your curiosity about it.
Stay curious. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe
to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.