You've co-founded 10 different companies. You've
been on the board of 20. You've also built two
unicorns including Waze. The biggest startup
lesson you seem to have taken out of that is to-
Fall in love, fall in love, fall in
love, fall in love with the problem,
and then actually what you're trying to do is
engage everyone else to fall in love with the
same problem, to go into this journey, into
this path and follow your leadership there.
Anything you wanted to share
around hiring and firing?
Every time that you hire someone
new, mark your calendars for 30
days down the road and ask yourself one
question, knowing what I know today,
would I hire this person? If the
answer is no, fire them immediately.
Let's actually talk about fundraising.
Most people are missing the most important slide
of their presentation is the first slide. This
slide is going to be presented for the longest
period of time. This is the place that you're
going to put your strongest point. Now the
second most important slide is the last one.
Today my guest is Uri Levine. Uri is the
co-founder of Waze and nine other companies.
He sold two companies for over a billion dollars.
He's also been on 20 different startup boards,
including a dozen he's still currently on. He's
also advised over 50 founders and startups over
his career. More recently, he wrote a book that
summarizes all of his advice for founders called
Fall in Love with the Problem, Not the Solution,
A Handbook for Entrepreneurs. In the foreword to
the book, Steve Wozniak said, "This book will
change your life and become your Bible if you
are an entrepreneur," and I cannot disagree with
that. This book is very tactical with amazing
stories and walks you through the ideation
phase all the way to exiting your company.
In my conversation with Uri, we chat
about many of my favorite chapters,
including why falling in love with the problem
is so important, how to find product market fit,
a really clever tactic for firing people
who aren't a fit for your company, a ton of
really genius tactical advice for improving your
fundraising pitch and so much more. With that,
I bring you Uri Levine, and if you enjoy this
podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow it
in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's
the best way to avoid missing future episodes and
it helps the podcast tremendously. Uri, thank you
so much for being here. Welcome to the podcast.
Thank you. Happy to be here.
Okay, so here's what I've
gathered about your career,
and let me know if I've missed anything.
You've co-founded 10 different companies,
including four you're still operating. You've been
on the board of 20 companies. You've advised 50,
maybe more, companies. You've also
built two unicorns, including Waze,
which you sold for over a billion dollars, which
back then was an astronomical amount of money.
It still is. So does that all sound right? Is
there anything big I missed about your career?
That sounds about right.
I think what's really interesting to
me is that from all of that experience,
the biggest startup lesson you seem to have
taken out of that is to fall in love with the
problem. It's what your book is called. You
have a T-shirt that you're wearing right now
that you wear on every podcast that says that
exactly. Clearly this lesson has struck a big
chord with you. I'm curious if there's
a moment where you realize that that's
the core and that's something that every
founder needs to get right. Is there an
aha moment or is it kind of this progressive
like, "Oh, wow, maybe this is the secret."
I'm not sure that this is a certain moment.
I think that that was evolving over time and
realizing that, look, at the end of the day, the
entrepreneurship journey is about value creation.
The simplest way to create value is solve a
problem. That's the simplest way. And in my
background, I'm an engineer always looking for the
simplest way, and solve a problem is the simplest
way, and so this is where fall in love with the
problem coming from, and people occasionally would
confuse the T-shirt with the book, and now the
T-shirt is about 10 or even more years old and the
book is only two years old, and so I was wearing
those T-shirts for a long while before I wrote the
book and when I wrote the book that was obvious
that this is going to be the name of the book,
but they are way more into that, right?
So when you fall in love with the problem,
then what happened is that the problem is going
to serve as the North Star of your journey,
and when you have a North Star, you're going to
make less deviation from the course and you are
way more likely to become successful. But also
the story that you are about to tell is way more
compelling. Just imagine that we will be here in
2007, just before I started Waze, and I will tell
you I'm going to build an AI crowd-source based
navigation system and you're going to say, "Oh,
yeah, very interesting," but you don't care. If
I will tell you I'm going to help you to avoid
traffic jams, then you do care, and when your
customer cares, they want you to be successful,
and when they want you to be successful, they
are going to help you to become successful.
And so in that sense, fall in love with the
problem is really a key to increase the likelihood
of being successful. So in general, all of my
startups start with a problem. Think of a problem,
a big problem, something that it's worth solving,
something that the world will become a better
place if you solve that and then ask yourself,
so who has this problem? If you happen to be the
only person on the planet with this problem, I can
recommend you a therapist. Don't build a startup.
It's way more expensive and takes way longer
period of time to build a startup. But if a lot of
people actually have this problem, what you really
want to do next is go and speak with those people
and understand their perception of the problem
and only then start to build the solution. If
you follow this path and your solution works,
it's guaranteed that you're creating value.
If you start with a solution, you might be
building something that no one cares and
that's really frustrating. So fall in love with
the problem. This is where you want to start.
Now this is really hard because I am getting tons
of emails every week from entrepreneurs and they
all start with what we are doing and I don't
really care what you're doing. What I really
care about is why you are doing that, and this
is the problem that you solve or the value that
you create or the value that you create for me.
This is what really matters, right? And so if you
start your story with, "Our company is," or, "Our
system is," and in the recent year everything is,
"Our AI system is," or, "Our AI company is." But
generally speaking, if you start your story with
that, you focus on your solution. If you start
with the story with, "The problem we are solving
is," Then you focus on the problem. If your
story start with, "The value that we create
for you is," then you focus on the user. The last
two are way better than focus on the solution.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta.
When it comes to ensuring your company has
top-notch security practices, things get
complicated fast. Now you can assess risk,
secure the trust of your customers and
automate compliance For SOC 2, ISO 27001,
HIPAA and more with a single platform, Vanta.
Vanta's market-leading trust management platform
helps you continuously monitor compliance
alongside reporting and tracking risk,
plus you can save hours by completing
security questionnaires with Vanta AI.
Join thousands of global companies that
use Vanta to automate evidence collection,
unify risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go to
Vanta.com/Lenny. That's V-A-N-T-A.com/Lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Mercury.
Mercury knows your financial operations are
complex. It doesn't have to be this way. I've
been a super happy customer of Mercury for over
a year now and it's honestly hard to imagine
a better online banking experience can exist.
Most founders and finance teams have to couple
together a patchwork of tools to reconcile
transactions from different sources, work
extra hard just to get a holistic view of cashflow
and have maps to company priorities and struggle
to get answers from platforms that all speak
different languages. Mercury knows that there's
an art to simplifying this complex patchwork.
With new bill pay and accounting capabilities,
you can pay bills faster, stay in control of
company spend and speed up reconciliation.
The end result is the precision control and focus
that startups need to transform how they operate.
Apply in minutes at Mercury.com and join over
200,000 ambitious startups like mine that trust
Mercury to get them to perform at their best.
Mercury, the art of simplified finances. Mercury
is a financial technology company, not a bank.
Banking services provided by Choice Financial
Group and Evolve Bank & Trust. Members FDIC.
I want to follow a couple threads here because
I imagine there's certain problems people fall
in love with. "Amazing. I want to solve this
very obscure problem for my family or a friend
of mine," and then they realize this is never
going to be a huge venture scale business, if
that's a goal of theirs. You talked about like,
make sure enough people have this problem
versus just getting a therapist that's
going to help you with this problem. What are
some signals and heuristics folks can use to
help them understand this is a big enough
problem that it's really worth their time?
So people ask me, "So you send me to speak with
users. How many?" And I will tell them a hundred.
You don't need a hundred, but the hundred
basically say you need to get out of your
comfort zone. It's not just your close friends and
family that you need to discuss that. You need to
discuss that with people that you don't know.
And usually what happen is, and the validation
is in most cases is really clear, right? If you
tell someone, "This is the problem I'm going to
address," and they will tell you, "Oh, I know
someone that has this problem," it's not a real
problem. If they will tell you, "No, no, no,
no, no. This is not the problem. The problem
is," and they will give you their description of
the problem. This is something that you really
want to follow. So if you speak with a hundred
people, but if you actually speak with 20 people
that you don't know, you will get validated
whether or not this problem is real or not.
And look, it's not the only way to become
successful, right? You look at one of the
most successful products in the world, the iPhone,
right? And you ask yourself, what was exactly the
problem when they started? And the answer is that
there was no problem when they started. There were
smartphones and people were actually very happy
with them. And so occasionally we need to invent
something completely new, but solving a problem
is simply the simplest way to create value.
Another element of picking a problem to work on,
so you say you fall in love with a problem. Is
being excited to work on this problem.
There's oftentimes problems you find that
aren't that exciting to you or you're not
excited to work on real estate software,
but you find there's a big problem. How
important is it that you're personally
passionate and excited to work on this thing
versus like, "Oh, wow. This is a huge business
opportunity. I got to go after it. It doesn't
matter if I'm not that passionate about it."
Fall in love, right? This is
really passionate. Really,
really passionate. Look, the journey
is really hard and complex and long
and so you have to be in love in order to go into
this journey because otherwise it's not going to
be successful. You really want to be passionate.
If you're not passionate about the problem,
even though that the problem might be real and
big and significant, there is not enough drive,
there is not enough internal drive to take
you through the hardship of the journey,
and so you need to be passionate. You need to fall
in love. You personally need to fall in love with
the problem. And then actually what you're trying
to do is engage everyone else to fall in love
with the same problem, to go into this journey,
into this path and follow your leadership there.
Is there an example of a pivot that you
maybe went through where you realized
the problem was not as big as you thought
or you realized there's a bigger problem?
So actually there are many, right?
So Oversee deals with maybe biggest
secret in travel industry. What happened to
airfare after you booked your flight? Now you
have no idea because you never compare
prices after you met the reservation.
But you know that airfare is going up and
down all the time. It's going up and down
before you are making the reservation and keep
on going up and down after you're making the
reservation. So if this is the price that
you paid and this is cancellation fees,
if the price drops here, you can rebook
the same flight at the cheaper price.
Genius.
If you would only keep on comparing prices
after that, right? So we started this company
that is actually monitoring your own itinerary
and we realized that this is going to be huge
benefits to travelers and we started that as a B2C
company, direct to consumers, and we realized that
even though the people really care, they are not
willing to take the action that is required, and
we ended up with doing that for corporates, and in
corporates there are very simple ways for them to
engage that automatically, so automatic rebooking
and so forth, and we can save corporates about 10%
of the travel budget that goes directly to bottom
line. So we started that as a B2C and then we
realized that this is way harder than we think it
is, and we ended up with converting that into B2B,
which turns out to be very successful for us.
And so occasionally there are companies that
you start your journey with one perception and you
change that and that will happen multiple times.
That's an awesome example. I want to, before I
move on to, I'm kind of thinking about this in
the phases of starting a company. So we're
talking right now about coming up with the
idea that you want to commit to. A lot
of people that want to start companies
are not sure how to find a great idea, so the
core advice you're sharing is find something,
find a problem, and fall in love with solving
that problem in whatever way you can. Do you
have any other advice for helping somebody
find a problem and finding a startup idea?
Where do you find startup ideas? What do
you find? What does work for you mostly?
So for me, it's usually personal frustration
that leads me to start to think about it,
whether or not we can change it. I hate traffic
jams, right? I hate leaving money on the table,
right? So there are many things that I ran into
and I get frustrated and I tell myself, "No, no,
no. There must be a different way to do that."
But in general, look, the problem itself needs
to start from you, right? Something that really
bothers you, something that you care about,
and then it's the validations of the
problem that you speak with many people,
try to realize. Now if you'll tell me, oh, this
is a B2B, then speak with many businesses, right?
Speak with those that you believe actually do have
this problem and I understand their perception.
Once you validate that, then there are few things
that you need to realize. One is about the journey
itself. This is going to be a multi-dimensional
journey. It's going to be at least three
dimensions and maybe fourth, right? So the three
dimensions, one of them is it's going to be a
roller coaster journey with ups and downs and ups
and downs. And look, if you'll tell me that all
the businesses in the world have ups and downs,
I agree, but the frequency of those when you are
building a startup? Way higher. I think that I
heard the best quote on that from Ben Horowitz,
Ben Horowitz from Andreessen Horowitz venture
capital firm, and before that he used to be
a CEO of a startup and he was asked whether or
not he was sleeping well at night and he said,
"Oh, yeah, I slept like a baby. I woke
up every two hours and cried." And that's
really the reality of that. The frequency of the
differences are so dramatic that there is nothing
compared to that, a roller coaster journey.
It's also a journey of failures. Look,
we are trying to build something new that no
one did before, and even though that we think
that we know exactly what we are doing, we don't.
So we try. We try one thing and it doesn't work.
We try another thing and it doesn't work. Or if
we keep on trying different things until we find
one thing that does work. Now, if you realize
that this is going to be a journey of failures,
then there are two immediate conclusions. The
first one is that if you're afraid to fail,
then in reality you already failed because you
are not going to try. Albert Einstein used to
say that if you haven't failed, that because you
haven't tried new things before. If you're going
to try new things, you will fail. Michael Jordan
used to say that, "I've failed over and over
and over and over again and this is what made me
successful." And so this is the first conclusion.
The second conclusion is that you really want
to fail fast. Just think about it, right? If
you fail fast, you still have plenty of time to
try another attempt and build another version of
the product. Try another go-to-market approach.
Try a different business model so you still have
plenty of time to make more and more and more
attempts, and the more attempts that you have,
you simply increase the likelihood of being
successful. Just think that you play basketball,
right, and you try to score from half court. If
you have one shot and you are not Steph Curry,
you are very likely to miss. But if you actually
have a lot of shots, one of them you're going to
make. That's it. Just think about it. The biggest
enemy of good enough is perfect. You don't need
to be perfect. You need to be good enough in
order to win the market, and the way that you
are going to become good enough, by the way, is
really simple. You start with not good enough
and you iterate and iterate and iterate until
you become good enough and then you'll win.
The third dimension is that this is going to
be long journey. Very long. Way longer than
you think it is. And the longest part of it
is until you figure out product market fit,
and product market fit goes into the different
phases of building a company. To a certain extent,
I would say, look, the difference between a
corporate and a startup is that a corporate
knows this is our value proposition,
this is the product that we are selling,
this is the pricing of this product that we are
selling, this is the target audience, this is how
we are going to sell them, this is how we going
to the market, and all we have to do is keep on
executing and hopefully nothing will change over
the period of time. When you start as a startup,
you don't have a product. You don't know what's
the business model. You don't know what people are
going to pay you for. You don't know how to grow
your business, and you need to figure out all of
those, and this is going to be a long journey.
Now, the longest part is usually figuring out
product market fit and product market
fit is really simple. That means that
you create value to your customers. If
you do not figure out product market fit,
you will die. As simple as that. You never heard
of a company that did not figure out product
market fit. They simply died. That's it. Now, once
they do, and for a second I want you to think of,
with all the applications that you're using every
day, right? From searching Google, using Waze,
WhatsApp, Facebook, Netflix, Uber, whatever it is,
and ask yourself what is the difference between
any of those today and the first time that you
have used that? And the answer is that there is
no difference. We are searching Google today the
same way that we searched Google for the first
time in our life. We're using Waze today the same
way that we used Waze for the first time in their
life. So once a company figure out product market
fit, they don't change their product anymore
because this is the value that they created to
the customers and you don't want to change that.
What we don't know is how long did it take them
to get to this point, right? Beforehand we never
heard of them and after that they don't change
that anymore. It's a matter of years. For Waze, it
was four years. For Microsoft, it was five years.
For Netflix, it was 10 years. Now if you'll tell
me, "Oh, today is very different. ChatGPT just
started a year ago." No, they're seven years old.
It took them six years until you heard about them
for the first time in your life. So it does take
time to create value and this is something that
is really significant. Now, at the end of the day,
product market fit have one metric. One metric.
That's it. Retention. That's really simple. If you
create value, they will come back. If they're not
coming back, that means that you are not creating
value. Now think about your episodes, right,
of this podcast, right? Most of your listeners
are returning, right? Because you create value
for them and they are coming back. That's it.
100%. Every single one, every episode.
Occasionally there are new one, right?
And there's new ones coming in all the time.
[inaudible 00:21:32]. By the way, this is
one thing that some businesses don't realize,
whether or not their customers are going
to be new customers or returning customers,
and in many cases they simply fail to
realize that upfront and the result is
that they are not building the
right go-to-market strategy.
We covered a lot of ground there. That
was amazing. I'm going to follow a number
of threads of things you just touched on. You
talked about product market fit briefly. What
was the moment you felt product market fit with
Waze? I don't know if I've ever heard that story.
We started in Israel and Israel is a
small place and we ended up with being
very successful in Israel and then we said,
"Wait a minute. Waze crowdsource all the data,
right?" Not just the traffic information and speed
cams and so forth, but also the map data itself,
so we can start from a blank page. And the users
while they drive, they create the map and they
create traffic information and so forth. And so
we figure out that we can start anywhere and we
made Waze global at the end of 2009 and we expect
that to work the same way that it did in Israel,
but it didn't. It was not good enough. It was not
good enough in the U.S. It was not good enough in
Western Europe. It was not good enough in Latin
America, it was not good enough in Asia. It was
not good enough anywhere that matters, right?
It was actually good enough in about four
places. In the Czech Republic, in Slovakia, in
Latvia and Ecuador, and that's about it. Rest of
the world not good enough. So what we did is we
spoke with the drivers. Look, they wanted us to
be successful. We basically said the drivers
are going to fight traffic jams together, so
common enemy, togetherness, all goodness. Everyone
wanted that to work, right? So people downloaded
the app and it simply was not good enough. So they
churned, right, because if it's not good enough,
you're not coming back. We spoke with them.
We asked them what didn't work for them. They
told us because they wanted it to work, and we
built the next version addressing everything that
they've told us, and we know that this is it, and
it's not. So we doing it all over again. We speak
with the drivers. We ask them what didn't work
for them, they tell us. Now we build the next
version and now we have the conviction that it's
going to work and it's not. Journey of failures.
Iteration after iteration after iteration after
iteration. More than a year of iterations until
beginning of 2011 that we actually started to
see that working, and then it's in multiple
places. In the U.S., one metropolitan after
the other, right? Los Angeles first and then
San Francisco and then Washington D.C. and Chicago
and New York and Atlanta and so forth. In Europe,
one country after the other. Italy first and then
France and Netherlands and Sweden and Spain and
one country after the other. In Latin America,
one country after the other. Colombia first and
then Chile and then Brazil and then Mexico and
then rest of Latin America. In Asia, multiple
countries one after the other. Not all of them,
by the way. Not all of them. Japan is a very good
example where it didn't work and it will never
work. Waze crowdsourced the information, right?
Which basically says that as soon as we get to
the level of good enough, then we are good enough.
House numbering plan. In the U.S., it's really
simple, right? Every block is a hundreth numbers,
right? And so if I have the map, I can actually
count the number of blocks and take you to
approximate the right location even if I don't
have exactly all the house numbers there. Most of
the western world, it's a geographical order. So
in Israel, this is going to be sequential order,
odd number on one side of the street, even number
on the other side of the street starting from one
until the end of the street and so forth, so
it's enough that I will have few house numbers
that I can actually take you to the right place.
In the UK, house number starts on one side off the
street and then on the other side they are coming
back, right? And so there is an order. In Japan,
it's chronological order. The oldest house
in the neighborhood is house number one.
Oh, wow.
And then the house number two can be miles away,
but it's the second oldest house in the
neighborhood and so you have to have all
the house numbers unless... Until then you
are not good enough. And crowdsource is,
if you need perfect information, crowdsource
may not be the right way to do that.
Just to close the loop on this question,
when you were launching these markets and
it wasn't working, were you actually
looking at retention at that point,
and if so, was there a number you were looking
for? Or was it more qualitative like it's just
taken off off into the right. Like where were
you actually watching back in the early days?
That was easier for us because we tried to
compare everything to Israel, so we looked
at the frequency of use or when our people are
coming back. How long does it take them until
the next try and until the next try. And in
generally speaking, if you look at something
that have high frequency of use, then you will
be looking at three-month retentions of 30, 40,
50% is actually pretty good indication. But
usually what would happen is that you would
know when they convert and that's going
to be after the third or the fourth time,
and if they're not getting to the fourth time,
then they are basically saying, "Okay. We gave
it a try. We really like this story. We gave
it another try, and it's not good enough."
That's a cool heuristic. Do you find
that that is useful for other startups,
consumer-type startups or is that
just something you think specific
to Waze at that point, this idea
of coming back for the third time?
It's really depending on the frequency
of use, right? If I will tell you that I
have a startup that helps you to file your
tax returns in three minutes, then okay,
that's absolutely amazing, but you are only going
to do that, next time is next year. By the way,
we did have a startup that was doing that.
It's still a little bit up and running,
but that was really frustrating
because the tax authority shut us down.
You got to fall in with the problem. You got to
power through that. Just change the government.
Just kidding. The story you told of Waze and
iterating is a really good example of falling
in love with the problem. You're really
passionate about. I want to solve traffic,
I hate traffic. By the way, what it made
me think about a little bit is Elon,
when he hated traffic, he built the boring
company and built tunnels underground,
and your solution to hate traffic is
I'm going to build Waze in a soft wrap.
We start Waze with the vision that we are going to
help people to avoid traffic jams. Now the reality
is that there are more traffic jams today than
there were in 2007. Obviously, number one, I'm
not done. And number two, if you ask people what
is the value of Waze, then it's not about avoiding
traffic. It's about creating certainty and
certainty is way higher value than saving time.
So you know exactly when you're going to get there
and this is a way higher value. And by the way, we
learned that in the U.S. market when we spoke with
people. They told us, "If I am living in Cupertino
and I need to drive up to San Francisco and I can
take 101 or 280, I don't really want to change
my route unless there is something dramatic, but
what I really want to know is how long it's going
to take me. So I'm going to stay on the 101. I'm
not going to get into service road. I'm not going
to take El Camino Real. I'm not going to try
something else. I'm going to stay on the 101.
Just let me know how long it's going to take." So
certainty creates way more value than saving time.
I want to talk through a couple other of
the chapters in your book. So chapter four
is around the different phases of a startup
journey and your core advice is that it's
important to focus on one thing at a time in
each of these phases, and the first phase,
you call it the all over the place phase,
I think, or yeah, the all over phase,
and the idea is you need to get out of that
as soon as you can and then focus. Can you
just kind of talk through these different
phases and what you think people do wrong
along the phases? Maybe they get them wrong or
they focus on the wrong things in each phase.
So initially you think about your new idea from
multiple perspective, right? This is the problem.
This is how this solution is going to look like.
This is what I'm going to do next year. This is
my 10 years vision. This is my business model
and so forth. So you think about everything,
but you actually need to execute only one thing.
Now this one thing is figuring out product market
fit. It's not one thing, right? Wait a minute. You
also need to build an organization and you want
that organization to be something that you really
like and so there are a lot of operational stuff,
but you need to figure out product market fit. As
we said earlier, if you don't figure out product
market fit, you will die. If you do, then you get
to live and die another day and the other day is
whether or not you're going to figure out how
to grow your business and whether or not you're
going to figure out your business model.
Now the good news is that I will tell you
that if you create value, you will figure out
a business model, at least for the people that
you create value for them. They are most
likely willing to pay. Now in general,
I'm not saying that this is the only business
model that is viable, but if you create value,
you will figure out a business model. But figuring
out a business model is a journey by itself,
and guess what? It's going to be a long roller
coaster journey of failures. When we started Waze,
we thought that we're going to sell map data
and traffic information and we ended up with
doing advertisement. Very different business
model. Because we realized that it's not for
us. It's too long sales cycles. We were very
mobile internet dynamic company and selling
to government is not exactly what we wanted
to do, and so we ended up with a different
business model, but with a lot of reasoning
why this is the right business model for us.
And figuring out growth, look, if I would ask a
hundred people on the street, how did you hear
about Waze? They, 95 of them, if not 99 of them,
will tell me, "Someone told me." Word-of-mouth,
right? So everyone wants to have word-of-mouth.
Word-of-mouth you can only have if you have high
frequency of use. If you're doing tax returns once
a year, even if you really like the experience,
then once a year you're going to tell
someone else. If you're using Waze every day,
then every day you have an opportunity to tell
someone else. So word-of-mouth, even though
that everyone would like that, it's only going
to happen if you have high frequency of use.
So those phases requires different focus of
the company, right? Initially if you focus on
product market fit, then you don't need sales. You
have no product to sell. You don't need business
development. You don't need even marketing.
You need product. You need developers and you
need product lead to define the product and lead
through the iterations of the product until we
get to the level that it's good enough. Once you
get there, you shift gears. If the product doesn't
change, if we search Google the same way that we
searched Google for the first time in our life,
then the product development is now not going to
be focused about value creation. It's going to
be focused about either figuring out business
model or figuring out scale, and the entire
company shift gears and move to a different phase.
Now, this is really hard. Just think about it. If
up until now the product development group was
the only things that matters, all of a sudden
we think about marketing now because we are now
in the go-to-market phase that this is the most
important thing of the company. Occasionally
I found companies that have challenging and
shifting gears so they didn't figure out where
the clutch is and you have to because otherwise
you're stuck in the previous phase that you kind
of finished that journey. This journey is nearly
done and you need to shift gears, and if you
don't do that, then you get stuck. If you do that,
if you try to do multiple things at the
same time, you will fail. Focus is not
about what we are doing, it's about what we
are not doing. These are the hard decisions.
I like that. So the four phases,
just to briefly summarize,
it's kind of like come up with the
idea, find product market fit, then
it's a question of should you keep focusing on
growth or should you figure out the business
model before focusing heavily on growth? In your
advice, it sounds like if it's high frequency,
word-of-mouth driven, focus on growth and then
you figure out business model later. If not,
figure out how you're going to make
money and then figure out growth.
Exactly. Because if you
have high frequency of use,
you will end up with growth coming
by itself, right, for word-of-mouth,
and therefore you should do that at the beginning.
If you don't have high frequency of use, you are
sentenced to acquire users or customers
all of your lifetime. If this is the case,
then you really want to figure out the business
model before you start and go and do that.
That's really helpful. I think actually
a counter example to your point about how
frequency of use is necessary for word-of-mouth
growth is Airbnb. Something like 70% of Airbnb
growth is word-of-mouth and frequency
of use is actually really low. It's
like once or twice a year. I wonder
if it's because the experience is so
unique and special that it still works
and enough people travel enough times,
slash if it was a higher frequency, it
would've grown even faster, I imagine.
High frequency of use is the simplest
way for word-of-mouth. The other thing
is coolness. If it's really cool,
then you'll tell more people,
and Airbnb was really cool at the beginning of
the journey, so now everyone knows about Airbnb,
but when they started that was way cheaper
and really unique experience than hotels.
It's still actually mostly word-of-mouth. I think
it was probably higher initially, but it's still
almost 70, 80% driven by word-of-mouth. So it's
still cool enough. Good for them. You have a
couple of quotes that I wanted to share, which are
along the lines of things you shared. One is just,
you have this kind of, what's the most
important stage at a company? They all are,
but one at a time. I love that line. The
other is the main thing is to keep the main
thing the main thing. The same advice you just
shared. Just like focus. So you're in the PM,
product market fit phase. Focus on that. Don't
think about growth yet. Don't think about business
model yet necessarily. I know investors are going
to push you to figure these things out and you'll
have to have some story of like, "Here's how it
might make money. Here's how we think we're going
to grow." Right? You need to think about that a
little bit, but maybe don't make that the focus.
So this is one of the areas that investors
don't like to hear the truth, right? The truth
is that I don't know how I'm going to bring the
users. I will figure that out once I get there,
but the reality is that right now I don't know,
but they don't want to hear that. What they want
to hear is that, "Oh, I know exactly how I'm
going to bring them." And what I will say is
that I know exactly where I'm going to start my
experiments, but most of the investors would like
to see a coherent story that makes sense, right?
This is our business model. This is how we going
to make money. This is what we're going to sell.
This is how much they're going to pay. This is
why it's a simple business model and these
are the comparable to this business model.
Yeah. But investors have the final
word, unfortunately. They decide
if they want to invest or not, and
so if your story is not compelling,
they're going to be like, "All
right. We'll find someone else."
You know, it's seasonality, right? There
are periods of time that raising capital
is easier and then many of the entrepreneurs will
be choosers are not beggars, and there are periods
of time that is that way around, and most of the
entrepreneurs will be beggars and not choosers.
Imagine a place where you can find all your
potential customers and get your message in
front of them in a cost-efficient way. If
you're a B2B business, that place exists,
and it's called LinkedIn. LinkedIn Ads allows you
to build the right relationships, drive results,
and reach your customers in a respectful
environment. Two of my portfolio companies,
Webflow and Census are LinkedIn success
stories. Census had a 10x increase in
pipeline with the LinkedIn startup team. For
Webflow, after ramping up on LinkedIn in Q4,
they had the highest marketing source
revenue quarter to date. With LinkedIn Ads,
you'll have direct access to and can build
relationships with decision makers including
950 million members, 180 million senior execs
and over 10 million C-level executives. You'll
be able to drive results with targeting and
measurement tools built specifically for B2B.
In tech, LinkedIn generated two to five x higher
return on ad spend than any other social media
platforms. Audiences on LinkedIn have two times
the buying power of the average web audience,
and you'll work with a partner who respects
the B2B world you operate in. Make B2B
marketing everything it can be and get $100
credit on your next campaign. Just go to
LinkedIn.com/podLenny to claim your credit. That's
LinkedIn.com/podLenny. Terms and conditions apply.
Let's actually talk about fundraising as
a topic I wanted to spend a little time
on. How much money have you raised for the
companies that you've started total, roughly?
So Waze raised about $50 million throughout
the entire journey. We started by raising
12. That was the first investment
round, and then we raised the 30,
and then there was the last round
that we raised actually not a lot.
That's a surprising small amount
of money to raise for the outcome.
In general, I would say Israeli startups are
leaner than American startups,
so you can raise less money.
Yeah, that's amazing.
At way lower valuation, unfortunately,
and end up with pretty successful results.
That's amazing.
Raising capital, it's a journey by
itself and different from the other
journeys that you need only once. Raising
capital is going to happen multiple times.
And if we say that building a
startup is a roller coaster journey,
then I will say raising capital is a
roller coaster journey in the dark.
It's like Space Mountain.
Yeah, sort of. And one of the reason is that this
is a different ballgame and you don't know how to
play at the beginning. I would say a few things
about raising capital for the first time. Number
one, I spoke with many investors and one of the
conversations that I had that they really, really
resonate with me was when I spoke with one of
the leading VC in Israel and asked their partner,
"How long does it take you to decide if you like
the entrepreneur or not?" And he asked me, "Do you
want the right answer or the real answer?" Say,
"You know, I heard the right answer so many times,
give me the real answer." And we were sitting in
a small meeting room, so the guy is looking at
me and then looking at the door and looking at me
again and say, "It's before they sit down." Say,
"Oh, no, no, no. Say that again, right?"
That's the first impression. Now we all
have first impression. How long does it take you
to decide if you like a candidate or not? Second,
you go on a date. How long does it take you to
decide if you like the date? Seconds. And then
maybe there are a few more minutes that you
allow yourself to either change your mind or
let that first impression solidifies. Now if this
is the case and you're looking to raise capital,
start with the strongest point at the beginning.
Whatever it is, and I don't care if this is the
size of the problem. This is the faction
that you have. This is the team that you
have built. I don't care what it is, start with
that, because by the time you'll get there,
they might be already setting up their mind. Then
start with the strongest point at the beginning.
And by the way, finish with that as well.
So this is the first conclusion. The second
conclusion is that I spoke with early stage
investors, those that invest the first money
in. So company has a story to tell. That's about
it, right? No traction, nothing yet is built and
so forth, and I asked him, "Why did you decide
to invest in this company and this company and
this company?" And I spoke with many investors,
and what I heard was actually pretty consistent.
I like the CEO. I like the story. That's it.
I like the CEO. I like the story. Now if this
is the case, then there are two immediate
conclusions. The first one is that the CEO
goes alone to the meeting. I need the headlight on
me. I don't need any distractions. I don't need my
team members. I don't need anything else in the
room, just me. Because if I bring other people,
then at the end of the day they might say, "Yeah,
I like the team, but the CEO was not specific,
right? Was not unique. Was not jumping out of
the pages." So CEO goes along and tell the story.
The other part is that they need to tell a good
story, and good story is not about facts. It's
about creating emotional engagement. It's about
creating the sense that the listener would like
to be part of this story. And for investor,
it's two things. Number one is that they
want to believe that this is usable, and number
two, they want to believe that you can build it
and this is the story that you need to tell.
Now, I would say always start with the problem,
right? Because guess what? Investors are also
users. If they don't think that they're going
to use it, so it's relevant for them, and
they don't think that they're going to use
it? They will basically dismiss that. They
will basically say the market is not there.
So these are two main things. The third thing
is it's a different ball game, right? So if you
have product and you tell the story to potential
customers, the right order of magnitude is that
about one third of the listeners will buy. So in
a more mature company, their pipeline is going
to be three eggs in order to sell at the end
of the year one eggs. One third are going to
say yes. In investors, it's 1%. Not one third, 1%.
So you're going to hear a hundred times no until
you hear one yes. And that a hundred times no is
something that you need to understand from the
beginning because that's really discouraging,
right? You go and speak with investors and
they tell you... I call that they open up the
big book of excuses why not. But in general,
they are not going to invest, right?
Now you look at it from the other side,
a venture capital partner is likely to see between
a hundred and 200 companies a year and invest in
one or two. 1%. That's it. So if this is the case,
then it's going to be the same case for you. One
out of a hundred. If you want to increase the
likelihood, learn how to tell a good story, start
at the strongest point at the beginning, remember
that they are users, too, so their emotional
engagement is going to come through the usage, the
use case, and not through how big the business is.
I love the summary at the end. I love that
you summarized your points, because I try
to do that. You did my job. I love this phrase
you have in your book, "The dance of 100 nos."
At the beginning you look at it and you
say, "Okay, they say they decided not
to invest because of X, Y, Z," right? Whatever
it is, right? Google can do that in no time or
the market is not big enough or the market is
complex or whatever it is, and then you try
to argue, and you don't know that it's useless,
right? It's like you go on a date and she said no,
and you try to argue, right? No, there is
nothing to argue anymore, right? That's no.
Yeah. I look at a lot of startups too. I
do a bunch of angel investing, and yeah,
if it's not going to be a fit, it's just not
going to work, and I could spend all this time
trying to explain it to you, but nothing's going
to change. And because there's other startups out
there is a big part of it, right? You just want
to pick the things you can that are the best,
not necessarily things that are good ideas.
I really like this idea of starting with your
strongest point. That's such an important tactical
piece of advice. To your point, investors make
decisions really quickly, and so starting with
something that really catches their attention,
it makes so much sense because once you feel like,
"Oh, wow, maybe this is a thing," your whole brain
is starting to look at it from a, oh, yeah, okay,
like you have a positive bend on everything you're
hearing versus like, "No, no, no, this is never
going to work and everything is already biased."
So I would add here another very strong advice.
Most people are missing the most important
slide of their presentation. The most important
slide of your presentation is the first slide,
not the one that you think about it.
The first slide. The one that says
Company XYZ intro. This slide is going to
be presented for the longest period of time.
Wow, that's a good point.
The longest period of time in the presentation,
this slide is going to be presented on
the screen and you didn't say anything
there. This is the place that you're
going to put your strongest point.
I love that. Is there an example of
someone that did that or did you do that,
one of your startups? What do you put there?
I do that all the time.
What's an example of something you put
on that slide that's such a good idea?
Maybe size of the market. Maybe description
of the problem. Whatever it is, right,
the strongest point is there. Now the second most
important slide is the last one. Not the summary.
The one that says thank you. That's the time to
repeat that. So most of their presentations will
end up with thank you and my email, right,
and this is going to be the last slide,
right? Which makes sense. You just missed
the opportunity. This is going to be the
second-longest displayed slide of
the presentation. Maybe the first.
Yeah. Everyone's sitting there chatting,
asking you questions. That's so smart. Are
there any more of these tips sitting in your
head to share, because these are awesome.
I do a lot of public speaking and usually my
last slide says one more story and I decide on
the story based on the audience and the dialogue
so far and so forth. But I have many of stories,
many last stories that I would like to tell. The
important part is that no one is going to cut you
off the stage if you have just one more story, and
so this is where you can recap everything. This is
where you can do whatever you want, right? Because
no one is going to tell you, "Okay, time is up."
Right, and they're not impatient
because they're like, "Okay,
it's almost over. Let's just let him finish."
Exactly.
Yeah. I love that. Speaking of stories,
what's the wildest fundraising story that
you've been through? Is there
one that comes to mind of like,
"Holy shit. I can't believe that happened,"
or, "I can't believe that worked out"?
One of the earlier startups that I was guiding
was about, eventually rolled into gift cards,
but in Israel, when you return something to the
store, you don't get your money back. What you
get is a gift card for that particular store,
right, and obviously if you return something,
then it's not necessarily that you have something
to buy in the store and you ended up with having
a gift card that is never being used, and so why
not sell this gift card? What happened is that I
heard the story of the CEO and I thought that the
story is not good enough, and I told him, "Look,
you have to tell a better story," and asked,
"Can you give me an example?" And I said, "Yeah,
just imagine that," and then there was a long
story about the microwave stuff working, and I
bought a new one and really long, long, long story
about with the details, right? How do you make a
story make believe? With details. Right? The more
details people think that this is real. Right?
If there are no details, then this is not real. So
I told him this story that was like five minutes
explaining, trying to fit the microwave into the
closet and it didn't fit in into the cabinet, and
it didn't fit in, and I had to return it to the
box and so forth and whole story. And then I spoke
with an investor in Israel and I told him about
this new company that I'm going to invest, and
I told him the same story about this microwave,
right, and he said, "This is interesting. I would
like to meet the CEO." Then he met the CO and
CEO told him exactly the same story about the
microwave. When I tell that, this is my
microwave, right?This is personal. This
has happened to me. And so he told
me, the investor called me up later,
he said, "He told me exactly the same
story." So that was really funny.
But at the end of the day, one of the things
that makes story authentic is details,
because otherwise it's not, right? If you're
going to tell me, okay, this is the use case
of the product and you end up with explaining a
use case in three lines, this is not authentic.
If you watch your real users, then what happens
is that you actually, and you speak with them,
then you have the audacity to tell a good story.
Really, really critical. If you want to tell user
story, these needs to be, real or you have to
learn how to tell a story with many details.
But interestingly, it sounds like the story itself
doesn't have to have happened to you in real life.
It could be a made-up story, but with a lot
of details is the lesson there. Interesting.
Yep. If you tell it very briefly,
then it doesn't sound right.
Amazing. Any other advice along those lines? I
want to talk about two more chapters before we
wrap up. Is there anything else around fundraising
that you think is important for people to know?
So I will tell you which chapters
I would like to speak about.
Let's do it. I wonder what they
are. I wonder if they're the same.
Understanding users and firing and hiring.
Okay, firing and hiring. That was on
my list. Okay. Let's start there and
then understanding users wasn't, but I'm
excited to hear what you have to say there.
So I send the book proposal to many publisher, and
there is one chapter that says firing and hiring,
and many of them came back and say, "Oh, it
should be hiring and firing." And I said,
"No. Firing is hard decision. Hiring is easy
decisions." You have to first of all learn how
to make the hard decisions. Now, the inspirations
for this chapter came from many dialogues that I
had with entrepreneurs that their startup failed,
and I asked them, "Why, what happened?" And about
half told me the team was not right, and I kept
on asking, "Okay, what do you mean the team was
not right?" And what I heard the most is, "We
had this guy not good enough and this guy not
good enough." So this is what I heard the most.
Another thing that I heard quite often is that
we had communication issues, right? Something that
I actually called ego management issues. And then
asked them the most interesting question, "When
did you know that the team is not right?" Now the
answer was actually rather scary. All of them told
me within the first month. Then you said, "Wait
a minute. If you knew within the first month that
the team is not right and you didn't do anything,
the problem was not that the team was not right.
The problem was that the CEO did not make hard
decision." Making hard decisions is hard. Making
easy decisions. This is why no one likes to make
the hard decisions, because you need to live with
the consequences. In a small place like a startup,
the hard decisions will always go to the top.
Now, if the CEO does not make that hard decisions,
the result is always the same. The top performing
people would leave. Now, they would leave because
they don't want to be in a place that is unable
to make hard decisions and they have a choice.
The nature of the beast is different. Startup is
a small organization. Just imagine that you are
a small organization, like could be a team,
whatever it is, right? 10, 20, 30 people,
and there is someone that shouldn't be there,
and I don't care if that someone shouldn't be
there because they are way underperforming or
because they are assholes. I don't really care.
They shouldn't be there. Everyone knows. Everyone
knows and the CEO doesn't do anything. That's the
nature of the beast and this is why top performing
people would leave. Now, building a startup is
really, really hard, right? It's hard if you
have the right team, but if you have people
that shouldn't be there that are still there and
the top performing people are leaving, then it's
going to be mission impossible. The conclusion
of this chapter is really, really interesting.
If everyone knows within a month and every time
that you hire someone new, what I really want
you to do is mark your calendars for 30 days down
the road and ask yourself one question, "Knowing
what I know today, would I hire this person?"
At the end of the day, I'd like to nail that into
yes or no, right? Because this is where decisions
are being made easily. If you ask yourself that
question, if the answer is yes, then go to
this person and tell them that you are really
excited that they've joined, they are exceeding
your expectations, and give them more equity,
and you buy their loyalty for life. If the answer
is no, fire them immediately. They're already set
on a trajectory of not being successful and
they're creating damage to you, to the rest of
the team and to themselves, right? They deserve to
be successful, but it's not going to happen here.
They deserve to find someplace else that they can
be successful, but it's not going to happen here,
and that decision is really, really dramatic.
Now, in many cases with hard decisions, we
know what is the right decisions. We are looking
for confirmation. If you look for confirmation,
then go and speak with the top performing
people and tell them, ask them the following,
right? "Assuming XYZ person is going to leave,
how sore are you going to feel?" And you will be
surprised that they are going to tell you, "Oh,
it's not a big deal." This is your confirmation.
Yeah. We had Elizabeth Stone from Netflix, the
CTO of Netflix on, and she talked about this thing
they called a keeper test, which is exactly that,
where every manager is always asking themselves,
"If this person were to leave tomorrow and tell
me they're leaving, would I fight to keep them?
And if not, I should just, I need to let them go,"
and that's always top of mind for managers there.
You know, one of my companies had a pretty good
year and they decided to have an annual bonuses
by and large to nearly all of the employees. And
then I asked the CEO, "So how did you end up with
the list?" And he said, "Okay. We had these
people that getting twice as much the others,
and then the others, and then there are four
people that are not going to get anything."
And I asked them, "Are they still
here?" They shouldn't be here,
right? If they are so much underperforming,
then they shouldn't be here. But generally
you need the time to ask yourself the tough
questions because only then you can answer them,
right? If you don't ask the tough
questions, then you don't answer them.
Yeah. I really love this very
tactical piece of advice,
which I was definitely going to
touch on, of putting a calendar entry
into your calendar when you hire someone 30
days in to remind yourself, asking yourself,
"Would I hire this person knowing what I know
now? And if not, you should probably let them go."
By the way, I can tell you that for everything
in your life, right? Everything in your life,
ask yourself, "Knowing what you know
today, would you do something different?"
Wow.
If the answer is yes, then
do something different today.
Today is the first day of the rest of your life.
That is powerful advice. So what I'm
thinking there is if I bought something,
maybe return it. What else have
you applied that to in your life?
Relationship in general. Directions that you're
going, right? Do you still like that? I have
five children and they're all in their twenties
and beginning of thirties and they struggle with
their career path, and I basically tell them,
"Look, if you are going to work in a place and
you don't like it, then what I want you to
do is ask yourself why you are not liking
it and whether or not there is something
that you can change, and I'm going to ask
you the same question in 90 days from now,
and if this still is the case, then quit."
It's interestingly you make that 90 days,
which it kind of applies some decisions. You
need to wait a little bit more. You need more
data. You need more time than necessarily
30 days, but set some kind of timeline.
If you don't set a timeline, it'll never happen.
I think the other really interesting implication
here is most decisions are a two-way door. Most
decisions, you can change your mind. You
can quit. You can leave a relationship.
I was thinking you were going to say with
your five kids 30 days after they're born,
"Do I still want this kid 30 days with knowing
what I know now?" I'm glad you didn't go there.
No, this is different, right? You go into
this journey of having children with the
understanding that this is long journey. Go
into this journey of building a startup with
the understanding that this is a long journey,
right? The fact that it's going to be hard? Okay,
so it's hard. It is hard, by the way. But
yeah, the decisions that obviously they need
to be relative to their duration, right?
So yeah, raising kids is a long journey.
And a one-way door, also. Is there
anything else you wanted to say
around the hiring and firing concept?
Clearly firing is the main lesson here,
is get really good at firing,
firing quickly and decisively.
You know, there are tons of advices in
the book and eventually I will tell,
even in the hiring process,
right, most of us are going
to interview candidates and then decide
that they like or dislike the candidate,
but they don't know. Then speak with someone
that does know. Speak with the reference.
Do you have a favorite question you like
to ask references? Is there something
that you find is really helpful to
tell you? Give you honest insight?
For reference?
Yeah.
That's really simple. Would you
hire him? Or would you hire her,
right? So essentially at the end of the
day you want to nail it into yes or no.
Yeah. And hope that they're being
honest. That's sometimes a challenge.
No, if they will tell me yes, then I would ask
them, "Why didn't you?" Someone asked me for
a reference on someone that I really enjoyed
working with. I really think highly of them,
and he asked me if they can schedule
a call for half an hour and I said,
"Look, I'm traveling. I don't really have
time. But if you want an email in one word,
take the guy." And then he was trying to
outsmart and ask me back, "Can I have that
in two words?" And I said, "Yeah, take the
guy fast." When you know, you know. That's it.
I like that. That's what you want to be
looking for. Okay. Amazing. So let's do one
more chapter. The one I was going to pick,
you choose what you're more excited about,
is selling a company. Your last chapter exit.
The one you were thinking about going to is
talking to users. I imagine that's
much more applicable to more people,
so that's probably the better
choice, but your choice.
Okay, then let's stick with understanding
users. Steve Wozniak, co-founder of Apple,
wrote the foreword to my book and he called it the
Bible for entrepreneurs, and when I sent him the
first chapter, he said, "Wow, I wish I had that
When I started." I met Steve Wozniak for the first
time about 10 years ago. We spoke at the same
conference in Guatemala, and look, when I grew up,
Steve Wozniak was my technological guru, right so
he was the most important person in the technology
space in my mind. And then we spoke at the same
conference and we had dinner the night before, and
the only thing that actually was really important
for me is to have a selfie with my idol, right?
And so I took up my iPhone and with the iPhone you
can take pictures by clicking here on the screen
or using the volume button on the side, right?
And so I took a selfie with him holding the phone
like that and clicking on the volume button
and he said, "Finally." And I said, "Finally
what?" "Finally someone using it the way that I
meant it to be." Now you realize that there is no
right or wrong. There are different people that
are using different products in different ways,
and occasionally if I would have large audience,
then I would ask the people, "Okay, how do you
use Waze?" Right? "So you go to your destination
and you enter destination, and then Waze guides
you through the screen with the display of the
maneuvers that needs to be made or with the audio
guidance of turn right, turn left and so forth.
If you are watching the screen, raise your hand."
And then I would have about 70% of the people
raise their hand." Then I ask people to watch
around them and see those people. Then I ask, "If
you are listening to the audio prompt, raise your
hand." Then I have about 20 or 30 more percent
of the people raising their hand. And again,
I send people to watch around and see those hands.
There is no right or wrong. Different people are
using it differently. Now, if you are using Waze
in a certain way, up until this moment, you didn't
know that there are other people that are using it
differently, and to be frank, you don't care. You
getting your own value the way that you get it,
then you don't really care that there are other
people that are getting it differently. But if you
are building a product and you don't know that,
then you are building the wrong product. You
don't know that there are other people that are
not like you, and you think that you're building
the product for yourself, then you're making a
big mistake. And the way to figure it out is, by
the way, two things. Number one, watch new users.
Simply watch users and see what they're doing.
And number two, if they're not doing what you
expect them to do, then ask them why, because
this why is the one that is going to make your
product successful. You understand the why and
the next version you're going to address that.
Now, this is in particular when it comes to
understanding users. Obviously there are a
lot of users, but we can group them into several
groups of their ability to adapt something new,
and something new is not necessarily new
technology. We think about it as a new technology,
but it's not necessarily about technology. It's
about new behavior, right? And then we look at the
entire population and every time that we look into
large numbers, they will have normal distribution,
right? So the bell curve of the distribution, and
then we will have about 2% of the populations that
they're the innovatives. The innovatives are going
to use something new because it's new. That's it.
They care about this subject and they going to
be the first one to hear about it and they're
going to try that out because it's new. The
second group is usually what we will get to
see as the first users are the early adapters.
As soon as they realize that there is value,
they're going to give it a try. And if there is
value, then they will keep on using it, and if
there is no value, then they will quit. Right?
The third group is the most important group.
This is where market leaders are, right? This is
called the early majority. This is about one third
of the population, and the one that wins the
early majority wins the market. The challenge
with this group, with the people in this group,
is that they're afraid of change. So their state
of mind is, don't rock the boat. Whatever I'm
currently doing is good enough for me. So if you
have Salesforce.com, which is absolutely amazing,
their reaction is going to be, "What's wrong with
Excel?" And because they're afraid of change, they
are not going to try something new. Now the reason
is that at the end of the day, they're afraid
that this is going to be too complex for them
and they will not get it, and they don't want to
be embarrassed and they don't want to feel like
idiots. And guess what? People don't like to feel
like idiots, and so they are not going to try.
And you need to see those people to understand
their barriers for starting to use your service.
And by the way, the solution is always the same.
Simplicity. Leonardo da Vinci said that simplicity
is the ultimate sophistication. If you want to
make it simple, in your journey of building a
product, we basically say this is iteration to
iteration to iteration. In many of those you add
features and you add features and you add features
until you all of a sudden you add the features
that people are using. What you really want to
do next is remove the rest of the features that
people are not using because they're adding
complexity. Now, most of the product owners,
they're either innovators or early adopters.
You cannot understand an early majority person.
If you belong to one group, you cannot
understand a person from that group unless
you watch them and [inaudible 01:10:57]. So
the most important part of understanding users
is actually seeing those users. And they
are not wrong. This is how they behave.
So a couple of threads there I'll pull out. One is
look for surprising uses of your product because,
as you said, you'll realize, "Oh, some
people are using this in a way that I
didn't expect," and it'll remind you
people are not the way you are and
don't assume that they're going to
want exactly what you're building,
so pay attention to things that surprise you. We
had Jeffrey Moore on the podcast and he talked
through a lot of this stuff, and one of the
lessons there to help you bridge that gap from,
to the, what is it, the third group? How
did you describe it? The late majority?
The early majority.
Late majority will never use the product. They
will use your product only if they have to.
Yeah. The laggards, I think he calls it.
They look for basically references. People
telling them, "Hey, you really need to
use this." A lot of people, just like
basically word-of-mouth is
the way you described it.
No, not just word-of-mouth. Even occasionally
someone to show them how to use it.
Yeah. That makes sense. Just like, "Here,
check out Waze. Here's how it works." Yeah,
that makes a lot of sense. Okay. Amazing.
Is there anything else along those lines
as you're talking to customers and understanding
what you're looking for that you want to share?
Occasionally what happens is that we speak with
the wrong customers. So just imagine that we have
what I call funnel of use, right? So on top of the
funnel, we have people that are download the app,
let's say, or have entered their website, and then
the next phase is that they registered and the
next phase that they're trying to use it for the
first time and then the next phase is that they're
getting the value and they're coming back, right?
In this funnel, what we usually try to do is speak
with the users at the bottom of the funnels, those
that were successful. But in order to improve,
we need to speak with those that fail, those
that were unsuccessful, those that did not
register, or they did register and did not
use, or they did use and did not come back,
because they know something that we really need to
know. Why? This why is what makes a great product.
Interesting. I imagine you could also
fall into danger there if people that
just aren't a fit for your product,
there's just no point wasting your
time on people that are just not going
to be a fit. So is the idea there find
people that are really far down the
funnel but still bounced and churned?
Yep.
Awesome. Amazing. Okay. So we've gone through
all the chapters I was hoping to go through,
plus the ones you were excited about.
Final thing before we get to our very
exciting lightning round, we have a segment
on this podcast called Fail Corner, where I
ask a guest to share a time they failed in their
career and what they learned from that experience,
and I'm curious if there is a story that
comes to mind of a time that you failed
either in a startup or as you were an employee
somewhere and how that was important to you.
So number one, I reserve the right for
my biggest failure yet to come. And look,
I keep on trying new things. I keep on doing
things, and so eventually I will fail as much
as... Maybe I'm more successful statistically
than others, but I will fail, and this is very,
very important part to realize. Don't be
afraid to fail, right? In your journey,
you're going to fail multiple times, and when
you fail and get up, you get up stronger. This
is maybe something that I will tell all the
parents in the world. The biggest advice that
I can give you is teach your children to fail.
Because when they get up, they get up stronger,
and when they know that they will get out of their
comfort zone and they will eventually discover
what makes them happy. At the end of the day, as
parents, there's only one thing that we really
like. We want our kids to be happy in their
own way. We don't know what it is. They don't
know what it is. We want them to explore, and they
will only explore if they are not afraid to fail.
Yeah. This is a very timely advice for me
because our kid is always falling down and
it's always this balance between helping them
not fall and letting them figure things out.
Let them fall. There is a Japanese
saying, fall seven times and get up eight.
Uri, is there anything else
that you wanted to share or
leave listeners with before we get
to our very exciting lightning round?
No, I think that was
actually, I really enjoyed it.
Amazing. Well, we're not done yet. We've reached
our very exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
Yep.
All right. First question, what are
two or three books that you recommended
most to other people other than your own book?
Mark Randolph of Netflix. That Will
Never Work, right? And by the way,
it's funny. Mark Randolph wrote endorsement to
my book and I reached out to him because I read
someplace that he's answering all of his emails,
and I reached, I sent him an email and said,
"Look, we have at least three things in common.
Number one, I do answer all of my emails as well.
Number two, I'm using your product, you are
using mine. And number three, I heard more
time that will never work than you did." And I
think that understanding this journey is really,
really important, so this is definitely a
book that I would recommend. Atomic Habits.
Getting habits and improving them, measuring
and improving, is really, really important.
Very cool choices. Do you have a favorite recent
movie or TV show that you've really enjoyed?
I don't watch a lot.
Easy, then. Do you have a favorite product that
you've recently discovered that you really love?
So I can bet that most of
the people say the ChatGPT,
but actually no. I recently downloaded the
Chess App and I returned to play chess with
the computer or something that I haven't done
for so many years, and I really enjoy that.
Amazing. It's actually, I don't think ChatGPT has
ever been recommended. Recent choices have
been a beautiful Persian rug, a Rivian,
a very nice Mercedes, and I think recently
it was a course on nervous system regulation.
Cool.
All over the place. Two final questions. Do
you have a favorite life motto that you find
really useful in work, your own life?
It may be the one on your shirt,
but is there any other that you
come back to often and find useful?
Don't be afraid to fail. I think that in
many cases we need to accept
the fact that we don't know.
Important words. Final question, is there a
problem you're starting to fall in love with
more recently, maybe tinkering with a new startup
idea? Or are you done with starting companies?
I probably will never be done. I have 10 different
startups in multiple areas. One of them, Pontera
helps people to retire richer, which is one of
the biggest challenges in the world in general,
but also in the U.S. If I would ask a hundred
people on the street that have 401k plans,
"What is your 401k plan invested at?" 95% of
them will tell me, "I don't know." I do know,
by the way. In the default. Whatever was the
default when they joined, right? Now obviously
if you didn't do anything and you think it's
right, no, it's not right. It's probably simply
not enough. So this is a big problem. I have one
in the medical space that is trying to create,
I would call that the AI of the medical
knowledge, so trying to improve doctors,
and in particular in clinical decisions.
That is going to change the world.
But if you would ask me, then I will give you some
examples, right? So mobility is still a problem,
right? You look at many areas in our lifetime
and mobility is still, every year it's,
instead of getting better, it's getting lesser. So
mobility is still a problem. And medical services,
right? U.S. medical services are five to 10 times
more expensive than they are in Germany. Now,
it's not that they're better. They're simply more
expensive. So obviously you ask yourself, "Okay,
where is this inefficiency? Where is it?" Right?
A lot of places of inefficiency in the medical
services if they're so expensive. Education.
Okay. Anything that I will tell you that we are
still doing the same way that our parents did
is probably something that we need to revisit.
I feel like I nerd sniped you with falling in
love with problems. Clearly fall in love with a
lot of problems. You want to solve
them all. You're addicted to startups.
The good news is that there are a lot of problems
and the bad news that there are lots of problems.
And you're there to solve it. I love it. Uri,
your book is amazing. It's incredibly practical,
full of tons of advice that
every founder should read,
and it goes from idea all the way to exit. So
basically, no matter where you're on the journey,
the book is going to be useful to you. Tell people
where to find it and where they can follow you for
more stuff that you share over time, and
then how can listeners be useful to you?
So obviously this is the book. Amazon, Barnes &
Noble, basically places that you can find it. You
can follow me on LinkedIn. This is pretty much
the only network that I'm actually engaged. If
you read the book, then you will find my email in
the book and then you can email me, as well. And I
do answer all of my emails. I want you to read the
book. I don't want you to buy the book. I want you
to read the book. And the reason is that I have
a purpose in life and this is creating value,
and I believe that this book is going to be
the best return on investment that you ever
made. Not the $20 or $30 that it costs, but the
time that you're going to spend on reading it,
and therefore, I can be valuable for you, and if I
can be valuable for you, then I serve my purpose.
Amazing. If you weren't on YouTube watching this,
the book is called Fall in Love
with the Problem, Not the Solution,
if you're trying to Google it and find that on
Amazon. And Uri, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you.
Bye, everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
Lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.