Been in the product management team
at Atlassian for roughly 10 years now.
I worked on HipChat and Stride, and more
recently I started Jira Product Discovery.
Why is it so hard to start new products,
go zero to one within large companies?
The company has a tendency to over-invest.
Startups have the benefit of starving,
and so you need to create scarcity.
What we try to do is remind everyone
things are going to fail, let's not
drag the rest of the company into it.
Sounds like one of the biggest
lessons is super silo sort of team.
I needed the rest of the company to go away so we
could get the autonomy to test the things that we
needed, but it's not going to scale. That is
not going to respect all design guidelines.
The biggest challenge I think a
lot of companies have is just,
it's been six months, no one wants this, we're
going to kill it. How do you protect that?
Be very clear about what we're
testing, doing that with data,
doing that with personal customer stories,
give people a sense of velocity and speed.
No one wants to fuck with a high-speed train.
Today, my guest is Tanguy Crusson. This
is a really unique and important episode
because we get into something you don't hear
much on podcasts like this, the real talk
challenges of trying to innovate and build zero
to one at a large company like Atlassian. Tanguy
has been at Atlassian for over 10 years and
has worked on a bunch of internal big bets,
some that have worked and some that have not,
including products like HipChat, which I was
a huge fan of back in the day, also a product
called Status Page, and most recently Jira Product
Discovery, which is one of the fastest growing
products in Atlassian history that Tanguy led
from idea to launch. We go through each of these
stories, and Tanguy shares what went wrong,
what went right, and everything that he's
learned about creating space for innovation
within a larger org, including how they structured
their internal incubation program called Point A.
There's a ton of gold in this episode and
a bunch of really interesting stories,
which is part of the reason that it went this
long. It's the longest episode I've done yet.
If you're looking to create change in your
organization and foster more innovation,
this episode will be worth your time. If you enjoy
this podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow
it in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube,
the best way to avoid missing feature episodes
and it helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you Tanguy Crusson.
Tanguy, thank you so much for being
here, and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you very much for welcoming me here, Lenny.
I'm actually super proud to be on this podcast.
I've been a huge fan. Whenever I get the chance,
I listen to you when I drive somewhere so yeah.
What we're going to be talking about in this
episode is we're going to be talking about
building new products and going zero to one
within larger companies, and in particular,
the pain and the challenges that come along
with that, but also the lessons that you've
learned from doing this many times and seeing
it done many times. You've seen a lot of this
happening at Atlassian, you've been there for
over 10 years at this point, and Atlassian has,
I don't know, over a dozen different product
lines at this point, something like that. I
know a lot of people come to you asking for
advice on how to build zero to one within a
large company. So let me just start with a general
question of just could you just share a bit about
your history of building zero to one and just
seeing zero to one happening within Atlassian?
Yeah, so like you said, I've been in the product
management team at Atlassian for roughly 10 years
now, and I've been working mainly on bootstrapping
new things. Initially, I joined to start the cloud
developer ecosystem so developers can build
apps on top of the Atlassian platform and
sell them on the Atlassian marketplace. I worked
on HipChat and Stride. HipChat was well-known,
Stride less so. We were trying to win the
enterprise communications market before Slack and
Microsoft Teams came about. I did lead a business
case to invest more in IT operations, got nowhere
with it than we acquired Statuspage, Opsgenie,
and something I tried to do with didn't quite
get off the ground. More recently I started Jira
Project Discovery, which was part of our internal
incubator for two to three years, and came out of
the incubator and generally available a year ago.
My track record at Atlassian has been 50/50 at
best. Jira Project Discovery is actually my first,
what I would call big success here. That one
worked, but it was hard and all the ones that
I worked on before were really hard to, and
that's the kind of stuff that really bothered
me for a super long time. The good thing is
working on a product for product managers,
I got to talk to a lot of product managers
and across all sorts of industries in the
past three to four years, and I realize
that 50/50 is actually not that bad.
Awesome, and I know there's going to be a
lot of real talk in this conversation. I'm
excited to share and hear all these stories.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta. When
it comes to ensuring your company has top-notch
security practices, things get complicated fast,
now you can assess risk, secure the trust of your
customers, and automate compliance for SOC 2,
ISO 27001, HIPAA, and more with a single
platform, Vanta. Vanta's market leading trust
management platform helps you continuously
monitor compliance alongside reporting and
tracking risks. Plus, you can save hours by
completing security questionnaires with Vanta
AI. Join thousands of global companies that
use Vanta to automate evidence collection,
unify risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go to
vanta.com/Lenny. That's V-A-N-T-A.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by WorkOS. If
you're building a SaaS app, at some point your
customers will start asking for enterprise
features like SAML authentication and SCIM
provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in, making
it fast and painless to add enterprise features
to your app. Their APIs are easy to understand so
that you can ship quickly and get back to building
other features. Today, hundreds of companies are
already powered by WorkOS, including ones you
probably know like Vercel, Webflow, and Loom.
WorkOS also recently acquired Warrant, the
fine-grain authorization service. Warrant's
product is based on a groundbreaking
authorization system called Zanzibar,
which was originally designed for Google to
power Google Docs and YouTube. This enables
fast authorization checks at enormous scale
while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases.
If you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features
like single sign-on, SCIM, or user management,
you should consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in
replacement for Auth0 and supports up to 1 million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
workos.com to learn more. That's workos.com.
Just broadly, why is it so hard in your
experience to start new products go zero
to one within large companies? What have you seen
are the biggest challenges and hurdles generally?
Yeah, so on the opportunity side, so Atlassian,
300,000 customers. We play in a whole bunch of
different markets, everything in the collaboration
space. We have a lot of markets that we play in,
which means that we've got a lot of competitors.
But basically when we look at the areas we could
go in, there's an endless list of areas that we
could go in, play and have a decent chance to win.
Much harder to do if you're a startup. The breadth
that we've got makes it easier to try find areas
where we could expand into. We're not starving
like a smaller company, so we can actually afford
to try to play somewhere, to do some bets, to
have some of them fail and some of them succeed,
so that's amazing. Now our customers, I said
300,000. The thing that I admire the most about
the Atlassian business model is it's very broad.
It's across small and medium-sized companies. We
have startups using our products, and we've got
also enterprises and very large enterprises using
the same products, which means that there's a
lot of areas where we could find a niche and
go after it and expand progressively into all
these areas so there's a massive distribution
potential that comes with that. When I worked
on Jira Product Discovery, I didn't start with,
okay, I'm going to need to start finding product
managers and it's going to be how to find them.
No, they were already all using Jira. Atlassian is
a company that has a relatively deep organization
hierarchy but relatively flat decision making.
So it's more like a, imagine a network of key
decision makers across the organization.
It doesn't really matter the job title or
whether you are a manager of people or not. The
decisions are made by people who drive change.
So there's a lot of empowerment that comes
from that, but also it's a mix of top-down,
bottom-up happiness I'd say. And so
it can feel really chaotic at first,
but once you know how to navigate it,
it's actually pretty easy to try to go
after something that you care about.
And of course, we're a big company,
so there's lots of ways we can get help.
Corporate development, research analysts
that we can talk to whenever we want to explore
something, thousands of customers that I just
have to put something in the addressable
community group and get hundreds of people
applying to talk to me from one day to the next.
So that's amazing, any startup would want that.
This sounds like how can anything not work
when you launch a new product? You have 300,000
potential customers to launch it to. You have
all the resources to build it. It sounds like
decision making is efficient relatively,
it's flat. You have all these different
customer segments that use all these different
version product lines of Atlassian. It's just
like all of the opportunity possible to launch new
products and still, many things do not work out,
so I think this is a really important
point and I think many big companies
are in this. We have so much opportunity.
Everything we're going to build is going to,
it's going to grow like crazy because we have
everything we need, but still it doesn't work
out. And that's why I think we're going to
talk about, it's going to be so important.
It's going to be a little bit of therapy for
me. Hopefully some people out there could go,
"Okay, it's not just me having a hard time."
It can happen in companies like Atlassian too.
Amazing.
So yeah, let's talk about the challenges.
Let's do it.
Yeah, for that. So you want to start a new
thing. This thing is going to take time,
and you need to be able to have that time for
the time it takes until you can prove whether
there is a thing or not. The thing inside
Atlassian is that the path for success is
super high for a new bet. If you come in and
you create a product and it's got 100 customers,
it's going to look cute. Remember,
we serve startups and enterprises,
we have self-service and sales, we've got
all these motions that are in place for our
bigger products. A $100 million business is a good
start basically. In most companies out there, $100
million business is a home run. For us, it's not
like that. We're trying to build businesses that
grow really big and keep growing big over time.
Now, evaluating success can look very different
between early stage and established products.
For a long time at Atlassian, we were treating
everything a little bit equally in that the
metrics success for the same. For example,
things like monthly active users is the way
that you, for a long time we looked at you go,
is that product being successful on it? And what
if you are building an "internal startup," your
monthly active user number should look very low
for quite some time up until you know that your
product is ready to serve the vast majority of
the customers that you want to put it in front of,
so that they don't just look at it
and go, "It's not ready for me."
They're going to try it and then they're going
to churn and it's going to take forever to claim
them back, so that makes it pretty challenging
to try and start new things unless we've got the
right metrics and processes and everything
internally that can give room and breathing
space for the bets to succeed internally. And
for many years, we were not there. We started
getting there more recently with the start
of Point A, which was our internal incubator
program, which is one of my latest that was
successful. The ones before didn't have that,
and I really struggled from that, and I see many
companies struggling with that exact aspect.
Amazing. Let's dive into an actual story. There's
three that I want to talk about. There's HipChat,
which you mentioned. There's Status Page and
then there's the product you're working on now,
Jira Product Discovery. So with HipChat,
funny story, I loved HipChat. I was a huge
user of HipChat at my startup back in the day.
I can never forget the billboard that you all
put out promoting HipChat where there's this
little stick figure meme guy and it just said,
"Why use HipChat?" And I thought
that was the funniest thing,
and the product was so delightful. There's just
all these little emojis in there, and the idea
with HipChat for Atlassian was basically to
become the Slack killer, that was the vision.
You just killed me. We were way before Slack.
Okay, so first mover advantage, amazing product.
It works, yeah.
And it was an acquisition for Atlassian.
It was an acquisition.
Awesome. So let's talk about what went
wrong with HipChat. What did you learn?
All know Atlassian as company, as the tool that
could almost have a, okay. [inaudible 00:13:57].
Yeah, this is the therapy.
The therapy session begins.
Yeah, it's going to start right there. Me and
everyone else from the HipChat team I can tell
you. Okay, so yes, HipChat was an acquisition,
team of 20 people or so. It was Slack before
Slack was there. Great traction and lot of, it
was a darling with startups. It was a new way to
collaborate back then. There were a few of these
smaller apps that were trying to do this thing.
I remember actually joining Atlassian. Before
that, I was working with financial services,
banks and stuff like that, and we were big meeting
to talk about stuff, or going to someone's desk to
talk about stuff. I joined this company where my
colleagues who sit on the same floor as me and on
the same table, we talk over the computer via
chat. I often felt weird at first looking over
my shoulder to the person I'm currently
talking to and we're having an argument,
but we're doing it over text. Anyway, it might
seem a bit cute to the people who had been
born in the Slack world, but it
was a major change back then.
Yeah, I remember that. I remember that,
I was in the same office with my team
and we're using HipChat to chat and it
felt strange. Now it's completely normal.
It's just normal, and Hipchat was one of the
first to move there. Slack came out of nowhere.
Company actually initially was focused more
on gaming and they really took the market by
storm. The growth numbers were dizzying when
we're looking at them. And so at some point,
Hipchat was left relatively alone for a while
inside Atlassian. You're doing something good,
so keep going after it. But with
Slack, we now had to try to go bigger,
so we started this thing called HipChat
Go Big, the team, they recruited-
That was the name of the project? HipChat Go Big?
Yeah, HipChat Go Big. And then it was HipChat
Next Gen, there was a few different. Anyway, yeah.
Very clear. HipChat Go Big, I love it.
Go big. But it was really a go big, lots of
new developers, lots of new product managers,
designers, the full company behind this
product kind of thing. We tried to grow it
very aggressively for a product that did not
change that fast before it had reached good
product market fit already, hundreds of thousands
of users on a daily basis, and all of a sudden
that you get a lot of people who want to make
changes to it, to compete against this new threat.
The platform is not so ready for so many people
to work on it. And so we got to the inevitable,
okay, it's too much tech, we can't do
much about it so we made the decision
to rewrite it. There's lots of literature
around there around should you do rewrite?
Should you not do rewrite? You ask
me now, I tell you never. Trust me.
That's what most of the advice is, never
do a rewrite, and people still do it.
Never do a rewrite, and there's good reasons for
that. But basically we did that and out of it came
up actually a new product called Stride, which
was initially "HipChat next gen." The problem is
that the product was great, but by the time
we were done, Slack was just miles ahead of
us. At that point, Microsoft launched Teams.
I don't know if you remember this moment where
Slack put an ad in the, I think it was The New
York Times, copying the Apple versus Microsoft
thing from ages before going, "Welcome to the
game, welcome to the party, we'll welcome you
competitors," and stuff like that and Slack got
pretty much destroyed by Teams. We started coming
because it was like Microsoft distribution
advantage. Everyone in Office is going to
get it. They're giving it for free as part of
Office, it was unbundled I think a few months ago.
Which is ironic because in theory,
Atlassian also has that same advantage,
right? You have all these
products, you could bundle it.
We are going to talk about
that actually in a minute.
Okay, great.
Because that was what helped us, how we thought
we would win, and it was how I think we lost.
Amazing. Let's get in.
So anyway, this all happened, and in the end
we executed the market. We sold HipChat and
Stride to Slack and basically exited
the enterprise communications market.
Just to double down that, but you sold
that to Slack and now Salesforce basically,
that's the word ended. I don't
know if people know that.
Yeah, actually, it was noticed by the market in
that as soon as we did that, our stock price went
up. I think it was $60 back then and it went
up to 70. I mean, that really sucked for us,
the team working on it. First, no one tells you,
but failure, everyone tells you failure is great
because you learn so many things, but failure
to start with really sucks. None of us here were
really happy about this on the team because we
had spent years, on my part, it was three years,
but the people who were before that on HipChat
was longer than that. Obsessing over it,
obsessing over every detail, every customer
conversation, every solution, should we rewrite,
should we this, should we do that?
So many intense conversations,
and from one day to the next, it didn't matter
anymore. We had worked on something and that's it,
that's the end. I'm sure many startups have been
through that before. For me it was the first time
it felt that personal, and the market the next
day went, "Oh, you're stopping doing what you're
doing? Awesome. Yes, 10 more dollars to your
stock price." So yeah, there's a personal side to
all the stories. For us, there was a bit like the
seven stages of grief after we shut down HipChat.
How long was that period of mourning
and stages for you and the team?
It lasted a few months. I was not part of the
decision making team for shutting down HipChat.
I was one of the product managers on the team
leading one of the three pillars. I got brought
in, I think it was a month or two, a month
before it was announced for the team to go,
"Hey, Tanguy, by the way, just so you know,
HipChat is no more, and now your mission is
to find a new mission for the team after that."
We basically spend the next two, three months
trying to make sure that the squads were created
to fully own what they do there, to make sure that
they're the ones talking to the customers, they're
the other ones trying to come up with strategies,
trying to come up with solutions and everything
in that area. As long as it was people interacting
with Atlassian products on other surfaces,
everything was fair game, and so there was a
lot of ups and downs and everything. I think it
took about two, three months before we got back
to a new rhythm. And some people, when we talk
about it, were still scarred by it basically.
What are some lessons from that experience?
Yeah, so the main one that I personally got from
this, and it's back to the hypothesis that you
talked about, which we have all these successful
products, we can expand into this one which is,
and I quote it, but it's just myself, don't
eat your own bullshit, which is a mix of two
things. We've got a company value that says
open company, no bullshit. So we need to be
able to talk about the things like they are, and
we don't try to make things sound smarter than
they are. We don't try to hide the truth, we
go after that truth, and we don't hide stuff
from each other. We share with everyone, we are
open by default. So that's one of the values and
we do a lot of dogfooding, so eat your own
dog food. We do test our own software a lot.
I've noticed that sometimes there are things that
we do while we tend to believe stuff because it's
worked for us before, and we have this assumption
that it's going to keep working for us forever.
The founders keep telling us what took us here
won't take us there. That's a thing we keep
hearing over and over again. But it's very easy
for teams when they see success of something to
think that it's successful because of X, but X
is not validated. That's where we go back to the
topic we've got today, which is why is doing this
in a successful company harder sometimes. Well,
Atlassian was successful with the playbook, and
the playbook was we've got people in developers
or tech or IT. They choose Atlassian apps,
they love them. They start to recommend them
to people in the business, and we start to see
adoption, bottom-up adoption across the company
before people decide to standardize on Atlassian.
We made the bet that we can apply this playbook
to this market, which is basically we can, from
people to use Jira, introduce HipChat, and then
people will go into HipChat first in tech teams,
and then it will expand into business teams,
and it'll go world to world basically from that.
The thing is we didn't, in my opinion, do enough
to validate that assumption early enough. We did
a lot of work, a lot of work even on other things,
even when faced with signals that this might
not work. I do remember talking with a lot
of customers who were like, "Well, we've got, the
IT is on HipChat, but the business prefer Slack."
And then we started to see those businesses
choosing Slack, which is the, initially it was
like the developers try things and they like it
and then everyone starts to adopt. In that case,
the Slack managed to create a very strong
fund base in roles that were not tech and IT.
It was the moment where the consumerization of
apps, that trend was starting to get really high.
Slack really rode that and they focused everything
in their experience to catch that. They gamified
onboarding, they focused a lot more on the
look and feel. They try to make it pleasant,
modern, functional to use. There's a lot of stuff
that we learned since then from what they did,
we had missed that part. The part that I took
personally from that is that there's a lot of
assumptions in what made us successful,
it doesn't mean that it's going to work.
Just I understand what you're saying, which is
really interesting that Atlassian was really
successful selling basically to the buyer
within the org, the IT team because they
had everything they needed. They checked all the
checkboxes, but it turned out in the Slack case,
it was the users that ended up having the
most influence over what tool they'd opted.
I'd actually phrase it more as both were going
after the users. Atlassian was going after the
users in tech teams, Slack was going after the
users in business teams. And in both cases,
what happened was a bottom-up adoption. The
people on the other side, the business would
prefer Slack, the developers, they prefer the
HipChat. We did a lot of work in the streams
I was working on. We're integrating with every
developer tooling out there to make sure that
every tool that they use goes into HipChat and
from HipChat back to those tools. And basically,
they can do a lot of work by seeing an activity
stream in HipChat. Business? Eh, not so excited
by this. Emojis, a lot of other things that
may at some point I remember we were thinking
those things were trivial. No, they were not
trivial. It was just a different approach for
using the tool by a different set of
users that we did not talk enough to.
So is the lesson here, don't underestimate the
challenge you'll have convincing a new segment
to buy your thing. You may think they're
close or similar, but they're probably not.
Yeah, that's one of them. The other one
is what took you here is not going to
take you there. And so go back and try to
explain why you are successful today, and
then if you think you can use the same thing
on the next thing, find ways to validate it,
find ways to test it. Don't just go and
build on those assumptions. That's the
main thing I got out of this ordeal
basically for the stuff I did after.
How would you do that? How would you go
about and test it? Is it use research?
Is it the PMs talking to potential
users? What would you have done there?
For example, when we started Jira for the
Discovery, which is, so maybe I should
introduce this for a second. It's a product
for product managers, which is mainly used for
prioritization and roadmap. People use Jira
to plan and track work when it's committed.
We wanted to create a space before that so
people debate priorities with everyone that
should be involved in that prioritization
process, whether it be the developers,
designers, so people in the product team
or people outside of it, customer success,
salespeople, support, leadership and so on and
so forth. When we started, that we thought, okay,
the product managers are already in Jira. You know
what? We can reach them. So we create the tool,
and then we'll distribute it from Jira. We
could have gone down the path of building
that and then started to start to distribute it.
Instead, we did things like before we brought a
single line of code, put an ad inside a Jira
newsletter going, "Hey, we've got this thing
for product managers coming up." And then we
had a website that before we had any line of
code written that said, "Hey, product managers,
your job is hard. We want to help, put your name
here if you want to join us on the journey,"
that kind of thing. And that's when we saw,
I think it was in two weeks, we got more than
3000 signups to that waitlist. We're like, "Okay,
cool. Validation of demand." We are talking
to people who are interested and we can reach
them. That's one examples of the things that I
tried later, just to make sure that we validate
the hypothesis that we've got much earlier on in
the game basically, and not once it's too late.
Awesome. That's an awesome, very tactical example.
Yeah, most of those are, none of what I'm going
to talk about today is revolutionary. A lot
of it is just trying to apply, asking
the right question at the right time,
and trying to go by whatever
means to answer it really.
Any other lessons from the HipChat experience
before we shift to a different product?
I've got two, I'm going to do them quickly. The
first one is competitive myopia, don't fall for
it. At some point, the Slack was really gaining
round and gaining round and capturing more of the
mindshare. And everyone on Twitter was always
loving them. Even when they had outrages,
they were getting congratulated. I was like,
"This is working mad." But the love was so strong,
and the way we tended to revert back is to
our functional side of the brain going, okay,
we just need this one more feature.
We just need this one more feature,
And we ended up reacting to whatever.
... more feature. We just need this one more
feature. And we ended up reacting to whatever the
competitor was doing, which I think is really,
really bad because that's when we lost basically
what made HipChat successful so far, which is to
serve some users really well. And instead we ended
up fast following based on what the competitor was
doing, which is super bad because your competitor,
if you think of what they do as an iceberg,
the top side, what comes out of the water
is what they've shipped in terms of features,
but it's based on all this stuff that they've
built in terms of research and understanding of
their customer base and everything else. And so
you're just seeing the manifestation of what
they were thinking maybe a year ago, based on
what they're shipping now. But we got there.
And now whenever I work, I tend to try and
ignore competition other than watching every
three months or so, seeing what came out,
if there's anything we should be worried about,
afraid of, stuff like that. But really just
try to disconnect all the creative process and
the research process from what competitors do,
because you can't compare. The market is huge.
There are hundreds of thousands of companies
out there. Not everyone has the same needs. We
serve a particular set of segments. We would do
better learning from them to then expand to the
others than watching what competition is doing.
And this is advice you give to your
teams, just ignore the competition,
maybe pay attention at big
announcements and things like that?
We always see in the Slack Channels team
sharing, okay, they just did this with AI,
they just did that. So it keeps coming up,
and so we often have discussions to go back,
to okay, let's watch again the user
interviews that we did over the past
three weeks. Let's watch them all together now
and remember who we are building this for. So
there's a lot of trying to anchor back on
what we know and how, basically building
our own journey on it. And I think it's
much richer for everyone to be involved.
I love that. So you're finding that when
there's a big announcement and everyone's like,
"Oh my God, look what Slack's doing," or
"Look what this company's doing." It's like,
"Okay, now let's spend a little time
reminding ourselves what our customers
have been asking us to do and let's
watch a couple of user interviews."
And even when there is something that competitors
do that is right, remember, we're playing the
long run and we don't always need to be first and
shinier. We need to make sure that people have a
problem, we solve this problem. They tell us, we
solve this problem for them. They are delighted
when we solve these problems for them. And so
that's the stuff we should be obsessing about.
I love that. And you said you had
one more lesson from this experience.
Yeah, the last one, startups have the benefit
of starving. Right? We're a big company,
we can throw a lot of resources at something that
we're excited about. So this notion of we rebuild
the HipChat, was coupled with we rebuild the
HipChat and we'll do this on a new platform,
which is microservices and everything that
we built can be reused across all the other
products. So the chat text box that you've got,
it's an editor that can be open full screen and
it's a Confluence editor with everything that you
can do there. It's built as a platform component,
which is amazing when the platform is there when
you start building the product. Where it's really
difficult is when you try to do the two at the
same time. So I think that part, if I were to work
on HipChat again and say I was leading that thing,
that's the part I would go, okay, we need to win
the problem space first, and if the platform
is there, let's use it. If it's not there,
we'll hack it, test it, iterate on it with
customers, and then whatever is good there,
let's platformize it later.
But that's where you see what
makes us super powerful as a bigger company,
can also slow us down and make us focus on the
wrong assumptions. So in that case, I think we
thought we will win. Interestingly, I think we
were convinced that we had a great shot at this
market. And at the same time we thought that we
could tackle the rewrite and we could tackle the
platformization. All these things were necessary,
but all of them at the same time was probably
a bit too much to bite. Now I'm saying that,
but today the editor you see in Confluence started
with what we did in HipChat back then. So I would
say that in terms of code, purely in terms of
code, 70% of what we wrote for HipChat is probably
still in the Atlassian platform today. But for
a new bet, local Optima, that was really bad.
Yeah. Just thinking about the fact that
Atlassian could have had this $30 billion
business if this worked out, and I could
see why people would be frustrated that it
didn't work out. So thank you for sharing
that story. Let's talk about Statuspage,
another journey that you were a part of, that also
didn't quite work out the way folks had hoped.
Our therapy session continues. Talk about
what that product was and what happened there.
Yeah, so this one is actually a success story,
but became a success story after
I was gone [inaudible 00:34:08]
Okay.
That's more like a story of big companies can
play the long run and for you individually
inside that process, it might look like a loss
and you might feel like you're going nowhere,
yet the company stays on the opportunity for
long enough to make it happen. So what we're
going to talk about here are my own challenges
working through it for something that ended up
being very successful in the end, but I
felt as a failure personally back then.
So Statuspage at some point... So Jira is
used by developers, right? And back then,
I think it was back in 2016 or even before that,
2015, everyone was moving to the cloud, everyone
was adopting DevOps, you build it, you run it. So
basically developers would implement the software
and then they would put it to production.
And after they put it to production, they
don't throw it over the wall to operations people.
It's the same developers who operate the software
in production. They go on call, yada yada.
So back then I did market research to see
whether Atlassian should play there, whether
we had a crack at going after all the jobs
around IT operations. So Jira was basically
Jira software to build software. Could we
have Jira for operations? So for operating this
software. And so I did market research, found a
few companies that were doing super interesting
things there, like [inaudible 00:35:37], Opsgenie,
New Relic. BigPanda was a small startup doing
lots of cool stuff there, and Statuspage. Now
I discovered Statuspage and found their offering
super interesting, in that Atlassian is not an
operations... We don't really build super deep
operations tooling, what we focus on a lot is
the collaborative aspects around everything.
And when I was watching teams in incidents,
I realized that there's a lot of chicken without
a head syndrome, headless chicken, people running
around like bunch of headless chicken.
Shit hits the fan, and then what you
see is teams just scrambling and everything
gets mixed up all together in trying to fix
the problem straight away, but at the same time
questioning what happened, arguing over why we got
there. Your boss is pinging you to go, "Hey,
what's going on? I've been hearing that the app
is down. We're losing money." Customers are
emailing you and asking you what's going...
Your support channels get blown up. Sales people
are worried because their customers are calling
them. So basically, it ends up being a
super stressful experience for everyone.
And what Statuspage was offering is something
seemingly super simple, which is, well,
what you should have is a status page for your
services and you tell your customers about it
and you can subscribe to your status page. Over
there, you've got your services, and for those
services you can publish an incident whenever
there is one, and your customers will be notified,
which means that they're not going to get in
touch with support because they know you're on
it. It's going to build trust with them because
basically you are open in your communication with
them. They're more likely to empathize with your
position and be supportive as opposed to, "Oh,
that stuff is done again." So there
was just so many benefits of that.
I'm going to share a quick story
while you're on this topic.
Yeah, of course.
Funny enough, a decade ago, I used to work
at a website performance monitoring company
and I started a blog called Transparent Uptime.
And my whole blog was about the power of being
transparent about being down, telling people the
status of things are broken right now, here's when
things are going to return. It was a whole thing
I was really obsessed with, and I was deep into
this space. So when I saw Statuspage back in the
day and Atlassian working, I was like, "I love
this." And I actually chatted with the founders
a bit, because they were fans of that work I was
doing back in the day. Completely unrelated
to anything else I've done in my life. But
I was really passionate about this very strange
topic and I love that companies are embracing it.
I really loved diving deep into it for a few
years, it's an amazing topic. And so anyway,
there's so many fascinating things about
this particular domain, but back then... So
find Statuspage and we invited a few of those
companies to work with us for a week to go,
hey, so we're at Atlassian, we're basically
the collaboration hub for everything that
happens for developing teams. What would an
experience look like that puts everything
together and where [inaudible 00:38:48] could
actually help you get the right information
to the right team so they can act on it?
And so we did a week of hackathon in San Francisco
all together. So people from New Relic, Statuspage
and a few other companies. And out of that came
really interesting concepts and there was really
something there and I was like, "Okay, I should
start to work on a business case for Atlassian for
basically IT tool/operations." Now, big companies
like Atlassian, we've got money. So in every
strategy that we've got, we've got cash in the
bank, we always look at should we build, should we
buy, should we partner? Acquisitions can be really
powerful to accelerate you. We've got quite a few
success stories there. Can't remember how many
we did, but Trello is one of the good examples of
that, for example. So we decided to buy Statuspage
and I was running the integration of the
Statuspage business inside the Atlassian business.
Thanks for sharing all that context. What
are some of the things that you learned from
going through this experience? It sounds like
basically it was really painful when you were
a part of it and then it ended up being really
successful. What are some lessons from the pain?
My learnings from it were on the acquisition
side. So big company, we've got cash,
we can buy a company, it will make us go
faster, is not always the case. In my case,
there were quite a few things that were not
as easy as I would've thought. The first one
is the culture shock of a startup that joins your
company. So imagine you're a startup, you've got,
I don't know, 20, 30 staff or something and
things are going well, and you are in full
control of your destiny. And then a company buys
you to accelerate you, but then you stop owning
all the decisions. So the CEO, maybe you become
a product person. The person who was running GTM
but was also doing a bunch of product stuff, and
was also doing a bunch of maybe engineering stuff,
all of a sudden is just working in marketing.
There are decisions that are made above your
head. For example, portfolio fit, which should
be part of your product, which is things that
should be used from the platform that we've got.
So there's a lot of decisions that we're able to
make on the day-to-day basis, that start to
escape you. Big companies look much further
out in the future. So Atlassian would look at the
long game. And so I remember with Statuspage when
they first joined, we asked about the roadmaps
and they were like, well, for the next three
months we're working on that and for the following
three months we're thinking about potentially X,
Y or Z. And so when we're like, "Okay, so what's
the three-year plan?" They're like, "What do you
mean the three-year plan? I don't know, we'll
survive, I guess." Which is what startups do. And
they were very penciled ideas about the future,
but not to the extent of what a big company would
expect. And so that's a really big culture shock.
And what you end up with as well, and that's for
companies who are looking to get acquired out
there or buying other companies, before, you
had a startup and everyone was one team, depending
on how the buying company is organized, you might
land with silos from within your team. So the
way Atlassian is organized is like many Atlassian
companies, we've got a product organization,
we've got an engineering organization, we've
got a marketing organization, design organization,
and they each roll up to a different leader which
may then roll up to the same person, but still by
and large different organizations that are then
assembled into squads and those squads operate
together. But there are rituals that are part of
the squad and there are rituals that ladder up to
where you are in terms of craft. So I do remember
how daunting it was for the Statuspage team when
they joined, to understand how to navigate that.
If I want to hire a new designer, I'm not
talking to the Statuspage CEO anymore,
I need to talk to the head of design for this
area, which has pretty much nothing to do with
the Statuspage business up until the acquisition.
So that is the things that people told me when I
started working on the integration, which
is, hey, remember, you don't know yet,
but integrations are mostly about people. They're
not about technology as much or product vision.
All of that stuff is the easy stuff. The hard part
is the people. And I didn't quite understand at
first and then I really got it by the end of it.
Because what we tell those companies is we can
accelerate by buying, but in reality they are
going to be faced with more internal processes
around how they manage staff, performance
reviews, this concept of engineering allocation,
revenue forecasts, OKRs, long-term roadmaps,
all that stuff comes in very new to them.
So one part of the company top-down says,
we bought you because you are successful,
keep doing what you're doing. While many other
teams without meaning to, basically end up
constantly interacting so that the right processes
are followed, so that the right things are done.
That's a really interesting point,
that one group is keep doing what you're
doing. We're going to leave you alone,
you're the experts. And then other people that
are on the ground actually building it are like,
"Hey, build with this component. Hey, we
need this process, we need this document."
And it's the things that you used to be able to
focus 90% of your time working on your product,
and all of a sudden all of that stuff may
seem parasitical but comes in and interrupts
you all the time. And often the new joiners, they
don't know that they basically are not only being
acquired, they've been hired by the company.
So they basically are joining a different
company with different sets of rituals, with a
different culture. All of that is very different,
basically. It's not going to be the same
for every acquisition. Like I said, we had
some acquisitions that were great. Statuspage
ended up being a huge success inside Atlassian,
but when I was there, I basically worked through
the difficult parts of it, where I was like,
"It's not as simple as people may think." So one
warning, if you're planning to do acquisitions,
make sure you factor all of that in and think
about the integration plans to compensate for
these aspects. So you don't expect the
business to join and keep running at
exactly the same pace, because going to be
a big slowdown before it accelerates again.
So maybe as a last question here, is just
say you were to do an acquisition again and
I don't know if you've gone through more,
what's one thing you would change? What's
one thing you'd recommend of let's make
sure to do this thing very differently?
One aspect that I'm going to talk about
to then go there, but one aspect we didn't
talk about which is we bought a product, how
does that product fit with the rest? And so
we had different types of acquisitions that we
did. One is we buy the company and we keep the
product running and then we try to integrate
it with our tech stack. And then the other
acquisition is we buy the company and then we
kind of rebuild on our platform, or we buy with
this huge synergy with our platform. And so we
call that the frankenstack, otherwise. Which is,
you get one tech stack here, one tech stack
there and they can't quite talk to each other,
identity is different, integrating is different.
And so it looks like a patchwork of products and
that's not what our customers want from us.
So the next time I try personally, I would
treat it like hiring over treating it like buying
business only. So there would be a huge component
which is to both educate and tease out what
it means to actually hire the team inside the
company. At the same time I'm saying that because
I don't want to do a big one. The next one I want
to do is relatively small. Find a company that has
amazing product that we can bring in as a tech-in,
shut down the product, rebuild it on our
platform and so it's basically the equivalent
of an acqui-hire, because basically what we'll
be buying is the acceleration of our roadmap.
We could try and form a team to do what they did,
but they've been successful so they know what
they're doing. We could probably get there one
year faster. What does that mean for our revenue
at the scale of Atlassian, if we can enter a
market one year earlier? It's probably going
to pay the acquisition back on its own. So my
learnings from it were basically that it needs to
be treated like hiring and what I would like to do
next time is more doing it like that, basically.
What about in the case of
HipChat, where it feels like
it was a mistake to rebuild a thing. Is there
for this kind of startup, don't rebuild for
this kind of startup? Start again. Do you
have a thought of how you separate those two?
There's actually a big difference.
There's a big difference. Which is
in one case what you try to do is.... So when
you rebuild, you've got a successful business,
you've got hundreds of thousands of customers,
for example, and you're trying to rebuild the
same thing or a different thing, but for the same
customers that have got expectations about your
current product. In the other one is you buy a
company that's got some traction, not too much,
so you can shut down the business and then rebuild
on your platform to reach your customer base. So
it's not the same as trying to rebuild the plane
mid flight, it's delaying takeoff. It's like,
"Yeah, we did a trial run, the plane landed. Okay,
cool. Switch to another plane, takeoff again."
Got it. I love that. Any other key insights and
lessons from this experience before
we get to your product discovery?
One last one and then I'm going to stop with the
therapy session, thank you very much for offering.
No, no, we got to keep it going. I got to
rack up the bill on this therapy session.
Which is, remember I mentioned I was working on a
business case for... Basically going bigger in IT
operations. And so there was as Statuspage as part
of it, but there was a lot of stuff that I wanted
to be able to do inside Jira and a whole bunch of
other products to basically go big in that area,
IT operations, before Jira service management,
which is a very successful product we've got
around that. Before it was really entering that
part of the market. Everyone was excited. It was
before we had an incubator internally. And
so I was trying to pitch it like let's build
a new product that's centered around that
thing. It's on Jira and it integrates with
these tools that we discussed and we can put in
Statuspage there and that's actually how we could
accelerate them as well, and so on and so forth.
Everyone was excited, thought it made sense,
lots of encouragement. I pitched it to every
level of the organization from business leaders,
to the CTO that we had at the time, to the CEOs.
No one said no, no one said yes. For months.
For months, I was in this limbo of, I think
everyone's excited about this, everyone wants
this to happen, but it's not happening. And so I
remember talking with my boss at the time going,
what's going on? When do I stop pushing? Because
at some point I'm sure I'm going to start pissing
people off. And he was like, "Well, basically when
you lose the passion for it. Keep going up until
you feel like it's not worth pushing anymore."
And I remember looking at this advice and going,
wow, that was not helpful at all, based on the
situation that I was in. But basically at some
point I basically gave up. What happens though,
and I understood that after because the company
ended up going there just a year later, was that
I misread the appetite and sense of urgency around
that topic and the fact that Atlassian being
Atlassian, we invest in so many markets, we have
many opportunities like this that sit on a shelf.
Someone did the analysis, someone created a
business case, that thing makes sense. There
may not be a trigger for the why now. So we
need a very strong trigger for why now to go
after it. And I did not do a good enough job
at articulating this. Why now? Why do we have to
do this now versus in a year's time, in two years
time? And the next team that came in afterwards
did a much better job at that. But for me, that
was a great learning, which is great work can get
parked and [inaudible 00:51:20]. And yeah, that's
just what happens, which is because we have so
many opportunities and there's many companies out
there that are probably faced with that, doesn't
mean that we have to go after all of them. But it
does make sense to explore them, and then decide
when to pull the trigger, and that rationale for
the sense of urgency needs to be there. It
needs to be beautiful to the business days.
This reminds me of my chat with Mihika, who
does similar work at Figma where she works
a lot of zero to one stuff. And she described
it as your job is to keep the flame alive and
help it spread throughout the entire business
if you're trying to get everyone on board with
a new idea. And I like this very tactical piece
of advice you're sharing here of how to do that,
is make it clear why this is.... I think
of it as why is it perishable? Why is this
opportunity perishable? Why is it going
to disappear if we don't act on it now?
And you could think of it as why do we have
to do this now? It's not just like "This is
a huge opportunity." But we also need to
do it right now to give people motivation.
Yeah, that was a huge learning for me. I wasted
months on it, but like with every failure,
learnings came out of it in the painful way. So
product managers are often biased towards action,
or at least that's my case. I want to go and
do stuff and build stuff, and try stuff with
customers. And so being idle, waiting for
a confirmation is not a great spot to be,
but sometimes you need to recognize when
you're there and it's good to step back.
This episode is brought to you by Coda and I mean
that literally. I use Coda every day to help me
plan each episode of this very podcast. It's where
I keep my content calendar, my guest research,
and also the questions that I plan to ask
each guest. Also, during the recording itself,
I have a Coda page up to remind myself what I want
to talk about. Coda is an all-in-one platform that
combines the best of documents, spreadsheets,
and apps to help you and your team get more
done. Now is the perfect time to get started
with Coda, especially its extensive planning
capabilities. With Coda, you can stay aligned and
ship faster by managing your planning cycles in
one location. You can set and measure OKRs with
full visibility across teams and stakeholders.
You can map dependencies, create progress
visualizations, and identify risk areas. Plus
you can access hundreds of pressure-tested
templates for everything from roadmap
strategy to final decision-making, to PRDs.
If you want a platform that empowers your team
to strategize, plan and track goals together,
you can get started with Coda today for free.
And if you want to see for yourself why product
teams at high-growth companies like Pinterest,
Figma and Qualtrics run on Coda, take advantage of
the special limited-time offer just for startups.
Head over to coda.io/lenny to sign up and get
$1,000 in credit. That's C- O-D-A.io/lenny, to
sign up and get $1,000 in credit. Coda.io/lenny.
Let's try to summarize some of the biggest
lessons so far that you've shared before we get to
product discovery. So a few things I noted here,
just how to be successful, building zero to one
at a large company. One is be very clear, are the
users you're going to be building this new product
to actually the same users you're already selling
to? And it may feel like they are close enough,
but in the case of HipChat, you learned maybe not,
and it's a lot harder than you expected.
Two is be careful when you rewrite. In some cases,
shut it down, rewrite it immediately,
accelerate this new idea internally.
In other cases and you shared, and so you
could rewind if you want to get the actual
details of when it makes sense to go one or the
other. Sometimes doesn't make sense to rewrite,
just keep what you're doing and focus on the
user problems and don't slow down. Another tip
I wrote down is ignore the competition. Don't
be obsessed with what they're doing. Focus on
what your users are asking you for. And then this
idea of paying attention to the why now, that's a
really good one. Just like when you're trying to
make a case, make it clear why it has to happen
now. Is there anything else that comes to mind
as I try to summarize some of the advice so far?
No, that seems like a good one. The
main one I'm getting also out of this,
is if you try to start new things, it's going
to be coming from your drive and your passion,
and that's what pushes stuff forward. So
don't give up. Because I try really hard
before getting to one that worked. So I guess
that's probably a testament for it's possible.
And a testament to your grit and desire
to make something work. So on that note,
let's talk about your product discovery. I know
this is a success at this point. I know there was
also a lot of pain that went into this and things
that didn't work. So I'd love to hear both sides
of it, just like what was hard about getting this
off the ground and then also just what worked,
what allowed you to make this work?
So start wherever you want to start.
Yeah, cool. So let's start with the good stuff
before we go back into therapy. Some of the
good stuff here is Atlassian at that point
had recognized we are innovating in our big
successful products all by doing acquisitions,
we have to correct that and start building new
products ourselves as well. And so there was a
huge push from the founders to go, "Hey, we need
to restart that." Out of it came Point A, which
was an internal incubator program that was meant
to fix that. And the way they framed it was that
innovation is like a muscle. Unless you exercise
it, it becomes weak, and what we have to do now
is to work on it again. And so out of that thing,
Point A and Jira Product Discovery was one of
the... I think it was one of the 100 pitches
that went through that innovation program.
There were 100 pitches and out of it came out
three products that basically went through all
the different stages of it. And so it started
with Jira Product Discovery was actually made
possible because of that and because we're inside
Atlassian. So we started with a lot of, I could
take time to focus on this stuff with nothing
else to do it. It was a full-time job, because of
this incubator. I was able to form a team easier
because there was budget allocated. I was able
to form a team that was not worried about losing
their job because the program was made so that
technically speaking, you would borrow people
from other departments. If that thing doesn't
work out, they go back to your department. So
there's no fear of losing your job, basically.
We were able to tap into all the research that
was done by our research and insights team
internally. We were able to have the corporate
development team working with us. I met with
probably 20 companies that played in things
around product management before forming a
view that, hey, maybe we should play there.
And all those teams are willing to talk to
us because Atlassian is a big player in this
market. And so there's always the opportunity of
integrating, being bought, partnering that can...
The opportunity of integrating, being bought,
partnering, that kind of stuff. I was able
to meet with analysts to say, "Hey, so what do
you think about the product management market?"
This was all part of the Point A structure?
So the Point A structure, not all of it was
formalized in Point A, remember Point A back
then was created alongside the first bets
that went through it, and ours was one bet
as part of that. So we forged the path for all
the ones that came afterwards. But basically,
it gave us the crags to go in and ask for help
from everyone, and everyone knew it was important.
Because everyone knew the company priorities and
the new products were top company priority. And
so Atlassian, playing the long game, had decided
that it was okay to invest in these bets and to
reassess them into every three to six months to
understand whether we should put more chips in it.
And so the psychological safety of everyone's
job was safe, coupled with access to all the
resources from the company. That part was just
invaluable to the success of what JPD is today.
So to give you a bit of context, Jira Product
Discovery started four years ago with some
research. I was alone back then, and then we
were three. The first line of code was written
three years before we launched officially,
as generally available. Which means that for
three years we were dogfooding alpha or beta
and able to do that with the full support
of the company. So when I mention the long
game, I mean it. It's something that's very
hard to get in most companies out there.
And when people ask me about how to stop
incubators, it's like think about it with when
you're going to get your dollars back and forget
about it for a while. What you need to see is how
the teams are answering the right questions that
they ask along the way, and seeing whether you
are still excited about the bets as they do that.
Anyway, so we launched a year ago. Fast-forward
to today, we've got 8,000 customers, amazing CSAT,
great traction. It's one of the fastest
growing products in Atlassian history,
which is great. So what was hard though, the first
one was reminding everyone that failure is the
most likely outcome. And I will die on that hill
to explain to people when they want to stop things
internally, frame it like that, remind everyone.
There's a [inaudible 01:00:28] 70% chance,
[inaudible 01:00:30] completely pulled out
of thin air that whatever you're working
on is not going to exist in six months.
We're trying to launch a new product, enter
a new market. Our goal is to get to $100 million
businesses. So there's not that many of them out
there. We have tried and we have failed. And a
few of them are Atlassian. And so remember that,
and it's super important to remember that because
otherwise the company has a tendency to over
invest, not the company top-down, parts of the
company have the tendency to come and try to help.
So for example, "Here, we want to build this."
"Oh, if you want we could change this service
to be able to XYZ for you." "No, we are a bet,
which is seven people. Let's not drag the rest
of the company into it. The appetite that the
company has right now is these seven people.
We'll see what we can do with these seven
people," was what I was telling everyone.
The reason I was saying that is that, otherwise,
yes, you get the help, but the help always comes
with condition and the condition is usually
things slow down. So what we try to do is
remind everyone, things are going to fail, so that
we could basically buy the opportunity to hack
shit together that is not going to scale, that
is not going to respect our design guidelines,
that is not going to fit with the JIRA target
architecture. But we're going to test this with
customers and see if the concepts make sense,
if the prototypes make sense, whether they get
value out of those before we tell you, "Hey, you
know what? That thing is a thing and by the way,
now we're a proper business. We should
build that thing into the platform."
This is really interesting because it's
counterintuitive to think that you should position
your new bets as, this is most likely going
to fail. This is just the thing we're trying,
don't worry, don't commit too much this
yet, don't worry about giving us all these
resources. Why do you think that's so important?
Because I don't think most companies position
new incubations that way. Why do you think
that's so effective and more effective?
Yeah. So the thing that we're trying to do when
starting new products is to basically emulate a
startup in an environment that is not hungry, is
not starving. And so you need to create scarcity.
What I wanted with my team is to make sure that
they feel the urgency. That thing needs to move.
I also needed the rest of the company to go
away, so we could get the autonomy to test
the things that we needed to know whether
this thing is even going to work or not.
We could not go into a planning session for
the next six months to negotiate something
with a platform service so we can build a
feature to then test with users. I said,
"Now, we're rebuilding this component and we're
testing this with customers next week. It's not
perfect. It's not perfect." And so that helped us
a lot, but otherwise there's always this tendency
of the process that works for everything else
is going to work for this and we do need to
keep reminding them, "Hey, we might not exist in
six months. Do you really care that much about
this process right now? The product might not
exist anymore." The process goes away usually.
So it's basically a trick to keep everyone
else within the org away and not worry about
what you're building? Because you just tell them,
"Don't worry, this is not going to work out. We're
just going to try this thing just to see." So it's
not for your team to feel like, "This is probably
not going to work out." I imagine the team is
like, "Oh, we got to make this work. It's such a
good idea." It's more as a trick to keep the org
from swallowing you up and pushing you around?
So there's a part of that, but
there's also really a need from...
We need to respect Atlassian's dollars here, and
if we don't know whether this thing is going to
work... I do not want to drag a team of 50 people
into this. I want to know that this thing is worth
the investment of a team of 50 people. So it's
a bit of both, actually. Now, it's of course,
easier said than done. And so that's where, again,
Point A helped. We had four stages called Wonder,
Explore, Make and Impact, where in the first stage
it was all about proving that there was a problem
area we could go into, there was a market.
We could answer very clearly, articulate why
Atlassian should move there. We could
articulate why now that stuff that
[inaudible 01:04:35] struggled with before,
and have enough data to validate all those
claims. Explore was about exploring solutions,
which doesn't mean build it and throw it out
there and see what sticks. It's about if you
get a bunch of customers raising a problem,
can you get them to play back to the solution,
[inaudible 01:04:53] address that problem?
And so in the case of Jira Product Discovery,
because we were not building, we didn't need
any new technology, it was mainly new UX and new
workflows, we basically validated a lot of that
with Figma in dozens of Zooms. But it's basically
coming back saying, "Here's how those companies
are framing it. Here's their problems, here's
how this thing would be solving it for them."
So that's part of Explore, which is
validating that it's worth investing
in in terms of solution. We don't only have the
right problem, we've got the right solutions. Then
Make is about making it happen in stages,
starting with an alpha, then a beta,
and then going out there. And Impact is that stuff
is actually ready to go [inaudible 01:05:37]. And
now let's see the impact it has on Atlassian's
business and keep monitoring it from there.
And it turns into a real business from that
point onwards. But everyone at Atlassian knew
these four stages, Wonder, Explore, Make,
Impact. Whenever we were talking with teams,
we were telling them we're currently in Explore.
And we started doing that with the full bet
itself. Then we started doing that to talk about
the different features that we were working on
or problem areas we were going after. Which means
that now every time we go into conversation with
other teams and we'll mention, "We're in Wonder,"
or, "We're in Explore," they know what to expect.
When we go to someone in the leadership team
and we say, "We want to go from Explore to
Make," they know they're going to [inaudible
01:06:22] because they need developers now.
So all that vocabulary and clear expectations set
for every stage of the process really helped us
to facilitate all the conversations that we had
with everyone in the organization. And really
protected us again from all those, basically,
teams that felt like they had to chime in. Now,
we're in Explore, we don't have anything ready
that's been validated. Let's not have opinions
about how the architecture is done before we
have validated that customers want something.
This is super cool. I feel like we
could do a whole podcast just on
the structure of Point A and how you
all do this. But just one question,
what does the gate look like when you move from
Explore to Make, Make to Impact? Is there a group
of people that sit in a room and decide thumbs
up, thumbs down? How does that decision work?
So we basically write a six pager that looks at
all the different aspects of all the questions
that we're going to answer. And then we are in
a meeting with the Point A stakeholders and the
founders of Atlassian. And everyone reads that
page for about 15 minutes and then question,
answers, comments, and [inaudible 01:07:31]
of that, by the end of this meeting, we know
whether we are clear to go to the next stage.
We got booted back one time when we were like,
"Hey, we're ready to go anywhere from alpha
to beta as part of Make." And they're like,
"No, you're not." And I was like,
"No, we're not." And so we stayed
and we basically got more time than what was
initially allocated to us. But basically,
the founders and the leadership of
Point A as well as heads from the
different lines of businesses at Atlassian
were participating in those sessions, which-
That is super cool.
Basically, visibility all the way up.
And they might also just decide,
"Let's kill this thing, it's not
working," at one of these meetings.
So it might be, "Let's kill this thing," which
happened to a number of bets that we did,
or it might be, "Let's roll this thing
into something else." So for example,
our new whiteboards product. I say product,
whiteboards feature part of Confluence
initially came out of Point A. And was
eventually rolled into Confluence instead because
[inaudible 01:08:32] made more sense there.
That's so interesting. So you said there's
100 projects that went through Point A. So
there's this funnel. Is there a meeting
for all 100 of these that the founders
go to for all these incubations or did
they come join later down the funnel?
Not the full 100 of them.
Okay, good.
And I'm saying 100, it's over a few
different quarters of teams coming in
and [inaudible 01:08:53], but not for
the initial stage of entering Point A.
I see.
It's usually when they've been accepted.
I interrupted you and took us on a tangent,
you were sharing essentially the things that
went well and how this all came together.
So failure as the most likely outcome. It's the
one thing I would stand behind in everything
because I've seen before what happens when we
get too complacent with it's going to work.
Lessons from the previous things I was talking
about. So this one really key. Second one,
this one is much harder, which is if you're
starting something like this, your teams will need
to break a lot of rules that are established. But
they need to be able to do that without breaking
the trust of everyone in the organization.
The rules were created to support the business
at the stage where it was successful, and it
just so happens that they might not work for
new bets. So the trick here for me has been
to... The way I pictured it is, I've got a
bunch of chips. Since I joined my class, I've
been accumulating chips and those chips are-
Like social capital.
Yeah. It's like trust I've built with the
founders, with the different business leaders,
with succeeding on stuff or failing and
explaining why and trying to do better
next time. And all that stuff gave me, like
you said capital. I've got these chips and I
decided on this bet, "You know what, I'm going
to go all in." So I always said, "If it works,
it works. If it doesn't work, I'm probably
out of here, but I'm going to go all in."
So if I see something that's not going to work,
I'm going to say it. We're not going to do it.
And so I knew I was going to put myself in
tough conversations because people are here
to protect things that need to be protected.
They just don't make sense for the stuff I was
working on. So one example, breaking rules
without breaking trust where it was tricky.
We have a lot of rules in a company like
Atlassian, and this is how it works in
engineering. I mean, engineers are the biggest
part of our workforce. Basically, shit gets
done because engineers work on it. And what I
needed was to be able to hire the right team,
only principal levels, people who have a lot of
internal credits so that they can commit to any
team's repo, no questions asked. People who
are not looking for the next promotion, but
they want to make a splash. And when that's not
possible, I wanted to be able to hire contractors
to fill in the gaps and stuff like that. And
I was like, "A lot of the rules that I need to
be able to break is basically in engineering."
So I decided not to have an engineering leader
in the team, and to do it myself.
So I was the product leader and the
engineering leader. I was technical enough to
be able to have these conversations, but mainly
I was just working with amazing engineers who
just could self-drive themselves. So they were
able to make changes in areas that were not owned
by them. They were able to do changes that do not
respect any of our standards. They were able
to hack their way around rebuilding services
and whatnot. We are now not in the position where
we need to do stuff like that, but at that time I
needed to take a position like that so we could
actually go and move fast with basically the
equivalent of being a startup inside Atlassian.
That's not comfortable to do stuff like that.
And I would not recommend that in many
environments. Atlassian was very forgiving
throughout the whole thing. It doesn't mean
that I didn't [inaudible 01:12:27] on that.
That was not simple. For example, one of the
rules is, at that time we didn't want to have
a footprint in Europe back then for more
engineering teams. It's different today,
but back then it was like that. I was like, "Shit.
I'm based in France, I'm trying to start this
stuff. I don't want to move to the US or move
back to Australia just for this right now." So
I hired contractors, lots of contractors when we
started, or not lots because we're not a big team,
but contractors to build this stuff.
And again, contractors, they don't fall
into the same rules as the rest of engineering
staff. So basically, all the rules around you
need to contribute to... For example, the
engineering team could say, "[inaudible
01:13:10] to the next, leadership could say, "You
need to invest 15% of your time in reliability."
And for us it's like, "We're not there yet.
We don't even have a prototype out." Yeah.
But that's the company rule, all right. Again,
no engineering manager and contractors, boom,
none of these rules applied. So it was people who
were looking at it from the outside who were like,
"Wow, dude, are you sure you're okay with all
this?" And it felt super uncomfortable, but
we have the support of leadership from it. It's
just a tough transition for Atlassian from the,
"We only invest in the big ones for acquisitions,"
to "Let's invest in [inaudible 01:13:46]."
This is a crazy story you're telling me. So you're
leading this team, you hired a team of contractors
to build this product. You're in a whole
different country from the rest of Atlassian,
basically. And the whole idea here was just to
do stuff that wouldn't be necessarily allowed
at Atlassian. They wouldn't let you work
this way. And you found that to make the
thing you needed to make, the thing that you
were betting your career on, it sounded like,
you're just going to be this pirate working
on this thing in France and it worked out?
So the Point A emoji and Atlassian is a [inaudible
01:14:24]. I was not the only one. There were
quite a few of us working on new bets, basically
operating like that. Each questioning different
rules. The end goal was not to question the
rules, the end goal was to get to the stuff that
we needed to do, which is we just need to clean
this space, to work with users to test prototypes
up until it works and progressively get to, as
I said, a product that's going to be enough to
launch. So we never intended to break the rules,
which is the things that we were going to choose
the ones that were going to work to support
us on this mission and say no to the others.
You mentioned Europe. At the time, a lot of other
Point A founders were struggling with the fact
that they were operating from their mothership in
Sydney because they're still with everyone else.
You were talking about doing all this stuff,
but remember that we've got this OKR thing,
we've got this vision for GR that we're building,
you need to participate in all this. And so I was
in Europe going, "Fine, schedule it at your time."
And I think a lot of teams were like, "We don't
care enough about this test. They're telling
us it's not going to exist in six months. I
don't care enough about this to stay up late
or wake up super early every day to disagree
with them." And so there was a lot of the
early success that we had in being able to
move super fast that came from being so far,
that people just did not engage to stop us.
And that's why we were initially the group
with the fastest speed. Then it was possible
to institutionalize those things into Point A
to then make it possible to do it from within
Atlassian. But at first, we just needed to
blaze our way through. So that's what we did.
So it sounds like one of the biggest
lessons and things that work well for
something like this is a super silo sort
of team, as much as you can disconnect
from the core business and let them
just do what you think you need to do?
You've interviewed Megan on the show before.
Yeah.
And I listened again to the way she pitched
Point A, and yes, that's exactly what came
out of what she was saying. Which is, we gave
the space for those teams to be able to do
this with a lot of autonomy. And that was the
outcome of all that work, basically, which is
the program was then set up so new teams could do
it and fitting within the mothership, basically.
And I think people hear that, like yeah, okay,
of course. [inaudible 01:16:59] incubations,
silo, separate, they do their own thing.
People hear and they try to do that,
but I imagine it's not actually what they need
to do. And what I'm hearing is you went to a
pretty far extreme of making that happen, not
basically breaking the rules to allow for a silo
to actually exist. And I love that. What else
was key to the success of making this work out?
So the one that I'm most passionate about is
how we work with customers is very different
in a super early stage bet versus to what you
do in a very established product like Jira. So
the first part is, how can we innovate in a way
that doesn't fuck up existing customers? Jira,
120,000 customers, Atlassian, 300,000 customers.
We can't just go in there, start experimenting,
breaking a whole bunch of shit that millions of
people experience and go, "What are you doing,
Atlassian?" So what we needed is to create
this area where we could experiment that's
away from Jira while being inside Jira.
That part was a bit tough. It's possible
to do. In fact, I came across an article
from Ben Weiss. No, sorry, Noah Weiss,
it's from many years ago now. Where he was
basically talking about innovating in a successful
material product and talked about three stages of
incubate, iterate, integrate. And as part of that
he gave the examples of Instagram, Twitter, and
Foursquare. Where basically he was explaining,
at the beginning, for example, Instagram was
a feed that was chronological. And then the
team started to experiment with a popular tab
that was on the side that was not integrated
into the core of the product that everyone uses.
They iterated on that for a while. That became
the explore tab and then the explore tab became
the main feed. The feed is not chronological
anymore, it's based on your interests. And that
part really resonated with me where I was like,
"You know what? We're going to try to apply that
to Jira, which is we're going to build it in Jira,
but we're going to extract ourselves
from a lot of the core components of
the core base to rebuild the UX that would
work for the audience we're going after."
Our audience is product managers.
They have no patience for spinners,
things need to be visual. They need to be able
to quickly move things around to visualize the
potential options they've got on their roadmaps
and stuff like that. It needs to be snappy,
it needs to get out of the way, but also something
that they can feel proud to present to their
stakeholders to have discussions around that.
It can be bogged down into the details. It can
go to very, very deep [inaudible 01:19:43].
It needs to be an area, a space where you
feel like you can breathe and have creative
conversations. And Jira's UI was not exactly
known for that. And in fact, most of the product
managers I talked to were like, "I don't want
to do this in Jira. It's too strict, there's
too many workflows, it's owned by IT," yada,
yada. And so we said, "That's fine. We're going to
experiment with an experience that's going to be
detached from Jira still on the same platform."
And that's what we did, basically. And so this
concept of incubate by working on something
on the site, iterate until you've got it right
and then integrate it back into the main
product is something I would definitely
do again. We're currently in the middle of the
integration phase for Jira product discovery.
So the lesson there is don't force yourself to be
a part of the broader product, initially. First,
figure out what it could be if it's its own
thing, and then eventually you can integrate?
It depends who you're doing it for and the
programs that they've got. Don't feel limited by
your platform to answer the core things that are
necessary for your product to work, basically. So
if the platform is good enough for us, if the
UX was good enough for the product managers,
we would not have done that. And we would've had
a hard time justifying it, but because it was not,
we basically gave ourselves the stamp to
be able to do it. So still in don't fuck
existing customers, something I read from a site,
from Reforge that talk about the Safety Funnel.
So they have this thing where the typical
growth funnel goes from acquisition all
the way to revenue and there's a whole bunch
of different stages in between. Your goal is
to maximize the number of people who
go through this funnel successfully.
And I was trying to explain to people what we
were trying to do with Jira Product Discovery,
and I was struggling to put a name on it.
And it was we're going to work with a few,
small number of customers up until it's right
for them and then we're going to expose it to
progressively more people. And I know it's very
common sense, but that's basically what we decided
to do instead of the Atlassian way, which was
more, "Hey, we measure our success based on..."
For example, at that time, I think it was still
before all those projects, "... monthly active
users." If that was a measure of success, we
would've been pushed very quickly to go and
expose it to as many people as we could. We
didn't want to do that because if they would
have a bad experience, it would've been
very hard to claim them back afterwards.
So someone in Reforge put the name on Safety
Funnel. So the Safety Funnel is amazing. People
don't understand that. You basically put a hard
stop and you limit the number of people who had
bad experiences. And you do that for a while,
up until you can prove it's amazing and then you
invite more people. So we did a lot of that. So
we basically created that pocket away from Jira
to reimagine what Jira could be for product
managers. And we only exposed that to a very
small number of customers at first. So that's
don't fuck existing customers' first principle.
And the reason that's important,
just to put a point there,
is the business will start to get upset
if you're making many customers upset.
That would've been it if we had
triggered an incident that brought
down Jira for millions of users. And
first time might have been okay. I mean,
by the third time we would've been
asked to pack up and go home, I think.
Got it. So the advice there is just limit how many
people get exposed to your very early product,
even if it's going to hurt your numbers.
You don't want to cause people to be like,
"What the hell are you doing over
there, man? [inaudible 01:23:17]."
So [inaudible 01:23:17] your numbers is now the
interesting one. So how do you frame success
and how do you define metrics when your goal is
basically to work with a small number of customers
for a super long time? So that's what I ended
up defining for this, is based on a term that
was used at Atlassian that I tried to formalize
it into something that everyone could refer to,
which is the Lighthouse Users Program. And
so the principle for it is it's a program,
so it's an official thing. We have hundreds
of thousands of customers at Atlassian,
but we would only build the experience for a small
number of them. And so there are stages to it.
The first stage is we work with 10 and we prove
that the problems that they had are the things
that we solved and where we spend most of the
time for the first 10 Lighthouse Users is to
explain why they are the Lighthouse Users.
Everything that explains why we believe they
are a proxy for every customer that we serve
afterwards. We then have this stage from 10
to 100 where we recruit more customers, but
we're still not in the fully self-service,
don't need a lot of onboarding stuff.
We're still testing out the value,
but we're testing the different variations in
the scenarios that people face to make sure
that the core solution that we've got can cater
for those. So there's a lot of different options
and different security needs. There's a lot of
subtleties that you catch between 10 and 100.
Then we get to a stage where we're like, "You
know what? It's good. It solves people's problems,
but it's not self-service. We just need to
explain stuff. We need to work with people
on Slack. We need to work with them and
answer a lot of support tickets or do a
lot of Zoom calls to explain stuff."
Now we need to get from 100 to 1,000,
and by getting there we basically need
to solve all of that and after that we
graduate. So basically by detailing that and
explaining all the success criteria in between,
it helps to define success in that in the make
phase, we've got 10, 100, 1,000, and then people
can understand exactly where we're at there, and
the types of questions we're trying to answer.
In the 10, we're answering every question with a
user, snippet of a video call with them, either
talking about their problem and solution but
showing the product and how they solve with it.
That's how we wanted our stakeholders to view it,
which is it's very qualitative, but have it felt
from the user's perspective. It's different
when we go from 10 to 100, from 100 to 1,000,
but for each of those there's a playbook for
how you go from one to the other. That helped
us because we could then clean the space to
do the right thing and we will not ask to hit,
for example, a multi-active user's number or
number of customers' number or percentage of
users who use this number. Because it's very
qualitative still when we're at that stage.
That is super cool and super interesting.
And it's along the lines of the gates. It
aligns with, at each gate, here's how many
users we're looking for. Basically, it sets
expectations for what success is, keeps you
from having to scale things too early. It's
such a cool idea. And you call it Lighthouse
Users, like the Lighthouse Users Program?
Lighthouse Users, and there's two sides to it.
We just talked about the stakeholder facing
side. The one I love is the team facing side
of this, which is I've seen a lot of teams,
Atlassian and other companies as the
products grow, you tend to leverage a lot
more user research, formal user research
or CSAT service. And the way I call it,
it's hiding behind research and not being
close enough to the ground with customers.
And what I want to do in the teams
I work with is to create a direct
feedback loop with customers, but not like someone
gives you feedback and you do it. We talk...
... with customers, but not like someone gives
you feedback and you do it. We talk to those
customers, we build stuff for them. So there's
something I've seen which is climate change.
It's a thing. Everyone knows it's a thing.
We all read reports about it. We're all
like ... Every time we read an IPCC report we're
like, "Shit." Do we change anything? Not enough.
What makes people want to change and actually
gives them a trigger to change? I've seen is
a lot more empathizing with individual
people's experience. If I know someone
that's impacted by climate change, it's going
to make me relate a lot more strongly to the
concept of climate change and want to change
myself. Sorry for the power note here. I'm-
No, that's such a good example. Such a good
way of making that point very clear of just
the power of talking to a small number of users
versus thinking that the more data you have,
looking at data, CSAT scores, NPS
retention will tell you what you need.
So what we do with that is we recruit 10
people and we put these people in front of
the whole team, not just the PMs, PM, designer,
engineering. We meet on Zoom, we chat, we work
with the same ones over months to build a product.
They are with us on Slack. We have regular things.
What we've seen, what I've seen going
fast is that the engineers would go into
a planning meeting and the PM would say, "So
we should work on X," and the engineer will go,
"Wait a minute. We've had a talk with this
customer and they struggle with this so I
think we should work on that instead and fix that
part of the experience," and so on and so forth.
So all of a sudden you're not
talking about a product manager,
you're talking about a product team
with product engineers. So there was
this thing at Atlassian where we called some
engineers were more like system engineers,
some were more product engineers.
In my opinion everyone can be a product
engineer. They just need to be exposed to the
right user context. The right user context,
what is it? It's 10 customers you
know by name, you know their context,
you know their problems. You can empathize with
it. This empathy makes you want to act to change
your product to solve their problem and you
get really huge pride coming back out of it.
It can seem counterintuitive in a company like
Atlassian. 300,000 customers, right? We should
build for them. Well, you can't, right? We're
limited in our ability to make changes that
will work for the vast majority so might as well
embrace that. Embrace that we are indeed biased,
that we are indeed reacting based on feelings,
like wanting to help or not wanting to help or
reacting strongly to what you've seen, but we
are embracing that to try and build the best
product possible. I've actually seen that the
outcome is, so far on this product it's worked.
If you actually think about this from the
perspective of how would a startup approach
this? This is exactly how a company that's just
starting out would approach it. So it makes
tons of sense to think of it this way. It's just
people don't actually do this. It's hard to do.
This is a segue to a question I wanted to
ask. So it took probably a long time for
you to show real success, real progress, real
like, "This is going to work." First of all
how long was that period of just like, "This
is probably not going to work too. Oh wow,
maybe this is going to work"? And along the
same lines, how does Atlassian slash ... What
have you learned about how to protect this, Pixar
people call it an ugly baby? When an idea is new
they call this an ugly baby. People don't want
it. It's just like, "Get rid of this thing."
Man, that sounds mean to say, but that's the way
they talk about it. That's the term in creativity.
That's a good one.
How do you protect that because that's the biggest
challenge I think a lot of companies have is just
like, "It's been six months. No one wants this.
We're going to kill it." How do you protect it?
So how long did it take for it to show success
and what have you learned about how to protect?
Yeah. So basically, internal comms is everything
there. The way I saw my job as, a large part as
being very clear on where we were, on what we were
learning on, how fast we were learning, how fast
we were moving. Being super honest every step of
the way, not try to make shit up and try to make
it bigger than it is, more successful than it is.
On the contrary, be very clear about what we're
testing, where we're testing it. Doing that with
data, doing that with personal customer stories
because we all can constantly relate to the
heart and to the mind. So that's what I always
try to weave into comms that I then send weekly.
So we've got this product internally called Atlas,
which have a project on Atlas. People can
subscribe to this project and then weekly
you send a tweet-sized update about
your project. I was using that as a
platform to communicate internally about this
product and there were actually hundreds of
people who ended up subscribing to this thing.
Every week when we were at the stage where we
were trying to get the first version out
to customers it was a weekly demo of the
product and everything that we built. Show the
momentum as much as possible. I was even saving
features for one week to the next just to ...
When I knew we were going to be on vacation,
for example, just to have something to
show this train that keeps moving, it keeps
moving. You don't want to get in front of it.
But then what I needed to do is to balance that
out with all the customer side of things. So when
we started to put it in front of customers then
it was snippets from customer conversations.
No one is going to read a research report that
takes 30 minutes to read. Everyone is happy
to watch a three-minute snippet with four
customers talking about something. So I was
using that a lot every week by posting those
out there and then sharing them widely on Slack
to go, "This is what we learned. This is what
this customer is facing in terms of problem
with Jira. This is how we're solving it. This
is them talking about it," that kind of stuff.
So I was publishing that there and then sending
that everywhere on Slack. Those kinds of things
are what give people a sense of velocity and
speed, and no one wants to fuck with a high-speed
train. You don't get in front of it. That doesn't
help and you're going to look bad by doing
that. So basically that ended up buying us
the time that we needed to get out of this, I
don't know how you call it, the ugly baby phase.
An ugly baby phase.
So basically it helped us get out of this
phase where we don't have anything to show
for yet because what we're showing is based on the
learnings we're trying to get and we're trying to
do that with, "Here's some numbers, here's some
demos, here's some user snippets." Doing that
every week because people can consume bite-sized
content every week. They just struggle with the
stuff where you come in three, four months later
and go, "This is what we have to show for."
Right. How long was that period before
it got out of this ugly baby phase for
you? When did people start to get
like, "Oh wow, this might work"?
Honestly, we had something dogfooding within
two months, in the hands of the first lighthouse
user within five months. We iterated on
the alpha for maybe six months. We then
entered a beta that lasted close to a year.
So I think at every step of the way people
could see us going somewhere, and I think
initially they judged, not the outcome. They
judged the team a lot more than the outcome.
So there's all this talk of founder market fit
and I think really that's what you need to be
teasing out, which is, is it the right thing,
going after the right problems? Then if they can
answer yes in ways that you haven't thought about
asking consistently week over week, it's enough.
I think that's where we were up until the stage
where we were able to give something to customers,
but the first lighthouse user was five months in.
So it didn't even matter whether it looked good
or not because people could see, "Okay, that's
what ... Oh, there's something there," right?
So I'm not sure if there's one precise moment
where it happened. However, there was this one
moment where we were like, "Okay, that's it.
We're ready to go GA." One of the founders, Mike
went, "No, you're not. That thing is ugly. I do
not want to look at it. It needs to level up with
the rest of the Atlassian design standards. Our
customers have expectations from us on that front.
Your stuff is functional, but it's way too early."
So we went and fixed it. Took us two, three
months and then we were okay to go. But yeah,
no, because we had point A, because we had
this expectation set that it would take a
while to get there and because we were able to
show progress every week, we basically didn't
really feel that moment where we don't know
what to do with this because it's too early.
This design improvement phase, what I'm
visualizing is you're this pirate that is
invited to a nice dinner and you have to start
cleaning up. You have to start looking good and
become inter-society. It makes a lot of sense.
Also, what you're describing makes me think
again of this concept of, it's your job to keep
the flame alive and help it spread within the
organization. So you have this idea and
you're just like, keep momentum going,
keep the flame growing by sharing
constant updates, sharing progress,
make it very easy to consume with little snippets
and videos. So there's a lot of great advice here.
So timeline-wise, interestingly what
I'm hearing is it basically took a
year from idea to alpha, something
like that. Is that roughly right?
Just like seven months ... No, five
months to first alpha1 customer.
Okay.
We stayed in alpha for six months.
Okay, got it. So through alpha about a year
total. Many people are hearing this. On the one
hand it would be like, "Of course, Atlassian
has all these resources. They're going to
spend a year on this idea that who knows is
going to work out. It's so easy for them."
I imagine there was much pain and suffering and
challenge along the way that happened that makes
it not so easy. Is there something you could share
by just the struggle to actually make this real
just as a way to wrap up conversation, go back
to therapy if there's anything you want to share?
Yeah. Basically, it's pretty much what we talked
about earlier with lots of processes that were not
changed yet because we're at the very beginning
of point A, and people still wanting us to chime
in on the things that were important for
their part of the organization where we
would play a part later if we become successful.
So none of that stuff was just solved once and
for all. It was just a constant process to play
with that, but I think we managed to get out of
these things pretty gracefully in the end and
I think we gained some level of admiration for
some teams from that and some found it a bit
... It's always interesting to see someone
breaking the rules and getting away with it. I
think it inspired some of the other founders to
try and do that, which was pretty cool to see.
It's actually something I'd love to see more,
hearing back from the customers I've been
talking to about this in their company,
rather than feel suffocated by the current
processes and they don't feel like they can
break the chains. So I'm hoping it inspires
a few more teams to give it a go, really.
There's clearly more I want to learn about point
A and how other companies do this incubation
stuff. So this is a really good inspiration
to dig deeper into those sorts of programs.
We've covered a lot of ground. We've
talked about things that have worked
and haven't worked, all kinds of therapy and pain,
but also things that help you succeed and build
amazing products. Is there anything else you
want to share or leave listeners with before
we get to a very exciting lightning round?
Yeah. I would try to balance the point I just
gave, which is it's hard so someone has to
try. Always feel like you can push. I'd like to
balance that a bit with be careful for yourself
as well and make sure that you're doing this
in an environment that's ready to welcome it.
So as I mentioned, I worked at Atlassian now
for the past 10 years. Before that I used to
work in banks, in heavily regulated industries,
in a whole bunch of different areas where that
kind of stuff was not okay. I could have tried
to push, it would have not gone well at all.
So I think I'm deeply convinced by the fact
that we don't need so much top-down leadership.
What we need is a lot of autonomous leaders,
regardless of their position within the org,
able to push for change, fighting for the right
things, but you need to do that in an environment
that's safe for you to do so. If it's not,
I think it's okay to consider alternatives.
So in other words, don't feel like you're
trapped. Right? You only have one work life. Do
it in places where you really believe you can do
amazing work and surrounded by people that you're
excited to work with. Otherwise, I've been there
before where it's possible to become cynical by
the weight of the things that are not
possible and ending up doubting your own
ability to do stuff really. So it's a bit
of a balance of push for the right things,
but also watch after yourself and if the
environment is not right, it's okay to change.
This is a really hot topic and common question in
product management and I imagine other functions
in product of just how much can actually change
as an IC at a company. I hear all this advice
about making change, changing culture, incubating
stuff, innovating. How much can you actually make
an impact versus, "Nothing's going to change.
I should go work somewhere else"? Do you have
any advice there? It sounds like basically
you're saying there's oftentimes you have
no impact on how the business and culture's
going to work and you probably should go find
a company like Atlassian that does learn how
to incubate and innovate and think differently.
Yeah. This one is a ... I'm not sure how to
answer that really because I've worked with,
consulted, worked for close to
50 companies. Atlassian is the
first company I joined where I was at home
from day one, challenged in the right way,
but fuck, I can really choose my battles and
go after them. Things are hard, but it's okay.
So I joined Atlassian. [inaudible 01:41:13] found
the trampoline like that, but yeah, I would just
go, not settle for status quo because you cannot
be the only sane person in a room. At some point
you will go insane. The environment will permeate
on you. You are not this entity that is absolutely
permeable to everything that happens around you.
Everything around you will affect you and will
change you as a person. I really believe that.
So you need to surround yourself with people
and environments that can help bring out the
best in you, otherwise you can turn bad. I
myself have been cynical in the past working
in environments that were cynical and I then
decided it's not me. I do not want it to be me.
It was me back then. I do not want it to be me.
So yeah, that's my only advice, which is
have the courage to ask yourselves those
questions because otherwise it might
change you in ways you don't want to.
Amazing advice. Really important advice. With that
we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
I am, looking forward to it.
All right, here we go. First question,
what are two or three books that you've
recommended most to other people?
Yeah, the first one was a book that was
recommended to me by Scott Farquhar, founder
of Atlassian co-founder. Who: A Method for Hiring
is basically a book about how to do the thing that
I for a while was really bad at, which is try to
interview to understand who's going to be a good
person, not a good person to join your team.
Second one, so that's one book about work.
Two other books that are not about work.
Highly recommend reading Hakim's Odyssey.
It's the story of a Syrian refugee moving
out of Syria, trying to move into Europe.
We hear a lot of these stats and numbers about
people trying to cross the Med Sea or basically
become refugees in other countries and it's
very easy to look at it complacently up until
you meet a personal story. This personal story
of Hakim that was told very beautifully by this
illustrator is well worth a read on that front.
The last one is a book that I'm not sure has
been translated from French. It's called Vivre
avec la Terre, To Live with the Earth and it's
about how we could build a different agricultural
system to the one that we have today that might
have better ways to feed us into the future
that doesn't require large monoculture of
vegetables that may not be as sustainable.
They managed to create a really efficient
structure on very small parcels of land with a
lot of species working together to control and
not need the use of any pesticides and stuff like
that. They've been always surrounded by teams of
researchers from the, I think it's called the
Inria. It's one of the French research centers,
have got really amazing results, but
I don't think many know that this
stuff exists and that it could actually be
used out there and I think that's a shame.
I think it's the first book that
sounds recommended that's only in
a different language, but may not be translated.
It might be translated. I hope it is. It's pretty
thick though and it's very technical. So I've read
the principles bit and I would get lost in all the
technical aspects of growing food, to be honest.
Okay, love it. So let's ask
you your favorite interview
question. What's your favorite interview question?
Yeah. So I struggled a lot with interviewing and
I've read all the standard interview questions
there is out there and I've heard them in your
podcast as well. There is one that came from this
book that Scott Farquhar also told me was working
really well for him is when people describe an
experience, you ask them the name of the person
that they worked with back then. And you ask them,
"So when I call this person after our call, what
do you think they're going to say about that?"
Apparently this does something and I've seen
it happen where people are unable to project
and invent on the spot something from the lens of
another person talking about them. So they might
be able to talk about, "I did this, I did that, I
did that. So when I talk ... "Who was your boss?
My boss was ... So when I ask this person, what
do you think they're going to say?" It's like,
"Ah, well actually, I was only leading a part of
it and maybe you shouldn't call them because XYZ."
That part makes people all of a sudden go out of
this scripted version they give of themselves and
become more real for a second. You get a bit of
the authenticity coming out, which often is very
hard to get to for me in interview questions.
I've seen it happen. I find that very funny to
do now because people get really uneasy for
a second and then you get to something real.
That is genius. Makes so much sense.
Makes me wonder how I can integrate this
tip into my podcast interviews.
Really good tip. Next question,
do you have a favorite product you've
recently discovered that you really love?
Yeah, it's got nothing with tech, nothing
to do with tech. I'm kite surfing a lot at
the moment and I came across hydrofoils, which is
basically these things where there's an airplane
underneath you on a mast which
is connected to a board. You're
on the board with your kite and you
basically just fly over the water.
That invention is just brilliant. It's relatively
easy to learn and I can spend basically,
parts of my weekend flying over water in as much
as a breeze of wind because there's absolutely
zero friction between the board and the
water. So that's, technically speaking I
think is genius the way they created that
and inspiring themselves from airplanes.
Is that the thing that Zuck was riding
with his sunscreen with the flag or is
that something else? I don't know if you
saw that photo. Don't worry about it.
No, I didn't see that.
I like that you say it's relatively easy
to learn even though there's a kite on you
pulling you in the water on this thing that's
above the water. I don't know if I believe you.
Yeah. I mean, there's sports and crafts
that are difficult to learn. This one
you can get comfortable in 18 months to two years,
which is really, really short. It could be
a sport that you would have done before.
Just a couple of years. Okay. I like your bar for
... I'm going to ask a question along these lines,
but before we get there, do you have
a favorite life motto that you often
come back to, find useful in work or in
life, maybe share with friends and family?
I've got two, one for work and one for everything
in life. The one for work is initially a quote
from Obama. I can't remember the exact quote. I'm
going to paraphrase, but let's keep it about the
work. So there's going to be moments in your
career where you don't feel valued and you
wonder, "Am I doing the right thing? Am I being
recognized? Am I valued? Am I at the right place?"
Whenever that happens, a lot of parasitic thoughts
may come in. You may face imposter syndrome and
stuff like that. Happens to me super regularly.
Whenever that happens, what I do is I remind
myself, "Keep it about the work," because as long
as you make it about the work there's always work
to be done and there's always a path that emerges
from that work. It's a bit of the same of this,
you've got this thing in yoga where once
you're committed good things will happen. Well,
that's exactly what I've seen and that's helped
me every time. I reread this quote whenever
I'm in these moments of turmoil around me.
Now when I face those moments I also remind myself
of the other one, which I invented, but I don't
think I'm the only one who has invented that one,
which is, "Remember that in 100 years we'll all
be dead and forgotten. So don't take yourself
too seriously. You're not that important. You're
probably not that important, as important as you
think for the people that you are arguing with."
That's also the beauty in all things, which is
it has an end. In the end it probably doesn't
matter so might as well give it your best shot.
That's what the existentialists back in France
many generations ago were talking about. This
point is close to Albert Camus' thesis, right? "If
it doesn't make sense might as well go for it."
Really good points, really good lessons,
really good mottos. Final question,
you were ranked number four worldwide
in a form of free diving. First of all,
can you briefly describe what
is free diving and then can
you share one thing that might surprise
someone about the sport and the skill?
Yeah. So yes, that's my claim to fame.
I was ranked number four in basically,
the distance you can swim in a swimming pool
without fins with 167 meters, which is 550 feet.
And underwater?
Underwater breaststroke. I went further with
the monofin, the thing you see back there,
but breaststroke was one meter away from
the French record and ranking number four
worldwide that year. The one I'm most proud of
is I actually went to 300 feet underwater deep,
came back in one piece and I
really enjoyed the whole thing.
300 feet. That's like-
92 meters.
Oh, geez. I'm trying to imagine
what that is like compared to a
Statue of Liberty or something like
that, but I'll look that up later.
I look at buildings one. Buildings can be as
little as 20, 30 meters and can go super higher,
but 90 meters is pretty high, yeah. Last
time I looked at a building like that,
I can't remember which one it was, but it's pretty
high. So it's take one breath, go down, touch the
bottom plate on the rope and then come back up.
One thing that may surprise people with this is
that everyone is much more gifted at it than
they think. So I used to give courses on the
weekend for free diving and most people when I
ask them, "Hey, how long do you think you can
be underwater?" And they tell me something
like 30 seconds, maybe a minute. "How deep
you think can you go? Ah, maybe five meters."
At the end of the weekend most people were able
to hold their breath for two to three
minutes and to go to 20 meters deep.
So it's one of those things where it looks
absolutely impressive and crazy and amazing
and in fact we're naturally gifted to it. There's
a lot of physiological changes that happen when
we dive that make it possible, but I think it's
fascinating how little we know about our bodies.
I'm looking up what is 300 feet compared to
real-life objects on perplexity. So what is
300 feet compared to real-life objects? Here
we go, 300 feet. The length of a football
field. Okay, yeah. I should have realized
that. Close to the length of a Boeing 737.
Yeah. You need to look at it
this way to get some perspective.
Yeah, and a football field-
You go underwater in that-
... Jesus Christ. Oh, my God. But
I love your advice that people can
do much better at the skill than they think.
Yeah. Everyone from kids to adults
are really amazing at it actually.
Tanguy, we've covered so much ground.
I think this is going to help a lot of
people that are trying to get better
at free diving, but also at building
zero to one within large companies. I
am so thankful that you made time for
this and that you shared some into this
real talk and as you called it, therapy.
Two final questions. Where can folks find
you online if they want to reach out,
maybe follow up on some of the stuff you talked
about and how can listeners be useful to you?
Yeah, so you can find me on LinkedIn if
you know how to ... You don't need to know
how to pronounce my name. You just need to
know how to write it. I'm not super active
on social media to be honest. I'm very much
in the trenches building this product so I
don't do much in terms of networking to be fair,
but if you are using this product for example,
and you have ideas for how we can improve it for
you or you'd like to share some stories about how
that's helped you or how it's not helping you,
I'd love to connect because I spend a large
part of my days talking to users, responding to
support tickets and stuff like that. So, yeah.
Amazing. Tanguy, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you, Lenny. Honestly, it's been amazing and
I hope some of my gibberish is useful to people.
Definitely not gibberish. I think it's
going to help a lot of people. With that,
I'll let you go. Bye, everyone.
Bye-bye.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to the show on
Apple Podcasts, Spotify or your favorite podcast
app. Also, please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.