hey everyone all right here's the plan in 30 seconds I want to share a little bit of kind of the laboratory of products that I've been exposed to then I want to share an
updated curated selection of the insights that I hold dear uh as I navigate product decisions and help some
of you as well um with the hopes that maybe two or three of them stick in your mind and become things that you can talk about with your teams and consider in
your daily practice and then finally I think there is a thread throughout all of these that I want to touch upon at the end uh about the very human aspect
of our discipline uh in a world where we're often times talking about the non-human aspects that I think is really important to touch upon and so really quickly you know my passion has always been to organize the creative world at
work whenever I told people I wanted to do that they were like yeah good luck with that but uh that was that's been the passion it started actually as a physical product of all things um it
evolved into books and conferences and a company ultimately called behance behance is a platform of 56 million creatives around the world showcasing their work and you can sort through the
work by you know by the person who did what for what agency with what tool um in what discipline in what color it's the organ it's organized in the creative
world at work we joined Adobe in 2012 and then I was faced with all these new challenges and things that I always considered broken as a customer of adobe and the idea was let's go and you know
try to fix some of these things I thought I'd be there for a few years ended up being there for three years leaving coming back for another seven years overseeing Creative Cloud bringing
our products to the to the web to mobile products like Lightroom mobile products like Adobe Express um and then have now you know been able to work with a lot of startups over the years as a very early
product adviser and Seed investor as they sort of navigate some of their product challenges um and and and write about it a little bit as well 30 seconds or less so now I want to talk about some of
these essential insights and the way I've been thinking about um these types of insights in our in our nomenclature is what do it what does it mean for all
of us to sort of see the Matrix as a product leader um what are those moments where something just kind of clicks and those become Cardinal uh insights or
perspectives or um just lenses that we that we take that make all the difference in our practice and uh and this is something I've been thinking about for a few years but I've lately uh and over the last month thanks to the
forcing function of this conference tried to put together uh some of the ones that I think are most important to think about and so we'll ask this question to kick off you know what is the equivalent of seeing the Matrix as a
product leader and I'll start with the most obvious and then we're going to get a bit more nuance and uh and dynamic here going along but data is a compass not a map right the idea that we
ultimately need to determine what mountain to climb right with the intuition we have with our understanding and with our empathy um and yet data is ultimately what helps us climb the
mountain we choose and but this is something I actually often come back to in in a discipline that's so driven by data these days is to remember that data is to help me get from the bottom to the
top of the mountain but not necessarily to choose the right mountain to climb and so I just wanted to put that up there very first because that's something that I that I think is very important all right another thing is to
see seeing the Matrix is that recognizing that with new products you need to prioritize and optimize for the problems that you want to have now what do I mean by this when you're building especially a new product or launching a
new feature What are problems you want to have you want customers to be using these products or features to this to the extent where they start to come to you and ask for things that power users
would would want that's success what you don't want is for them to get stuck in the onboarding what you don't want is for them to realize that because of security issues they can't even use the
product and and so I've started to think about everything on a product road map in the standpoint of things that you you know this is a time scale here you need
to optimize for shallow value before you optimize for the Deep value and it's a sort of contrarian view because you would argue that we should build products with this great deep High
willingness to pay value from the start when in essence if most if any of our products you know get any more than 30% of the people at the top of the funnel
through they're worldclass products so why not optimize for all the things that help people discover the shallow value quickly AKA feeling successful quickly
which is in some ways the definition of product L growth before um they discover that that deeper value and in some ways then when you're looking at a road map and a list of things to debate
prioritization around thinking about well what do we want people to be requesting let's not do those things let's instead do the things that could conceivably become
obstacles and recognizing that whatever the MVP is I think one mistake we often make is we forget how much gravity an MVP has whatever you put out your instinct as a team will always be
iterate from there and so to also make sure that while it can be the MIM and viable version of most things the thing that distinguishes your product the most needs to be done extraordinarily well
before you put it out because it's hard to iterate your way out of not getting that right another thing is about realizing that we should only do half of what we want to do I mean this was probably the greatest mistake we made in
behance which is now a far simpler product than it was actually when it launched like well over a decade ago when we had groups we had something called tip exchange we had something called circles we had something called
work in progress and we we realized every time we killed one of those things the engagement on the core feature that actually mattered most which is just people publishing projects to their
portfolio went up and so we started going on these killing spre and I think that was one of those moments when I realized that it's I think our practice in product is much like the the Bonsai
cultivating Master where you're constantly pruning those beautiful branches those things that are just taking flight you're actually cutting to enrich this kind of core and so that
that notion that voice in your head of half half half is somewhat seeing the Matrix as a product leader knowing that is that is what compounds are likelihood of product Market
fit defining the product life cycle is something I want to spend a few minutes on because we have to obsess over this and and what do I mean by the product life cycle it's as simple as this users
flock to simple products we love simple products both as Enterprise customers and as individuals those users you know all sort of inate a product and what does the product do it takes those users for
granted by saying oh my goodness now we need to start to monetize let's add power user let's let's listen to Power users and see what they want let's add features um and uh and before you know
it the product becomes more complex you're focusing on adding now that deep value and what happens users flock to simple product again and again and I feel like this is almost what fuels the sil conv valy life cycle of so many
industries of product is simply this you know strange flywheel or I don't know or cycle in another word you know that we go through and so how do we keep products simple is probably one of the
most important product questions that we always have to be asking ourselves and I think a big part of this is always ensuring that the product is working for the newest cohort of new customers
recognizing that every new cohort is different you know early cohorts are more willing and forgiving and then later cohorts are not willing at forgiving they are they sometimes against their own wishes and they better
get a very simple experience and a different experience in the onboarding so I think that the realization here is the recognition that every customer of any type of product I would argue even
in the Enterprise in their early stage of using the the product is lazy Vain and selfish they're lazy in the sense that they don't have time to learn something right and they don't have
tolerance for on boardings that are bad instructional videos more than one line of copy and so part of the solution here is to show rather than explain how to do something and you know we we've explored
with some of those ideas for example in Photoshop with sliders to just and and Tool tips that just basically show people you know in the product how to do something the only thing I think better than that is to actually do it for the
customer and this is where templates and chat uis and presumptuous defaults you know come into play um and and know and we've tried to actually build new features on top of features in Photoshop
for example to just do things for you as opposed to having to teach you how to do them anymore um moving on here oh there we go so my favorite saying I think in this
whole Space is uh by my friend Dave Marin that the devil is in the defaults and really I I I can't emphasize this enough often times we think about the default state of our product in the
final mile of shipping it when in fact it might be the only state of the product that most of our customers ever experience using it and so to really argue and think about what that default
experience should be is an absolutely crucial thing to do vain need to make us look good and quickly especially in the early stage of using it a big thing about in this is what I call ego
analytics how does the product make me feel good about myself in my job in my life you we've always seen the hearts and likes and appreciate buttons and everything else on social but it's
interesting when you talk to people who work at companies like Instagram what they will admit is that the engagement in a product like that actually goes up
after the user posts something which suggests that maybe people are actually going back to the product more often to see who saw their content than to see
other people's content which is the more intuitive reason why people would go to a social media site and so that's an example I think of ego analytics of
merchandising to the customer what's happening you know and certainly in the creative world we've seen that when customers can see who likes and who appreciates and you know who views their
content we made the decision to let every everyone appreciate work even if you weren't logged in because of course you know it's giving that gratification to the customer that their work is getting appreciated why would you want
to lock people out of expressing that and and receiving that that feedback mechanism progress be gets progress uh there are a number of studies there's a study by this woman named terresa Mo at
Harvard Business School about motivation in organizations but I think it applies to customer basis as well where people make more progress when they feel like they're making progress as lead leaders
we need to merchandise to our team the progress they're making to get their continued commitment and similarly to customers helping customers understand the progress they're making through our products actually makes them make more
progress and it's important to keep in mind and then the last piece is just around this selfishness people need to feel like they're quickly benefiting from spending a little time on this
because most customers at first carelessly engage with the product you know Pinterest before it was a discovery engine it was simply a very immediate
ility to your bookmarks and the idea of people suddenly using it for other things Beyond was more of a hope uh than than an actual reality in the beginning
getting paid faster right was the value proposition of stripe when other I'm sorry when with square uh when other value props didn't work about the terminals but they realized that small
businesses just wanted to get paid faster it was like a very selfish need and they didn't really care about the point of s system and everything else like that but that was the value prop that that worked similarly with stripe the two lines of code You could argue is
capitalizing on the laziness uh of a developer who was saying hey you know I want Commerce but I want to have to work with Merchant providers and all of this spaghetti of uh of work and so this
notion of two lines of code was actually something that really pierced through uh that that that industry which goes to suggest a question that I always grapple with personally around copy believing
that effectively copies part of the product experience and needs to be born from within a product team it's part of the overall end to end and most companies are not structured that way or
will even Outsource copy to some degree and that's never really intuitively made sense to me because we're very we're very skeptical of long-term promises that that products make and we need to
make sure that we're merchandised the value we're getting now that has to be nailed and I think that goes also into the the defaults and the types of capabilities that we surface in our
products in the first mile experience okay so moving on to another you know what does it mean to see The Matrix as a product leader recognizing that you need to get customers to talk
about their problems and not your product and I don't know about you but I've held actually only a few focus groups uh for behance very in the beginning and everyone told us they didn't need another social network they
had Deviant Art they had um Facebook you know they had um they had LinkedIn and they were like last thing I need is another place to put my work and then we said well what are you what are you
suffering from and that's where we understood that people didn't get attribution for their work their portfolios were always out of date and they weren't reaching new potential people that would hire them and so
always making sure that you focus on the problems which goes to say that I think that empathy empathy for the problems our customers are are are are suffering
with outperforms passion for the solutions and if I were to characterize some of the entrepreneur that I've backed over my years as a seed investor that I was most inspired by that were
not successful it was because they were so governed by their passion for the end state of what the world needed to be and they never really had that empathy that was the difference between that 30
degrees of being product Market fit off because they didn't really understand what that customer was going through on a daily basis even though they were saying this is what they wanted they really needed to get the credit from
their boss or whatever the case might be that actually drove the ization of the product another Insight is that the most powerful and affordable driver of
product growth may not actually be what customers want a great example of this was the early days of slack I mean our team was using this product called
hipchat from atlassian at the time that slack rolled out and then our team started to use it only because of the animated gif capabilities and uh sending a random one to your colleagues and not
knowing what it was going to be and then it became a place where people would say hey I'm going to Coffee does anyone want to come with me and then before you know it it became a utility that people were
using every day novelty does precede utility and we have to sometimes remember that when we are planning and prioritizing road maps for our products
it's very easy to be reasoning oriented of what we know the customers saying they want as opposed to the things that they'll get excited about at least initially um which brings to a moment
you know just a point on product Le growth people don't Rave about products doing what they expected they only really Rave about products doing what they didn't
expect in Tesla you know no one was in the early days saying I just love how this car functions as a car as much as they were saying oh this cool Rainbow Road Easter egg where you like do this
on the dashboard and touch this button and this happens you know these were these moments of delight that the customer did not effect that drove the exchange the the the discussion the
people that were raving and so it's important now I often times wonder you know how do you actually get a team to prioritize in a roadmap session about D building a high performance car
something like rainbow road but but I think what you have to recognize is that your job is to get your customers to discover and adopt your product and if novelty does precede utility if people
do Rave about things they didn't expect how to be prior prze those things another Insight that I've had that I really hold strongly as a product
leader is whenever I review any part of a product any screen I'm ultimately asking myself three questions in every
moment when I see something new I'm asking how did I get here what do I do now and where do I go next to me this is
like the ultimate object model test it's knowing whether or not the customer who's usually carelessly using a product because they're busy and they're distracted and whatever else if they do
they know the comfort of how they got to where they are or is your product doing the equivalent of dropping them off in the desert somewhere without a map and so constantly asking this question of
orientation boils down to whether the actions are clear or the actions are confusing are you pushing enough emphasis in the direction that they're most likely to go are the defaults
correct you know I find that these sorts of questions became a bit of a Holy Grail uh for me and a number of folks that I work with uh which is why I wanted to share them with
you another Insight that A+ designers you know are ultimately this cheat code and I have to admit and if I look back to my career as a product leader the things that I am most proud of were the
result of a partnership with designers that made all the difference part of the reason is this power of this prototype right being worth 100 meetings people going around a table deba debating And
discussing whether two products could connect or whether some new feature makes sense or whether some m&a opportunity could actually connect to the user's experience and then a designer suddenly shares a prototype of
what it looks like and it's like magic you know it is that hot knife through the butter in the sense that everyone either agrees or disagrees but suddenly it prompts decisiveness what an example of the
power of design represented at the table another Insight that I've learned was kind of humbling you know for those of us who also have engineering responsibility is that perceived
performance can matter just as much as actual performance I remember the early days uh when Pinterest started to scale in like 2011 2012 and the team was like racing to keep this product up and
running there was this big road map you know uh of of how to get scalability and performance and improve performance of the of the site loading and then the designers came up with this idea to
basically load the color of the PIN before the actual pins and suddenly overnight customers were like oh my gosh Pinter is so much faster and it wasn't there was no change under the hood other
than a design change another example of having designers at the table to solve what was actually an engineering problem but was really a user experience
problem and then in the age of AI more and more of our choices in every industry are being made at the surface right and I think that's another opport another argument that design will
increasingly commoditize Tech to some degree and that having this designer empowered and have a seat at the table will be more and more important you have to prioritize grafting Talent as much as hiring Talent
this is something that I've learned the hard way many times right when you hire some amazing person but you fail to suppress the immune system of your team that has always done it a certain way to
allow this new organ transplant to come on and take hold in order to change the way your organ ation works and so you have to suppress the immune system to
allow this new often times senior person or someone with great um you know great a great history of executing but does things slightly differently than you and
it's amazing to me how we have a huge industry to higher talent but grafting Talent is sort of like oh yeah like make sure they get a computer and a login and they'll figure it out like so I think
that us making sure we graft Talent onto our teams very thoughtfully is important a few other thoughts real quickly on the talent front because I know that's a theme um of a lot of uh this conference you know is hiring for initiative over
experience I think a lot of people have learned this the hard way or in some ways the easy way when they hire someone um because they can they can't afford the experienced people they hire the people with initiative and those people
just come on and just do amazing amazing things beyond your expense expectations it's because they had a history of taking initiative of what matters to them celebrating impact over tenure when
I came into Adobe they had these tenure awards that I was supposed to do every quarter at my all hands and I was like wait I'm celebrating someone for how long they've survived here as opposed to
someone who's come in and made an impact on day on day two like that doesn't make any sense to me and so I replace them with the impact Awards and I think that's such an important thing to especially bring in new talent and make
them feel like their contributions are valued despite how long they've been there and then finally that you have to collapse the talent stack every chance you get when you do have that opportunity to hire that product leader
with a design background or that Designer who was a friend and engineer you know or the growth hacker who was also a designer that conduit that you then collapse is an incredibly effective
way to unlock something new in your organization and so I can't emphasize that enough whenever I've had the opportunity to collapse the talent stack it's always surpassed my
expectations you only can in expect what you inspect this is important right each of us has to find the few level ones the few things that you want to hold
yourself directly accountable for and if you hire other product leaders and you delegate effectively to other people that's great so long as you hold yourself accountable to the things that
are most important to you by inspecting them rigorously and this is actually something I've learned from our CEO who had to delegate almost everything but he always has a list of a few things that
he goes so deep on inspection and I you know I feel like that's a that's a best practice for all of us that you level up when you learn to
know when to amp up this volume of your own intuition and this goes to that earlier Point around the data you're going to be thrown data constantly you're going to be told best practices
from other people coming in maybe people like me and others and yet at the same time knowing when to tune into that feeling over the thinking that you have
from the more academic side knowing that conviction should outweigh consensus when you have faith and trust in somebody who feels suddenly super strongly you know that's when you can
make a non-popular decision that differentiates you in the market so learning to gain that con value that conviction over consensus at times to lead with curiosity over criticism when
I am frustrated or disappointed what I challenge myself to do in product meetings is just to ask an a barrage of questions to tune into my curiosity on what's off what's wrong and just go
poking with questions and questions and questions to the point where the team can suddenly you know realize something's wrong or I realize that I was wrong and then I think you know La last
couple points here but great product management these days in a world where so much of product management is being offloaded to compute and we're start to get these new this new generation of
agents that complement us as managers which is both exciting and scary but I think that more of our jobs will become less about how to do something and more
about what to do and if you think about this dilemma of the you know what to do versus the how to do it's kind of the it's kind of this new era where it's
more about taste than about skill as skill becomes offloaded to compute and and AI agents are assisting you it's really your intuition and your taste
that is ultimately going to make some of the most important decisions in your organization and in your product and those the what to do is a human discipline you know models are trained
on the distribution of data in the middle but great great decisions and new Creative Solutions to problems always fall outside the distribution of what's been done before otherwise they would
have been done already and so remembering that our job is now to start to think about outside the distribution of what's been done before is I think such a new critical practice of this
thing that we all call product and finally that the best new products in the world they really take us back to the way things once were that we long for but with scale and efficiency and if
you just think about a few examples of that you know we want our we want to be known in our in our towns we just like you know 300,000 years before the Industrial Revolution we were known
until we became Anonymous and so maybe things like marketing Tech at its best can help us be known again hopefully we know how we're known or why we're known we want scarcity LinkedIn is about
networking instead of job boards it's about the old way of doing things where it was through recommendation and referral as opposed to these you know Anonymous job boards AI driven interfaces in some way take us back to
natur language which is the old way we used to do things before before these graphic interfaces and so I think it's just a great litmus test um and then finally finally product right this is
the thread product is mostly ultimately this people discipline these product decisions that all of us make they need to be boiled down to this deep understanding and empathy for natural
human tendencies that lazy vein and selfish that first smile that to build these products of the future we must understand the parts of the past that that we long for but with scale and
efficiency and finally that a product you know this is the craziest thing and I think we all know this in a room when you use a product you can kind of tell by using the product who did and didn't
talk to each other right did they get along did they not get along was the copywriter in the room or not in the room did the marketing department have to get the product leaders sign off before they ship this
thing the Apple doesn't fall far from the tree so thank you so much for your time and and looking forward to seeing you at the rest of the conference thank you