Get clear on your objective function, and one
way that I've gotten clear on it is trying to
think about it from future me because five years
from now, I'm not going to give a if I made the
presentation slightly better, but I'm going to
care a lot about what kind of relationship I have
with my daughters, and that means that the next
action, the next thing I do today and tomorrow,
those will translate into the relationship with
her, right? Not to be morbid, but just again,
most of us just aren't really tuned into an
awareness that our lives will come to an end.
We try to pretend like we're going to live
forever and just not think about it. And the
horror of it is that we succeed, right? We mostly
manage to just go live our life and eat ice cream
and go to work and go on vacation and do what we
do. To me, an awareness and mindfulness that our
lives will come to an end punctuates reality in
a way that requires me to rethink my priorities.
Today my guest is J.M. Nickels. J.M. has been
a product leader at Waymo, DoorDash and Uber.
He's also an engineering manager at Groupon, and
before that an equity trader at Getco. At Uber,
he built and launched the very first version
of Uber Pool and then went on to lead the
team responsible for the infrastructure and
algorithms powering the economic and logistics
brain behind Uber's matching and pricing systems.
At DoorDash, he was head of product for DoorDash
platform. At Waymo, he led product for the
commercialization of autonomous ride hailing
and last mile delivery. And he recently returned
to Uber to lead product for the mobility team.
This conversation is a unique and beautiful
mixture of hard skills, soft skills, tactics,
and emotions. I won't give away too much about the
conversation, but this is a powerful one. Tears
are shed, stories are shared, and I'm confident
you'll become a better leader and human having
listened to J.M.'s insights and lessons. If you
enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting
app or YouTube. It's the best way to avoid
missing future episodes and it helps the podcast
tremendously. With that, I bring you J.M. Nickels.
J.M., thank you so much for being
here. Welcome to the podcast.
Thank you, Lenny. Thanks for having me. I'm
thrilled to be here. Really appreciate your
dedication to helping product managers improve
their craft and up-level. We've done a lot of
great researches out there for that, and coaching
and development, as I'm sure we'll get into,
is a passion of mine as well, so we
have a lot of shared interests there.
Oh, I really appreciate that. I want
to start with a phrase that came up
again and again when I ask people what to
talk to you about from your colleagues,
and this phrase is conscious leadership. What is
conscious leadership? What does this phrase mean?
To me, leadership is broadly defined as having
influence in the world, and so by that definition,
to me, everyone is a leader because we all
have influence in some way. It's not about
whether you're a manager or not, it's like I
have influence on my kids or my partner or my
community, or the world, the way I vote, the way
I show up. So we all have influence. We're all
co-creating influences of each other. So that's
the leadership piece. The conscious piece then is
becoming more aware, waking up. To me, it's
like learning more about my interior world,
what my background is, my biases. We all inherit
certain belief systems from our parents or our
church or our community, and a lot of times
they kind of go unquestioned and then they
end up in conflict. And so it's really just about
becoming more aware and then taking responsibility
for the influence that I have. So yeah, taking
responsibility for my influence in the world.
As you talk about this, something that came
up and something that I thought about as I
was preparing for this episode is this idea
of soft leadership, the power of soft skills
and just how important that is in success.
Is there something there that comes up when
I say that? Just the power of soft skills and
the importance of those in being successful.
Yeah, it's, what was it? Theodore Roosevelt,
speak softly and carry a big stick? Yeah,
I think I've evolved in that department.
I think when I was younger in my career,
I thought it was really important that we got
to show up to the meeting and have the right
slides and be the loudest, rightest voice in the
room, and that's the way to have influence. And
there's certainly a place for having leadership
in a meeting and presenting a point of view and
helping guide the narrative, but to me, yeah,
I would say I've evolved more towards sitting
back. It's also as I've become a more senior
leader, I'm aware that there are power dynamics
there. There's imbalances where junior folks
don't feel as comfortable speaking up or I
say something's not a good idea and then,
"Well, I don't want to disagree with J.M."
So it's like, back to being more aware of my
influence in the world. I really try to spend
more time being mindful of that and say, I want
to hear from other people first. I want to create
space and I don't need to win the argument in
the meeting. There can be a follow-up. It's
not like this is my last chance to say something,
but that's also more true when you're more senior
because when you're more junior, it's like, well,
this is the one presentation I have with Dara for
the next six months. I really got to nail it. And
so the pressure is a little bit different. Yeah.
This episode is brought to you by Pendo, the
only all-in-one product experience platform
for any type of application. Tired of bouncing
around multiple tools to uncover what's really
happening inside your product? With all the
tools you need in one simple to use platform,
Pendo makes it easy to answer critical
questions about how users are engaging
with your product and then turn those
insights into action. Also, you can get your
users to do what you actually want them to do.
First, Pendo is built around product analytics,
seeing what your users are actually doing in your
apps so that you can optimize their experience.
Next, Pendo lets you deploy in-app guides that
lead users through the actions that matter most.
Then Pendo integrates user feedback so that you
can capture and analyze what people actually want.
And the new thing in Pendo, session replace, a
very cool way to visualize user sessions. I'm
not surprised at all that over 10,000 companies
use it today. Visit pendo.io/lenny to create your
free Pendo account today and start building better
experiences across every corner of your product.
P.S. You want to take your product-led know-how
a step further? Check out Pendo's lineup of free
certification courses led by talk product experts
and designed to help you grow in advance in your
career. Learn more and experience the power
of the Pendo platform today at pendo.io/lenny.
Pendo.
This episode is brought to you by the
Enterprise Ready Conference, a one-day event
in San Francisco, bringing together product
and engineering leaders shaping the future
of enterprise SaaS. The event features a curated
list of speakers with direct experience building
for the enterprise, including leaders from OpenAI,
Vanta, Checkr, Dropbox, and Canva. Topics included
advanced identity management, compliance,
encryption, and logging. Essentially, complex
features that most enterprise customers require.
If you're a founder, exec, product manager or
engineer tasked with the enterprise roadmap,
this conference is for you. You'll get detailed
insights from industry leaders that have years of
experience navigating the same challenges that you
face today. And best of all, it's completely free
since it's hosted by WorkOS. Spots are filling
up quickly. Make sure to request an invite at
enterpriseready.com. That's enterpriseready.com.
There's a couple of threads I want to follow
here, but first, I was thinking as you're talking,
when people think Uber and people that work
at Uber, I don't think they imagine people
like you. And I know you were there early and
then you joined again. Was that ever like a,
"Is this a place for me?" Did you ever go through
that struggle or is it just, yeah, I don't know?
Yeah, yeah, I mean, I would say I have been
fortunate to experience probably three Ubers
at this point. We joke about Uber 1.0, the
Travis era, and you hear a lot about in the
media the kind of bad parts of that, but there
were some really good parts too. I mean, I think
there was a lot of... Like when I joined in 2014,
there was this mission of making transportation
as reliable as running water for anyone anywhere,
which is bold, audacious, and maybe a little bit
pretentious from a little bit of Silicon Valley
edge, but you could feel the electricity in the
air. There was this energy and excitement
like we're doing something transformational,
autonomy is coming, car ownership will change.
And it just like, feel, like my vibration.
And then, yeah, the good parts of that era were,
Travis was a very great visionary product leader,
and we started ATG and Elevate and these
future-forward things and the way he would
conduct product reviews, I learned a lot. It
was stressful at the time, but looking back,
I was like, wow, I learned a lot. But
yeah, I would say it was not a very
conscious leadership sort of place. You're
right, it was like many organizations that
run on fear because you can do that, carrots
and sticks do work. But actually that's kind
of how I found this work is it was in 2015 and I
was a very junior product manager at that point,
in over my head in a fast-growing place. And
in these weekly reviews with Travis as we were
building out Uber Pool, and I had a six-month-old
daughter, my firstborn, and we had just moved to
San Francisco from Chicago. So my whole life
was in flux and it was a very stressful place,
and I was like, "I think I'm going to
snap. I don't think I can handle this."
And that's kind of what led me to start to explore
this sort of inner work and meditation and sort
of finding a way out of that. And that's what
got me interested in bringing it to teams too,
is because I remember I was in one meeting where
we were working on this future pricing thing,
which is rider pricing, driver pricing,
incentives, and how we bring surge pricing
and all that together. And it gets very, I'll go
heavy, and we have all these PhDs in the room,
some of the best minds in the world. We were
able to hire people like Garrett van Ryzin,
who was the foremost [inaudible 00:10:04]
more person from Columbia and other people.
But everyone's back to lizard brain, everyone's
arguing. They're like, "Well, no, I think we
should do it this way. We should do it this
way." And I was like, huh. As much as I enjoy the
content of this, believe me, I'm an algo PM end
to end, I love that stuff. But I was like, I don't
think this conversation actually needs another
PhD, or I'm not even PhD, but content expert. It's
like what we need here is a way to shift again,
back out of that fear, threat, righteousness sort
of state into a more co-creative, collaborative,
open-minded, curious, trusting sort of space.
And that got me interested in pursuing more
skills in coaching of individuals and teams.
But yeah, to your Uber question, yeah, the
Uber 1.0 was crazy. Uber 2.0 was kind of like,
Travis is out, the board is feuding, is leaking to
Mike Isaac, whatever. And then Dara comes in and
the peacemaker and then tries to stabilize, but
the IPO is rocky. And so now I would say we're in
Uber 3.0, which it's full pirate ship to navy, in
Reid Hoffman's words, a profitable company. We're
printing free cashflow, we're in the S&P 500,
we've established the independent contractor model
in a lot of states and jurisdictions, and it's
like there's less risk of that model changing.
And yeah, I would say we're in an era now
of Cambrian explosion of different types of
transportation. The company really just built the
UberX model and scaled it out to the world. That's
primarily how we got here. And now it's like
we're going out for all these different new sort
of modalities, whether it's reserving a ride in
advance or shared rides or renting a car or buses,
and then different supply types too. It's not
just contracted, we have a lot of fleets in
the platform, we now have a lot of taxi drivers in
the platform. You've seen we've signed deals with
Waymo and Cruise and other autonomist players. So
I feel like we're now at the beginning of another
era of Uber and transportation, that the next
decade or two, it's going to be super exciting.
One quick tangent, UberX, a previous guest
shared that the name UberX came from...
it was just like the internal code name,
UberX, we'll figure out a real name later,
and then it stuck and no one
had a better name. Is that true?
Yeah, that's right. I think that's right.
Amazing.
When I joined, we were already
scaling UberX rapidly. I joined
in early 2014. That's amazing. But I
did help name Uber Pool, Uber Pool,
which I selflessly like to bring back. It got
renamed to Share during my external APM rotation.
Okay. I want to come back to the thread that
I pushed us off of, which is you talked about,
you made this really interesting point about
emotions, and this is something I've been
learning myself recently with having a kid and
also a couple of previous guests. So you say
that when you have... so you're in this meeting,
you're stressed, there's a lizard brain kicking
in. Something's like, "Oh, Dara's going to
think I suck and it's going to really screw
my career if I mess up this presentation."
Your advice there is very counterintuitive,
I think for a lot of people, which is accept that
emotion. Because when I feel stressed and nervous
in a meeting, I'm not, "Embrace the nervousness,
let it out." It's more I'm just like, "No, it's
fine. Going to be okay. Don't worry about it."
Talk about why that is actually more effective.
Yeah, yeah. It's like my daughter the other
day had some nightmares and she was like,
"Dad, how do I stop thinking thoughts about the
nightmare or whatever?" And I said, "You can't.
Don't try to stop the thought. Just allow it.
Let me show you why that doesn't work." I said,
"Don't think of a pink elephant. What did you just
think of?" And she's like, "A pink elephant." And
then now she thinks it's hilarious and she tells
her sister, "Don't think of a pink elephant."
But yeah, I think you're right. It is a little
counterintuitive, but one of my first coaches
actually had a great phrase, what you resist
will persist and what you fear will appear. And
so in my experience, this is another reason why
becoming more aware of my internal world has been
so important. I have more agency than I realized
on the outcome of my experience. And so when I
think a thought like, Dara might think I suck and
then I have a thought that I suck, that can become
a self-enforcing negative feedback loop where I
have a thought that creates stress, anxiety, fear,
and then that triggers more thoughts and we call
it cognitive emotive loop where you're kind of in
this cycle of thinking stressful thoughts and then
having unpleasant, anxious, fearful feelings. And
so one way to break that is to just allow it
and not try to fight it with other thoughts.
So the advice is very tactically,
so you're in a meeting with Dara,
you're stressed about something. Just allow it,
let it be. Don't try to pretend like it's
not there or don't try to convince yourself-
Well, that would be the first step,
is just to allow whatever's here,
thoughts and emotions are rising. They
come, they go, they're transient. It's
not permanent. There's a lot of wisdom
I think in the Buddhist lineage around
those concepts. And then the next piece for me,
once I can take a breath and relax a little bit,
is coming home to the fact that I... and this
is a little more radical for some people,
I don't actually need Dara to approve of
me in my presentation in order to be okay.
What I'm up to over here is trying to force
self-worth and self-love from within. And so
we talk about approval, control and security. It's
very easy to look for that from the world. Do you
approve of me? And if not, can I control outcomes
to get approval or get security and get the job,
the bank account, the house, whatever it is?
But what I kind of woke up to at one point was
that as long as I was going out there looking for
all that stuff to try to complete something inside
of me that was missing, it's like I was a hungry
ghost. It's like, it doesn't matter how many
Michelin star meals and promotions and money and
title and whatever. It's like it's never enough.
It's like you kind of enjoy it for a little bit
and then you get back to like, hm, you know?
So it's like a never ending sugar addiction. And
so that's the next step for me is allow it. Yes,
allow the emotion, allow the thought. Come home
to, "I am okay even Dara does think I suck."
And then also it's not permanent, right? It's like
sure, there might be some high stakes things in
life where you only get one shot, but for the most
part it's like if I didn't do a great job on this
presentation, there'll be another one. It's okay.
And think of it as practice. The other thing is
from the fear threat state, I'm like, uh-oh,
this is a risk, alarm bells, my career could
be over. Whereas if I'm in that trusting, curious,
open space, it's like this is an opportunity for
feedback. How can I learn? How can I get to become
a better presenter? It's like the feedback from
others is no longer a threat. It's actually
a gift. It's like information that I can use
or not use to alter how I show up in the future
and the skills I develop and all that good stuff.
I imagine some people may hear this and feel
like if Dara or Travis or whoever thinks I suck,
my career is at stake and that really matters
and everything's going to fall apart in my life
because I get fired, there's stakes involved
with messing up. Is there anything that helps
you get past that and not worry so much about
just this trickle effect of all the things that
could go wrong if you mess something up in an
important high stakes meeting or presentation?
Yeah. Again, and maybe it is a little paradoxical,
but what I found was the more I focused on how I
show up and optics and having a good deck and
all this, the less I got promoted and then the
more I dropped focusing all that. Because for
my first few years of Uber, I was a senior PM
and then I finally got my groove and started
kind of moving through the product ladder. And
it was really correlated to me at least, maybe
causal, with dropping a lot of the focus on the
presentation and how I show up and whether people
like this or not, and just really focusing on the
work. It's like, you know what? I am here to be
a conduit from what wants to happen in the world
of transportation and mobility and shared
rides is one that I've always been particularly
passionate about, so that's a good example,
and then how can I get present and listen
to what wants to happen next in the world of
shared rides? And there's lots of different
ways we can take the product and all that.
And it's really about, I want to make a
fucking awesome product, right? And it's like,
whether people like me or think I'm a good PM or
presenter, as long as I manifest a great product
into the world that makes riders better off,
drivers better off, cities better off, less
congestion, all these things, that to me is the
reward. And sure, in order to manifest that, it
is often helpful to communicate things, present,
align, all those sort of things. But those are a
means to a more powerful and transformative end
than just my career. I'm tapping into a larger
purpose and sense of belonging and identity and
sort of meaning. And from that place, it's like
I've just dropped the kind of egoic, self-centered
focus on whether I did good in the presentation
or not. And then yeah, maybe paradoxically,
by doing that, it actually goes better and
we do great work and it gets recognized.
Wow, that is fascinating. To make that work,
you need to really connect with the mission
of the company you're working at. You really
need to believe this is very important and
very meaningful. So maybe that could be
an issue for people if they don't really
care about what the company's doing, it's
going to be hard to allow for that approach.
Totally, totally.
It's interesting that you say that optics
aren't as important. I think the reason I
think about this as you talk about, a lot of
people feel like there's the work and then
there's talking about the work, making the
work, the optics of what you did is really,
really important. And I love to
hear. Nobody wants to do that,
but they always get this advice. So important,
optics, how you share the impact you've done,
how you represent yourself. I guess, is there
anything else you can share there about just
helping people relax about that aspect of
their job and without being so critical?
Yeah. And to be clear, I do think it's
important. It can't be all work and no
optics or all optics and no work. There does
need to be a balance there, and I think it
does change depending on the size of the company
and the level of seniority. When you're an IC,
you're probably hopefully doing more actual work,
and leaders are supporting them and presenting and
communicating that work so that they get.
I mean, the optics does matter, right? At
some senior level, you do spend more time
on that, and it does have influence, back
to the influence piece, which is like, how will I
communicate an idea and the need for engineering
resourcing and so forth might mean that team gets
more engineers or doesn't get more engineers, or
we do this project or we don't, right? Because at
the end of the day, executive resource allocation
is largely based on the, quote-unquote, "optics
layer". So it does matter. I want to be clear. I'm
not saying it doesn't matter, but to me, again,
it's more about that's a means to an end. It's
not about the optics itself. It's like say what
the Buddha is saying, don't mistake the finger
pointing at the moon for the moon. And the finger
pointing at the moon could be the presentation,
the OKR, you know, whatever. And it's like,
that's not the actual outcome we care about.
That's an input to the output that really
matters, which is the work, the product.
Okay. I'm going to shift this to hard skills and
another kind of direction. So another thing that
came up a bunch when I was asking people what
you're amazing at and what you're really good at
is strategy and vision. I had this quote from one
of your colleagues, Brent Goldman, "J.M. thinks
big, has lots of great ideas, will 'yes, and'
to other people's ideas, will inspire everyone
around him to be more creative, ambitious,
and hardworking. He doesn't climb hills,
he finds bigger mountains and will bring you
there." So along these lines, say someone comes to
you and wants to build these skills, wants to get
better at strategy, wants to get better at vision,
which is something basically every product leader
is trying to get better at and every leader wants
to get better at, what advice do you generally
share? How does one improve in these areas?
Yeah, thank you. I appreciate the compliment.
Thank you, Brent. That is a great quote. Wow.
Yeah, I mean there's no magic toolkit or manual.
I've long ago given up on the notion that I'm
one book away from the perfect elusive answer
to whatever plagues you in life. And there's
obviously lots of books about strategy
and you get into all that. I guess for me,
a couple of things have been helpful. One is you
mentioned earlier finding a mission that you're
really passionate about. I think it would be hard
for me to come up with a strategy for improving
the healthcare system. It's like, sure, it's
important. I hope someone does it and figures
out how to deal with HIPAA and whatever,
all this stuff, but it's just not for me.
It's not my purpose, mission and vision in life.
And so step one is, am I working at a place and
in a product area in which I have a tremendous
amount of passion? Because for me, that is
the fuel and the motivation that helps me break
through to getting the strategy. That's the first
step. So that's where I feel enormously lucky
because again, this revolutionizing transportation
and car ownership and what happens with autonomy
and form factors and future of cities is something
that I'm super excited about. I think about my
daughters growing up and having a different world
to live in that's safer and more environmentally
friendly, all this stuff, and I get really jazzed
when I think about, wow, the work I do could
actually impact their future lives and other
people. It's like, whoa, I can feel the chills
right now. It's just super motivating. So that's
the first place, just getting myself fired up.
And then the next thing I guess that's been
helpful is I've deeply immersed myself. I haven't
really jumped around between crypto and gen AI,
this stuff, and a lot of people do that.
It's great, nothing wrong with that,
but I've been in this largely focused on mobility
space for 10 years now with some stints over in
the restaurant tech and delivery side, but very
related in terms of last mile logistics. And so
I think it's hard to come up with a great
strategy if you've only been working in an
area for six months. Especially things like
this, they're super nuanced. Shared rides is
another a good example where it's a super hard
problem to crack and it's going deep on that for
a long time is a precursor to being successful.
The other thing I would say though is people
always talk about first principles thinking, but
if there's truth in it, I think that's like when
Elon's like, "Well, why does the rocket cost
a gazillion dollars to launch? And there's no
reason they have to throw away the materials
and blah, blah, blah." One example might be,
why do we need a 4,000 pound vehicle to move
a human three miles? Okay, well... Or even a
couple of humans. We do an Uber Pool or a Share,
and you move two humans or three humans, even then
that's pretty inefficient. If you think about
just the physics there, the energy expenditure.
And that's where I think you might come up with
bikes and scooters and little other things. And
sure it's not always, it's raining or you want
the car, but that's sort of an example of why
questioning why are things the way they are,
and then is the way they are super inefficient
or not optimal in some sense? And that is often
a doorway to opportunity to see, okay, well maybe
things could be different. And so I kind of
extend that at a larger level to the future.
My general thing is just like, yeah, that's
the mountain thing is I try to just close my
eyes and imagine the future as far out as I can.
It's like five years from now, 10 years from now,
whatever. And it's develop a really salient
picture of what that looks like. It's like,
we could do this right now, it's okay. 10 years
from now, what could San Francisco look like? Or
some city? What happens to the parking spaces?
Are there still parking garages? Are those parks
now? What are the modes of transport? Are there
bus-like things that are autonomous that are
connecting people to bikes and scooters? And
how are people living? Do they live in the
far suburbs even more because autonomy and they
have a nicer house and they come in, or is all
the space repurposed and actually it's cheaper
to live in the city because we compact things,
blah, blah, blah. It's not even about having the
right one, it's more just developing some sort of
picture of the future that gets you fired up.
And then yeah, you got to go articulate that
and communicate it and get people to come on
the journey with you. But from that picture,
it's like, well, first principle, what's going to
be true 10, 20 years from now? Well, autonomy is
a given. I think most people would probably agree
with that, and we'll probably solve it with just
cameras and won't need lidar because humans don't
have lidar. The cost of vehicles and sensors will
come down, remote support will come down, and at
some point it'll be super cheap and it's like,
okay, I can extrapolate, that will be a thing.
Separate from which player wins. I'm not saying
I can predict the ecosystem of companies
that will win here. It's more about just
the underlying dynamics. And then that would be
one, and another one would be sharing. It's like,
well, a lot of people are like, "Oh,
well, once we have cheap autonomous cars,
everyone can just have their own super cheap
Uber, Tesla or whatever it is here in the city."
And you're like, "Well, that doesn't work because
then we're going to hit this induced demand
concept," which is what economists call it, and
you used to, when text messages cost 50 cents a
piece, how many did you send versus now when it's
free, it's in the millions. Same thing when they
add a lane to a highway, the traffic just gets
just as bad as before because more people drive
and so forth. So if we flood the streets with
super cheap autonomous cars with single occupancy,
we're just going to have even more good luck than
we do right now. Maybe we'll do The Boring Company
thing and dig tunnels, but that seems unlikely.
So then for me, it's like, well, from first
principles, shared rides is going to
continue to be an important part of the
future of transportation. And other modalities
where yeah, back to the three mile thing,
it's like, well, there probably will be various
form factors of bikes, scooters and little mini
golf cart things and whatever we end up building.
And so that's hopefully an example of how I try
to think about what are the likely things
to be true in the future, and then how does
that lead to a potential ecosystem and strategy
around what we might build towards that future.
This is great because this is something everyone
can do, and there's all this talk of creating a
vision, painting a vision, communicating a vision,
and what you're describing is how to actually sit
there and think about what it might look like.
Sit there, close your eyes and in your head
visualize in the next five or 10 years, what does
the future actually look like? And do you do this
in a state of if we were to do this product and
change, or is it just even if we're not around,
here's where the future is going to go most
likely, which direction do you usually take?
Yeah, that's a good question. I think you
could probably do either. I typically like
to start with the former, which is just
like, what will the world move towards
absent of me? Just trying to pick a bird's-eye
view of what I think the trajectories are
and trends and what's going to happen. And
then yeah, you could apply a lens of, okay,
if we were to build product XYZ or have the
strategy, how might we influence the outcome
or benefit from it, or is it in congruence
with that or is it rubbing against that and
trying to change that? Either could be good,
you might say it's a tailwind or a headwind,
both are overcomeable, but having some awareness
of the relationship between those things is good.
And I think transportation, Uber, Waymo, in
theory it might be easier to visualize that
future and how exciting that might be versus a
B2B SaaS payroll app or some photo sharing thing.
But on the other hand, not necessarily,
right? What in the future in 10 years,
how are people going to be paid? How
do people work at companies? I think
there's an opportunity to do that no matter
what you're building. Is this something you
actually do? You just sit there in the office,
close your eyes and just imagine? Is this more
of an iterative process where you get with
your team, how do you actually practice this?
Yeah, it's not like something you can just
schedule 30 minutes for in the middle of your
day of packed OKR reviews and random one-on-ones
and meetings. It's like, I like to do it on my
own at first unless it's something that I already
have an outline for and I'm ready to move into a
team space. So for me, it's like, yeah, can I get
into a quiet contemplative space? So yeah, I like
to go for a run and that obviously gives me ideas,
or I'll go for a hike up in Marin and sometimes
I'll just think of stuff or jot something down
or make a voice note while I'm doing that to get
things going. But yeah, the first step for me is
just getting out of the craziness of day-to-day.
To me, it's still insane how many product manager,
leaders of all kinds just run the schedule of back
to back meetings, 30-minute review, big meaty
topics, you run out of time, run to the next
thing, answer a bunch of emails, and then cram
some PRDs in there. It's like, it doesn't work.
And so I'm a big fan of carving out time, again,
first for myself, a couple hours, whatever,
where I can just get out of the day-to-day
craziness and get into that head space of five,
10 years from now. It's just a different place.
So you need to transition to that. And then bring
that to teams. If I have an outline of that kind
of future of transportation in my head, I might
share that with a group of folks and we'll come
together also for some extended period of time. We
recently had an all-day Monday thing where eight
of us came into the office to talk about future
of marketplace, and it was super productive. It
was like, laptops down, we're going to spend all
day together on a whiteboard. It's like a lost
art. People don't use the whiteboards anymore.
But yeah, and then from there it's getting more
people and then you can kind of iterate on it.
It's like I had some vision of the future and
someone points out something that is a little bit
off with it or has a better idea. Then you move
into co-creation. But I love that. It's like Pixar
calls the brain trust. If you read [inaudible
00:32:28] book, how they come up with a Toy
Story and Inside Out and all these things, is
they have this group of people that just sits
around riffing on ideas. And again, there's no
judgment, there's no attachment to being right.
They're in a co-creative sort of space where
they're just like co-exploring and riffing
with each other. And I love to be in that space
with other PMs and engineers and data scientists.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta.
When it comes to ensuring your company has
top-notch security practices, things get
complicated fast. Now you can assess risk,
secure the trust of your customers and
automate compliance for SOC 2, ISO 27001,
HIPAA and more with a single platform, Vanta.
Vanta's Market-leading trust management platform
helps you continuously monitor compliance
alongside reporting and tracking risk. Plus,
you can save hours by completing security
questionnaires with Vanta AI. Join thousands
of global companies that use Vanta to automate
evidence collection, unify risk management,
and streamline security reviews. Get $1,000
off Vanta when you go to vanta.com/lenny.
That's V-A-N-T-A dot com slash lenny.
Something I've started to do, which is hard,
but I find really valuable is when I'm driving
to not play anything on the radio, not listen
to any podcasts, and it's so unnatural and it's
like, oh, this is hard. I don't want my brain to
just go... you don't trust your brain to go to a
place that's fun, but it always does. It always
ends up being like, oh, that was so interesting
just to think of this idea that just came up. So
I've been trying to do that, and that's such a
simple thing to do. Just don't turn anything on.
Well, it's not really good for your podcast
business to tell people not to listen to podcasts.
Okay, everyone, we're cutting this.
What I find really helpful is playing
Lenny's podcast every time I'm out and about.
No, but there's something to what you said,
which is there's always a lot of content out
there to pursue, and I've been in that mode where
I'm like, yeah, more content, more... But yeah,
actually similar to you, spend a lot of time now
not listening to anything. Go on a hike where you
don't listen to a podcast or music on your commute
and see what happens. You might be surprised.
Yeah. And it always ends up being like, oh,
that was cool. And that's where shower ideas
come from and all these things. Maybe
just to see if there's something here,
in this meeting that you have, this
ideation brainstorming meeting,
is there anything that came out of that
that was really surprising or new from a
recent experience? Is there anything there
of just like, oh wow, we really uncovered
this potential wrinkle of the future that
we really need to think about differently?
Well, it wasn't maybe a specific wrinkle, but one
of the things that we're thinking a lot about,
like I'm fortunate to be involved in trying
to help develop and articulate a multi-year
three-year product or even overall tech strategy
for the mobility business at Uber. And one of the,
I guess big ahas for us is as we move away from
the, in some ways simpler world of UberX being
the predominant product, which is it used to be
pretty simple. It's kind of like a taxi meter
on the driver's side. There's a time and distance
rate that everybody gets, and then on the rider's
side it's like, sure, there's some surge pricing
based on supply and demand, but it's one product,
it's pretty straightforward. And so this future
of multi-modality and on the both demand side and
the supply side is what makes the marketplace
even more complex and challenging to build.
And so it was kind of all this around, okay,
well now that we have taxis in the platform and
we have fleet providers and we're starting
to add Waymos and Cruise and other things,
we have to have a marketplace that's aware
of those different types of supply and which
one might be available for what trips
and how to think about cost and quality
and allocation of trips and all that. And
then on the demand side, it's like, yeah,
we've got all these different products like
shared rides and reserved rides and comfort
and X and priority, and it's like how do we think
about how to price those relative to each other?
How do we think about which one's to show which
user? How do you think about the ranking and so
forth? And then that all has feedback loops
into the pricing and matching itself as well.
So the dynamics of the thing, when I think
about the future of marketplace, Uber, is like,
whoa. And I don't think anyone's ever built
that. That's the super cool thing about it.
I think we have the best logistics marketplace
tech on the planet and we built something that
no one else has ever built, relative
to digital marketplaces, for example,
just different physical world requirements.
And then this next arc of what I described
of thinking about different types of supply and
different kind of demand channels just adds even
more complexity to that. But the aha was like, I
guess, yeah, we got to think about all that stuff
and think about how the supply and demand relate
to each other and yeah, it's going to be cool.
It's just an infinitely cited marketplace
now. That's wild. One last nugget I wanted
to just reinforce that you shared about how to
become better at strategy and vision, developing
great and interesting and innovative strategy,
and vision is going really deep on a topic. So
you've been in the space for a long time. There's
this idea that Paul Graham talks about, I think,
called your top idea or something like that,
that when you have... Whatever your top ideas,
the more you can just think about that and
keep that top of mind as you go about your
day and just have one core focus, the more likely
it is you're going to come up with new interesting
ideas because your brain's going to keep working
on it when you're driving around listening to
Lenny's podcast. Just kidding, or going on hike.
So I think that's a really important point is if
you're finding you're not coming up with a great
strategy or vision and just having struggles,
part of it might just be you're not
spending enough time in that space,
you're not going deep enough in the problem
area. One approach is just spend a decade
in that space. Is there anything else just
comes up as I say that of just how to do that?
Yeah. Well there's also, that's at the macro
level, maybe spending 10 years in a space,
but at the micro level, back to kind of
like defrag your day, don't just do the 20,
30 minute meetings on 20 different topics.
Sure, sometimes you do that first and you
got to do that. You have a large team like I do,
obviously reviews across teams. I'm not saying I
don't do that on some days, but it's like, yeah,
what are my top few things, right? I think,
you're right, I think it was Peter [inaudible
00:38:52] or PayPal guys talked about that too,
going really deep and having a person or a leader
really responsible for one core, deep thing for
the company, and that's something they immerse
themselves in. And so in the micro, that to me
again translates to, yeah, I don't have a to-do
list of 20 things. I try to have a to-do list of
three of the most important highest leverage
things that could have impact broadly across
the company and then try this, like you said,
let that one top thing marinate and chew on it.
I love that. And I recently had a post about all
these productivity tricks, and one of the things
that I find really helpful is at the beginning of
each day and also at the beginning of each week,
just write down, here's the one to three things
that I need to do and get done. And everything
else, I might have this really long list,
but here's the three things if I get done,
life will be good. I've done a lot. I've
accomplished really great, important things.
Totally. I tried to do the David Allen GTD thing
once, the super complicated organization system.
It was too much structure for me. I couldn't do
it. At the end of the day, what you said is right.
There's basically three things that I need
to do next, and then there's just some random
backlog that I can just scan through periodically
and that's it. That gets you most of the way.
It's crazy. I read that book 20 years ago at
this point, and there's elements that still
make things, like I leverage and benefit
from. Even if you don't do the whole thing,
that book I recommend people read because there's
just like, if you pick a couple things from there,
your life gets better. The things that
have stuck with me, the main one is this
waiting for concept of if you're waiting,
if you email your designer and like, "Hey,
I need you to review this product," just
note, "Waiting for Dan to review design."
And just having that thread written down
and not in your head really helped me.
Totally.
Yeah. Anyway, I'm not going to go on that tangent.
Yeah. It's the core concept of like,
whatever steps you use. I think the most
powerful takeaway from that book
for me was if it's in your head,
you're screwed because it's like you're trying
to keep track of stuff and be creative and
come up with the future of transportation
and remember to pick up something from the
pharmacy. It's a recipe for disaster. This
whole idea of empty mind, beginner's mind,
well, you have to empty the mind of all the
to-dos first. Just get that out of the head.
Absolutely. I think it was mind like
water, that's the one that stuck with me,
where nothing you need to remember
can be in your head. It needs to be
written down somewhere Anyway, let's not
go into a whole productivity podcast here.
Perfect.
So we talked about vision strategy. So
there's classically two problems people
have with vision strategy. One is how do I
get better at it? The other is just like,
I need to actually get shit done. I can't spend
all my time thinking about vision. You have a
really good take on how to find this balance
and you've seen it work well and not well,
just vision versus execution. When do I go big
vision, how much I spend on vision versus just
get shit done, execute, execute, execute?
What could you share about just what you've
learned about how to find that balance
and what you've seen work and not work?
Yeah, I think you can go too far either direction,
right? It's like everything in life is about
balancing the polarity between two opposing
forces. And so in this one it's like, yeah,
you go too hard in division and theory land, I've
seen that go off the axle, early Uber where again,
back to the future of pricing, it's like we have
all the data scientists and PhDs locked in a
room for two weeks and there's a beautiful
whiteboard diagram. What did it look like?
And then it's like, why don't we actually
build this thing? And engineers are like,
this is like boiling the ocean. And you just
get wrapped around the axle of like, well,
that sounds really good in theory, but I have
no idea how to even start executing on this.
So that's probably an example of we tilted a
little too far towards the vision theory land.
And this was, you're describing the original plan
to make a really good surge pricing algorithm?
Yeah. This was a plan to try to bring
together, say how we do driver pricing,
time and distance rates, but also we do incentives
for drivers where it's like if you drive this many
hours a week, you get a bonus. And there's
also surge pricing and how to tie all those
systems together in a very sophisticated sort
of way. This was back in 2017 or something and
it winged a little too hard into theory land.
And we still have that bias sometimes. We joke
about marketplace, especially when we talk about
with other teams that are trying to integrate
in the marketplace, let's say they add fleets or
teams with a big new product. And then marketplace
people would be like, "Well, have you thought
about this one random problem that could happen
two years from now if teams become this much of
demand and blah blah blah, whatever." And it's
just like we do get wrapped around the axle on
that sometimes. But yeah, so the future of pricing
is a good example, we winged a little too far
into theory land. But you could probably go too
far into execution land too. And I'd say DoorDash
in my experience would do that sometimes where we
used to actually even half joke there, some of us
leaders would be like, "It's ready, fire, aim."
And it was like, people would be like, "I'm just
going to run through a wall. I have no idea if
that's the right wall to run through, but at
least I know I'm running through a wall." So yeah,
I think it's about balance and can you adjust.
Again, it's dynamic. I think there's times where
you're in a soul searching sort of, "What is our
product strategy? We got to pivot." Maybe you're a
startup and it's not working and you want to think
about... And then it's like, okay, well pull off
the gas a little bit, ease up on the execution
and let's lean into the strategy vision piece.
And there's times where the strategy and vision's
pretty baked at least for the next whatever, six
months, a year. And it's like, okay, pedal to the
metal. Let's just go execute. Let's get it done.
I just went to this Acquired Podcast
event at the Chase Center. Zuck was there,
and the CEO of Spotify was there too. And there's
two quick anecdotes that you remind me of. One is,
Zuck talked about how once Facebook and Zuck
and the team align on here's where we're going,
no matter how many walls appear in front
of them, there's going to be a Mark
shaped hole in the wall very soon because
they're just going to run through and get
things done that they need to get done.
And I really love that mentality of once
we're sure where we're going, we're
going to bust through these walls.
That's awesome.
The other is a really interesting value at
Spotify. So Daniel Ek shared this. He said, "At
Spotify we have this core value, talk is cheap."
And when you hear that you think it's saying talk
is not valuable, and it's actually they look at
it as a virtue. Talk is cheap, we can talk and
it costs us no money, very little money compared
to building something. So they actually spent a
lot of time at Spotify refining their ideas and
discussing until they're really sure something
is right. And I guess any reaction to that?
Because I thought that was really interesting.
Yeah, I love that. It's almost a different flavor
of, I think the base of saying of he's like,
I like a crisp dock and a messy
meeting. The whole Amazon thing,
if you have the three-page or seven-page
narrative, it's written with the clarity
of angels singing from on high, at least
describing how the problem statement or
feature or whatever. And so it's super crisp and
organized and well articulated. And then you might
have a meeting where you pick it apart and you
talk a lot. That's what made me think of that.
Yeah. Awesome. Okay, couple more things I want
to spend some time on. One is you've worked at
a lot of really interesting successful hyper
growth companies, DoorDash, Uber, Waymo. You
were also in finance for a while. I want to pick
on a few of these and just see what's a lesson you
took away or what's an experience from that time
that might be interesting or helpful to people?
Sure.
So you talked about DoorDash a bit. What did
you take away from your time at DoorDash?
What's something you saw there that either
is like, wow, that's a really cool thing I
want to do in the future, or here's something they
weren't amazing at that I learned to try to avoid?
Yeah, yeah, it's really amazing to get to see
different places and pick the best of what you
like. And also the other thing is back to like,
for me, there's no right or wrong, it's just
differences have pros and cons. There's always
two sides of the coin. So what's interesting I
think about Uber and DoorDash is first back to
the mission and the strategy. They started with
different DNA, right? So Uber started with it was
to utilize blocked cars at the airport that were
not doing trips, but it was more about the riders.
It was like whatever origin story you believe,
Travis and whoever can get a ride in Paris. And
so then it was about better than taxi and all
this stuff, but it was very rider centric.
It was consumer centric in that sense.
And so for a long time, I think Uber kind of took
that too far. We got to the polarity of drivers
are a commodity, blah, blah, blah, and they had
to flip that back and start really investing more
on the driver's side of the marketplace.
But you look at DoorDash and it's like,
Tony grew up in his parents' restaurant
kitchen and the DoorDash thesis was how
can we help small businesses be more successful?
And delivery was just the first instantiation of
that sort of meta purpose of DoorDash. And so
they're much more merchant centric as opposed
to consumer centric. And by the way, the
consumer centricism of Uber that started
with rides than translated to Eats. I think
when Uber started with Eats, it was like,
"Well, we just want Lenny to have some great
Thai food and sushi and have some options. But
selection is a means to Lenny having a great eater
experience." Whereas DoorDash with their merchant
focus is like, "We want every Thai restaurant in
this city to be successful and be on DoorDash."
So their motivation for selection is, "We want
all of the merchants to thrive and survive." So
that happens to give you better selection as a
result. But the motivation was very different.
So the analogy I use is Uber is to Amazon as
DoorDash is to Shopify, if that makes sense.
Amazon has always been more consumer focused,
Shopify is obviously very merchant focused.
Interesting.
And by the way, either of those,
again, there's no right or wrong,
is a fine strategy. They're both great
companies. And I actually don't know if
you could do both. Is it possible to be Amazon
and Shopify? To really focus on consumers and
build all the merchant restaurant tech?
And maybe with enough resources and time,
but that would lose focus. So it's
like there's a trade-off there. Yeah.
Yeah. Like at Airbnb, there was always this,
"Should we optimize for hosts? Should we
optimize for guests?" And there's always this
like, "This time, guests are most important.
Right now hosts are more..." Make these
trade-off decisions in the marketplace. So
it's interesting that at Uber, your insight
there is Uber is always very rider focused,
and DoorDash from its DNA was very merchant
focused. You also talk about at DoorDash,
there's this mentality of just going before
figuring out where to go. Is there anything
more there that might be helpful, either
as a cautionary tale or as a lesson?
Yeah, I think it's a balance. It's back to
I don't want to deliberate and pontificate
for weeks on end about which door I should
run through. And I don't want to go to the
other extreme and just spend 30 seconds
thinking about what to do and just go,
go, go. So it's finding that kind of
happy medium. If I had to pick one,
I'd rather bias towards running through a
wall than not doing anything, because you
still get learnings from that and you either
make progress or you don't, and that gives you
feedback and you can run through another
wall as a result. So I think the biggest
failure case is probably erring on the other
side of deliberating too long without action.
What about Waymo? What's something that
you took away from that experience as a
thing that you want to do more of or
something you want to try to avoid?
Waymo is, you've probably seen people in San
Francisco, they're quite prolific now in terms
of they're all over San Francisco and you see
them all the time. And I'm not sure, I can't
remember the last time I saw one towed, I don't
want to say that they've solved self-driving,
but they are obviously driving at scale with
very minimal, at least real world intervention.
You can't tell by looking at the cars how many
humans behind the scenes might be helping provide
guidance of the car or whatever. But yeah, I
would say what's really interesting about Waymo
is they've largely solved the self-driving
piece, however they've done that, and in a
complex environment like San Francisco, and you
see them driving in fog and rain and puddles,
and it's like, wow, that's pretty cool.
But I think what Waymo was learning,
and I was trying help them learn is that building
a self-driving car on a test track is a very
different problem statement than scaling a fleet
of thousands of cars. And how do you operate them,
clean them, charge them, maintain them,
and then how do you build the ride share
network? It's like, okay, well we got to
build an app and we got to acquire users
and do classic growth stuff and think about that
marketplace and matching and pricing and those
are very different skills. And so it's like
a warning that those are different things.
And trying to hire for that and build culture
around that was hard, honestly. It's just like
you're kind of a different thing than the
host organism. Most of the host organism is
just obsessed with perception and planning and
all the core autonomy pieces and you're like,
the commercialization people there, "Well, now
we've going to make money with this thing."
That's why I think that's an example where your
overall vision would say Waymo is to build Waymo
One. Just be mindful that it's more than just
one. There's multiple pillars of that. There's the
self-driving piece, there's getting a lot of cars
at scale, financing them, operating the fleet,
getting the demand, filling the cars with
people, and then it has to all come together.
Right. Yeah. It's so interesting that your
title is Lead Product for Commercialization
of Autonomous Ride Hailing at Waymo, and
now it's come full circle where at Uber,
that's going to be in a sense
the way that people call Waymo.
And so it's so interesting that
you've seen both sides of this.
Yeah. Well, we'll see what happens. I think
Uber, it got out of the autonomy business when it
divested Autonomous Technologies Group or Advanced
Technologies Group. And right now our stated
strategy is to be an aggregator. So it's like, we
are partnering with Waymo, with Cruise, Motional,
others in China, et cetera. And then the idea
is to have every vehicle on the platform really,
right? Autonomous or not. And then use the
power of the platform, we have this big
demand base, we have a lot of riders.
And so I think what you're seeing is,
Waymo and Cruise and others are like,
"Okay, now that we've developed autonomy,
what's the path to profitability for us?" And so
they can go it alone and try to build a ride-share
network. And Waymo is doing that with Waymo One,
but it turns out it takes a while. It's funny,
I feel like engineers too are always skeptical
of why other people's engineering problems
take so much work. There'd be engineers at
Waymo would be like, "Why does Uber have so
many thousands of engineers? How hard
can it be to build a ride-share app?"
But when you look at what made Uber successful,
what we've been perfecting for the last decade,
A, the marketplace tech that I alluded
to earlier, but also how we manage a
large rider base and doing rider support and
driver support and logistics and all of the
helping finance electric vehicles and working
with regulators and cities and making sure we
have safe and accessible pickup points and
on and on and on. And those are all the
depth of the iceberg that you don't really
realize or think of when you're like, "Oh,
I can just build a ride-share app." Right?
Tesla publishes their sigma design and some
earnings report and everyone goes crazy like,
"Wow, okay, well I don't want to bet against
Elon because that sounds scary," but there is
more to it than just the app and the autonomy.
So yeah, I think these companies will have
an interesting question. Do they go alone,
build their own ride-share network to
capture all the value, or do they say,
"Well, I could just work with Uber and have a
faster path to high utilization of the vehicles,"
which unlocks financing and more vehicles and
that gets them to scale faster? And so if you
look at the landscape right now, it's a bit of
both, right? Waymo is obviously working with Uber
in Phoenix and we just announced Cruise will
come back to some city next year I think, but
Waymo is also still building their own thing, so
they're kind of hedging their bets at the moment.
I want to take us to a recurring
segment on the podcast that I
call Contrarian Corner. I feel like
you're going to have a good answer
here. What's something that you believe
that most other people don't believe?
One is back to being aware of your internal state
and allowing emotions and thoughts is... Emotions
in the workplace, a lot of people have the thing
of like, "Well, there's no need for emotion in
the workplace. We're going to be logical. We're
going to be data-driven. Keep your feelings at
home. Just show up and presentation J.M. Mode."
And I guess in my experience, there's this thing
around whole body intelligence and whole body,
yes, which is yes, there is signal from the head
and logic and data and left brain reasoning are
amazing and it could be great, but there's also
heart and gut. And to me, what is an emotion?
It's just energy moving on the body. Often it's
correlated with a thought too as well. I might
have a thought that creates fear and so forth.
But to me there's wisdom in emotion and I
can start to access noticing them more. Like
where do I feel sadness in the body? I notice
I feel fear in the kind of center of my chest,
and then sadness is like a sinking feeling
in my stomach. And I notice when I'm angry,
my jaw gets tight and my eyes furrow a
little bit. And so those are common ones,
but you may have your own little signatures of you
pick up where is joy, where is creative energy?
Where is fear or sadness, anger? And then noticing
those in a meeting or in a conversation or review.
And actually if you're willing, even just voice
it to other people, that's like the next step. But
start with just acknowledging it to yourself.
And so for me, the wisdom of emotions is fear
is something wants to be paid attention to.
There can be the saber-toothed tiger is not
really Dara disapproving of me, whatever. I
shouldn't be afraid of that. But there are
times where fear is applicable. There might
be fear around, let's say back at Waymo,
you want to be really intentional about safety and
you want to be super... That's one of the things
I love about Waymo is they're very committed to
having a super strong safety record. And so there
might be fear around did we really consider all
the edge cases of what might happen if a dog runs
in the street or a ball or child or whatever,
and you might see wow, fear. It's great. The
wisdom of that is something wants to be paid
attention to and listened to. Okay, great.
Sadness for me is something wants
to be let go of. There's a mourning,
there's a letting go of I had an idea or
vision for the future that will no longer be
because whatever, something happened, other people
don't want to do it, this or that. But it could be
a vision of a relationship, it could be a vision
of what you thought your life would look like,
whatever. We all go through those sorts of things.
And there might be micro-moments of sadness of
like, wow, that feature didn't work. It's like
I really wanted it to be successful. I just let
go of that, welcome the sadness. Anger to me is
something is not of service to me or my people
or my mission or whatever I'm up to. And so
again, that can be a great signal to like,
okay, I pay attention to that. I want to change
something. And then joy is something that wants
to be celebrated. We had a great win. We nailed
the OKR, we had a great product launch. A lot of
times we spend too much time moving back
into the next, okay, let's set another
goal. It's like, it's okay to stop and celebrate.
And then creative energy is something wants to be
born into the world. It's like it's almost like
I'm going to birth an idea or a vision or some
new product thing and then just tuning into that.
So yeah, I would say welcome emotions, maybe even
talk about them, god forbid, in the workplace.
Imagine that instead of having a OKR review
where you're behind target and everyone's blaming
other people, and you could tell when it's kind of
fearful, if someone was just like, "Wow, I noticed
that I just feel fear around this." Everyone was
like, "Wow, I feel fear too." That would just
totally change the tone of the conversation.
The advice here is bring your emotions
into work. Don't let emotions...
What most people believe is leave your emotions
at home, don't bring your emotions into the
workplace, and what you've found is they actually
can make you more effective and make your teams
more effective. And you even talked about it
helps you make decisions in a more intelligent
way because your gut and lizard brain almost
tells you things that you should pay attention to.
Totally.
I love that. Okay, so I'm going to close with
a question that is rooted in something that you
shared with me when we were chatting about this
podcast that I think is going to be helpful to a
lot of people. What have you found to be keys
to a successful, impactful, rich, fun life?
It's a great question, and I think lots of
people have different prescriptions for that,
and I don't claim to have the one truth around
that, but the first thing I would say as a meta
observation is I spend a lot of time thinking
about objective functions. We design algorithms
to do matching and pricing and think about
short-term effects and long-term effects. And
so I really am ingrained in this idea of we have
an objective function for our life. And then the
problem is that a lot of us aren't conscious
of it. It's just like an implied OF that you
inherited values from your church or community
or what your parents valued or what you learned
to be good at, and I do this for work and blah,
blah, blah, and I'm just kind of bobbing along.
That's why I love Ray Dalio's principle thing
where it's like, Hey, write down your values and
your principles and get clear on what they
are. Or Clayton Christensen wrote a great
book that he's less known for, he's obviously
known for Innovator's Dilemma, but he wrote
a book called How Will You Measure Your Life?
And he was trying to answer this question of,
he teaches whatever, MBA students at Harvard,
and he's like, "Wow, all these executives are
super successful. They're like Fortune 500 execs.
They're most super successful, but they're all
divorced and their kids hate them and their
personal lives are a mess. What's happening?"
And so one of the key insights he comes to is
like, it's Sunday night and you have the choice
of playing with your daughter, or you're
reading a book or playing a game, and you
have a presentation to Dara on Monday. And he's
like, "Well, I could make those slides a little
bit better and I could go practice or knock out
some emails," or whatever it is you want to do.
And so what he basically found was the type
A exec, successful people are very short-term
OF driven. They're like, "Well, presentation's
tomorrow, and that can either go great or okay
based on Sunday night." Whereas like, "My daughter
will be here, I'll play with her next week." And
the problem is that he's getting in this cycle
where it's like, okay, you start working every
Sunday night and then years and years go by
and suddenly you don't have a relationship
with your daughter who's now a teenager.
But I think we're just not conscious of
that. So to me, the first piece of advice would
be get clear on your objective function. And
one way that I've gotten clear on it is trying
to think about it from future me. Because five
years from now, I'm not going to give a shit
if I made the presentation slightly better,
but I'm going to care a lot about what kind
of relationship I have with my daughters. And
that means that the next action, the next
thing I do today and tomorrow, those will
translate into the relationship with her. And I
think a lot of us aren't just tuned into that.
I love the stoic stuff, being mindful of death,
Seneca, Marcus Aurelius, all those great ones.
Not to be morbid, but just again, most of us just
aren't really tuned into an awareness that our
lives will come to an end. And we try to avoid
that and we try to pretend like we're going to
live forever and just not think about it. And
the horror of it is that we succeed. We mostly
manage to just go live our life and eat ice cream
and go to work and go on vacation and do what
we do. And that can lead us to doing things
that ultimately don't matter in the long run,
and focusing on the wrong things.
And so to me, it's like an awareness
and mindfulness that our lives will come to an
end punctuates reality in a way that requires
me to rethink my priorities, stop wasting time on
things that don't matter with people who matter.
This relationship, this journey, it will come
to an end. I'm actually tearing up and feeling
tingly just saying that. It's like even right
now, come back to it. How am I going to spend
my afternoon? Am I going to hug my daughters?
Am I going to spend time with them after work
or am I going to do email all night? What would
I wish I had done when I'm in my last breath?
There's a quote that I heard once
that really stuck with me that I
think is going to hit a lot of people really hard,
which is that the only people that will remember
you working late every night is your kids.
Wow. Yeah.
Yeah. An important reminder. J.M., we've covered
a lot of stuff. Is there anything else that you
think might be helpful for people that you want
to leave listeners with? Or we're going to have
a lightning round coming up, but before we
get that, we ended on a really powerful,
impactful note. Is there anything
else along these lines that you
think might be helpful for people
that you want to leave them with?
The one thing I'd encourage folks to do out
of all of these we talked about is to see if
you'd be willing to commit to breaking out of
victim consciousness and mentality. And it's
not to say there aren't victims in the world,
there are real injustices and things happening,
but most of us, I've experienced, I often can fall
into the trap of living my life at the effect of,
right? I'm at the effect of other people and what
they do. I'm at the effect of circumstances like
COVID or Trump or whatever. I'm at the effect
of the conditions and circumstances of life,
and I feel like life is happening to me.
And so to me, the most empowering and
radical transformation that I've been able
to cultivate and develop is shifting from
that to a state of I I am willing to take
responsibility for how I see the world. And
I may not be able to change the weather or
the election or all that, but I can change
how I'm being in relationship to it and choose
to see it as a growth opportunity, as learning,
how am I co-creating it, even things that I
play a small part in, injustice in the world,
how am I perpetuating that and being willing to
see the world as I'm the painter of my existence?
I think Viktor Frankl's Man's Search for
Meaning is probably the best example of that.
He's in a super oppressive situation that is very
horrific and tragic, and the way he described his
relationship with the people in the camp and the
guards, and he given he gave a talk after he was
free, the amount of compassion and empathy he had
for his oppressors was just amazing. So I'm like,
well, if he can do that in the face of those
conditions, I can show up differently in a
product review or in a conversation with
my partner or meeting or whatever it is.
Yeah, I think just that skill alone is such a
powerful unlock for a lot of people instead of,
here's all the things that I don't have and here's
all the things that are setting you back and
all the things that are hard for me versus other
people. Shifting to, I need to take responsibility
for my own success and no one else will. And just
taking agency is a really powerful thing. It's
easier said than done. There's a lot of hardships.
People have a lot of things that they don't have
that other people have that are hurting their
career and hurting their ability to be successful,
but still, the more you can take responsibility
and have agency and the less you have this victim
mentality, I 1,000% agree, there's so much
power there. So that's an awesome lesson
to end on. With that, we've reached our very
exciting lightning round jam. Are you ready?
I'm ready. Let's do it.
Okay. First question, what are two or three books
that you've recommended most to other people?
In the realm of the soft skills
and conscious leadership,
the best one is the 15 Commitments of
Conscious Leadership by Diana Chapman
and Jim Dethmer. And those were my early
coaches and teachers almost 10 years ago,
and Diana is still my coach. So I think that's
a fantastic book that we'll go into more detail
about some of the things we talked about around
fear and threat versus trust and drawing a
triangle and all that great stuff. That'd
be one that I'd definitely recommend first.
Another one more in the content world is I think
you had Nancy Duarte on your podcast one point.
Yeah, Nancy Duarte. Yeah.
Or Duarte, sorry. I love her book Resonate.
I know she has some other ones too,
on slide design and stuff. But what was so cool
about that, I gave it to PMs all the time when I'm
trying to help them develop their communication,
storytelling, and presentation skills. And she
goes through those TED talks and Martin Luther
King, I have a dream, and going to the Moon,
and basically make the spark line against it
to understand this concept of resonance with
the audience. It's actually a great skill
for, back to vision and north-starring,
she said what all these things do is they
alternate tension between the world as it
is and the world as it might be. And it's like,
here's that beautiful future of transportation,
San Francisco, blah, blah, blah, but here's why it
sucks today, all these problems and this and that,
but here's how it could look in a few years.
And then you're creating that tension and the
audience at the end is like sweaty palms and like,
"I want to help build that future." What do you
need? You need money, you need time, resources,
join your company. Great. So anyway, Resonate,
Nancy Duarte, great book. Those would be some
of the top two that I recommend. There's not
one specific book, but I really love Alan Watts'
books if you're into... He was one of the first
people to articulate and kind of import Buddhism
and that sort of Eastern thinking into the West,
and he just has a very satirical, comical
sort of not taking myself too seriously
style and just like the way he explains a lot
of those concepts. So that'd be another one.
He also has an amazing voice if you
listen to recordings of him with music,
it's just so fun to listen to.
Totally. Actually, Sam Harris's Waking Up app
now has the entire... he worked with I think
Alan Watts' son. So the Waking Up app has all
80 or 100 hours of recorded Alan Watts lectures.
Oh my god. There's YouTube videos.
[inaudible 01:10:06]
There's some awesome YouTube videos of him
that are worth watching, we'll link to some
of those. And then Nancy Duarte, she shared
exactly that lesson on the podcast that we
had together. So if you don't want to read the
book and listen to her give this tactic of this
way to communicate a vision, you can listen to
that episode, we'll link to it. Next question,
do you have a favorite recent movie
or TV show you have really enjoyed?
Yeah. The last movie I really enjoyed was
Inside Out 2 with my kids, which is very-
I could see why you'd love that.
Yes, consistent with the emotional awareness
and allowing the different emotional parts and
don't want to spoil the movie, maybe everyone
hasn't seen it, but it's very simpatico with
that lesson of you can't just let one emotion run
the show, they all have wisdom. On the first one,
Sadness, Joy learning that Sadness is
necessary. It's all about integration,
but it was beautiful the way kids understand
it and it's a way to teach emotional literacy
to your kids. So I think what they've done there
with those Inside Out movies is just brilliant.
Do you have a favorite product you've
recently discovered that you really
love? It could be an app, it
could be something physical.
Yeah, so Eight Sleep is a smart mattress company.
They're on their third or fourth rev now,
but it's like a Tempur-Pedic mattress, or you
can put their cover on any mattress, but it has
a cover that has little tubes of water, and then
it has a little computer thing and you fill with
water and then an app. And basically what you do
is you program it and it learns, it has sensors,
it can measure your heart rate, your HRV, body
temperature, all that, but you're basically
trying to program a temperature curve to help you
maximize your kind of REM sleep and deep sleep and
get more value out of the sleep that you do have.
And so for me, it's super cool early for deep
sleep, and then it warms you up as you want to
wake up, which is... or an alarm and all that.
But it's back to my thing about wanting to show up
with the right mindset and energy and aliveness.
Having really high quality sleep has been a really
key part of that, is like if I don't sleep well,
I didn't get enough sleep or didn't sleep
well, you're already starting off on a bad
foot. So yeah, if you haven't checked out Eight
Sleep, great product. No endorsement fee for me.
What's also cool about it is it tracks your sleep.
It gives you all these stats. Instead of wearing
a ring, and it gives you all these stats about
your sleep quality. And there's this guy, Brian
Johnson, I don't know if you follow him, he's like
this guy that's trying to stay alive as long as
possible, and he had a perfect sleep score
for six months in a row to set the record.
Wow.
Yeah. He knows what he's doing over there.
Okay, two more questions. Do you have a
favorite life motto that you often come back
to, think of, find useful in work or in life?
Yeah, I probably have had different
ones over the years. The one right now
that really serves me is there's this track
called Sit Around the Fire by Jon Hopkins,
but it's on Spotify, Apple Music, but it's
basically music with one of Ram Dass' talks,
lesser known talks. And so the mantra that's
been really serving me recently is the very
first part of that, which is he says, "Beyond all
polarities, I am. Let the judgments and opinions
of the mind be the judgments and opinions
of the mind. And you exist behind that."
So sometimes I have an abbreviated version of that
where I'm noticing I'm activated, I'm clinging
to an opinion, I'm arguing with somebody,
and I'm just like, "Beyond all polarities."
An abbreviated version.
I do that in front of my kids and they laugh
at me like, "Daddy is so weird sometimes."
Beyond all polarities, kids. That's so funny.
Oh man. There's another Ram Dass line that I
often use with my wife, Be Here Now, which is
the title of his book that everyone sees with
the blue cover. And I do that when she's on her
phone and we're doing something. I'm like, "Be
here now." And she's like, "Okay, okay. I'll put
my phone away." Yeah. Final question. I was going
to ask you about the line tracking and what you
learned from that. You already shared an awesome
lesson from that time. So let me ask you something
else. I'll ask you about Travis. Any crazy, fun,
memorable stories of working with Travis Kalanick?
However you say his last name, Kalanick, Kalanick?
Travis Kalanick, yeah. Yeah. I'll share a
quick one that's short but sweet or hilarious
to me, and maybe lesser known. So we used
to have the Uber office at 1455 Market,
and so there was one conference room where we'd
often do reviews with Travis, and it wasn't the
war room, whatever whenever room it was. That was
interior and no windows. So this room had windows
overlooking, what was that? 11th street. So 11th
and Market. And so we'd have a presentation up
on the projector, some big screen we're about to
go through something with Travis. And reliably,
every time he'd come in, he would close the blinds
of the windows. Everyone like, "Travis, what are
we doing?" It's not because there was glare.
They were orthogonal to the screen. And then
one time I was like, "Why are you doing
that?" He's like, "I'm pretty sure Lyft has
drones outside the windows of our office
and they're spying on our presentation."
Oh my gosh.
I was like, whoa, your competitor paranoia
runs deep, man. Okay. Yeah, yeah. Anyway.
It's hard to mention Lyft doing that.
I could see Uber doing that to Lyft.
Old Uber. Uber 1.0
Old Uber. Yeah. Wow. That's amazing. It's like
coaches in the NFL that are covering their lips
always when they're telling and giving plays, just
like, I wonder if people actually do that. That's
amazing. Yeah, I get that. It's like high stakes.
You never know. Might be a drone out there.
Right.
Amazing. J.M., what a roller coaster of a
conversation. We covered so much ground. I
can't even name all the things we covered. So
let me just ask you two final questions. Where
can folks find you online and reach out if they
want to work with you? I know you work with folks,
talk about that. And then finally,
how can listeners be useful to you?
Yeah, yeah. So I am occasionally on Twitter
@NickelsJM, but I don't tweet a lot,
but maybe I should start. But the best
way to find more about my thoughts
and thinking on the soft skill stuff is
a website called rhythmofbeing.com. And
I've got some blog posts and stuff there that go
into detail on some of these things. And yeah,
I do a little bit of coaching on the side with
folks. I do very little now. My day job at Uber
and my night job with my kids takes up most of my
waking hours. But for the right person and a few
select spots, I can make time. But yeah, that's
the best place to find me, is rhythmofbeing.com.
And then how can listeners be useful to you?
Well, in the spirit of welcoming and
embracing feedback, you could most be
useful by reaching out, telling me what
resonated, what didn't, what was useful,
where did your energy go up when I talked,
and where did your energy go down? Because
that to me is a signal of where I'm back to
tracking the life, where's the juice? And
then that way in the future when I do other
versions of this or other conversations,
I'll pay more attention to the energy up stuff
and go more there, and the energy down was like,
okay, maybe that wasn't as interesting
or didn't resonate. Great. No problem.
J.M., thank you so much for being here.
Thank you for having me.
Bye everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.