I've had thousands of people tag my CEO on Twitter
calling on him to fire me. I was actually on
vacation and I got bored and I was like, "I
haven't logged into Twitter, I haven't posted
anything to Twitter for a while. What's going
on on Twitter?" And I see that the notifications
number is maxed out. It's like 999+ or whatever.
And I was like, "Wait, what?" And I clicked the
notifications tab and I see the first tweet
has @CEOhandle fire Tal Raviv. And I saw that
that has a ton of retweets and I keep scrolling
down and I start to piece together the story.
Today my guest is Tal Raviv. This is a very
special episode for me because Tal was one
of the first and most active community members
when I was just starting my newsletter and Slack
community. And as a PM I've admired from afar for
a very long time, he's got some really unique and
insightful takes on how to be a great product
leader. And interestingly, he's decided to stay
in IC product manager throughout his entire career
up to this point, which is over 12 years as an
IC PM. I've never met anyone that's stayed in IC
for this long. He's been a PM at Patreon, at Wix,
at AppsFlyer, and most recently joined Riverside
as their first ever product manager. Riverside,
by the way, is the platform that I use to
record my podcast, so this was kind of a meta
experience for both of us. He's also former
founder and outside of tech he volunteers as
a surf instructor for people with disabilities.
In our conversation, we talk in depth about the
IC career path, a bunch of tactical
advice on how to be more productive
as a pm, including a killer example of how he
uses ChatGPT to scale himself. Tal also explains
why every tech company has just two departments
that matter, the difference between book smart
decisions and street smart decisions. We also
spent the most time I've ever spent in Failure
Corner where Tal shares all of the times that he's
failed in his career and how those experiences
made him stronger. And it was really important
for him to share these things because he wants
people to understand that successful people
fail a lot and those failures make you better.
If you want to learn more from Tal, he's
actually about to launch a course on Maven
that's called Build Your PM Productivity System,
which based on the conversation that we had I'm
confident is going to be awesome. If you
enjoy this podcast, don't forget to follow
it and subscribe in your favorite podcasting
app or YouTube. It's the best way to avoid
missing feature episodes and helps the podcast
tremendously. With that, I bring you Tal Raviv.
Tal, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you. It's great to be here.
This is a long time in the making.
It has been a long time in the making.
You're interesting in so many ways,
we're going to talk about a lot of different
things. One of the things that makes you most
unique and interesting as a PM is that you've
stayed in IC product manager for your entire
career for 12 years. I don't think I've ever met
a PM that's been in IC for 12 years. I imagine
you've had many opportunities to be promoted,
I imagine this has been very intentional. And
I also know a lot of people actually think about
this a lot, "Should I move into management? Can
I stay in IC and be successful?" So I'm going
to spend some time here to start. And my first
question is just why? Why have you decided to stay
in IC? Why have you not moved into management?
I don't really have a strategy for my
career. My strategy is not to have a
strategy. For the longest time I've gone by,
am I excited to wake up in the morning and
what's going to make me excited to wake
up in the morning? Not every single day,
not all the time, but for most of my days that I
work, what's going to make me hop out of bed? And
just kind of follow that. And over time, as I
got to have different managers and different
product leaders that I've worked with, I've
never looked at their schedule or their days
or how they spend the high percentage of their
time and said, "Wow, that's what I want to be
doing," if I compare their days with mine and
the stuff they're busy with and focused on.
And at the same time over the years, I've
also noticed that the colleagues that I
identify with the most, like the ones
where I just feel I most relate to them,
many of them have that same pattern where
they've gone to team lead or director and so on,
and their next role they request to be an IC,
they insist on being an IC. Yeah, so from the
tech world, that's what informs that. And the
values I had growing up just watching my dad,
he's a researcher, he is a professor, and he
has a blast every day. He refuses to retire,
he's just so enthusiastic about what he does
and he's never aspired to be a chairman,
provost like that. He just loves what he does and
he stayed there. And I just see the joy, the fun.
This episode is brought to you by Gamma,
an entirely new way to present your ideas
powered by AI. If you hate designing slides and
dread that feeling of staring at a blank slide,
Gamma is here to help. Just upload your PRD
and turn it into a beautiful ready-to-present
presentation in seconds. Gamma works with
all types of formats from Google Docs,
PDFs to PowerPoint. You can even drop in a
link to your favorite Lenny's Newsletter post
and turn it into a presentation for your team.
Gamma has become one of the fastest growing AI
web products in the world, adding 20 million
new users just this past year, and is setting
its sights on becoming the modern alternative to
PowerPoint. Whether you have design skills or not,
Gamma can save you hours of time synthesizing
your ideas and shaping your content. Visit
Gamma.app and use promo code Lenny to get a
free month of Gamma Pro. That's G-A-M-M-A.app.
This episode is brought to you by WorkOS. If
you're building a SaaS app, at some point your
customers will start asking for enterprise
features like SAML authentication and SCIM
provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in, making
it fast and painless to add enterprise features
to your app. Their APIs are easy to understand so
that you can ship quickly and get back to building
other features. Today, hundreds of companies
are already powered by WorkOS, including ones
you probably know like Vercel, Webflow and Loom.
WorkOS also recently acquired Warrant, the fine
grain authorization service. Warrant's product
is based on a groundbreaking authorization system
called Zanzibar, which was originally designed
for Google to power Google Docs and YouTube.
This enables fast authorization checks at enormous
scale while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases.
If you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features like
single sign-on SCIM or user management, you should
consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in replacement
for auth zero and supports up to 1 million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
workos.com to learn more. That's workos.com.
So much of that resonates with me. There's
actually a period of my career where I was was
not an IC, no, I wasn't IC, and I was just like,
"I don't want to be promoted any higher. Everyone
I look at above me is just so stressed and I just
don't need this and things are great. Why would I
want to change that?" And I love that you stayed
close to that. I know a lot of things pull people
towards management, which compensation, there's
status, more impact, trying to learning to be
a manager. Is there anything there that's
just pulled you and you've been just like,
"I'm going to give that up and I don't need that,"
or is it or life is just as good as an IC for you?
I won't lie, over the years, despite everything
I said, if somebody who is my same amount of
experience or same cohort gets promoted and
becomes a team lead and makes that decision
and rises up, it does twang in my stomach, it
gets in my ego. I have that moment where I'm
like, " Wait a minute, what about me? And
should I be doing that?" And it makes me
question everything. And then I say to
myself, "Okay, so go for it. Tell your
manager you changed your mind or whatever
it is needs to happen." And then I'm like,
"Well," I kind of get back to the same logic of
I don't actually want that. So if I could push
a button and switch with them, I wouldn't.
But definitely very human at the same time.
For someone that's trying to pursue this path,
trying to avoid these sorts of things and say
just trying to be successful. And as an IC
looking back, is there anything that you've
learned that has helped you be successful
and pursue the thing that makes you happy?
I think the big elephant of the room is
compensation. I think whenever I have
this discussion with friends and colleagues,
that's always the... Well, there's two things,
there's compensation and there's can it
be interesting? Don't you get sick of it,
right? So I think that classic book
drive, motivation comes from autonomy,
mastery and purpose. And I think for me, the IC
role, it definitely is very autonomous. Being
a product manager is one of the most autonomous
roles and most amount of agency you can ask for.
I think mastery, I once heard Mark Keating say
in a workshop, product manager role is one of
those roles where you can just keep doing
it for a really long time because it just
keeps changing. And you can change industries
without having background in it, the situation
changes every time you do it in every different
context, it's just so different and interesting.
And purpose is one that I took for granted in
the past and I learned how important it is. I
think if you feel that you're building something
that you really want to see happen in the world
and you really want to make sure it's done
well, you don't trust anybody else to do it,
you want to be the one to work on it and make
sure that this gets done well in the world
because it matters to you, then I think you're
in a really strong place from that point of view
that really gets you motivated and you want to
be hands-on and it keeps you really focused.
I want to drill into something you said around
compensation and just generally what you've done
to stay down this path. Because I know the
compensation, that's a real thing. Is there
anything you've seen or done that has helped
you be more comfortable with that in terms of
getting the comp you think you deserve being
an IC this long being basically a super IC?
I think first of all, you have to believe
your worth. You have to genuinely believe
and understand that an individual contributor in
product management is worth, can have a really big
scope, really big ownership, really big impact
and matters a lot. And I think the industry is
coming around to that, right? We'll talk a little
bit more about this, but the great flattening of
the last few years, and I've seen talking to
friends who are founders and the founders here
at Riverside are really looking for people really
experienced who are really hands-on. First of all,
we just need people who get stuff done. And
just recognizing that in yourself and believing
that and recognizing that in the industry and
remembering, there's a really good analogy here in
engineering where it really makes sense to all of
us that you shouldn't have to rise into management
in order to increase your compensation, you're
equally or just as valuable not as a manager,
as a domain expert. And that's step one,
really understand that you are really,
really, really valuable as an IC.
I think tactically speaking,
one thing that I've done a few times in different
interview rounds is when it comes to compensation,
you've probably heard the line, "Well, that's a
really high number, but we can't reach it. But
don't worry, we're growing a lot, the product door
is going to grow lot. There's going to be a lot of
opportunities to rise into management, so there's
going to be a lot of opportunities to increase
compensation over time." And that's a classic line
you might hear from a recruiter or hiring manager.
And in those moments, it kind of puts you in a
weird position where it's like, well, you don't
think you're going to rise up, you can't debate
that so well. And what I say in those moments is,
"I'm glad you mentioned that, I actually
have no intention of going into management
or rising up in those ranks, and I know that
you and I know that the industry traditionally
undervalues the IC role so it's really important
for me to have that number now," and that works.
Wow, okay. Very straightforward. So maybe
along those lines, just a final question
on this track is just for people that are
trying to create a space for an IC path at
a company or as a company trying to do this,
anything you suggest they do to make this a
thing for people that actually want to stay
ICs to set this up as a real career path?
Have the titles. I think having good titles that
are clear that you can move up into, first of all,
just creates it as an idea that there is progress.
Creating clear levels and rubric just like you
would for within any level or within any title,
I think saying it out loud, recognizing it. I
think it's just at the end of the day, we all want
respect, we all want to feel that we're growing,
we want to feel that that's recognized. So I
think putting it in words goes a really long way.
So in terms of titles, what are the titles
you find? Is it principal product manager? Is
there other titles you've found helpful? And
how many levels of IC do you find you need?
The ones I've seen on LinkedIn, there's
product manager, senior product manager,
principal product manager. I've seen a
distinguished product manager last year.
Yeah, I think Amazon has that too.
Amazon too, yeah. I think those are the exception,
not the rule, but yeah, I think
putting into words really helps.
Okay, so principal and distinguished,
distinguished is the highest
level you've seen of an ICPM?
I think, or super IC, I guess.
Super IC, and we're going to talk about that.
And then in terms of rubric and career ladder,
basically it's just the same way
you have career ladder for managers,
just have it further go further for ICPMs?
Yeah, I think product is usually the last
department to really just
because smaller, I think.
Yeah. Okay, amazing. Really helpful.
We've talked about this idea of super ICs,
and as you mentioned, there's this been
rise of and shift of flattening of orgs,
as you said, of people hiring more senior
product managers, there's a sense of that,
and companies are expecting more of PMs just doing
the work, not managing their PMs. And I feel like
you're such an interesting prototypical example
of the PMs people want to hire. And with AI,
it's unlocking a whole new lever and opportunity
for a lot of PMs where they in theory can actually
achieve this thing that companies are looking for
them to achieve, which is just get more done. So
any just thoughts along that track of just more
is expected of ICPMs, there's more need for
ICPMs and AI making it easier. What have you seen
there? Where do you think things might be going?
We've seen the last couple years, I think you had
on here Nikhyl Singhal talking about when Facebook
had those really big layoffs that they were biased
towards keeping individual contributor product
managers. Zuckerberg talked about the flattening,
and I've seen here at Riverside during that same
time founders talking about how they're just
really looking for, "Can we just find some really,
really senior experienced people who want
to stay hands-on? That would be the dream,
right?" I also have heard from friends in the
market, the hiring market, that there's just
a lot more experienced people competing for
the same IC roles as a result of all that. So
I think the result of that is being at 10x PM for
example is becoming more and more table stakes,
especially like you mentioned with AI.
That's just the tailwind for all of that.
And we don't have to go too far down this
track, but have you actually experienced
this yourself? Have you found really interesting
ways to leverage AI and become more effective?
Just this week I have an example. My team, I have
one team that's trying to introduce much more
rigorous scrum as it hires a lot more developers.
Part of that is a lot more paperwork as a product
manager in some companies it's a whole role that
they hire just to do that. And what we did is
basically took ChatGPT, told it the format of the
stories and epics and so on, and tried something
where I just dictated and spoke as if I was doing
a kickoff and I just talked naturally and it just
put out all this really, really, really amazing
detailed stories and so on, and just had to edit
it a little bit. So that was a aha moment for me,
like, "Okay, that would've taken either dividing
the team into smaller pieces or multiple
product managers to be able to keep up."
And obviously the next step is we just take
the actual kickoff record that, transcribe that
and feed that in? We're playing around with
that as well. You can imagine what might've
taken 10 years ago, five years ago a director
organization, like a director level organization,
and everybody reporting to that director to
achieve something could probably be achieved with
an IC now. And I think this ties in because the
product career path is going to be even less about
people management and just more and more about
leadership and the core of product manager skills.
This is a really interesting example of how you're
using AI, I want to definitely spend more time
here. Help me understand exactly what you did. So
you had a bunch of projects that you were kicking
off with a bunch of different teams with a PM
leading each one or scrum master leading each one?
Actually, we tried this on one team, but it was a
really big project, like a ton of stories, yeah.
Can you explain what the project is briefly?
Sure. I'll say it's a pretty fundamental change to
the user experience. So it touches on everything.
At Riverside? Okay, man, here we go. I'm
excited. Okay, so you have this big project
you're kicking off to rethink the experience
of Riverside. And normally you're saying you
would've had to write all these one-pagers
and specs of the components of this project,
the different features and product, is that right?
So the high level why we're doing this,
usability studies, the design, the vision,
all that stuff we did without AI, that was me,
director of design, and our founder. But then it
came time for the rubber meets the road, we did
a kickoff in the engineers, everybody's bought
in and everybody's excited and now we need to
really make sure that things are really, really
well-defined and very, very clear and easy for
testing afterwards and just make all that stuff,
the high level stuff really, really specific.
And so that means user stories in JIRA,
in this case for this team, that's how they prefer
to work. And a specific format that they've asked
for and so it's like a story and there's, it's
called like gherkin, "I'm learning this too,
this is new to me. Given this when that then
that," it's really tedious. When it's small,
it's actually really fun to write because it makes
you think. But when you have so many things that
need to change, it's overwhelming and would
either delay the team and there would be the
bottleneck or we just have to split it up.
And what we did is we took that template,
my team lead said, "Hey, this is the template I
would love," I gave to ChatGPT, said, "You're an
expert PM, product owner, scrum master," whatever,
"This is the template. Do you understand?" It's
like, "Yeah, let's go." And then I said, "Well,
actually before we get going, I want to tell you
I'm holding down the dictation button,
used Whisper AI to dictate. And I was like,
"Let me just tell you a little bit more
background," I just started talking to it
like I would for a developer joining the team, and
I just started to talk about why we're doing it
and so on. I was like, "So do you understand
that?" I was like, "Yeah, cool, let's go."
And then I said, "Okay, well the first thing
is we're going to change this area and it's
going to work like this, and it's really
important that this and this happens."
And I just talked super naturally to it just
like I would to a person. And when I was done,
I hit enter and it created that user story in that
format with all those cases that would take me so
long to write. And I would say the thing that we
still really needed a person for was deciding how
to break up this really, really big change into
those stories, what is the logical way to split
it up engineer wise? Which my team lead did. But
once you have that, each one individually worked
really, really well. So I'm now experimenting
with taking the transcript, I tried this actually
experimenting with taking the transcript of
the actual kickoff that we did and that we
recorded on Riverside and how to transcribe,
and I copied it and put it into ChatGPT,
it didn't work as well. So I'm experimenting,
tweaking it to see how far can we push this?
This was awesome, I love that you're sharing
this. So basically you described the project
and all the different features and user stories
and words using Whisper. And do you use Whisper,
is it an app or is it within ChatGPT?
Where do you actually access this?
It's built into ChatGPT's desktop app and mobile
apps if you dictate it that way. I also
have a desktop app on my own that I use,
it's just such a great transcription model.
But it's open source free provided by OpenAI.
Right, it's OpenAI's speech to text system,
and then they're adding voice mode soon like
it's coming out to people so this is going
to be built into ChatGPT soon. Amazing, okay,
so you talk about, "Here's all the things we're
going to be changing in the product," you give
it a template. Where do you give the template?
Is it you put the transcript into ChatGPT with
a prompt of, "Here's the template," or are you
just even still describing that in the recording?
No, the template is something that my team leads,
like, "This is how I'd love
to have these written."
He just says it as part of the transcript?
He sent it to me on Slack. He's like, "This is
how I want it written." So the first thing I did,
I opened a new thread in ChatGPT and I said,
"You're an expert product manager, product owner.
This is the template we want to use for user
stories. Do you understand?" Hit enter. So
it's like, "Cool, I get it." And then I start
to talk about the changes we want to make.
Okay, this is amazing. I could go down this track
all day, but let's shift a little bit. Is there
anything else you found to be really helpful
in having leverage as an ICPM kind of along
these lines, whether it's or not just being the
super IC essentially getting more done as an IC?
So the way I think about this is how you
manage your own time, how you design your days.
How you manage your own time, how you design your
days, your energy, your focus, and then your team
and how you build that culture and those habits to
just give you a lot of leverage as an IC so that
still as one person you can own a lot of scope,
you can influence a lot, you can manage a lot.
So personally for my time, I really believe,
and I think you've written about this as well,
in actively designing your days. And for me, I
really strictly split my days between deep work
and what I call ping pong or ping pong. You can
imagine it's like when, you open Slack and it's
just constant hitting the ball back and forth,
it makes your brain feel like scrambled eggs.
You're not going to be doing any deep thinking
or reading or strategy. So for me, I'm a morning
person and I block off my morning for meetings.
A lot of people give that tip. I go even further
and I don't open Slack before noon.
I've been doing this for eight years.
I don't open Slack at all. It gets really extreme
to the point where if I need to send a message,
it usually fails. I usually open Slack before
noon because I need to send a message and then
I realize all these messages don't need to
be sent before noon. Just because I thought
it at 11 AM doesn't mean I need to send it
at 11 AM. There's no urgency at that level.
So I actually keep a section of my to-do list,
which is when I open Slack, here are the messages
I'm going to send. And I write them as if I'm
about to hit enter in Slack, but they're in
my to-do list. And sometimes if I really, really,
really rare moments, I'll need to check something,
I'll ask the person next to me like, "Hey, can
you go into this channel and just show me that
thing?" Because all their notifications don't
trigger my brain into scrambled eggs again.
That's an awesome tip. And I know
people will hear this and be like,
"There's no way I can do this."
Is your insight is you can?
Yes. Usually when I share this, people are like,
"Well, what if something urgent happens and people
are looking for you?" This has happened twice a
year. You realize how not urgently needed the PM
role ever is. And first of all, over time people
really respect it. They learn that this is how you
work and they come to really respect this.
And second, the key people that I work
with have my phone number and I
tell them, "Feel free to call me
at any time if I'm not on Slack. If you really
need a response, just call me, WhatsApp me,
whatever it takes." And first of all, it's like
a barrier. It's not like a quick message. So it
really is only for urgent stuff. And twice a year
I'll get a WhatsApp message from my manager, from
my team lead. "Hey, something urgent is happening
in Slack. We really need you." And then I'll open
Slack and I'll violate my rule. It's totally fine,
but it's so rare that the system works for me.
Amazing. Okay. Anything else along those
lines? This is an awesome little tip.
I personally keep a weird habit. I realized it's a
weird habit. I call it product scrapbooking where
I have this massive notion database of every
opportunity, big or small that's ever come up.
And when a piece of evidence out in the world
comes in, it could be like a support ticket or
a CSM sends a gong call or there's a really great
Slack thread with an amazing brainstorm happening
and ideas, piece of data, whatever it is, right?
I'll file it. I actively take a screenshot or
whatever it is, I file it and I start to
cluster these in this really messy notion.
And the reason I do this is that I've learned
that we have these roadmaps and strategies
that seem linear, but life and customers and
insights are not. So when the time does come
around to work on that thing and that opportunity
comes up, I can pull up that notion and I already
have a bunch of really in the weeds real
world clues to start with and even persuade
people that we should dig deeper into this.
Or for example, another advantage is that if
I'm on a conversation with a person from sales or
CSM from customer success and they'll mention a
request, I can open that up and I'm like, "Yeah,
this is actually this client and that client and
that client also mentioned that." And you see
in their face that they feel heard. "You've been
listening all this time, you've been writing this
down?" I think that's really important as well.
I love these tips. I love product scrapbooking
as a term. It makes so much sense and it's just
immediately clear what you're going to be doing
and I love how simple the approach there is. Is
there anything else along those lines or is there
something you want to share around this other
bucket that I think you hinted at of helping your
team set you up for success and get more done?
I believe in cultivating very self-reliant teams.
And I think that's really key to having a lot
more leverage as an IC, being able to manage
multiple teams if needed on much bigger areas of
the product. I think the key of that is having
this mindset that product isn't a role, it's
a team. And I read a quote once by Ebi Atawodi
and she's worked on Netflix and Uber and she's
super experienced and she says something like,
"It's not about waiting for products, product
said this or that or waiting for product. We're
all product." And I really try to have that
as the cornerstone of a culture of any team
that I am on. I had a new teammate come up to me
recently, he just joined and he was on engineering
and he came up to me excitedly and he's like,
"I found a case that you didn't think about."
And I was like, "Okay, awesome. But hold on,
let's talk about language. Product is not a role,
it's a team." And whatever it is, I don't even
know what it is, but everything that we own,
both design was involved, engineering was
super involved. Yes, I was there and it,
let's call it, "Hey, I found a way to improve the
product, or Hey, I found something that we didn't
think about." It's really, really important.
So first of all, that language, that culture,
that it's not like this hub and spoke model
and the PM is at the center and making all
those decisions and passing things through.
So first of all, that's like a fundamental
mindset. It's really important for each team
to have to be more high leveraged as an IC.
The second thing is personally to seek to not be
needed, but be valuable. The difference is like if
you think about your day as a product manager,
look for situations where is there a game of
telephone that's constantly passing through me?
Are there a lot of situations where clearly you're
the bottleneck, like your attention, your ability
to get to something is the bottleneck and a lot of
people are waiting on you? Do you find a lot of
communication is happening, direct messages with
you instead of public channels for the team? Are
a lot of working meetings just like you and one
other person on the team instead of maybe two
or three? Not too many either. All of those are
opportunities where you can create a different
situation where a culture on the team, where
people are figuring things out between themselves
and maybe involving you at the very end.
So one of the things that I really put a lot of
energy into is really encouraging people to get
conversations out of direct messages and into
channels. This is a really important way to
cultivate people with just working together and
figuring things out in between one another. And
anytime somebody sends me a direct message, I
say, " This is a great question. Can you please
put it in this channel with the team? I'll answer
there", but it's really important for me that any
decisions we make are transparent, that it's easy
to find it later, that there's a few other people
who should probably chime in if they want to.
And this could be at the team level. I worked at
a company that had a really, really big customer
success organization. They'd constantly find you
as a PM and just DM you these questions. And I'd
say, "Great question. Put it in this really big
channel." And I give a reason, so that way other
people on the customer success team can search
the channel and find the answer later. It can
help other people. And if you do this enough,
it becomes a snowball effect because other people
on the team will see that other people are posting
in public channels and feel more comfortable
with it. And that just becomes a chain reaction.
Such awesome advice. It's so counterintuitive also
I think to a lot of product managers where you're
basically saying remove yourself as a dependency,
delegate more, empower everyone in your team,
have engineers come up with ideas, have
them write things, one page respects,
things like that. Become less valuable almost,
which I think is not the natural tendency.
Become obsolete.
That's the dream. No? That's my dream.
I love that. But if I think about trying to do
this, I think you need a real confidence as a
PM and comfort with chaos. A lot of times PMs,
they want to be the hub because the more they can
control the narrative, the more they can control
what people see. PCX pinging an engineer like,
"Oh my God, they're just going to start
working on this thing. And then we have
this roadmap. We have priorities. What are
they?" How do you manage that challenge?
Yeah, there's a great phrase I heard a mentor
once say, which is culture of a process. Process
is important. And sometimes you need to process
to scaffold until you build the culture. But I
think it's like you got to view the team as this
asset you're building. This culture is an asset
that you're building and you're investing in it
and you're cultivating it and you want to build
something that's stronger than... That's a great
example, a CX person or just directly messaging an
engineer or just asking for something. You want to
build something that's resilient to that. That's
the real product that you're building as a PM
I think is the team that builds the product,
and is resilient to all these things.
It doesn't happen overnight. It's not going
to happen in the first quarter that the team has
formed. But it happens over time gradually with
little messages and little interactions and
positive feedback and asking people to work
a little bit differently and giving them a reason
why and building trust. And I think that success
in my job is to build a very self-reliant
team that's very resilient to all those
things that I would otherwise, like you said,
to keep me up at night really make me worried.
You shared an example of how you do that. These
little, I call these micro interactions. So much
of a PM is these micro interactions with team
members, which is so much harder now in a remote
world where you can't just walk by and just do
a little chat. The chat you shared I think is an
awesome example where the language was a really
powerful shift in how this person thought. Is
there anything else along those lines you could
share of how to create this sort of culture?
One thing that I try to do is when somebody takes
something that would be my job and does that,
whether it's on the design side, they
lean in more or on the engineering side,
they lean in more people bring ideas or they say,
"Hey, I took the liberty of doing this." It could
be as small as something bureaucratic or as big as
an idea or a suggestion. I just shower them with
positivity. I just show them just how excited I
am that they did that. I just want that to happen
again and them to feel even more bold. And just
like when somebody takes something off your plate,
when somebody does kind of the PM, what
you think is like, that's PM thinking,
what are you doing? Right? Just really want
them to feel that that is extremely welcome.
And I imagine there's a bunch of coaching you
do to help engineers, designers, researchers,
data, people think the way you think almost, to
become more PM-y. Is that a part of this too?
I don't know if I would call it coaching. Like
I said, it's just a lot of little behaviors.
So one thing I try to do along those lines is
when there's something that's on me to do for
someone or the next logical step, I try to do
that live with them. So if somebody asked me
a question about, "Hey, what does the data show
about this? If we went that direction?" I'm like,
"I don't know. Let's find out." Instead
of saying, "Hey, I'll get back to you,
let's open Mixpanel, let's play around with this."
And I don't tell them, "Hey, it'd be great if" I
just show them how easy it was. Like, "Hey, if I
could figure this out, this Fisher Price data for
PMs, you could totally figure this out." That's
what I'm trying to imply by showing it. Or if
it's create a JIRA ticket just to make something
happen quickly and document it, I am like, "Hey,
let's just do this together on the call right
now and make sure I get it right." And what you
see is over time, some people more than others,
but they start to just naturally want to do that
themselves. Ask you for that access, start to
do those things. "Hey, I did this and I wrote
the JIRA ticket for it. I did this and I did
the data analysis" and that grows over time.
You actually have a course that
you're launching or is out now or
about to launch that teaches a lot
of these things. Talk about that.
Yeah. This is a passion project I'm working
on with Maven, the learning platform. It's
a course called Build Your Personal
PM Productivity System. And it really
goes super deep and super practical into these
topics, exactly like how to design your time,
how to manage yourself, how to manage your
emotions, how to cultivate self-reliant teams,
how to give feedback and create a product org
that puts less overhead on you as a PM. And yeah,
the idea is to just take all these topics and
just make this really, really, really hands-on.
Awesome. I feel like I wish I had this.
And I feel like you're such a great person
to teach this because as an IC, this is how you
succeed. This is the thing that makes it hard to
stay as an IC. And again, with the rise of
AI almost creating a space for super ICs,
as we talked about, it feels like this kind of
stuff is going to be more and more important. So
we'll definitely link to that in the show notes.
I want to shift to a different topic. I think
you've kind of shown people this already,
but you have a lot of very contrarian
opinions about a lot of things. You see things
a little differently, and there's a few other
things that I've seen you talk about that I
want to spend a little time on. So I'm just
going to go through a few of them and just share
whatever you want to share on this. Sound good?
Sure.
Okay, cool. The first is you have
this phrase that, or this concept
that every tech company basically
is just two departments that matter.
So yeah, over time working at a bunch of
hyper growth companies, I've started to
notice that there's some departments
that are the reason that company won
the market. And also started to realize that,
and this is sometimes true of the department
that I'm in product, that even if product did
a 10X job, it wouldn't be a 10X outcome for
the company over the decade. But for example,
it could be if marketing did a 10X job, the
company would have a 10X outcome over the decade.
And I started to observe this over the years,
and I noticed it's roughly usually two things.
Two companies, sorry, two departments. It's
roughly two departments that this boils down to
in each company. So I'll just make this really
concrete without naming names. The companies that
worked at, the two departments at one company
was product design and support. If those two
departments were 10X, then the company would win.
Another company was data accuracy and customer
success. Another company, the thing that made
them win in the market was trust slash brand, like
a trusted brand and payments. And another company
that I worked at looking back, what made them
win in the market was marketing and engineering,
like scalability. So product sometimes is on
this list. So one of the companies I worked at,
like I mentioned, product design product,
if that department does 10X impact,
then the company will succeed 10X in the
market. But in my career, it mostly hasn't
been product. Product has to do a good job, but
it's not the biggest lever for that company,
even though it's a tech product company.
And I think this really crystallized for
me when I finally worked in a company where
product is that department. You feel that.
Okay, so the $64,000 question,
whatever billion question is,
how do you know which two departments matter most?
First of all, look at what really drives the
growth. What's the growth model? What are the
levers? Ask those questions. How does it work? Ask
officially and ask as part of your back channeling
and reference checking. And the second thing is
if you're really seriously checking out a company,
evaluating a company, truly understand
that customer and what are they actually
paying for in this industry? What is the
real product? What's the real value that
they're getting? Clearly they're paying for
a product or a service, but beyond that,
what are they actually paying for? Ask those
questions and I think that'll make it clear.
I think maybe one trick here is just see what
team drives growth. Oftentimes it's going to
be sales, oftentimes it's going to be product
experiments they're running, could be marketing.
Exactly. And that department, whatever role
you have, if you're in that department for
that company, that's going to be your career
defining work. That's why it's so worth it.
You're going to attract the best
colleagues or careers are going to
have a step function jump. It's
a totally different experience.
And this is when people say a company is
engineering driven, product driven, marketing
driven, sales driven. This is exactly what they
mean, which team matters most to the company
because they're driving the most growth. So if
you're a salesperson on a sales driven company,
you'll be valued more highly than being a
product person at a sales driven company.
Yeah. When I graduated from college, I
had a friend give me advice. He was like,
"Don't be a finance guy at a tech
company and don't be a tech guy
at a finance company." This was 2009. So anyways.
Yeah, and I think this is where a lot
of people struggle with their PM at a
company that is very not product driven,
and you read all these books about being
empowered and having agency and autonomy,
and instead, they're just the team that,
they're just feature factories because other
teams are running the show and we don't need
your opinions. We know how to grow this
thing. Just build this thing for us.
And here's the thing. That's okay. That's what
that company needs to succeed in the market. You
think about the Olympics, this is analogy that
came to mind recently. It's like, let's say you
can think how a marathon runner looks and how
a swimmer looks. They look very different. You
can spot them in the row of athletes. And
if you imagine product being a lap muscle,
that's product department, you can be
a lap muscle for a marathon runner. You
can be one for a swimmer. And a marathon
runner needs one and it needs to work. But
where do you want to be that lap muscle.
On the swimmer, on the marathon runner?
I love that analogy.
This episode is brought
to you by Eppo. Eppo is a next generation A-B
testing and feature management platform built
by alums of Airbnb and Snowflake for modern
growth teams. Companies like Twitch, Miro,
ClickUp and DraftKings rely on Eppo to
power their experiments. Experimentation
is increasingly essential for driving growth, and
for understanding the performance of new features.
And Eppo helps you increase experimentation
velocity while unlocking rigorous, deep analysis
in a way that no other commercial tool does.
When I was at Airbnb, one of the things that I
loved most was our experimentation platform
where I could set up experiments easily,
troubleshoot issues, and analyze performance
all on my own. Eppo does all that and more,
with advanced statistical methods that can
help you shave weeks off experiment time and
accessible UI for diving deeper into performance
and out-of-the-box reporting that help you
avoid annoying prolonged analytic cycles.
Eppo also makes it easy for you to share
experiment insights with your team, sparking
new ideas for the A-B testing flywheel. Eppo
powers experimentation across every use case,
including product growth, machine learning,
monetization, and email marketing. Check out
Eppo at getEppo.com/lenny and 10X your experiment
velocity. That's getEppo. com/lenny.
Let's move on to another, let's say hot
take that you have. You have this kind
of phrase that there's a big difference
between book smart decision making and street
smart decision making. What's that about?
Yeah. This one comes out of a lot of mistakes I've
made myself and seen around me as well. So I'm so
guilty of this. Book smart decision making as a
PM is all the stuff we talk about all the time.
That's data, design, technology strategy,
frameworks, all that stuff. And it's really
important and it's why we're strong at it. Street
smart decision making is taking all that and then
seeing something from somebody else's point of
view. This goes beyond empathy. I'll tell you what
I mean. It's like giving the customer's perception
just as much weight as you would to logic.
A really big example of this, and I won't name
the company. I was at this company that changed
the structure of the pricing and the change
was actually not meant to make more money. It
was meant to unblock a payments roadmap and enable
all these feature requests that were stuck behind
this fundamental change. And in preparing for
this, the company did a lot of analyses and just
made sure that this was actually really good for
customers and that this would only, the number-
This would only ... The numbers and the
predictions and the models are like,
"This is a positive thing." I know all the people
that were involved were the most empathetic,
did this because they really cared about this
customer, genuinely. I've never seen people,
at the executive level, at the product level,
at the data level, these are the people who
really genuinely wanted the best for this customer
and they rolled out the change, and in reality,
bottom line, it was a big revolt on the internet.
It was a big deal and it was rolled back.
And the bottom line why there was such a
gap between everything ... And actually,
by the way, all the analyses proved that to be
correct. All the models, all the predictions,
everything played out the numbers as predicted.
The problem was the perception, the narrative
behind it, what it looked like when you've logged
into the product and you saw only the negative,
but you didn't see all the positive because the
positive was what happened 30 days later and you
saw the negative immediately. A lot of things like
that.I would've made exactly the same mistake. Not
a criticism. I would've probably made more
mistakes, but that's what opened my mind to,
oh my God, you have to really think more than
just logical, more than just utilitarian.
Another example of this is there's a company
I worked at where all the features that were
on a higher plan were invisible to the
lower plans just because everything was
built really fast and there was time
to make them visible so people could
upgrade. So we got that ready and we
did this and we're about to release it,
and we realized tomorrow morning a bunch of
customers are going to log into the product
and there's all these features that they've been
asking us for because they didn't know that we
have them, because they were locked and only on
higher plan. Suddenly, from their point of view,
the company built everything they'd asked for
and all of it requires paying more money. How
are they going to feel? And so, we didn't roll it
out that way. We rolled it out in smaller pieces
and in different ways because we realized that's
going to feel really if you think about it. But,
practically speaking, or theoretically speaking,
we didn't upsell anything. These were all things
we already had built. Everything's above board.
That's the perception of what was going to happen.
And that second example, is there anything
that triggered that recognition or is it
just people sitting around being like, "Oh,
what about this?" Because the first example,
you had a great point where customers were
telling you this isn't necessarily what they want,
and you're like, "No, no, no, you're going
to do great. Trust us, it's going to be
really good for you." But there's feedback,
at least, in the safety examples or something
that's like ... What I'm asking about is how can
people develop the skill? I love this advice.
I think that intuition came from spending time
in the customer community and support tickets
and just noticing smaller versions of that
that people have feedback on. And you kind
of start to see what our customers,
at the time, what they would tend to,
what their suspicions always were. They're very
trigger-happy to blame the company for XYZ,
and if you see enough raw data from
customers or if you get on a customer
call and they mention nickel and diming and
all these things, you start to understand
this is the target persona. This is how they
think. This is what they're sensitive to.
It's interesting because at
Airbnb there was a lot of that,
a lot of hosts being really upset about changes
constantly. Everything that changed there. And
usually the changes are to help the business
in some way, help the guests in many ways,
and it's always this balance of we got to
do this. This is just the future. Is there
anything there, just real quick, of just
learning when we got to do this anyway,
even though they're going to be versus like,
"Oh, [inaudible 00:50:12] let's roll this back."
Yes.
Okay.
Yes, for sure. This is just what I'm talking
about is to recognize it. What you do with
it is a different thing. I joke when we do
changes to redesigns or changes to the UX
and we're going to get inevitable complaints. I
just tell my team, "We're going to deploy this
and we're all going to log out of social media
for two weeks." And that's the strategy. That's
extreme. We don't actually do that, of course,
but that's what we wish we could do sometimes.
And the insight there is just social
media will amplify one person's loud
voice versus how many people actually
are upset about this? How important are
they to the business? It's like, don't
pay attention to the loudest person.
Also, I think the key there is the two weeks,
because if people are still complaining after
two weeks, then there's something here.
But in those two weeks there's going to
be a lot of feedback that comes from a
resistance to change that they're going
to adapt to and won't be able to remember
what was before. But sometimes you make
mistakes and if there's a real mistake,
you'll know about it for a long time.
And obviously you'll pay attention to support
tickets and all that stuff. It's just-
Obviously, a disclaimer, during those two weeks,
we look at every support ticket and we look
at everything on social media, for sure.
Okay.
Two more examples about the street smart
book smart that are really important.
Oh, please, let's do it. Let's do it.
This has happened twice to me where
I worked on a team that made a very
logical UX change and quickly found
out that we ruined the sales demo. So,
for the users of the product,
the experience became a little
bit smoother. It was an optimization. It wasn't
something critical. But then, for the sales demo,
it communicated the value less. It was harder
for people as to really understand in one glance.
So, a lot of times, this comes from taking
something that's very visual and making it
very efficient and small, so you might gain fewer
clicks, but it'll make it harder for the sales
team to communicate and for that ah-ha moment to
happen on a call, to the point where we made this
change and then salespeople would send me Gong
link recordings in the past and in the current
demos and just show me the difference and it
would pain me to watch these. And I was like,
"Oh, we got to fix this. People aren't getting
the value, how they even going to experience it?"
Okay. I know that you have a couple more hot
takes that I wanted to make sure we have time
for. One that I love that I agree with, and
it's kind of the thesis of this podcast almost,
which is that there's no right way
to get things done in a product,
team, or in a business, in spite of what you may
read online. I'd love to hear your take here.
Yeah, I didn't always understand this. In fact, I
moved continents because I had professional FOMO,
so I moved from Israel to San
Francisco because I believed,
and actually a lot of people had that feeling
that whatever we're doing here in Silicon Valley,
they know how to work. That's the big
leagues. And I got to work shoulder to
shoulder with people who came from Apple, YouTube,
Salesforce, Facebook, Slack, Amazon, Stripe.
I got to work with the people who came from these
companies I admired so much and I came over with
a conclusion that we're all just making it up as
we go along in tech, we're all just improvising,
as we should. That's the beauty of it. Every
situation is different, every market is different,
every company is different. What it
takes to win is different. And so,
myself, I've had phases where I've been this
zealot of everything has to be outcomes driven,
and then I've gone to let's just ship as much as
possible and figure it out and everything needs to
be A-B tested and quarterly planning has to work
this way and should do scrum or don't do scrum.
And they just realized it's not that simple.
It's about figuring out the problem at hand and
optimizing for that and having an open mind and
just understanding that we're all improvising.
That's really powerful and I think
people may hear this and be like,
"Yeah, I think I get it." I guess for people that
are just ... Everyone's reading my newsletter,
reading all the newsletters, listening to
podcasts, listening to how people work, what's
your advice? What should think, in your mind,
when they read about how another company runs?
My personal story, one of the things that
happened when I landed in San Francisco,
I really felt like an imposter. I was
like, "Okay, wow, everybody else here
really knows how to work and I need to
learn from them." And six months later,
I found myself giving talks and writing blog posts
about how to work, blog posts that were being used
in like Reforged courses and all that, advising
people and sharing. And that's when it hit me.
That's the beauty of this industry is that that
can happen because everything is changing so fast.
How did I get there? I was just on a team doing
something really difficult and interesting in a
very unique way, and that's how you learn. That's
the real way to learn. My manager Adam Fisherman,
at the time, told me something related to this,
which is like, "The best networking is just to
do really good work at a successful company and
everything else will work out." So I think the
same goes for learning. The best learning is
to just do really good work at a really good
company with really good people and solve problems
that have never been solved before in this way,
which will inevitably happen. That's what
we're all doing. And everything else will
work out. You'll be the one writing
the blog posts, not just reading them.
Such important advice. So kind of the takeaway
here is just if you want to become much better,
if you want to be the one sharing
advice versus the one reading advice,
easier said than done, but the advice
is work at a company doing interesting,
hard things, driving impact, growing, being
successful, and that's how you level up.
Yeah.
I love that.
That's the best way.
Yeah. And again, easier said than
done. Not everyone can join an awesome,
high-flying tech startup. Interestingly,
you did this in Israel, right? Away
from the core of Silicon Valley, so you can
find great places outside of Silicon Valley.
Absolutely.
Great. Okay, so I know that you wanted to
spend a bunch of time in Failure Corner,
which I love. It's this recurring segment
on this podcast where folks share times
they failed in their career and things
they've learned from those experiences,
and you wanted me to carve out meaningful time
here, which tells me that you've had a lot of
these experiences, for better or worse.
So, what I'm thinking is let's just go
through a few of these stories that you think
might be helpful to people to hear about times
things didn't go great and what you learned
from those experiences. How does that sound?
Yeah. It's really important for me to share
this, I think. During low points in my career,
having someone share with me a failure
story just really helped me understand
that that's part of it and I'm
not alone. You browse LinkedIn,
you see these incredible profiles
with these incredible pedigrees
and what you don't see ... It gives you this
sense that everybody's just had a smooth sailing
and everything's going great, and everybody's been
here long enough, has had a ton of failure stories
and a ton of low points and self-doubt. So, it's
really meaningful for me to just talk about this.
Let's do it. Let's get into it. Let's get real.
I'll say this, twice I've wasted an entire
quarter of a growth team's time because of
my poor use of user research. First time, I can
look back, and after 12 failed A-B tests ... 12
failed A-B tests set us on the right path and
got us to revisit our hypothesis, but if I had
only spent more time with the customer, and this
was the kind of A-B testing that people say, "No,
you can't do user research. You can't ask somebody
how a button's going to affect their purchasing."
But if I had spent time with the customer to just
understand who they are, what motivates them,
how they got there, why they're paying, all that
stuff, I would understand that not every checkout
process is the same psychology as Groupon or
Amazon or Booking.com. So, the things that work on
those sites work not just because people are the
same everywhere, but they work because people are
in the same mindset. For Groupon, for example,
Amazon is different, Booking.com is different,
and what you're working on, why people are buying
in this situation that I was in was so different.
They had so much motivation over such a long
period of time. They had constant reminders
naturally in their lives that they were happy to
get and the things that didn't work were all the
things that worked that Groupon and Booking and
Amazon, all these e-commerce sites did, those
were not relevant. And we tried all those things
and they fell flat. The moment we realized that,
and it clicked for us, all these A-B tests
that should have printed money, did nothing.
Once we realized that, then we really started to
increase conversion and it was a super successful
team. But man, I look back and if I just used more
qualitative research, even though it was an area
that traditionally you don't use qualitative
research, I could have saved so much time.
It's also a great reminder of just not assuming
wins that work at another company will win for
you, which I think everyone's like, "Yeah, I
know that." But I think people don't know that.
I think they often, "Oh, look at this. Amazon's
killing it with this feature. If we add it,
we're going to win so hard." And so
this is a great reminder. Don't just
take stories from others. This is something
[inaudible 01:00:54] actually talks about
a lot is don't take stories from other
companies as gospel. You're a company.
There's so many things that are not the
same. Awesome. What else else do you got?
The second example of that is I was building
a referral program and we made a user research
plan and we ended up only executing half of it,
which means we talked to the people who were
already using it successfully, and we decided to
skip talking to the people who should use it but
didn't. And we're like, "Yeah, we get it. It's
probably the same feedback." We were in a rush
for a lot of other reasons. There was a lot
of pressure, just unrelated reasons and just
decided that, "Okay, we have enough information.
We don't need to spend more time. Let's start
shipping." And that was a huge mistake as well.
Just spent so much time building something that
didn't work. And yeah, I think my lesson there
is the reasons that got me to hurry and make that
decision with not as much data were reasons that
I just kind of took people's word for stuff. I
didn't think as first principles as I should and
I really caved into the time pressure. So, yeah.
It's like [inaudible 01:02:11] therapy. Just
letting it all out. This is great. And so
far our recurring theme is spend a little more
time on the user research, talk to more customers.
Again, something we always hear, but a lot of
people are like, "Ah, user research. I don't
need that." And what we're hearing here would've
saved your team months and quarters, potentially.
Yeah, each of those wasted an entire quarter.
Oh, geez. All right, cool. All
right, what else? What else we got?
I have, three times, been a hair away from
getting fired. And what I mean by that is a
senior executive has come to me and said, "You are
a hair away from getting fired." And one of them,
there were changes that the head of product
really wanted to make and I felt strongly
that it shouldn't be made, and I voiced that
directly, candidly, personally, and repeatedly,
and then we had that conversation and a colleague
told me, "Listen, look at it this way. If you
trust the leadership team to adapt if something's
not working." I said, "Yeah, I trust them."
"Well, what they need from you is just to rely
on you that you're going to be with them even
if [inaudible 01:03:29] the disagreeing come in,
that's what they need from you. If you're right,
they'll adapt. If you're wrong, then great. You
learned something. Product work got better." So,
the most important thing was there's a song, a
lyrics that goes, "You got to give in to win."
It wasn't about being right, it was about just
being supportive and letting things fix themselves
instead of ... So, that was that moment. Literally
that was the conversation. The second moment,
bigger story, but I was on a group that my manager
and I, we just weren't a fit. And that happens.
It's really important to share that happens.
It's common. It's somebody I respect deeply and
has done amazing things and I still respect them
and we didn't work well together. And the next
step was, okay, well I guess it's time to let me
go. His manager was like, "Hey, before we let you
go, I want you to stay at this company and let's
find you another group to work in." I was like,
"Okay." He's like, "Just finish the initiatives
you're on. Don't start new ones. The quarterly
planning is coming up. Sit in all the meetings,
look for opportunities, and things will work out."
And I did that and I didn't find an opportunity
that I was excited about and my initiatives
wound down and I didn't know ... Okay, well what's
going to happen? And then there was a group where
actually three PMs left at the same time. One went
on maternity leave, one got an offer from Feng,
and one had to start an emergency tiger team
for their area of expertise. And this director,
he filled two of the roles, one internal hire,
one external hire, and there was one more role.
I reached out to him and he is
like, "Yeah, great. Come put your
desk next to mine. We'll just work on a few
projects together, get to know each other."
And I could tell after a few weeks that, even
though we'd been getting to know each other,
he was still interviewing for that third
role. And I realized that something was
stuck. And at the same time, the director who
had reached out and said, "Hey, please stay at
this company. You'll find something," called
me with a very different tone. He is like,
"Listen, you can't just float around without
a role. If you don't find something soon,
we're going to have to let
you go." And he was right.
So I found myself in this situation and
I actually reached out to a friend, Gai
Peleg. He's a friend and a mentor. I actually met
him through the [inaudible 01:06:14] community.
Oh, amazing.
Yeah, he's here in Israel. We got coffee and
he told me, "Listen. Clearly you have nothing
to lose. There's probably an elephant in
the room. This new director is wondering
why'd you leave this older group? He's
not opening, he's not broaching the topic,
so it's up to you to do it." And I was like,
"Okay, what do I say?" He's like, "Well, what
would you say to him if you didn't have to edit
yourself? You didn't have to censor yourself."
And I told Gai, "Well, this is what actually
happened. This is what I believe. This is what
I could have done better." And he's like,
"Dude, that's totally fine to share. You
should share that. Word for word, just say
that." So, the next day, I took the director
aside and we had this conversation. I shared
vulnerably just like, "Here's what I think I
messed up. Here's what I think. It wasn't under
my control." And that conversation, just the vibe
changed. I could feel like a weight off our
shoulders. It really felt like we got closer.
Two days later, I was part of the group. I joined
the group. I did some really awesome work there.
That's such a powerful lesson right there of just
opening up and being vulnerable and just sharing
what you're actually feeling. And this has come up
a couple of times in the podcast. It's what brings
people closer. You think being vulnerable and
showing weakness makes people think less of you,
but almost always they think more of you because
they didn't realize what they were doing. They
didn't realize what you're going through.
You kind of think they're reading your mind.
Yeah, we've all been through that. It doesn't
look like it. When you see someone you think
is successful, that you admire. You look at
somebody's LinkedIn profile, you look at their
resume, you look at their bio. It doesn't look
like that, but we've all been through all of it.
And most times, folks don't know what you're
feeling or going through, and so, just sharing,
"Here's what I'm seeing, here's what I'm feeling.
Here's why things maybe aren't working for me."
Goes a long way. Amazing. These are awesome
stories. What else? Where else have you failed?
I've single-handedly tanked new payments
for a whole week for a company I worked for.
It was a well-meaning change. It was super
logical. It was kind of streamlined. And I
violated my own framework for when do you run
A-B tests. I even wrote a blog post about this
and I violated that and I was like, "Oh,
there's no downside here. We don't need to
measure this. This just kind of makes things
way smoother." And then I get a call from
marketing and they're like, "Why are none of our
campaigns converting?" Listen to your own advice.
Run A-B tests sometimes.
Run A-B tests sometimes. If you're
dealing with really sensitive
flows that have big downsides, even
if you think logically in your mind,
there's no reason there should be a downside
here. If the stakes are really high, yeah ...
There should be a downside here?
Great.
Yeah, if the stakes are really high.
Yeah.
All right. What else?
I have some stories. I don't know if they're
failure stories, but they're like wild west-
Let's do it. Let's do it.
That's what it feels like, one time I completely
disobeyed quarterly planning. My team was told to
do one thing and we just said, "No, we're going
to do something else." It's not as dramatic as it
sounds. It was like, "Hey, we really, really
believe that this is an opportunity and if
we delay this, there's going to be a really
nonlinear cost, opportunity cost to this and
we really should do this." I'm like, "No, you
should still work on this." We're like, "Okay,
what if we made it a really small team and it
was just for one quarter," and then, "Fine,
okay, we have built that capital to be able to
do that." But I remember your W framework post,
I love that, and I don't know what letter
that would be, but that's how that you got-
You go up to the side, split it off in
two, make it a Y. But most importantly,
did it work? Was that a good
idea? Was that a right call?
Yeah, it was a right call. It's become a way
bigger team today and yeah, I still read press
releases and blog posts from the company where
it's clearly that team's work continues so yeah.
Amazing. Excellent.
I got lucky though.
Yeah. All right. It sounds like.
Again, this is just like-
Wild West.
... Wild West. PM is no less wild than
life itself. I've pulled an April Fools
prank on an executive team that resulted in
my CEO seeing me... the next time he saw me,
just looked me in the eye, said,
"You Tal," and walked away.
Can you describe the prank?
So the prank was... I'll say, first of all, the
best April Fools pranks are the ones that touch
just ever so gently on people's biggest
fears at that time. So in a work context,
whatever somebody's biggest strategic fear is
that quarter or that March of that year, whatever
people are talking about, you just have to touch
it a little bit, they'll do the rest of the work.
So this company, there's this really big debate
about internationalization and should we do that,
and there's a big trade-off to doing it and other
things we could be doing with the same resources.
And this was just on everybody's minds, especially
the leadership team. And it was March, so my buddy
and I, also at the company, we decided what would
be people's biggest fears would be that a really
big company would launch the same thing in Europe.
And we created not just a fake screenshot,
not just fake news, we created a fake domain name
website publication. It was really detailed. We
really invested a lot in it, and of this German
website, and we made up a tech arm of Der Spiegel.
We called it Spiegel Tech. We bought the domain,
I'm probably incriminating myself by saying this,
and then what we did is we knew that if we
had sent that link on the 1st of April to
the executive team, nobody would believe
it. So what we did is every executive on
leadership team has that senior report that they
really trust. So we got all of them in on it,
and the link would come from them and each of
them took it further. The senior engineer who was
really critical to the company, he created a fake
recruiting poaching email. If I recall, I think
the legal counsel created a fake cease and desist.
We just went all out and this was on a Saturday so
we ruined the executive team Saturday, they had an
emergency call. It was a Saturday. We ruined the
executive team Saturday. And every time that we
decided that a particular executive had suffered
enough, depending when they woke up and how long
they had been dealing with us, we would let them
in on it, let them into the private channel and
ha ha. So Monday rolls around, CEO sees me, "You,
Tal." "Great. I'm still employed." And I hear
later that day that the leadership team had
their Monday meeting and somebody mentioned that
even though that was a prank, it really got me
thinking. And then the CTO of the company goes,
"Wait, what do you mean prank?" And it dawns on
him and he just gets up, throws down his jacket
and walks out of the room. So we forgot to tell
him. He had to stew with that the whole weekend.
So yeah, sometimes something goes too far.
And that is well executed. Oh my god. It actually
reminds me at Airbnb when I was leading a lot of
the April Fool's jokes year after year, and one
of the best ones we did was we launched, it's
basically we did the opposite of what you did. We
launched AirBrb, which was a desk sharing service,
and we made a whole launch video. We announced it
as a new product, AriBrb and the idea is you go
get lunch and you can, "I'll be right back," and
then your desk can be rented out for 20 minutes.
For 20 hours.
And we had a whole website and we
had amazing video launching it,
and basically it was the opposite. All the
desk sharing companies got freaked out.
Oh no.
Because they though we were legit.
It's the greatest fear, yeah,
Yeah, exactly.
You don't have to do too much. Yeah.
Yeah. And the good news is they
quickly realized it was not real,
but we probably led to some calls, some board
calls. Okay, this was awesome. Any other stories?
I've had thousands of people tag my CEO on
Twitter calling on him to fire me. This was
by accident. But yeah, I was actually on
vacation and I got bored and I was like,
"I haven't logged into Twitter. I haven't posted
anything in Twitter for a while. What's going on
on Twitter?" I see that the notifications number
is maxed out. It's 999 plus or whatever. I was
like, "Wait, what?" And I click the notifications
tab and I see the first tweet is, "Has @ceohandle
fired @talraviv yet? And I saw that that has
a ton of retweets and I keep scrolling down. I
start to piece together the story and there was
a change, the pricing change earlier I said had
an uproar and the Internet was up in arms about
this. And somebody found a blog post from a year
earlier because Brian Balfour interviewed me
about an onboarding experiment that we did.
And part of that interview I shared that
at this company, we'd rather have fewer
customers where we make a bigger impact
on their lives than a lot of customers,
that we make a smaller impact, and explain
the logic and the product principles. That
was really core to the mission of the company.
And somebody took a very limited screenshot of
that to prove that know Tal Raviv hates poor
people or something. And that screenshot went
viral and that those tweets got embedded on like
NPR and Washington Post, and that was a little
nerve-racking. I wasn't fired because I actually
wasn't connected to that. I wasn't on that. I
really felt bad that the PR team, marketing team
and all that, I reached out to them and was like,
"I'm so sorry. You guys are working overtime
because of my big mouth." And they're like,
"Don't worry. This is happening to everybody
at the company right now. Everybody's having...
People are digging stuff up, unrelated
stuff." But yeah, that's stuff that happens.
What a life you've led, Tal. Maybe just to close
out this portion or discussion, is there something
that you think people should most take away from
this really important stuff you're sharing of just
things that usually don't go well for people that
do well in, there are many things that go wrong?
So the feedback I get from executives about these
moments that really I think is transferable and
helpful is that they know that no matter how
silly I'm being or what stuff I get myself into,
that they know for a fact how seriously
I take everything. They know how much,
if I make a funny presentation about something and
I put a lot of jokes into it, but they're like,
"It's still extremely clear how seriously
you're taking this." So I have peace of mind.
Yeah, I think you have to have both. You can't
just have these adventures or do these silly
things or make these mistakes. It's important to
give the confidence that you know you're making a
mistake, you're on top of it before anybody else,
that it's bothering you more than anybody else.
That if you're communicating and you're trying
to make you creative and that first of all,
you've done all your homework and you've put a
ton into it, and that gives you the basis. The
funny side of this is I have friends who make fun
of me that I work really hard to justify... I have
friends that make fun of me, that I work really
hard so that I can increase the amount of bullshit
that I can get away without being fired. Depends
how you look at it, but it's really important-
That's amazing.
... to give that peace of mind.
Yeah, build that trust bucket and then
just deplete it completely every time.
And then just throw it out the window.
Amazing. Tal, is there anything else
that you want to share before we get
to our very exciting lightning round?
We've covered a ton of stuff. It feels
like there's been three podcasts within
one podcast. But just before we move on,
is there anything else you wanted to
share or touch on or leave listeners with?
Oh, let's do it.
Okay.
The lightning round, yeah.
Well, with that, we've reached
our very exciting lightning
round. I've got five questions. Are you ready?
I'm ready.
First question, what are two or three books
that you've recommended most to other people?
The best book on product management that I've
read. It's called How to Talk So Kids Will
Listen & Listen So Kids Will Talk. I encountered
this book, my sister is a speech therapist and
she had it on her bookshelf at home in her
apartment. And I was jet lagged one night I
was visiting her and I read it, and if anybody
has read, Never Split the Difference by Chris
Voss where he talks about how these senior FBI
agents in 70s, 80s were realizing that all they
were doing in their negotiating tactics were
just not working and decided to try something
different. And that's something is basically
nonviolent communication. And he gives these
amazing examples of decades of using this with
kidnappers and terrorists and organized crime to
defuse situations and create productive outcomes.
So this book, with all due respect to FBI agents
and terrorists and hijackers and kidnappers, this
is about kids. So this book for me, this is what
really the example is how it's communicated.
It's illustrated almost like a comic book,
tons of super concrete examples. And for me, I
think that's when these principles really sunk in.
That book really resonated with me the most, more
than the book itself for Nonviolent Communication
or the Never Split the Difference, both of which
are awesome. So I really recommend that book.
Man. I want to do a whole podcast on what
you learned there, but I'm going to force
myself to move on. That's awesome.
This is going to be really helpful
to me as a new parent. There's a book
that another, I'm just going to throw
out a book recommendation reverse lighting
round on this topic, that Joe Hudson recent
podcast guest recommended offline that I've
found to be incredibly helpful. It's called
Listen. It's an orange book so there's a few on
Amazon and will link to them in the show notes,
but it's just called Listen. And it's about
why listening is the most powerful way to
help your kids get through stuff that is
challenging to them. I'm not going to-
It's a powerful title.
Just listen, that's it. And there's all these
different ways of listening. So anyway, okay,
we'll keep going. Do you have a favorite
recent movie or TV show you really enjoyed?
I recently rediscovered Ted Lasso. The first
time I watched it, I got tons of recommendations,
it's hilarious. I didn't connect to it. I just
didn't connect to the humor. I was like, "Ah,
okay, fine." I stopped watching it. And then
I heard a podcast where somebody recommended
watching it from a point of view of leadership
lessons and they just couldn't stop recommending.
They so passionately recommended it and I
was like, "Okay, let me revisit this." And
when you watch it from that point of view, it's
mind-blowing. If you think about, I'm sure a ton
of people listening to this have watched this
show, you think about the premise of the show,
it's this guy who's been given an impossible task
and he's surrounded by the worst human beings in
the world in terms of just the worst human beings
and behaviors. And the way he gets through that
is... It's hard to describe, you have to watch it.
I think any attempt to summarize it, but the show,
just watching it how this character behaves
and gets through this stuff is incredible
when you watch it from that point of view.
And for me, it definitely affected how I work,
definitely influenced me, but not just work, just
also how I deal with aggressive Middle Eastern
urban life situations, how I deal with... I've
applied this dealing with really tough locals at
surf breaks in South America. It's incredible.
I'll give a story of the surf break. I was in
Chile and I was surfing and it was an hour the
day where a lot of the people who were local would
be surfing. And a bunch came out and they started
giving me these looks. This happens in everywhere
in the world, every surf break and just really
uncomfortable. And one of the guys especially,
and after a while I was realizing I'm not
going to get to surf if this keeps up and
there's no conflict to get out of this.
And I swam up to him and I asked him,
I was like, "Hey, are you from Pichilemo?
Are you from here?" And he's like, "Yeah,
why? I was like, "You are one of the luckiest
people in the world." And he didn't... he was
totally caught off guard. He started smiling
and that just changed the whole vibe. It got
to a point where he was telling other people, let
me have this wave. And that's how my experience
in a lot of surf breaks and
my friend calls it Ted Lasso,
the Ted Lasso somebody, which is also very
genuine. You really have to believe it.
Okay, next question. Do you have a
favorite product you've recently
discovered that you really love?
So this morning I spent half the day
surfing. And I think the products I've
really come to appreciate, there's not a lot of
products used in surfing. It's like a wetsuit,
board shorts, maybe a hat.
But you can really feel,
I surf with O'Neill wetsuit, Hyperfreak wetsuit
but that doesn't matter. It's one piece of gear
is really well constructed, you can feel that the
person behind this also surfs or spends a lot of
time with surfers and really gets you, probably
gets you more than you understand on face value.
And you start to notice all these details over
time. It takes a long time to notice all these
details and you can really feel that there's a
person behind this product that gets you. And
it's like art almost. When you feel a piece
of art or music really resonates with you,
you feel that the artist is communicating with
you directly and letting you feel something that
they were feeling. It's almost like that.
So I think for me, it's outdoor equipment
that you can feel that the person behind
this is using it along there with you.
First time a wetsuit has been recommended
on the podcast, a great milestone.
Two more questions. Do you have favorite
life motto that you often come back to
find useful and work and life
share with friends or family?
I think I can... I'm doing
three surf stories in a row,
but this is a life motto that's
just stuck in my head for almost,
for more than a decade now, which it comes from a
piece of plywood outside of surf shop in Mexico,
that was painted on it, "You can't stop
the waves, but you can learn how to surf."
And yeah, there's a lot to that, that over time
that I've really tried to apply that in a lot
of ways, emotionally, organizationally
at every level, you think about that.
Along those lines. Final question. So at the
beginning of this podcast, you mentioned that this
podcast has been a long time coming and the reason
that's the case is we had this scheduled for some
time in early October. You live in Israel, war
broke out. You've been living through that,
being in Israel this entire time. I saw
this Venn diagram that you put out that
I think summarizes your life right now, which
is... I forget one side of it, but just like-
Apocalypse.
... apocalypse, one circle, the other is,
got to get to work. Got to wake up and make-
Israel's in the middle. That's what it... Yeah.
And you've been in that for the past year.
So I'd love to just briefly just hear how
that's been for you in the past year.
How are you doing? How's life for you?
Here at Riverside, we've had a bunch of people
out for reserve duty. I think all of them are
back now. I have a team lead. Well, people are
still going in and out of reserve duty while
working here. I have a team lead who leaves
on Sundays around 4:00 PM, goes to the base,
won't say what he has to do, but it's super
intense and shows up the next morning a little
tired but back at work. And general, it's not
just in Israel, we have teammates in Ukraine-
Oh wow.
... all along at the same time. Yeah, one of my
teams is almost entirely in Ukraine. So we've
had moments where we'll all be on a call and
then there'll be missile siren here in Israel,
here in Tel Aviv. And we'll say, "Hey,
sorry, we got to go." Go down to the shelter,
hear the explosions overhead, come back, sit back
down. Later that day, we'll have another meeting.
And on the Ukraine side, you'll hear like, "Hey,
that beeping, isn't not the missile alert on your
end?" And, "Andre, isn't that not the critical
alert on your iPhone?" He looks at his phone,
he'll be like, "Yeah, but I got 10 minutes.
Let's just finish the meeting." Right? These
surreal moments where you just, at the same
time where everything's not normal, people
have this really strong desire for normalcy.
It's work and everything around us and our
routines become more important than ever. And it's
just these... You have, "Oh, where's Vlad?" "Oh,
the power grid was attacked in this town," so he's
working, I mean in getting the generator back up.
Oh okay.
But I don't know if it's a no excuses mindset
or badassery so much as I know on my end,
it's just that, I think for Ukraine team
definitely, at my end is just really,
really crave the routine and the sense of normalcy
when you can get those moments. And like I said,
I think during this podcast working
on this course, all these things,
I'm not doing them because things are normal.
I'm doing them because they're not. So,
yeah. And I'll use this opportunity to say that
biggest thing in all of our minds is there's
107 hostages that have been held for 328 days
by Hamas and you need to bring them home now.
Yeah. Well, let's hope the hostages come home.
Let's hope things end soon. I'm really impressed
with how much you've been able to get done
in the middle of all of that. And thanks for
making time for this. I know that this isn't the
most important thing in the world right now, but
I think this conversation is going to help a lot
of people, and you have so much wisdom to share.
Thank you.
Thanks for being here, Tal.
On the course real quick, just
to make sure people check it out,
how do people find it, just throw
that out there as a final step.
It's on maven.com in the product
catalog, and I'll have it... I'll
probably post links to my LinkedIn as
well. You can find it there. And yeah,
it'll launch in mid-October.
That'll be the first cohort.
Amazing. And we'll link to it in the show
notes. Tal, thank you so much for being here,
All right, thank you.
Bye everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.