When people say, "I want someone that's
strategic," what they're really saying is,
"I want someone that can come up with and
articulate a compelling and simple why
behind the decisions and the direction of the
company and product." So that's number one. And
the second piece is, "I want someone that's
going to champion and be a change agent to
do things that may be hard but actually best for
the long-term interest of the product or company,
even though those things are not going
to be easy to execute on." And I think
if you have one without the other, ultimately
people are not going to see you as strategic.
Today my guest is Anneka Gupta. Anneka
is Chief Product Officer at Rubrik,
a lecturer on product management at Stanford
University's Graduate School of Business and
on the board of Tinuiti. Previously, she was
President, GM, and head of product at LiveRamp,
where she spent 11 years and joined as
one of their earliest employees. A bunch
of former guests recommended Anneka Come
on this podcast and you'll soon see why.
In our conversation, Anneka shares a ton
of powerful advice on navigating difficult
personalities, giving and hearing hard feedback,
bringing humor and gratitude to every situation,
managing your energy versus managing your
time. Super tactical tips for how to become
more strategic and how to make better decisions,
and also how to break into product management
for people that are trying to become product
managers. There's something in this episode
for everyone and I am excited for you to
learn from Anneka. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's the
best way to avoid missing feature episodes and
it helps the podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you Anneka Gupta. Anneka, thank you so
much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Thanks for having me.
So, I want to start with a question that I've
started to ask guests that come on the podcast
that have had extraordinarily successful careers
and also just consistently successful careers.
So here's the question. What do you believe
are one or two skills or mindsets or habits
that you think most contributed to your
success that you think might be helpful
for other people to learn and build to
help them have more successful careers?
So it's funny, before we kicked this
off, you talked about the post-it that
you have on your computer that says have fun.
My one mindset that I really have leaned into
after someone actually gave me advice on this
is to figure out how to have fun in my job,
even in the most difficult of times. The reason
why I say that is because when you're hit with
really hard times, it's easy to operate from a
mindset of scarcity and to look at everything
as an unachievable hurdle to overcome. And when
I was able to switch my mindset and say, "Well,
I'm actually going to figure out a way to have
fun with this," it actually changed my entire for
how to deal with super difficult situations.
This advice specifically came up to me when I
had a scenario where I had to essentially change
out all of my direct reports in very short order,
and I figured that out. It was a super
daunting situation. I didn't know how I
was going to manage and at first I felt so scared
by what was ahead of me and how much change I was
going to have to go through in a very short
period of time. But when I got this advice,
I started to try to reframe my thinking and it
actually really made it so that I was able to get
through that hard time and opened my mind up to so
many more opportunities. So, now I try to embody
that in every situation that I come across where
I'm faced with something super, super challenging.
I love this advice. It's something that I've
recently seen also in public speaking. If you
can just reframe your thinking from "I'm scared
of this" to "This is going to be fun. I'm going
to have so much fun doing this. It's going to
be like this energy and anxiety I'm feeling
is me feeling like it's going to be a lot of
fun." So, spending a little more time here,
how do you actually do this? So in this case,
you shared an example of basically you have
to fire a bunch of people, not something one
can quickly think about how to have fun with
that. How did you do this? Is it just in your
mind you're like, "I'm going to have fun with
this," or is there something tactically
people can do to make something fun?
I think there were a couple of things
that I did and I've continued to do.
One is figure out and really look
at the situation and ask myself,
what can I learn from this situation? What can
I get out of this that's a positive outcome
even though it is incredibly challenging to be
facing it right now? So that's one thing that
I've done. The second thing I think that has
been really helpful is in going into meetings
or other situations where I was trying to figure
out how to collectively solve some big challenge,
figuring out how to bring humor into the
meeting. Just starting it on a light note
and that elevated my own mood and way I was
approaching the meeting, but also adds a level
of levity to the situation for other people
as well, which I think as a leader is super
important because it's not just about your
own mindset, but how are you transferring
that mindset to the people that you're working
with and the people that are working for you.
Got it. So part of it is just like, "How do I
add a little humor?" Part of it is just thinking,
"How do I make this fun?" Is part
of this just like this is not as
important as people make it out to
be and we could just have a little
fun with this thing. It doesn't have
to be like we're not curing cancer.
Yeah, definitely I think that helps. Reflecting
on this too, I feel like a lot of it comes down
to the amount of emotional and mental energy
I can bring to solving a problem. And there's
always so much going on in life, like personal
life as well as professional life, trying to
figure out how can I architect my day and time to
maximize my energy and be able to bring my full
self to work and to these difficult so that I can
have that mindset to look at things more broadly
versus operating from a place of scarcity. That
may come down to simple things like making sure
that I have lunch. Sometimes when things get so
busy you're like, "Oh, I'm just going to grab a
protein bar and I'm going to skip lunch." But
I found that that really decreases my energy.
Or, trying to do things that are really difficult
late in the day. Five to 6:00 PM is my worst time
of day and I know that about myself, so I'm not
going to schedule in my most difficult meeting
or writing up a strategy deck or something for
that period of time because I know that that's
not going to be my best and it's actually going
to make it more difficult for me to get the work
done. Being able to manage my energy levels and
figuring out how to schedule my time for my energy
has really allowed me also to figure out how to
have that abundant mindset in all situations.
This episode is brought to you by the
Enterprise Ready Conference, a one-day event
in San Francisco, bringing together product
and engineering leaders shaping the future
of enterprise SaaS. The event features a curated
list of speakers with direct experience building
for the enterprise, including leaders from OpenAI,
Vanta, Checker, Dropbox and Canva. Topics included
advanced identity management, compliance,
encryption, and logging essentially at complex
features that most enterprise customers require.
If you're a founder, exec, product manager or
engineer tasked with the enterprise roadmap,
this conference is for you. You'll get detailed
insights from industry leaders that have years of
experience navigating the same challenges that you
face today. And best of all, it's completely free
since it's hosted by WorkOS. Spots are filling
up quickly. Make sure to request an invite at
EnterpriseReady.com. That's EnterpriseReady.com.
Today's episode is brought to you by Command AI.
If you're like me and most users that I've built
product for, you're probably used to chatbots
at the bottom right of websites where you ask
a question and it says something like, "Check out
these three helpful articles. Did that answer your
question?" And then you click away and then a
few seconds later you get bombarded with some
other useless pop-ups. For those of us who work
on software, no one wants their product to feel
like this. Command AI is an AI power toolkit
for support, product, growth and marketing
teams that embeds in your company's product.
The AI support agent can deflect upwards of
80% of support questions providing actually useful
answers, and it can magically co-browse with your
users to show them around your interface. They
do pop-ups too, but their nudges are based on
in-product behaviors like confusion or intent
classification, which makes them much less
annoying and much more impactful. Command AI
works with web apps, mobile apps and websites,
and they work with industry-leading companies
like Gusto, Freshworks, HashiCorp, LaunchDarkly,
and over 25 million end-users interact with
Command AI interfaces. To try out Command AI,
you can sign up at command.ai/Lenny and
experience a custom demo of how it works
in your app. That's command.ai/Lenny.
I'm going to go in a totally different
direction. Before we were recording, we
were also chatting about founder mode,
and this is recently. This episode we're recording
shortly after Paul Graham put out his now classic,
instant classic founder mode post. And he had
some really interesting takes on ways to think
about founder mode, both from product leader
perspective, from a founder perspective. So,
there's kind of two questions I want to ask, but
just broadly, what's your take on founder mode?
Well, first of all, I think Paul Graham did an
amazing thing by putting a name to something so
many of us have seen in practice. And while he
didn't in his article say this is exactly what
this is, I think many, many people that I talked
to were like, "Oh yeah, I recognize this." I
recognize people that I've worked for, CEOs, that
have done founder mode, great founders that have
done founder mode poorly. And it opened up a level
of discussion that I think is really valuable for
everyone to be having, whether you're a founder
or you're someone that works for a founder.
Okay, so I'm going to ask two questions around
this. One is from the perspective of working
for a founder and founder mode, the other is
being a product leader in founder mode. So,
first of all, imagine you've worked with a few
founders that operate in founder mode. As a CPO,
as head of product, that's often a
difficult place to be between the
founder and the team that are building
the thing. What have you learned about
how to effectively work as a product
leader with a founder in founder mode?
So, I think when a founder's in founder mode and
if they're doing it well, what they're doing is
really deeply understanding the business and then
figuring out when to use their power as a founder
to either tweak things and send something in a
slightly different direction or fundamentally
innovate and completely change directions or
completely innovate in a totally new area. Now
I think the way to use that effectively as a
head of product is to recognize that they have
that power to figure out how to use that power
to get the things done that you know are best
for the company. So, I always think about
I have all the people around me. Whether
they're people on my team, my peers, or my CEO,
these are different resources I have to go get a
initiative done or get work done in the company.
And as having a founder that can effectively
operate in founder mode means that I can go and
have a conversation with the CEO and say, "Hey,
look, we have this huge opportunity and these
are the things that aren't working, and I need
your help to help figure out how we can move the
needle more substantially in the direction that we
need to go." And so activating that founder, that
CEO to really be able to push the initiative that
I think is best by making them an ally in doing
so. I think one aspect. The second aspect is,
which often happens, it's very difficult for many
people and I've had this happen to me many times,
is when a founder is like, "Well, I have
this idea," and then you may or may not
agree that that's the best direction to go in
and how do you navigate that kind of situation?
So, one is actually taking a step back and
objectively saying, "Well, why are they
pushing this?" Maybe it's the wrong mechanism
to go actually get done a strategy that's quite
important for the company. So having a really deep
understanding about why are they asking this, what
are they ultimately trying to get at and what is
the objective that they're trying to get at and is
this the right way to get at it? If the answer is
no to that, then you can go have a conversation.
If you know what the objective is, you can go have
a conversation with that founder and say, "Hey,
look, I know this is what you're trying to do, but
maybe instead of looking at option A here of how
we go about tackling this, we should have explored
these three other options instead." And that can
help you and help navigate that conversation.
Now sometimes it's difficult to even get to that
kind of understanding of the objective because
someone might be just super set in their ways of,
"Hey, I really want to go after this opportunity.
It's my pet project." Then you have to decide
as a head of product, do I really want to
fight this or do I just give in on this,
let it go? And also make sure that we get the
stuff done that's most important to the company.
You have to make that judgment call as a head
of product and decide what is really going to
make or break the company. What's the hill that
I'm going to die on and is this something that
I can shift or is this something that is not
worth shifting? Of course it comes down to the
personality. I've been very fortunate that I've
actually had very few of those situations where
the founder has been like, "Hey, I really want
to go in this direction and I haven't agreed,
at least with what we're trying to go after,
regardless of the mechanism behind it."
I really love the point you made, especially
about how the founder could be this lever to
get things done. When you identify something
needs to change, the best way to change that is
just have the founder go in there, tell everyone,
"Hey, we're going to do this thing differently."
It's such like a positive spin on how to leverage
founder mode where a founder actually has a lot of
power to change that other people in the company
don't. Okay, so let's go from the other side. So,
I was talking to Nikhyl Singhal who runs the
Skip, which is a community you're part of about
you. And he said that you're a leader who excels
in founder mode, that you operate in founder mode
a lot. And so as a product leader, what have you
learned about just how to think in founder mode,
operate in founder mode, leverage that approach
to leading teams, leading product teams?
Yeah, I think it's often easy as a leader to
say, "I'm not going to roll up my sleeves and get
into the details of the business or ask a lot of
detailed questions about the business because you
want to empower people and make them successful."
What I've found is that understanding the
details of the business and asking questions and
understanding to the utmost extent you can, what's
working, what's not, what are the financial goals
of the business? Are we on track to get there? How
are we making decisions? Getting into that level
of depth is super important, and then you can
decide as a leader, what do you want to do with
that information? So there's a lot of information
that I collect about what's happening in the
organization, the decisions that we're making that
I don't do anything with at a point in time.
That's my choice to make, but I want the
information because in understanding the depth and
what is happening, I can decide where I actually
think I need to go in deep and make either very
significant course correction or a small course
correction. Then the way that I think about how do
I bring my team along for that so they don't feel
like I'm coming in and stomping all over the work
that they're doing or trying to re-adjudicate a
decision, one, is how do I get in there early?
One of the tactics I use is I ask people
to present their strategies for things that I
think we may need to do a course correction on,
and I have them come in and then I ask them
questions and then I make suggestion. And I'm able
to do that in a forum where it doesn't feel like
I'm coming in and rewriting the entire strategy,
but I'm giving them there an opportunity
to present their best thinking and then
trying to figure out how do I take that and
make that better and make them feel like I'm
making it better versus stomping all over
and dismissing the work that they've done.
I pick a strategic set of areas. So I think about
what is most important for the business? What's
going to kill the business if we don't get right
and what are the biggest opportunities for the
business that we need to go after regardless of
how difficult it is for us to actually execute on
that? By doing that, then at least I have clarity
in my mind and I can provide clarity to the team
about what is most important and rally the troops
around making that stuff happen if that is what is
essentially right. And I'll have all the context
because I've asked all the questions of why this
is right for the business, why is this going
to help us with increased margins or get better
growth or get into a new persona if that's what
we're trying to do as an overall organization.
So in that example, and I love this
tactic, you have your team come in,
you ask them, "Tell me what the strategy is
for this thing that you're working on." What
you've seen work is instead of like, "No, this
is broken, this is wrong, this isn't going to
work." Your approach is ask questions and hope
that they see the flaws or gaps. Is that how-
Yeah, it's ask questions, but you can't always
lead someone somewhere with asking questions.
It's also sharing a hypothesis. So I might have
a particular hypothesis about the business where
I might see something like, "Well, I was talking
to security leaders in our customer advisory board
recently and I heard this piece of feedback and
this is what it made me think about our strategy,
what do you think about that?" And then let
them say like, "Okay, yeah, actually I see
this or maybe I have some follow up questions."
It actually opens a whole discussion where I'm
still able to provide my perspective and
point of view but not completely shut down
the discussion. Because what I always
worry about is a leader is I'm going to
come in and say something, and because I'm
one of the more senior people in the room,
no one is going to say if they have a concern. And
the reality is I'm not always right far from it,
but I want to be able to seed an assumption
and then have a discussion based on that and
then figure out what the right outcome is about
what we should do next based on that discussion.
Speaking of strategy, you shared
with me that at one point in your
career you got this feedback that you
just weren't strategic enough and that
that comment led you to research and dig
into what does it mean to be strategic,
and also just to level up your strategic
mindset and the way you think about strategy.
What did you end up with recognizing as being
strategic? What is that in your work and in
your research? And then how did you actually
get better at this work of being strategic?
I got this feedback once in a performance review
and then I actually got it as well a few years ago
when I was interviewing for head of product roles
and I thought I had made a lot of progress on it,
but when I reflected back, I think it actually all
came back to the same themes. Which was I think
when people say "I want someone that's strategic,"
what they're really saying is "I want someone that
can come up with and articulate a compelling
and simple why behind the decisions and the
direction of the company and product." So
that's number one. The second piece is,
"I want someone that's going to champion and
be a change agent to do things that may be hard
but actually best for the long-term interest
of the product or company, even though those
things are not going to be easy to execute on."
And I think if you have one without the other,
ultimately people are not going to see you as
strategic. If you're really good at articulating
the why, but you're only bringing small ideas to
the table, then that's not strategic. If you're
championing big ideas but you can't articulate the
why behind them in a compelling and simple way,
then you're not going to be seen as strategic
either. So, that's the formula that I've come
up with. This is what it means. And so I focused
a lot on how do I make sure I do both of these
things? How do I champion a few things that a
really big ideas that are going to help change
the direction of the company, and then how do I
articulate that in a simple and compelling why?
That's such a cool simple way of thinking
about this. Is there an example from your
work that might illustrate some of this from a
project you worked on or a product you built?
I can take some recent examples. We've been doing
a lot of strategic planning for where do we want
to be as a company over the next three years,
and Rubrik operates in the cybersecurity space.
It's a very fast moving landscape. There's a
lot of places that we could go as a business,
and one of the ways that I've exhibited this,
and this is what I recommend to other people too,
is sometimes it's really hard to come up with
the compelling and simple why behind something
and sometimes it's also really hard to come
up with a really big idea out of thin air. So
these things can be very challenging. The first
step that I found as very useful, and I use this
tactic every single day in meetings, is just
summarization. So, bringing people together,
lots of different voices into a room and hearing
what they have to say and at various times in
the conversation summarizing what people
are saying and summarizing what that means
in terms of the direction that we could go in.
And then that's a checkpoint of saying, "Okay,
this is how I've synthesized what is happening. Is
this correct or do we actually need to do another
turn because we don't all agree with where we're
landing here?" That summarization, even though I
may not be adding a new idea into that, I found
people actually view that as strategy. They view
the effective summarization as strategy. So I
think that's one element. Then what I've also
found is that when I summarize what other people
are saying and especially multiple different
stakeholders, then I can think about offline
and not in the context of right in the meeting,
sometimes in the meeting too I guess, is how
do I make this idea one click better? It's
not about how do you do something radically,
radically different, but taking ideas and then
making it slightly better, slightly better.
When you think about that, especially from an
outside-in perspective of what are the customer
problems we're trying to solve and how are we
going to take this to market, and don't worry
about how difficult the technical implementation
is going to be, then you start to get to these big
ideas that can really be the change agent ideas.
So, I've started doing this more and more and I
think especially in the past three to six months,
and I'm seeing a material difference in terms
of the number of big ideas that we're going
and pursuing overall as a company and also
the quality of the strategic thinking that
I can bring to the table, and it's
been really exciting and rewarding.
There's so much you're sharing that resonates
with other podcast episodes. For example,
this idea of just going one click better. I had
Roger Martin on the podcast where this book,
Playing to Win, which is one of the more popular
strategy books, and he has this concept of
betterment as a way to work on strategy. A lot
of people go huge with a big strategy and vision,
and his advice is just find the thing that is
the biggest constraint and bottleneck to your
business right now and just make it better and
that's your next step. And then just keep doing
that and you'll end up in a much better place over
time, even though it feels like you're just doing
one little thing. And so I love this idea of just
picking one thing and making it one click better.
There's going to be an episode that comes out
right before this with Alex Komoroske, and he
has this concept of the adjacent possible and it's
just find the next thing that's possible and focus
on that versus some big lofty thing. So I'm just
sharing a bunch of stuff, that's not a question.
That totally resonates though.
Okay, okay. Okay, great. And
then the summarization idea,
I love it. So tactical, basically any PM
can do this just in a meeting just like,
"Okay, let me just summarize to make sure
everyone's on the same page." Funny enough,
this is the feedback I get on this podcast and I
haven't been doing this in our conversation yet,
but I often try to summarize the
person's point and everyone's like, "Oh,
I love that you do that. That's so helpful." So
I totally see the power of that in my experience.
It also makes people feel heard
and especially when you have a
lot of diverse voices in the room that may not
agree on all things but have valid viewpoints,
it helps bring people together and ultimately
the diverse perspectives are going to yield
better insights and better decisions
for the organizations. You want that,
but some people shy away from that because it's
scary because you have to deal with a lot of
conflict and it's a way to kind of move beyond the
conflict and get to the heart of an issue, which
in my mind, that's what the PM job is all about
is getting to the very, very heart of a problem.
If someone wants to work on this skill
of summarizing as kind of a tactic,
can you give just an example of how you would
do that? Is there like a phrase to use? Is there
words or an example you could give of just
like here's how it would look in a meeting?
Yeah. So, often if there's a lot of discussion
going on, sometimes it can be a little hard to
insert yourself. I still may insert myself and
say, "Hey, let me pause here for a second and
try to capture what has been said." This is
what I've heard. I've heard that our customers
are having these kinds of challenges. We feel
like this is the way that we want to solve these
challenges. We have a right to win in this way
and therefore we're going to take this action.
Is everyone in agreement with that or is there
some dissent about whether that's an accurate
portrayal of where we've landed with this
conversation? That's the way I'll frame it
up and again, ending it on a question so that
you're not coming in and just being like, "Hey,
this is where we're at." But then inviting
people to discuss and say "Yes," or "No,
I agree with 90% of that or 10% off."
And that helps move the conversation
forward because sometimes you'll get
stuck in these circular discussions
that aren't moving forward and you need
to figure out a way to move it forward.
And then you experience is just doing
that makes you look more strategic
and gives people the impression
you're thinking strategically?
Yes. Yeah.
Awesome.
The other way you can do it is if you're in
a room with someone and you have a whiteboard
is actually summarize on the whiteboard
while people are talking and then show
your summarized framework or whatever on that.
So that's kind of a good way to do it too. If
you're having a hard time interrupting the flow
of discussion or you don't feel as comfortable
thinking on your feet and interrupting and then
framing your point of view, you can do that. In
Zoom you can also use a chat. I've done that
very effectively and said, "I'm not going to
interrupt the flow conversation. I'm just going
to summarize in Zoom chat this is what I've heard,
and this is what I think we're saying in this
conversation." And then sometimes that'll get
invited back into the broader conversation
that's happening live on the Zoom itself.
That's a much lower stakes way of doing it, and
I'm picturing all the PMs listening to this,
they're going to start doing this
and there's going to be all these
summaries now in Zoom chats and everyone will
be like, "Oh my God, why is everyone sharing?"
And then Zoom AI will start just doing it
all for you. Then we'll have to think again.
And then PMs are over and AI replaced us all.
Yes.
Okay, so then just to close the
loop on becoming more strategic,
your advice is when someone's like, "Hey,
you're not strategic enough. You need to be
more strategic." Your insights is
the two things to work on is one,
be clear on the whys behind the ideas that you're
working on and be very crystal clear. People may
not be understanding why you're working on the
things you want to work on, the things you're
pitching. And then two is actually be the person
that makes these things happen, not just put a doc
out there. If you're not actually achieving them,
people are going to think you're not strategic.
Yep.
Awesome. Okay. I want to talk about
decision-making. You have a really interesting
perspective on how to become a better
decision-maker in relation to being kind
of a historian, which I love this
concept. Talk about that insight.
Yeah, so I was at my previous company for
11 years, so I kind of ended up becoming the
historian. And when I joined Rubrik about three
years ago, I came into an organization that had
a lot of history that I just didn't know about.
So one of the things that I decided to do when I
joined the company was to really understand what
happened in the past. What were the products that
we launched that weren't successful? Why weren't
they successful? What was the perspective on the
history of how we've decided to develop the things
that we did and why? What was the perception of
different people in the organization? I tried
to construct this past knowledge of what had
happened and what were the decisions that
were made and why were those decisions made,
whether they were good or bad it didn't matter,
so that I could better understand how to make
decisions going forward and to learn from the
mistakes that I didn't personally live through.
I think that's the part that's really
important about being a historian. You
can always be a historian. It doesn't have to
be just when you join a company, but even today
I'll hear about projects from many years ago
that people will bring up and I'll be like,
"Tell me about this project. What happened with
it? How did we decide to do this?" And just
really learn and be curious about it because
that gives me more context into, well, what
is it that we did poorly and how can we do that
better? And also, what is the baggage that people
have around trying to do something similar again?
Because people always come with their baggage of,
oh, this hasn't worked before, so why is it
going to work now? And as a product leader,
you're obviously putting in place a lot of
thoughts and ideas around this is what I
want to go achieve and these are the initiatives.
And some people are going to come and say, "Well,
we've tried that before." Especially you've been
at an organization that's been around for a while.
I've been that guy. We've done this so many
times. It didn't work. Why are we thinking
about this again? Okay, so the advice is
if you're new to a company especially,
just study the past decisions that were made
and share them out as a part of that and
then as a side effect, it'll help you make
better decisions because you'll have this
history about what the company has done. I love
that. Along the same lines of decision-making,
I asked your former colleague Rachel Wolan what
to ask you, and she said that your parting advice
when she left to join a different company
was it's not about making the right decision,
it's about making the decision. That's like
the things she remembered about you most,
that parting advice. Talk about why that
is so important and your insight there.
Very easy to get into analysis paralysis
before making a decision and say, "Well,
if I just had this one more data point, if I just
knew this, then I could make a decision." But the
reality is that you were always operating
off of imprecise information as a product
leader. What I've found is that once you commit
to a decision, you actually learn more post
committing to that decision about what's going to
work and not going to work, and you move out of
the hypothetical. And as long as your decision
is like 70% right, you can iterate on that 20,
30% in either direction, but if you don't commit,
then you don't actually get any new information
that is high fidelity and high quality. So,
I'm a big believer in making decisions...
I know you've had a few guests talk about speed
is super important in organizations. Well,
I think making decisions quickly and then being
able to iterate on them is a form of that. Just
make a decision. Don't make it uninformed, but
have a strong hypothesis and then just keep
testing whether that hypothesis is accurate or not
and you'll shift here and there. You might build
something that you have to throw away 20% of the
work on, but that's okay. It's better than making
no decision at all because you won't get any new
information if you don't make any decision at all.
As a PM that might be listening to this, feeling
like, "Okay, yeah, that sounds great." But then
I make a bad decision and then Anneka is going
to be like, "You messed up here. You've shipped
the wrong thing here. It didn't work." How do
you create a culture where people don't feel
that and aren't as afraid of making bad decisions
and making decisions with 70% of the information?
I think part of it comes down to making sure
there's a strong hypothesis that everyone
understands when you're making the decision.
Or it might not just be one hypothesis,
it might be a series of hypotheses and assumptions
that we're making that are informing the decision.
So it might be a hypothesis that this segment
of customers is going to be willing to pay for
this product because it's solving an urgent and
important enough need for them that they're going
to go do it and this is the evidence we have to
find it, but this is also the stuff we don't know.
Then along the way, we learn whether that
hypothesis is true or not. And so at the
end of the day, if something didn't work out, we
can go back to the original hypothesis and say,
"Well, this is what we learned in this process
that our hypothesis was actually not true,
and we learned all of this after the fact." I
think the way to make a culture of risk taking
and people willing to make these bets and
go out on a limb is to reward the learning
versus the outcome. That's what I try to
focus on is if we're constantly learning,
it is okay if we make bad decisions, but we
learn from them and we get better for next
time. Even in making this bad decision,
we learn something about our customers or
our business that we otherwise wouldn't have
learned that we can use in another context.
First of all, I love that this comes
back to your strategic lesson of just
if you have a strong why behind something,
that's incredibly powerful and people will
be confident that you're thinking strategically.
Two, I was just at a talk with Zuck. He's being
interviewed at the Chase Center, the
Acquired Podcast at this whole event,
and his main thing that he talked about that
he values most in the culture of Facebook is
learning faster than anyone else. Shipping stuff
that isn't perfect, but just so that you can get
one more turn and learn something faster than
someone else. So, that super resonates that's
Facebook's culture. Is there an example of
something you worked on where you did that,
where you kind of ship something that you
weren't fully confident in and you learn faster?
Yeah, I mean, I think there's a lot
because anytime you're shipping products,
there's so many different things that could
go right and wrong. There's a situation
where we created a really amazing high value
product and we decided not to monetize it,
and then we realized after the fact, "Wait, we
should have monetized it. So, we're trying to
figure out how to package some new capabilities
to monetize this thing that we know has a lot of
value without taking away what we've already given
to existing customers." So that was something we
learned along the way that we originally
didn't think, oh, we should monetize this,
but then we realized that there's actually
an avenue to do that after the fact. There's
been other things where we've developed a set of
capabilities thinking that it will solve for this
new persona's problems, but then we misunderstood
how easy it was going to be to go sell to that
new persona within our own organization.
I've made that mistake many times actually.
And so now I think now what I've taken from
that is really know how you're going to sell
something and who's going to do the selling
before you actually go build out the product.
Because if you don't have that right focus,
you may build out the best product and yet
it's going to get zero adoption because no one in
your organization is ready to sell it. So there's
tons of stuff like that where it's like been
okay, yeah, we've learned something from this,
and it's not all throwaway, it just means
that we've got to do something differently
for this product and we need to do something
differently for our organization going forward.
This episode is brought to you by Eppo. Eppo is a
next-generation A/B testing and feature management
platform built by alums of Airbnb and Snowflake
for modern growth teams. Companies like Twitch,
Miro, ClickUp and DraftKings rely on Eppo to
power their experiments. Experimentation is
increasingly essential for driving growth and for
understanding the performance of new features.
And Eppo helps you increase experimentation
velocity while unlocking rigorous deep analysis
in a way that no other commercial tool does.
When I was at Airbnb, one of the things that I
loved most was our experimentation platform where
I could set up experiments, easily, troubleshoot
issues, and analyze performance all on my
own. Eppo does all that and more with advanced
statistical methods that can help you shave
weeks off experiment time and accessible UI for
diving deeper into performance and out-of-the-box
reporting that helps you avoid annoying prolonged
analytic cycles. Eppo also makes it easy for
you to share experiment insights with your team,
sparking new ideas for the A/B testing flywheel.
Eppo powers experimentation across every use case,
including product, growth, machine learning,
monetization, and email marketing. Check
out Eppo at geteppo.com/Lenny and 10X your
experiment velocity. That's geteppo.com/Lenny.
I want to come back to something Rachel
also shared with me when asked her what
questions to ask you. By the way, first
of all, she spent a lot of time raving
about how amazing you are first. That was the
first set of conversations, and then she came
up with a bunch of questions to ask you. And
so her other question was about how good you
are at navigating very difficult personalities.
She showed this quote that she constantly saw you
interact with and bring together several leaders
who had much higher egos and very disparate points
of view who are not informed or thoughtful or as
gracious as you were, and she also said you have
very low ego. She wanted me just to ask you for
what you've learned about how to navigate very
difficult personalities and help people align
when it's not neatly what they want to do.
I try to embody the mindset of feeling
like and believing that I can work with
anyone. I think what I do when I hit a difficult
personality and difficult personalities come in
all shapes and sizes and forms is I really try
to understand what drives that person. What is
it that they really care about? Hopefully they
care about something deeply about the company
and making the company successful. Sometimes
they care about their own personal career,
how they're showing up, what people view of
them. That's fine. I just need to understand
what it is that they really care about,
and then if I need something from them,
what is it that I can do to motivate them
to find what I need from them important?
And trying to make that match of they have this
desire kind of like building a product, they have
this desire and how am I going to get them to
care about the thing that I want to care about?
The other thing I do is instead of feeling like
anger or frustration with the person and instead
trying to shift that to a mindset of feeling
gratitude and a positive emotion about them is
I look at them and I ask myself what can I learn?
Maybe I don't want to adopt their personality
or operate the way that they are operating, but
everyone has something that they can teach you,
whether it's their communication style or the
way they're able to marshal people together,
the way they come up with visionary ideas,
whatever it may be, trying to study that
person and be curious about them, learn from
them and then thank them for that and feel
the generosity genuinely about what I got from
this situation. It's easier to do sometimes than
others, but I think it comes back to that abundant
mindset. If you can approach it with an abundant
mindset, then you can really consciously do
this and when you actually learn something,
you will feel the gratitude when you recognize
that you are able to get something from that.
I love that this connects with your other original
piece of advice of just turning something into
this is going to be fun. Let's make this fun.
And in this case it's like make it great. What
can I learn from this person even though they're
really annoying me and it's frustrating and don't
want anything done? Then your other point of
understanding what they want and kind of using
that as a way to pull them in your direction, how
do you figure out what they want? Do you have any
tricks for just like, "Here's how I learn what
this person's motivations are and goals are"?
Talk to other people that have worked with
them before and have done so successfully.
So that might be people that work for them
because if you work for a person like that,
you have to figure out and or you're
successful working for that person,
you probably understand what makes them tick.
So that's one, or talk to people that are peers,
anything like that to try to understand and build
this view of this person that helps me empathize
with them and also helps me understand what they
may be wanting to get out of a situation and why.
I love that. Yeah, they don't have to be
involved in that. You just ask other people,
"What is this person's motivations?" And
then the idea is connect what they want
with the thing you're trying to achieve.
Beautiful. I really love this idea of when
you're frustrated by someone just reframing
it to like, "I'm grateful I'm going to learn
something from this person in our interaction,
even though they're making life hard for me." I
really love that. Another skill I hear you're
really strong at, and this comes from another
one of your colleagues, Hema Mohan shared
that you're world-class at giving feedback,
giving hard feedback, and receiving hard
feedback. And so I want to just ask you,
what have you learned about how to do this? It's
very hard to give hard feedback. That's why it's
called hard feedback. So from either direction,
what have you learned about receiving hard
feedback or giving hard feedback where someone
actually hears Zoom doesn't get defensive?
The answer is so much, I've learned so much
from it. So maybe I'll start with receiving
feedback. So, on the receiving feedback side,
I think it's very natural to feel upset,
defensive, all the negative emotions when
you first see a piece of negative feedback,
whether it's you're reading it in a employee
survey or you're receiving it in a one-on-one
from a direct report or from a manager or from
a peer. And I try to let myself just feel the
things that I'm going to feel. Sometimes that's
an emotional feeling, sometimes that means I
want to step out of the room or it depends on
who I'm talking to, but let myself feel the
things that I'm going to feel. Then once that's
passed, whether that's a few hours or a few days,
don't react. Don't try to say, "Oh, I don't
believe this." Listen. And then ask myself,
okay, well where is this feedback coming
from? Why am I getting this feedback?
And try to be super curious about it. And that
might be going back to the person that gave me the
feedback and maybe asking someone that's a peer
somewhere in the organization that might have more
context and flavor to what the feedback really
is, just trying to learn. Then I can decide,
do I think this is valid or not? Is this something
I should do something about or not? Actually,
all feedback I think is valid. People's feelings
are valid, but it doesn't mean that you need to
do something about all of those things. Going
through that process and letting myself ride the
emotional wave and not judging myself for that,
but then not reacting and letting myself then
figure out and come back curious. I think when
you come back curious, people then want to give
you more feedback because they know that you're
listening and that you're hearing what they say.
So the advice is feel it, don't block it off and
be like, "No, no, no, no, no, this isn't real." So
fully let your body go through the roller coaster
of feeling the negative feedback. Sometimes the
feedback is just like, "No, this isn't actually
a thing." Do you have any just heuristic of like
I should actually pay attention to this deeply
or just like let me wait for more data points?
Yeah, I think in product you receive feedback all
the time for your organization or for yourself,
and you can't make everyone happy. Everyone wants
a different thing from product. So I think this
comes up quite often where there's a lot of
feedback for the organization or for you as a
leader and you have to decide what to focus on and
what not to focus on. I always try to anchor on,
"Well, what is best for the company and
what does the company need for me and for
my team at this point in time?" There's
stuff that is a must-have on that list,
and there's stuff that's nice to have. Sometimes
there's just too many must-haves to go deal with
the nice-to-haves and you have to just
be like, well, I know this is a problem,
or I know we could be 10% better in this,
but it actually doesn't matter as much as
fixing these things that are really, really
important and are really what's going to
help my organization deliver what it needs to
for the company and for the business overall.
In terms of receiving hard feedback,
so you shared one example or I shared
an example where someone said you weren't
strategic enough. Is there another example
of receiving hard feedback that you got
that you're like, "Ugh, that sucks"?
Either earlier in your career or more
recently, anything else come to mind?
I mean all the time. So there's always hard
stuff. Well, people will give feedback of,
"Oh, I feel like we're not moving fast
enough on our roadmap and priorities.
We need to be doing more. Why
aren't we moving fast?" Or-
Never heard that one before.
Never heard that one before, right? Or
disparaging the direction that we're
taking a certain product because they don't agree
with it because a competitor is doing something
else, but we've decided for our reasons that we're
not going to go follow that path. There's always
something that people have negative feedback
about and sometimes I'm like, "Okay, this is an
eye roll." I understand where they're coming from.
I understand why they're giving me this feedback,
but I also don't agree that we should change
directions because of it. I don't know,
some of the things cut deeper than others, but
I think people are making personal statements
about my team or they're feeling like, "Hey,
the product team isn't listening to feedback,
or the product team has a bad culture. Anneka
isn't listening." Things like that cut deep and
are a lot more... I know like physiologically they
make me kind of seize up a little bit, but again,
then I try to feel the things I'm going to feel
and try to understand why are they saying that.
Why do they really feel that and what does that
mean behaviorally that I have to do differently
or my team has to do differently or maybe just
two people on my team need to do differently
and someone is extrapolating this out to
be a much bigger problem than actually is?
Awesome. Okay, and then we were going to shift
to what you've learned about giving hard feedback
so that someone actually listens and doesn't
just put up a shield and like, "It's not real."
So I think in giving feedback, you can never
fully control how someone else is going to
respond to that feedback. All you can control
is what you do, your body language and what you
say. What I have found is that if I can convey,
and I will say this very directly to people,
I care so much about you and I'm giving you this
feedback because I want you to be successful and
I want you to be able to reach the pinnacle of
what I know you can accomplish. And you do all
of that setup and you don't just hope that they
understand that, you actually explicitly say that
and you show that in your body language, then
it makes the other person much more receptive
to hearing whatever you have to say. Then I think
the other piece is that you've got to be direct.
The worst feedback is the kind of
passive-aggressive feedback versus saying
directly this is what you are doing or this is
how you are being perceived in the organization,
and here are the three things that you can do
to change the way you're being perceived or to
change the outcomes of what you're driving or
become more strategic or whatever it is that
I'm trying to give feedback on. I do a lot of
prep before I give someone a lot of feedback.
I really think about how can I frame this in
a way that's going to resonate with them that
doesn't come across as attacking them, but
helps them understand why what they're doing
isn't working or is being perceived poorly? And
try to give them examples and even examples that
I've personally had to go through myself of
how I've approached those situations. And let
them ask questions and brainstorm with them,
be part of the solution versus saying like,
"Here's all this feedback, now you
go figure out what to do with it."
This reminds me of Radical Candor. Basically
make people feel like you care deeply about them,
but be very direct about what they can be doing
better. Are there phrases or ways that you set
up the conversation? You mentioned a few
of just like, "I want to help you become
the best version of who you could be and what
you're capable of." Is there any phrases you
find helpful that you come back to often
of just a way to start the conversation?
Yeah, I think what I started with is like,
"I care a lot about you. You have a lot of
potential. I can see you doing these kinds of
things. I can see you getting to where you want
to go in your career." Sometimes I even start the
conversation by asking them, "What do you want to
do? Where do you want to go in your career?" And
that will help me frame up which of these things
are important. Because honestly, if someone wants
to be eventually like a CPO, the feedback I'm
going to give to them is very different than if
they're like, "Hey, I don't really want to manage
people ever. I just want to be the best I see
I can ever be." I'm not going to give them the
same feedback. And so having that conversation up
front also allows them even before I jump into the
feedback to give them their perspective of
what they want and then I can tailor the
conversation more to what they're looking for.
I think that has really helped as well make
sure that I focus on the things that are going to
really matter. During the feedback conversations,
I also try to frame things as this is how
you're being perceived than you are doing X.
Because I think even though it's hard to hear,
"Oh, hey, this person doesn't perceive you in
the way that you may think," then we can talk
about, "Well, what are ways that we can change
the perception?" I also think it's important
because sometimes people are like if you say,
"Hey, I don't think you're X," and then they're
like, "Well, yes I am." And if you're saying,
"Hey, well this is how other people perceive
you including me, but maybe this is not what
you are intending," and you actually say that,
you're giving them the benefit of the doubt
of actually how they're trying to show up is
different than how people are perceiving them.
You can have a better conversation then around,
"Well, what can you do to change that perception?"
You mentioned I see product managers, and this is
a good segue too. You're a big deal, fancy chief
product officer person. A lot of people listening
to this podcast are early career PMs or trying
to get into product. I want to ask a couple
of questions along these lines. One is about
getting into products. So, interestingly, you
got into product the same way I got into product,
which is you used to be an engineer and then
you moved into product within a company,
which is maybe one of the simplest ways to get
into product potentially. For people that are
trying to break into product management, what
advice do you often give them of how they could
go about doing it? I know there's never
the silver bullet, but what's your advice?
I definitely think doing it within the
same company is a lot easier than trying to
switch companies and switch jobs at the same
time because when you're within a company,
you've already built credibility, hopefully. And
if you haven't, then go crush it at your job so
you build the credibility. Then you can start to
raise your hand, interact with the product team,
take on projects and do things that allow you
to get some experience and build a relationship
with a leader on the product team who then may
be willing to take a chance on you to put you
into a product role even if you don't have the
experience. Especially when you're within the same
company, you bring other things to the table.
Let's say you're working in customer support,
well, you have a huge amount of knowledge about
what are the big problems that people are calling
up the support team or opening tickets on
the support team for, and that is valuable
knowledge for being a product manager.
You're coming from the sales side,
you're coming with a knowledge of how to
sell the product, what really resonates,
how do you do the objection handling, and that
can be a valuable perspective. If you come from
the engineering side, but you understand how the
product is built and you understand that technical
nuances of that well, that can also be a valuable
way to enter into the product team. That way,
even though you don't have the direct product
experience, you're still bringing something to
the table where you are going to have to
get trained on core product management,
but you're not going to have to be totally
trained on the business or the technology.
So is the advice basically get a job in any
function, not necessarily any function, but join a
company however you can essentially and then push
to try to get into the product team in some form?
Yeah, I think join a product adjacent function,
which honestly pretty much every function is
product adjacent, because what function does
product not engage with, but as closely product
adjacent as possible, and then yeah, find
your way into the product world from there.
Ideally there's something within the company,
there's some program I imagine that does this
sort of thing. Some companies have something
structured, some are just kind of ad hoc. Is
there anything there you're just like should you
talk about this in your interview just like, "Hey,
I would really love to become product
manager someday." Do you have anything
along those lines that would help me get
into that or not? Or should you not talk?
Well, I think it depends. For instance, when I
joined LiveRamp, which was my previous company
as a software engineer, I actually did say in
the interview process I want to become a product
manager I think. At that point I was still
early in my career, I didn't know for sure,
but I said that. Now that was a 20-person
startup, so it was worth saying it because
they didn't really have a product team and
I wanted to put it out there that that was
something I was interested in growing into.
If you're joining a 5000-person company, you're
hiring manager is probably not going to receive
it well if you're like, "Hey, I'm interviewing for
product marketing, but really what I want to do
is go into product." So, it just kind of depends
on the company and the stage. You have to play
that wisely. But I think once you're in a company,
then finding a way to make a relationship with
the product leader, or if you're in a startup
that is really small and they don't have product
management, well then you have the opportunity
to take on projects for sure that are product
management related because no one is doing that
work. Really taking initiative to do that so that
you can find an inroad into product management.
Kind of along these lines, you have a really
unique perspective on new PMs because you
teach product management at Stanford. You've
been doing that for a while. I just want to
ask you work with a lot of people that are new to
product, thinking about getting into product, then
get into product. What do you find are the things
that new PMs or people getting into product most
misunderstand about the role of PM or are most
surprised by when they become product managers?
When we interviewed students as we were designing
the class about what they wanted to learn,
what was most surprising to me was
that students would say, "Well,
can you teach me how to use Figma? Can you teach
me the tools that product managers are going to
have to use?" What was surprising me about that
was I don't think it's the tools that you need to
learn to be successful. I think what you need
to learn to be successful is how to take very
ambiguous situations and consistently
drive more and more clarity over time.
So, it was interesting to see this mismatch
between what people said they wanted to learn
and what I felt they actually needed to learn.
Now, having taught this class for a few years now,
I think talking to students who have then
left and become product managers, they've
seen a lot of this in practice now and I think
they understand that, but there is this mismatch
of people who haven't been in product management
saying they want to go and thinking that they need
to learn some tools or process versus the mindset
and the skills required to clarify ambiguity.
Along those lines, I actually saw you somewhere
in a talk or maybe something you wrote talk about
how creating this class and creating the
curriculum helped you crystallize your own
thinking on product and helped you crystallize
the mental models of becoming a product manager.
Is there anything that you recall from that
time of like here's something that's really
helped me understand about this function and the
skill as you were putting together the class?
Yeah, I know anytime you're teaching something,
you have to figure out a way to synthesize it for
another audience, and so many of us have learned
product management just figuring it out on the
job. I don't know if there's a particular
framework that I would say came out of that,
but what I found very interesting was seeing the
questions that people asked in the class and then
feeling like, "Oh, I understand how to answer
this question. I can provide an example for it."
That was super interesting to me because I didn't
expect that coming out of the conversation. Yes,
there's frameworks we developed to talk about
ideation and product discovery and all of that,
but I think those are fairly flexible frameworks.
What was most enlightening was being able to
crystallize the answers to some of these
questions, whether it was about how do you
interact as a PM effectively with engineering
or what happens if the data shows you that it
doesn't matter which direction you pick,
like there's merits to both ways. How do
you actually go about making those decisions?
It was very interesting being able to then have
those conversations with students and bring in the
real life examples. And I found in some situations
that actually go back to my own team and share
the same answer that I came up with in class,
I was like, "Oh, this is actually a valuable
thing to share with my team back at my company."
Reminds me of the recent chat I had with this
guy Alex Komoroske, where he talked about how
oftentimes talking with people helps them uncover
new insights that he had in his head and then
he writes them down as soon as he says something
that's really clever in any way. He's like, "Okay,
I'm going to remember that now." Coming back to
how to become a PM, so you see all these people
getting and taking this class want to become
product managers. I know they're like Stanford
students and people more likely hire Stanford
people. But I guess in terms of how they end
up becoming PMs, if you were to look at the pie
chart of the people that end up getting a PM job,
what's the biggest chunk? Is it they join at some
other function and then move into product? Do they
just join as a junior PM somewhere? How are people
actually getting into the PM role in that class?
Yeah, I think very few are directly going to an
established company and becoming a PM directly,
so I would say a big chunk of them. Some of them
are, but many of those then had PM experience to
begin with or had engineering experience
and then went to a technical company into
a PM role. The vast majority of them are
joining product adjacent roles or they're
going to small startups where they might be
doing product management, might be the first
product manager, or they might be doing
product management plus plus, chief of staff,
something like that where they get to put their
hands in product management, but it's a super
small company. So I think those have been the
two most successful paths to get into product.
Awesome. That's a really interesting
lens into how people actually get into
this role. Potentially final question,
but we'll see where it goes. I have this
recurring segment on this podcast called AI
Corner where I try to get a sense of just how
people are finding AI tools useful in their
work, in their life. So, let me just ask you,
is there anything you've found useful in some
AI tool in how you work? Like something you
found that helps you work more productively, more
efficiently, either you or people on your team?
One way that we're using AI today is summarizing
our user research calls. So, that has been really
valuable because we're doing all these calls all
the time, we're getting a ton of rich insights.
Some of those rich insights are related to
the specific project that we were doing this
call for and some of them aren't. And now we have
that summarized and tagged in a way where you can
look up any sort of thing that you want around the
calls that we've done and it'll find you the call,
it'll find you the context, it'll find you
the transcript and summarize exactly what
we've learned from that call. So we're starting
to use that more and more. It's very powerful
capability. I definitely think that that
kind of summarization of information for
PMs is a big unlock for organizations
and I think we're still in the very,
very early days of AI making a meaningful
difference to the way that PMs do their work.
Is there a specific tool that
you love to help you with that
that you may want to give a shout-out
to or is it something you guys built?
Yeah, we use Dovetail and it's been
fantastic. Connects into all of the
Zoom calls and everything, it does a great job
with summarization, with search, everything.
Awesome. I love it when someone recommends a
very awesome sponsor of the podcast. Dovetail
is ongoing and excellent sponsor, so I'm
really happy to hear that. Amazing. Anneka,
is there anything else that you thought you
wanted to share or that you want to leave
listeners with that you think might be helpful
before we get to a very exciting lightning round?
The mindset that you bring to your work
is actually the most important thing over
anything else that you can do. And if you are
approaching every situation as much as possible
with the positive mindset, you can do more
than you could ever possibly hope to achieve.
I'm going to pull on this thread because
this is such a powerful point and I think
it's easy to just hear that. It's hard to
learn to do it. Do you have any advice on
just how to build that mindset? Like it
connects to many of the things you said:
how can this be fun? How can I be grateful to this
person that's annoying me and the things that they
might teach me? Is there just anything you've
done that has helped you build this mindset?
Journaling is very powerful. So actually growing
up I journaled every single day of my life from
when I was 13 to when I was 23. And while
I cringe to go back to read any of those,
I think what it helped me do and build a practice
around that I still do today is when I have a lot
of thoughts going through my head, especially
negative thoughts, just putting them all down
on a piece of paper, writing them on my phone and
trying to explore why am I feeling this way? Why
am I getting triggered? What is it about the
situation that's making me feel so strongly?
And when I put it down on paper, then it takes
this thing that's abstract and things that I'm
ruminating on and actually makes it possible for
me to break it down and understand, "Well, okay,
this is something I may feel, but the why behind
it is a little irrational, so let me let this
go." I realize that this isn't rational way to
think about this. Whereas other things I start to
uncover, well, what is it about the situation and
what is it that I need to do differently? What's
within my control and what is it maybe that I
need to go talk to someone about and say, "Hey, I
need you to do this differently to be able to make
myself feel better and make the situation better."
It's interesting this is another thread that's
been coming up a bunch on the podcast recently
that when something is bothering you or something
is hard, the more you actually listen to that
part of yourself and dive into it and explore it
and give it a space to share and talk, the less
power it gets and the more space is created for
the stuff you actually want to take space. It's
not what you would expect because usually it's
like, "No, shut up, everything's fine." But the
more you actually hear that out, the easier
things get. So, I love that you share that.
It's like doing cognitive behavioral therapy on
yourself. That's how I think of it. I've never
actually done cognitive behavioral therapy, but
I've read a lot about it and sometimes when I go
through this, I'm asking myself the same questions
that I think are asked in those settings.
Love that. All right, Anneka,
is there anything else that you wanted
to share or leave listeners with?
I think that's all I can think of.
Well, with that, we've reached our very
exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
I'm ready.
All right. First question,
what are two or three books
that you've recommended most to other people?
The Hard Thing About Hard Things
by Ben Horowitz, such a great book,
great again about mindset of how to approach hard
things. Second is I'm a huge fantasy sci-fi fan,
so I love Brandon Sanderson's books. I
highly recommend those to people as well.
All I know about him is I saw videos
of him after COVID where he just said,
"I wrote five new books during COVIID."
I was like, "what is going on?"
He is someone that is at the top of his
craft and I admire people so much that
are truly the elite in what they do, and
he's truly the elite in what he does. He
writes a lot about writing, he podcasts a
lot about writing. It's pretty impressive.
And he writes fantasy books, is that right?
He writes fantasy, yep.
Okay, cool. It feels like a lot of
books to read though. I'm just like,
"Oh, my God, so many books." Okay, great.
Next question, do you have a favorite recent
movie or TV show that you've really enjoyed?
Again, on the fantasy sci-fi track, I really
like Fallout, which is a dystopian show based
on a post-apocalyptic, post-nuclear
war world. It's very entertaining.
Yeah, it's just very quirky and fun.
Yes.
And unexpected. Awesome. Do you
have a favorite product that
you've recently discovered that you really love?
My eight-foot iPhone charger. So I have
a cord that's very long that allows me to
move around the house and do stuff while
my phone is charging because my phone is
always running out of batteries. So, highly
recommend getting a super long charging cord.
I've got one of those and I know
exactly what you mean. Do you have
a favorite life motto that you often come
back to find useful and work during life?
I think it comes back to dealing with lots of
different types of people. I really try to remind
myself that everyone has something to teach and
everyone has something to learn. I think that
helps not only think about how you interact
with other people, but also combat imposter
syndrome because you have something to bring
to the table and teach as well as anyone else,
no matter what your age is, no matter what
your background, and leaning into that and
realizing that people can learn from you and you
can learn from others in every single situation.
Final question. I heard that you're a big fan of
Isaac Asimov. Do you have a favorite Asimov book,
one that you'd think if someone were to explore
his canon, they might want to start with?
I really like the Foundation series, so
starting with that is really good. It's
a very different style of writing. You kind of
have to stick with it, but it's good, I promise.
And I'll build on that and say, "Don't
watch the show because the show is so
different from the book series." I
don't know if you've seen it and-
Yes, I have.
... not nearly as good.
Okay.
I was just like, what is going
on? This is not the story.
Yeah, very different.
What are they doing? Amazing. Anneka,
this has been amazing. We covered so much
ground. I feel like this is going to help
a lot of people. Two final questions,
where can folks find you online if they
want to follow up on things, maybe ask you
questions or just check out the stuff you're
up to and how can listeners be useful to you?
You can find me on LinkedIn, follow me, DM me.
I would love to connect. The way you can help me
is we're actually redesigning our Stanford class
right now for PMs, and I would love to hear from
you if you don't have any PM experience, what
is it that you wish a class could teach you?
And that would be super helpful for me
as we're redesigning this class. Thanks.
Amazing. And the way they could share
that is DM you on LinkedIn or Twitter?
Yes.
Easy. Amazing. Anneka, thank
you so much for being here.
Thanks for having me.
Absolutely. My pleasure. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If you
found this valuable, you can subscribe
to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.