Most people are better at understanding the
feelings and sensations that typography and
logos give us than they give themselves credit
for, because what we are as people are endless
absorbers of patterns, and information, and
all this kind of stuff as we move throughout
the world. We don't take time to sit and digest
it, but it's still coming in and getting logged,
and so even as a non-designer, I think
you can look at examples of logos where
something's not quite right and be
like, "Something's not right here,
I just don't know how to name it." But I think
a good exercise is just like looking at fonts
that are available in the world and asking
yourself, "What feeling does this give me?"
Today, my guest is Jessica Hische. Jessica is a
design legend, and it was such an honor to both
have her on this podcast and also to work with
her on a refresh of my newsletter and podcast
logo and brand, which is launching around the
same time as this episode comes out. Jessica is
a lettering artist specializing in typographical
work for logos, film, books, and other commercial
applications. Her clients include Wes Anderson,
the United States Postal Service, Apple, Nike,
Tiffany and Company, The Gap, and Penguin
Books, and her work has been featured in
design and illustration annals, both in the U.S.
and internationally. She's helped create logos
for Philz Coffee, Eventbrite, and Mailchimp,
is a best-selling children's book author,
and if you live around the Bay Area, you've seen
her work all over the city without knowing it.
In our conversation, Jessica shares the
process that she went through to update
my logo and brand for my newsletter and podcast.
What specific elements of a logo and brand impact
how you feel about that brand, why a good enough
logo is just buying for a long time for most
startups, and when it makes sense to refresh your
look, also some really clever productivity tips,
design advice, and a bunch of really fun
stories. Jessica is a master at what she
does and I am excited to spread the Jessica
Hische gospel. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's the
best way to avoid missing future episodes, and
it helps the podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you Jessica Hische. Jessica, thank you
so much for being here. Welcome to the podcast.
Happy to be here.
I thought it'd be good to start with asking
you just to describe what it is you do,
because you're very atypical of the
kinds of guests I have in this podcast
and you also have very unique skillset.
Yes. Well, I will describe what I'm most
prominently known for, because I'm a person
who just does a lot of things, but the thing that
I do the most professionally is custom typography,
like bespoke lettering pieces. That
translates to working for all kinds
of things. Sometimes it's for film and
television. I've done movie titles and
things like that and television credits and
stuff. Sometimes it's book covers. Actually,
a lot of times, it's book covers, and then
a big part of my business is doing logos,
and logo refreshes, and things like that,
so basically being the person who knows
all the things so you don't have to have that
person on staff when it comes to typography.
This episode is brought to you by the Enterprise
Ready Conference, a one-day event in San Francisco
bringing together product and engineering leaders
shaping the future of enterprise SaaS. The
event features a curated list of speakers with
direct experience building for the enterprise,
including leaders from OpenAI, Vanta, Checkr,
Dropbox, and Canva. Topics include advanced
identity management, compliance, encryption, and
logging, essentially at complex features that most
enterprise customers require. If you're a founder,
exec, product manager, or engineer tasked with the
enterprise roadmap, this conference is for you.
You'll get detailed insights from industry leaders
that have years of experience navigating the
same challenges that you face today. Best of all,
it's completely free. Since it's hosted by WorkOS.
Spots are filling up quickly, make sure to request
an invite at enterpriseready.com. That's
enterpriseready.com. I am excited to chat with
Christina Gilbert, the founder of OneSchema, one
of our longtime podcast sponsors. Hi, Christina.
Yes. Thank you for having me on, Lenny.
What is the latest with OneSchema? I know you now
work with some of my favorite companies like Ramp,
Vanta Scale, and Watershed. I heard
that you just launched a new product
to help product teams import CSVs from
especially tricky systems like ERPs.
Yes. We just launched OneSchema FileFeeds, which
allows you to build an integration with any system
in 15 minutes as long as you can export a CSV to
an SFTP folder. We see our customers all the time
getting stuck with hacks and workarounds, and
the product teams that we work with don't have
to turn down prospects because their systems
are too hard to integrate with. We allow our
customers to offer thousands of integrations
without involving their engineering team at all.
I can tell you that if my team had
to build integrations like this,
how nice would it be to be able to
take this off my roadmap and instead
use something like OneSchema, and not just
to build it but also to maintain it forever.
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many
horror stories of multiday outages from
even just a handful of ad records. We are
laser-focused on integration reliability to
help teams end all of those distractions
that come up with integrations. We have
a built-in validation layer that stops
any bad data from entering your system,
and OneSchema will notify your team
immediately of any data that looks incorrect.
I know that importing incorrect data can
cause all kinds of pain for your customers
and quickly lose their trust. Christina, thank
you for joining us. If you want to learn more,
head on over to oneschema.co. That's oneschema.co.
Part of the reason I was excited to have you on
this podcast is that I was lucky enough to get
to work with you on a refresh of my logo and
brand for my newsletter and my podcast, which
I'm very, very excited about. It's actually
going to be launching right around the time of
this episode going live, so this is, in part,
a celebration of the new look, and logo, and
brand. I thought it'd be an awesome excuse to
bring you on the podcast and give an inside
glimpse into the process of updating a logo
and a brand. Partly, because I think it'll just
be people are like, "What the hell? How did this
change? Where did this come from? Why this versus
that?" and also just for people that are thinking
about this for their own product or business,
to understand the process and understand when
it might be right for them, when it might be not
right for them. Broadly, how does that sound?
Sure. Yeah, of course. Everybody that starts a
company knows that they need a logo. That is a big
thing. Some people start a company and think the
logo is going to drive the culture of the company,
which I don't think that that is true. I think
that the product itself, and the team you build,
and the people you put together are the thing that
should be driving things forward, but I do think
the logo and the brand assets can generate a lot
of both internal and external excitement and just
tell people what to expect from the thing that
they're about to engage with. Some people say
don't judge a book by its cover. I'm the opposite,
where any book... The cover of the book should be
giving you incredible insight into what is on
the interior of the book and setting the tone
and setting the vibe so that when you open the
book and read the book, it's a symbiotic thing
where you're like, "Oh, I understand what I was
getting into. This got me excited about starting
it," and whatever. It keeps that ball rolling.
But with the refresh work that I do, a lot of
people start companies and they have a certain
amount of money. If they're bootstrapping it,
they have less. If they get venture money, they
have a little bit more. But what they don't want
to do is spend venture money on a massive brand
exploration when you're still in the hiring
process, you're still trying to get early stage
engineers, and all that kind of stuff, and so
I am sort of a weird contrarian in this way in the
brand world where brand people are like, "Brand
is everything. You need to take a significant
investment in brand because that guides the
vision of the product or whatever." But I think
being a bit more of an insider within the tech
world, I understand that sometimes people start
companies and have an intention to do something.
While they're doing that, they're building the
team, they're doing cool stuff, but then the
company has to pivot for one reason or another,
whether a competitor immediately comes out with
a thing that you're doing or the technology
that you're doing gets postponed, whatever's
going to feed into it, and so if you invest super
heavily on the whole brand vision from the jump,
sometimes it's like throwing away money if you
have to pivot. What I love about the work that I
do is that I understand that a lot of people
have to just have something to put on decks
and have something to put on a holding page
or whatever, and internal teams are totally
capable of doing that early work. But then if
it does become successful, you don't want to get
locked into whatever it is that you had to throw
together before an investor meeting or something.
I come in then to take the existing vibe and
smooth it out, address any of the concerns that
came up. A lot of times, it's really utilitarian
stuff like this doesn't scale well, or this thing
falls apart in this context, or we never had a
good avatar version of it, or whatever. Sometimes
it's really specific utilitarian fixes, and
sometimes it's just about growing it up and
sophisticated it without losing what was there
in the first place that people got excited about.
To give people maybe a couple more tactical piece
of advice here, what's a sign that it's maybe
time to do something with your logo and brand
from you took a first pass, it's good enough,
your wife made one, your husband made you
a logo, it's like, "Well, this is great.
Let's just go with this"? What's a sign that
maybe it's time to, "Okay, we should actually
at least uplevel this, not necessarily hire
studio but takes something to make it better"?
Well, one of the things is if, suddenly, you're
starting to deal with the greater rollout of the
look and feel of the brand. If you, at first,
just basically had a really beta website and
small version of the app but you're about to do
a new one that kind of updates and expands it,
that could be a really good time to roll it
out. One of the things that a lot of people
do when they're starting a company is that they'll
make a logo with a font that is really popular or
widely available or free. If you are about to,
let's say, print a bunch of swag for new hires,
or you're hosting a conference, or whatever
is that event where suddenly you're going to
physically invest money in making stuff with your
brand on it, that might be a good time to do it.
One of the reasons why I tell people why
having a custom logo or custom typography
can really matter is that if you're using
something that's available to everyone,
the chances of someone else coming in
and copying you are very easy and high.
You might be one of these lucky companies that
just out the gate is outrageously successful,
but with success comes people climbing up
behind you trying to copy your success.
If that success is very easily copyable and
people will try to trick your customers into
coming their way by repeating the things that
you're doing, including the branding, one way
to avoid that is by doing something that's more
customized when it comes to the logo and brand.
Let's actually talk about the work that you
put into updating my logo and brand. From that,
we can spin off into lessons and insights
that you have along these lines. Overall,
just high level, what's the process you
go through to go through a logo refresh?
Sure, of course. Super high level, it's figuring
out what the goals are. Some people have a goal
where they want their customers to not notice it
at all. They're like, "Oh, everybody loves this,
but I, the person with a design eye, can
see all the problems with it. I need to
roll something out that fixes the problems that
I see but that no one else really notices." If
that's one approach to it, which is a very
close in refresh where we're just trying out
little things to make it feel custom or fixing
things that have come up when stress-tested,
whether it looks crazy when you scale it and looks
like horsey and heavy-handed when you scale it too
big or when you scale it too small, you lose a
lot of legibility and stuff like that. That's
what would be a really close in exploration.
For other people, they might have bigger goals
where they're about to pivot the company to try to
attract a different audience or things like that.
They might have this really cool and successful
group of people that are super users but they're
trying to expand it, so then it's about, "What can
we do to shift the vibe to make it include these
new people without excluding our core folks?" My
first round is figuring out what that scope is,
how experimental, how broad are we going to go
for that first round, because then everything
else cascades from there. If we go really broad
for the first round, then we're in this process of
narrowing down the scope as we go down. Whereas if
we go really close in for the first round, we're
already just talking about really technical stuff.
This is another thing that is a little bit unique
to me that not everybody else does,
but I will hand off files to clients to
try in situ really early on if what we're
trying to do is solve utilitarian issues.
Most other people are like, "No, you don't get
the files until we do the final because I don't
want you to run away with this or whatever."
There has to be some trust with it. Yeah,
figure out what we're trying to accomplish and
always keep those goals in mind, and then scope
out the process based on what those goals are.
For each round, we're addressing different things.
First round might be about just capturing the
overall look and trying things as broad as we can,
and then the next round is, "Okay. Well,
now we have generally a look that we want,
but is it the right weight? Is it the right
letter height? Do we have enough details?"
That kind of thing, and then we get narrower
and nerdier as we go along in the process.
Awesome. In the experience of my podcast logo,
I was an ass. At the end of it, I'm like,
"No, this isn't right," because we narrowed,
narrowed, narrowed, and then I was like, "No,
I'm not feeling it," and then we unnarrowed
it and went back. [inaudible 00:15:02]
That is not an uncommon experience though. This is
why there's a few things that I'm not opposed to
that I know people that are very opposed to. I'm
not opposed to Frankensteining options together.
To me, it's like I'm giving you a menu of all
the things that we can do, but I'm like a chef
that puts a menu together where you can combine
different appetizers and different mains and they
all still make sense. Some people will give you a
menu and if you try to do that, it's insane and it
tastes terrible. But for me, everything that we're
doing, I feel like, mixes and matches fairly well,
and I will let you know if it doesn't.
It's not unreasonable for clients to go
down one path and then use that as validation
or confirmation that something that we did
much earlier was actually the right way. In that
way, if a client ever asks me to do something,
they're like, "Let's see it in purple or
whatever." There's designers that will
really fight you tooth and nail, because they're
like, "That is wrong, that is wrong," but I know
that some people just have to see it before they
can let it go. Sometimes you have to walk down
a path before you're able to understand
what the right thing to do was all along.
That's exactly how it felt for me. Going back
to the goals, the different goals people have
when they're exploring this, you mentioned
there's just little problems with the logo,
it doesn't scale, it doesn't print well,
that kind of thing. Another goal is people
are pivoting and they want to change
the vibe and the feel of the brand.
What other goals might appear that you've
come across why people want to do this?
Well, sometimes there's a legibility issue
that is really glaring once you see it and
then people are too close in to notice it,
so this is why it's like you have to show it
to a lot of people that aren't familiar with
looking at those letter forms and stuff. The
one that came to mind immediately when you asked
was when I did a refresh for Jeni's Ice Cream,
which is a really amazing ice cream brand based
out of Columbus, Ohio. They had a few utilitarian
things in mind. They had this long J that created
this pocket of white space underneath it that
made it really hard to design with, but then
the biggest glaring one was that they decided
to make the apostrophe of the Jeni's over the
I as a cool thing. It made the word look like
it said penis because of the way that J was drawn.
It had a little loop at the top of the J. That was
the most specific fix that I've ever had to do,
is make the logo not say penis anymore. But yeah,
I feel like a lot of it is misreads. When
you think about logos and things like that,
you want it to be something that, at a super
fast glance, people can read it right away.
That doesn't mean that everything has to be
simple, but it just means that everything
has to be incredibly legible, especially when
you're starting a new company or you have a
less recognizable brand. Because eventually, you
become a household name and then people can look
at just the color and recognize that it's you or
whatever, but it takes a long time building equity
before you get that. Until that, it's really
important that the legibility is just super tight.
Let's talk about actually thinking
through my new logo and brand. Can
you just talk about what you had
in mind as you started to explore
directions and we started narrowing what was
the mindset, and the approach, and the vibe?
I think with the Lenny's brand, you are what
I would call a person that has a beloved fan
base that we don't want to exclude or offend by
shifting gears super crazily. When I was looking
at redoing your brand, it was about what's here
that we can look at that we should keep or at
least explore keeping in order to make sure that
it still feels the same on the other side? We
didn't want to do anything super drastic. Some
of the things to think about in that way are
you have this sort of handwritten approach to a
lot of the parts of your brand, and I was like,
"How do we do something that feels handwritten,
that feels like it could jive with the handwriting
scripts and stuff that you were using but might
feel a little bit more refined moving forward and
in a way that could blend with illustration so
that the illustration and the letter forms all
feel like they were created by the same hand?"
A lot of times for me, when it comes to doing
an exploration like that, it's about how do we
make sure everything feels like it was created
at the same time and not that we just tacked on
new things? Figuring out how to blend everything
together is important. Color was also a big
one. I feel like people's color stories are
something that is an immediate read, where
if you blur your eyes and look at a brand,
you can recognize it by its color, and so I
think keeping your color similar was a big
one too. But then I really wanted to try different
approaches with the typography, doing stuff that
was a little bit more clean, doing stuff that
still had a bit of a funky edge to it. Because
your original Lenny's podcast type had this sort
of cut papery, a little bit off kilter vibe to it,
and so trying to capture that but with new
cleaner typography. That was really fun.
I was using a typeface Degular as part of it,
which has a nice wonkiness to it. It was drawn
by a friend of mine, James Edmondson, who I
love all of his stuff. That was one of the
things that we approached because I felt like
it could capture the look of the original cut
paperesque type. But yeah, it was really fun to
try a lot of different things and work within the
iconography that you had used on a few stuff
with the microphones, and also marshmallows,
and campfires, and all kinds of things, and
just trying to make a more unified system.
Are there things that didn't work as you
tried to explore this process that you recall,
that might be worth sharing of just like, "Oh,
that was a cool concept," but didn't
quite work the way you thought?
With working on this refresh, so much of it was
thinking about what are the immediate uses of the
logo. Your logo, you have these very specific
uses that you need it for, the avatar for the
podcast being a top one. Some people, they'll
design a logo and then have these illustrative
versions of the logo that get rolled out for
other things, but I feel like those layouts
were actually more important than even just
having a basic letterhead-esque logo. That's an
interesting way to approach it, because usually,
it's like let's start simple, and expand, and make
it crazier. I felt like we had to always keep
those things in play, so it was designing brand
assets while also designing the logo. Sometimes
you'll see examples of that in early explorations
just because it makes it feel real to the client.
That's why there's always the tote bag. You got
to put the logo on the tote bag and then it feels
real or whatever. But in our case, we had really
specific uses that needed to get explored very
early on, and that made it a slightly different
process for me. In terms of things that didn't
work though, I think just trying to work on the
level of detail within the illustration and type
so that it could shrink down, because we knew...
One of the primo examples of the logo being
used was on that podcast avatar, and some of the
versions felt a little bit too detailed to shrink
down that much. Trying to get the balance of that,
having the illustrations feel illustrative and
whole, but not when they scaled up, to feel too
simple like we just pulled it from a icon library.
I think that was an interesting challenge.
One of the impetuses for changing my logo,
for motivating me, is my wife's a designer,
as you know. She's got strong opinions about
my logo, and she always was making fun of
my logo saying it looked like a clip art
fireplace that anyone just could just plug
and play. She's always like, "Oh, that's
so bad. You got to change it." That was
one of the motivators. I think I might have
shared that when we started working together.
Yeah. Also too, I think that really talks to
what I was saying earlier about making sure that
everything feels like it was created together
rather than it feeling like these disparate
elements, because I think you can have an icon
or logo that is quite simple as long as the rest
of the brand matches that simplicity. I think, for
you, the biggest thing was making the illustration
and the typography just feel like it came from
the same universe instead of feeling like these
separate elements. When I first moved to San
Francisco, I moved to San Francisco from New York,
and as a New Yorker, I had an apartment with
a full kitchen that never got used. I just ate
at restaurants and did takeout for the seven
years or whatever that I lived in New York.
Learning to cook, at first, when you learn how
to cook, it's like you're making a pot full of
ingredients and none of the ingredients are
actually working together. But then the more
you do it and the more you understand how these
things are meant to blend and cook at different
temperatures at different times, you start having
this cohesive dish rather than hot ham water. You
know what I mean? I feel like a lot of clients
come to me and they have hot ham water when it
comes to their brand. It's just about turning
that into a soup, something that feels real.
I want to take a quick tangent. Most people
listening to this podcast are not designers.
They're product managers, founders, engineers,
and folks building product. I've always wanted
to see the world through the eyes of a designer,
because there's so much I don't see and there's so
much that affects how I think about something that
I don't understand when I look at a logo, and so I
thought it might be helpful just to spend a little
time helping people see a designer a little bit.
Let me just ask you this question. When people
look at a logo or a brand, what are just elements
that make it what it is, that make you feel the
thing you want to feel that we may not recognize?
I think most people are better at understanding
the feelings and sensations that typography and
logos give us than they give themselves credit
for, because what we are as people are endless
absorbers of patterns, and information, and
all this kind of stuff as we move throughout
the world. We don't take time to sit and digest
it, but it's still coming in and getting logged.
That's why if you see something funky in the
world, you're like, "That's weird. I don't like
that. I don't know why I don't like it, but I know
I don't like it." I think even as a non-designer,
you can see that in typography. The whole
being able to recognize patterns thing,
I talked about this a bit at config, it's like
it's a safety thing. Looking into the world, your
eyes can spot that thing that's a little bit off,
and that thing that's off feels not safe to you.
It's thinking about when we look at a meal and
there's a thing on the plate that looks like it's
moldy or something like that. You understand
that doesn't look right to me, this doesn't
smell right to me. Your body knows it before
your brain knows it. Even as a non-designer,
I think you can look at examples of logos
where something's not quite right and be like,
"Something's not right here, I just don't know
how to name it." But I think a good exercise is
just looking at fonts that are available in
the world and asking yourself, "What feeling
does this give me?" and just write them down. It
doesn't matter, just give yourself permission to
say whatever is happening in your mind, the first
thing. Don't overanalyze it. Just look at it and
be like, "That feels calm to me. That feels
exciting to me. That feels whatever to me."
The more you do that, the more you
can start seeing similarities in the
ones that feel exciting, and the ones that
feel calm, and the ones that feel whatever,
and then get into analyze mode of, "Oh, these 10
things that I said feel calm are a lighter weight,
have more generous spacing, have rounded edges,
have rounder bowls to the letter forms." You just
start seeing commonalities between the
things. It's just about seeing them all
together to understand what those similarities
are. I think anybody can do that. I mean,
you're not going to have the language of the
leg of the R and the tittle of the I. Don't
worry about that. You don't have to know
typography language to think about it, but
anybody's capable of doing that. It can be really
fun to just stop and ask yourself and notice.
This is great. I want to go actually a little
deeper. What I'm hearing is look at something,
tap into the feeling you feel when you look
at it, actually pay attention to it because
there's wisdom in that. The specific things that
you pointed out that impact that feeling are,
you mentioned, spacing between the letters,
the edges. I imagine there's just the color
of it. What other specific elements impact the
way someone feels when they look at a logo?
There's the width of the letter, so if it's really
narrow versus really wide. I always think about
the width, the weight, [inaudible 00:28:35]
facing, sort of detailed treatment of things,
whether things are very hard and jagged or
soft and how soft it is. Sometimes we just
add a tiny bit of softness so that it just feels
printed. You can take a typeface like Helvetica,
just the one everybody knows. But if you take
Helvetica and just ever so slightly round the
edges just a little bit, all of a sudden, you
have this typeface that feels more vintage,
or softer, or whatever, because we're
perceiving it, we would perceive it
if it were printed on paper versus perceiving
it as this hard geometric piece of technology
that we're viewing. You know what I mean?
I know that it's because when you look at stuff
printed on a page, it bleeds into the paper a
little bit, which means that that softness reminds
us in our bodies of a thing that we've seen that
was printed. It's cool to sort of walk back your
feelings also. You'll look at something and go,
"That feels like this," and then ask yourself why
does it feel like that. It might be because you
saw it on a flyer for a band when you were 22,
and it brought out that feeling in you of
what it felt like to be 22 at that thing.
That's a very specific feeling to you, but
it can inform your decisions about design,
because you can be like, "Oh, I'm not that
much of a special snowflake." Other people
might have that same reaction but have different
experiences that are adjacent to that reaction.
It's cool because you are reverse-justifying
decisions. I think that's a really fun exercise
to do, is to Song Exploder your intuition.
You make a decision intuitively or look at
something and intuit what you feel from
it, and then really try to dive in,
"Why do I feel that way? What could this have
reminded me of that made me feel that way?"
You have to be just so forgiving and loose with
yourself as you do it because then you'll get
into some really weird stuff, and that's really
great inspiration juice for picking other things.
I love the exercise that you gave. The one you
gave earlier is look at a bunch of fonts, look
at your font folder. Is that a place to go, just
open up your font folder and just go through them?
Totally. Look at your font folder, or go to
MyFonts, or a place where there's a ton of fonts,
and just search for something. Search for
sans serif or whatever. Search for a really
basic category of fonts. Serif, sans serif,
script, whatever, the top level edge of stuff,
and then just page through, page through, page
through. Screenshot stuff that you like and make
a folder full of screenshots, and then you can
take those screenshots and start categorizing
them. "Oh, this one feels feminine. This one
feels masculine, this one feels aggressive.
This one feels whatever." Just take some
notes on it. Then, you ask yourself, "Well,
why did I feel that way?" You're like, "Oh, well,
this feels feminine because it reminds me of
wedding invitations," and wedding invitations feel
inherently bridey versus groomy. All of a sudden,
you're like, "Okay. Well, now I know that
if I'm going to use a script for something,
this zone of script feels very wedding, so maybe
I avoid that for this brand that's actually a
cutting edge food packaging company or whatever
because it feels too aligned with that industry."
Stereotypes are real and trends are real,
and what can sometimes happen is some
industry usurps an entire style for a period
of time. If you use anything within that style,
it's like you're aligning yourself to that
industry. I mean, everybody that does branding,
one of the things that they do is they analyze
the competitors of the company. You just look at
a landscape of what are all the competitors doing,
what is their visual vibe, and do I lean into that
or do I avoid that? If I lean into it, then I'm
immediately getting this... Everyone that looks
at it understands I'm a FinTech company because I
look like a FinTech company. If my whole thing is
I'm trying to be divergent from that, I'm trying
to show how different I am from the status quo,
then you use it as a reactionary thing of I
want to do nothing like that and do something
really different so people understand
this isn't just another FinTech company.
Yeah. I'm thinking green. The color green has to
be a part of the logo if you
want to be a FinTech company.
Yeah, exactly. If you're trying to
be weird, then you're like teal.
On this topic of seeing a designer, is there
any other tip, just before we move on to a
different topic, of just how someone could
learn to see a designer a little bit more?
Yeah. Another thing to notice, because
I'm assuming you're... Product people,
I feel like a lot of product people end up
having some engineering background, whether
or not they're engineers themselves. They have to
interface with the engineers and they build stuff,
and so they come at it from a data standpoint.
I can always tell when there's an engineer that
has suddenly got taken an interest in
type design and is now a type designer,
because everything is very, very regular. You can
draw a grid on top of everything and the lines
all line up perfectly. You see lots of reverse
justification of that when people are making logos
and they have a more engineering background. The
thing to notice, that is interesting within type,
is that, yes, you're absolutely following
rules, but you're breaking those rules
quite often to correct for optical tricks.
If you look at a geometric sans serif, for
instance, that's like a category of sans serifs,
and they're meant to have a lot of really strong
geometry, be very regular, like most of the sans
that you think of that you're like, "I'm in love
with this over the last 10 years," like geometric
sanses. But when you really start to examine them,
you notice that there's all these little
things that people are doing to make them
look perfectly geometric even though they are
not mathematically perfectly geometric. That's
another thing that you can do, whether you're
doing it in Figma or doing it somewhere else,
is just type out a couple of lowercase letters.
Lowercase specifically are really good for
analyzing this because they're smaller than the
uppercase letters. You usually have to accommodate
for the weight a little bit differently. You'll
notice that when strokes combine, so say I have an
A and I'm combining the lower bowl of the A, I'm
going to get a little thinner as I come into that.
Or say I have a two-storey A, so a two-storey
A is the one that's like this and then a bowl,
you might notice that this vertical of the A
there, the bowl actually eats into that stroke
a little bit to erase a little bit of that added
weight that would've been perceived optically had
you kept everything perfectly regular. It's
weird because you end up creating something
that's perfect and then have to make it not
perfect in order to make it be perceived as
perfect. That's another just fun thing to start
noticing. You notice it a lot more on typefaces
and typography that is heavier in weight, because
when things are heavier weight, you're constantly
managing these really inky moments where things
join together and you have to subtract a bunch of
weight from that so that it doesn't get perceived
as this dark mark where the letter is happening.
I think about lowercase Rs and lowercase Ns,
where the shoulder of the N or the R comes out,
sometimes the top of the R is actually
narrower at the top than it is on the bottom,
and that's to try to subtract some of that
weight in there where that join happens. Anyway,
that's just a fun thing to notice that you
have to do that. Once you start seeing it,
you start seeing where it happens more often,
and the answer of why it happens is because
correcting for this optical weight issue. You're
like, "Oh, man. Now I have x-ray vision. I can see
all these weird things I've never seen before."
It's very fun. But anyway, a lot of people, when
they first start out doing typography, whether
you're an engineer or whether you are a designer,
they don't account for that. I can always just
look at something and see whether someone is truly
an expert at typography or whether this is a fun
hobby for them when they're pretty fresh at it.
The exercise here is open up Figma, start typing,
and make it really big so you can
basically see the font really zoomed in.
A single letter.
Make a single letter the whole page
and then just draw some vertical lines,
or do the thing where you draw a little circle
or whatever and see if that circle is the same
size at the point where two strokes
join together or the point where the
stroke is just vertical and on its own.
You'll notice that there's differences
even in typography that's meant to
look extremely rigid and geometric.
I want to come back to my logo just to
close the loop there. Talk about just
the final result that we landed on, and
why you think that was the final answer,
and what you think people might get
from it, whatever comes to mind.
Yeah, totally. I think the final answer or the
final logo, we took it down a lot of different
paths trying to see where it was going to land,
but ultimately ended up keeping it pretty close
to home and really focusing on that asset of the
fire. We tried so many different versions of it's
microphones with the fire and marshmallows with
the fire, et cetera. It was just about sometimes
the simplest solution is the correct solution. I
don't know, I just feel like in terms of what we
were doing for blowing it out and making it
really cohesive, we went a lot of directions
where there might've been multiple versions of
the logo depending on the scale and ultimately
ended up in a place where it's much more
in line and consistent across the bar.
Yeah. Maybe what I'll do is we'll share, I
don't know if you're comfortable with that,
we could just share all the iterations
somewhere that we went through.
Oh, yeah. I love sharing
iterations. It's very fun. Yeah.
Okay, cool. Sweet. The biggest issue we
had with the podcast logo specifically is,
originally, I was thinking the mic
made sense to differentiate it from
the newsletter. At the end of it, it's just
like, "Why do we have this freaking mic in
there? It just feels strange." That's where
we revisited the whole idea and killed the
mic and went back to a different version
of the fireplace but with marshmallows.
Yeah, I love the marshmallows.
Awesome. I love it. That was my wife's...
My wife loves the marshmallows also,
and it's so versatile. We can
use it in so many different ways.
Indeed.
I guess maybe one last thread there is we
explored handwritten typography that you
created from scratch, and then there's
the block letters. Maybe just thoughts
on those two options and benefits and
why go one direction versus another?
The handwritten one, I really liked because
I felt like we could bring the line quality
of the illustration into the handwriting, but
then the only problem with the handwriting is
that if you want to blow that out, if you want to
include other handwriting throughout the rest of
the brand, finding something that matches that
perfectly without creating a custom typeface
is a whole thing. I really like being able to
combine the two, where we have this broader
visual vocabulary that we can pull from,
because you're going to have headlines,
you're going to have subheads, you're going to
have all these other uses for typography moving
forward. If you just have one thing to pull from,
it's a lot harder to work with. It's just nicer
when you have a few elements to play with. It's
like having a wardrobe. If you have only one
shirt and one pair of pants, there's only so many
things that you can do. But if you have all these
things that work together and can recombine, then
you can blow out a brand system much more easily.
Yeah. That's one of my favorite
things about working with you,
is you create all these different variations
of ways to use it. It doesn't always have to
be the handwritten one. It could be the
blocky outlining one. It's not like,
"This is it, don't change anything about
this. This is the only way to use it."
Well, part of that is because some brands, if you
have a massive company, like hundreds of employees
generating hundreds of things, sometimes having
too many assets can overcomplicate stuff. Because
unless you have a really, really well-written
brand book outlining how to do everything that
people are adhering to very closely, you can
get the assets running rampant throughout all
of the stuff and being used incorrectly.
But because you're not a massive company
and you have creative control over the things
that are happening and can help direct that,
we can be much more playful with the assets and
give you the ability to use things in different
ways. It depends on how much you trust all
the people that are handling your assets.
I am of the mind that you shouldn't need a
500-page brand book in order to direct how
the brand is used moving forward, and that if
you do, the brand might be quite complicated,
or there might be even just parts of the logo
that make it difficult to work with. My goal
always when designing a logo is to design a logo
that's so easy to use that you don't have to be
an extremely skilled designer to design well with
it. That's my number one goal, because I know not
everybody is going to be at a stage where they
have an internal brand team or a designer that's
a rock star designer that can work with really
complicated assets and make them look good.
I just want the assets to teach you
themselves, by just how they exist,
how to use it. You, as a person that has any
taste whatsoever, and hopefully people that
you're hiring for any job at your company have
some degree of taste. If you hire an engineer,
they have to have taste about how that
happens. If you hire a marketing person,
they have to have taste about how that happens.
They should be able to look at that and intuit
most of the way that you should be able to use it
without being explicitly told, "Do not do this."
This episode is brought to you by Merge. Product
leaders, yes, like you, cringe when they hear
the word integration. They're not fun for
you to scope, build, launch, or maintain,
and integrations probably aren't what led you to
product work in the first place. Lucky for you,
the folks at Merge are obsessed with integrations.
Their single API helps SaaS companies launch
over 200 product integrations in weeks,
not quarters. Think of Merge like Plaid,
but for everything B2B SaaS. Organizations
like Ramp, Dorado, and Electric use Merge
to access their customer's accounting data to
reconcile bill payments, file storage data to
create searchable databases and their product,
or HRAS data to auto provision and deprovision
access for the customer's employees. Yes, if
you need AI-ready data for your SaaS product,
then Merge is the fastest way to get it.
Want to solve your organization's integration
dilemma once and for all, book and attend a
meeting at merge.dev/lenny and receive a $50
Amazon gift card. That's merge.dev/lenny.
This is a good circle back to something
you touched on earlier that I wanted to come back
to, which is a lot of companies, in your opinion,
put too much weight on the power of brand,
and rebranding, and how much a brand can fix
their problems. Can you just again share your
perspective on just how this might be an issue
for people where they almost overemphasize
the power of brand? [inaudible 00:44:32]
Yeah. Well, there's different companies. There's
companies where brand is literally everything,
where they're doing something that's not crazy
innovative in the first place and the brand is
the thing that is the whole company, and that's
fine. That's a completely valid way to do stuff.
It's like people that can take in information
and recommunicate it in a way to another audience
or whatever that they hit that audience in a
way that the original information couldn't do.
Think about all of the people who write books on
psychology, and medicine, and all kinds of stuff
that write it for a broader popular audience.
They're the ones reading the medical papers,
they're the ones digesting all of this really
huge complicated data, and turning it into
something that normal people can read. I think
that there are companies that are doing that.
They're taking a thing that is not innovative or
isn't like they're not the only ones doing it,
but they're repackaging it in a way that takes
that and makes it so accessible to so many people.
In that case, brand can matter immensely,
where the brand really is the thing that
shows people that the thing that you're
doing has value. But for a lot of people,
the brand should be somewhat invisible so
that the thing itself becomes the star. If
we think about the experiences
that we have using products,
sometimes there's products where there's a ton
of fun and delight built into how you use it,
and that can happen through brand through design
choices and things like that. Sometimes the
delight is the fact that nothing is getting in
your way as you're using that product. You just
figure out what's your ethos of your company. Is
the whole thing about doing a thing well, doing
it simply, and making sure that everything gets
out of the way of that experience, or is it like
we're trying to generate this delightful thing
or we're trying to open it up to a new audience
or whatever? Depending on whatever that goal is,
brand can have a different place in that equation.
I think some of this unique perspective
on the power brand and the need for it in
tech companies comes from you're not like
a tech person. You work with tech people,
you work with tech companies. Do you feel like
that has an impact on the way you think and
the value that you bring to companies to
give them this very outside perspective?
I mean, most of the folks that I know that work in
brand or traditional graphic design, print design,
they don't necessarily have a lot of insight into
how building companies works. They're not friends
with a ton of startup founders and things like
that. I've just had been in this very fun position
being like everyone's token creative person in The
Bay for a while, and this been for a long time. I
remember speaking at a Silicon Valley event that
was women in Silicon Valley in 2009 or 2010,
something like that. It's interesting to be
a person that has never actually, themselves,
worked at a tech company but felt so involved
and understanding about how all of that works.
My partner, the reason why we're in The Bay is
because he got hired by Facebook back in 2011.
We were olds at the time. Take that
with a grain of salt, don't judge me.
Because we were 28, 29 coming over to work
at Facebook and everybody there was 23, 24,
and so all the people that we ended up meeting
in The Bay were more people our age that were
moving on to start companies and things like
that. We just got to see that perspective so
clearly of what it is to branch out on your
own, to fundraise, to do all this stuff,
to pivot, to do little experimental apps and see
where that goes to get acquired as a team versus
getting acquired as a technology or whatever.
I've been able to see that in a way that I feel
like a lot of people that do my job don't get to
see. That makes me very sympathetic and towards
what it is to want to build a brand as a founder.
I understand that you have limited resources and
those resources aren't necessarily going to get
devoted to doing a $200,000 brand exploration,
because when you have $500,000 of money at all for
a year to try to get things going, you certainly
should not spend half of that money on branding.
That's my opinion, but that's not to say that
brand can't be important and can't come in at
some level or can't be thought of as a partnership
between you and someone else where... There's
this whole idea of fractional leadership now,
which I feel like hasn't really infiltrated my
world as much, but I don't know why it hasn't,
because most people don't have internal comms
teams, internal brand teams, until the company
is very mature. The idea that you could bring
someone in who is a real expert in whatever
it's that they do, just as you need them, and
they just get consultant equity kind of thing,
that should be more present because people don't
necessarily need to have internal brand teams
for the first six months to a year of when they're
doing stuff unless they grow really significantly.
Along these lines, you have a pretty unique way
of pricing your work. For people that may want
to explore this with you, share whatever you can
about just how you think about pricing and ideally
even an order magnitude of pricing so they're
like, "Oh, okay. We should actually do this."
To go back to the process how it's always about
figuring out what people are trying to accomplish,
so a lot of my process scales depending on how
broad of an exploration that we're doing. The way
that I treat it is I treat my branding work not
dissimilarly to how I treat commercial lettering,
which is atypical. Brand people, what they
typically do is because the client has to
own the assets outright at the end no matter what,
they tend to do is bill everything that the client
owns everything as you are moving along. It's
all sort of work for hire, but the idea being
that it's a buyout of everything that is being
made. What that means is that when a branding
agency is pricing stuff for you, they're
taking the buyout rights and baking it into
every round of work so that every round gets more
expensive because you are owning all of the work.
What I do is I treat it much more like a
commercial lettering project where I say,
"You have to own the rights to this eventually,
but hey, let's break that out and let's keep the
creative process lighter and less expensive so
then we have more room to explore. So then if
some stakeholder comes in last minute and blows
everything else up and we need to start over,
you haven't already paid to own everything that
we've created, you just pay to own the thing
that we create in the end that gets chosen."
I really like the idea of keeping the creation
process more flexible and to try to scale to
what people need versus having a really rigid
way of approaching everything. Sometimes people
will bring me on really early in the process,
where if they have an internal team or if they're
working with an external agency or something,
they want me there from the get out.
Some people are like, "We have no money
and we are going to try to do this as much as we
can inside of our business, but then can we hire
you at the end to make it look good? If we can
get everybody bought in and get it 80% of the way
there." Depending on what people's budgets are, I
have different ways of working, or just depending
on what their needs are. Because my whole thing
too is I don't want to step on anybody's toes,
because sometimes companies have these really
amazing designers that are working in-house, and
it sucks as a designer who started at a company
and thinks that you might be able to get a chance
to work on what is considered the most important
asset in terms of the brand and they just farm it
out to someone else instead of letting you touch
it. To me, that's a recipe for anything that I
create to be immediately killed, because someone
inside is going to be like, "It's time to shine,"
and then they're just going to kill all my work.
I'm always like, "How do we collaborate? How do I
make it so that I'm an asset to you? Not that I'm
trying to step on your toes, not that I'm trying
to take over what's the cool juicy work from
the people who inside that are really excited
to do it." I just want them to feel as bought in
as I can be. But yeah, it becomes interesting.
I feel like I get told by branding people that
I'm too inexpensive because they're like, "Oh,
for what you do, it should be 60 or $70,000 at a
minimum to do all this kind of stuff." I'm like,
I feel like the majority of the projects
that I do end up being between 25 and 35,
but depending on how you bring me in, it can be
less if it's just as a consultant. It's not out
of the realm of possibilities to hire a proper
crazy expert at stuff. It's not like you're
thinking about sinking half a million dollars into
the brand. That's a very different experience.
Awesome. Thank you for sharing that. Before we
get into other stuff that you do, because like
you said at the top, there are many other things
you do outside of this specific time of work,
is there anything else you think might be helpful
or important for people to know about working with
you on a logo refresh or just thinking about
logos and this whole space we talked about?
The best thing is just seeing what's there and
really being able to understand what's not working
about it and what your goals are. Like I said with
that reverse justification of intuition, I think
if you know that the logo is not quite where you
want it to be, just spend a couple days asking
yourself why. "What is the thing about this that
bothers me?" Don't get specific. Don't be like,
"The way the R is," or whatever. Maybe that's the
thing that we talk about down the line, but always
think big picture before you think minutiae,
because sometimes people think that... They'll
throw a bunch of minutiae stuff at me, but it's
because they haven't really stopped to think about
what is the overall thing that's bothering them.
You just never get there if you're always trying
to address detail before you address the big
picture stuff. You have to just always start
super top level, and really ask yourself very
broad questions about why you think it's not
working, and then go tighter, and tighter, and
tighter, and be like... It really could be like,
"This C has always bothered me," and then we can
get real specific about that when I'm doing the
refresh. But I think I also need to understand
the overall reason why we're doing this,
not just the little bugaboo that bothers you
specifically but might not bother anybody else.
Yeah. When I was thinking about this,
it feels like my whole feeling was this
could be better. That's all it was
for me initially, is just like I
feel like it could be a lot better. I
imagine that's enough for some people,
just like, "I think this could be better,"
and then here's things [inaudible 00:55:50].
Yeah. That's definitely enough for some people,
because I think sometimes... I think you,
specifically, had a very clear vibe going on
with all of your brand stuff. Some people,
it's totally like a mishmash grab bag of random
trends and there's no real voice that's coming
through. But I feel like you've been doing this
for a while, and when you see everything together,
there's definitely a very clear vision
and vibe that you get from everything.
I always tell people that having terrible
vision can be your best asset when it comes
to logo and brand, because it allows you...
Just take your glasses off if you have terrible
vision, and look at it, and get the feeling when
you can't see the detail. You have to be looking
at it with blurred eyes. What is the overall
look of this thing? Just trying to get as broad
and noodly as you can with it instead of it
being about those really specific one by one
stuff. I think when you blur your eyes on your
brand, there was a really clear cohesiveness to
it already. It was just about massaging it into
a more consistent professional-looking place.
Well, I can't look at the old logo anymore now
that I've gotten this thing coming together,
so I'm really excited for this to come out.
Just a couple closing questions. One is you
have a lot of other stuff going on that is not
just typography and logo refreshes. You have
children's books, you do lettering for
classics, you have a store in Oakland.
Talk about all these other things you got
going on in case it might interest people.
Sure. Yeah, of course. I'm based here
in The Bay, as we've talked about,
and I have a studio in Downtown Oakland. My
studio is like Barbie's creative Dream house,
where the top floor is my office, that's where I'm
right now, and then the bottom floor on one side
is a workshop. I do a lot of printmaking. I went
to college at a school that was very focused on
interdisciplinary work, and I feel like I bring
a lot of manual analog processes into my work a
lot. I find it really important to make physical
things as a part of my creative process, so I do a
lot of printmaking. On the other side downstairs
is a brick and mortar store. I've always wanted
to have a brick and mortar store because, as an
artist, I think having people have a physical
connection to your work can be really important.
I think one of the reasons why people hire me to
do things for them is because one of the gifts
of working with someone that is a real nerd
professional about whatever it is that they do
is that they bring you along the journey and give
you the language to talk about the thing through
their eyes and through their experience. To me,
the funnest thing for me is actually telling
clients and teaching them about all the things
that we are doing along the way so then they go
out into the world as a newly-minted type nerd
and can communicate all of these things to other
people. That connection is just really important.
The connection to the work, the story behind it,
I feel like that's one of the ways that we create
lasting work, is understanding that the work
exists because there's a story behind it. Things,
if they're just created because of the aesthetics
or they're just created quickly or whatever,
it's really easy to discard them
because there's not a story behind it.
But if you think about all the objects in your
life that have followed you throughout your life,
what's a thing that you've had since you were in
fifth grade or whatever that is still magically
in your possession in your house? You have that
because the story of that thing is so important
to you. I think that the work that we create,
the design that we create, can have that. It
can be imbued with so much story and meaning,
that when we think about moving on from it,
we're like, "Ugh, but this." I think that's
one of the ways to build a lasting brand,
is to just make sure that the story of
creating it feels so real, and visceral,
and important. The store is a way for people to
have a physical connection to other work that I
create, like the prints and things like that.
With the kids' book stuff, that's also about
creating lasting stuff. I like creating physical
things in the world. I like repackaging things
that I've learned in therapy in a way that
kids will appreciate and enjoy. I'm just always
thinking about what's a way that I can say a thing
that has been said before but hasn't been said in
this way. If I can turn that into a physical
object that people can have and appreciate,
all the better. But yeah, I don't know. While,
professionally, what I do is considered very
niche, I feel like all the things that I do are
quite diverse, because they tickle different parts
of my brain. I have to use my hands in different
ways and my mind in different ways. It's how I've
been able to generally avoid feeling burnt out as
a creative, is just being able to move on between
different kinds of work and just feel excited
about different things at different times.
For folks that want to maybe check out the store,
how do they find it? It's called
Jessica and Friends, is that right?
Yes. It's called Jessica Hische and Friends.
Jessica Hische and Friends.
You can just Google JH&F.
Google Maps, yeah. [inaudible 01:01:17]
Yeah. I put JH&F on as a part of the Google
Maps name so I don't have to spell my name
to strangers, because I have a weird German
spelling last name. I also have a second store
called Drawling, which is drawing with an L thrown
in there. That one is an all-ages art supply store
that's sort of a kids' art supply store. That one
grew out of JH&F as well. Those two stores exist.
With my books, if you just look up my last name on
any of your favorite booksellers, you'll find me.
Last question. I'm just going to throw this out
there in case something interesting comes up. We
have a segment on this podcast called AI Corner,
where I like to see how people have found ways to
use AI in their work, in their life to be more
productive, do cool things. Is there some way
that you've found a way to use AI in the work that
you do that makes you do more interesting stuff?
A little bit. I am in this really interesting
position in terms of AI where my partner works
at Meta on GenAI stuff. He's a director on the
GenAI team at Meta and is very bought into AI
as a whole thing. I am a little [inaudible
01:02:28] about its impact on a lot of the
things that we do. I think, overall, it
will become a tool and be very useful,
especially in a lot of different fields. But I
think this timeframe in which it's more novelty
is going to have not the best impact on things
like illustration, but eventually, we'll all come
out of it and it'll be fine. In terms of how I've
been able to integrate it into my process, I did
some work for Salesforce last year where the theme
for Dreamforce was going to be very AI-driven. I
felt like I needed to explore AI as a part of
the generative process for creating that art.
I did have fun creating custom lettering and
then trying to run it through stable diffusion
to get stable diffusion to generate instances
of my lettering in different styles. We were
making these clouds. We ultimately didn't end up
using it, but it was still really neat to see.
I could see the validity of that in the creative
iterative process. I think the biggest thing for
me is that I find that the sloggy, slow dregs of
work is very fulfilling to me, that a lot of the
evangelists of AI are like, "Oh, imagine if you
could spend all of your time high level thinking,
and coming up with the concepts, and guiding the
vision, and whatever, and then just get AI to do
everything else that you don't care about." For
me, that just sounds like not the most holistic
approach to how I work, because the reason why
I do all the things that I do and why my process
is the way that it is because while I love
thinking and I love coming up with conceptual
stuff, I find it to be very cerebrally taxing.
I need a break from that by doing the more low-key
production end of stuff. That's my favorite part
of the process, is we know what we're doing,
and now it's just about going in. When it comes
to judging logos, for instance, the days that I
spend knowing exactly what I'm going to do
and all it is me just moving little Bezier
handles around and getting it feeling right and
whatever, those are pure therapeutic zen for me.
I think I will always have that as a part of my
work and will probably not have AI be outputting
that part. But I have been able to have it be
helpful in the iterative process a little bit,
both through generating sketches with that project
and then also through a lot of stuff with writing
with my kids' books and things like that, is
coming up with lists of words and concepts
that are adjacent to each other, whatever.
I have found that Claude and ChatGPT are very
good for things like that. I'm working on another
kids' book now, and I'm trying to think of the
directions that it can take. One of them is sort
of illustrating different feelings and things like
that. I could sit there and brainstorm what are
the different emotions or whatever, or I can just
ask Claude like, "List 50 emotions," and then I
can cherry-pick the ones that come up that feel
right. I do find it's really good for that early
brainstorming stuff, and that's been really nice.
Is there anything else that you want to share
or leave listeners with before we get
to our very exciting lightning round?
Yes. Well, I do have a new kid's
book coming out in October.
Oh, [inaudible 01:06:02].
Aside from all the logo stuff, please do check out
my kids' books. It's called My First Book of Fancy
Letters, and it is like a new spin on an alphabet
book, but instead of it being an alphabet book for
brand new babies, which you could totally buy it
for brand new babies because it is very simple,
and fun, and they'll like the bright pictures,
it's for the age where kids can recognize letters
but can't necessarily read and write yet because
they get so into seeing letters drawn in these
different styles and imagining what other letters
could be drawn in. Each of the letters is drawn
to represent the word that it sounds like. Letters
can be athletic, bubbly, or creepy, and then it's
like, "Well, what does a creepy C look like?"
When kids are starting to understand letter
sounds and recognizing letters, they can start
thinking about what other words start with that
letter sound, and then they start listing stuff
out and become immediate over-the-shoulder art
directors. It's been really fun showing it to
other preschoolers, and TK, and kindergarten kids,
because they're immediately like, "Well, R
should be a river. It should be a river."
I'm like, "Well, how do you draw a river?"
It becomes this fun imagination exercise too,
so definitely check that out. It's up for
pre-order now and comes out October 22nd.
That is so delightful. I know you have
multiple kids. Do you start to see the idea
with one age of kid and then by the
time the next kid reaches that age,
it's ready and published?
Does that work timing-wise?
Yeah, the only thing is both of my... Well,
my oldest child is a real super reader. She's
always ahead of the game. The second that she
could read, she was like, "Oh, picture books
are for babies." Now she's reading, she goes
into Pegasus books and is just like, "Where
are your books for teenagers?" They're like,
"You're nine. We're not going to show you that,
but here are the middle grade books or whatever."
There is a little bit of that. You are a parent,
but you are a parent of a very young person.
Kids don't want to buy anything you're selling
as a parent. There's a little bit of that
where I feel like I get so many wonderful
letters from other families about how it's their
favorite book, and they read it every night,
and it's so important, and then my kids are like,
"Yeah, yeah. It's just mom's book, whatever."
Yeah, that's bittersweet.
Well, with that, Jessica,
we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
I'm ready.
Speaking of books, first question,
what are two or three books that you've
recommended most to other people?
Rick Reuben's creativity book is so good.
Definitely recommend that. I haven't listened
to it on audiobook. I read the physical book,
but I also heard the audiobook is very zen. I
feel like it's just a very good palate cleanser in
terms of being an artist and creating because it
feels both high level but also very actionable,
so really recommend that. In terms of learning
about and understanding typography, there's this
book called Inside Paragraphs by Cyrus Highsmith.
It's very small and very digestible.
You can read it in one bathroom visit,
and it's illustrated really well. It has cool
illustrations. If you want to learn about some
basics of type and typography, it's a really
great book, and incredibly accessible, and not
like reading Bringhurst or something like that,
so big ups to that book. Oh, what's another book?
I don't know. I feel like I'm just going to
end up recommending all the books that I'm
currently reading. This month, I read both
Patti Smith's Just Kids, which I loved also
and was also... I feel like I'm reading a lot
of books about being an artist more so than
being a designer. That book, I found really
interesting, just hearing her story of moving
to New York and having nothing. Just trying to
be an artist, and make art, and having that be
the thing that drove everything that she
and Robert Mapplethorpe did. I don't know,
I just feel like I'm looking for ways to get out
of my very business-driven sensibilities around
art making and get into a space that's more
loose, and free, and driven by passions and
feelings more so than necessarily career-based
milestones and things like that. This is a wild
card one too. I just finished The Emperor of All
Maladies. I'm just a big fan of reading things
about human biology and things like that and found
it totally fascinating, so do read that one too.
I can't help but ask, how do you
have time to read, raise children,
work on so many projects, have a
run a store? What is your secret?
Well, you get pretty ruthless about
your schedule when you're a parent,
where when you're at the office, you are just
heads in working, and so I think just trying
to stay as focused as possible in that way. I do
this thing where I bounce back and forth between
projects a lot as I'm losing steam, and so
having multiple things to work on keeps me
motivated to keep working. I think it's kind of
an ADHD thing, where I will start my day one way
and then as soon as I start losing steam,
I switch to a different thing, lose steam,
switch to a different thing, lose steam, switch
to a different thing. Rather than taking breaks,
I just take a break by working on something
that feels fresh. That can be super helpful.
That's an awesome tip.
Yeah. I mean, it's incredible. I also would
tell people when I had first started out,
I had a full-time job and then was doing freelance
in the evenings. People were like, "How do you not
get burnt out, whatever?" It's because my day job
was so different from my night job that it felt
like I was doing two separate eight-hour shifts
instead of one continual sixteen-hour shift.
I think that's something to sort of think
about, is that there's always going to be
things that need to get done as a part of
your work or things that you're interested
in and passionate about. Just having enough
diversity in what that means is going to allow
you to maintain enthusiasm for doing all those
different things for much longer. Actually,
the more homogenous your life and career and
job is, the faster you're going to burn out,
so just making sure that you have enough
variety and all the things that you do.
That was an awesome tip. I'm glad I
went there. Okay, back on track to our
lightning round. Is there a recent favorite
movie or TV show you've really enjoyed?
Severance was my favorite TV
show I think I've ever watched.
The second season's coming out.
I know. That came to mind because I
knew the second season was coming out,
so I'm just really excited about it, but
I think that was probably tops for me.
Is there a favorite product you've
recently discovered that you really love?
Oh, yeah. Well, there's a few things. Well, there
was one that's just a super random one that was
just pure delight. There's a Japanese brand,
Penco, and they make a lot of wonderful stuff. I
carry a lot of their stuff in my store. One of the
things I bought recently from them is a pen cup,
a pencil cup. It's ceramic, but it looks like
a paper bag, a lightly crumpled paper bag,
and then it just has printed on it Penco,
whatever. I just really like it when you
take an existing object and give it a new form. I
find that to be very delightful, and so that was,
I think, one of the things that I really
loved recently that I bought for the store.
Awesome. Pick two more questions. Do you have a
favorite life motto that you often think about,
come back to share with folks,
find useful, and work your life?
It's funny being a lettering artist because
I'm not much of a quotes gal, all things
considered. I should be because I could make
a million dollars by just making "live, laugh,
love" pillows or whatever, but I am not usually
continually collecting quotes. But I was just at
a conference up in Portland called XOXO, and one
of the presenters showed a quote on the screen
that resonated with me more than most things that
I've seen in recent memory. I feel like this is
my new... It was one of those quotes that I was
like maybe I should get a tattoo of that. When
it gets to that level where you're considering a
tattoo, you're like, "Okay, that's official." It
was "hope is a discipline". I just really loved
that. It's by Mariame Kaba or Mariame Kaba.
The idea that we have to choose to create
positivity, that it's like a choice,
and that in order to dream of these things, you
can actually create structure and discipline
around it, and that it's not just something that
is just inherent and comes, you have to actually
have a practice around being hopeful and positive.
I just really liked that as a concept because I
feel that way just about navigating through life,
that everything that we do is a choice and that
we can choose to frame things one way or frame
things another way. Understanding that you have
power in that, I think, is really important, and
so I just really loved that. Hope is a discipline.
I really love that. I love any quote that
inspires you to not feel like a victim,
and gives you agency, and reminds
you that you have agency over.
Exactly. That's, I think, was the biggest
thing for me is just... Because I feel
very well-resourced in being able to deal
with hardship because I'm always able to
recontextualize and reframe. I think part of
that is doing so much intuition justification,
which is what we talked about, is
walking through things, being like,
"Why is this? Why does that happen, la,
la, la?" When something bad happens,
it's understanding why it happened and
then understanding the paths that it can
take forward and the different attitudes that you
can bring to it that can help you come out of it.
That's beautiful. Okay, final question. I know
that you recently remodeled your home. It's
quite stunning. You share photos of it online.
You worked with this amazing architect to help
make it as amazing as it is. As a designer, here's
the question, how do you find the balance between
trusting someone, their own perspective and
design approach, versus pushing into a direction
you think that it should go? How do
you find a balance as a designer?
Well, I actually feel like it's quite easy
for me to trust people to do their own thing,
because as long as I go to them as being like, "I
appreciate you and your vision and that's why I'm
paying you," then the last thing that I want
to do is micromanage them, because the reason
why I'm paying them is because I don't have the
bandwidth to do that myself. Because honestly,
I'm one of those people that if I had nothing
going on, if my job totally blew up or whatever,
I would probably be one of those people that just
specialize in a different thing every six months
and would be like, "I'm going to build a house now
from the ground up. I'm going to do this from now,
whatever." I just feel very capable of doing
anything that I want to do because I understand
that I can find the resources for it.
When I hire people to help me do a thing,
it's because there is this implicit trust in
what they do and that that's why I want to work
with them. With the house, I definitely
had opinions about stuff. But in general,
I'm just like, "Hey, this is your thing. You're
the expert. What do you think? Let me give you the
parameters and the things that we have to think
about. Because you know more about wood resources,
and you know more about the cabinet spacing, and
whatever, you tell me what you think is going to
work best based on all these things that I
laid out for you." I found it to be quite
easy. I only got really wigged out about
a couple of different fine tune-y stuff.
I imagine architects and designers
are like, "Oh no, it's going to be
a designer I'm working with. They have
opinions." I'm glad it wasn't that bad.
I feel like my strength with the work that
I do in general is just being incredibly
decisive and understanding that there's 10 good
answers to every one question. Some people are
real maximalists about decision-making and need
to look at every gray sofa that exists before
they can choose the one gray sofa. Whereas I
feel like I can look at 10 gray sofas and go,
it feels like there's two or three categories
of sofa here, and then within those categories,
there's a couple of good options. Here's a brand
that I recognize is known for being of high
quality. That one's good enough. I can get to it
really quickly, and I feel like not everybody can
do that. And I think that that permeates through
everything that I do in my life. It definitely is
a huge part of the logo work, because you really
can do anything when it comes to typography.
It can go in 50 million directions. It's just
about having someone tell you, "Yes, we could take
this anywhere, but these are the valid paths. If
we go down this path, this is the most intuitive
and most correct way to do it that is closest
and most accessible to us. We can noodle on it
until kingdom come, but do we have to? This is
good." I don't know. I feel like there's some
weird knowledge around understanding that nothing
is ever 100% perfect, and the most you can aspire
and get to is 99.8 or whatever. That last 0.2%,
you could spend your whole life trying to do that,
or you could move on and do other things
and understand that it's nearly perfect.
That is really good advice and a
freeing piece of advice. Jessica,
it's been an honor to work with you on this logo.
I am really excited for people to see it, for it
to be the new look of everything I'm doing. Two
final questions. Where can folks find you online
if they want to learn more and potentially work
with you, and how can listeners be useful to you?
Oh, yeah. Of course. I have a website
that I occasionally update. It is
jessicahische.is/awesome. You'll notice I have
a bunch of weird URLs on my website. That's a
place to find me. Otherwise, I am on Instagram
and Threads a lot. I was formerly a very active
Twitter person, and now I'm not really there so
much and I bop around with the Twitter clones,
but I'm on Threads quite a bit. Instagram and
Threads are good for social. Email, I'm easy,
hello@jessicaHische.com. What your readers could
do for me, I think it's the work that I do in
terms of the logo refresh stuff. I feel like this
audience is just totally my perfect audience for
it because you guys are all a bunch of smart,
awesome founders that want beautiful logos,
but understand that sometimes you just
got to get that first viable option out
the door. Once you're ready, you come
to me and I help you and it's great.
A match made in heaven. Jessica,
thank you so much for being here.
Happy to be here. Great convo.
So good. Bye, everyone. Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable,
you can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can
find all past episodes or learn more about
the show at lennyspodcast.com.
See you in the next episode.