The PM job can become a little too internal,
influencing my stakeholders and getting
alignment and all these things. But if you
can't sell or support your own product,
I don't trust you to build the product.
You think every PM should keep a decision log?
We all talk about product sense. To me, it's
just a fancy way of saying you can make good
decisions with insufficient data. PMs need
as many reps as possible in making decisions,
documenting the rationale behind those decisions,
and then crucially seeing the outcome of them.
We have a lot of interesting approaches to
hiring, including this idea of a unsell email.
When you get to offer stage, I send an email
and I say all the terrible things that are
probably going to reinforce their fears.
If you can tell them that upfront and they
can read that whole email and still be equally
excited to join you, find yourself a A+ hire.
I'm curious if you found any
interesting uses of AI in your work.
We are not even beneath the dust on the surface
when it comes to what's going to change.
Today, my guest is Kevin Yien. Kevin leads product
for merchant experiences at Stripe. Before that,
he built the restaurant business
and the ecosystem teams at Square,
and most recently was head of product and
design at Mutiny. He also makes ice cream and,
as you'll hear in there conversation, was a pretty
competitive eater for some part of his life.
In our conversation, Kevin shares a ton of
unique and insightful perspectives on how to
be a successful product manager, including
how to get into product management, how to
improve your relationship with your engineers
and designers, bunch of advice on hiring, why
you should keep a decision log, how to automate
your customer research, plus a ton of really
powerful stories around failure and AI and career.
This episode is for anyone looking to become a
better leader, thinker, and builder of products.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow in your favorite podcasting
app or YouTube. It's the best way to avoid
missing feature episodes, and it helps the podcast
tremendously. With that, I bring you Kevin Yien.
Kevin, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Thanks, Lenny. I am humbled to be here.
I've been a big fan of yours from afar.
I've been following you on Twitter for a
long time. You have a very distinct
profile photo that I feel like you
maybe haven't changed for a long time.
How long have you had this profile?
Oh gosh, probably 2011 or 2012. The story
behind that is I was inspired actually by
Chris Dixon's avatar at the time and I
wanted something really similar to it,
but I couldn't figure out how to. Luckily, I
was dating a designer at the time, and so she
made me that sort of custom pick that has been
my profile since then, and she's now my wife.
Oh my god. Funny enough, I had a
startup idea once where it's like
a profile picture as a service business
where there's these three tiers where
it's like one has automated,
one has someone illustrates,
and one is a professional photo. It feels
like everyone profile photos are so important.
True.
But I never follow through.
Probably not a good business anyway.
Yeah, but a good idea, a good tool.
Good idea. Thank you. Thank
you for making me feel better.
I've been looking forward to this
conversation for a long time. As I said,
I've been a big fan of yours for a long time.
Something that I've noticed about you is you
have a lot of really unique perspectives on
a lot of different things, and in particular,
product management, how to be successful as
a PM, how to get into product management,
things like that. So I thought it'd be fun
to start there talking through some of these
things that I've heard you talk about and then
get into some very tactical stuff that you found
to be useful in your product management career.
The first thing that I've heard you talk about
is that you discourage people from going
straight into product management. If they
want to become product managers, you encourage
them to start somewhere else first. Why is that?
Where do you think people should start?
Talk about this insight that you've had.
Yeah, so follow me on the detour to science
world temporarily. If we all remember high
school science classes, there was this concept
of potential and kinetic energy. There's so many
different definitions for product management, but
the one that I have come to myself that I really
like is, when you are building a product,
you have this team, engineers, designers,
so much potential. The purpose of product
management, not the person, but the practice,
is to convert that potential into as much
realized value for someone as possible,
right? Minimum loss. When you're just getting
started with a new product, the people that should
be doing that are the people who are building
it. That's an engineer, that's a designer,
that's a sales person or a support person. They're
the front line of the smallest loop possible
to get something going, and it's through those
practices that I think you're able to get the most
exposure to what it takes to build a good product.
And then from there, that's your foundation.
That's the unique perspective that you
bring and allows you then to actually
take on a "role" of product manager in a good,
unique, insightful way. That's sort of like the
foundation. There's a lot more to unpack behind
that comparison, but that's where it comes from.
I love that. I'd love to unpack it further.
This episode is brought to you by
BuildBetter.AI. Back in 2020 when AI
was just a toy, BuildBetter bet that it could
cut down on a product teams' operational BS.
Fast-forward to today, 23,000 product teams
use purpose-built AI in BuildBetter every day.
First, BuildBetter uses custom models to turn
unstructured data like product and sales calls,
support tickets, internal communications, and
surveys into structured insights. It's like having
a dedicated data science team. Second, BuildBetter
runs those structured insights into workflows,
like weekly reports about customer issues,
context-aware PRDs, and user research document
with citations. It even turns standups
into action items that automatically get
assigned and shared into your tools. Plus,
with unlimited seat pricing on all plans,
BuildBetter ensures everyone at your company has
access to this knowledge. Truly, no data silos.
In a world of AI demos over promising and
under delivering, see why BuildBetter has a
93% subscription retention. Get a personalized
demo and use code LENNY for $100 credit if
you sign up now at buildbetter.ai/lenny.
I'm excited to chat with Christina Gilbert,
the founder of OneSchema, one of our
longtime podcast sponsors. Hi, Christina.
Yes, thank you for having me on, Lenny.
What is the latest with OneSchema? I know you now
work with some of my favorite companies like Ramp,
Vanta, Scale, and Watershed. I heard
that you just launched a new product
to help product teams import CSVs from
especially tricky systems like ERPs.
Yes, so we just launched OneSchema FileFeeds,
which allows you to build an integration with
any system in 15 minutes as long as you can export
a CSV to an SFTP folder. We see our customers all
the time getting stuck with hacks and workarounds.
And the product teams that we work with don't have
to turn down prospects because their systems
are too hard to integrate with. We allow our
customers to offer thousands of integrations
without involving their engineering team at all.
I can tell you that if my team had
to build integrations like this,
how nice would it be to be able to take
this off my roadmap and instead use
something like OneSchema and not just to
build it but also to maintain it forever.
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many
four stories of multi-day outages from
even just a handful of bad records. We have
laser-focused on integration reliability to
help teams end all of those distractions
that come up with integrations. We have
a built-in validation layer that stops
any bad data from entering your system,
and OneSchema will notify your team
immediately of any data that looks incorrect.
I know that importing incorrect data can
cause all kinds of pain for your customers
and quickly lose their trust. Christina, thank
you for joining us. If you want to learn more,
head on over to oneschema.co. That's oneschema.co.
Every PM has their definition of what is product
management, and I have one that I'm trying to
find exactly what I wrote, but essentially,
it's to marshal the resources of your team to
solve customer problems and drive business impact
most efficiently, something like that. And I feel
like it's very aligned with your perspective,
but I really love this view of it's unlocking the
potential energy of the team. Not just marshaling
the resources of a team, but it's there, and your
job is to maximize their effort. And this is why
when people say, "I hate product managers. I
don't want any product managers at my team.
We don't need product managers here," I feel
like that's often because you've had a bad
PM. Good PMs make you better and make your life
better, allow you to do the work you want to do
and they take all the stuff you don't want to do,
make sure the stuff you're doing is worthwhile.
Is there anything more you
want to add along those lines?
To elaborate on that, I think the broader point is
that truly not every team needs a product manager,
but the activities, the outcome that one would
drive needs to get done no matter what. And in
some cases, this is why the prototypical companies
that everyone references when they say, "They
never had product managers, look at how successful
they are," they're all building for themselves.
Stripe, Twilio, Figma, designers for designers,
engineers for engineers. When you are the
customer, why the heck do you need someone else
to help do the things that let you make decisions
on what to build? But if you are not the customer,
if you're working in a particularly complex space,
if there's something that you, as the person that
could build the product, feel you don't have,
that's when you can essentially delegate that
responsibility to someone else to say, "Hey,
let me do the things I'm really good at and you
do something that I need to get my job done."
So it's that sort of relationship that I think
is often missing in the discourse. I think it
would alleviate a lot of the, "We don't want
PMs. PM is useless" or, "PM's one of the best
thing since [inaudible 00:09:52]," which they're
not. It's just a manifestation of that problem.
Yeah. Just to build on that, we're going on a
tangent, but I think that's really interesting.
I think there's another element of that, SNAP
actually is another example where they waited,
I think, until they had 200 people before they
hired their first PM. To me, that's an example
of other people were doing the PM job. As you
said, there's PM activity, someone's doing them,
lining people, prioritizing, making sure things
are clear, making sure people aren't surprised,
all these things PMs do. Someone's doing
that, and my feeling is like, "Okay,
your designers may love doing that, great. Let
them do it." If your engineers that have a lot
of product sense may want to do that, great.
But there's some point they either is like,
"Forget it. I just want to code. I want to build
that. I want to be sitting around in meetings
all day," or they just aren't as good as things
are scaling. And so it's kind of like, if your
engineers, designers want to do it and are good
at it, great. You don't need PMs for a long time.
Oftentimes they're not good at it or they don't
want to be sitting in doing all these PM things.
Yep, precisely.
Okay, so going back to the question
of... So your advice is don't go
straight into product management if you
want to become a great PM. Where do you
think people should start if they can?
What are some options you recommend?
The best way to think about this, in my opinion,
is who were the people that you would be taking
the PM responsibilities from and then do those
jobs? And so for me, the sort of foundational
three are going to be engineer, designer
or salesperson. I think sales also gets not
a bad rep, but a misrepresented reputation
in tech where all they care about is quota,
it's just about numbers, et cetera. In reality,
the best salespeople are the best listeners,
the best people at understanding the problem that
the customer is having and then translating that
into what you can do for them. And so if
you get really good at having those calls,
getting told no a lot, and being able to translate
that, I mean, why would you not want to start
there and then eventually move into something like
product? So that's the foundational three for me.
So your advice is essentially if you want to
be a PM, start as a designer or an engineer
or a salesperson. I was an engineer, so this is
exactly the path I went on. And I think there's
an element of you start there and then you
realize you're never going to be as amazing
as the other people at that role and you're
like, "Okay, maybe I should explore this other
thing," because I was like, "I'm never going
to be an amazing engineer. I'm good enough."
Totally.
I'm like, "I'm pretty good at this
other stuff. Let's explore that."
The one thing that I might tack on there, because
this could lead to a negative perception, is,
"Well, I'm never going to be a world-class
engineer, world-class designer or et cetera, and
so let me settle for being a PM." That
could be the conclusion you arrive at,
but I think a better way of framing it is, "I'm
okay at those things. I'm potentially world-class
at this other thing. Let me see what it
feels like to double down on this area."
Absolutely.
And I think that's just a good framing.
Okay, so let's talk about another insight and
piece of advice that you have, is that you think
that great PMs need to be great writers. I think
a lot of people don't necessarily think this. I
think people may probably think, "If I'm an okay
writer, I can probably be really successful PM."
Talk about why you think it's so important to be
a really great writer to be a really great PM.
It's actually shocking for me to hear that
this isn't commonplace sort of acceptance,
but the place that this comes from for me is,
writing is clarity at scale, and a key component
to a PM's job is creating clarity both internally
and externally, but it is both sides of that that
I think often get lost. A lot of times the
PM job can become a little too internal,
and it's about influencing my stakeholders and
getting alignment and all these things. Don't get
me wrong, all that's very important. You should
write your PRDs, they should be super crisp,
they should articulate things really well, but I'm
not saying that every PM needs to be a marketer
or a world-class copywriter, but you should be
able to write really compelling messaging in the
voice of the person that you're trying to serve.
And I'm working backwards from the beliefs that,
if you can't sell or support your
own product, I don't trust you to
build the product. And so that's where I think
writing is the foundational component there.
There's a few quotes I say often on this
podcast just because they always come to
mind. One is by Joan Didion who said that, "I
don't know what I think until I've written it
down." And that's what I find with writing
where I need to actually write it down for
me to really understand what the heck
I'm thinking to really crystallize it.
Yeah, and I think writing is, it's
both a mechanism for translating what
you're trying to think into that thought
into what you're actually trying to do,
but then it needs additional revs to be
properly consumed by everyone else. And
that's I think the really hard part that a lot of
folks don't do the extra mile effort to take on.
And this to your earlier point of a job of PM
is to unlock this potential energy of your team,
of the various resources you have
and obviously having everyone aligned
behind a very, like, "This is what we
are doing and everyone understanding
it" and it being very clear
is really powerful there.
Okay. So this begs the question, how does
one become a great writer? What helped
you become a better writer? How do you feel
about your ability to write at this point?
Oh man.
Any advise on becoming better?
I'll start with a slightly cheeky comment, which
is, I think some of this is changing with the
advent of large language models and the ability
to actually just mimic someone else's tone. But
I take inspiration from the camp of Anthony
Bourdain, and he has, I'm going to butcher the
exact quote but it's something like, "If you want
to know how to make good food, you have to eat a
lot of food, and you have to be willing to have
a bad meal every now and again." And so for me,
good writing comes from consuming as much good
writing as possible. Sometimes you'll read
something and say, "That was actually absolute
fresh." But that's okay, you have to be willing to
take on some of that stuff. But the more you index
towards developing your own taste for what you
think is good by consuming others, then you can
shift into producing your own and then comparing
them and riffing it off other people. So I think
that's sort of the cycle that I've gone through.
I have a friend who's a very good writer and a
poet and helped me develop my writing early on,
Vanessa, and she said exactly the same
thing. Just to become a better writer,
read beautiful writing, and it just kind of
infuses you or your brain. In your experience,
is there anything you read, anything you
found really effective? Anything that you
think influenced the way you write
or think that people can check out?
I explicitly do not mean read a bunch of
other PM artifacts. You're not going to
become a better writer by reading PRDs
or whatever it is or support articles.
It needs to be writing that compels. That's
the theme I would go back to because that's
what you're trying to do at the end of the day.
And when I say compels, I mean it pushes you to
action. Because if you read something and you're
like, "Oh, that's interesting," that's not enough.
You need to be able to give someone something that
then allows them to do something differently. And
so the things for me that have been best...
Obviously there's all the Paul Graham essays,
I think his writing is very succinct, very clear,
that's not novel. I learned a lot by finding
specific voices back in the day on Twitter, and it
wasn't always what they were posting on Twitter,
but if they wrote an essay or a post, that would
be their crispus thinking. And so you can use
these broadcast channels to find where their
golden nuggets are, but then spend time with
those instead and don't worry about all
the additional noise that comes with it.
Paul Graham actually, you mentioned him, he
has a great piece on how to become a good,
that we'll link to, where basically his advice is,
write the way you talk. Just keep it really
simple and really regular. And so we'll link
to that. Is there anything else along these
lines of writing that you'd recommend for
folks that are like, "Okay, I need to
become a great writer. How do I do this?"?
Actually along the lines of write how you
talk, there's this concept of cadence that
I think is really important when it comes
to internal writing. There's probably some
very good article about this, but it's the idea
that if you only write in a monotonous cadence,
either all really short sentences or all really
long sentences, then your brain just tunes out
eventually. And so you have to interrupt the
pattern intentionally, and so you go short-long,
long-short, whatever it is, but there's a
few various specific things that you can
do that allow someone to just roll through
a post or something when you write that way.
Along those lines, there's a book that I just
found to make sure I had the right title called
Several Short Sentences About Writing that is
really helpful along these lines. And the whole
book is very short sentences and it teaches you
to write very short sentences because once you're
good at that, you can get better writing longer
sentences. And so we'll link to that too. It's
like a really good book that I have two copies
around my house that I kind of poke at sometimes.
Nice. I'll have [inaudible 00:19:09] too.
Okay. Another area that you have a really
clever insight into is how the PM role fits
with engineering design. We've talked about this
a little bit, but you have a really clever way
of just thinking about how these roles interact
and who's responsible for what. Talk about that.
So this description came from writing
PRDs at Square. I think there was a lot
of confusion from my team specifically
when I joined them. For what it's worth,
it was new product line, three engineers, three
designers, there was nothing but a slide deck.
Three engineers and three designers?
The best ratio ever. This is a whole other thing.
Most people, I would say, under invest in design,
point-blank. When you get to a certain scale,
maybe things change, but truly I don't think most
teams have experienced what it feels like
to have a really high design ratio and what
that actually does to the quality of the
work and the quality of the thinking. So
shout out to designers. We need more,
is the short version. And I would
rather hire an incremental designer
than PM almost any day of the week.
Wow. I've never experienced
this ratio. Incredible.
Yes, I was very lucky. Shout out to Bruce
Bell, who was my manager at the time,
who was an ex designer, at the time,
GM, and declared that starting ratio.
So anyways, with that setup, they all had sort
of an opinion. They had seen PRDs in the past,
they weren't quite sure what the purpose of it
actually was because they had designs already.
They had something to start from. And when I
came in and talked to everyone and figured out
where we needed to be in a year's time, I was
like, "Okay, here's how I think it. Let me know
if you agree." And this is a whole other concept,
which is, the best way to get feedback from people
is not by asking what they think, but to put
something concrete in front of them and then
have them react to it, right? So chewing fork.
And so my description is, PM should be doing
everything in their power to draw the perimeter of
the space, of the problem space. And it's within
that, eng, design, everyone else that you're
working with, they can go as crazy as they want,
push up against the bounds and it's
fill the box to its maximum capacity,
but you've now applied the constraints that allow
you to actually have productive conversations.
On the other end of the spectrum though, I
think there's a lot of folks who think, "Oh,
PMs are just strategy high in the clouds.
All they do is kick things off." You need
to be obsessed about the final deliverable
and whether or not value is actually getting
to the customer. I have a really trite
example of this if you want to go down it.
Please.
But the key point I want to make is, I think
it is tempting when we think about engineering
product and design to draw these really clear swim
lanes and say, "You do X. I do Y. Don't tread on
my area." But you need these murky overlaps
in order to build something really good.
And so even if the engineers are going to build
a better product than you and the designers are
going to design something better than you, you
need to come with a strong opinion and you need to
do the legwork to get their trust so they actually
care about your opinion in the first place.
So time for a mini story. So Square, we're
building a point of sale for restaurants. If
you've ever seen one of these in a restaurant,
there's this sort of grid of tiles that they tap
to enter your order when you're sitting down for
dinner. We were developing one, and there's this
concept of a menu group. So it's a little box, you
tap on it and then it pops the screen in so you go
to the next level of the hierarchy. So example
would be you have a wine button, you tap it,
and you see your reds, whites, et cetera.
If you think about the people that we were
trying to serve, there's the restaurants that
were coming from a really old legacy system. And
if you've seen a bartender tap on one of these,
I mean it is muscle memory to the max. They're
not even looking at the thing and just punching
in the order blindfolded, and it's rapid fast.
On the other hand, you have people who
are entering the workforce the first time,
they've never used a point of sale. And so
we have to serve both of these equally. Well,
how do you deal with that level of speed but also
the ease of use that anyone can learn it for the
first time? And so there was this interaction
that we really cared about, which was, when you
tap on a menu group, what's the animation to pop
you into that next level? This seems like such
a small thing, but it made the difference in how
easy it was to adopt for a lot of the restaurants.
And so a designer and myself spent literally an
entire week just fine-tuning how many milliseconds
it would take to pop in and out so that it felt
right. And we actually brought in servers and
bartenders to play with the prototypes we
had on iPads and be like, "Here's an order.
Pop it in." And we would see where they
would sort of flinch or hesitate because
the animation was too slow and they thought, "I
can't tap it yet," or something related to that.
And so it's easy, I think, for a PM to say,
"That's not my responsibility. I define the
requirements. Have a menu group that goes
to the next level, design or engineer,
figure it out." No way. That's fully on you,
and you better be involved in those details.
I love this. There's two directions I want
to go. So there's the drawing the perimeter,
and then there's this paying attention to the
final deliverable and keeping the borrow really
high, which I love and I totally agree with both.
In terms of this animation, people hearing this,
that our PMs are going to be like, "How do you
have time to spend a week on animation for one
little product? I have so much to do. I get to
hit some goals, drive some numbers. I have people
waiting for me." Maybe because Square is like
this, once you deploy, it's harder to change and
it's like a big deal to ship. But I'm curious if
you have any advice or things you've learned about
how to create space for that sort of thing to
create time to spend a week on this animation? Or
was it just obvious to everyone, "We need to spend
as much time as we can"? Top down, everyone knew.
I definitely don't think
it was obvious to everyone,
and I can definitely say that because we
were given a pretty strict deadline that
we needed to launch by and I pushed it out three
times. That's not because of this one animation,
but it's because of a series of decisions where
we said, "This is what we believe we need to ship,
and this matters much more than hitting
some artificial external GA date."
There's this other aspect that I think PMs like
to feel good about how busy they are and they're
like, "I'm involved in so many processes and
I have to talk to this person and talk to that
person." All that might be true, but I think
there needs to be a calibration or at least
a spring-cleaning of, "What's everything I'm
doing?" and how much do these things actually
matter to getting value to a customer. Because as
a company gets bigger, as teams get more complex,
it's very easy and natural to spend more time
on things that are internally-focused and not
externally-focused. I think we just all have
to have sensitive antenna to that so that we
don't fall prey to, "Well, the way that my job is
described is to do these things," but really it's
the outcome again of put something in a customer's
hands that's also a problem, and it's amazing.
Reminds me of your now colleague Jeff
Weinstein's advice he got from one of
the Coulsons where they came to him and
they're like, "You're world-class at doing
the second and third most important
things and you're not focusing on the
most important thing because it's so hard,
and that's something you need to work on."
Totally. I will say so one on that, the CEO
at Mutiny, Charlie, she always repeated to
me nonstop, "Keep the main thing the main
thing" and would just say it ad nauseum,
and I'm really glad that she did. The
one excuse I don't want to give folks is,
as you progress in your career, you have to walk
and chew gum at the same time. You can't say,
"Oh, I'm only focused on this thing over here, so
other folks handle that." You do have to figure
out how to do a little bit more at the same
time, but prioritization does play a factor.
There's a framework [inaudible 00:27:27] suggested
that I really like, the LNO framework. I forget
exactly what the LNO stands for, but leverage
something something. And we'll link to it in
the show notes that gives you some advice on
how to prioritize your time based on the stuff.
Totally.
Okay. So I guess in the case of
pushing back to create space,
this was just you as a product leader
recognizing, "This is really important
to get right. I will convince people
we need to make more time for that."
I don't want to make it seem like it
was me against everyone because that
was definitely not the case.
I think the starting engineers
and designers on that team really cared about
the quality of what they built too. That's a
pretty structural DNA for a team as well. If
you don't start with that, and as a comparison,
you have a team that really prides themselves
on shipping fast and meeting deadlines really
prescriptively, you might end up in a different
world or your role as a PM might be a little bit
more challenging if you want to push on this
stuff. So I do think you have to take into
account what is the DNA of the team. And then can
you exploit that? Which I was able to do. Or do
you actually have some change management to put
into effect if you believe that it's worthwhile?
Let's go back to the perimeter, drawing the
perimeter concept to make that a little more
real for people. So your advice here is the role
of a PM, part of your main job, especially when
it comes to engineers and design is to draw the
perimeter for the team. Can you make that a little
more real? What's an example of that maybe from
something you worked on? What does that look like?
Totally. The best word to describe the perimeter
is just constraints. At the end of the day,
you should be adding as many constraints
as reasonable in order to let engineers
and designers come up with the most creative
solutions for whatever you're trying to do.
And so again, if we just stay focused on this
point of sale example, one constraint would be,
"Who the hell are we serving? Are we trying
to go after sit-down restaurants that are
serving five different courses and have
a 200 item wine list? Or are we trying
to serve the taco truck?" Those will lead to
very different spaces. And if you leave both on
the table, the lack of that constraint makes
designing a good solution that much harder,
that there instances where you actually can't
apply that many constraints. But I bet that
if you push on enough different axes, you
eventually scope it down to a point where
it feels really good for the team. It's
just about how do you remove decisions,
right? Because this I think is maybe a trite
phrase, but the best decision is no decision.
If you don't even have to think about the
decision, the team is that much more effective.
So yo give people a few maybe even pointers of,
"I need to create more constraints maybe for my
team to help them go crazy, but within
this box that we all agree on," so you
mentioned make sure the user's clear of who
you're designing for. Is there anything else,
just thinking about maybe the PRD someone's trying
to write to help create this constraint? What
other maybe bullet points, sections would
you imagine or do you find useful to add?
So beyond customer
segment/like-what-their-specific-role is,
I think another one would be, we can
loosely call it, jobs to be done,
even though I know that's becoming
an increasingly loaded term.
Yeah, it's great.
But what's the thing they're trying to do and
how many different pathways are you willing
to entertain around it? That's another one
that I would think about. Depending on what
you're building, there's availability. So
do you care about desktop web, mobile web,
native mobile, et cetera? And maybe another one
to think through just as an example would be,
this is probably getting closer to what a lot
of people think about in terms of principles,
but what are the things that you want to be
known for when you ship a product? One example
there might be speed. And so if you say speed
is more important than consistency of data,
that's a huge tradeoff and constraint
that you can give the team." Oh my god,
if an engineer hears I don't need real time
consistency of data, I can do so much cool
stuff and easily accomplish that speed thing."
And so that's just a very technical example maybe.
Awesome. Okay, I'm glad I followed up on that.
There's a couple more things you mentioned that
I want to come back to real quick. The first
is this tuning fork idea. I completely agree,
this point you made, that the best way to get
feedback from your team is to take a first pass
at it, and here's a rough quick draft. I find with
design, especially if you design something ugly,
designers are often like, "Let me make that
better. We can't stand this thing." Is there
anything else you want to add there? Just this
idea of tuning fork as a feedback strategy.
Okay, there's two areas we can go deeper on
here. One is in how you get the feedback. So
this is definitely a Square-ism, I think it was
probably adopted from Amazon, which is around
the silent read of documents. When you are all so
busy and someone's like, "I wrote a doc," you send
it into the Slack ecosystem and everyone goes,
"Please give feedback." You have so much going
on... You'll be lucky to maybe get a response.
Maybe there's one or two people that chime in.
And so even though we hate meetings and we love
asynchronous, there is a lot of value to saying,
"I need 20 minutes of focused time to interrogate
something that I've done. We're not going to
talk. I'm literally going to force us into a
room or Zoom. You're going to read this doc,
I'm going to watch you comment on it in
real time. I'm going to respond to your
comments in real time. And at the end of
this thing I'm going to have enough really
good input that I can do a huge rub on
this thing and get to the next phase."
I love that. So it's basically instead of,
"Hey, I'm sending you this doc to go review,
give me feedback," it's, "I'm going to schedule a
meeting, and the meeting is for you to spend time
reviewing this doc and giving me feedback
and then maybe we could talk about it."
Yep. And I think a lot of people are going to
hate hearing that because like, "Oh my god,
I have so many meetings already. Why do I want
another meeting that isn't even a meeting?"
But that's the best kind then, because
it's actual work getting done, right? And
maybe you carve out two minutes at the end
for one really immediate discussion topic
or something. But I don't think we give
enough space in any type of meeting for
people to actually think. And when you are just
staring at a doc with your camera off and the
only expectation is to engage with that thing,
thoughts are a little bit better and crisper.
And I think with this idea, if someone says,
"I want a meeting where you just sit and review
this doc," you could always say, "Let me just
review it asynchronously. I'll give you feedback,
I promise. Give me 24 hours." Right? It's
not like they have to come to this meeting.
Although I would urge you to
make them come to the meeting.
Okay, say more there, because you
find that that's a lot more effective.
I think there's two sneaky things
hiding behind that. One is the, "Yeah,
I'll get to this in the next 24 hours."
Maybe they don't. Maybe you've really
trust that person and they're the exception.
But beyond that, there is something else to
the real time interaction that can happen when
you're commenting and responding on a dock at
the same time. I think this is the part that
often gets lost, which is the latency between a
comments or question and a quick follow-up from
the author just pushes that cycle speed really
long in a way that doesn't need to be. And so when
people are trying to find how do you move faster,
this actually is one of those very good
examples of moving slower to move faster.
It reminds me Claire Vo, I think it was her
phrase of moving one clock speed faster,
and just like that's the way you speed up a
company is try to move one clock speed faster,
which in this case is just reduce the time
between feedback and iteration. I love it.
Okay, I want to shift to talking
about a few very tactical things
that you've found really helpful in your
PM career and something you recommend
to other product teams. The first is
something you call a decision log. You
think every PM should keep a decision log. Talk
about what that is and why that's powerful.
I will say there's two different decision
logs we could talk about. We'll focus on the
former though. The latter is just as you're
making decisions within your job, you should
document those within a PRD. Make sure everyone
knows. It's just a silly, very small thing,
but I think every PM should do it.
The other decision log though that
I think is quite critical is if
we zoom out for a second, every
person has something that they can do to
slightly increment in their craft. Sprinters
have certain exercises that they do. There's
something beautiful about pianists and piano
scales where it doesn't matter if you are just
learning the piano or you are a 30-year veteran,
you're still doing your scales, and
it's because it lays the foundation
for everything else that you need to do.
And so we all talk about product sense. It's this
super mystical thing that no one knows how to get
better at. To me, it's just a fancy way of saying
you can make good decisions with insufficient
data, and the core of that is decisions. And
so PMs need as many reps as possible in making
decisions, documenting the rationale behind those
decisions, and then crucially seeing the outcome
of them. And so the natural followup would be,
"Well, I only have to make X decisions in my
job. How the hell do I make more of them?"
Look around you. There's other teams that are
making decisions. What would you do if you
were in that position with the information
you have? Great, write it down. Say why.
There's other companies that are doing crazy
things. What are they doing? What would you
do if you were responsible for the roadmap?
Write it down. A year later, see what they've
shipped. You can just do this for anyone.
It's free, and no one takes the time to do it,
but that's how I think you get better at actually
making decisions, is just doing more of them.
Hearing you describe this, it feels like,
"Obviously yes, why aren't we doing this?
How else can we get better if we're not reflecting
back on the decisions we've made? And realizing,
"Hey, I made a bunch of bad decisions, but
I'm always so confident in my decision still,
maybe shouldn't be. So I guess first of
all, do you actually do this? How often
do you do this? And is there an example of you
learning something from your own decision log?
Many. And many of them because it was a wrong
decision. But yes, I do keep a decision log.
I have a separate sort of practice where it's
just a daily log, which is everyone wants the
perfect note-taking system. To me, the best
note-taking system is inspired by... What is
it called? big ass text file, BATF. There's a
funny blog post from 2001 on it, but it's just,
you write everything that happens to you in a day
in a bolded list and it's all in one big note.
That way you can command F it, do whatever you
want. The way that I keep track of it is I do a
little hashtag decision and then write things down
just as I think about them. And then I'll have a
reminder to comb back through on some cadence.
And so I'll first use a positive example, which
is a funny one. So if you rewind to, I don't even
know what year, but Shopify had just launched Shop
app, their consumer application for what started
as tracking your order when you bought something
from a Shopify customer and then it's evolved
into a full-blown Amazon competitor, where you can
actually find merchants and buy things through it.
When they first launched it though, I was like,
"Oh my God, this is so brilliant. They have
completely hijacked this specific loop for
consumer buying behavior via this very unassuming
thing, which is package tracking." And so that
morning I was like, "Whatever, I'm going to
quickly draw a diagram of this flywheel that
I think Amazon owns today. I'm going to show
how Shopify is slowly planting their little
seed to take over this and how Shop app fits
into it." I tweeted out. And then I don't know,
that day there must have been 60 Shopify
employees that followed me. I was like,
"What the hell is this guy talking about?"
And so funny enough, fast-forward,
I've talked to some of the folks that worked on it
and they're like, "Yeah, nailed it. Here's what we
were thinking. Here's why." It's no longer secret
sauce. But that was a really interesting example
of both doing a decision log, putting my rationale
down on paper. In this case, broadcasting it out,
but then having that be a mechanism for
it making its way back to me to actually
better understand why did they make the decision
versus what I thought, because the reasons were
a little bit different, but the outcome was
the same. So that's one interesting example.
It's an amazing story. You doing this
explains why you've been so successful.
I could see how this all connects
now. I think for a lot of people,
they would want to build this habit.
Clearly there's a lot of value here,
but they just don't because they got a lot of
other things going on or it's just like this new
thing they have to start doing. Is there anything
that helped you adopt this practice of this daily
log/decision log that you think might be helpful
to folks to motivate them to give this a shot?
This is probably just general advice on building
any habit, which is start small and just force
yourself to do it. And there's that old saying
around, how do you start running as a hobby? You
don't do it by saying, "I'm going to run a mile
every day." You do it by putting your sneakers at
the foot of your bed unless you take your shoes
off inside, then you put it at the front door,
you have your shorts ready to go and you're
like, "I commit to putting on my shorts.
And if I decide after getting dressed to go
run, that I still don't want to go run. Okay,
fine." But you build up to that thing.
I think decision logs are the lightest
weight thing possible. And so you can start super
easy by saying, "You know what? Every Sunday
morning I'm going to scroll through Twitter, I'm
going to check out Hacker News, whatever it is,
I'm going to see something interesting and
I'm going to make a bet. I'm going to place
my decision on this thing." Write it down,
and then set a calendar invite in X weeks,
X months to see what plays out. And that's all
it is, right? 10 minutes once a week, super easy.
And then over time you can crank it up. And then
eventually you're just constantly writing these
decisions down and then it's like feeding its
way back into you. It becomes second nature.
And you're touching on something that there's
been a little bit of talk on this podcast
and newsletter post about this idea of
to get better product sense and product
taste and also just decision making this
case, one of the best strategies is to
simulate other people's decisions and
simulate what they're thinking through
and predict what they're going to do,
which is what you're describing here.
Totally. I do want to apply a pretty
severe caveat here though, which is,
a decision log is not a replacement for building
products. It's a additional complimentary thing
that you can be doing on your own. But if you
think that you can just sit back in your chair,
look out at the market, make
a bunch of calls and be like,
"Look at how smart I'm getting without
actually being hands-on with building
a product," you're not actually going to get
any better. So I just want to interject that
Amazing caveat, very important. Don't
just sit and read Hacker News and
think you're going to be become an
amazing founder or product leader.
This episode is brought to you by Eppo. Eppo is a
next generation A/B testing and feature management
platform built by alums of Airbnb and Snowflake
for modern growth teams. Companies like Twitch,
Miro, ClickUp, and DraftKings rely
on Eppo to power their experiments.
Experimentation is increasingly essential
for driving growth and for understanding the
performance of new features. And Eppo helps
you increase experimentation velocity while
unlocking rigorous deep analysis in a way that no
other commercial tool does. When I was at Airbnb,
one of the things that I left most
was our experimentation platform,
where I could set up experiments easily,
troubleshoot issues, and analyze performance
all on my own. Eppo does all that and more with
advanced statistical methods that can help you
shape weeks off experiment time and accessible
UI for diving deeper into performance and out
of the box reporting that helps you avoid
annoying, prolonged and analytics cycles.
Eppo also makes it easy for you to share
experiment insights with your team,
sparking new ideas for the A/B testing flywheel.
Eppo powers experimentation across every use case,
including product, growth, machine learning,
monetization, and email marketing. Check out
Eppo at get eppo.com/lenny and 10X your
experiment velocity. That's get eppo.com/lenny.
If someone wants to try this idea of a daily log,
what is it exactly? Say decision log or daily log,
is it just things that happen today and
then hashtag, "Here's a decision I made,
or here's a decision I think Shopify will
make in the future"? Is that the format?
Yeah, it depends on how far you want to go down
productivity and notetaking as to rabbit holes,
but let's start basic. This is not what I do,
but I think it's the easiest place to start.
Spin up a Google doc or a Notion page, just call
it daily log and then bullet point out the date
of today. And then as you're going through
your day, you have a meeting, just type in
the meeting name. If there's a takeaway, put it
under there. If there's a decision you can make,
do hashtag decision. And in this case, say,
"Shopify launch Shop app. I think this is their
way to take over the fulfillment to buying
behavior loop. The reason for that is X, Y,
Z." Follow up on this in six months
and then set your calendar invite.
Awesome. So as motivation for listeners to try
this sort of thing, just look at the success Kevin
has had as in his career and how insightful
he has been so far and will continue to be.
And this is how these happen. This is how your
mind learns to see things in a really unique,
interesting way. So I know you're modest
and aren't going to take any credit,
but I'm just saying this is how you
get better, is trying stuff like this.
Footnote, correlation versus
causation. It's all put out there.
Could be all genes. Could be completely unrelated
to anything you've done entire life, I suspect.
Could just be me being very
lucky, I'll put that out there.
Could also be luck. Okay, so something I
wanted to touch on with this decision log idea,
and it's a segue to talking about hiring,
is I think interviewing is also really good
opportunity to try some like this. I feel like
people interview lots of people. They think
they know what they're looking for. They think
they've made all these decisions. They think
they have these amazing interview questions that
are going to help them see really good signal,
but you never actually go back and see,
"Was I right? Should we have hired that
person? Did this person work out? Was that
question asked them at all inform? Was it
at all a leading indicator of anything?" And
I feel like this is a really good method for
improving your interviewing abilities, is
like, "Here's the questions asked. Here's
what I decided. Here's what I think," and then a
year later look back, "Was that actually right?"
Yeah, totally. I think some of the best companies
actually do have a practice around this where
they have a 6, 12, 18 month check-in on new
hires and they then compare their performance
against level hired at and then review against
the scorecards. It's a pretty laborious process.
So startups aren't probably going to do it
in the same amount of rigor, but it shows
you so much about the holes in your interviewing
process. So I definitely plus one of that one.
I love that. Oh my god, that puts
all this pressure on your score,
which is great. So that's actually a segue
talking about hiring. There's a couple more
tactics that I've seen you be really good
at. So one is just hiring in general. You
have a lot of interesting approaches to
hiring, including this idea of a unsell
email where you try to convince someone not
to join your company. Talk about that and why
you think that's effective and then anything
else along the lines of hiring you've learned.
I'll say the idea of the unsell email came
from a place of failure, which is at Square
I had shifted into a position where I had to hire
a lot of people really quickly. And through that,
as a fairly new hiring manager, you're like, "All
right, great. I've been told the goal is to hire
fast." Okay, you give me a metric, you're
going to go after it. So you do your best
to get as many people in the door as possible.
When you're talking to your recruiting partner,
they're incentivized to increase pass through
rates, offer to close rates, all these other
things, and so they're like, "Yeah, this
person's really good." And you listen. "Yeah,
they are pretty good, aren't they?" Even though
there's a sneaking suspicion that maybe they're
not the right fit, but you move forward anyways.
So fast-forward, there's a few folks I bring on,
and within six months they come to me and they're
like, "This is not at all what I thought I was
going to do. This is not the environment I thought
I was going to walk into. You didn't warn me about
this, that and the other. I feel terrible. How do
I prevent this?" And the reason it's bad is not
just because they feel surprised, but because
then, either one, they decide to leave, two,
they're not performing because it's not the
right role or environment for them, or three,
maybe the company is still good, but that
role isn't. And so they immediately try to
do internal mobility or something to another
team, which then leaves you with the same
hole. So all of those bad outcomes. [inaudible
00:48:37] "How do I prevent this?" Well, I just
got to front load all the gnarly stuff they're
going to find out in their first six months.
And so the practice I started developing is
you go through the whole interview process.
During that period, you're collecting all these
little concerns, fears, anxieties that they're not
explicitly saying, but they're definitely hinting
at. You got to be pretty honest with yourself
about which ones are real. But then when you get
to offer stage, I send an email with no more than
eight bullet points and I say all the terrible
things that are probably going to reinforce their
fears. I'm pretty candid about, "This is what
it's like here." Maybe one example would be,
"Hey, I'm a parent and I'm worried about
work-life balance." Maybe they don't say that
explicitly in the interview process, but you get
a feeling for it. And I get that as a parent too.
So if I'm at a startup, I'll be really clear
and I'll say, "You know what? We are a series
A startup. We are pushing really hard at
product-market fit. The expectation here
is going to be that you're online at 10:00,
that you can occasionally hop on a meeting
on a Saturday or Sunday." And if you can tell
them that upfront and they can read that whole
email and still be equally excited to join,
you find yourself an A+ hire. But if they
read that and they're like," I don't know
anymore," it's way better to say, "Great,
this is not a good fit. Let's go our separate
ways" than have them leave after six months.
When I first instituted this, I lost
30% of candidates at offer stage.
Oh wow.
Which drove my recruiting partners insane because
they look terrible. Their manager is like,
"What the hell are you doing? You're losing
everyone at the very end." And so they ask,
"Can you either not send this thing?" Or,
"Can you send it at the very beginning?" And
my answer is no, because I don't know what
they're afraid of yet. I have to go through
the whole process to actually understand the
thing that's going to potentially make them
say no, and that's really crucial I think.
But once you hear it again, this
is such an obviously good idea,
clearly not an easy thing to do. In
this case where recruiters were upset,
is it just get buy-in from folks above, like,
"Okay, this sucks for them, but at a macro level,
this is good for the business" and they're
like, "All right, let's keep doing it"?
At Square, at least, when I first started doing
it, luckily I had a very good relationship with
them. So that's a good starting point. This is
maybe going to come across a little bit flippant,
but they can't stop you from sending an email
technically. So I'm just going to send the
email. And if someone really wants to come and
say, "This is bad for business," whatever it is,
I have very strong reasons for why that's not
the case. And now I've done it so many times,
at least, that I can point to very clear
proof points on why this is the right path.
In theory, the incentives would be aligned where
the recruiter success matters. It's based on,
did they actually have a good time? Did
they stay? Did they have good impact?
Totally.
But since they're not, obviously
incentives aren't right.
I think some companies have shifted on that,
where recruiters and salespeople are compensated
sometimes in similar ways in terms of quota
and whatnot. And so they'll hold the recruiter
accountable to six, 12 post offer tenure before
they say, "Oh yeah, you successfully landed this
role." So you can tweak the incentive structure
a little bit, but not everyone does that.
Okay. So the advice here is to end up with
better people that end up being successful
and happy. Keep track of the things that will
probably be painful for them at the company,
and then craft an email that shares upfront,
"Here's what made be a problem if you join,
and I just want to be very upfront
about it." I think you actually
shared a template of one of these
emails in one of your blog posts.
Yep, that's right. I have a fairly
real one in [inaudible 00:52:30].
Is there anything else hiring-wise? I
know there's probably infinite things
that you've done, but is there anything
else you think might be worth sharing
of things you've learned to be more
successful at hiring awesome people?
One final note I'll make on unsell email is it's
not as if you just send the email and then they
either say yes or no. Most of the time they will
say, "Thank you. I am cool with six of these.
This one freaks me out. Can we talk more?"
Definitely. And I think this is where hiring
managers have an incredible responsibility that
sometimes isn't taken as seriously as it should,
which is, when you are working with
someone to get them to join or to offer,
you need to bend to do whatever it takes
for them. And so if they're like, "Hey,
the only time I can talk is tonight at
11 o'clock after my kids go to bed."
"No problem. Here's my phone number, let's hop
on. I will walk you through whatever you want
to talk about." That sort of has to be the
place you get to for really strong hires.
So that's just one other thing I'll say.
The meta point around that is you need to
be really invested in the candidates. This
probably does change at a certain scale,
like if you're "organization" is hiring a hundred
engineers or whatever, you have process around it,
you have pipelines, there's a machine at that
point, but I do think the direct hiring managers
have a responsibility to be really involved in
every individual, because there's no one who's
directly hiring a hundred people. It's always
within a number that I think you can take on.
Okay, so this is the final tactic that I heard
you're amazing at, which is automating user
research. On the surface this sounds amazing. "I'm
going to automate my user research. It's going to
be amazing. So great." Talk about why you find
this really powerful and important. And then how
do you actually do this? How do you automate user
research? How have you done this on your teams?
Let's start from why this even matters.
I think a lot of folks, going back to
what is the point of product management, I
think there's a similar overlap with UXR,
like user experience research, and people
will say, "Well, if they're doing research,
what do I need to do? I should just be consuming
what they're producing to help with that."
I know PM should settle for looking through
bent glass in my opinion because whether
it's a research report, whether it's
something a salesperson is telling you,
whether it's market research, don't care,
it's been processed by someone, and PMs
need direct exposure to raw material. End of
story. And so that's where I think you just need
to constantly be talking to or interacting with
whoever is your customer. That's the foundation.
So okay, if we all agree on that, then the
question is, "Well, I don't have time. It's
so hard. How do I find them? My customer success
manager says I can't talk to the client." If you
are in a situation where the product manager
is literally not allowed to talk to a customer,
there is something structurally wrong and that
needs to be fixed first. So I'm going to ignore
that one for now just because that's a whole
other rabbit hole, but you need to fix that
in order to even get close to the next thing.
Okay, now the excuse is going to be, "Well,
I don't have time. I don't want to run a program.
I don't want to have to query and look up and
send out emails every week." There's so
many good resources out there right now,
and I think that there are... I'll speak
mainly from a B2B sense. I think B2C, slightly
different story, I don't have as much experience
there. But B2B, the two things I will say, one is,
there's this thing called userinterviews.com.
Shout out to them. They're pretty much user
testing but explicitly focused on B2B and you can
put in super clear criteria on the type of people
you want to talk to. They do the heavy lifting
and sourcing it, and then you just review and say,
"Yes, yes. No, no," and you can have a steady
stream of the exact ICP, you want to go after.
ICP is ideal customer profile that you want to go
after just coming to you automatically. Amazing.
The next one though, it depends on whether
or not you have this tooling in place,
but the broader theme behind this next category
is your sales team is a research team, and if you
don't view them that way, you are missing out on
half the value. And so there's tools like Gong,
which do call recordings, and you can set
up filters and alerts for specific terms,
phrases, competitors, whatever you want. I
don't care what PM you are in the team. You
can find the terms that are associated with what
you care about the most. Those then get pushed
automatically to a Slack channel or otherwise. And
then you can set up workflows either via Zappy or
something else to say, "Who was the customer?
Pull their email, put that into a sequence,
drop in my Calendly" and you just have interviews
showing up automatically on your calendar. I will
say I cannot take credit for this. Shout
out to Beth Hills who was a PM that hired
at Mutiny. She is the queen of automating customer
research and built an amazing system around this.
So the way it works is you set a
term for like, I don't know, POS,
point of sale, something in Gong, and if
somebody says that or has an issue there,
talk about again how that schedules
a meeting with you potentially.
Yes. So Gong has an integration with Slack.
You set up this alert, it posts to Slack
the excerpt of the transcript where it was
mentioned along with the user or customer
name. So in this case, it'll be Lenny's
Burger shop. lenny@lennysburgershop.com,
and then you can set up a Zapier to take every
new Slack post from that and then send using,
I don't know, customer.io in email to
that person using that field. And then
in that template of the email, drop in your
Calendly specifically for user research.
Wow, that is genius. I love that. There's
another similar tactic that Teresa Torres
shared on the podcast in one of the earlier
episodes where you have a little popup on your
homepage asking people, "Hey, do you want to talk?
We'd love to hear feedback on our product. Click
here if you want to give us some feedback,"
and then that schedules Calendly on the PMs.
Totally.
PM's calendar. So you mentioned Gong,
customer.io. There's some tools here.
Zapier obviously. Is there anything else you
find useful to help automate the sort of stuff?
If I take a step back from the automation side
or maybe straddle it, depending on the type of
business you're in, there's ideally people talking
about you somewhere, right? It's either happening
on Reddit or Twitter or on some forum or your
support forum. There is a community, there's
a destination somewhere. And if there isn't,
then I don't know, that's too bad. Maybe you
don't have product-market fit. If you can
take advantage of that, you can usually set up
something. And if it's not a Gong or a Zapier,
maybe it needs to be just a custom script that
you write or you sit down with an engineer to
say like, "How do we set up alerting around this
thing so that I know when things are happening?"
I think you can't use the effort required
to do that as an excuse to not be talking
to your customers more frequently. Because
again, if we go back to a product manager
should be trying to convert this potential into
kinetic energy, part of that understanding and
part of knowing the constraints you can apply is
just living in that world as much as possible.
The best comparison I can give is, there
is a world of difference between reading
a report about a lime cook and then standing
with a lime cook. You will just pick up on
so many ancillary aspects of what their life
is like that cannot possibly be communicated
in a report. You owe it to yourself as a PM
to be exposed to those things all the time.
In my experience, every time I talk
to a customer, I'm always reminded,
"Why have I not been doing this more? How can
I not be doing this? It's absurd that I haven't
done this," like every time you actually
do it. But until you do that, you're like,
"No, no, I know what they want. I'm reading all
the customer service talent issues, I'm reading
their emails, I get it." Until you actually talk
to them, you're like, "Oh wow, I had no idea."
I love that your advice is like,
the tactics you're sharing aren't,
"Here's how you get a bunch of feedback."
From your users, it's like, "Here's how
you actually get to talk to the right users."
It's like in the end of the funnel talking to
a potential customer. It's not just reading
a cool... some feedback that they shared.
That's right. I think just like the last
point on this one is when you join a new
team or start a new role, every PM
is budding with energy to do this,
"Of course I'm going to talk to my users."
But then you reach a point where you go,
"No, I know them inside and out. I don't need
to talk to them anymore. I can write a PRD in
my sleep. And I'm so busy doing both, product
improvements, maintenance, annual planning,
something else.I can use my intuition from the
hundred interviews I've already done. I don't
need to do one more interview." And that is a
very tempting lie to tell yourself because the
world is changing, their lives are changing,
and you need to constantly be exposed to those
little micro changes in their lives in order to
build the product that they'll eventually need.
The best explanation I've heard of this is
actually from your new boss, Patrick Collison,
boss's boss's boss, I don't know how far
away you're from him, where he talks about
user research and where it fits in. And the way he
described it is, instead of doing user research,
talking to customers, informing what to build,
it's talking to user, talking to customers
informs your mental of what the customer
needs and then that informs what to build.
100%.
Beautiful way to think about it.
Okay, so I'm going to take us to a
couple recurring themes of this podcast, a couple
corners of this room that we have. First of all,
I want to go to AI corner, so let's walk
over there. Hello, AI corner. I'm curious
if you've found any interesting uses
of AI in your work or in your life.
There's plenty in work. I don't know if
any of them are interesting or novel. I
feel like everyone's just figuring it out in
real time together. So I'll actually take us
in a slightly different direction. And this may
be isn't directly useful to product managers,
but I think it's a really good story.
So when Midjourney V1 was released,
if we can remember that far back, it
was at least I got beta access on a
Saturday. And for what's worth, I have three
daughters, one of them's seven years old,
and so her and I were awake. We were waiting for
the other two to wake up and I was like, "Oh,
I have this cool new thing. Do you want to play
with me?" And she goes, "Of course." So we log in,
we create an account and I type in the first
prompt, image gets generated, it's like a rainbow
or something. And then I ask her, "Do you want to
try it?" She goes, "Of course." So she types in
unicorn prancing in a field and it generates this
hideous looking demented unicorn with two rear
ends and a demon flying over it. And I'm appalled
at first thinking that she's going to feel really
bad about what she got shown, but instead I
look over and she's in awe. She is amazed.
And then she turns to me and
she goes, "Did I draw that?"
"Yeah, I guess you did." And the thing that
I got hung up on was that she used the word
draw. She didn't say, "Oh, I enter a prompt and
the LLM produced this thing," or whatever weird
terminology that all of us use. It's like, "Did I
draw that?" I don't know when it clicked for me,
but at some point in time after that I was
like, "The concept of these image generation
models is the same as a crayon to her. There is
no difference in her mind." And that is an insane
change that I can't even comprehend. And so for
me that's just been I think an experience that
I go back to when I think about people asking,
"What do you think AI is going to do and what's
the next thing? And is it chat or is it something
else?" I cannot comprehend what a child who grew
up with a crayon of an LLM is going to think
is a good product in 20 years. I need to start
crying. But goddammit, I have no freaking clue.
And so I think I have a cheat code actually as
a parent, because I get to see how they evolve
and use these tools in real time. But all I can
say is we are not even beneath the dust on the
surface when it comes to what's going to change.
Wow, that is an amazing story, it gave
me tingles. It makes me think a little
bit about how we used to code in binary
and then assembly and now it's Java,
and then I don't know, all the languages,
Python. And now it's like AI, LLM generating
code and it's the same thing for drawing
potentially. It used to be sticks on a cave
and then became crayons and pens and iPads
and all that stuff. And now it's again LLMs,
so that's pretty bonkers. Amazing story. Thanks
for sharing that. Useful to PMs and non PMs alike.
Okay, I'm going to take you to another
recurring corner/segment of the podcast,
fail corner. I'm curious if there's a story
of failure that you can share of something
that didn't go the way you wanted and still
had a positive impact on your life or career?
Well, there's countless stories of failure,
but I'll choose the one that I think I've had
to reference the most with people and has been
to date the most difficult one to really talk
about. I'm on the other end of it, and so now it's
very easy, but it took several years to get there.
So context, I'm [inaudible 01:06:47] my way
to PM, I land my first official, by title,
PM job at a startup. I made it. I've arrived.
I'm officially a product manager. And we go up,
we go down, all the things happen. Fast-forward,
the company is really struggling and so we go
through a series of rolling layoffs and I'm round
4 something. At that point in time, my wife was
nine months pregnant with our first child, and
so I am freaking out. There is the personal side
that I'm worried about, but then there's also
my identity that has been completely crushed,
because in the moment all I could think was,
"I thought I was a product manager. This is
evidence I am not," and I couldn't get past that.
And so for what it's worth, this is the one post I
have on my website that I actually feel really,
really proud of. It's called Finding Swagger. I
can talk about why it's titled that way, but it's
the thing that I really wrote more for myself
because it's a good reminder to me every
time I fall into this mentality again,
because that may have been the first time that I
really had the feelings of, "I'm not worth it" or,
"I'm not meant to be this person," but it's
recurred several times since then over the past
decade. And when I read back through my mentality
of how I got to the other end of it, it helps
even myself sort of get back on the horse.
So okay, I get laid off, I'm distraught, I have
no purpose, I'm nothing. And it was through a lot
of reflection, a lot of conversation with friends
and my wife where you eventually need to convince
yourself that there is a difference between you
not being good at something and a business or
company not needing that thing at a particular
moment in time, or you being very good at
something but not in the way that a company needs.
And so I think once I was able to get to that,
Square for me was the immediate subsequent role
that I took on. And I went into that thing just
full steam ahead, I'm going to prove myself. "I
know I'm good," because I think I'm good, "and I
am going to prove the hell out of that" mainly to
myself, but ideally to other people too.
I think you shouldn't do things for
other people for validation, but the initial
success I got to see in launching a product,
gaining the trust of my peers, having something
that restaurants were texting me about, saying,
"I can start my restaurant because of this.
I didn't go down during rush hour because of
this," that gave me the validation to say,
"Okay, I am competent at this thing called
product management." And then from there you
can continue to build and continue to grow.
But I think right now, the market's weird, right?
The market's wonky. There's a lot of really good
talent that is just getting hit over sideways.
I have a lot of friends that are having the same
mental conversations around, "Well, I guess
I'm just not worth it. I guess I wasn't cut
out actually to do this job, do this role, be of
this purpose." In some cases, maybe that's true
and you can sort of have a career transition or a
pivot in your life, but I think it's worthwhile to
reflect on what are the things that were in your
control that you can now change moving forward?
And then what are the things that were truly out
of your control that you can now apply to find
a better fit? And that's one of the big things
that I've been able to, I think, come around to.
And it's really hard because early on I think
it's very tempting to associate a lot of different
things with your identity. You're like, "I'm
a startup guy. I'm a PM, I'm a fast whatever,
I'm a fast thinker." And when an event happens
that pokes at that part of your identity,
the rest of it crumbles. And so long story short,
I think it's really important for folks to use
these moments where it feels bad and feels like
a failure to reevaluate what parts are actually
part of your identity and which parts are in
your control to change in whatever you do next.
Wow, what an important and great story. As
you mentioned, a lot of people are dealing
with finding it hard to find a new gig and a
bunch of layoffs. I think this is going to help
a lot of people. The two categories you shared I
think are especially powerful. So the advice here
is just separate, "This company just doesn't
need someone with my skills right now" from,
"I'm not good at these skills." Can you just
share those two kind of things that might
be true that you may not be recognizing
about why they maybe laid you off again?
Totally. So one is the business just doesn't have
a need for you. They got ahead of their skis and
that's their fault. They probably admit that,
but that's not up to you. The second one though
is my skills and the way that company operates
are not compatible. This one I think is really,
really important because I've seen so many
times where there's been a PM engineer,
designer, whatever role, they
cannot make it work at company A,
and then you see them five years later just
killing it in company B and you're like,
"Did they change as a person? Did they get super
good at what they were bad at before?" Maybe a
little bit, but honestly it was just a change
in environment. And when you find the right
environment in the right role, you just flourish.
And I think this is actually... Sorry,
we'll go back to hiring for just
a moment or at least management.
Please.
This is why performance conversations
can always feel so difficult because
it seems like you're telling someone you
are bad, and as the recipient you're like,
"I am bad." No one wants to hear that. But the
reality is, you are not bad. It is that maybe
the way that your environment is working,
the machine that you exist as a part of,
is not the kind that you thrive in. And
so it's within your control to decide,
"I'm going to change how I work to fit
that environment" or, "I'm going to find
a different environment that actually fits the
way I work much better." And that's empowering.
I think that also applies a lot to interviewing.
A lot of times you interview, don't get the job,
and you exactly feel like, "Oh, I'm just not
good enough." But really that company's way of
working just may not gel with the way you operate.
Like Uber operates very differently from Airbnb,
operates very differently from Google. And so it's
not that necessarily something you're doing wrong,
they just don't think you're fit.
And this connects to something. I
just had another guest on the podcast. He was a
brain science dude, and he talks about how every
company has this kind of habitat. What habitat
are you creating for your employees to enable
them to think differently or to be shut down
and not feel like they can be creative or try
big things or not? And basically, the way
he just kind of to leverage that metaphor,
like you may be a palm tree and you're trying to
join Antarctica and it's not going to go well.
Totally.
You got to find Palm Springs or some hard
place. Kevin, this has been amazing. Okay,
so before we get to very exciting lightning
round, is there anything else that you
think is important or valuable to share,
leave listeners with? And if not, absolutely.
I think we'll probably find
ourselves on interesting
detours to the lightning round, so let's roll in.
Kevin, with that, we've reached our very
exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
Hell, yeah. Let's do it.
Let's do it. Question one,
what are two or three books
that you've recommended most to other people?
I'll start by saying the type of book by
volume that I read and get the most joy
from are autobiographies and memoirs.
It is just the ultimate cheat code to
spend time with people that you respect,
are interested by, or want to learn from.
Could you imagine what it would take in real
life to sit down with Albert Einstein for 50
hours and just have him talk to you about
his life? Impossible. But you can read
and pretty much get the same thing.
So anyways, strong requirement or a
strong suggestion, go read autobiographies
and memoirs of people that you respect,
mostly for their mental model and way to approach
thinking, less about specific things. But the one
book that I read without fail every year has a
very misleading title. It's called The Courage
to Be Disliked. I think it's been mentioned
previously on the podcast, but it covers...
It's a very Socratic method style, so it's about
a philosopher and a young person, and it tries
to teach you the ways of Adlerian psychology,
which is sort of counter to Jungian theory.
The reason I really like it is because it
makes me uncomfortable. So the whole premise,
in my opinion, behind the book and other in
psychology is focus on what you control. That's
the one line. Don't worry about everything
else. Don't worry about what other people
think. Don't worry about what other people
do. You cannot control those. You focus on
yourself and you focus on the actions you can
take. And be the person that you think will
attract other people, that you want to be around.
There's some really pointed notes in there that
I'm like, "Ha-ha-ha-ha. I don't fully agree
with that one," but it always pushes me to
question something about what I believe. And
so in every physical copy of a book I have,
I write the date that I started reading it
again. The front inside cover of this book,
I think it's been seven or eight years at this
point that I've read it every single year.
Wow. It's like a decision logging
in another context almost.
Yeah, a little bit. I would say the other
book I was going to mention is The Paper
Menagerie. This actually shout out to
Sean Rose for... I've never met him,
but I really appreciate Sean. He was one
of the early, if not, first PMs of Slack,
and he used to be really loud on Twitter
in a very good way, and I think I learned
a ton from stuff that he would post. But one
of the things that he posted was this book.
It is just the most beautiful collection of
essays that span sci-fi and fantasy. And so
if you're into that kind of stuff, if you like
exhalation, then Paper Menagerie is even better.
Oh, shit. Guess I got to add this
book to my list. I do love exhalation.
There you go.
Oh, man, this job is tough. I get to learn all
these amazing books and then I got to read them,
but I don't have time. Hard.
Speaking of more time,
next question. Do you have any favorite recent
movies or TV shows that you really enjoyed?
There's less time for either these days. I
will say not novel, the Bear holds a very
special place in my heart right now, both
because I worked in restaurants and I got
to build for them. And so seeing the details that
they do actually gives me a lot of anxiety, but I
really appreciate the craft they put into it.
The other show, actually, I think this is the
first time, Physical 100. So this is a Netflix
show. It's a Korean show about a hundred different
bodybuilders, athletes, what have you, on who
has the optimum physique or whatever. I don't
really care about that part. The two things I
love about the show are, one, it's ridiculous
what people are capable of. You see what they can
physically do and you're like, "Oh my God, that's
amazing what they can put their minds to." The
other part though, and this is maybe a trend of
Korean shows that I've noticed, is the amount of
respect they have in this competition is bar none.
You have this guy who is historically famous,
was the top champion in judo or something, and
you have all these other athletes that are 15, 20
years younger, and they're bowing and just humble
to compete against the guy. I kind of wish that
more American Joes had that level of respect as
opposed to just trying to find the most conflict.
There's something that I really like about that.
That's beautiful. I've started that show, but I
haven't continued it, so I'm going to revisit it.
Cool.
Do you have a favorite product that you've
recently discovered that you really like?
We got a really old 2002 Jeep
to work on with my daughters,
just like a true junker. And as a result of that,
we're repairing it. We're taking off the rust,
replacing parts, and so there's these little
magnetic trays that you can hold screws and
nails and whatnot, so they don't go
flying and rolling around everywhere.
It's stupidly useful when you're working on a
car. And the girls love it because they can use
it for other things like collecting hair clips
or whatever else. So magnetic trays, shout out.
And then selfishly, I will say my buddy
Arjun Mahanti has an app called Circuit.
If you search the app store for Circuit, like
C-I-R-C-U-I-T, HIIT timer, it's such a delightful
little app that lets you track Tabata sex or
whatever else to just get a little workout in.
Super cool. Magnetic tray is not boring
at all. That is extremely cool and it
has a really cool story too. Do you
have a favorite life motto that you
often come back to and find useful to share
with friends and family in work or in life?
I think we've actually maybe touched on both
of these. I'll cheat and I'll pull one from
maybe each parent so that in case they see this,
they don't feel like I'm favoring one of them.
So my mom's side, I think something that
she would always repeat to me growing up
is everything happens for a reason. I hated that
growing up because she only said it when something
bad would happen. Something bad happens, she goes,
"Everything happens for a reason," and I'm like,
"No, it doesn't. Life just sucks." And to no
surprise at this point in the conversation,
I've now grown to really, really appreciate
that piece of advice because what it's
actually trying to communicate is, when
something happens, good or bad, frankly,
don't dwell on it. That's the past. Focus on what
you want to do and then just move towards that.
And then in most cases, you'll be
able to look back in one, five,
10 years and connect the dots in a way where
the story makes sense in your mind. And so just
having that shift in perspective I think has
helped me a lot to not overreact to anything
that happens in my life. So that's one side.
And then on my dad's side, so the funny origins of
this, unsurprising to anyone with Asian parents,
I'm a spunky little 7-year-old, I come home with
my math test one day. I got 97%. I think that's
pretty good. I go show it to my dad with beaming
eyes and pride. He sort of stares down his
nose at it, looks at me, "Where's my other 3%?"
Oh, my God.
I'm just distraught and I sulk away. I'm very
sad. I study hard. I do the next math test,
I get 100% yes. All right, dad's approval, here
we come. I come flying back, I put the test in his
hands, he stares down his nose at it, looks at me,
"Where's my other 3%?" I'm so confused. I'm like,
"I got 100 out of 100. I have no clue what you're
talking about." He just looks me down the eye and
goes, "Who said a hundred is the most you can
get?" At that age, I literally had no clue what
he was talking about. And he had to reframe
it for me in the moment around like, "Well,
was there extra credit? Can you just write
your own problems to challenge yourself more?
Could you have given yourself another test? And
maybe the teacher won't give you credit, but you
give yourself credit for doing additional work."
I think I carry that theme forward where there's
this weird transition we all go through
from childhood to adulthood where we no
longer receive homework, we're responsible for
defining the work that we do. And when you do
that, if all you do is the minimum of what
defined the 100% of what your job requires,
you'll never grow. And so it's up
to you to actually find what is
the additional 3%? There's always three
more percent. So that's my dad's lesson.
Kevin, you're blowing my mind.
There's so many great stories,
you're just full of them. And I feel
like this lesson also applies really
well to product and building
product and founding companies.
Totally.
Just pushing further than people expect and making
it a lot more delightful than the minimum bar.
Final question, speaking of things that maybe
people don't expect and may not understand is
possible, looking at you, nobody would've
guessed that you're a competitive eater
at some point in your life. As a final
question, tell us about this part of your
life. What did you eat? How does this
work? How far did you get in this path?
It's probably misleading to say that I
was a true competitive eater. I wasn't
on the circuit with a... I forget
his name, but Johnny Chestnut.
[inaudible 01:24:21]. Oh yeah, Chestnut
Back in the day, that's like the OG competitive
eater on the hotdog circuit, I guess.
Right.
For me it was more eating challenges.
And so whenever I would travel,
I would find the local eating challenge, whether
it was time-based, volume-based, something else,
and just try to see what I could push my body
to do. I was blessed with a great metabolism,
so I never really had to worry too much
about anything else. And the origin,
the first moment of this was when I was 14,
my sister was going to college in Minnesota and
there's this steakhouse up there called Manny's,
which is where the Vikings Frontline goes to after
every game. And they have this ridiculous 97 ounce
order house. I don't know how many pounds that
is, but it's too much meat for a human to consume.
97 ounce.
97 ounces, yeah. And so I sit down, I order it
thinking, "This is going to be great." They put
it in front of me, it's a monster. You have to
eat in under an hour. And so 45 minutes into it,
I'm halfway through and about to die. And the
catch is, if you finish it in under an hour,
you get it for free. And so my dad again leans in
and goes, "You can't afford not to finish this."
And so, "Message received, sir." Hunker down.
I plowed the other half in 15 minutes. I then
slept for I think three days afterwards.
But after that I was like, "Oh my God,
if I could do that, what else could I
do?" And so, [inaudible 01:25:54] carried
for, I don't know, nearly a decade of
trying to do these interesting challenges.
Wow. I don't know how that's physically
possible, but clearly you did it.
Kevin, this has been wonderful. I think there's
so many lessons here for people in so many ways,
life and work and parenting. Two final questions,
where can folks find you online if they want
to follow you and learn more from you over
time? And how can listeners be useful to you?
I'm on Twitter, just @kevinyien. Technically, I'm
on LinkedIn. I don't post over there. I probably
should. I hear it's very good. But that's where
you can find me. Also, my website. I don't write
that often, and I don't have an RSS feed, which
has always been on my backlog, and I'm always too
lazy to do. But one day I will add it.
One quick note, I'll actually make on
websites. So on one hand, I love all the
different website builders that exist.
It's amazing what we've enabled anyone to be
able to do. There is something really special
about having your corner of the internet
that you built sort of hand by hand,
line by line. And so my website is, it's
a GitHub page. It's hosts on GitHub pages,
but it's just raw HTML, CSS, nothing fancy. I
get so much joy every year just doing a slight
tweak or cleaning of it. And so I really do
recommend that for anyone with the curiosity
and the desire to buy your domain, even if
you're never going to write anything on it,
you're never going to share it out, just own
a little piece of the internet. It feels good.
I love that. I didn't know that
about your website. And I could
see it now as I go there. It's .html,
which you don't see as much anymore.
Exactly. [inaudible 01:27:37].
And then... Yeah, can listeners be useful to you.
This is going to sound trite, and it has
nothing to do with product necessarily,
just be kind. Make for a nicer world, right?
Say thank you a little bit more often. Hold
the door open a little more often.
Wave if you cut someone off in a car.
I think there is a temptation and incentive
structure to create conflict intention.
And in most cases, the world would just
benefit from a little bit more kindness.
What an incredibly beautiful way its ended. Kevin,
this was so much fun. I'm so glad we did
this. Thank you so much for coming on.
Thank you for having me.
Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.