NewBank is bigger than Coinbase, Robinhood,
Affirm, SoFi, and Lemonade combined. 80% to 90%
of NewBank's growth is through word of mouth.
We're not trying to be incrementally better,
we are trying to be fundamentally different. We
want our customers to love us fanatically.
It feels like NewBank is one of the
historically most successful companies
that launching new business lines.
We built a lending product, we built
an investment product, we built an insurance
product, we built a series of small business
products. We rarely scale a project until
we know the Sean Ellis score hit a threshold
that we find really compelling.
I want to talk about strategy.
Kevin Systrom in the early days of Instagram, I
heard him say it at a conference. We may not be
right, but at least we are clear. Even if your
strategy isn't right, you have a very clear
idea of what was supposed to be happening.
Where do you think all this goes in the future?
Why not have the company that reinvents banking
come out of Sao Paulo, Mexico City, Bogota?
Today my guest is Jag Dougal. Jag is chief product
Officer at NewBank, which is one of the most
under-the-radar monster businesses that you'll
ever come across with a fanatical user base, and a
really unique approach to building product. Before
NewBank Jag was director of product management at
Facebook, leading monetization of video and
third-party content, including news, gaming,
and influencer content. Prior to Facebook, he
was senior vice president of product and strategy
at Quantcast, and group product manager and head
of strategy for Display ads at Google, which was
Google's second-largest business at the time.
In our conversation, we cover how to build
products that people become fanatical about,
how to develop a strategy, category design,
product line expansion, the future of FinTech
and tons more. With that, I bring you Jag Dougal
after a short word from our sponsors. And if you
enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting app or
YouTube. It's the best way to avoid missing future
episodes, and it helps the podcast tremendously.
This episode is brought to you by Work OS. If
you're building a SaaS app, at some point your
customers will start asking for enterprise
features like SAML authentication and skim
provisioning. That's where Work OS comes in,
making it fast and painless to add enterprise
features to your app. Their APIs are easy to
understand so that you can ship quickly and
get back to building other features. Today,
hundreds of companies are already powered
by Work OS, including ones you probably
know like Vercell, Webflow and Loom.
Work OS also recently acquired Warrant
the Fine-Grain Authorization Service. Warrant's
product is based on a groundbreaking authorization
system called Zanzibar, which was originally
designed for Google to power Google Docs and
YouTube. This enables fast authorization checks
at enormous scale, while maintaining a flexible
model that can be adapted to even the most complex
use cases. If you're currently looking to build
role-based access control or other enterprise
features like single sign-on, Skim or user
management, you should consider Work OS.
It's a drop-in replacement for Auth zero
and supports up to 1 million monthly active
users for free. Check it out at workos.com to
learn more. That's workos.com. This episode
is brought to you by Mercury. Mercury knows
your financial operations are complex. It
doesn't have to be this way. I've been a
super happy customer of Mercury for over a
year now, and it's honestly hard to imagine
a better online banking experience can exist.
Most founders and finance teams have to couple
together a patchwork of tools to reconcile
transactions from different sources, work extra
hard just to get a holistic view of cash flow
and have maps to company priorities, and struggle
to get answers from platforms that all speak
different languages. Mercury knows that there's
an art to simplifying this complex patchwork
with new bill pay and accounting capabilities,
you can pay bills faster, stay in control of
company spend, and speed up reconciliation.
The end result is the precision control and
focus that startups need to transform how
they operate. Apply in minutes at Mercury.com,
and join over 200,000 ambitious startups like
mine that trust Mercury to get them to perform
at their best. Mercury, the art of simplified
finances. Mercury is a financial technology
company, not a bank. Banking services provided
by Choice Financial Group and Evolve Bank and
trust, members of FDIC. Jag, thank you so much
for being here. Welcome to the podcast.
Lenny, I'm honored to be here. I'm a big
fan of the show, and look forward to the
conversation, so thanks for having me.
I'm even more honored. Thank you for being
here. I want to start by sharing just some
facts about NewBank that I think are going to
blow people's minds. I think a lot of people
in the US especially are sleeping on NewBank,
and I think this is going to help people that
are listening pay even more attention
to the stuff we're going to talk about
and the lessons we're going to share.
So one, NewBank is bigger than Coinbase,
Robinhood, Affirm, SoFi, and Lemonade combined.
80% to 90% of new Bank's growth is through word
of mouth. Three, NewBank has more customers than
Bank of America, which is one of the four big
banks in the US, while also only operating
in three countries in Latin America.
That's right.
And then also, you guys
held the Guinness world record for the world's
largest simultaneous unboxing for a credit card
that you launched at some point. Although I think
somebody beat that record, is that accurate?
I believe that is correct. We've recently set
a new world record for the first underwater
credit card transaction, so we're always
looking for some fun things to do there.
I like that that's a record no one can break
because it was the first one. That's a sneaky
way to get a record. That's hilarious. So my sense
is the reason that NewBank thrived and made it is,
there's this obsession with building a product
that customers are fanatical about. The stat
that I shared of 80% to 90% of growth is word
of mouth. And this idea of growing through
word of mouth in this way is the dream of every
company, whether you're consumer business, B2B,
a bank especially, very unlikely that you
grow at this rate through word of mouth.
So I want to try to help people learn from what
you guys have figured out about how to drive
such massive word of mouth growth. And maybe
just to start from the product perspective,
how do you build a product team and a product
development process that enables you to build
a product that people get fanatical about. And
just want to tell all their friends about?
Yeah, I think there are a few things that are
the fundamentals of making that happen. And
to be clear, a lot of this predates my joining
the company a little short of five years ago,
but I think is an incredible story and is part of
what inspired me to join. But first I would say,
really think hard and tap into a very deep pain
point. The large incumbent Brazilian banks were
amongst the most profitable in the world, they
were also amongst the most hated in the world.
And my personal experience with that is early
in my career, 20 years earlier in the late '90s,
I had done a consulting project in Sao Paulo.
And I remember walking to lunch one day with
the client, who's a friend of mine, and we were
going to Classic Churrasque Korea in Sao Paulo.
And we were walking by his bank branch, and
we were at a stoplight, and he basically said,
that's my bank and I hate them. It was 1997.
And it always stuck in my head. It stuck in my
head for 20 years later when David first reached
out to me. So we were tapping into a deep pain
point, we can go into exactly why. But that was
one thing. The second thing that I would say,
and this is very intentional from David,
and Ed, and Chris, our founders, is we have
a culture at NewBank, which is the most alive in
our employees' minds that I've ever experienced.
Having worked at Google, and Facebook, and other
places like that, I would bet that probably 80%
to 90% of our employees could recite the five
values to you if you stop them in the hall.
It's not just on the wall somewhere. And the first
of those values is a very peculiar phrase, set of
words strung together. We want our customers
to love us fanatically. And I remember when
I interviewed at NewBank for the first time, and
actually flew down to Sao Paulo, I remember seeing
that phrase and thinking, "These are my guys.
These guys are taking this seriously." And a lot
of my interview process from my side was really
vetting if that was real, or if that was a sign
on the wall. So you start with the intent that
you are going to make your customers love you.
And there are a million reasons, operational,
convenience, short-term financial viability,
which is a real thing when you're a venture-funded
startup. Any number of reasons why you can
compromise those things on the edges, and in a
decision day to day, minute to minute, "We can
cut the edges, cut the corner here on that." And
look, I don't think we have been perfect on that,
but we try very hard. And when there are hard
decisions to be made, we bias in favor of the
customer. The customer's love, will they want
to tell their friends, and neighbors, and family
about it? And so I think that's the heart of it.
Once you get those things right, the deep pain
point, and a culture that is maniacal about making
your customers fanatical, then you start to do the
trade craft of product development. You make sure
that you focus on customer discovery before you
start building. You make sure that that discovery
is focused not simply on asking the customer,
but on innovating on their behalf. You make sure
that you take techniques from all over the place,
from Procter and Gamble, to Google, to you name
it, of maybe you can't ask the customer to tell
you what massive new innovation they would love.
You've got to observe them, and find their pain
points even when they aren't noticing it.
And then as you build, you commit to measuring
whether they in fact love the product, not fooling
yourself about that. And iterating like crazy over
and over and over again until you get it just
right. So those are some of the principles,
but I think the trade craft follows the
focus on finding a real deeply held,
emotionally held pain point, and a culture
that says, that's your North Star.
Amazing. There's so many threads there I'm going
to follow, first of all, I want to go back to the
values. So you said there's five, you mentioned
one. Can you just quickly share the rest?
The five, I'll mention them in the order
that most resonate with me. First, we want
our customers to love us fanatically. Second, we
are hungry and we challenge the status quo. Third,
we build strong and diverse teams. Fourth, we
pursue smart efficiency. And one that is in
many ways underlying all of it is, we think
and act like owners, not renters. We do what
is right even when no one is telling us to do
it. And we have many instances of our employees
taking that degree of extreme ownership as
they build products and get them launched.
Okay. And then going back to this idea of
building products people love fanatically,
you talked about how there's this the number one
principle, and it's going to be on everyone's
minds when they're building is build product
people love fanatically. Talked about, you index
towards if you had to make a decision, we're
going to do something people love. Is there
anything more you could share about just how you
operationalize this? For example, is there design
reviews where just you come in, or your head of
design comes in like, "Is this helping customers
love us fanatically?" What's in the systems and
processes of how you operate that allows you to
build that other than just cool, everyone has to
remember this, this is what we're trying to do.
Yeah, we do a few things. And again, I don't
want to also overstate that we've achieved
some nirvana. We honor many of these things in
the breach sometimes, but we have a series of
techniques that we've begged, borrowed, stolen
from other places, some of which we've invented
on our own. But some examples, we love the Amazon
mock press release technique. Explain to me before
we've put a single engineer on the project, not
explain to me actually, explain to the intended
customer why they should care. Because if you
can't tell me in two paragraphs why the customer
you're building this for should care, then there's
still work to do. So that's one technique.
We do have product and design reviews several
times a week where we're asking ourselves that
question, why is this great for the customer? Why
is this fundamentally different for the customer?
How does this redefine the category that we are
thinking about on the dimensions of quality,
on the dimensions of complexity, on the dimensions
of price, and usually on the dimensions of all
three of those at the same time? And breaking
some of the trade-off constraints that you often
wrestle with, and seeing if that's possible,
which isn't always possible, but we frequently
reach for that and sometimes find it.
And then there are other things you do after
you've built and launched a product, whether it's
alpha, beta, or a later stage. The measurement
stuff. And some of your previous guests have
talked about product market fit and how do you
measure? Actually, it's strange. I was sitting
here in Silicon Valley for well over a decade,
I landed in Sao Paulo when I first joined Newbank.
And the small product team at the time is telling
me about this thing called Sean Ellis score. And
we recently had Sean visit us in Sao Paulo and
talk to all of the product managers and designers.
But we are amongst the most fanatical followers of
his methodology anywhere in the world. We rarely
scale a project, a product we've launched, until
we know the Sean Ellis score and we know that it's
hit a threshold that we find really compelling.
Can you describe the actual
score and the approach?
Yeah, the Sean Ellis score is a really simple
methodology used by lots and lots of companies
that a gentleman named Sean Ellis popularized
well over a decade ago. Which basically asks
your customers at each stage, and at each
stage you have a small number of customers,
then a larger group, and growing over time. But
at each stage you ask them, how disappointed would
you be if this product went away? And what Sean
has said is that if at least 40% of your customers
are not very disappointed, not just a little
disappointed, but very disappointed, he has
essentially a three point scale. Not disappointed,
somewhat disappointed, very disappointed.
If at least 40% are not very disappointed, you
haven't reached product market fit. Now we've
had to do some things in NewBank, Brazilians
are a culturally happier group than the global
average. So for us, our threshold isn't 40%, we've
generally moved it up to 50%. I don't believe we
have product market fit unless 50% of Brazilians
are telling us they would be very disappointed,
because Brazilians are inherently polite. And
more polite and more optimistic than average,
so we make our own little tweaks and adjustments.
But we find that to be very helpful. As a company,
this extends beyond product, we are addicted to
our NPS score. And we reach for world beating net
promoter scores as a company, and product
vertical by product vertical as well. And
we are maniacal about tracking how we do. And
again, we compensate for some cultural biases,
and we make sure that we hold ourselves to a high
bar. But there have been, for example, in Mexico,
we've recorded an NPS when we launched
the first couple of years of 94-95.
That's absurd. I've never heard of that.
Yeah. Which is way better than we got in Brazil,
but our NPS scores skew in the 70s, 80s, and
occasionally 90s. And when they dip down even one
or two points, that's a reason for alarm. And we
try to figure out why and we try to make sure that
we make the iterations. So those are the things
we build in. Those are the things we build in.
I'm glad you got into this, I was going to
get into how you measure this stuff. So what
it sounds like is the Sean Ellis survey
is used as you iterate and launch towards
launch. And then NPS is maybe post-launch
to see how people like the product.
NPS is post-launch. We also look at metrics like
churn to make sure that we're not building a leaky
bucket, and that's part of this viral customer
acquisition loop that we've built. We want to
make sure we're building products that are great
enough that our customers will tell their friends,
and we don't have to invest as much in marketing
to drive our growth. And that only works if the
customers you get you retain. I have built earlier
in my career products that have leaky buckets,
and that's a very frustrating treadmill to be on.
So I am personally maniacal about making sure that
the bucket doesn't have a hole in the bottom.
So in this Sean Ellis piece, which is really
interesting because I think it's something a
lot of people can adopt if they're trying to
build products people love, and also that
succeed. Is this a goal for every project?
And I don't know the strategy, or the one
pager. Or is it just implied, "Okay, we're
not going to move past this gate if 50%, less
than 50% of people are not very disappointed."
Is that how it's operationalized?
Yeah, we basically operationalize it. We don't
have it as a hard and fast rule that is in black
and white, but essentially that's the question
people know they're going to get in any product
review that's a post-launch, post data product
review is what's the Sean Ellis score? How do you
know that customers love it? Not just like it,
but love it to the degree that they're going to
tell their friends about it. That's pretty baked
in culturally at this point.
This is an incredible insight,
and I think it explains a lot of the success you
guys have had. Because that's a very high bar.
Many people run the survey, and getting to past
20% is very hard. You have to be very disappointed
if there's a new product they've never used goes
away, that's a high bar. Most people are like,
"Ah, whatever. I don't need this thing."
And you're saying you look for 50% of
people feeling very disappointed if this new
thing they've never used before goes away.
Yeah, that's right. There are several on the newer
side of products that we're launching now we're at
borderline 50, and my push to the team is what are
the three, four, five things you need to build to
really get decisively beyond 50? And what are the
segments or cohorts where it is above 50, and what
is that telling us versus the cohorts where it's
lower than that? So we put a lot of analytical
effort, and a lot of depth of thinking. We were
in a product review several years ago, and our
lead designer, whose ex Google and ex-Facebook, we
were in a review together and the team was saying,
"We think this is good enough for launch."
And he used the phrase, which both Chris and Kara,
one of our co-founders and I have now adopted,
which is, "Good enough, isn't good enough. Is it
great enough?" Is it great enough? Because
that's the bar, particularly for some of
our ten-pole products, but we try to apply it
largely across the board. A lot of companies,
not just in Brazil or Latam, but everywhere, spend
a ton of money on marketing. Their VC budgets,
VC funding basically goes to Google and Facebook.
And I've spent a lot of my career taking that
money on board for Google and Facebook. But it is
a much better scenario if that's a small portion
of what you're doing, and the main portion of what
you're doing is actually investing in making the
product great that you don't have to do that.
Is there an example of a project that comes to
mind that was below that bar and then
you pushed it above where you're like,
"Here's the thing we were missing."?
Yeah, I'll give you one that we're wrestling with
right now. We have a product called Assistente
de Pagamentos, payments assistant. It's right
now only launched in Brazil, we haven't yet
launched it in Mexico and Colombia. Paying
bills in Brazil is quite complex. There are four
different ways, four different payment rails that
different payments use. From the mobile payment
system that has exploded in Brazil the last three
years called PIX, that's become fairly world
famous in the FinTech world, to more standard
and some more archaic rails as well.
So if you're a customer, you've got to
keep track of your bills like we all do.
You've got to keep track of which rail,
you got to collect your bills, you got to make
sure that you pay them. And some of the rails
actually aren't that reliable. So you've paid
it, it doesn't go through. And the consequences
for not paying a bill is getting reported to
the credit bureau and becoming what is called
negativado, having a negative mark on your credit
report. And that can be a big deal for the average
customer. And so this was a real deep pain point.
And as we launched the product in a Reid Hoffman
style, if you are not embarrassed by V1 you've
waited too long. As we've done that last year,
we found that a very interesting pattern. We
had a decent Sean Ellis score, borderline 40%,
I forget the exact number, but basically in
that ballpark. But we found that there was a
small cohort of a customer base who had more than
four plus commitments registered. And even more so
within that small cohort an even smaller bullseye
cohort who had more than four commitments on at
least two of the four rails. And their Sean Ellis
score hit 70% and we're like, "Okay, the key is
we need to across these rails, not have them one
by one. And we need to make it easy for customers
to onboard multiple bills across multiple rails."
And then the automation takes over and people see
the real, benefit because there are ways ...
Patient takes over and people see the real benefit
because there are ways. On the surface if you
said to the average person anywhere, any sort
of developed country, we're going to have a bill
auto-pay, that's on the face of it not necessarily
exciting, but if you build it right, it is
actually a fundamentally different experience
rather than incrementally better experience. And
that's what we've done. We've systematically made
dozens of iterations on the product to allow
customers to in one go do multiple bills across
multiple rails and make that tiny bullseye cohort
that we had, segment that we had a larger and
larger proportion of the customers who are trying,
and by the way, that's a journey still underway.
We have a whole road map for the next year of lots
of small quality adjustments that we're going to
make and we're seeing some great feedback.
We're now over 10 million monthly actives
on that product when we were struggling in the
hundreds of thousands about 15 months ago.
That is a really interesting insight there
of just using the score and survey to narrow
in on who actually loves this the most
and see if there's something there. Is
that something that you generally do or is that
just like, oh wow that came up in this exam?
We do that fairly frequently. When we did our,
we have a high income rewards credit card. It's
called Ultravioleta. We went through a similar
process where at launch there were many different
customer segments, but there was one that really
loved the product and it was not surprising. There
were the ones where the customer spent enough
each month that they got the fee waiver and
then all of the other benefits that we had built
in really resonated. Whereas if you're paying the
monthly fee, those other benefits were not quite
as exciting or didn't quite compensate. So we've
done this several times and we've started recently
combining it with trying to get very agile in
getting that feedback from that bullseye segment.
So we've told many of our product managers and
designers over the last two years, don't worry
about serving 1000 customers, taking three weeks,
serving 1000 customers, getting a bunch of cross
tabs. Even at the end of which it's very hard to
read the real fine grain customer feedback.
So we just tell them, call 10 of them. Pick
up the phone yourself. Don't ask a researcher to
come up with a plan to go do the research to then
summarize it, to then bring it to you, which has
so many degrees of distance built in. You pick
up the phone, call 10 of them and nine times out
of 10, by the time you've made your fifth call,
you could predict what's customer six, seven,
eight, nine and 10 are going to tell you. And
then you know what it is that is the gap or what
it is that is truly resonating that you want to
double down on. So we're constantly trying to
iterate in small ways the ways to get really
that voice of the customer straight lined in
to the people who are building the product.
I love this advice. I imagine as a PM that is
extremely scary to go call a customer. Most
people don't do that. By the way, do you
actually operationally, is it actually a
call or do you recommend the email? What do
you actually recommend they do because,-
We literally pick up the phone.
Okay.
Pick up the phone.
Okay. Great.
Because you can get tone of voice. Brazilians
and Mexicans are incredibly expressive. There
is a degree of real fine grain sense
that the statistics never tell you.
Yeah.
And it's very aligned with design thinking
and there's a lot of literature around how this
works well, and I wouldn't say we're doing it
especially to the best practice scientific. We're
just like, just make the call. Make it as simple,
as unobtrusive with as little overhead as possible
to make sure the voice of the customer is coming
directly into the teams that are building.
Jeff Bezos had this quote on his Lex Friedman
podcast where if you have data and you have
an anecdote, usually the anecdote is right.
I love that. That sounds exactly right to me.
To make it even more tactical for the surveys you
run, is there any tool you find? How do you
actually collect this data? Is there anything
interesting that you could share of just how
to operationalize collecting this data?
We've used a series of tools, many of the main
survey vendor tools, we still use many of them,
but we don't standardize or find one that
dramatically changes our life beyond the mindset
of we are going to make sure that this product
has product market fit before we scale it. One
of the things I've seen throughout my career as a
product manager and CPO, we live with it today at
Nubank every month is the pressure on the line
product manager to scale the product that the
entire company, the entire executive team, the
entire management chain has been counting on.
We're launching this thing [foreign language
00:29:16]. We all wanted to scale. We all are
very excited about it. We had the product review
six months ago and we thought this is going to be
amazing. And the pressure on that product manager
to scale a product is immense and the job of the
product manager in many instances is to say no.
And one of the things I try to say frequently
within the walls of Nubank is we are not going to
take a small problem and scale it because if we do
that, we end up with a big mess. Something
isn't working at small scale, no problem,
especially if we have a strong hypothesis and a
lot of ways of getting good customer feedback.
We iterate, we iterate, we get it right and then
once we get it right, scaling if you do it right
in many cases takes care of itself because the
customer is now excitedly telling their friends.
Whereas you can pour a lot of money and a lot of
effort and when you have a big app like Nubank or
places like Google and Facebook, you can make any
product look great for months if not years because
you have such a large customer base that you can
always get them to try it with all sorts of basic
techniques, but you're bouncing a dead cat. And
then you've got a real big mess to untangle when
the thing is much, much larger. So we try to be
pretty disciplined about that. And that's a lot
of what the Sean Ellis does is it bring science to
some of that art of making that judgment call.
This point you made about it's the PMs job to
push back and stop bad things from happening
I think is such an important one. A lot of PMs
are just told here, build this thing and they
kind of know this is not going to work, this
is a bad idea, but either they don't think
they should be pushing back or they are not
good at it. From the PMs you've worked with
that are good at convincing and pushing back,
like we should not do this yet, do you have any
tactics or ways of communicating that you found
effective for pushing back to, like you said,
all this pressure that's coming down on them?
One of the things I've learned relatively later in
my career, I wish I'd learned it decade earlier,
decades earlier even is how important culture
is. And we talked about the five cultural
tenets, but this idea of we are owners,
not renters. You're an owner of that product as
the product manager or the lead engineer or the
lead designer or in fact anyone on the team.
If you really don't think it's going to work,
don't tell me what I want to hear. It's incumbent
on you, it's expected of you as an owner to tell
me the bad news and tell it to me early, even when
it's convenient, even when there's a promotion at
stake, these dynamics get very real very quickly
then look, I don't think it's going to work and
here's why, or it's not working and here's
why, or we should kill it and here's why.
The second thing I would say is senior leaders at
companies that have gone, especially startups that
have scaled well, you usually have people who
have been in that boat who have seen products
that weren't working who have killed them or
who have pivoted them pretty dramatically. And
there's a lot of respect for someone who has a
real clarity of thought and brings a high bar
and is not simply going with the flow. So I think
that's the main thing, is bringing that ownership
mindset. And the second is bringing clarity and
bringing data and understanding that most senior
executives in whichever company are strong-willed
and bring strong opinions. That's part of the job
description. That's okay. It is your job
whether product or design or engineering
or whatever function as a leader to if you think
you are practicing for one of those senior jobs,
it's sort of let's say a mid-level, it doesn't
come miraculously when you get a C-suite title,
it's something that's going to be practiced.
And it's something that is expected and
I think that's not just a Nubank thing.
Certain cultures promote it better than others,
but I think it's pretty universally important.
And so I would just encourage people to try it,
understand the trade-offs, understand
the challenge, articulate the other side,
but if you genuinely believe it's not yet ready
to scale your products, at the end of the day,
the big mess is a thing you're still going to owe
and we're all going to forget that we told you to
scale the thing. We're all going to still blame
you at the end of the day. So you might as well
bite the bullet earlier, pivot it when it's easier
to do and it'll work out better in the end.
I want to come back to one more thread and
then I'm going to go in a different direction.
You talked a bit about talking to customers,
finding innovative ideas, not just listening
to what they're telling you. There's this whole
skill of user research and interviewing customers
and finding the pain point, figuring out what
to build. Do you have any just, I don't know,
tips or tactics or lessons you've learned about
just how to do this well, how to uncover the pain
point and then figure out what to actually
build when you're interviewing customers?
I'll share a couple of thoughts, but I will
tell you as a preface that it is arguably
the area right now that I still wrestle with. I
still think I, and we are not doing it as well.
I've never seen it done quite as consistently
great as it could be, and I think it's an area
for where design thinking and a lot of the design
function can help us, but it's very, very, it's
one of the areas of greatest inconsistency that
I see in product development. Having said that,
a couple of things that I see that we sometimes
do really well at Nubank and other times we miss
on one dimension or the other. First off, per your
Jeff Bezos anecdote, the anecdote usually trumps
the data. And there are many times when I see
teams that are doing very sophisticated analysis
and they've sort of forgotten what the question
is or what the conclusion they can draw from it
truly is. So never lose sight of the value of the
customer's words and the anecdote. That's one.
The second one that I believe very, very
strongly in is I think teams often skip the
step of clearly, very, very clearly working
very hard to be super crisp in articulating
their hypothesis. If you don't have a hypothesis,
you're going to spend a lot of time researching,
you're going to get a lot of data back,
qualitative, anecdotal or quantitative
and you're not going to know what to make of it
because it's not either validating or invalidating
your hypothesis because there isn't a hypothesis.
So it just becomes an interesting conversation.
The third one is, I've got a hypothesis, I've
got it really crisp and now the pitfall is I've
fallen in love with my hypothesis. I'm a lawyer
for my hypothesis. I'm not a judge of whether
the hypothesis is right or not right. So I think
that's another common pitfall. I've fallen into
that one too many times to count. And then
the last thing I would highlight is even
when you have a strong hypothesis and you're
actually in the mode of doing the research,
observe more than ask questions if you can, ask
indirect questions more than direct questions.
Would you love this product? Right. Excited
product manager has been working for two months
on a design. You're searching for the problem more
than the solution. You're looking indirectly and
asking from multiple directions the same question
rather than trying to find a yes, they love the
thing you've been thinking about and swaying
on for a long time. And if you can, observing
is better than asking, although that's a tricky
skill. Those are the things that I look for.
With the hypothesis point, just
to make sure people understand,
your suggestion there is before you start talking
to customers, doing your easy researches as a PM
or just anyone on the team, essentially have
a perspective on what you think is going to be
true. Is that how you think about it?
Exactly. Have a point of view on what
you think the customer will say that will
lead them to be really excited about your
product. That way you will get very clearly
eh or yes, bang the table excitement and you
will know when you're getting that reaction.
Is there an example of that just to make it even
more concrete? Because I imagine many PMs are kind
of feeling like they have to be unbiased and just
like, let's see. Let's see if this is something we
should do and I don't want to bias anyone against
it. Is there a quick example of a hypothesis?
One of the famous examples that's somewhat
hypothesis related and somewhat observation
related is the invention of the Swiffer from
Procter & Gamble. Right. The people hate mopping
and they will do it and they won't even realize
how painful an experience it is because
they've just developed the work arounds
and they just deal with the burden. But if you
observe very granularly what the problems are,
then you can see where the problems are.
And so if you bring a strong hypothesis to,
that this is a real problem, even if customers
aren't telling you it's a problem because they've
just sort of gotten used to it. So that's one.
We have a hypothesis at Nubank. I'll give you one
that's live. We have a hypothesis at Nubank that
the joint bank account, I was doing some research
on this just last week. The joint bank account was
invented in the early, it's actually hard to say,
but it was invented, depending on what source you
believe, in the late 19th or early 20th century.
And it was basically invented coincident with the
social movement, sort of the women's liberation
social movements before women in the US were
legally allowed to vote, where women were not
allowed to open a bank account without their
husbands prior approval. That is the era from
which the joint bank account that we still live
with today came from. It's 120 to 150 years old.
I don't think it's surprising. Our hypothesis
is it's not surprising that that artifact,
that that product is not made for the modern
customer, that it is easier for me to share a
Spotify playlist with my wife or my daughter
than it is for me to share a savings goal
just mechanically. So we're going into a product
development cycle that says there is a new social
banking arrangement that is not about tweeting and
it's not about social very broadly defined. It is
about our financial lives are inherently social.
And it is very hard to share with my spouse,
with my kids, with my parents who might be helping
me pay for my child's education as an example,
use case. It's a very strong hypothesis.
But when you go into the research with the
customer, you don't try to sell them. You try
to see if they're experiencing pain points.
And it becomes very hard when you're in and
they say even something a little bit in the
direction of what you hope they would say to
not be like, jump in with a lot of excitement
and then get into more of a sell mode with
them and almost try to sell against your idea,
push back against your idea, make the customer
sell you in the interaction. And you play the
devil's advocate. So those are the kinds of
things we search for as we build products.
That sounds like a great idea. I believe in
this hypothesis. Today's episode is brought
to you by OneSchema, the embeddable CSV importer
for SaaS. Customers always seem to want to give
you their data in the messiest possible CSV
file. And building a spreadsheet importer
becomes a never-ending sink for your engineering
and support resources. You keep adding features to
your spreadsheet importer, but customers keep
running into issues. Six months later you're
fixing yet another date conversion edge case bug.
Most tools aren't built for handling messy data,
but OneSchema is. Companies like Scale AI and Pave
are using OneSchema to make it fast and easy to
launch delightful spreadsheet import experiences
from embeddable CSV import to importing CSVs from
an SFTP folder on a recurring basis.
Spreadsheet import is such an awful
experience in so many products. Customers
get frustrated by useless messages like error
online 53 and never end up getting started
with your product. OneSchema intelligently
corrects messy data so that your customers
don't have to spend hours in Excel just to
get started with your product. For listeners
of this podcast, OneSchema is offering a $1,000
discount. Learn more at oneschema.co/Lenny.
I want to talk about strategy. I know that
you have a very strong perspective on how to
think about strategy and approach strategy.
This is something that everyone always wants
to get better at. Every PM is always told you
want to build your strategic thinking muscles
and this is really important to your career.
I'd love to hear your take and how you approach
developing strategy and your advice to folks.
I will readily admit, I bring a bias. I spent
almost a decade at the beginning of my career
right after college working in a strategy
consulting firm. Right. So I bring a bias,
which is to some degree, certainly for the length
of time I did it, an unusual background for a
product manager. When I first showed up at Google,
it took me a couple of years to realize my job
was not to produce a nice PowerPoint, it was to
ship code. And I was doing a poor job of that for
at least the first 12 to 18 months. But I think
there is almost a countervailing dogma in Silicon
Valley or in tech companies more generally, that
strategy is easy and execution is everything. And
I think that's probably because there are a small
number of companies that get the strategy right,
but the legendary companies that we all know about
not only got the strategy right, but then executed
it really crisply. What we don't hear about
are the companies that got the strategy wrong,
never got even into the conversation and all of
their great execution was multiplied by zero.
Great execution multiplied by a poor strategy
is a waste of everyone's time. And because the
strategy isn't clear, you can waste a
lot of time executing years and years
against something that was destined never to
work. One of my favorite quotes from the Valley,
from Kevin Systrom in the early days of
Instagram, I heard him say it at a conference,
this is pre the Facebook acquisition. And he
was like, I don't know how old. He had just
left Google. He was probably, I don't know, 20
some years old. He said, "We may not be right,
but at least we are clear." And what I love
about that is even if your strategy isn't right,
and it will never be exactly right because no
plan ever is, you will have a clearer read on if
you are going off course because you have a very
clear idea of what was supposed to be happening.
And so I think being very clear in your strategy
is really important. You've had some great guests
on the podcast. Richard Rumelt is one of my
absolute favorites. He's written a couple of
books, one called Good Strategy Bad Strategy,
another more recent one called The Crux,
where he does a great service to the world by even
more than describing what strategy is, focusing at
the beginning about what strategy isn't. Strategy
isn't an ambitious goal, it's not an aspiration,
it's not a set of financial outcomes. It is
a coherent plan for how you going to apply
your strengths in a leveraged way against a
core important problem. And that's a very,
very rough paraphrase of the way he thinks
about the world. And I find that we often
confuse strategy with a vision, a broad idea,
a very, very broad, vague aspiration. Nubank
strategy isn't we want to be the world's
largest neo bank. We do, but that's not an
interesting way to dimensionalize the problem.
In 2014, we had millennial, middle-class,
urban Brazilians who hated paying credit card
fees and were not able to get credit in the
first place because they were too young and
without a credit history. And we could offer
them not just a lower-priced credit card, but
a no-fee credit card, which was an emotional
thing. That fee got people angry and we could do
that because we were branchless and digital. Now
that is a coherent description of a very specific
problem for a very specific set of customers with
a very specific solution based on a very specific
advantage. By the way, all of this predated my,
this has got nothing to do with me. I wasn't
there. But that's what I mean. Strategy is very
specific, it's very detailed, it's very locked in.
And working backwards from that I think is really,
really important. And if you get that
strategy right, it informs the minimal
set of activities you need to do to get...
... minimal set of activities you need to do
to get traction and to win, whereas if you don't
have that degree of coherence, you're trying to
serve all the customers. Maybe we should go to
Mexico prematurely. All sorts of things happen
and your execution gets very diffuse, and you
can't even tell why you're not getting traction
across the company, whereas strategy allows
focus and it allows a much more rapid read
of whether your focused bets, your
concentrated bets, are actually working.
You've had some investors on your podcast over the
years, and they will tell you that concentration
is what builds wealth, diversification is what
preserves wealth. And you're a startup. You're
not trying to preserve anything. You're trying to
build something. It requires concentrated bets,
not hedging. And because you're concentrating
bets, those bets are high stakes. You need to
be very, very clear on what bets you're making
and why you think it's going to succeed.
When you work with PMs on your team in the past
that are trying to get better at this muscle
and following this advice that you're sharing of
strategy, what do you find most helps them build
this muscle? Is it just doing it over and over
and over and over? Is it reading good strategy,
bad strategy, practicing it? What do you find is
most helpful in helping you build this muscle?
One is taking it seriously. It's a little bit like
what we talked about with Nubank's culture. First,
you got to want the customer to love you
fanatically as something that you value.
After that, I think frameworks really help,
whether it's Good Strategy, Bad Strategy,
whether it's Play to Win from a relatively
recent guest of yours, Christopher Lochhead,
who I really admire, whether it's Where
to Play and How to Win from Roger Martin,
which is a phenomenal book about-
He's coming on the podcast in a few weeks.
Is he? He's fantastic. And having those
frameworks, all of which in many ways,
if you synthesize them, are getting at the same
thing around focus, around a clear understanding
of the customer, around not trying to be in the
words that we literally have on Nubank coffee
mugs, "We're not trying to be incrementally
better. We are trying to be fundamentally
different." These are all very similar
ideas expressed in slightly different ways.
Once you understand the frameworks and you
distill them, then it's about practicing
them and practicing them is scary. Hedging is
appealing. Hedging means you don't have to make
choices. Hedging sounds smart. Concentrating all
your bets is the thing that desperate people do,
and startups are desperate entities
because they're burning cash in almost
every instance. But successful startups, the
ones that become profitable... I'm very wary,
given the places I've worked, of the successful
company with one or two monster products,
and Nubank is now in that fortunate
position, that starts to get conservative,
that starts to forget that focus, concentration,
customer obsession are every bit as important,
that even though the company won't go bankrupt
if products three, four, five and six don't
succeed because products one and two are monster
cashflow drivers, that's a slow path to death.
And so practicing that discipline and having,
and I use this word very intentionally,
having the courage to make those hard choices
and to concentrate the bets, which goes against,
by the way, a lot of what's taught in business
school and a lot of MBAs is really important,
and then it's a matter of you get better the
more you do it and you get more practiced and
more grooved and more principled in how you
get to a methodology the more you do it.
Did you say the mugs at Nubank say,
"Be fundamentally different"?
The product team, a little over a year ago we
put together some schwag, which was fundamentally
... I have a mantra within the company since
roughly the time I joined, which is, "We're in
the business of being fundamentally different,
not incrementally better." Again, it goes back
to only fundamentally different, gets customers
to tell their friends. Incrementally better.
And by the way, there are certain features ...
I don't want to overstate the case ... There
are certain features where you're in the
incrementally better business. Not every
single thing of the hundred things you launch in
a year can be fundamentally different, but we're
searching for those anchors that are going to be
fundamentally different all the time around which
you build some sustaining innovation as well, but
we are in the fundamentally different business,
not the incrementally better business.
I love that, and that's a great segue to
where I wanted to go, which is I know you're
a big fan of category design. You mentioned
Christopher Lochhead, former guest. This is
actually one of the more common debates on
this podcast of do people believe in we should
be creating our own category or should we not?
Is that a terrible idea? Is it a good idea? It
feels like you're in the camp of this is actually
very good and important. I'd love to hear your
perspective and also just how Nubank did this.
You know Lenny, literally earlier in this
week, I was listening to your podcast with
I believe it was Todd Jackson, ex Gmail
product leader and now venture capitalist,
and you guys had a very interesting discussion
about it, and I think he took largely the other
side of the argument that you go in a category
where customers are already spending money. And
it's hard to argue with that fairly robust logic.
I will tell you how I think about it. It forced
me to think about where are the nuances in how
I believe. I think overall, particularly at a
company level, successful companies are typically
in the fundamentally different business. They're
in the new category business. Google was in
the new category business. Netflix, Airbnb,
you can go down the long list, Salesforce, et
cetera, et cetera. That's really important.
In Nubank's case, we were the first, and actually,
it's not that important that we were the first,
but we were very intentionally trying to
build a branchless bank based on the rise
of the smartphone in Brazil and Latin America
at that time, the sort of rapid inflection,
and a branchless bank that could bring, as David
likes to say, put a bank branch in your pocket,
where at the time access was the big problem, and
that you could do that on a digital cost structure
that allowed you to essentially disruptively price
across the board was the thing that led to the
massive wave of success, multiplied by, unlike
almost everywhere else in the world, including
in the US where the answer was, "We're going to
do the bank account first." Nubank's answer was,
"No, we're going to do credit first and credit
is 10 times harder and 100 times more risky,"
because you get credit wrong as a young
company that doesn't know how to do it yet,
you've blown everything up. The money's
never coming back. Those two, again,
concentrated bets, defining a new category,
were I think the key to our success.
Now, there are times when you're trying to go
into an adjacent market. We've recently gone
into a market called Consignado in Brazil, which
is secured lending for government employees. Very
stable job, easier to underwrite against their
salary at a much lower interest rate. That's a
market that's existed for a couple of decades in
Brazil, and our job was to go in there, and we
believe we built something that is fundamentally
different. It wasn't digital. It went through
middlemen. We built it D to C, and we've been
able to undercut the pricing pretty dramatically.
So even within an established category, we've
tried to build a fundamentally different
experience, but there are also times when, look,
it's not quite me too, but the differentiation's
a bit more incremental. But at the company level,
I think it's absolutely imperative to be designing
your own category so you can then dominate it and
defining your own category. And even when you're
entering a place where customers are spending
money, I think going in with a mindset that says,
"This is going to be a bit better," and I
think Todd would probably agree with this,
given the way he described it, you should
try to be reinventing that category,
even if you're not inventing that category.
Amazing. I like this battle we're forming here
of people on two sides of this debate, and I'm
excited to see where it goes over time. It feels
like the do not create a category side is
winning so far in terms of volume, but there's
a lot of passion from this other side.
I'm happy to be on the contrarian side.
Okay, there's a few more things I want to touch
on before we wrap up. It feels like Nubank is one
of the historically most successful companies
launching new business lines. I think you guys
are maybe like 10 years old, and how many products
slash business lines are there at this point?
It depends on how you categorize it, but
I would say we have roughly a dozen to 20
core product lines.
Okay, that's wild.
Our story started as, we were a Brazilian credit
card monoliner in an app and all the rest of it.
Around the time, slightly before, but around
the time I joined the phase two of the company,
the mandate of what we were trying to do, which
has really been the story of the last five years,
was we were going to go from a Brazilian
credit card company to a full solution
Latin American bank, which meant we launched
five new products. We launched a bank account,
which allowed us to go from being
a secondary banking relationship to
increasingly a primary banking relationship.
About half of our 90 plus million customers,
we are the primary relationship. We built a
lending product, we built an investments product,
we built an insurance product, we built
a series of small business products.
While we were doing that, we were also making the
leap to prove, despite a lot of skepticism, that
our business model was exportable and not a unique
Brazilian phenomenon. So we launched into Mexico
and launched into Colombia and now we are starting
to take the full suite of products and go beyond
credit card in Mexico and Colombia as well.
So depending on how you look at that matrix,
we are a dozen plus products and we're working
on the phase three of our products, which is
moving beyond financial services. We've launched
an e-commerce marketplace within our app, which is
perhaps a bit counterintuitive if you're coming
from the US. And we're also envisioning a world
where banking is, again, to use the phrase that
we love at Nubank, fundamentally different than
it has been in the last 100 years. And we believe
that social technology, self-driving and AI
technologies can build a just completely different
experience, where we're not building a bank branch
and putting it in your pocket. We're building
a personal banker, which today, I don't know,
10 million people around the world have access
to and you got to have a lot of money to do it.
We believe that job can be democratized ultimately
to all eight billion people on the planet,
and we believe it can be done better for those
eight billion even than the 10 million are
getting today. But that's a lot of work, and
that's, to use Christopher Lochhead and his
co-author's language, that's the new category that
we are trying to define over on a global basis.
It's going to be a tiny little banker to
fit in your pocket, tiny little person.
That's it.
I want to follow on this thread,
but before we get there, so in terms of
adding new product lines and business units,
watching how Nubank has done this, is there
something you've learned about just how to do this
well? I'm imagining there's a spreadsheet where,
"Here's all the things we're going to do in the
future. Here's how we're thinking about all the
factors of all the new businesses we can launch."
Is there anything there you've seen of just
like, wow, that's a really smart way of thinking
about the sequencing slash where to expand next
that you think other folks can learn from?
I wish I could tell you that there was this
predestined master plan that was so scientific.
The reality is smart people around the table with
a culture of robust debate and real candor about
the pros and cons is how we went about it, and a
constant re-examination of how things are going,
what's going well, what's not going well,
what's taking off, what's not yet taking off,
what are the principles by which we're
making these decisions has been important.
Some of these things are obvious. If you're
running a bank, a bank account is probably a
good product at some stage, but a lot of it in
terms of sequencing and when we invest where,
some of it's obvious, what's the TAM and where's
the customer paying, but a lot of it is art and a
lot of that resolution of the art and the debate.
It comes from a fairly robust debate, so I'm
avoiding your question. I have no good answer.
Just a lot of complicated decision making,
but I think what's interesting is, coming
back to your very early lesson, is using the
gate of is this hitting this 50% of people be very
disappointed before launching feels like a key.
Yeah. That's the one thing is we try not
to scale big problems, and so we try to
solve our problems when things are small. Our
ultra violetta are higher income, rewards-based
credit card. We launched, it happened to be, I
think it was July 4th, 2021 was the launch date,
so it's easy for me to remember. We started
scaling it two to two and a half years later.
In the meantime, we were in the lab figuring
out where's the product market fit? Why is it
not resonating? Oh, it's resonating with these
guys. What do they particularly love it? Let's
iterate there. And now we're at a point in
the last six to nine months where we can start
scaling aggressively, learning some of the credit
dynamics that are different and reinventing some
of those methodologies, and there's a second
phase of scaling that will come. But yeah, one
form of distraction we don't get into is fixing
massive problems that we've overscaled before they
were ready. That's a bit of an overstatement, but
nothing's quite that clean, but generally true.
Coming back to your thoughts on the
future of FinTech and in LATAM especially,
you talked about how the vision is essentially
a banker in everyone's pocket. Is there anything
more there? Just where do you think all this
goes in the future in terms of FinTech banking
for people in LATAM and then globally?
Yeah, there are a handful of principles,
call them hypotheses, that we believe,
and there are, I should be super clear,
unproven hypotheses that will take years for us
to prove out, and I'm sure there will be pivots
along the way as we learn that things aren't quite
the way we would've hoped at the beginning. But
first off, the idea that banking should be
holistic, that we need to provide a full
solution across what we call the five or
six financial seasons of someone's life,
right? We spend, we save, we invest, we borrow, we
protect, et cetera. And that's a lot of what we've
been working on for the last handful of years.
So one is we want to be a full solution bank.
Second, something we have started, we have
had some real success in on the business side,
we've made some mistakes on the technical
side that we are iterating through is,
we are trying to build, and some might argue
I'm overstating a bit, but just to be clear,
we are trying to build what we believe is
the first global bank on a single code base.
I come from a world places like Google and
Facebook, Google, my first product management
experience. I was not allowed to launch unless
my product was ready for 40 countries and 40
languages. I believe language number 40 was
Finnish, so we were always making sure the thing
worked in Finnish. And there are good reasons why
ADVA, global online advertising, worked that way.
It was a great principle by Google.
When you get into FinTech and into
banking where the regulations are very
local, where the stakes are much higher,
that you serve the right 300 by 250 ad, there is
a lot of pushback on that kind of, "We're just
going to scale this everywhere," sort of mindset.
And so how do you marry those two things? There
are global banks like Citi or Santander, a lot
of them have been built up through acquisition.
A lot of them are on distinct code bases and
technology infrastructures. We believe there's
a lot of leverage if you can build a global
bank on a single code base. That's another
principle that we are trying to make real.
The third is that social mechanics around
your financial life, not in general, not
another WhatsApp, not another Twitter,
and self-driving automation. Why do I have to
remember to pay this bill every month? Why do
I have to remember to save for my child's
university education every month? Why can't
I keep my life goals really well-organized? Which
is almost impossible to do. My wife and I open up
different bank accounts at different banks just to
try to do that job, which is, talk about customer
workarounds. How do we make the life life cycle
of managing your financial life exponentially
easier, leveraging these technologies and
then using AI, which is an overhyped term
right now, but AI to turbo-boost these tasks?
We have a phrase we've started using at Nubank,
which I really like. David first introduced
it. Customers everywhere around the world
live harshly unoptimized financial lives. I
think that's true regardless of income level,
regardless of geography, regardless of sort of
life stage of where people are at. If you have
a young child, it is very hard to keep track of
all the things you should be doing. You should
be opening a savings account of a specific
kind that stacks advantage in this way.
These are problems that should be solved and
should be solved soon and can be automated and
where insights can be brought to bear for
customers who are not super sophisticated
in their level of financial education, which by
the way is almost all of us. Some of the people
who think they're the most sophisticated
are the ones who burn the most money in
casinos that they call the stock market.
And so these are some of the principles
around which we are the next phase. What if
there were someone right next to you who could
tell you what the smart move was to make today
at this life stage? You've just had a child,
you've just gotten married, you've just
bought a house, you just want to remodel,
whatever it might be. We think the technology is
there or thereabouts to be able to do that. Why
not have the company that reinvents banking come
out of Sao Paulo, Mexico City, Bogota? Why does
it have to come out of San Francisco, New York
or London? We see no reason why it can't be us,
so we're going to give it a whirl.
Amazing. I love all of this. I can't wait
for this to be real. You mentioned AI, so I just
have a couple more questions. You mentioned AI. We
have a recurring segment on this podcast called
AI Corner, so let's walk over to AI Corner.
All right.
Usually I ask how you
use AI in your day-to-day and your team, just
like what are the tools and things you find
useful to help your team operate with AI and
tooling, but I'm also curious just how you're
integrating AI into the product. You touched on
this a little bit, but just how AI is going to
supercharge the stuff that you're building.
We use some of the tools that everyone is
using these days. Our ringfenced version of Chat
GPT and some of the standard tools, we're using
them in some of the obvious initial wave ways. How
can we improve our customer experience? If you're
fanatical about customers, you're fanatical about
customer experience, and Nubank has always been
that way. How can we make it even better while
we're also making it more efficient? So we're
doing all of those things as part of our coming up
the learning curve in the last 18 or so months.
And then we're starting to think about what
are the ways in which we can build AI native
products. And I will not pretend to you that
we've cracked that code, but a former boss of
mine spoke a while ago, Fidji Simo, who's now
the CEO of Instacart, but she was talking about
the evolution when she was the product lead
for Facebook Ads back when the big migration
from the desktop to mobile was happening, and she
talked about we needed to become mobile native.
And by analogy, companies today need to figure out
what does AI native mean, not how do we append AI
at the corners of the product, but how do we
build it at the heart? What would you design
if these tools existed from the start? I mean,
Facebook's migration to mobile is a phenomenal
example of that pivot. And they like to joke,
and I wasn't there at Facebook at the time,
but they liked to joke at Facebook, even seven,
eight years later when I joined, about the company
had IPO'd and needed to find a business model and
Fidji was responsible for making that happen. And
the core of it was bringing this mobile native
mindset. So we are trying to think through what is
an AI native mindset? In financial services, what
would that look like? And that requires ...
... services. What would that look like? And
that requires analysis as much as analogy,
and we are very much in the middle of that
process and we don't know all of the answers.
The metaphor of a what if everyone in the
world, regardless of their income or wealth,
had a private banker sat next to them that
they could turn to whenever they needed to
is a good metaphor. And so we are using that
metaphor and seeing where it takes us.
Let's now move on to a different corner, failure
corner. This is another recurring segment on the
podcast. Is there a story you could share
of a time in your career where you failed,
where something went wrong, ideally really
wrong, and how that impacted and helped
you in your career? Kind of a lesson
you learned from that experience?
There's a pretty seminal story from my career that
ultimately ended in failure and that I had to sort
of rebuild from. I had done strategy consulting
for just shy of 10 years. I decided I was going
to go to grad school. I was going to pivot my
career into public policy and politics. I was
at the Kennedy School of Government at Harvard
and a year into that a friend of mine had, the
startup he was working at Get acquired by Google
I this company was premised on the idea that you
could bring AdWords/AdSense style advertising to
the terrestrial radio market and one of Google's,
perhaps the biggest diversification bet Google was
working on at the time beyond search and display,
which were up and running, was let's go
disrupt TV, radio, and print. It was 2006.
My friend convinced me to drop out of grad school,
both the Kennedy school and business school. I had
done a year of the Kennedy school. I was one
credit short and in business school I had done
a week of and move out here to California
and join Google. First off, the premise
of the hypothesis proved to be wrong or at least
harder than we thought, and in the following way,
terrestrial radio or for that matter, TV
advertising, broadcast media advertising
works very differently. It serves actually a
different market. It serves brand advertising,
top of funnel kinds of goals as opposed to the
bottom funnel that Google really knew well.
Back then.
So that was one piece. There were all
sorts of technical methodologies like reach and
frequency that are really important that we simply
didn't know about. We were determined to run an
auction. We have patents to our name to this day
that were how do we bring auction methodologies to
work in a broadcast medium? Some very interesting
technology. At the end of the day, one of the
things that you really needed was a surplus of
inventory, ad inventory, which there actually
isn't that much of relatively speaking compared
to online. The other thing that is true is the
people who control that inventory are not nearly
as fragmented, so when you're negotiating with
NBC or CBS or Clear Channel, they have much more
leverage than in the online world of bloggers and
small websites. The fragmentation wasn't there,
the methodology was different, it was going to be
a tougher slog. And in the meantime, Google made
actually a very smart bet and this was a pivot
on Google's part based on a lot of learnings
from the failure on the one side and some of
the success happening on the side of YouTube.
In the meantime, Google had acquired YouTube
and somewhere along the way, and this was over
multiple years, Susan Wojcicki and the leadership
team of Google and Google Ads in particular came
to the conclusion that rather than Google
chasing TV, let's have TV come to Google,
I.e YouTube. And we've seen what's happened
in the ensuing 15 years where cord cutting
and all of the rest and now the online digital ad
methodologies that Google is best in the world at
can be applied in a much more straightforward
way. But I was collateral. Me and some of the
teams I was a part of, we were collateral
damage in that evolution. There was a point
where Google did a small layoff and it was largely
concentrated in my group of this acquisition.
Along the way, Google acquired YouTube, Google
also acquired Double Click and Double Click served
all of the brand advertising online. And a couple
of years later... Well firstly at the time I was
within weeks of being laid off, having dropped
out of two grad schools and moved 3000 miles west.
That felt really crappy. There's a great song from
around that time, which is a mashup from Coldplay
and Jay-Z. Lost. You should listen to the lyrics.
Just because I'm losing doesn't mean I've lost is
literally the first line and I would have that
on repeat at that time within a couple of years,
within a year, probably year and a half maybe that
was around the time I was married. So it was a lot
going on. It turns out that within a year, sort
of post the Double Click deal, Google decided look
with YouTube as an anchor asset and some other
things and the Double Click acquisition, there was
a technology now pretty well established 15 years
later called Real-Time Bidding, and we were going
to bring the search auction methodology across the
entire web for all of display advertising and we
were going to use that core underlying infra
to be able to build not just a spot market,
direct response advertising, but a futures market
which could apply to brand advertising and we are
going to use that disruptive vector, something
fundamentally different, not just incrementally
better, to essentially dislodge Yahoo from owning
brand advertising online. And I ended up getting
that mandate because I had learned a lot about how
brand advertising worked, 12/18 months earlier.
So that was a fairly spectacular failure.
The acquisition, by the way, ended up in
arbitration, big lawsuits, depositions, and it was
messy from all sorts of angles. We all worked our
way through that and then in the end we ended
up building what is even still today, I believe
Google's second largest business, which is the
display advertising business. But that transition
was messy, excruciatingly difficult from a
strategy perspective as we talked about earlier,
but from a emotional as well and figuring out
your way. Given I was new to product management,
I was new to Silicon Valley, I was new to Google,
I was new to advertising and I had no idea whether
I was ever going to be good at it or not.
Do you think the lesson there is basically
that song just because you're losing
doesn't mean you've lost or that
you're a loser and just keep going?
Yeah, bloody-mindedness is a dramatically
underrated quality as we over-intellectualize from
strategy to execution and all the other things.
Sometimes persistence is key and persistence
while still being clear-eyed about what the
odds of success are is also key.
Jag, we've covered everything
I was hoping to cover and more. Before we
get to your very exciting lightning round,
is there anything that you'd love to leave
listeners with or share as a last tidbit?
I would just summarize a couple of core points.
I think the idea of perseverance and being very
clear about what you're trying to achieve and
how much it is worth to you and how much you're
willing to fight for it, while also being very
open and transparent to feedback that you're
getting from people, from the market about
whether what's working and what's not and
knowing what parts to let go and what to hold
onto really tightly is an important lesson.
I think the other thing that I would just
emphasize again is, and this goes a little
bit back to the debate you're trying to frame
up on new category or existing category, I think
within that debate there's really a synthesis
that says, and I think most people would agree,
if you're trying to break through as an insurgent,
you cannot fight on the ground that the incumbents
stand firm. You have got to find a disruptive
vector and that means searching hard for what is
fundamentally different so that it breaks through
the noise and the volume of the noise has just
gone up so much in the last 15 years that I think
that's even growing in importance. Incrementally
better doesn't get you there. It doesn't
get you there unless you have that hook.
I love that you summarized your key takeaways.
It's something I've been wanting to do and
I might ask every guest to try to summarize
what they've shared because that is incredibly
helpful. With that, we've reached our very
exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
I am ready. Let's do it.
First question, what are two or three
books that you recommend most to other people?
The business books, one is Play to Win. I think
that is a great modern strategy book that takes
a lot of what's happened in the digital world
and summarizes it really well. Second one that
I would highlight, which I think is a really
good non-digital world summary and really
distillation of the essence of strategy and
as you mentioned earlier, he's coming on your
podcast soon from Roger Martin is Where to Play
and How to Win, which I think is a classic.
And as I mentioned, I went to study public
policy and politics back 15 years ago. One of the
ultimate startups and one of the ultimate startup
stories in my mind is the story of Singapore
and there's a autobiography of the founding
prime minister of Singapore from 1965 till he
retired, he passed away a couple of years ago.
Lee Kuan Yew. His book about the story of being
kicked out. Singapore being kicked out of Malaysia
as a tiny in business terms, sub-scale, little
country with no natural resources is I think
inspiring. His book is called From Third World
to First, and I think it's a great story that in
many ways is a parallel to what startups try to
do, which is essentially go from third class to
first and it's a very tricky ride and requires
a ruthless honesty about where you stand and
what it'll take to succeed. And it usually
gets prettified up when told in retrospect,
but it is messy every step of the way and I
think it's an awesome, unapologetic summary
of what it takes to achieve greatness in a very
different sphere than we're used to talking to.
I love that. I definitely want to read that now.
Next question, do you have a favorite recent
movie or TV show you've really enjoyed?
There's the great series that my wife and I
watched fairly recently on HBO called the Gilded
Age, which really shines a very interesting light
on how technology, this is from the late 1800s,
19th century, how the technological changes
disrupts both the economic world and the world of
wealth, but also the social dynamics in a society.
And it's fascinating because we're living through
a new Gilded age right now and we're seeing a
lot of those dynamics, but turbocharged on
social media, so extra, extra exciting.
Good times. Do you have a favorite product
that you have recently discovered that you
really like? Either an app, some physical,
anything that's bringing you joy? I