I've always wanted to create a very
tactical episode on how to do sales,
especially with a focus on founder led sales.
A lot of early stage founders get tripped up
as they're taking late stage sales advice.
The founder is the product. You have
studied. You have experienced something
that most of the market hasn't even had
a chance to maybe see or visualize yet.
A billion SaaS tools emailing me constantly
about their product. How do you get someone
to even want to talk to you and be open
to learning about what you're doing?
So if you can focus the messaging in a way
that speaks to something that is a bit of
shock value or is counterintuitive, you'll
get them to continue reading. When a problem
is truly being felt by the market, people
will get on a call, people will respond.
The next step I imagine is you're on the
phone with them trying to convince them
to actually care. What do you do there?
How do you get them to engage further?
You need to be vulnerable. I would be very open
and honest with where you are. Hey, I'm an early
stage startup. We have a lot to learn. Can we
kind of gain your insight into how this problem
is manifesting on your side? Founder led sales is
not about revenue on day one. It is about learning
as fast as humanly possible to get to that
pulse, so that you can earn the right to sell.
Today my guest is Jen Abel. Jen is the co-founder
of Jellyfish, where her and her team help early
stage founders learn how to sell, do early
customer discovery, and set up a repeatable sales
motion. Prior to Jellyfish, Jen was an enterprise
sales director at the Muse and a general assembly,
and she's obsessed with helping founders in
the zero to one stage of their journey. In our
conversation, we get extremely tactical and in the
weeds on how to actually do sales as a founder. We
talk through each step of the sales process, and
Jen shares what you should be doing and saying
at every step. We go through how to find your
first set of leads, how to reach out to them,
what to say in your message, how to structure your
first sales call, how to get through procurement,
and how to get that final signature.
She shares actual words you should be using,
and phrases and structures, and pitfalls that most
people run into at each of these steps. I've never
heard a podcast episode with this much advice
that you can put into practice tomorrow, and
I am very excited to hear how it goes for you. If
you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting
app or YouTube. It's the best way to avoid
missing future episodes and it helps the podcast
tremendously. With that, I bring you Jen Abel.
Jen, thank you so much for being
here. Welcome to the podcast.
Thanks, Lenny.
What I've always wanted to do is to create
a very tactical episode on how to do sales,
like how to actually have sales
conversations, how to find leads,
how to close deals. Especially with a focus on
founder led sales, where founders are doing the
early sales versus hiring salesperson. Which one,
I know you're a huge advocate of and we'll talk
about this. And two, you basically spent all your
time working with founders and founding teams,
helping them learn how to do sales, how to set up
their go-to-market motions, how to scale teams,
sales teams, how to hire sales people. So I'm
very excited to have you here to create a very
in the weeds, hands-on episode on how to
do sales. How does that sound broadly?
That sounds awesome, and thank you
so much for having me, Lenny. I mean,
it's a true pleasure to be here with you.
It's my pleasure. Many people have recommended
you come on this podcast. I'm excited we're
doing this. Let me start with just this kind
of question, our founder led sales. Maybe just
briefly explain what that term means and
then talk about why this is so important,
why this is the way you recommend
companies start doing sales?
Founder led sales is really that first milestone
that a startup goes through on the commercial
side, which is, how do I go out and get my first
few customers? Some people might say zero to one,
which is, how do I get my first million?
Others might say, how do I go out and get my
first 10 customers? It's all kind of in the same
vein. And founder led sales is really, really,
really important because in the very, very,
very early days, when there is no brand equity,
when there is no marketing engine running, when
there is limited to no reference ability, the
founder is the product, right? Because the product
is still, could be abstract, could be an MVP or in
it's really early formation. So the founder is
the product. When people say, well, what does
that even mean? It means that you are a subject
matter expert on something highly specific.
You have studied, you have experienced something
that most of the market hasn't even had a chance
to maybe see or visualize yet. So you have this
novel insight that you are building a business
around. And it's that novel insight and the way
you see the world that gets the market excited,
in absence of a product. And that's actually
happens even before you even show the product.
So founder led sales is how do you bring the
founders vision into the world and have the
market, and understand what part of the market
accepts it, and then what part of that vision
are they accepting? So it's aligning the
founders vision with the market reality.
This episode is brought to you by Brave Search.
Brave Search is the private independent search
engine that doesn't bias or censor results.
Brave Search and its answers with AI
feature are available for free to all users on
desktop and mobile devices. With Brave Search,
you get real answers faster, served from their
own independent index of the web. Their AI search
engine can give lightning fast, incredibly
accurate results for almost any question. But
Brave isn't just AI answers, it's also a powerful
traditional search engine with real innovations
versus big tech options. It fights bias and
SEO spam. It brings a cleaner results page
with fewer ads. Reddit threads in the search
engine results page, powerful local results,
and even community-driven ranking options. Tired
of big tech, same old list of links? It's time to
try Brave Search. Visit brave.com/Lenny
to get started. That's brave.com/Lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta.
When it comes to ensuring your company has
top-notch security practices, things get
complicated fast. Now you can assess risk,
secure the trust of your customers, and
automate compliance for SOC II, ISO 27,001,
HIPAA and more, with a single platform, Vanta.
Vanta's market-leading trust management platform
helps you continuously monitor compliance
alongside reporting and tracking risks. Plus,
you can save hours by completing security
questionnaires with Vanta AI. Join thousands
of global companies that use Vanta to automate
evidence collection, unify risk management,
and streamline security reviews. Get $1,000
off Vanta when you go to Vanta.com/Lenny,
that's V-A-M-T-A dot com slash Lenny.
And this is counter to what many founders hope is,
I'm just going to hire a salesperson, they'll
handle sales. I'll build the thing, I'll wait
for them to find deals. And this is like a lot
of people think this way. And founder led sales
is the movement of just like, no, no, you should
be doing the sales for a long time as a founder.
Absolutely. I mean, it is the competitive
advantage. I don't think people realize how much
of a competitive advantage the founder led sales
motion is, for three specific reasons. One is that
the founder is the visionary. No one's going to be
able to speak to it like they can. No salesperson,
really no non-founder. The second is that they
are the highest order in the hierarchy of the
startup. It's the founder. So the market is
excited to talk to a founder because they
usually know something that the market doesn't
know. And they want to learn and maybe they want
to experience something differently. So being able
to speak to the person that's running the vision,
speak to the person that's crafted the vision.
And then that third piece is that the founder
can see something budding in a conversation
that a salesperson won't be able to see. And
it's those budding moments that's where
all the gold lives. And I don't think a
lot of founders realize that. Their day one
market vision is never the same vision that
takes them in a product market fit. And I say
that all the time. It's these little budding
moments where it's like I was able to get to
that budding insight because I went deeper
and deeper and deeper and deeper through these
calls and these conversations, to fully refine
how we want to go out and sell it. And only a
founder is going to be able to see those things.
I love this because this connects
really well with an episode I just
did with the CMO of Wiz. And the founders
went through this exactly. They had 10 to
15 conversations a day for weeks, and then
they're like realizing people keep telling
us they like it, but no one's buying, no
one's excited enough to want to actually
move forward. And that was only happening
because the founders were on these calls.
Yeah, I mean, the other thing too is that it
becomes a game of telephone. It's like, hey, this
salesperson says that no cares about this. What do
you think the first thing the founder's going to
say is? It's the salesperson. So much easier
to say that than, is it me? Is it my vision?
So it also kind of brings the accountability
closer to the pulse where decisions are made.
It's interesting how similar
this is to product building,
where there's this idea that a founder top down
can tell the team what to build, and it's this
very waterfall cycle. When in reality the idea
of the product and feature is just like step one,
and then there's actually building it, testing
it, talking to customers about it, that actually
turns that initial seed of an idea to
the real thing that people will want.
Totally.
Okay. So the catch 22, I don't know if that's
the term here. The challenge is, okay, so great,
founders should be doing sales. Most founders
have never done sales. They just want to build
product. They're mostly product people,
design people. Sometimes there's founders
that are salespeople. Rarely is that the case
in my experience. So doing sales is very hard,
not something that comes naturally to a lot
of people. A lot of people are very afraid
of it. So with that, let's get into how to
actually get better at the sales process.
I think a nice framework for how we can go
through this is basically first let's talk
about the sales cycle, the steps, the key steps
of a sales cycle. And then we'll just go through
each step and help people learn some tactics
to get through each of those conversations.
Sounds great.
Okay. Yeah. Cool. So what's the simplest way
to think about the steps of a sales cycle?
The traditional sales stages that most CRMs are
even set up as is you have your intro call. You
have your second call, which sometimes could
be the demo depending on the stage of market
you're selling to. Then you have your third call,
which is going to be more about walking through
a proposal, a scope of work, maybe going deeper
into the demo to contextualize it to everything
you've learned. The fourth call is going to be
getting their feedback and kind of co-authoring
that scope of work even further. The fifth call
is going to be around probably an introduction to
procurement. And then selling into procurement
in itself, it's its own little sales cycle,
but we could talk about that in a sec. And then
post-procurement, it's going to be obviously
getting that signature and knowing who the actual
signatory is. Sometimes it's not even the business
unit, it's sometimes legal, CFO, procurement
themselves. So just understanding who that is.
Okay, great. So let's walk through each
of these steps. So I love that each call
has its traditional goal, demo, proposal,
then co-authoring, and then procurement,
and then post-procurement. I
love how consistent everybody is.
Yeah, well, it's also, it's interesting because
it's also predicated on their buying process as
well. So if they're really used to buying, if
they're very mature in their buying process,
they actually might guide you to what
the steps are. But most startups are
turning non-consumers into consumers.
So that's why this kind of fits well.
Got it. So there's this intra call step.
So kind starting about where it begins. I
think where a lot of people struggle most
is getting anyone to even pay attention.
You don't want to talk to them. A billion
SaaS tools emailing me constantly about
their product. So maybe we start there
of just like how do you get someone to
even want to talk to you and be open
to learning about what you're doing?
Yeah. And this is why that founder
led sales piece is so important. One
is when it's coming from the founder, it's
an entirely different weight. You're like,
oh, interesting. This founder is reaching out to
me. Okay, I'm going to seek to go a layer deeper,
knowing who is sending me this note. The
second piece is this is why that novel insight,
that technical insight, that business model
insight that you've uncovered needs to lead
here. People are inspired by a new way of
thinking, usually something counterintuitive,
something that's really different. I really
try and stay away from better, because that's
really hard to define, and better means something
different to everyone. So if you can focus the
messaging in a way that speaks to something that
has a bit of shock value, or is counterintuitive,
you'll get them to continue reading. So first
and foremost, I usually like to open it with,
which is why is this relevant for me in my role?
Why are you reaching out to me? So first and
foremost is relevancy. I think that matters
even more so than personalization right now.
I think it's so easy to personalize anything,
and it can also come across as really stressed
when you're like, hey, I noticed you were on
such and such podcast, and that was when they
were previously two roles behind. So I always
say relevancy. If you can get to relevancy,
that's the most important piece. The second most
important piece is really getting to that level
of differentiation or counterintuitive nature.
So say something that would literally make them
say what? Or that makes no sense. Maybe not that
makes no sense, but what or how could that be?
Or I've never thought about it that way. Or I
actually don't fully understand what they're
saying, but there's something there that's
interesting. Get them to pause for a minute.
And the most important piece is getting this done
where, if they get it on their mobile phone, which
everyone is looking at their mobile phone and on
email, they don't have to scroll. So usually three
to four sentences max. That also, that's how a
founder writes. That's how an executive writes
if you're selling top down. But most importantly,
leave them wanting more. Don't say everything,
don't even talk about the solution. Talk about
the problem that you want to solve, and why it
needs to be solved or why it's not good enough
today. So those are the four main components.
Just to reiterate, relevancy, bring some level
of counterintuitive or really different approach
to the conversation, focusing in on a problem
that's predicated to them, and really concise.
I love this. Is there an example
you could share that helps make
this even more real? Maybe an email
you helped with. And by the way,
this is email and LinkedIn, I imagine
is where you're communicating mostly?
LinkedIn, email, you would
be shocked to hear this,
but cold calling. I never used to
do this. It is one of the most...
The interest rates on cold calling are
a lot higher than email in many cases.
So it's calling, email, cold email and LinkedIn
DMs, is that the three channels generally?
Yep, those are the three, yeah, the main ones.
Cool. Yeah. Is there an example?
It doesn't have to be word for
word which you've done or people
done, but just how do you... Yeah.
Actually our first three years were built on
cold email before we actually had clients,
before we got word of mouth from the founders we
worked with, I cold emailed the first 20 customers
we had at Jellyfish. And the line I used in
there was zero to one sales talent doesn't
exist. That's why I want to have a conversation
with you. So that was kind of that leading,
wait, what? What does that even mean? And what
I would do is tie that to them in some respects.
If they recently raised the seed or series A,
where they are in that journey. But I would
lead with that and then tie it into like,
hey, I noticed you're looking to target X,
Y, and Z based off of what your website.
I'd love to have a conversation with you.
And that first piece is the relevance.
Here's why this is relevant to you.
Yeah. And then I say, our belief at
Jellyfish is zero to one sales talent
doesn't exist. That's why we built this model.
Awesome. And you kept it really short.
So it's relevance, counterintuitive,
keep it really short. And then
what was the fourth piece?
The fourth piece is just make sure it's concise
so that you don't have to scroll on mobile phone.
While we're on this topic. What's a good
conversion rate of these sorts of cold outreaches?
Conversion rate is interesting. Because
everyone's so focused on conversion rate.
I get that in the beginning until you
have some wins, you have to focus there.
But I just want to reverse engineer it
backwards a bit. Once you kind of have this,
and I'll talk about it in a sec, which is win
rate. Win rate is if I got Lenny on a phone call,
and he went through the sales process, and
I signed him up. And I spoke to 10 Lenny's
and only Lenny R was the one that signed.
That's one out of 10, that's a 10% win rate.
So if you have a really high win rate, let's
say 30 or 40%, you actually don't need as high
of a conversion rate on the outbound, because
you know if you get someone in the funnel,
the throughput is very healthy. If your win
rate is really low, you need that conversion
rate to be much, much higher, because you need
more and more and more at bats. So conversion
rate is a funny thing. In the beginning I get it
because you don't have a lot of customers going
through the pipeline yet. But there's people
focus on it in a little bit of a false sense
because interest rate truly is also dictated
by win rate. So I just want to specify that.
That's a really good point.
I would say if you're doing a win rate around 15
to 30% and you need to carry, oh I don't know,
a million dollar quota. I would say a healthy
conversion rate from outbound probably sits
around, when it's mature, around five to 7%.
Sometimes it could be two to 3%. Sometimes I've
seen eight to 15% because it's coming from the
founder, and they're solving a really heartfelt
problem. So interest rate is also predicated on
the problem that the founder has decided they want
to solve for, and their insight on that problem.
And everyone wants to keep going back to, well,
email rate is really low, email doesn't work
anymore. LinkedIn, I'm not getting the connects
I want. Yes, you can argue that the game has
changed a little bit, but when a problem is
truly being felt by the market, people will
get on a call. People will respond. And if I
can compare two engagements at a time that we're
running, I see one where it's a 2% interested rate
and then I'm seeing another one that's actually
at 12% interested rate. And we're doing nothing
different. The only thing that's different is
the insight that the founder has on the market,
which is a hard pill to swallow.
And I know that's hard to hear too.
And those are two different
companies selling different things?
Two different companies selling
to two different markets,
but they're not fundamentally
drastically different markets.
Got it. But one's basically got
more product market fit essentially?
That's exactly right. So everyone always
comes back to we have the sales problem,
we have the sales problem, we have an outbound
problem. And yes, there could be some technical
things going on that you need to look at. Maybe
you leveraged clay and you blasted a thousand
people and now your domain health has been
impacted. But the vast majority of the time,
maybe you're just not saying anything
interesting at all. Maybe the problem
you're looking to solve just isn't widely
felt. Maybe the perspective you have needs
another level of refinement because
you're just not getting those bites.
I feel like this question you just touched on is
something a lot of founders are always wondering,
is this product not the thing people
want? Is it my sales skills? I guess I
imagine this is a very difficult question
to answer, especially quickly. I guess is
there anything there that's more likely
because of this, it means your product
isn't something anyone's want, versus
you're not doing a good job selling it?
Remember that amazing chart you
drew where it talked about the
length of time it took? I think
you picked the top 25 startups.
For product market fit
timeline [inaudible 00:20:51].
Product market fit. Yeah, that amazing
image that I think has been reshared
more times than anything I've ever seen.
It's interesting because if you look at,
I was looking at this closely the other day.
If you look at the top section where the time
to product market fit is consolidated, and you go
all the way down to the air tables and the figmas,
which a long time to get to product market fit.
If you think about the earlier ones, which were,
it was like GitHub that had product market fit
pretty quickly. The SOC 2 compliant company.
Vanta.
Vanta. There's this thing in my head and I haven't
fully validated it but I'm going to share it with
you, which is did they start with the market
problem first and then build the product?
Because they knew who their market was right
off the bat. Versus an air table and a figma
that I think started with a technical insight
and then were trying to find their market.
I think that's absolutely right. Vanta, the way
they approached it, Christina, she was searching
for a pain. She was obsessed with talking to
everybody about a pain that they needed solved,
and then she just built it in spreadsheets.
So she started with the market very much so.
And I think product market fit when you start
with the market first, it's accelerated. But I
will say this, I think that it's also capped
on the upside. Because you're starting with
the market versus the air table and the figma,
which started with the technical insight and has
uncapped upside. But one is certainly riskier
than the other. Starting with a product is a
hell of a lot riskier. And this is where
I come back to so many people will say,
how did you get funding and not know
who your market is? And it's like,
because if they do find it, that's a really,
really, really big win. Versus I think if
you start with the market first, you could
potentially get a good win but is it more capped?
Interesting.
I don't know, it's just a thought. I
was staring at your grid for so long,
I was like, there's something here. And I
kept coming back to those were more like
I kept breaking it down to market versus product.
Yeah, I love this. I think there's
definitely something there. There's
also horizontal versus a very
specific problem you're solving.
Totally.
Okay, so you mentioned clay and you kind
of nerd sniped me there of just what tools
do you find useful? And it makes me think about
finding leads, which is kind of going backwards
through the sales process, but it might be
okay, so maybe let's spend time there. Just
like what do you recommend to founders to find
the good leads? Glengarry Glen Ross good leads.
So I say before you buy any tool, don't even
think about tools. I feel like people turn
everything into this complicated mess with all of
the tools that they start integrating. And then
they're engineers, I get it. So now they start to
engineer these sales tools together and then they
blast their market, and now they have 5,000 notes
out in one day and their domain takes a hit. So I
think before you even overthink about the tools
right now, can you manually find 30 people that
you want to spend 15 to 20 minutes writing a
rock solid note to? Are there 30 people that
you are deeply excited to learn from, that you
are willing to invest 15 to 20 minutes to write
a really thoughtful note? Let's just start
there. So some questions. One, are they even
discoverable? How hard is it to find 30 people?
What have you noticed across those 30 people?
Are there any interesting insights? Maybe it's
the size of the team they work on, maybe it's
the industry they're in, maybe it's the length
of time they've been in their role, maybe it's
their previous roles in their career. Are there
some commonalities? There's always some level
of a commonality usually in most cases. Okay, so
now you're starting to collect some parameters.
Just by doing this exercise, you're starting
to collect some parameters around who you want
to learn from and sell to. Now if you send out
those 30 notes and you wrote them specifically,
and you spend good quality of time on it. And
you've hit them on email, you've hit them on
LinkedIn, maybe even tried to call them, maybe
you've sent them a Twitter DM, pulled out all
the stops. How many people respond? 1, 5, 0?
If it's zero, it begs the question, do you now
want to do another 30 in a very similar fashion?
Do you want to change the messaging a little bit?
Now it forces these natural experiments. Or do
you want to maybe go after a different role?
So it forces you to answer these questions in
a very manual way before you even think about
integrating and spending time on tools. And
then you get to a point where it's like, okay,
now I'm starting to get some learnings and now
I've realized, okay, it's this group of people,
I've spoken to maybe two or three, now I want
to go out and actually build a campaign to now
talk to the next 10 to 15 people in that group.
Truncate this as much as you can because I think
people focus so much on volume in the beginning.
Even if you're selling down market, mid market,
enterprise, volume comes once you've identified
it and know the parameters. Parameters then allow
you to do really strong enrichment with a clay.
You now know the types of questions to give it.
If you're not asking it the right questions,
these enrichment tools, these sales tools will
yield nothing. So it all comes back to even
before you start your sales call, you need to
make sure you're asking the right questions with
am I even engaging, or do the people that I want
to learn from or sell to, am I even messaging
them in the right way? Are they even the right
person? And the only way you can do that is by
actually truncating these little experiments.
I love how tactical that is. And what I love is
even one of your nuances you mentioned is can you
even find them? This gives you a signal of how
are... You're going to have to have hundreds of
these, thousands of these eventually. If 30 is
hard or impossible, you're in trouble already.
Totally. And it was funny, I was talking to
someone today that said they had a target
segment of high net worth individuals that
they wanted to go out and serve. I'm like,
how do you find those people? I guess when you
get to a certain level, your net worth may be
public. I don't know. That stuff's very hard to
have certain parameters that are undiscoverable.
And then if they're undiscoverable and
it requires you getting on a call to
understand if they are a fit, that does impact
conversion rates. Not necessarily in a bad way,
but now you need to kind of bring that back
into the math equation, which is like, okay,
if I speak to 10 people, I know two out
of these 10 will be qualified. But I don't
know which of those two out of 10. Well, that
means you probably need more of those numbers.
So to quickly recap a few of the key
things that I've written down as we're
talking. So if you're just trying
to figure out who to reach out to,
make a list of 30 potential prospects
that you think are good fits,
that would be excited about what you're
building. Spend 15 to 30 minutes writing
them each an email. Do these emails have to be
really short the way you described previously?
I would say the shorter the better,
but would you respond to that? If you
got this email, would you respond it?
Got it.
One of a great little tactical test is on Gmail,
you can highlight the message and then have it
replay it back to you from an audio perspective.
Oh wow.
You'd be shocked how many notes I've changed
when it replays it back and I'm like, oh,
that sounds really passive-aggressive.
Interesting. And so you also shared
the structure for how to reach out
to folks. So let me just share that again.
And that applies to this initial email too,
but it sounds like as you automate, you want
to make it more precise and focused and not...
Basically they're not as customized as
you start reaching out to more folks.
Totally.
So start with something, here's
why this is relevant to you. You're
looking for salespeople in this market. Here's
something that's unexpected or surprised,
like zero to one salespeople don't exist. Keep
it short and then I always forget the last one.
Focus on the problem.
You don't even need to talk about the solution.
That's the big takeaway, which is if you get any
sales email, you get what's the primary focus of
that email? It's usually like here's what we do.
But I bet if someone reached out to you with a
novel insight and said, I'm really passionate
about solving this problem, if it's something
you're focused on, you'd probably reply.
If it's a big problem. If it's like,
oh yeah, you're so right, I need this.
The beauty with the American market,
and I say this because we do a little
bit of work with international startups
too, is if something doesn't feel right,
people love to complain about it. And it's like
use that to your advantage. Get that intel.
A note that I just looked at, that I wrote
down, that I think is very important is avoid
using "this is better" as your pitch.
Yeah, yep.
Different. Here's something
shocking about what we're
doing. Here's something that'll surprise you.
Yeah, or counterintuitive. Exactly.
Counterintuitive.
Yeah, it's interesting. I spoke to a good friend
that leads procurement at a massive organization.
And he said to me, he goes, "One of the worst
things someone can say to me is we're better than
X product. Then I ask them to define that. And
then I ask them, okay, how do we measure that?
And then I say, okay, should we give this
company another year to give them this feedback
before we make this huge transition and disrupt
momentum?" Yeah, better is a dangerous place.
I invest in a bunch of startups and I find
it's impossible to get anyone to care if
things are good enough with what they
got today. I'm happy not using the best
possible product if my life is okay. And
I have so many other things I got to do,
I'll just deal with this
good enough solution for now.
Absolutely.
Okay, amazing. So we talked about how to figure
out who to go after, how to pitch them to get
them to want to talk. The next step I imagine
is you're on the phone with them trying to
convince them to actually care. What do you do
there? How do you get them to engage further?
One is you need to be vulnerable. You're an
early stage startup, okay. The market, we're at
a point now where the market is smart. I always
assume that the buyer I'm speaking to is highly
educated and knows way more than I do. So just
have that perception because what I've learned is
a lot of the market will play dumb, and you can
get yourself caught pretty quickly. So when you
speak to them, I would be very open and honest
with where you are. Hey, I'm an early stage
startup. We are deeply passionate about solving
this specific problem. We have a lot to learn.
Here's how we are thinking about it from a problem
priority perspective. Can we gain your insight
into how this problem is manifesting on your side?
And then let them open up. Now you have them one,
talking about the problem. Now you're getting
the intel about their perception of the problem,
and is it even a problem? When you say
you're early stage and there's still a
lot to be done, it is easier to be honest.
If you tell them you have a fully baked,
ready to go product, they're not going to
give you honest feedback. It's very hard
to say to a founder and look them in the eyes
and say, hey, we built this product, can I
show you what it is? You're just going to get
someone that's going to say, oh, this is great,
this is wonderful. But when you're vulnerable
and when you tell them it's not fully built yet,
even if it is, you will get more raw and honest
feedback. Because it is easier to tell someone,
hey, before you make this mistake, I actually
don't care about that. If you've already built it,
they're not going to give you that feedback.
So the further you suggest you are,
you're actually going to hamstring a lot of the
intel, hamstring yourself on gaining a lot of
the intel. So that's one counterintuitive thing
that I think a lot of founders don't realize.
This episode is brought to you by Paragon,
the developer platform for building native
customer-facing integrations with third-party
apps. Our native integrations on your product
roadmap, whether it's to ingest context from
your user's external data and documents,
or to sync data and automate tasks across
your user's other apps, integrations are
mission-critical for B2B software products
today. But building these integrations in-house
cost an average of three months of engineering
according to the 2024 state of integration survey,
which results in difficult roadmap trade-offs.
This is why engineering teams at Copy AI,
AI21, and over 100 other B2B SaaS companies use
Paragon, so they can focus their efforts on core
product features, not integrations. The results,
they've shipped integrations seven times faster,
all while avoiding the never-ending maintenance
that comes with rolling your own integrations.
Visit UseParagon.com/Lenny to see
how Paragon can help you accelerate
your products integration roadmap
today, and get $1,000 in credit
on their pro and enterprise plans.
That's use P-A-R-A-G-O-N dot com.
So I had April Dunford on the
podcast a while ago. I don't know if-
She's awesome.
Amazing. And her last book, it actually has
the opposite advice, but I think I know why,
which is she focuses on later stage companies
and her advice is the buyer. She has this really
interesting insight that it's harder to buy
software now than to sell it, because there's
so much to consider and your job is on the line if
you make a mistake. It's easier just to be like,
forget it, I'm just going to go with what we have
today. I don't want to put my ass on the line for
buying this new thing that someone's trying. And
so her advice is you actually have to educate the
buyer on the market and here's what's happening.
Here's where things are going, and here's why I
think this is the future. But I think again,
I think that's focusing on later stage stuff.
A hundred percent. And you raised such a good
point, Lenny, which is late stage sales and
early stage sales are very, very different.
And I think that's where a lot of early stage
founders get tripped up as they're taking
late stage sales advice, usually coming from
an investor. Or they've maybe hired a salesperson
that's focused on more mature sales. But I think
she's spot on. Buying is just as hard, if
not harder, than selling right now. Because
who wants to make a mistake and also who wants to
go through switching costs? Oh, it's so painful.
Yeah. I think the other really important
point here that you're making is that
part of this initial sales experience of
founder led sales is not sell as much as
you can. It's to learn what people want.
And so I love that you're sharing here's
how to get the best possible feedback,
not necessarily close the most deals.
Totally. And founder led sales is
not about revenue on day one. It is
about learning as fast as humanly
possible to get to that pulse,
so that you can earn the right to sell.
There's this concept that I talk about,
which is you're going out to run sales to collect
the research, which is what founder led sales
is. And then you have sales for revenue,
which is that post founder led sales stage.
And your milestone that you suggested
of how far to take founder led sales,
you said around a million ARR, right?
Yeah. I think it's about, some people say 500,
some people say a million. I think if
you get to 500K really, really fast,
then I think absolutely you can move out of it.
If you get to 500K really, really, really slow,
you might not want to get out of it right away.
You haven't reached that velocity point yet.
Awesome. I have a post that we'll link to
that has actually numbers and when all these
big startups move from founder led sales. It's
in that same series about product market fit.
There's two stories this makes me think of I'll
share real quick. One is Sprig. They shared a
story of first round capital at their first
round and their partner there is just like,
we will not let you hire a salesperson until you
hit a million ARR. We're going to help you. We're
going to have salespeople helping you through
it, but we're not going to let you hire someone.
And he was really happy about that. The other is
Zip, which just raised a $2.3 billion valuation,
a procurement company that I was lucky to be an
investor in. And their first founder led sales
motion was they just reached out on LinkedIn to
heads of procurement, and just leaned into what
you're saving more, which is we just want your
advice on this product that we're building. Just
tell us what problems you have. It was very advice
oriented versus we want to sell you this thing.
Yeah, no, absolutely. I have this theory
that maybe you shouldn't hire any salespeople
until series A, right? Because seed is all about
experimentation and proving out that experiment,
and then obviously series A is about exploiting
that learning. But I see so many people,
I mean hiring for early stage sales is the odds
are actually more against you than trying to
get your next round of funding. Because it's
truly, truly such a counterintuitive stage.
Interesting. Okay, so I kind of took
us on a whole tangent. You were sharing
advice on how to get someone excited.
So the first is when you're engaging,
you're talking to the prospect and company ABC.
Your advice is be very honest and vulnerable
about your stage. Tell them you're early
stage. You're building this thing. You're
deeply passionate about this problem.
Here's what we're trying to do,
here's our priority problem perspective, and
where we're focusing, and kind of get their
feedback on your approach. Cool. You were going
to go to the next tip and I took us off course.
Testing the questions to ask. Where is that
aha unlock for you? But more importantly,
where's that aha moment unlocked for them? Because
when they start getting their gears churning
in their head about, and this is the beauty
about not having a product and not showing
them anything, they're visualizing in their
head now. This is a really powerful thing,
which is like, so tell me how this looks in your
head? How are you seeing this? And they're like,
I don't know if I can see it. And I'm like, great,
we'll show you that. Great insight to know by the
way. Or so I think this is how, I guess this is
how it would work. Walk me through what's living
in your head right now. You pick up on so much and
then all of a sudden they're like, wait a second,
we've tried solving for this and it's still not
solved for. Or you know what? We hired someone
last year to manage this. Great understanding.
Is it being measured? Is it being managed and
have they tried to solve for it? The leading
indicators that you're onto something here.
I love this thread because this
is what everyone's always like,
how do I know if I product market fit?
There's these signals that you're talking
about of signs that there's something here. Like
a big enough pain point where they're excited to
basically they want to pay for it, they will
pay to solve a problem. So maybe just again,
say the things you notice that are signs
like, okay, you have something here.
So I think the first is it has to be a growing
and widening problem. No one's going to spend
time fixing a pretty fixed problem, because it's
not necessarily really a priority anymore. It's
maybe a pain in the butt, but it's not a priority
if it's not growing or widening. So gate check
one is like, what is the implication? Are you
measuring? Are you managing this problem today?
Yes or no? If they don't know, great
to know. If they said no, okay,
move on to the next. That's pretty powerful.
No, we're not measuring or managing this. Okay,
there's probably not much there.
If it is being measured or managed,
then the next question you want to get into
is how have you tried to solve for it? Is it
through that head count that you just hired?
Is it through another tool? Is it just still
an open gap because nothing exists yet to solve
it? Just understand their maturity around how
they've tried to plug it. These are all that make
the secret moments in intel to close that gap.
That's awesome. And essentially it's
showing you that there's a pain here
that they're paying attention
to and are trying to solve.
And what you're psychologically doing
is now you're flipping them into a buyer
where they're like, wait a second, hold on. I
need to bring on so-and-so on the next call,
they also think that this is not good enough.
That's funny because that's exactly what Wiz
noticed, is they moved from people being like,
oh, this is cool. I like it, I like it. To,
okay, I'm going to pull in this person. I'm
going to pull in this person to talk about it and
make sure we're... And they were pulling in other
people exactly as you described it, because
they wanted to move forward on this thing.
Absolutely. And that's when you know there's some
momentum behind it, which is when they're bringing
in other colleagues. Whether it be the potential
users, if you're reaching out to the executive,
or the users like, hey, I actually want
to bring my boss on to the next call.
Good sign. Cool. Anything else
along these lines of how to get
someone excited slash understand
if there's going to be pull there?
I guess the one thing is please, please,
please do not ask questions like what keeps
you up at night? If you had a magic wand,
what are your pain points today? I can guarantee
you that answer changes every single day.
That's super interesting. Is there any
tip for how to end one of these calls,
as someone that's never done sales is like-
Yes.
Okay.
Get the second call booked on the first call.
Love it.
Pull up calendars. Look at
calendars. Who else should
be invited? It's just a natural
evolution to ending the call.
Great. So that's in 30 minutes though, right?
And if they say, ah, I'll email you.
I could say.
That's also kind of a leading indicator. Yeah.
So do you recommend not getting off the
call, trying to avoid that, or is it just-
If they won't give you time on the calendar,
you could say, listen, great. Feel free to
email me. Maybe they're just being honest
and they don't have their calendar available,
but nine times out of 10, it's usually I don't
have the heart to tell you I'm not interested.
Yeah, it's hard. It's hard to tell people
you're not interested. Very cool. Okay. This is
amazing. Okay, so the next step, if I remember
correctly, is kind of co-authoring and co...
Yes.
Okay, cool. Talk about that.
In the early, early days, one of the biggest
ways you can get folks excited is it feels like
it's going to be built specifically
for them. The power of specificity,
the power of being extremely focused. With that,
you can literally turn a customer into a guide by
asking them to co-author the scope. The scope of
work. The co-authorship piece is important for two
reasons. It helps you understand where they're on
their biomaturity. Let me explain. If they do not
have an existing process or strategy to solve
X problem, they can't buy a technology yet,
which means you need to sell them. And this is
why I go back to you need to sell them some form
of a service, right? Why? You want to be the one
in there educating. You also want to get the logo.
You also want to show the revenue. While it's
not recurring revenue, it still shows intent.
And I think that that's really important.
Every founder I speak to is like, well,
my investor really doesn't want service-based
revenue. That's fine. But then you can also
tell your investor, great, should I wait 18
months to when they're ready to buy a solution,
and be the one that's not the one selling
them because someone else educated them?
These are all of the implications of waiting.
So yes, is service-based revenue great? No,
we all know why it's not great. But it's
great in the sense that it shows intent.
It's great in the sense that you can call them
a customer. It's great in the sense that now you
can use their logo. And it's great in the sense
because you are getting paid to educate them.
You are getting paid to help them design their
process. This is where all the power lives. And
this is why so many AI startups a year and two
years ago were going in on services contracts,
because they wanted to set the mindset with
the buyer around what this would look like.
Is there anything you recommend
to time box contain the services
piece? Because I know a lot of companies-
Yes, such a great point, Lenny. You absolutely
need to time box this. I would time box it as
90 days and then what you can say in the next 90
days, we'll scope where we are and what you need.
Scoping out more than 90 days, listen, so much is
going to change. You might also not want to do it
anymore, so you don't want to lock yourself up.
So I would look at 90 day increments. A specific
example. We had a founder that my colleague
was working with, and they were selling a
very specific technology to a non-traditional...
Sorry, a very traditional industry. I don't want
to be two bleeding with what it is, but a very
traditional industry that's not used to working
with startups, or necessarily plugging in a
new technology right away. And they were very
honest. They said, listen, we haven't changed
vendors or partners in over five or six years.
I actually don't even know how we would do that
today. Could you come in and explain to us,
understanding where our workflow is and how we
would integrate this, before we even consider the
technology? Which we did. We got paid a nominal
amount, but we're now a customer and now we get
to set the stage for how they think about this.
And then they won the technology contract. But
everyone is so focused on selling the technology
really, really, really quickly. That works in
markets that know how to buy that technology,
have a process in place, have a strategy in place,
have an implementation team in place.
If it's a new technology like AI right now,
they need a strategy and process like who's the
human in the loop? Is it them or is it you? How do
we measure success? What does success look like?
What risks should we be aware of? Our legal team's
not even aware of all these risks. You want
to be careful because legal can immediately,
and procurement, can shut these things down if
it seems too novel, where it's foreign versus
they're so used to buying services, especially
at market. It's their largest budget line item.
So it's interesting because most founders are very
afraid of moving into services. I
hadn't heard this advice before.
Probably going to get slapped for
saying all this stuff, by the way.
Well, so along those lines, what percentage of
companies that you've worked with or
see do that or have to do that step?
This is going to be a shocking step.
So I would 40 to 50% have to sell some
form of service before they can sell a technology.
Wow. Of B2B SaaS company?
A B2B SaaS. And this, again, this is
specifically more top-down sales. But yeah,
because the user and the buyer are different,
which means there's user value, there's buyer
value, there's all different players, there's
procurement you have to go through. But yeah.
And just to make it even clearer,
what's an example of a service that
you've seen company offer in a step?
So I've seen, hey, can you come in and actually
help me pitch this, design a custom pitch to my
boss as to why we should do this today? And
we literally got paid to build a sales pitch.
So it's not necessarily providing a service.
It could be just helping them sell this.
Yeah. It could be helping them sell in a
way that makes you... You need to get a lot
more context on their business. It can also
be, hey, we haven't actually thought about
a process for how we can actually deploy something
like this. We're currently using this technology,
which we want to change from. You've kind of hit
this at the right time. How would we implement
or how is it best to integrate with this tool? Can
we get both of you guys in a room to map this out?
Got it. So it's like consultants almost, like
coming in to help you solve this problem.
It's a great point. It's consulting them towards
the acquisition of the product. It's
not consulting as one-off consulting.
Got it. And they know that obviously
you're biased, but they also want the
problem solved. And they're like, great,
you're going to help us solve this problem,
because it's on my plate and I need your
help convincing leadership that this is-
And I need to craft the storyline
as to why we need to do it anyway,
so I will pay you to do it, but
here's the format it needs to be in.
Fascinating. Wow. Okay.
Anything else along those lines?
And then of course, if you're in a
position to actually sell the technology,
because the market is able to acquire and adopt it
and not have to create a new strategy or process,
then obviously sell the technology.
You don't need to be selling services.
I want to come back real quick. The
previous call, I wrote this note down as
you were talking. You recommended not doing
a demo and just talking about it broadly.
Yes.
Is that your advice there?
On the first call. Yeah. On the first call,
my fundamental belief is that the demo is a
bit of the only carry you control in the
sales process, right? Once they see it,
it's kind of like pitching an investor. Once
they take a look under the hood, that dreaminess
in their eyes, they're like, oh, I saw it. So
leave them wanting more. And the demo is that,
leave them wanting more. Even when you do a
demo, don't demo everything. Leave it for a
second call. Let them invest a lot of time in
you. Again, if it's qualified. Preface that,
if it's qualified. But everyone races
through the sales process like let's do
a demo call as quickly as humanly possible.
Yes, that is important down market. That is
important if you're selling a $3,000 tool, you
absolutely want to be demoing as fast as humanly
possible because it's a high-volume game.
Upmarket, when you're talking about hundreds
of thousands of dollars, you want to slow that
down as fast as possible. Because you want to,
one, make sure all of the right people are in the
room. As soon as there's one lead on this, and if
it requires other people involved, it doesn't
feel like anyone else's baby. So you want it to
make it feel like the group's baby versus this one
individual's baby because it's very quick. Someone
can easily say, I'd rather use this tool. And
then there's this stalemate of nothing happens.
Just to maybe reiterate, so far we've
talked about figure out who to talk to,
pitching them on talking to you, then having
that first conversation. Maybe there's another
conversation in there to get them excited. And
then there's just getting them past the finish
line, keeping everyone aligned. Is that roughly
the next step or how should we think about this?
Yeah, so if you are selling upmarket
and you now need to go to procurement,
who is the group involved in the bot. They're
the professional buyers. Procurement is a very
interesting function. They are very smart,
very, very smart. They do this for a living.
They are professional buyers. So there's a couple
things that you need to be aware of. You need to
sell them as well. You need to really make this
sound... Don't over complicate it. Don't add in
jargon. Make it feel like, okay, I can wrap my
head around this. The second piece is it's got
to feel different from anything else out there.
Because the professional buyer, it's much easier
to say, wait a second, we have these 17 other
preferred vendors that do similar ish work.
Why don't you just go use one of them? Because,
oh, by the time this gets through procurement,
it could be another three to four months.
I've seen deals die on the vine because
procurement actually suggested they go use another
vendor in the system, that this buyer wasn't even
aware of, because they didn't differentiate.
It didn't feel different. It just felt slightly
better. That's how it was positioned. The
third piece is when you get to procurement,
you're going to have to do all the work. Make
their job easy. You are probably a very small
piece into the very large deals that a lot
of these people buy. So you can get easily
sidelined just because you're just a small buy.
So do the work for them. Literally say, I want to
make this as easy as possible for you. Give me
the forms that you need to fill out. I'll fill
them out for you, and you can do it yourself. You
can edit them. Do the lift for them. If you don't,
it's so easy for it to just go there and die.
Another piece that's important
with procurement is explaining exactly what you
do and don't do. Because if you say you do a
bunch of things and they can't really place you,
they're going to send you to the kitchen sink of
contracting an MSA, which is going to ask you for
$5 million in an insurance policy and all sorts
of other things. And the ability to look at your
book at any point in time. And the reason they did
that is because they can't classify you. So the
easiest thing to do is classify you as high risk.
So make it easy for them, make it simplified. You
can also truncate your contracts, meaning let's
say IT is maybe, and you want to ask this, how
long does it take to get through IT due diligence?
They might say, oh, it's a 90-day backup,
it's a 60-day backup, it's a 30-day backup.
There's no backup. If there's a backup, you
also don't want it to die and you want it
to give an incentive. So this is when you
want to truncate contracts to a technology
contract and a service contract. Service contract
allows you to onboard them, get them prepped,
come in and educate all of the users about what
they're about to go through. So that then there's
an incentive to get that technology piece through.
There's all these little things to think about,
and I think everyone... Getting to procurement
is also creative. And knowing who you're dealing
with and how to make their job as easy as
humanly possible. Because what you said
and what April said is spot on, which
is buying is just as hard as selling.
As I'm hearing you describe this, I feel
like we might be discouraging people from
selling because this feels very not fun.
All these steps, all these procurement work,
anything you can say to get people
to feel like, okay, this is worth it?
Yes, I can get people very excited by this.
Once you are in, you are in. Once you are in,
you are now a preferred vendor. You now
have the ability to cross over into other
business units. You are now the reason
that, hey, if your competitor comes in,
well, you got there first. So what do
you think procurement's going to say?
This is why it's so important to get into the
enterprise as fast as humanly possible. While it's
a headache to get through, if you project manage
it, you'll be good. If you make an accountability,
just like if you were to go through fundraising.
If you are a part of a team that had to raise
money, it's no different. There's always
some level of due diligence. There's always
you doing more of the work than them. That's
just enterprise sales. But if you prove value,
your hundred thousand dollars deal could be
$500,000 next year. Your $500,000 deal could
be a million dollars the following year.
This is where stuff begins to compound,
and this is where your growth journey really gets
accelerated. So the beauty with enterprise is once
you're in, you're in. You beat out your competitor
for a short period of time. There is a little bit
of a moat there, but it's not forever. You all
have intel that no one else will have. Meaning
you're a part of the conversations, you
have the badge, you can join the meetings,
you can ask for introductions. They'll do it.
It doesn't feel like sales anymore. You're now
a partner. This is why it's so powerful to get
into the enterprise because there's so many
compounding effects. If you put the effort
in on the sales side, the return is insane.
That was awesome. Nailed it. I'm excited.
Just for folks that are listening,
just to calibrate what size of company
you're talking about selling to here,
what's the size of the advice
you've been sharing so far? Roughly?
So I've been talking a lot about enterprise
sales, which is I would say anywhere north of
500 to a thousand employees. Just mental model.
I'm talking about enterprise sales specifically
because there's so much nuance involved in it,
because the user and the buyer are very different,
right? As you go down market, let's talk
about small business for a second. The
user and the buyer are the same person. There's no
procurement. If they like what you've built, it's
pretty straightforward process. In the mid-market,
mid-market is a funky place because you either are
anchoring towards the lower end of mid-market,
which is more upper end of small business,
or you're anchoring towards lower end enterprise.
Those are two very different divides. So
mid-market, just if you're talking about lower end
enterprise, again, this is all relative. If you're
talking about lower end small business, again,
your user and the buyer probably are the same
person, which makes sales a lot more streamlined.
But churn. Small business, challenge with small
business is the churn. If they get pissed
off, if they don't feel like it's good enough,
they are gone faster than you don't even realize.
And they might even tell you. They'll just cancel.
And we always see this on Twitter. They'll call
American Express and say, cancel these charges.
I don't want to talk to these people anymore.
They're just more irrational because sometimes
maybe it's their money if they're a small
business. So small business in mid-market, while
sales is a bit faster, you really got to be on
the product market fit side, worried about churn.
And they also go out of business at a higher rate.
Exactly.
And so you have that kind of churn.
A churn piece too. Yeah, exactly.
Amazing. Okay. What comes next? So we're
kind of in procurement at this point.
Okay, so now we're at signature, right?
Okay.
Okay. So as you enter procurement, okay, you
want to know before you get to the next stage,
who is signing this deal? Here are some examples
of signers I've seen. Chief financial officer,
chief legal officer, the business unit head
themselves, the head of procurement. You want
to know who that person is so that you can
literally say to the head of procurement,
hey, listen, I want to make sure this person
has everything they need when they review this,
to know what they're signing. Who is it and
how can I give you a few bullets to share that
you can maybe respond to, that we get tight so
that they know exactly what they're looking at?
This was two or three years ago, I was involved
in getting a deal over procurement that was just
truly, it was a pharmaceutical company and it was
very, very long process. And we got to the finish
line and the CFO was the signature. And this is
when I made the mistake. CFO responds back to
the procurement lead who sent it to the business
unit, who sent it to me and was like, what am I
signing? I don't actually understand what these
people are doing and why are we doing this?
So then she quickly said to me, hey, listen,
we need to defend this. Can you put together
some bullets? And I'm like, well, what kind of
bullets do I need? What does this person care
about? And again, it created so much anxiety
and now I'm back in the bottom of the queue.
Probably he or she's looking at the things
that come in in an order of priority. So now
I've elongated this by another month simply
because I didn't plan. So this is just to say
I'm learning from my own mistake of know who
the signature is, because if they don't know
what they're looking at, they're going to kick
it out and you're going to lose your queue spot.
So many ways to fail. And this was you selling
Jellyfish or this was you working with a company?
This was me helping [inaudible 01:00:15].
Oh man. Okay. Anything else in that
step that might be helpful to folks?
Yes. One thing to caveat is you do not get
paid until you are approved by finance,
and procurement has a signature on the
contract. Meaning don't start any work.
Or if you do start work, know that there
is no payment. The business unit can't
just pay you. It's paid through a purchase
order, which is paid through by finance.
So don't rely on that money unless
it's finally, unless the signature's
on the paper. Quick tangent, thoughts on
discounting at any parts of the journey?
If there is a reason as to why. So discounting
just to get the deal over the line, you're
negotiating with yourself. Unless they ask for it
and then ask them to defend it. Certain segments,
like small business, you should leave
a little bit of room for buffer because
sometimes that's their own money. It's like their
own small business. Mid-market and enterprise,
there's got to be a reason why and ask them.
Be like, hey, so if I give you a 30% discount,
can I remove 30% of the value? You can kind
of play it a little bit like that. I don't
recommend it, but that's kind of what they're
saying. But discounting is great if they're
doing something for you far and beyond.
For example, if they're a design partner,
if they're going to be a reference for two
years, if they're going to give you something
far beyond just using the technology, then
yeah, I think a discount is a good reason to
give back to somebody that's giving to you,
but not as a strategy to get a deal done.
Okay. Is there anything beyond this step
of getting the signature? Are we done?
Yeah. I hope you celebrate because-
Okay, great. You got a signature
from this whole process.
Yeah. Hopefully I'm not making this sound too
daunting. I'm just really trying to
lay out all the mistakes I've made.
Yeah, no, this is exactly what people
need. This is amazing. And your pep talk
was really helpful too. Along the way.
What's the general timeline for sales
process like this in your experience,
with these 500 plus ice companies?
So there's three things that dictate sales cycle.
One is how well are you project managing it? For
example, I'll say, let's have our second or third
call in two weeks. Two weeks? Do a week. Why are
you elongating this? Keep your calls as tight
as possible because that shortens your sales
cycle. The second is just how complex the
organization is. If you're dealing with a
highly regulated industry, just know it's going
to take a bit longer, sometimes 20 to 30% longer.
So a highly regulated industry, nine to 12 months
on conservative, on the conservative side. Again,
it's tricky because is there a budget line
item dictated towards it yet, or are you
creating budget? How painful is the problem?
And how senior have you gone? If you're talking
to the SVP or chief of whatever, they're pretty
good at about being able to navigate the traps.
If you're dealing with a director or
mid-level person, they maybe have not
purchased something before and just make
some internal mistakes. I always say it can
range anywhere. I've seen enterprise deals
close in 90 days, believe it or not. Rare,
but I've seen it. I've also seen enterprise
deals typically take anywhere between six and
12 months. Really important but. Enterprises know
that the process and the length to get the deal
done is what costs more than the technology
itself. Meaning the effort it takes to get
through their system. That's why they're willing
to spend so much. Sometimes that's actually more
expensive than the technology itself. So don't
negotiate with yourself, understand the value
you're delivering, but don't be crazy. I've seen
people try and go in with a million dollar deal
as a seed stage startup. Oh, interesting thing.
So interesting tactic. I've seen contracts in
the enterprise that state that the deal cannot
exceed more than 20% of the existing revenue.
So there are these things just to be aware
of. In most cases, you can ask them be like,
is that a hard line? Is that hard, hard line?
Or how negotiable is that? Sometimes it's
negotiable. Sometimes it's like, no, this is a
hard rule. But then it seems silly because you
take a hundred thousand dollar deal and bring
it down to 20,000. It's just be careful that
you're stripping some of the value out. But I kid
you not. I've seen an enterprise deal go from,
it lands at 60 and it turns into
280,000 in four months. So again,
I want to encourage, yes, this is a lot
of work, but the payoff is exponential.
What's a good ACV to start with if
you're trying to sell to enterprise,
to make it all worth it for your startup?
I would say anywhere between 50 to 200K
depending on the business unit you're
selling to. That's kind of like sweet spot.
They're used to something in that realm.
And this is a startup
selling [inaudible 01:05:38].
Early stage startup, like
founder led, early stage.
Initial contract. Wow.
Yep. Initial contract. I would say, okay,
probably caters more towards like 50 to
100K. But I've seen people sell to...
Again, it's how big is the problem? Who
are you selling it to? Is it the SVP that you
started with and they've got a large budget,
and it's a pretty healthy business
unit? Or are you selling to a director?
If you're not able to sell your product at
that price? What's your advice to teams?
If you are a startup, I always ask the founder,
did you build this for the enterprise and is
that the model you want to play? Or did you
build this for small business? Small business is
a marketing game. Marketing intensive activity,
right? It's high velocity, high volume, lots of
dials. It's a very different game than enterprise.
So which game do you want to play? Let's just
start there. Which game is more attractive to
the founder. Or who is more exciting to serve?
What's the storyline you want to tell investors?
That plays a lot of it into it too. And do you
have an enterprise product? Are you solving an
enterprise problem or do you think you're solving
an enterprise problem but you're not sure yet?
And your point is also mid-market
is it's rarely to be successful.
It's hard to start there because you're
straddling two very different go-to-markets,
right? One that's of high value, one that's
of high volume. And also mid-market companies,
this is where a lot of people don't... If it
requires heavy integration, they don't have
those resources. That's usually outsourced to
an Accenture or some of these consulting firms,
and now you're having to rely on third
parties to be involved. It gets messy.
This is fascinating. I have a list of questions
from the audience that you pulled from Twitter.
You asked on Twitter what questions to ask you
as you're coming on here. So there's one that's
very related to this, which is someone said, if
you're still very early in pre-product market fit,
but get initial validation from both
small to medium businesses and enterprise,
how do you decide which one to focus
on? Is there a counter argument against
starting or SMB going up market
over time like most companies do?
I've seen companies successfully do in both of
those motions. Truthfully. We know all of those.
We know people that started small business
and worked their way up into enterprise and
were successful. We've seen people be really
successful by starting at the enterprise,
like a Wiz. That's more of an internal
question, which is like, who did you build
this for? Where's the problem most felt and
which go-to-market game do you want to play?
And I think that latter part is so important.
It sounds like why should it be what I want?
It's like what's going to make a big
business? But I think people forget,
this is going to be your life for 10 years.
Do you want to be selling to enterprises and
building all the enterprise features? Would you
prefer to build for small companies? Pros and
cons to both but it's important to think about the
life you're creating for yourself and your team.
A hundred percent. And I built
my career in enterprise sales,
upper-end mid-market enterprise sales, and
yeah, that's just the game I know the best.
Yeah, that's also an important part of it. Just
to double down on that is like what do
you have experience doing? Not like...
Exactly.
Yeah. Where's the opportunity? Okay.
Another question that I love is,
and we touched on this initially, but I think
it's good to come back to this. Someone said,
customers are fascinated with what
we're offering from the initial calls,
but responsive momentum is too slow from their
end. Would be great to know how to fix this.
Yeah, it's tough because unless you're in the
weeds to understand why. I'll give you a few
examples that it could be. Did you speak to
a buyer who now is trying to sell this up to
their boss, and it's just getting sidelined and
they don't know the executive value? They've
just been selling the buyer value the whole time.
That's one reason things can slow down. Another
reason things can slow down is you haven't
really framed the problem well and they don't
understand the full implications of why they need
to solve it. So it's kind of just sitting there
a little bit. The third is they've just been
really nice and it's not going to go anywhere.
I guess that that's usually the latter. Was
that true or it's kind of all over the place?
It's so hard to give a founder
hard feedback. Because they've
just dedicated their life to this thing.
Who wants to be the bearer of bad news?
And sometimes you just need to let
the actions speak louder than words.
We've talked about all these steps. I'm curious,
when you come to a founder or your team,
where do you find the most on lock often?
Which of the steps of the sales process do
you find the biggest opportunity
to improve conversion in sales?
It's qualification. Qualification because
if you spend your time on the wrong leads,
that equates to a zero. So if you don't get
that first level right, let me put it this way,
everyone that I know says they have a bottom of
funnel problem. It's never a bottom of funnel
problem. It's a top of funnel problem. I've
actually never seen a bottom of funnel sales
problem. It's always qualification, which is a
symptom of not reaching out to the right person,
not having the right messaging, not solving the
right problem, or not being different enough.
I love this. So basically the
biggest pitfall people fall into,
in your experience, is they're just talking
to the wrong people, wasting their time?
Yeah. Talking to the wrong people
or using the wrong message or...
Pitching them something
they can't actually deliver.
Yeah. Here's the other thing too. Sales is
supposed to feel fun for the buyer. They
should be like, this feels fun. This
person's invigorating. They're going
to change my world. They're going to make
me see things differently. They're going
to get me promoted. They're going to help me
increase my influence internally. And so many
salespeople are so boring. How many times
have you got off a call and you're like,
I can't wait to get off this call? And founders
too, just like all of a sudden their passion,
they go like stone cold face. And it's like
bring the passion. Bring the energy. That
is felt by the market. Remember, some of these
people are in boring jobs. Give them an outlet.
So along those lines, I think a lot of
people are just not... Like me included.
I feel weird doing sales. It's a weird
experience trying to convince someone
to buy something. Is there any advice you
could share to get someone over that hump?
If you have built something that you believe in.
Very hard to sell something you don't believe
in. I think everyone agrees that. If you've built
something you believe in and they have a problem,
that's a beautiful thing. Truthfully, that's what
makes the world go around, is I have a solution
to your problem. Now you just need make sure
that the problem, you just need to be honest,
that the problem they have, your solution truly
can solve for. And you're not short selling just
to get a logo and a deal over the line, and see
them churn in six months or nine months or three
months. That what you are selling is truly
going to solve their problem. And be honest
about it. I can't tell you enough when I tell
someone, listen, I don't think I'm the right
fit for you. They try and sell you on them.
They're like, well, wait a second. Hold on.
What if we did this, this, and this? And it's
like, no, no, no. Here's what we're great at.
And then they can say, well, I also need that
too. And all of a sudden, this level of trust
comes out. And trust is the number one currency
in sales. If you are a trusted salesperson,
people will recommend you all day and every day.
If you're a trusted founder, your market will
continually send you leads and word of mouth.
So don't try and sell something just to prove
to investors you sold something, because it'll be
quickly seen on the other side when they churn.
Amazing. Okay, Jen, so I'm going to cut the
lightning round. I know you also have to run
and do real work. So let me give you a
chance just to talk about what you do,
how you help companies in case folks
can find value in working with you.
Deeply passionate about sales, as I'm
sure you can tell. We specifically help
founders through this pain. Navigating
enterprise sales, mid-market sales,
and really trying to crack that first million
of ARR. Or sometimes even that first 500K of ARR
if they move fast enough. And it is really hard.
It's counterintuitive to what most people think,
but it can be really, really
fun when we show you the way.
And you described to me how it works,
and I think it's important to clarify
this. You basically embed with
the team and help them do this.
Yes. So I fundamentally do not believe in
outsourcing the heartbeat of the organization,
which is sales. So what we do is we embed
alongside the founder and drive a lot of
the execution, but make sure that they are the tip
of the spear engaging directly with their market,
and learning directly from the market's
mouth, not playing this game of telephone.
Amazing. And I mentioned this when we were
chatting, but I think of it again, is when I was
interviewing all these companies about how they
started selling early on. One of the interesting
threads that I heard again and again, is how
many of them hired a coach or a consultant as a
founder to help them learn to do sales. And that's
essentially what you do. And I didn't even know a
service like this existed, so this is super cool.
It'll point people to what you do. I also have to
ask you, the question I ask everyone at the end
is just, how can listeners be useful to you?
Help each other out. I think so many
people have helped me in my career,
and in this journey, that the pay it forward model
that exists in the technology space is
so beautiful. So just don't let that die.
Beautiful. Well, Jen, thank
you so much for being here.
Lenny, this was awesome. Thank
you so much for having me.
So awesome. So excited for folks
to hear it. I've learned a ton.
Okay, I'll let you go. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If you
found this valuable, you can subscribe
to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
Lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.