all right thank you Jay-Z and big thank you to Lenny for putting on this amazing conference inviting all his friends welcome Lenny's friends all right so today uh we're going to talk about
rituals for great decision- making and before we get into decision- making we're going to talk about the first word rituals so rituals is a topic that I'm
obsessed with I think people have some normal Hobbies I have this weird one I like to collect up people's rituals uh I'm actually turning into a book it's called rituals of great teams and my
whole inspiration for it started with a conversation with this guy Bing Gordon and Bing if you don't know him he was the chief creative officer at Electronic Arts uh he's now a famous investor
places like Zinga uh Amazon many other great companies he and I sat on a board together and he kept harassing the CEO with this question he said what are your golden
rituals and and none of us really knew what he was talking about so he said Bing what's a golden ritual and he saidwell great companies have a small list of golden rituals and they have
three tests and you quickly rattle them off number one they're named number two every employee knows them by their first Friday and number three they're templated and he quickly gave his list
Amazon has six pagers Google does okrs Salesforce does V2 mom and if you want to be a great company you have to have a great set of golden rituals
so I got pretty obsessed with this idea started collecting up all of these uh rituals I could find and putting them into a book um by the way if if you'd like I'm writing the book in the open uh so you can come join what I call the
Brain Trust uh ritual great teams.com and I published about a chapter at a time and I'd love your feedback and your contributions along the way I got to meet lots of interesting people one of
the most interesting conversations was with daresa so dmesh for those of you that don't know him he's a founder of HubSpot and he had this really interesting
perspective on uh rituals so first off you shared a ritual called flash tags I'll talk more about that a little bit later in the talk but he also made an observation that everyone everyone here
we all build products and for the most part we focus on one customer we build products for our end customer but we actually build two products there's another product we build for our
employees and if you ask people to describe that they'll often use a term like culture but then if you ask them to start describing culture they'll
describe it using the word rituals so often times we talk about these rituals and they feel like oh that's just the way we work that's our operating system but actually when we're designing
rituals we're building a two-way mirror of our culture so we're going to spend a lot of time on decision- making but actually my broader ask of all of you is to think
about what you spend your days on you're probably spending most of your time on the right hand side of this picture designing products for your customers think about how you can spend just as much time designing the product for your
teams the rituals that really run how your culture operates all right that's rituals today we're going to talk about a specific type of rituals about great decision-
making and we're going to focus on four different uh topics how can we ask the right question how we can follow the right decision process in the right Forum with the right
stakeholders all right before I get started on this I have two big caveats so first one is I'm going to give you a lot of examples I stuffed as many examples in the 25 minutes as I possibly
could um the examples are meant to be uh inspirational if some of them resonate with you you should use them exactly as is but really my main point of this talk
isn't to take someone else's rituals it's to be inspired to design your own and the second big caveat is I'm going to show you a lot of examples uh from Kota the company from Kota customers and
so on um while I think Kota is a great product for running your rituals in you can uh feel free to implement these in whatever your toolkit is the main point is take control of how your teams run their
rituals all right ready for topic number one let's talk about asking the right question and I want to start this with a story from my time at YouTube and we're going to
talk about a topic called igen questions so describe IG questions maybe I'll go back in time to 2008 and tell you about a uh a situation we had we called this
topic the Modern Family question so as JayZ was saying I joined YouTube fairly early on 2008 uh YouTube was facing a lot of hard times we were losing a lot of money we had grainy
videos we had a big lawsuit but actually if you sat in one of our staff meetings any day in 2008 you'd probably hear us talking about this thing called a modern family
question the uh so what was the question so we would look at every day we'd look at our search queries YouTube was then and still is now the second biggest search engine on the planet we get our
list of search queries and one of the top five queries every week was for Modern Family that wasn't that big a surprise Modern Family was a number one show on TV at the time there was one big
problem we didn't have Modern Family on YouTube and there was a big debate about what we should do about it now in the meantime abc.com had decided to upload
every episode of Modern Family online available for free and I know that's not such a big deal now but in 08 that wasn't a very common thing to do especially not with the number one show
on TV and so the team divided up and basically half the team said we should link out to abc.com we're owned by Google do the right thing by the user
and the other half of the team felt that was uh suicide if we did that then nobody would ever upload great content to YouTube and we absolutely should not do that every meeting we'd have the discussion wouldn't get a resolution
we'd roll it over and uh the Modern Family question persisted so at some point we decided to hold an offsite to talk about what we're going to do about this and I got asked to go frame the uh
frame the discussion pull some data try to come up with the framework and it was really hard because everybody was already stuck in their Viewpoint they already knew what they felt and the night before I ended up
reading a paper from another team from the Google shopping team and they had gone and done all this research on why people were choosing Amazon over Google shopping and what they learned was all
the users kept telling that we know that Google shopping has indexed all of Amazon and the rest of the internet but I prefer Amazon because it feels like a consistent experience doesn't have everything but I know how
the reviews work I know how the pricing work I know how the the the shipping works so I'm going to pick consistency over comprehensiveness so I decided that rather than talking about Modern Family
and should we link out sites we decided to start this discussion with a different topic and said in 10 years will the online video market value consistent or
comprehensiveness this discussion we got through pretty fast took about an hour and we came to the conclusion that it would be about consistency and I think by the way looking backwards now this discussion was 16 years ago I think we were right
the online video Market exploded and there is no one site that is comprehensive consistency definitely one but it turned out that by answering this question we not only answer the question
about whether or not we should link out sites we answered many other questions as well we decided not to take uh third party Ed players on YouTube probably one of the most famous things was we ended
up taking back control of our IOS app from the Apple team which is probably a story for a different talk but this whole concept of choosing the right
question got a name it's called igen questions so uh first off the word igen question is completely made up but it's based off of a math word called igen vectors so for those you that remember
from linear algebra class an igen Vector is the most discriminating Vector in a multi-dimensional space but if you don't remember that don't want to remember that doesn't really matter um you can just use the word so here's what an IG
question is is the question that if answered first would answer most of the other questions it's a pretty simple idea I'm sure you can picture time you sat down
to have a discussion you've got 10 questions in your list and how are they ordered they might be ordered by you know the whenever it got brought up it might be by severity the reason we were talking about the Modern Family question
was we were trying to do deal with abc.com and so that's what was at the top of the list but actually the right question answer might be number six in that list and if you answer that question you'll end up answering all the
others as well another way to think about this is we spend a lot of time trying to get to the right answer and I'd encourage you to think about how do you get to the right
question if you want to know more about this uh I wrote a piece about it on IG questions you can go hear more about those stories but I'll move on to topic number two so you got the right question
you're ready to make a decision how do you form the right decision process I had this really fun conversation with Colin Brer uh Colin was uh former Chief of Staff to Jeff
Bezos at Amazon he wrote a book called working backwards and we ended up talking about a famous moment in 2004 turned out two important things happened in 2004 the first one was there was this
really famous memo that got sent out from Jeff Bezos saying no more PowerPoints Colin told us the story apparently he was the one that drafted this memo he hand it to Jeff sent it out they didn't think it was going to be
that big a deal but of course the deal that not only changed all of Amazon it probably changed every other company my guess is everyone here either runs the Amazon writeup culture or anti- runs the
Amazon writeup culture one or the other so I said two things happened in 2004 the other thing that happened in 2004 was a new product came out called rightly rightly was a predecessor to
Google Docs and all of a sudden we had Jeff telling us to do writeups and we had a new product that allowed us to co-write with each other totally magical experience and it had one really
interesting feature that everybody took for granted it had a right-hand rail where we could all add comments and we could sort of talk with each other that way so we had a uh event we were talking
about this process uh with Colin and a few other people and one of the folks asked this question said felt that it feels like the most important decisions in our company are jammed into the 100 pixel panel hanging off the side of a
Google doc is that really the best we can do and this led to a really interesting conversation about what's wrong with that and so we came with a few different
things first one we said is um you send out your doc and what does everybody do you watch the avatars at the top and the CEO comes in wanders around
your document and then leaves what the hell does that mean so we have one problem first comments have a you need to actually
leave them um another problem you get to the review and you're ready to go through the discussion so what do you do you go through them in order the comments and the first one says hey you
made a spelling mistake here second one says this I don't like the grammar here third one says do you really think it's a good idea I think maybe we should cancel this project and you kind of work through these things in clearly the
wrong order to have your discussion but the most important thing is while you're talking and going through all these comments there's a slack thread in the background where people are asking is it are they really serious about this we're really
going to do this this a or or maybe it's a great idea but all of that's happening outside of this discussion so is there a better way um so I'm going to tell you a
little bit about a ritual we do at Kota and if you were to ask a sakota employees about our golden ritual they would almost certainly tell you about this uh we sometimes refer to as two-way write-ups sometimes get shortened a Dory
pulse it's a pretty simple idea you send out a writeup um the the driver of the meeting will add a done reading button different points in the document just to make sure you're there and keeping up then rather than blurting out questions
or going through them in comment order we add them to a table we vote them up and down we call that Dory it's name for the fish who ask all the questions but the most important part of the ritual is this thing in the middle we call Pulse
and pulse is where we ask everybody to go on the record on your view on this discussion I'm supportive I'm not supportive uh and here's why and we do one specific thing is we have a little
toggle at the top where we hide everybody else's uh pulses until everybody's done writing it's how we remove group think so if you asked the code employee on the first Friday about our golden ritual they would almost certainly tell
you about this one not because they're meeting wonks they'll tell you about this one because it's reflective of our culture I'll hear them talking to their friends and they'll say oh yeah I joined this company Koda they have this value great ideas can come from anywhere and
they really mean it I was in this meeting and my topic outvoted the CEOs I don't know why out voting the CEO is a big deal but apparently it's a big deal and they'll say got asked my opinion on this topic and I actually got to write
it down in a thoughtful way and it wasn't performative and it got incorporated into the discussion and Koda really means it with this with this culture so this is our golden ritual but it's reflective of our culture it also
happens to be one of the most copied rituals in the Koda library and so I've seen many other ways that people have adapted it and I wrote a little piece about it um about a year ago called 14
ways to Dory pulse where I selected the variations that we've seen at other companies each of which are tuned to what their company does so I'll give you
a few quick examples so at Zoom uh they have a decision-making process they call root cause reasoning comes right from Eric uh rather than Ian questions he's very focused on make sure you get to the
root cause of a question not just to proximal problems and they built it into their template how do you get to the RCR the root cause reasoning at coinbase I had an interesting conversation with
Sergey who was CPO there at the time and he saw all the stuff about Dory pulse he says that's the opposite of our culture we're not doing democracy here we're not voting things up and down we we need to make it one clear decider and decide
what we're going to do he said but I really like the idea that everybody has to write it down and we don't waste a bunch of time talking about it and so they ended up taking a version of this and doing it a little bit differently where they took their version of pulse
and they use Rapid there and they just took every person's opinion but they clearly indicated who's recommended agree perform so on at the bottom is the decider and that's the one that really matters
uh one back from YouTube one of the problems we had at YouTube was uh we would sit down to do our planning we called it Big Rock Planning and inevitably everybody would ask for resources for their project it's a very
natural thing to do so we started doing a different ritual there we called $100 voting a simple idea everybody you need to be pretend you're in charge of YouTube and you allocate $100 across all
the projects and all of a sudden we saw people take off their team hat and put on their company hat and changed how we thought about our decision-making uh another one from this
is from David Singleton at stripe um when I asked him about the rituals there he said well the secret to Y stripe has 59s of reliability is a ritual they call spin the wheel and it started with a
operational reviews where they used to come in and they would look at all the outages for the week and they would say uh go through them in order of the you know the most severe ones to the least severe ones and instead of doing that
they said everybody prepare but we're going to spin a wheel and we're randomly going to pick who who whose outage we're going to talk about and it was meant to send a message that if you really want to have 59s of reliability you can't do
it by just worrying about the big problems you have to worry about the small ones too and they end up taking that same idea and applying it in all sorts of other rituals they do at stripe spin the wheel all right one last one is from
zapier uh I love zapier rituals I I think um Wade and that team I think is zappier as the OG distributed uh distributed team company uh they did it
before anybody thought remote teams were cool and so they developed a whole set of rituals around that one of which was something they call silent time so they get into a meeting and they have everybody write what they're working on
how they're thinking about something and then they're supposed to go read what everybody else thinks but what actually happens is everybody spends time writing and no time reading and so they ended up adapting this ritual a little bit
differently and saying we're going to have a very specific phase where everybody writes and then we're going to take everybody's uh topics and and they added a little button there so you could mark them red and we're not starting until everybody has worked their way
through their feed of everybody else's pulses uh and mark them red all right those are a bunch of different examples if any of those resonate with you that's great but the real point is to take your culture and
your decision process and make sure they match what are you trying to get done what are you trying to emphasize and find the right ones that matches your culture all right ready for topic number
three um so you've got the right decision process now we got to put it in the right Forum uh lots of great rituals I've seen for this um a couple really famous ones Pixar runs a ritual called
Brain Trust you know as a side note Pixar's uh uh if you read the book creativity Inc they'll talk about a lot of their rituals the first 11 movies at Pixar were all nominated for Academy
Awards and they credit it mostly to their review process they call Brain Trust um another one is from Netflix they call their product reviews their Gladiator meetings uh they're held in a room that's the picture of the room
there that literally looks like a four around Gladiators so lots of different ways I've seen people run their decision forums but one question I love to ask people is how many standing attendees
are in your decision-mak meeting and as we start talking about people will say well I have decision making me meeting and it's got you know the eight people on executive staff so well actually that
one it's grown it now has 20 people well actually the real one where decisions get made has 60 standing meeting standing attendees I have a
provocative a plea for all of you no standing attendees in your decision-making meeting and if that seems impractical hopefully I'll show you one way you can think about
it so first off what's wrong with uh um sing attendees in your decision-making meeting well first you start off you have all these people there three people care about the topic that's being
discussed but you have to discuss it one Topic at a time everyone else is either unnecessary or Worse disruptive so we had a different idea
for how to do this we call this Catalyst and the core idea is to go from a single-threaded meeting to a multi-threaded meeting here's how it works um at Kota
we block everyone's calendar from 1 to 2 P.M every day of the week you're not supposed to schedule anything over this time we call that Catalyst there's a doc you go in and you schedule this is the topic I need you
fill in the stage it's at and you fill in who you need and we've outlined the roles it's kind of our version of DAC or rapid but we use our terms for it for example you'll see that it's called Brain Trust that's our version of how to
uh pull forward what we loved about the Pixar uh culture and then one very uh important thing happens uh every one of those things generates a unique calendar
invite on the calendar with just that set of people with that topic as the title and that may seem like a small thing but it end up being the hack that really makes this whole thing work there's also another step where it goes
and generates a set of slack notifications and these are B meant to reinforce behaviors so you'll get a a notice saying you're invited for this review this is your role and here's a principle of what you should remember
about what that role means here you put all those things together and you change the process completely we used to have the single threaded meeting you get through topics one at a time and all of a sudden we started paralyzing
them and I did the math on it we used to get through something like five or six topics a week we now get through an average week we get through 50 decisions it also has some uh other
interesting benefits one of which is you can use this to get rid of the meeting all together maybe we can do it async so we added a new little piece of it where
you get the slack reminder saying you're invited to this Catalyst and you can go mark it to say it's default async and what that means is everybody gets a notice saying please fill out your
Dorian pulse before this time and then assuming that all goes well another message will go out saying great news all the feedbacks been received the driver of the meeting has decided uh we no longer need the meeting and all of a
sudden the meeting becomes a forcing function instead of an obligation so those are a few different examples you might take the Pixar Brain Trust model or the Netflix Gladiator
model the coda Catalyst model but the key thing is does your decision Forum accelerate or decelerate your decision-making process all right one last one so you've
got a great forum who do you invite and more specifically do you have to invite the founder to everything so um I'm going to tell you about a
different ritual and then come back to uh this one um so this is a ritual from dares I mentioned earlier called flash tags and dares as a Founder had this observation that whenever he gave
feedback people would often misinterpret it they didn't know sometimes he meant it as a small thing sometimes he meant it as a big thing and he decided to take all his feedback and add a little
hashtag to it and he published this guide of how to interpret his Hashtags with a kind of funny analogy about dying on a hill he said if I say # FYI it
means I don't even see a hill and if I say # plea it means dying on a hill is not on my bucket list but if it were this would be a really good candidate and he started adding this to try to indicate severity of whatever his
feedback was so first off we took this ritual and we started adding it to a number of our other uh templates you you add feedback you fill out in addition to the feedback you add your flashtag of
how serious uh you feel about it but what we noticed was that it Al often happen too late and at that point you come in and you say # plea and the team
is already ready to ship and it just seems like the feedback is the wrong part of the process so our marketing team came out with this idea and they called proactive flash tags it's a pretty simple idea we built a list of
decisions we're trying to make and we added four columns that kind of map to those four flash tags says I don't need to be involved just let me know the decision I'd like to give input or I may
have strong opinions and the idea is all the stakeholders are supposed to come and you're supposed to pre- indicate where you're likely to be on this topic and one of the nice Parts about it is the implications are really obvious so
if I come in and say I don't need to be involved that means don't invite me to the Catalyst I don't need to hear anything about it if I say I may have strong opinions that means not only do you need to invite me to the Catalyst
you need to invite me to the Catalyst at the beginning of the process so that you can hear something about what my strong opinions would be and not be surprised later on now one problem with this is you get you need to actually get your
stakeholders to engage and fill this thing out and so the way we handled that was we put it everywhere so we took it there's a central decision tracker in our company Hub but we then linked it
into basically every other spot the exec staff meeting has a list of the upcoming decisions where we pause and make sure people fill in the ones where they haven't indicated every team sync meeting has the same thing even down to
one-on ones where you'd say here's the list of upcoming decisions and ones where you haven't indicated where you're likely to be on the stakeholder list it totally changed how we thought about
who to invite to each of our forums so as you think about it uh there's lots of different ways to do this but it's one thing to have a great way to answer ask questions in the structured decision-making process in a
great Forum but if you don't have the right people none of it works and so how do you find a scalable way to find the right decision stakeholders for every decision all right so these are the four steps so as you think about your
decision- making process think about all four parts of these how are you encourag encouraging people to ask the right question what is the actual process for making decision is it reflective of your
culture do you have a scalable way for your decision Forum to accelerate progress instead of decelerating progress and how do people figure out who the right decision stakeholders are
for their Pro for their problems uh everything I talked about here um uh is publish
codh 2024 um that also has uh links to all the different uh rituals if you want to take any of those um but it also has a link to what I call the rituals Brain
Trust and I'd love to invite you if you're thinking about this topic go join that and contribute a ritual or take ones from others and help all of the community improve their decision-making
process that's it for today thank you