A lot of the people in my circles
may have spent hundreds of millions
of dollars to try to arrange a life that
they enjoy, and it doesn't fucking work.
What is holding people back?
It's the fact that they have emotions
that they are not sitting, feeling,
or expressing. Whatever emotion
that you're trying to avoid,
you are inviting into your life in exactly
the way that you're trying to avoid it.
What the hell? Why would... Why does
this... You have this really amazing
insight. The voice in your head
is often telling you bullshit.
What most people try to do is they try to
stop it, and that doesn't work very well.
I think the best way to work with the voice in
the head is to pick an experiment every day and
respond to the voice in the head in a new way
every day. One of my favorite responses is,
"Oh, I see that you're really scared. Don't
worry. I'm right here with you. I got you."
You're really big on helping people feel joy.
It's such an important tool
for productivity. If you say,
I'm going to figure out how to enjoy what
I do 10% more and you succeed, you are 10%
more efficient. Not only that, usually, the
quality is going to get a lot better too.
Is there just one thing you recommend that
basically everyone try to experiment with?
Yeah, it'll change your life
dramatically really quickly.
Today, my guest is Joe Hudson. Joe is one of the
most sought-after executive coaches amongst tech
leaders and has worked with folks from OpenAI,
SpaceX, Apple, and other world-class companies.
Joe's unique approach to coaching draws from
his spiritual, psychological, and neurological
practices. In his intimate courses that he
runs a few times a year, and in his podcast,
he helps people create the life that they want
with enjoyment and ease. In our conversation,
Joe shares the two things that he finds most often
keep people stuck in their life and in their job,
and how to work on getting these things
unstuck. Why the critical voice in your
head is always wrong, contradictory, and
telling you bullshit, and how to build a
different relationship with that voice.
Why falling in love with your emotions is
so important and so powerful. Why you'd be
better off focusing on what you want versus
what you think you should do or think that you
need to do, plus a bunch of amazing advice on
how to make better decisions, help your team run
more effectively, and why a seven-minute daily
gratitude practice will change your life. This
episode is basically for every single person.
It will make your life and your work better. If
you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting
app or YouTube. It's the best way to avoid
missing feature episodes and helps the podcast
tremendously. With that, I bring you Joe Hudson.
Joe, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Oh, thanks. Good to be here.
It's good to have you. I'm curious if there's
any common themes that emerge often in terms of
what is holding people back from success
or just living the life that they want,
especially ambitious tech people, which I know
is a lot of the folks that you work with. Are
there archetypes of like, here's the thing,
often come up most often and hold people back?
A nonspecific answer to that would be a critical
voice in their head and a relationship with
that critical voice that is not productive.
Oftentimes, the critical voice in the head says,
"You need me to be productive," but it's usually
a huge detriment to being able to really be
successful. Even if you are successful with a
really critical voice in your head, you never get
to enjoy it. You might have the money, but then
you're like, "Oh, shit, I'm still miserable." Or,
"I got the car, I got the house, I got the money,
I got the successful career, and why am I unhappy
all the time?" That would be, I would say one
of the biggest ones. Another really big one
that in a large category I would say is their
relationship with emotions is all fakata. They
are either trying to pretend they don't have them
or compartmentalizing them or trying to manage
them rather than harnessing them and falling
in love with them. That would be a big place.
This episode is brought to you by BuildBetter.ai.
Back in 2020 when AI was just a toy, BuildBetter
bet that it could cut down on a product team's
operational BS. Fast forward to today, 23,000
product teams use purpose-built AI in BuildBetter
every day. First, BuildBetter uses custom models
to turn unstructured data, like product and sales
calls, support tickets, internal communications,
and surveys into structured insights. It's like
having a dedicated data science team. Second,
BuildBetter runs those structured insights into
workflows, like weekly reports about customer
issues, context-aware PRDs and user research
documents with citations. It even turns standups
into action items that automatically get assigned
and shared into your tools. Plus, with unlimited
seat pricing on all plans, BuildBetter ensures
everyone at your company has access to this
knowledge. Truly, no data silos. In a world of AI
demos over-promising and under-delivering, see why
BuildBetter has a 93% subscription retention, yet
a personalized demo and use code LENNY for $100
credit if you sign up now at buildBetter.ai/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by WorkOS. If
you're building a SaaS app, at some point your
customers will start asking for enterprise
features like SAML authentication and SCIM
provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in,
making it fast and painless to add enterprise
features to your app. Their APIs are easy to
understand so that you can ship quickly and
get back to building other features. Today,
hundreds of companies are already powered
by WorkOS, including ones you probably know,
like Vercel, Webflow and Loom. WorkOS also
recently acquired Warrant, the fine-grained
authorization service. Warrant's product is
based on a groundbreaking authorization system
called Zanzibar, which was originally designed
for Google to power Google Docs and YouTube.
This enables fast authorization checks at enormous
scale while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases.
If you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features like
single sign-on SCIM or user management, you should
consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in replacement
for Auth0 and supports up to one million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
workos.com to learn more. That's workos.com. These
are awesome. Okay, so the voice in your head, you
have this really amazing insight that I heard on
one of your podcast episodes that the voice in
your head is often wrong, often contradictory,
often telling you, and that your advice is to
learn how to work very differently with this
voice in your head, which a lot of people just
assume, oh, that's just like what it is. It's
telling me how it's trying to help me, but it
turns out it's not. Can you talk about that?
I would say every single time the voice in
your head is wrong. That critical voice in
your head. To be specific, I'm talking about the
voice in your head that is critical and repeats.
There's the voice that says the same thing
over and over again. You got to work out more,
you got to work out more, you got to work out
more. Whatever that is, it's always wrong,
and that doesn't mean there isn't truth to what it
says, but it's incorrect. As an example of this,
you should work out more, you should work out
more, you should work out more, or you need me
or you just sit around on the couch as a great
example of one. If I was your boss and I was
sitting right next to you and I was criticizing
you every couple of minutes, there's no way that
you would say, "Wow, I really need you. I couldn't
be productive without you." It's a bunch of crap.
Or you should work out, you should work out.
I see the truth that I'd be healthier if I work
out. I get that. Should I? Is it really a should?
There's another question. What makes it not say,
"Oh, hey, why don't you enjoy working out?
How do we get you to enjoy working out? What
would motivate you to work?" It's not doing
any of that. It's, "You should work out,
you should work out." It's never an accurate
thing that's happening inside of your head.
Until you can see through that, it's hard to
work with the voice in your head. You can do it,
but until you see through it. The second part that
I would say is that if you want to work with the
voice in your head a new way, what most people try
to do is they try to stop it. They try to control
the voice in the head, and that doesn't work very
well. Instead, I say, change the way that you
relate to the negative voice in your head.
Instead of being, "Okay, stop doing that,
stop doing that." Say, "Oh, I see that you're
really scared and I'm right here with you." Or
sing a musical to it or just go, "Eh, I don't
believe you." As a matter of fact, I think the
best way to work with the voice in the head is
to pick an experiment every day and respond to
the voice in the head in a new way every day
to have an experimental approach and say,
"Oh, what's the relationship I want with this
negative voice in my head?" Because right now,
what it's typically doing for most people is
that it says something and the person's like,
"Yeah." Or, "Yeah, but I'm not going
to do that, so fuck off." Or, "Yeah,
that'll never work." Something like that is the
response. What happens if you change the response
to the voice in your head? That gives you a crap
ton of freedom, and it's the beginning of what can
be a state where the negative voice in the head
disappears, which is really, really quite lovely.
Oh, wow. I love this so much because there's
so much that comes from this thing in your
head just shooting you down or scaring you
about stuff. It's so hard. I hear this,
but it's so hard. Next time I'm, I don't know,
giving a big presentation, I'm going to hear like,
"Oh, something could go wrong. You could
look really stupid or you could totally
forget what you're saying." It's hard to really
intellectualize, okay, I don't have to listen
to this. Is there anything more there just how
to turn that around and be like, just shut up?
The shut up usually doesn't work.
Experiment with all of it. To me,
one of my favorite responses is, "Oh, I see
that you're really scared. Don't worry. I'm
right here with you. I got you." Because
part of the deal is that the voice in the
head has assumed the position that it's
like the boss, but it's really a little
kid having a temper tantrum. If you listen to
it, if you just dictated everything it said,
it sounds like usually like a five-year-old
having a temper tantrum, or it sounds like
the way your mom used to chastise you or the
way your dad used to chastise you or whatever,
a teacher. It isn't, it's not logical, it's not
thoughtful, it's typically not thoughtful, it's
usually abusive. It's a lot of fear. It's one of
my favorites, one of my favorite ways to respond.
I've tried, I mean, gosh, dozens of ways,
and there's a lot of neat effective ways. I
particularly think it's really good to set up a
series of experiments rather than just take the
one that I have because the experimental mindset
means that you can never really fail. Typically,
somebody, like worse with the voice in
the head, they fail and they go, "Ah,
fuck it." Because we have this part of our brain
called the habenula, and the habenula basically is
the part of our brain that is trying to teach
us not to fail over and over again. It's the
thing that when you go on a diet or you go to work
out and then you don't do it one day and you say,
"Ah, fuck it, I messed up," and then you
don't try anymore or you don't try for a
couple of weeks or whatever, that's basically
what's happening in that part of the brain.
If you do it as an experimental thing, then
you can't lose, you're just learning about
yourself. You're learning about the voice in
your head. The way I like thinking about that is
people are like, "I understand the problem,
but I don't have a solution." I'm always like,
"If you understood the problem, there would be
no question about the solution." If you fully
understand the problem, you know the solution.
All you have to do is really fully understand
the voice in your head through a series of
experiments and the whole thing goes away.
The advice here is next time you're hearing
something in your head that you don't think
is going to be helpful to you is try to respond to
it in a different way from what you've been doing.
I would be even more subtle than that, which is I
really wouldn't care if you think it's helpful to
you or not. I would just experiment with different
ways of interacting with it. I wouldn't even do it
as a goal of, okay, I want the voice in the
head to be nicer to me. I would do it with
the goal of just, hey, how do I learn? How do I
understand this thing? It's a far more productive
self-development. Generally, it's far more
productive to learn, say about the river valley
by walking through it, putting your feet in the
river, going down the river with a canoe, smelling
the soil, looking at the plants, than it is to
say, "Okay, I am going to dam this river valley
and try to..." You're not going to understand it
the same way. You're going to make some mistakes.
Amazing. The second bucket that you shared of
what you find most often is the root of what's
holding people back is the way you described
is your relationship with your emotions,
which I don't think a lot of people
would think of as the thing that's
holding them back. Can you talk a
bit more about what that looks like?
Yeah, a great way to explain it. For
the logical folks, so in 2012 or so,
there was a person who wrote a book called
Descartes' Error, and in Descartes' Error,
the whole idea is that I think therefore I am, and
this person's like, "Yeah, that's the error." It's
a neuroscientist who looked at people who had
damage in the emotional center of their brain,
and they just basically ceased to be able to
make decisions. Their IQ would stay the same,
but it would take them half an hour to decide
where to have lunch or decide what color pen
to use. It would take hours and hours to make
simple decisions, so their IQ would stay high,
but their entire life would completely fall apart.
What it tells us, and this is not exact, I'm
paraphrasing for a podcast, but we make decisions
in the emotional center of our brain. We use logic
to try to figure out how we're going to feel.
You can see this just by asking yourself the
question, how many decisions have you made to
feel like a success or to not feel like a failure
or to feel happier, to not feel trapped? There's
these huge buckets of emotions that we are trying
to feel and not feel, and we're making decisions
based on those. There's no such thing as a logical
decision. That idea is like, I'm just going to
be logical and just make a logical decision, it
doesn't. Neurologically, it's just untrue. If you
learn to fall in love with all of your emotions,
then solution sets become available that you
didn't have before. If you are like, "Oh,
I can't feel like a failure." Well, then you're
probably not going to take certain risks. If you
are, "Oh, I want to feel loved and I can't feel
unliked by people." Well, then you're not going
to say your truth, and then the world is going to
not give you the things that are truthful to you.
I go into my boss, I say my truth, I get fired.
Okay, I get fired, but then probably my next boss,
I say my truth, I'm going to find a location where
my truth is and how I want to be in the world
is going to be acceptable. If I don't do that,
if I'm constantly managing myself, then I'm not
going to have that reality. It's really important,
just for the decision-making part, how important
emotions are to be able to fall in love with each
of the emotional experiences so you're not making
decisions based on your inability to feel stuff.
That's like one, there's literally a thousand
others. Most people, they feel stuck. They can
have a big emotional release and they don't feel
stuck anymore. When people feel overwhelmed, it's
usually not the amount of crap that they have
going on in their life. It's the fact that they
have emotions that they are not sitting, feeling
or expressing. That's another huge chunk of stuff.
Depression is usually unmoved anger, is another
example. There's so many levels in which people
not able to feel really limits their life. Just
one that's like almost everybody can relate to is
feeling excitement is something that most people
can only do for about 10 to 20 seconds. Most
people aren't like, "Oh, I'm excited." If you
walked into a Denny's and there was this person,
a 60-year-old man and just excited and was
excited for 10 minutes, you'd be like, "What's
wrong with this person?" When we're excited,
it's contagious. I walk into a meeting and
I'm excited, probably other people are going
to walk out excited. We're limiting just our
ability to create collaboration by the fact
that we're limited by our excitement. I could go
on forever. There's so many experiences like this.
What I'm hearing is the core issues, we're not
able to feel our emotion, but there's something
there, like we are angry or scared. Because we
can't feel it, we just can't break through that.
Not quite. If you have somebody who's experienced
a lot of emotional abuse in their life,
then they might not be able to feel the emotions
that they're having, and particularly where
you experienced the emotional abuse. That
might be the case for them. For instance,
if you had physical abuse and I put a quarter
in one of your hands and a key in another one
of your hands without telling you which was
which, you wouldn't be able to tell me if you'd
suffered enough physical abuse because you've
literally cut that sensation off. Similarly,
people who've experienced emotional abuse can
often not tell what the emotions are. Now,
emotional abuse is, it's a big word. Generally,
people don't even like equating the two.
Just to agree on terms here, when I
say emotional abuse, I mean you were
told that you weren't allowed to have a certain
emotion. That's what I mean by emotional abuse.
Maybe you got fed every time you got angry or
you got your love removed, or you got punished,
or maybe every time you cried, you were made fun
of. My particular background was that. It's when
you weren't allowed to feel certain emotions,
you were told to cut it off because it wasn't
going to be safe because you're either going
to get bribed out of it or punished out of it,
or loved removed because of it or made fun of or
whatever it is. That might be a step that one has
to take, but the place you want to get to is
where the emotions are fluid, where it just
moves right through you. It doesn't mean that you
lose control. As a matter of fact, losing control
means that there's still resistance in it.
The way I think about this is that emotions
are like a tube, let's say, and there's water
moving through the tube. You kink a tube one way,
the water comes out a little funny. Kink the
tube the other way, it comes a little funny.
Let's say you have anger and that's the tube
of, and you kink it one way and it's like,
"You son of a bitch. You blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah." You kink get another way and it's like,
"Nice dress. You crank it another way and it's
guilt. It's like, "Why would you ever do that
to me?" Then if it's unkinked, then it's like
Gandhi or Martin Luther king. It's this very
loving boundary that's set. It's this clarity of
purpose. That's how I think about it. The idea is
to get to fluidity, to unkink the hose so that all
of the emotional experiences come out with love.
I did a meditation retreat, a 10-day silent
meditation retreat, which I know is a big part
of your practice and something that led to the
work you do now. A term that's coming up for me is
non-judgmental awareness. Basically, experiencing
the thing you're feeling and just letting it go,
not attaching to it, not judging it. Is that
along the lines of stuff you'd recommend?
Yeah, it's definitely a huge part of it. There's
a couple of things that I noticed get in the way,
or the translation gets in the way there. One is
it's like, think about emotions as like kids in
your house. If a kid came into your house and
you're like, "I will be non-judgmentally aware
of you." You're probably going to get a very
different response from the kid than if you're
like, "Oh, I'm so excited to see you. I welcome
you in my house." The emotions feel different if
you're like, "I am non-judgmentally aware of this
emotion," or, "Oh, cool. Oh cool, I'm sad. This is
fantastic." If you have that welcoming invitation.
One of the quotes that I'm most famous for is joy
is the matriarch of a family of emotions and she
won't come into a house where her children aren't
welcome. A very joyful life is a life where
all the other emotions are deeply welcomed,
not accepted, not non-judgmentally aware
of. I think those are really great steps,
don't get me wrong. If you can be in
non-judgmental awareness of an emotion, fantastic.
The other thing that's a little bit different
about what you said is that emotions do need to
be felt. If you stop feeling an emotion, you have
to constrict your muscles. I can watch somebody
come in, come up for one of my coaching rapid
coaching sessions. By the crease in their eyebrow,
I can know that there's repressed anger. By the
hunch in their shoulders, I can tell you about the
critical parent that they had. The body takes on
a shape that's based on the emotions that you've
been taught to hold. You don't just by sitting
there, well, it's not entirely true, if you
just sit there and feel them in that way without
the full expression, they will move eventually,
but it might take a couple of decades.
You can actually just move them. You can
actually make the sound, move your body. All
mammals do it. Like mammals releasing fear,
they all shake. It's part of how we exist. That's
also a really big part of emotional fluidity. It's
not just being still and feeling them, it's
letting the muscles move, making the sounds.
For someone that wants to get better
at the skill of feeling emotions,
being more in touch with emotions,
helping their emotions be more fluid.
I know this is a lifelong practice and not
something you would just hear on a podcast,
okay, I've installed this. Is there anything
tactically you can recommend to a listener
of just like, here's something you could do
this week that'll help you, along these lines?
We have a free audio on our website called
Emotional Inquiry, and that would be the easiest
way that I would, that's a really good entry
level first step into emotional fluidity. The
bigger problem is that every step has a different
thing. If you're in the not aware of emotions,
then that step may not be the right step for you.
Though, if you are aware two or three emotions and
you can do emotional inquiry, usually, it'll
open up a lot of the other ones. There might
be a point where you really need expression,
and so emotional inquiry is not going to work.
Just generally, the emotional inquiry practice
is a really good one. What it is, is imagine
you're a little kid and you pick up a toad.
You're going to pick it up, you're going to
look at it, you're going to feel it, you're going
to smell it. Some little kids are even going to
lick it a little bit. They're going to really want
to explore this toad, and that's what emotional
inquiry is, is a somatic mental experiencing of
an emotional experience in your body and what
is it like and what happens when you welcome it.
What happens when you love it. What happens when
you resist it. It's a series of experiments that
you're playing with the emotion and observations
and felt sense of the emotion, and that I find
to be incredibly, incredibly useful for people.
Just getting very curious.
Yeah, a lot of wonder.
By the way, the quote you shared about joy
being the matriarchy of all the other emotions,
imagine people have said this, but inside out too,
I think is exactly a representation of what
you're talking about, where joy is actually,
she's like the protagonist almost.
I don't know if you've seen it yet.
I think I've heard about
this. I haven't watched it,
but I think where you think it's
all about being happy and you find
out that you have to accept everything
for happiness to really work, kind of.
Exactly.
Yeah, I have heard about it.
Anxiety takes over, and then things don't go
well. Something else that I've noticed listening
to a bunch of your conversations, you do these
lightning round coaching sessions with people,
and so I listen to a bunch of them.
Something that was really interesting
to me is that a lot of people come
to you and they're like, "Hey,
I have this problem. I can't do this
hard thing I know I need to do." Or,
"I have imposter syndrome just keeping me from
doing this thing I need to do." you're often like,
"No, that's not actually what's going on here. I
can see that's not a problem for you. It's really
this other thing." Is that super common where
people think they need to work on this one thing,
and it turns out that's not at all, they're
actually okay at that and something totally else?
I'd maybe put it a little bit differently.
They're living in a story that describes an old
version of themselves or they don't see themselves
clearly enough to be able to see the whole issue,
and so they're just kind of living with a story
that's in the past. That's a really common thing.
Oftentimes, if I do that in a coaching session,
typically it's because they're showing me right
there that it's not true. Somebody's like,
"I'm so scared, I can't do anything." I'm like,
"You just got in front of a hundred people
to ask me a question. Clearly, you're not
so scared that you can't do anything, so I'm
not buying it." I don't do it quite like that,
I do it with a lot more love than that.
Oftentimes, I see that people's stories are
a culprit, like how they describe themselves.
A great way that you can really see this in
folks is that nine out of 10 times that you
compliment somebody, I really appreciate this
thing about you, they're going to go, "Nah." Or,
"Well, my sister is even more." Or, "If you knew
me." They're going to do some sort of version like
that. It basically is one of the indicators that
they can't actually feel who they are. They would
rather, in effect, call you a liar. You're lying
to me or you're wrong than they would to actually
accept the experience of being seen in that way.
It does a couple of things. One of the things it
does is it stops people from seeing themselves
clearly. The other thing it does is it makes
people forever want to be seen and complimented
and acknowledged and validated because they're
getting the food, but they can't digest it.
Do you have any advice other than
working with you and you telling them,
"Hey, here's actually going on," for
someone to like, okay, maybe revisit,
maybe this isn't actually a problem
to see what's actually going on?
We have a set of five kind of what we think
are foundational tools for transformation,
and we do these free workshops on them, and
one of them is question the assumption. That's
a really great way to have people start to see
through their stories. At the beginning, I said,
"Nothing in the critical voice in your head says
is true." This is how it applies, so typically,
there's an assumption that you have to make for
the problem to be real. If somebody says to you,
for instance, if somebody comes to me and
says, "I am an asshole to my girlfriend."
That's their problem. One, you have to assume that
the girlfriend doesn't want you to be an asshole,
as an example. Two, you have to assume that you
know what being an asshole actually is. It's
not just what your mom told you an asshole was.
Three, there's some validation, there's another
assumption, there's some clear thing that says
this in the world. Everyone's like, that's an
asshole and that's not, rather than what actually
happens in the world, which is 50% of the people
think that this person is an asshole and 50% think
they're a hero. It's something like that. Also,
another assumption there is that the problem is
that you're an asshole, instead of that you're
resisting the fact that you are an asshole,
and therefore, it comes out sideways instead
of really clear. There's so many assumptions
in there. If you see through those assumptions,
usually the problem starts fading away.
It's like, "Oh, okay, what do I mean by asshole,
exactly? How do I define that?" It seems
like a silly thing when I am using this
example of asshole. I remember this moment
in my own development, I was in Bodega Bay,
out of all places, and this very good
friend of mine at the time was like,
"Joe, you're an asshole." I was like, "No, I'm
not." He's like, "Why resist it? Just fall in
love with the fact that you're an asshole. Just
allow yourself to be an asshole for just a minute,
just one minute." I stopped, and I thought of
like, I was doing venture capital at the time,
and I could think of all the things that I
had done that somebody would call an asshole,
and all the ways in which I was unattuned
to people, and I could, "Oh, yeah, okay,
I can totally see that I'm an asshole."
In that scene, not only in the scene of it,
but as the shame fell away, oh, this is nothing
I have to defend. This isn't something that I'm a
bad person because of, I don't need to be ashamed
of it. This is just some actions that I took.
As that faded away, then and then over the next
couple weeks, lo and behold, I became less of an
asshole. It's a strange thing when you really grok
that, that it's often shame that holds bad habits
in place. Is it a problem that I'm an asshole,
or is the problem that I'm ashamed of being an
asshole? Is the problem that you're a smoker,
is the problem that you're ashamed of being
a smoker? Typically, there's so many assumptions
built into everything that we call a problem, and
if we look through those assumptions, the problems
disappear. As in this case, it disappeared for me.
Wow, okay. There's a lot there. It connects
to something I know you recently talked about,
which is the emotion we want to avoid
is the thing we end up experiencing a
lot by trying to avoid it. What's going on there?
Since I'm coach executives, let's do an executive
example, so conflict avoidant executive. I don't
want to feel the out of control in this that
I do when people argue. I don't want to feel
that level of out of control, so I am going
to be conflict avoidant. I'm going to avoid
conflict. Every way that we go to avoid a feeling,
becomes the way that, that feeling gets invited
towards us. We all know what it's like to work
for a conflict-avoidant CEO or a boss, people
get really fucking upset. Eventually, people
get really upset. Decisions aren't being made.
There's all this tension. It's never relieved.
Then wow, sure enough, the conflict-avoidant
CEO is dealing with a whole organization that's
tense and they feel completely out of control and
the fact that they can't do anything about,
so that's an example. Or when I was younger,
it was emotional abandonment. My dad was an
alcoholic, and I didn't want to feel that
emotional abandonment again, and so I would
get really hard when I felt like people were
leaving me, I'd be like, "What the dah,
dah, dah, dah, dah?" Which of course,
made them abandon me quicker, or I would try to
caretaker people, which would build resentment,
which would make people abandon me. Whatever
emotion that you're trying to avoid,
you are inviting into your life in exactly
the way that you're trying to avoid it.
What the hell? Why does this happen?
That doesn't sound right.
This is counterproductive.
It is counterproductive. I think that the really
cool thing about it is you can look at any issue
that you're having in your life, so you can say,
oh, one of the problems that I have in my life is
that I am constantly in an argument with my
girlfriend or boyfriend, let's say. What is
the thing that you don't want to feel in that
argument? I don't want to feel ashamed. You're
getting in arguments because you don't want to
feel ashamed, and that's making you feel more
ashamed. What am I doing at that first time to
not feel ashamed? I'm defending myself. Oh, and
me defending myself is actually the thing that's
starting the fight. You can backward engineer it
to, oh, I don't want to feel ashamed, therefore
I'm going to defend myself, which creates
the fight, which makes me feel more ashamed.
Any problem that you're having, you can actually
backwards engineer it and see, oh, I can solve
that problem by just being okay with that feeling.
God damn it, you didn't take out the trash. Oh,
that's a shame I don't want to feel. I'm not going
to defend myself. I'm going to feel that shame.
Oh, yeah, then maybe I'm going to say I'm sorry
I didn't take out the trash, or I'm going to
say, I don't feel ashamed, I don't want to take
out the trash. I have to defend myself to get in
the fight, and then I'm going to feel ashamed.
You can reverse engineer all your problems
this way. It's like it's such a cool hack,
but it's very hard. For somehow or another, it's
very simple, but very hard for people to utilize.
This is amazing. The advice is basically feel
the thing and just come to terms with this
is the emotion I'm feeling, and maybe, like an
example, the asshole. Well, maybe I'm an asshole.
It's what's required for you to love and
accept yourself would be, and love and accept
the emotion that you're having in the moment
instead of resist it. There's that saying,
what we resist persists. How do you
fall in love with and stop resisting
the reality on the ground? In doing so,
it changes the reality on the ground.
In this argument with your supposed girlfriend,
say you disagree about her perspective on what's
going on. I guess that's not the root issue
here. It's your feeling, it's not her perception.
Hey, sweetheart, I really hear you want me to
take out the trash, and that's not my truth.
That's going to be very different than defending
that shame. The defending the shame is going to
be like, no, it's not my job to take out the
chat. You're trying not to feel the experience,
which is what's going to do it. The response
isn't the important thing. It's really where
the response comes from. It's so interesting
because people are taught constantly, this is
something we teach in the connection courses
that it's really not about the conversation,
it's about where you're at in the conversation.
For instance, when my friend said to me, "Hey,
you're a dick." Here's what he didn't do, he's
like, he didn't go, "You're a dick. You asshole.
You're being an asshole. You're being a
dick. Fucking stop it." He was like, "Eh,
you're a dick, so what? What's the problem?"
He was coming from a place of love for me,
and so I could not be defended in my response
to him. It's really where you come from.
It's the emotionally where you come from, that's
the important part. Not as much what you say.
You can see this, a perfect example of this is,
this happens all the time in my work. Let's say
there's a person who has a CEO and the person is
scared of their CEO. Let's say this is the CMO,
and they're, "I'm scared of the CEO. I can't say
my truth. They're always getting upset. They're
going to yell, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah." I'll say, yeah, there's one person
who says it though. The answer is always yes.
That CEO has one person who they don't yell at,
who they listen to, who they'll take the objection
from, that they don't get angry with. It's because
there's somebody who doesn't approach them in
fear. It's because somebody approaches them a
different way. Not with judgment, but like, "Hey,
look, this is what we have to pay attention to."
It's really about how you're coming at
it and not what you're saying typically.
This episode is brought to you by Coda. I use
Coda every day to coordinate my podcasting
and newsletter workflows. From collecting
questions for guests to storing all my
research to managing my newsletter content
calendar, Coda is my go-to app and has been
for years. Coda combines the best of documents,
spreadsheets, and apps to help me get more done,
and Coda can help your team to stay aligned and
ship faster by managing your planning cycle in
just one location, set and measure OKRs with
full visibility across teams and stakeholders,
map dependencies, create progress
visualizations, and identify risk areas.
You can also access hundreds of pressure-tested
templates for everything from roadmap strategy
to final decision-making frameworks. See for
yourself why companies like DoorDash, Figma,
and Qualtrics run on Coda. Take advantage
of this special limited time offer just for
startups. Head over to coda.io/lenny and sign up
to get six free months of the team plan. That's
coda.io/lenny to sign up and get six months of
the team plan. Coda.io/lenny. This is amazing,
Joe. I'm very happy with what advice we've already
shared and there's more I want to tap into.
You keep using the word advice, and I just
want to, so for anybody who's listening,
do not take my advice. Do not, do not, do not.
Test it. Experiment. Set up an experiment, try it
out. See if it's true for you. It's one, I just
made this shit up. Somebody else could make up
something different. It's like Jeff Bezos made up
Amazon. We make stuff up, but we're humans. Two,
is if you instead of just listen to it as a
soundbite, if you actually do it and make an
experiment out of it, you get to learn. It's in
your bones. You get to see what's actually real
for you. What's real for you in this moment
might not be real for you what's in the next
moment. For instance, I could give the advice that
says, hey, you can't even control your thoughts.
You can't even decide what thought you
are going to have next is, it's just
going to fucking happen. you're completely out of
control, and so it's all a gift. Can you look at
life as all a gift? Wow, that could be really
useful for one person, but the other person,
they feel so disempowered that they're like, "I
can't even control my own thoughts. Man, I am
totally trapped." They might really need at that
moment to learn that, "Oh, I have empowerment,
I have choice." That's the advice that they need
to hear. Do the experiment, find out what's true
for you in this moment. If there's a piece
of advice, that's the one I want to give.
let's share more experiments people can
run. Another is this thread that I feel
comes up a lot in your work is you're
just really big on helping people feel
joy. Feels like that's the core of what
you're trying to help people is feel more
joy. Why is that so important? Why
is joy so important, so powerful?
I definitely would not want anyone to feel joy. I
wouldn't want to push somebody into or like, "Hey,
you should feel joy." What I would say that's a
close cousin to that is that enjoyment is such an
important tool for productivity. Enjoyment is such
an important tool for living a meaningful life.
Enjoyment is an amazing tool. As an example, let's
say you drive a Ferrari, you're not going to say,
hey, that's an efficient car. That's a
super-efficient car. You're going to say,
no, that's a fast car. Somehow in our own
lives, if we get something done quickly,
we're efficient, but that's not efficient. You
can go and get something done quickly and then
you're so exhausted. What's efficient is if at the
end of whatever you did, you feel like you have
more energy, like you're stoked, like, oh, I can't
wait to do this again tomorrow. That's efficiency,
is that you've actually used the least amount
of energy to get something done. If you say, oh,
I'm going to figure out how to enjoy what I do 10%
more and you succeed, you are 10% more efficient.
Not only that, usually, the quality is going to
get a lot better too. If you enjoy running, you're
probably going to run more than if you don't enjoy
running. If you enjoy doing a podcast, you're
probably going to make a better podcast and you're
going to do it for longer if you enjoy doing
it. There's something really, really important
about enjoyment because it's not only a measure
of efficiency, it also has a strong correlation
with hire in most things has a strong correlation
with how long you're going to do it, your staying
power, the quality of what you're going to do, all
of that. That's one of the reasons that I think
enjoyment is really great. The other thing is that
if you enjoy things, they feel different. I think
one of the things that people do is they say this,
they say, "I want to enjoy my life more, so I'm
going to do less things, take out the trash, and
I'm going to do more things like go on vacation."
That's not how enjoyment works. You can enjoy
taking out the trash or you can hate taking
out the trash. That's a choice. Right now,
somebody listening to this as an experiment that
they can run is like, okay, you're going to stay
listening to this for the next minute. How do you
enjoy it 10% more? Typically, what will happen is
somebody will take a deeper breath, they'll settle
into their body a little bit more, they'll relax
a little bit more. They might physically get more
comfortable. There's a thousand things that they
might do to just enjoy the experience 10% more.
That, and in that, they're becoming more efficient
in that the quality is getting better in that
they're hearing what I'm saying differently.
It's just a really powerful tool. What I know
the problem to be is that some people will go,
"Okay, now I have to enjoy life. I'm going
to disregard all these negative emotions so
that I'm in enjoyment." That doesn't work. It's
horrendous. It's just a recipe for shit stew.
Along these lines, how much of the work
is learning to enjoy the thing you're
doing more versus finding something that you
innately enjoy? Which one is more powerful?
I guess, which do you point people to? Which
experiments do you find people should run more?
In our society, typically, it's how to enjoy what
you're doing more. What happens typically is that
if you find a way to enjoy the thing that
you're doing more, you're more likely to do
the things that you enjoy. It's just an order of
operations thing. As compared to there's people,
a lot of the people in my circles because of who
I coach and everything, they're billionaires and
they have spent hundreds of millions of dollars to
try to arrange life that they enjoy and it doesn't
fucking work. They actually have more power
to make everything that they're doing exactly
what they want to do, but that doesn't work.
Flying the jet or buying the island or blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, doesn't do it.
Whereas if you really learn to enjoy
what's in front of you, all of a sudden,
one thing that happens is that you're
not as scared of enjoyment. You start saying,
"Oh, wow, enjoyment makes me really effective,
and so I'm want to do the things that I enjoy."
You're more likely to do the things that you
enjoy. Instead of having this story, I have to do
X, Y, and Z so that at one point in the future,
I can do what I enjoy. It's just an order of
operations things. If you learn to enjoy the
things that you're doing, you're going to
naturally start doing the things you enjoy.
If you only do the things you enjoy, you will not
learn how to enjoy what you're doing very well.
You show this tip of how can I enjoy
this 10% more? Just ask yourself,
how can I enjoy this 10% more?
Yes, right now.
Is there anything else that you
find helpful for helping? Yeah,
right now, how can I enjoy this 10% right now?
That's right. It's not about changing
anything in the external world.
Got it. Internally, what can I do? What can
I change about the way I'm experiencing this?
Yeah. I like to ask it as how do you enjoy it
10% more, because if it's what can I change,
then there's trying, trying is usually not
more enjoyment. It's actually usually letting
go of trying that creates more enjoyment. The
phrasing can really make or break the question.
Enjoy it 10% more. Say someone's sitting in a
boring meeting that's really sucking their soul,
look, they should ask themselves this
question, how can I enjoy this 10% more?
Well, should, they can. They
get to, it's a great experiment.
It's an experiment. Okay, perfect.
The reason I do the should thing is that as
soon as you say you should and then you don't
then you can fail. If you fail, then you're less
likely to try it again. That's why the should,
it ends up usually in stagnation. If you think
about the way it feels in your body when you say,
I should do something, and there's a
stagnation, there's a, hmm. whereas
if you say something like, oh, I want to
do it, or here's an experiment I can do,
or here's what I enjoy, there's less
stagnation, there's more movement.
This touches on something else that you talk a
lot about, and we've been circling around this
idea of authenticity versus improvement, where you
help people realize that you are good as you are,
you don't need to necessarily improve. We've
talked a lot about these sorts of things already,
but just what else can you share there
just how to help people learn this?
My favorite metaphor on this one is at what time
in the journey of an oak tree is it perfect? Is it
when it's an acorn, when it's sprout, when it's 20
years old, 40 years old, 150 years old, 200 years
old, depending on the oak tree? Now, I'm perfect.
The idea is ridiculous. It's a similar thing for
us. The idea that I need to improve myself, it
really disturbs the natural process that's at
hand, which is we evolve. We as human beings
evolve. If it's like, oh, I'm evolving and I
can enjoy it, and I'm acting from my authenticity,
then that has a lot of alacrity. That moves quick.
If it's I need to improve, there's something
wrong with me, I need to improve, I should do it,
that all goes really fucking slow. Because
there's a lot of emotional stagnation in that.
There's a lot of should shame. There's a lot of
stagnation in that, and so you don't actually get
that natural flow of life. The Taoist talk about
this as kind of like a river always finds its way,
it just always goes in that direction. We are
naturally evolving. That is our nature. Then
to put a whole bunch of shoulds and shits
in the way just slows the process down.
The other thing about authenticity that I think
is really important too, is that if you are one
of the few people, I'd say 10, 15%, who can say,
I should be this way, this way, and this way,
and then you do it, which is very few people can
actually do that. What most people do is they say,
I should do this, should do that, should do that,
and then a decade later, they're still saying they
should do the same things. Let's say you're one
of those really successful people, then you have a
life for not you. Then you have a life of who you
think you should be, not for who you actually are.
If you move from authenticity, naturally, certain
things aren't going to work, certain things are
going to work. Certain people are going to work,
certain people aren't going to work. Certain jobs
are going to work. The ones that you end up with
over time are going to be the ones that are right
for you, not right, for who you think you should
be. The most obvious of this is you meet a woman
and you're like, oh, this is how I should be for
them to love me, and you just do it. You just
do everything that you think you should do, and
then you get married, and then they love not you,
they love who you think you should be. They don't
love who you are. What kind of marriage is that?
As opposed to, this is who I am and I'm going to
be as genuine. I'm going to show you all my parts.
I'm going to be as genuine as I can with you. Then
if you do get married, you're married to the right
person, you're married to the person who actually
sees all that and loves that and wants that.
How do you hold that idea with
I also want to get better,
I want to develop myself, I want to feel
my emotions more, those sorts of things?
I love that I want to, the better part is kind of
just, gets a little bit in the way. We all want
to, like a little kid wants to run faster. They
might want to be a better runner, but the part
that they missed, the reason that they develop
so fucking quickly is because they don't think
they're going to be a better person if they run
faster. The idea is like, yeah, you have this
natural want, that want is the thing that moves
evolution. A plant is like, "Oh, there's sun. I
want to move in that direction." As compared
to I should. Both of them are human concepts,
but the want, it's the thing that what allows
us to know that's our evolutionary path. Oh, I
have this want to be closer to people. Oh, I have
this want for great sex. Oh, I have this want for
being able to have a business that supports me.
These are great wants, and they show where the
growth is occurring or wants to occur. It's like
that's our natural evolution. It's great. What
makes it need to be better? I want to be better.
It just slows it down instead of, it's like saying
that what I am is broken and therefore, the whole
thing slows down. We try to word everything as
more in the experimental framework, but also,
we try to word everything as self-awareness,
self-experimentation, self-discovery, instead of
self-improvement. Because if you understand the
problem, then the problem goes away. Just explore
it. Just understand it as compared to making a
list of things that you should do to get better,
that you will eventually fail and then you'll
just be stuck in this should loop where you beat
yourself up and where most people hang out a lot.
The experiment here that I'm taking away is
think more about your want versus the should,
and then things you think you need is okay.
Because typically, when you say, I want to
improve, it means the subtext in that is
once I do X, Y, and Z, then I'm lovable. Once
I do X, Y and Z, then I'm okay. Once I do X,
Y and Z, I'll be worthy. Once I do X, Y and
Z, I'll be enlightened, whatever the fuck,
the thing is. That's just not how it works. What
works is the person who loves themselves has
loving relationships. It's not the person who's
done X, Y, and Z so that they can be lovable,
has loving relationships. The people who do X, Y
and Z, so they can be lovable have relationships
where people are critical and constantly
telling them that they have to be better.
Coming back, you just said this
interesting quote that you also
shared at the beginning. This idea, once
we understand the problem, it goes away.
Yeah.
Let's make sure people understand what that means.
Is it related to this idea once you feel like I'm
an asshole, okay, and then like, oh, okay, and
then it starts to kind of away, is that the core?
I just mean practically. It's like, can
you really fully understand a problem if
you don't understand the solution to it? There's
a principle, and I can't remember the name of it,
like it's Strickland principle or something.
It's something that this CFO that I used to
work with said, and he would say, "Problems
get solved if you spend time on them. If you
just give enough attention to a problem, the
problem will solve." That's the way it works
in business. An unsolvable problem, obviously,
it's not going to work that way. The reason that,
that works is because the more you spend time
on a problem, the more you understand it.
Another one, love him or hate him, one of
the things that Elon Musk has said that I
found it very valuable in my time, is that
if you really want to interview somebody
and they claim that they've done something,
you ask them six levels down. You improved
sales. How did you do that, exactly? Well,
we improved the pipeline. How'd you do that,
exactly? Oh, well, we made the pipeline more
measurable by having things that could be. How
did you know? What were the seven stages of the
pipeline and what made you pick them? You go six
levels down and you can really understand if
somebody was the person who solved the problem
or if they're the person who is claiming that
they solved the problem. It's the same thing.
If we just explore a problem enough, the solution
is apparent. If we understand the problem enough,
the solution is apparent. Typically, if we
come to a problem with a kid's mind, wonder,
if we come to it, what could I learn here? What's
exciting? What are the experiments I can run?
Then typically, that's the most efficient way,
enjoyable way to solve a problem as compared to,
I have to get to this problem by this time
and we're going to do it this way. Usually,
that doesn't work. I could geek out on why that
lets democracies win over autocracies because
they're far more experimental by nature, and
it's not one person saying how things are going,
but just generally, just we're more efficient
when we're exploring. We're more efficient when
we're exploring ourselves and understanding
ourselves and trying to improve ourselves.
There's a couple of more experiments I want to
help people try to run. One is you have some
really good advice around decision-making and how
emotions and getting better at understanding and
working with your emotions helps you make
better decisions. Can you talk about that?
That's similar to what I said before, which is
if you learn to fall in love with the emotional
experiences, then you have more solution sets.
Let's say I want to have all human beings, I
want to be a part of a great team. Nobody has ever
raised their hand and said, "I'd like to be a part
of a team." Yet, grand majority of people at their
work right now have shitty teams or not A teams,
not great teams, even though nobody wants that.
If one of the things you're unwilling to feel is
that conflict, that tension, as we talked about if
you're conflict avoidant, you're not going to be
able to make an A team because there's nothing
that is alive doesn't require tension. A cell
requires tension. Breathing requires tension.
Playing pickleball requires tension. A good team
requires tension. If you're going to avoid that
experience, you're not going to be as easily,
if at all, be able to create a quality team.
To be able to look forward to any emotional
experience, creates more and more solution sets
for more and more optionality. In creating a
great team, for instance, you need to be good
with people hating you. You need to be good
with drawing boundaries and having people
upset. You need to be able to have high
expectations. You have to be okay with somebody
being disappointed with themselves. You have to be
okay being disappointed with yourself. All these
emotional experiences have to be available to you
if you're going to find the solutions to make an
A quality team. The more you can fall in love with
each emotional experience, the more you have and
then the clearer the decision making gets. That's
one thing for making great decisions. The other
one that I find really, really useful and very
hard to execute on until you really understand
it is creating a set of principles to live by.
We all have a set of principles to live by
that we're doing it. For a lot of people, those
principles are what do I have to do to get likes
on Facebook? I'm going to make a decision based
on getting likes on Facebook. I'm going to make
decisions based on whatever it is. Pretending that
I want to get wealthy or trying to get wealthy or
there's a series of things. If you really take a
look at what it is you're making your decisions
on and then really think about, well, what
would be the five or six things that if I made
decisions with these principles, I'm guaranteed
success? Then experiment with them and then
refine those principles and then experiment
with them. Then there'll be these moments where
you don't want to do it, but those are your
principles, so you're going to go and do it.
As an example for this, one of the principles
that I live by is embrace intensity. It's not
create intensity, it's embrace intensity. It
means that right now, any moment in my body, for
instance, there's going to be a sensation that's
more intense. How do I welcome that sensation? At
any moment in running my business, there's going
to be something that we don't want to talk about.
How do we lean in and talk about that? We start
all of our meetings with what are you scared
to say in our business? What are you scared
to say? Not all of our meetings, but some of our
meetings are started with what are you scared to
say? Because we want to embrace that intensity
because we know that if we lean into the thing
that we're trying to avoid, our life is going to
get better, our business is going to get better.
If you can see what those principles are for you,
and then run experiments to see if they work and
then refine them every once in a while. Because
of that embrace intensity, if somebody comes to me
and says, "You're fucking up this business. You're
doing it all wrong." I don't have to think about
what I'm going to do. I'm like, "Oh, cool. Tell
me what I'm missing." It's going to be immediate
because I live this way. Maybe I don't
want to hear it. Maybe I'm having a bad
day. Whatever it is. Maybe I'll say, "Hey,
I want hear you give me, I'm not able to,
give me a day and I'll come back to you." all of
a sudden, my decisions get made automatically if I
live by a set of principles and very effective, I
find very effective living by a set of principles
For someone that wants to create their own set of
principles. Is there a guide you have? Is there
any advice for how to actually go about
starting this list, putting it together?
We have a decisions course, which is a large
part of it is about how to do that. It's a
difficult one to explain because there's a
lot of nuance in it. Just as for instance,
one of the nuances is defining the
principles, not just by what it is,
but what it isn't is a really significant,
very minor thing, but it ends up being
incredibly major. If you're going to do your set
of principles and you want to do them on your own,
the main thing I would say is keep it to
five. I wouldn't even do six. I don't do six,
but I keep it to five. I would test
each one of them for five days.
Make your principle and then see if it
works for you for five days and then keep
on experimenting until you find five. When you
look at those five and you say, "If I do that,
if I live by those principles, I am just almost a
hundred, if not a hundred percent confident that,
that's going to create the life I want if
I live by those principles." Then you have
a really good start and make them simple. Mine
are things like embrace intensity or connection
first or everything is in iteration. As soon
as I live by them, things work, company works.
Amazing. We'll point folks to that course
if they want to take it themselves. Cool.
It's only once a year, so it's a rare one.
Oh, wow. When is the next one?
January.
Okay. Not too far away for folks to want to
wait. Again, the two pieces of advice you shared,
and that's our experiments that we can run
to help become better decision makers. One
is create a list of life principles, and
there's a course that will point people to,
to take that. The other is the thing you keep
coming back to over and over and over, this idea
of falling in love with your emotions, embracing
your emotions, welcoming your emotions. There's
also, I know you do a lot of work with teams. I
imagine there's very similar advice for how to
help your team be more effective. Principles,
I imagine is a part of it, falling in love.
We've run principles for teams, yeah. That's one
of them. Teams would be more effective. We have
a lot of, I mean I think I have, at this point,
I have 12 things that I'll go into a company and
do with a company. Typically, the way I like
to do it is I will go in and I'll talk to the
leader typically and they'll say, "This is what
I want." Then I really want to assess. Typically,
if the person who is a big part of creating the
problem has a hard time seeing the way through
the problem, or it wouldn't have been created
generally. This is not demeaning any leader,
we all have these issues. Usually, what I
like to do is I like to go in and I like
to talk to three or four people, see what their
perspective, not just the leader's perspective.
Then I like to sit in a meeting or two and just
see actually what the dynamic is. One of the
things I like to say about how to change a company
is that the atomic structure of a company is the
meetings and the decisions. It's particularly true
in Silicon Valley, but it's really true in all
businesses that all we are as a company is a group
of people's relationships and ideas. Especially,
like Amazon, you got a couple of buildings and
some servers. There's not a lot of hardware there,
and they wouldn't be useful without the people
anyways. Anybody, whether you're running a farm
or a shoe factory or anybody's successful is
going to tell you it's all about the people.
The atomic structure is what are our meetings like
and how do we make decisions? I'll just really pay
attention to a meeting. One of the things we do
is we talk about what we call five-star meetings,
which is how do you make every meeting enjoyable?
Literally, how is it that everybody when they walk
out of a meeting, they're like, oh,
fuck, that was great? It turns out,
we've all been in meetings that are hard as shit,
and we've walked out and gone, oh, those are
great meetings. We've all been in meetings where
nothing happens and we're like, "Oh, God. Fuck,
another one to just drive a nail through my head.
I don't want to sit there." What's required to
make one of your meetings five stars? If you
do that, that's one of the things we'll do
inside of a company is work with them to figure
that out. If you do that, every single problem
with your company will come to the surface. Every
single one of them. I had ten five -tar meetings,
but these two meetings sucked. That tells me
exactly where we need to focus as a company.
That tells me exactly where to look for the
problem that's happening. It's the same thing
with decisions. If you really start unpacking how
the decisions are made where people are frustrated
in the decision-making process, you're going
to find exactly the problems in the company. An
example of this, I was working with a friend and
he's a content person, and we were just talking
about how do you make every one of your meetings
a five-star meeting? He's like, "Okay, great."
He's like, "Yeah, I'm never going to do this."
I was like, "Really? Tell me why." He's, "My
YouTube meetings fucking suck." That's not where
he makes most of his money, but these YouTube
meetings suck. They're never going to get better.
Luckily, there's a couple other people around at
the time and everyone's like, "No, wait, I
love my YouTube meetings. What do you mean?
How could this not work for you?" He noticed,
oh, the team didn't, the content, none of it
was working for him. None of it was him. He was
just like, "Ugh." He changed it. He was like,
"Okay, I'm going to commit to that. I'm going
to see what it's like for me to just say every
one of my YouTube meetings have to be something
that's super enjoyable to me." When he did it,
his YouTube numbers went off the charts in
a very short period of time. It's just that
common. Wherever the meeting is that sucks, it
means there's something else that's a problem
that needs to be worked on. That's typically
how. I can just look at, usually sit in any
team meeting and see at least three or four of the
major problems that are happening in the company.
Such a cool way of thinking about where to
focus decision-making meetings. I love that
the story comes back to something you shared
earlier with the more you enjoy something,
the more joy there is, the better
it's going to go anyway. The more
you can find those moments and
make things enjoyable, the better.
The other cool thing is most of the executives or
the CEOs that I've worked with, when they get to a
point, and it usually takes them like, we always
have the goal of a month, it usually takes two
months to make sure every one of their meetings
is five-star meetings. Once they've done that,
then it's like, how do you make sure all of
your teams have five-star meetings? Usually,
it's like within two months and they usually have
half the amount of meetings at the end of it.
Half the amount of meetings in their companies
are more effective. It's an incredible tool.
I could see why people enjoy that if
you were meeting as well. Is there
anything more along those lines before
we start to close out our conversation,
either around teams or decision-making?
I'll say for anybody who's running a
team, Harvard has got a couple of these,
but we used to do these tiny pulses. As a VC,
one of the strategies that was really effective
that I saw very few VCs doing was I would want
these pulse, I would like to read the pulse of
teams with these short surveys and stuff. It
was the most effective way of not very happy,
didn't want to come to work on Monday. They
weren't going to make their numbers. The
likelihood of them making their numbers is
going down. There was this interesting thing
that just about how Drucker, I think
said it first and then the Virgin guy.
Branson?
Branson said it. He's like, "Culture eats strategy
for breakfast," or some such. If that's true, then
it's measurable and it can be a leading indicator,
and it absolutely is. If you really pay attention
to the culture on a team-by-team basis, it's an
amazing, very effective way to drive results,
but also, a very effective way to know when bad
results are coming. What's interesting to me is
most people feel like they can't control
the culture, like most people feel like.
Most people, I notice, they feel like, it's more
likely for me to hear from a CEO, "God damn it,
everybody agrees when I get out of the table.
When I get off the table, everyone's like, yeah,
we're going to do it. Then they don't do it.
Why aren't they doing it?" I'm going to hear
that more often than I'm going to hear a CEO
say, "Oh, wow. I really noticed that the way
the email system was working in our company,
we were disempowering people by not requiring
an action after every..." I'm going to hear more
complaints about why shit isn't working than I'm
going to hear about strategies, like very gentle,
simple strategies to change the culture. it's
an amazing thing to me that it's so powerful
and yet people feel so out of control with it
To give people something they can do,
say today or tomorrow to work on a lot
of these things we've been talking
about. Is there just one thing you
recommend that basically everyone should
try to experiment with in the next day,
couple of days or weeks, just to help them
be better and more successful and happier?
I would do seven minutes, no less than seven
minutes. You can do more than seven minutes.
Seven minutes of gratitude with another person
every day. It can't be, I'm grateful for this,
I'm grateful for this, I'm grateful for this. It
has to be feeling the gratitude and then seeing
what comes out of your mouth when you're coming
from the felt sense of gratitude and doing it
back and forth. You're savoring the experience
of gratitude and you're going back and forth
with another human being. Call mom, dad, sister,
brother, business partner, friend, and every day
just express gratitude back and forth for seven
minutes, coming from the feeling, not from the
thought. If you have a full body sensation of
gratitude and you experience that for seven
minutes a day, it'll change your life dramatically
really quickly. Really, really quickly.
Wow. I already feel it. The practice is you are
expressing gratitude to the person you're with.
It can be gratitude for anything in your life. As
a matter of fact, I would say do it for a couple
of weeks and then do it on the places where you
feel lack. That's where the superpower comes in.
In my own personal life, I was meditating. I spent
seven, eight hours a day meditating for years.
That's a lot of hours.
You can imagine, I didn't have a lot of
money. The joke I used to make is I would
meditate and worry about money most of my
day. It's funny, but it's truth. One day,
I was thinking about money and thinking I
was driving in my car and I was thinking
about this billionaire I knew and I was thinking
about how I didn't have enough and then I thought,
"Oh, this billionaire doesn't think they have
enough either. I know I'm well enough." I'm like,
"Oh, I have the experience of a billionaire right
now." I was like, "He's probably driving in a car
somewhere thinking he doesn't have enough, and
I'm driving in a car somewhere thinking I don't
have enough. This is great. I'm a billionaire."
It tickled me, the idea tickled me. Then I was
like, well, what happens if I start focusing
on everything I do have instead of focusing on
what I don't have? Which is where the gratitude
practice came from. My wife and I would sit every
day and just be grateful for all the physical
stuff that we had. We were living in a hobble,
were living 15-year-old year cars. We had no
money. I was in debt. I was in, I think $40,000
in credit card debt or some crazy shit. We just
did it. Literally, was it three months later,
my credit card debt was gone. Six months later,
I had $60,000 in the bank. Entire life changed
because I no longer defined myself by somebody
who didn't have, I defined myself as somebody
who did have. All of a sudden, I could look out
the window and it wasn't, "Oh, shit, I can't have
that. I can't have that. I can't have that."
I look out the window, I'd say somebody made
money on that. Somebody made money on that. Every
fucking thing I looked at, somebody made money on.
20 people, 20 companies made money on the
fucking lamppost. The person who installed it,
the energy company, the rubber company, there's
just, holy crap, it's all over the place. Then
in that definition, all of a sudden, it became
really clear. It doesn't matter if the thing
that you feel like you lack is time, or the
thing that you feel like you lack is love or
the thing that you feel like you lack is
money. If you can really do a gratitude
practice on the thing that you lack, there's
a superpower in that one, changes everything.
Do you still do this?
I do gratitude, yes. Do I do
gratitude on stuff I lack? I
don't really have an experience
of lack. That's not really...
You still do this gratitude, seven minutes?
Of course, yes. That's like asking if I still have
sex. Why would I give that up? It feels great.
Just to be clear, you find someone seven
minutes every morning, probably think
about things you're grateful for and share
back. Focus not on your intellectual thing
you're grateful for, but just what's
coming out of your emotional body.
Feel the gratitude.
Yeah, then gratitude.
Let the feeling of gratitude speak rather than
your mind, so that you get the felt sense of it.
Joe, I'm incredibly grateful for you. I really
appreciate you sharing so many experiments for
people to run. I think this is going to
make a real impact on a lot of people's
lives. Two final questions. Where can folks
find your courses? I know you have a podcast.
Where can folks find the stuff they do online,
and then how can listeners be useful to you?
First of all, Art of Accomplishment, the podcast,
it's Art of Accomplishment with Brett Kistler and
Joe Hudson, I think. Then Art of Accomplishment,
the website will show you where all the courses
are. It'll give you a whole bunch of experiments
you can run. There's all sorts of really great
information there. The other thing that we just
mentioned also is just that we really want to
make sure that you think that the courses
are for you. The way we do courses is that
it's a very felt experience thing. It's not
intellectual at all. It's really in your
body. The way we like doing it is that you bring
real problems that you're having and you use the
tools that we teach you. The foundational course
for that is called the Connection Course. If you
want to get into it, go to the Connection Course.
To find out if it's right for you, if you're not
already know that it's right for you, we do these
little hour and a half free workshops and it'll
give you a taste of what it is that we do because
it's like anything that's going on out there. It's
people doing, they're like, "What the hell was
that?" It's just a completely different thing.
It's not like learning in the normal way. You
literally sit down with another person and run
experiments face-to-face with how you're being
in the moment. You learn all this stuff through
direct experimentation. If you find out it's right
for you, you can do it through these workshops,
and I'm sure there'll be a place where
they can find out where to go for that.
There's one coming up in September, I believe.
The Connection Course is coming up
in September. It's a great place
to start. It's foundational
for everything else we do.
Then how can listeners be useful to you?
I want my children to grow up in a
fantastic world. The best way that,
that can happen is that if the people listening
to this discover who they are and their nature and
the truth of how they operate. Not for them,
but for their children and their children's
children. You want to do me a favor and
make my daughter's world a better place.
I also just had a son, and so
I totally resonate with that.
Yeah.
Joe, thank you so much for being here. What an
amazing podcast episode. This
ended up being as I expected.
Pleasure. Thanks for having
me. Appreciate it, Lenny.
Bye, everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.