Why are so many people bad at strategy?
What's taught now in business schools generally
sucks. People aren't prepared educationally,
and they sure don't get prepared for
it in companies. It's intellectually
challenging and it's emotionally intimidating.
You have something you call
the strategy choice cascade.
You have to have answers to five questions.
What's your winning aspiration? Where to play?
How can you win? What capabilities do you have
to have that your competitors don't? And then,
what enabling management systems do you
have to put in place? For the most part,
in the leading business schools,
it's illegal to teach that.
Playing to win, you talked about,
and there's kind of these two routes.
You have to be either differentiated or low cost,
there's no way to protect yourself
if you're not one of those two.
Is there anything else you wanted
to just leave listeners with?
I have never met this mythical
beast called a great natural
strategist. Great strategists have all
one thing in common, they just practice.
Today, my guest is Roger Martin. Roger is one
of the world's most trusted strategy advisors.
He's professor emeritus at the Rotman School
of Management, at the University of Toronto,
where he served as dean for five years. In
2013, he was named Global Dean of the Year,
and in 2017 he was named the world's number one
management thinker by Thinkers50. He's also the
author of what many listeners consider their
favorite book on strategy, called, Playing to
Win. I've gotten a lot of requests to get Roger on
this podcast, and I can now see why. This is the
most tactical and fascinating conversation I've
had on this podcast about developing a strategy,
and that is a really high bar.
We delve into the five questions
that you need to answer to help you craft your
strategy. How Hamilton Helmer, Michael Porter,
and Richard Rumelt's work fits into his framework
and worldview, what people most often get wrong
when they're developing their own strategy, the
two options you have for how to win with your
strategy, a very tactical and simple trick for
getting started, thinking through your strategy,
and so much more. This episode is for anyone
who is trying to build their strategic thinking
muscle. If you enjoy this podcast, don't
forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app, or YouTube, it's the
best way to avoid missing future episodes,
and it helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you Roger Martin.
Roger, thank you so much for being
here, and welcome to the podcast.
It's great to be here,
Lenny, thanks for having me.
What I want to try to do with our time
together is to help people that are on
the ground at a company, say, like the product
manager, designer, engineer, data scientists,
folks that aren't necessarily the CO, or
the founder or exec at company get better
at product strategy. At crafting
a strategy, evaluating strategy,
developing a strategy. Because it feels like
there's always tons of advice for the leaders
of a company, but less for people on the
ground doing the thing. And I feel like,
luckily, your stuff applies to everyone.
So, how does that sound as a lens for-
That sounds great, and can I tell
us a little story to that end?
Please.
So, recently there was a newspaper article saying
that, pointing out that 10% of the S&P 500 CEOs,
10% are ex Proctor and Gamble people. It's
an amazing number, like a stunningly high,
high number. Why would that possibly be? I believe
it's because at Procter and Gamble there is a view
that people way down the organization, like let's
just say the head and shoulders brand franchise
leader, who reports to the head of shampoos and
conditioners, who reports to the head of beauty
care, who reports to the CEO, so at least four
levels down in the organization, in the guts of
the organization, Proctor understands that that
individual, not the CEO, not the global president
of beauty care, not the head of haircare, not
the head of shampoos and conditioners, the
brand manager makes super important strategic
choices, and if they don't make them well,
the brand does terribly. And so, I believe... And
not many companies have enough of that attitude.
So, I'm a big believer that people down
organization have to make really important
strategic choices or bad things are going
to happen, if they make really great ones,
good things are going to happen,
and they get trained to be a CEO
someday. So, I'm with your thesis. But yours
is counter, what I would say is normal. What is
most normal is people at the top do strategy,
and people down below do something, and it's
usually called execution, and I hate that, I hate
that term of art, for what it's worth. And so,
I think you and I are singing from a bit of the
same songbook, even if it's a minority songbook.
This episode is brought to you by Webflow. We're
all friends here, so let's be real for a second.
We all know that your website shouldn't be a
static asset, it should be a dynamic part of
your strategy that drives conversions. That's
business 101. But here's a number for you,
54% of leaders say web updates take too long.
That's over half of you listening right now.
That's where Webflow comes in. Their visual
first platform allows you to build, launch,
and optimize webpages fast. That means you can set
ambitious business goals and your site can rise to
the challenge. Learn how teams like Dropbox, IDEO,
and Orangetheory trust Webflow to achieve their
most ambitious goals today, at Webflow.com.
This episode is brought to you by Work os.
If you're building a SaaS app, at some point
your customers will start asking for enterprise
features, like SAML authentication, and SCIM
provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in,
making it fast and painless to add enterprise
features to your app. Their APIs are easy to
understand so that you can ship quickly and get
back to building other features. Today, hundreds
of companies are already powered by WorkOs,
including ones you probably know, like Vercel,
Webflow, and Loom. WorkOS also recently acquired
Warrant, the fine-grained authorization service.
Warrant's product is based on a groundbreaking
authorization system called Zanzibar, which was
originally designed for Google to power Google
Docs and YouTube. This enables fast authorization
checks at enormous scale, while maintaining a
flexible model that can be adapted to even the
most complex use cases. If you're currently
looking to build role-based access control,
or other enterprise features like single
sign-on, SCIM, or user management, you should
consider WorkOs. It's a drop-in replacement
for auth zero, and supports up to 1 million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
Workos.com to learn more. That's Workos.com.
I just want to ask this broad
question about strategy,
why is strategy so hard? Why are
so many people bad at strategy?
Perhaps the thing that makes it intellectually
hardest is that it is an integrative activity.
It answers to a bunch of questions that have to
fit together and reinforce one another. So, that
just makes it a little more complicated, it's not
like saying, Lenny, what do you want for lunch?
It's saying, Lenny, what kind of diet do you
want that'll keep you healthy? And that includes
breakfast, lunch, dinners, snacks, a whole bunch
of other things that you got to fit together. So,
it makes that harder to do intellectually. Another
aspect of it is, it is intimidating. Strategy
involves making choices to do some things and not
other things, and it is often intimidating to say,
oh dear, I have to cut these things off, and
not do them, and actually make a decision that
I'll be held accountable for potentially,
or I'll even hold myself accountable for.
So, that's a second thing. It's harder
emotionally, not harder intellectually.
And then, there's the training aspect of it, the
knowledge aspect of it, which is, what's taught
now in strategy in business schools generally
sucks. It's gone on a crazy theoretical bend,
the strategy academy as a whole has fallen in
love with a theory called the resource-based
theory of the firm, that silly and nobody uses it
out in the world. And so, students are no longer
trained on useful strategy. And the other feeder
into people learning strategy were the strategy
consulting firms, but the strategy consulting
firms, the so-called strategy consulting firms,
do almost no strategy anymore because it's
a little business compared to post-merger
integration, digital transformation, and a bunch
of other things. So, people aren't prepared
educationally for it, and if they're not prepared
educationally for it, then they sure don't get
prepared for it in companies. It's intellectually
challenging and it's emotionally intimidating.
On this point, you made about how
schools are teaching strategy wrong,
how do you describe what the wrong approach is?
It's a theory that's sort of taken over,
called the resource-based view of the firm,
that was... In the world of academics,
there's a weird place where the number
one emotion is jealousy, and people
were massively jealous of Mike Porter,
who created many of the most important
concepts of strategy when he wrote a book,
Competitive Strategy, in 1980. And so, they needed
to counter him because they just didn't like the
fact that he was so prominent, and they decided
they would say he was about positioning. So,
they called his the positioning school, and they
caricatured what he said, which he never did,
but they said he said it's all about finding
a place that is structurally attractive,
and then milking it for everything you can.
We at the resource-based view of the firm
think that strategy is all about building
resources. And if you build resources,
it's almost like if you build it, they will come.
And that's what you should pay attention to. Now,
the problem is, any resource that may be useful
somewhere is not necessarily useful elsewhere. So,
it begs the question, how would you think through
what resources to invest in building? What
would be a way of doing that, investing here,
versus here, versus here? It's silent on that
because it's a dumb theory, and it doesn't have
anything useful to say, in my view, about that.
And so, when the students go out and say to
their company, I'm going to do a VRIO analysis,
or a VRIN, some people just roll their eyes at
them, and so it doesn't get used. I've only seen
it used, I've been in consulting companies for 42
years, and I've seen it used once. And the trust,
as is usually the case, is that it's
both. And that's why the model I use
for strategies says a lot about where you play
is important, that's one of the key questions,
and your capabilities are important, and you've
got to link those things together. But that's,
for the most part in the leading business
schools, it's illegal to teach that.
Illegal to teach your approach.
Yes. I couldn't teach my approach
at my own business school.
What?
But when I was dean, the most powerful person,
the departments, or areas as we call it,
like strategic management is an area, they have
100% control over what's taught in strategic
management, in finance, et cetera. The dean
may be the most powerful person in the school,
and I happened to be a super successful dean,
so if anything, I was a super powerful dean,
and students would beg me, they'd say,
"Roger, you have 20 years of experience,
you're sort of a famous consultant in
strategy, and you've got these theories,
please teach a course in it." Nope. I did do
extracurricular stuff, where I had practice of
one Saturday a year, teaching everything I knew
to anybody who wanted to show up. But for credit,
I was not allowed. And if you try to get a job
at any business... The only exception might be
Harvard Business School, maybe. But if you took
the 49 other top business schools in America,
and if asked the question, do you swear
allegiance to the resource-based view of
the firm? If you don't answer an enthusiastic
yes, you have no chance of being hired, zero.
Wow. This academia drama, I had no idea.
A loyalty test.
This is unreal. Makes me even more excited to
dive into your world, and your ways of seeing
things. Before we do that, just we've had
a few other strategy people on the podcast,
it might be helpful to frame where they fit
in the spectrum that you're describing. So-
Oh, okay. I may not know all
of them, but you give me-
I imagine you do. So, we've had a Hamilton Helmer
on the podcast, and then Richard Rumelt on the
podcast. How do they relate, just for people
to get into your stuff versus this dogma?
So, one of them is an academic, and
one of them is a quasi-academic,
or non-academic, like me. I was a
tenured professor for many years,
but don't consider myself an academic guy. I don't
think Hamilton does, though I've never asked him-
He's an investor now.
... that question. Yeah. So, he's written
a very, I think, useful book that would in
some sense fit into my how to win box, right? I
say strategies about how to win, and he has a,
what I call, a categorical model. Here are
categories of things that you should think
about. If you're trying to win, here are
seven ways of winning, and I categorize
him as a non-academic practical strategy guy.
Richard Rumelt is a now retired Tuck professor,
and he is this hyper competition thing that he
does. He also is of the, I'm jealous of Mike
Porter kind of thing. So, I've got to say, Mike
Porter is wrong, and here's how I am so right,
and the competition doesn't take place in the way
Mike says, where it's really stable, and whatever,
it's really hyper competition, Mike Porter
never in his entire life has said competition
is stable, he's repeatedly said the opposite.
But in order to say I'm not like Mike Porter,
and in fact, I distinguish myself
by saying he's wrong, and I'm right,
and so... I don't know. He seemed like
a fine guy. I don't think that he,
like most business academics, he doesn't know
much about business. He hasn't gone out and
practiced a lot. He came to our school, and gave
a lecture because people loved hyper competition
because he would blast Mike Porter, and he
gave a example of Proctor and Gamble, I've
been consulting at Proctor and Gamble, and know
everything about Procter and Gamble, basically.
And what he said about Proctor and Gamble had
zero to do with reality, like zero. It was just
completely, utterly, absolutely wrong. And I asked
him afterwards, just sort of like, "Why do you say
that?" And he said, "Well, I think that's the way
it worked." Are you kidding me? So, I'm not a fan
of that piece of work. I would say it doesn't fit
nicely into research-based view of the firm versus
Mike Porter, it's sort of like, here's another
lens to take on the world, and I'm going to take
that lens, everything's hyper-competitive, and
here's how you think about hyper-competition.
This is fascinating. I love that we're spending
some time on this, this is really helpful to
hear the landscape of strategy minds.
Okay, let's dive into your worldview,
and maybe the simplest way is just, how do
you define strategy? What is a strategy?
Strategy is an integrated set of choices that
compels desired customer action. So, the way I
think about it is, there's a whole bunch of things
a company controls, how many factories to build,
how much R&D to do, in what areas, and how much
advertising to do, how many people to hire,
what to pay them, blah, blah, blah... Those
are all the things under our control. What,
Lenny, is the thing we have almost no
control over? What, if we're a company?
What customers do.
Yeah. We would like them to take some of
these out of their pocket and give them to us,
can we make them? No, we can't. So, essentially,
the job of strategy is to make decisions on the
things we do control that will compel, we can't
force, but it'll compel them. They'll say, gosh,
I should take my hard-earned cash, and whether
it's a company or an individual, I should take
my hard-earned cash and give it to you, rather
than give it to nobody, if there's no product now,
or give it to a competitive product. So,
the important pieces of it is integrated,
it's the whole set of choices that has that one
outcome, that it compels desired customer action.
Amazing. Okay. And to help
people define their strategy,
you have something you call the strategy
choice cascade, which is basically five
questions that you need to answer to help you
think trough strategy. Can you talk through this?
Yeah. And this is the fruits of many, many years
of doing strategy work, and trying to figure out,
how do you do this thing? Because the fun thing
was, I was in the era, I started in strategy in
1981, and that was early in the era, strategy
was born in 1963 with the founding of Boston
Consulting Group by Bruce Henderson, who was
the father of strategy in my view, of practical
commercial strategy. So, it was still in the early
days, and Bruce Henderson had a theory of how
strategy should... What result it should produce
for you. Mike Porter then came along in 1980,
so '63 Bruce Anderson, and '80 Porter, the two
most important figures in the history of strategy,
came along and said, a strategy has to look like
this. It has to have this as its output. But
neither of them was very good on, because again,
it was early, they can't do everything right away,
of, well, how would you get one of those?
So, Mike Porter says you have to be either
differentiated or low cost. Good. And if you look
through competitive strategy as landmark seminal
book, to say, how would you do that? There is no
answer. And because Monitor Company, the firm I
was one of the leaders of for a decade and a
half, was founded essentially to commercialize
Mike Porter's work, customers would ask us, they'd
say, well, we like Mike Porter, and we'd like to
have one of those. We can look at ourselves under
his framework, and we can say we're stuck in the
middle, and he said, that's bad, and he said, good
is this or this. How do we think through creating
one of those? We didn't actually have an answer.
And it turned out, because I was the most, I don't
know, intellectually engaged on this, and didn't
mind the hard work of product development from
about 1987, when we discovered we really didn't
know that, and clients really wanted us to tell
them that. Between 1987 and 1995, I did all this
work on, well, how could you develop a process
for getting yourself one of those, one of those
excellent strategies? And I came to the view that
you have to have answers to five questions. You
have to have an answer to the question of, what's
your winning aspiration? What are you trying
to accomplish? Because it'll help contextualize
the kinds of choices you could make. Then
there's a where to play, on what playing field,
or if you're like military stuff, battlefield,
are you going to plop yourself down on? You're
not going to play everywhere, in every product,
at every vertical stage around the world,
you're going to pick someplace, and in that place,
how can you be either better than competitors,
in terms of creating customer value,
or lower cost than those competitors?
To win there, where you've chosen to play to
meet your winning aspirations, what capabilities
do you have to have that your competitors don't,
that would enable you to win that way? And then,
what management systems, enabling management
systems, do you have to put in place to make
sure you build and maintain those must have
capabilities to win, where you've chosen to play,
to meet your winning aspiration? And so, I came to
the conclusion, actually it was in 1995, the end
of an eight-year journey, I came to the conclusion
those were the five, and you had to do them
together, and that is the essence of producing
a strategy that compels desired customer action.
I want to go through an example of a company,
but before we do that, something I think that's
important to talk about is, if your book is called
Playing to Win, you talked about this idea of you
need to play to win, and you argue that a lot
of people are just playing to play, they're
playing to play the game. I'm guessing most people
listening, and most people developing a strategy,
don't think they're doing that, they don't think
they're just playing to play the game. They think
they're playing to win. I'm curious what are
signs that you're not actually playing to win?
It would be mainly signs given to you by
customers. So, if you say, we're the most
innovative company in our industry, and
customers... And let's say the industry
distributes through a given channel, and customers
come into that channel and they look at the two
products and say, I could flip a coin on this
one, you are not effectively playing to win. Maybe
you thought you were winning, but customers don't
think you are better. Or if your competitor lowers
their price compared to your price, and you say
to yourself, oh my God, if we lowered our price,
we would make no money, but your competitor
keeps on pricing there, you may think you
have the low cost position, but they do, and you
have to give them whatever share they desire at
that lower price because you can't compete there.
So, you'll know you're playing to play if you're
not aiming to, and accomplishing, having either an
offer where Lenny walks into the store, whatever
kind of store it is, and says to the person in
the store, I want that brand. An example, Lego,
one of the companies I've worked with for a
long time, great company. It turns out that
if you do market research on kids, a store that
purports to be a toy store but that doesn't have
Lego is not a toy store. They would define it as
not a toy. Mom, why are we here? I wanted to go
to a toy store. And she said, but it says toys on
here. And the kids said, uh-huh. That's an insane
brand. That's an insane, insane, insane brand.
And it has a price premium for anything, over
any of its competitors by a long shot. It keeps
growing, it actually for most years in the last
decade it has had 80 or 90% of the entire category
growth is Lego. And so, they're playing to win,
to be distinctive in the minds of consumers.
But Vanguard has got $9 trillion of assets
under management last time I checked. Does it do
anything distinctive? Not really. The customer
bought, do they have the lowest cost position
so they can charge the lowest AUMs? Absolutely.
And so, there's different kinds of ways, but
you'd know by the actions that customers take.
So, essentially, to mirror back
what you're saying, to win,
there's kind of these two routes
you talk about. One is you're the
lowest cost option, the second is you're
differentiated. You have a differentiated
brand, where it's not a coin flip, it's
like, oh, I really need that for this reason.
Yes. Yeah, you got it.
And if you can't do that, then the advice you
share is go find a different playing field.
Well, or get out of business, whatever... It's
only a matter of time until you're dead, is the
sad truth of the matter, which is the competitors
in your industry, who are either low cost or
differentiated, can essentially jerk you around as
much as they want. It's like Southwest Airlines,
right? Southwest Airlines was just a tiny little
airline that flew Austin, Houston, Dallas,
and now it's number one in passenger seat miles
in America, and the only airline that's earned its
cost of capital over the last half century, all
the rest are losing money for their shareholders
over time. They have good cycles and bad cycles.
How did that happen? Well, it's just the other
airlines had to step aside whenever Southwest came
into a route, the other airlines just had to say,
well, I guess you're going to get your 30
share, or 35 share of passengers on this route,
welcome to town. That's all they can do.
They just have to seed position. And that's what
happens, if you play to play, you'll end up just
being... It's literally like having a bully who
can just shove you, and you take one step back,
then they shove you, and you take another step
back, and they shove you, and you take another
step back. There's no way to protect yourself
if you're not one of those two. You cannot bully
Vanguard, you cannot bully Southwest, you cannot
bully Proctor and Gamble, you cannot bully
Lego. That's the way the business world works.
And in the case of Southwest, the reason they
couldn't be bullied is they were the low cost
provider and the other airlines
couldn't meet their prices. So,
they're like, all right,
there's nothing we can do.
Yep, yep.
Awesome.
So, while I was living in Boston, they
entered the Boston to Chicago route,
which was a duopoly of American and United at
the time, and the price was about, in those days,
a $1000 for a round trip because it was a nice
duopoly. When Southwest come in, they say,
we're going to fly Providence to Midway, not
Logan to O'Hare, and it's going to be $200.
And they had great advertising, I always loved the
advertising that they had when they entered the,
they did maps of Boston, and said, if you live in
any of these places, kind of the south, the west
of Boston, it takes you less time to get from your
house to the gate than it does to go to Logan.
Because at Logan, you park in a parking
garage, and then walk a half an hour,
and then when you get through security, you
still have to walk 20 minutes... Blah, blah,
blah. And at Providence, if you've ever flown
out of Providence, you can park about 100 yards
from the gates. And so, they just had to say, we
can't stop that, not everybody's going to do it,
but a whole bunch of people are, and
there's nothing we can do to stop that.
What I love is we're already diving into these
five questions. So we've been mostly talking
about how we will win, basically, here's
your options to win. Low cost provider,
or be differentiated, or find a different place to
win. Let me summarize the five again. What is our
winning aspiration? Where will we play? How will
we win? What capabilities must we have in place to
win? And what management systems are required
to make sure the capabilities are in place?
Right. You've got it.
Okay, cool.
You're a very quick study my friend.
I got some notes here. So, coming
back to the how will we win? Because
I think everyone's listening to this,
okay, cool, we got two ways to win,
we're going to be the cheapest or we're
going to differentiate, okay. Okay,
how do we differentiate? Is there a taxonomy
of options that you think about or tell people,
what are the ways and options for
exploring, here's how we will be different?
It is mainly understanding customers,
as well as you can, and then saying,
is there a way to be distinctive against
that? And there are lots of ways to do it,
but it's tied very closely to the capabilities,
which is, if you have a way of winning, you say,
my where to play is I'm going to sell pet food
on the internet, and my how to win is I'm going
to be the best. But it turns out that anybody
who can build a website can sell pet food on
the internet, and in fact, 20 of them do it almost
immediately, and they all go bust. You don't have
the capability, so you've got to ask yourself the
question, can I serve a particular customer need
with a set of capabilities that are going to be
hard to replicate by my competitors? They either
can't do it, or they won't do it. And both are
important questions because sometimes it won't.
Do you really think Walmart couldn't have built
as good a website as Amazon, and at massive scale?
I think they could have, right?
Yeah, probably. I don't know.
Did they? They didn't. They said, I hope this
online thing doesn't really take off because
that would be a pisser because we've got 5,000
stores across America, and we've got all that,
and that would be a bummer. And so, they don't do
anything for 10 years, giving Amazon the scale,
so that Amazon then has this huge scale advantage
on this, and network effects, and voila,
you've got a competitive advantage that you
didn't necessarily completely deserve. You
needed the help of the player who stood to lose
the most to hope that it wasn't going to happen.
Same with Tesla, Tesla got a 10 year headstart,
not because the OEMs couldn't, they could have,
and of course GM did many, many years ago, create
a fully functioning electric vehicle. But they
couldn't figure out how the hell you make a buck
on it, and so they didn't do it, giving Tesla the
ability to establish a brand that people associate
with that, electric vehicle equals Tesla, and
allow them to jump way ahead, and then have the
scale that is hard to hard for others to match.
You said something that's really interesting
that I think is also really important, which is,
you said that just being the best or better is
not a solution. You can have a better pet food,
you implied that's not going to get you
there. Can you talk a bit about that?
Yeah. You have to answer a second question
I guess, which is, here's the way I'm going
to be better, and here's the way somebody else
isn't going to be able to simply replicate that
quickly. One of my favorite businesses, because I
was on the board of Thomson Reuters for 14 years,
it was Thomson first and then they bought Reuters,
so Thomson Reuters. Best business is a business
called Westlaw, and it's the dominant provider of
online legal searches. So, if you're a litigator,
and you're trying to, you're getting ready for a
case, and you need to know what are the important
precedents for this case, you go on to Westlaw,
and put in some search terms using a Westlaw
keyword system to help with it, and you get the
five cases that really matter. You can Google it,
and do the same thing, and you'll
get the 500 cases that might matter.
How does Westlaw do that? Well, for now over 100
years, they've taken every case that's come out
of the US legal system, had a lawyer, a Westlaw
lawyer, write a head note that summarizes what's
in the case, using these keywords so that they
were searchable, and today, to do 2024, takes
1500 full-time lawyers. So, if somebody else said,
this Westlaw business is incredibly profitable,
and it keeps growing, and it's awesome, I'd like
to be in that business... All they'd have to do
is hire 150,000 lawyers full time, and you'd have
to create a numbering system and a keyword system
that's different than Westlaw's, and then
you'd have to do what Westlaw has done for
the past 50 years, which is give it free to law
schools so that they teach their students before
they even get out how to use Westlaw, and all...
No probs. That'll be easy, right? Nobody's even
tried. Why bother? Life's too short. And that's
the kind of capabilities you need to be able to
say we'll win by having the searches that make
the lawyer's job the most effective. And if it
saves them time, it saves them money. And you
don't need a huge law library. Law firms used
to have these huge law libraries, you don't
need one, you need a terminal, or actually,
now it's on everybody's PC. And you don't need
a bunch of librarians to go and find the cases
that you need, they pop up on your screen.
That's a great case of competitive advantage.
Today's episode is brought to you by Cycle,
the AI-powered feedback platform for product
teams. Is your customer feedback
a tangled mess of Slack threads,
survey responses and overflowing inboxes? Wish
that you could know what your customers really
need? Cycle unifies all of your customer
interactions, from support chats, to user
research, gong calls, and app store reviews
into one neat collaborative space. Cycle's AI
then extracts actionable insights on autopilot.
Cycle will learn what you're building so that
it can label incoming feedback automatically.
That means you'll get a full voice of customer
report without manually triaging feedback. Then
simply use Cycle Ask to dig deeper into any topic,
and generate custom AI generated summaries
across your entire feedback repository.
What makes Cycle different is the way that it lets
you close feedback loops in each release. Feedback
is not used just as a way to prioritize what to
build, but also as a tool that creates trust with
all stakeholders. Sign up for a free Cycle trial
today, at Cycle.app/Lenny, and put your feedback
on autopilot. That's C-Y-C-L-E.app/Lenny.
So, essentially, we're talking about moats.
What are some moat that you can create where
people can't just copy what you're doing?
And Warren Buffett likes that terminology,
right? That's what he says, he invests in moats.
Yeah.
Yes, yes.
I'll find the quote we used in a
recent podcast episode, but he's like,
castles with moats. And maybe along those
lines, is there a way you think about types
of barriers to recreate capabilities?
It's like, here's the options we have,
is it like... Essentially, the seven
powers I think talks about this.
Yeah. Yeah. That's why I like Helmer, because
he categorizes them. And I've got to look into
it some more because I haven't studied it to say
whether I would concur that there are just seven,
or there are more. My suspicion might be that
there are more, but there may not be. They may
be all clustered, there may be variants
that cluster behind those. But I don't,
myself, have a categorization scheme that
says, here's how you search for the moat.
Great. That would be nice. So, here's
the quote from Buffet, by the way,
"I look for economic castles
protected by unbreachable moats."
Yes, I like that.
There we go.
I like that. And he's smart, he's consistent.
Though, everybody makes mistakes, right? And
he did too. Solomon Brothers, US Air...
Anybody who thinks they can be perfect on
strategy is delusional. And so, even the
very, very best, like a Warren Buffet,
who's outstanding, arguable genius, is going
to sort of think, I think this is a moat,
and it's going to be ephemeral. But any
of us should be pleased to have a track
record that would be anywhere close to that,
on really identifying moats, because he has.
We talked about that with Hamilton
Helmer, that every startup deck has,
here's our moats, here's how we're
going to have barriers to entry,
and they're all delusional, rarely is there ever
an actual moat, especially in the early stages.
Yes. Yes.
Let's go back to the five questions again,
because that's so core to the way you think
about strategy. What do you think about using,
say this FigJam as an example, as a hypothetical,
just to think through questions that
they might ask to think about strategy,
and I can describe what FigJam
is so you [inaudible 00:40:38]-
Sure, sure. I do not know that product-
Okay. It's basically a visual whiteboard
collaboration tool, where people can put
in sticky notes, and put little mocks, and
kind of play around with all the cursors.
Oh, okay.
And so, it's for brainstorming, and ideation,
and things like that, and laying out concept.
Gotcha. Okay, that would make sense for Figma.
Figma. Yeah, exactly.
Right. Okay. So, you'd asked the question, what
are we trying to accomplish? Are we attempting
to create something where nothing digital
exists, people do this in pen and paper,
and so we're trying to invent a category and then
be transformative by making the user experience
better? Is that what we're trying to do? Or are
there players already doing this and they're just
not doing it very well? You'd want to say, well,
what are we trying to accomplish? And I don't
spend a whole lot of time on that because you
got to toggle back and forth between those five
questions, but you have to have a reason for
searching in a given space for where to play,
how to win. What do you think their reason for
thinking FigJam is worth investing in is? What
do you think it is? Is it white space, or is
it crummy offerings in the market currently?
If I had to get to it, I think they're
trying to expand their market and they
have a stronghold in design tooling, and
there's this adjacent market for product
teams broadly to be using Figma more. And there
are existing tools similar to that, that are good.
Okay. So, I don't love it to start.
Say more.
So, there's a big market over there, we'd like
to get some, is a terrible reason in my view.
The reason should be, customers are bereft,
customers are lacking something that we can
provide. This is why I hate... And most
entries by foreign companies into China,
they get their faces shot off. And the reason is
the rationale is, it's big, we could get some of
that. So, I don't love it, for starters. And
I'm not saying that that'll guarantee failure,
but if somebody gave me a review of a pitch deck
for that, I would not invest [inaudible 00:43:14].
Well, I imagine you can also frame it
in other terms, like our customers are
demanding more ways to work within Figma
with their teams, and there's these-
Yeah. So, that would be a better
one. And you're speculating,
I've asked you to speculate, so we don't know.
But I like that one better, which is, what's our
aspiration? It's to satisfied core customers,
who love what we do, but think it's too narrow,
that if we could broaden that for them, into
this market, our customers would be very happy.
That is really cool. And so,
you want to frame it in the words of how
customers would benefit, essentially.
I just think those tend to be stronger, strongest,
if there's a link. Because remember, what is
strategy about? Compelling desired customer
action. So, everything ties back to that. So,
then the where to play would be, you just want to
say, okay, what customers are we talking about,
or what parts of our current customers that we
don't serve are we attempting to serve with that?
And with what product? Is it a finished product?
Is it a component of a product? Through what
distribution channel would we sell this? This is
another self-serve type product. I think Figma is
mainly self-serve, right? And so, you choose that
where, and then say, how can we solve the problem?
Before we get to that, before
we get to that real quick-
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah, please. Please.
So, the things you mentioned there is who
specifically are the customers? So, in this
case it'd be like product managers,
engineers, and other functions,
and then there's the distribution
channels, how we'd actually get to them?
Get to them, yeah.
And then, what other questions are
there within this where we will play?
To what extent is it a finished product or
a component? Because sometimes it could be,
we'd like to supply this component
that could be integrated into other
people's products. That's
what Apple apps are, right?
Got it.
We don't sell them an iPhone, we sell them a
component within the iPhone, a customer's iPhone,
is that what we're doing here? Because
then you have to ask questions about,
well, how does it fit in with the rest?
So, the where also implies where
in the product it lives? Where-
At what vertical stage? Is it an integrated
product, where it's the whole thing from soup to
nuts? Is it some upstream pieces that some people
downstream? Do we take pieces from other people
and assemble them? So, we're the integrator?
Those are all important where to play choices,
from my view, because those make a big difference.
Like Four Seasons chose... Four Seasons the
hotel company, luxury hotel, chose a completely
different choice on the vertical stage where to
play, back in the 80s, they said we're going
to get out of real estate development... So
buying land and getting it zoned for hotels. We're
going to get out of construction, building hotels.
We're even going to get out of the business
of owning the land or the hotel, so that we
can be awesome at hotel management.
Rich people, like Michael Dell,
and David Thompson, and Bill Gates
will own the hotels, as an investment,
and they will be happy to have Four Seasons brand
on their hotel, and we will charge a management
fee. That is a where to play choice. Even though
somebody could say, well, you're a luxury hotel,
you're like the other luxury hotels who serve
luxury customers at a high price. Oh no, no,
no, no, no, they do it with a stack this
thick, we do it with a stack this thin.
So, it's like a value chain question. Where
in the value chain are you going to play?
Value chain. Yeah. Where in the value chain?
That's exactly right. And everybody has value
chain questions. They often complain, after the
fact, like all the apps complain about what cut
Apple is taking, but they made a choice, a
value chain choice. We are going to design
something that will appear on an iPhone,
or an Android device, if it's that case,
and then good luck to you. You can complain
like crazy that they're taking so much of it,
and this is unfair, and they've got to duopoly...
Yeah, but you guys cooperated 100% in building
that. 100%, never complained about it, until
you wanted a bigger piece of the pie. That was
a vertical stage, a value chain stage, that you
chose, willingly. Nobody forced you to do it.
And Apple's not playing ball,
giving it back too easily.
No. No. And do I love just how controlling and
everything Apple is? Do I? No, but would I say,
oh, those poor apps, right? Yeah, no,
get your own distribution channel, buddy.
Cold blooded.
Yeah.
Okay, so we've talked about the winning
aspirations, so for FigJam, it would be
satisfy customers that are trying to work
with their team in these different ways,
and make sure they're staying, make sure
they get what they need out of Figma,
versus go maybe to other tools. And then, where
will we play? Let's say, engineers, product
managers is trying to target them, distribution
through the existing product, and so it's like a
feature of the existing product. And then, it's
how will we win? How do you think about that?
Yeah, yeah. Well, you ask the question, how
can we solve... Well, how can we either solve
that problem at a much lower cost, so we can
always be a sharper price point than them? So,
if there are solutions, but they cost 50,000
a user because their costs are 30,000 a user,
we can do this for $15 a user, and
so we can charge $100 per seat,
and absolutely annihilate the competitor by
figuring out a less costly way to do it. Or
there are other selections, but they make the
user do all these things, and it's ponderous,
and it takes a long time... We have shortcuts,
we use AI to, you just say a few words into it,
and they say, oh yeah, I know what you
mean, and here it goes in the workflow.
Or we're more integrated, like Thomson
Reuters, the company I was on the board of,
our advantage was we were better integrated into
the workflow. You didn't have to get out of your
workflow to go use this product, and then you get
back in, we just said, what's your workflow? Oh,
well, integrated. Is it better integrated
into their workflow that makes their life
easier? It would be questions, possibilities
like that that I would be asking. Essentially,
you've got to have a theory there, of how
are you going to be better or lower cost.
On the lower cost front, I think generally
the advice is you don't want to go that route,
that's a very difficult route. What's
your thinking of just when to go that
route that you might actually win at lower costs?
That's not advice I give. I think they're
both completely legitimate strategies. They
have implications. So, if you want to be the
cost leader, it is rare that you can be the
cost leader without having dominant scale in
the territory in which you're operating. So,
if you want to be a niche cost leader, good luck
to you, that's almost never going to happen. So,
Vanguard had to make a race to, we're going to
do index mutual funds, and it doesn't exist now,
we're going to do it and we're going to
get gigantic, and we can't let anybody
get close to us in size because we want
to have the lowest cost position. And so,
they are the world's biggest mutual fund company,
and you have to do that, and same with Southwest,
to really make that model work, they had to
keep expanding and expanding to get bigger.
M&M Mars... It takes an enormous amount
of commitment to say, we're going to go,
and we're just going to keep charging
ahead on this. Whereas, in differentiation,
I think you can differentiate sometimes at
lower scale, and build yourself slowly towards
higher scale. But the business world is just
getting so much more scale sensitive. When you
think about the costs of differentiation, it's
often spending on branding, spending on R&D,
R&D innovation. Those two are of the most scale
sensitive elements of anybody's cost structure.
And so, being a niche-y differentiator
is getting harder and harder in my view.
I think it's also important to
say, either path is very hard,
it's very hard to build a business that makes
money and is profitable and survives just broadly.
Yes, yes, I agree.
And you're not going to have this formula of how
to win, okay, we got it. We got a big business.
I agree. I agree. And that's why, if
I looked at 100 strategies of major
companies, I'd say I didn't
like 90 of them very much.
And then, the other nine out of 10 probably
look good, but also don't work out.
Yes. Yeah, no, that's true.
There's lots of spaghetti
thrown at lots of walls in the world of business.
Yeah, capitalism.
Yes.
Okay. So, now we're at the capability step of
trying to figure out what capabilities you need
to win. Can you talk about, say with FigJam, what
are the sorts of things you think about here?
Well, I guess I'd ask myself questions,
like, is there a learning curve to this,
where we could have better capabilities
because we started earlier than anybody else,
and have more essentially cumulative experience?
Is there a way that we've figured out how to serve
customers that make them feel tended to better
by us? So, we've got helpline... We figured
out how to do the helpline, because if it's
self-serve and that's how they get the product,
and then they've got issues with how to use
it, they feel that we're just better. We're
the best of all their providers at that. How
to win is a theory of how customers are going
to perceive us better, if we're differentiated.
And then, it's what capabilities would we have
to have to make that theory come true, rather
than just be a wish. So, if we want them to
feel like we're the easiest to deal with,
we have to have capabilities to do that.
It's just like again, Four Seasons said the reason
they're by far and away the most successful,
profitable, best in all fronts, luxury hotel chain
in the world... Biggest, best, most profitable,
best employee rankings, best guest rankings, all
of those. Well, their how to win was they said,
people, if you talk to people who are in luxury
hotels, they'd rather not be there. You'd say,
wow, they're in the lap of luxury, why would that
be? Where do you think they'd prefer to be, Lenny?
At home.
Yeah. Dominantly at home, for their segment, which
was high-end business travelers. They've traveled,
they've stayed in one luxury hotel too many 20
years ago. And so, we're going to have luxury
defined as not grand architecture and decor
and [inaudible 00:55:38] service, but rather,
we're going to define it as a service that makes
up for what you left at home or at the office.
Because people would rather be,
if they have to not be at home,
they'd rather be at the office than in a
hotel because they can be more productive. So,
we need capabilities, we need staff that can
deliver on that capability. What's the problem,
for that? The problem is turnover in the
hotel industry globally is 80% a year,
which means that the average person you
meet, the average staff person you meet
in the average hotel, is on their way to
a 16-month career at that hotel chain. So,
how do you deliver that really cool special kind
of service with that? The answer is... And now I'm
skipping ahead to enabling management systems.
You have to have a different way of recruiting,
a different way of onboarding, a different way
of career development. And if you do all of those
things, you end up with a 10% turnover rate, so
that your people are there 10 years on average,
and you can then get them trained up to deliver
that kind of service. So, that's the capability
that you build, and the people, to be able to
take more decision-making at a lower level,
and treat the guests in a customized way that
makes them feel that this wasn't by the book,
some rule book, that this person just said,
no, this is a good solution for my guest.
It's interesting that these capabilities
and even the management systems,
which is step five, relate to your moat.
Which is the thing you need to achieve,
also, ideally is the thing that other
people, it'll make it hard for them to do.
Yep. So, you're exactly right. You can call if
you want, how to win, moat, right? Definition
of your moat. And so, capabilities and management
systems are what both build and maintain the moat,
and the maintaining is an important part because
if you are the most successful, people are going
to say, I want to do that too. But here's where
there's this modern, unfortunately, bull shitty
thing that says, oh, competitive advantage is
fleeting in this modern hyper-competitive world,
and you can't have long-term advantage anymore.
And I just say, oh, I see. So, Four Seasons,
I guess that isn't very long-term, that has only
been 45 years now, since they... No, 35 years I
should say. Don't exaggerate. Since they went
to that strategy. Oh, and Tide. So, 77 years
isn't a long time, I guess either, because they've
been the number one detergent for 77 consecutive
years. I guess you're right, it's fleeting.
It's not. But what makes it fleeting is when
you have one thing, and one thing only. So,
let's say you build the biggest polyethylene
plant in the world, near a good feedstock
source, and you have the low cost position,
what's somebody else going to do when they
see how much money you make doing that?
Build a polyethylene plant beside yours, twice
the size, and then you're toast. Why? Because
the competitive advantage was too simple. But at
Four Seasons, you got to sell off all your hotels,
you got to fire all the people involved in hotel
development and everything, and actually, the
people in the business like doing that, you have
to essentially get rid of your entire staff, start
from scratch, paying them more than you do now
by far, giving them more career security, giving
them more training, giving them better uniforms,
whatever, spending 10 times as much hiring them,
with the hopes that maybe someday you'll be able
to produce the kind of services Four Seasons does.
The competitors basically say, life's
too short. Do they give up and die? No,
there are other great chains, Mandarin Oriental,
my wife loves staying in Mandarin Oriental,
even more than Four Seasons often. But they've
not said, we will replicate Four Seasons,
they've said, we'll pick a different where, and
a different how, and that's, in the end, what
you want. Is rather than complete overlap, where
you've got concentric circles of people picking
the same where, you convince people to pick
different wheres. That's why people sort of say,
Roger, how to win, that's so impolitic, because
you're producing losers, and then there's victims,
and all that. There's oppressor and oppressive. It
fits in the modern dialogue. And I say, no, what
I want to do is encourage them to find someplace
else to prosper, rather than smash on top of us.
And so, if you have completely different
capabilities and management systems,
it'll encourage people to choose a different
where to play, how to win. If your capabilities
and management systems are very similar to your
competitors, and you're succeeding with your
chosen where to play, how to win, what are they
going to do? They're going to drive straight to
your where to play and try to win exactly the
same place and wreck your market for both of
you. That's what you don't want. And the more
complicated, in some sense... I shouldn't use
complicated. The more nuanced and multifaceted
your capabilities and management systems are, the
more likely they're going to say life's too short.
That's what everybody says about Southwest. So,
if you're the only airline in the United States
that's earning its cost of capital for 50 years,
wouldn't you say, gee, I'd love to
be like that? But what does it mean?
Well, it means selling off most of your aircraft,
so that you can have only one kind of aircraft,
737. Tearing up your entire root structure,
your entire hub and spoke structure,
and make it point to point. Changing your complete
labor relations strategy, from fighting the unions
to paying them a lot, as long as they're highly
flexible. People think Southwest is non-union,
it's not unionized [inaudible 01:01:55], but they
do different... You have to essentially fire all
your travel agents, and convince your customers
to book online, by themselves, to save more
money. Life's too short, it's just too short. So,
they try things like Continental Light, or Ted,
that do half the things that Southwest does, and
then you're what? A crappy Southwest. So, to me,
that's the ultimate. The ultimate is,
it's like the ultimate weapon is the one
you never use. The ultimate way to compete to
win is to never actually be forced to compete.
Wow, that's a great quote. This story
about Southwest makes me think about
Hamilton Helmer's counter-positioning,
I don't know if you've heard that term,
but basically, you position yourself
in a way where the competitor can't do
the thing that you're doing because of the
way their business is already structured.
Ah, that's sounds right. The can't.
Yeah, can't.
The can't thing. Awesome. Yeah, and Mike
Porter, and he may quote Mike on that,
Mike was very big on that. He said, it's
fault lines. You're trying to find fault line,
where it is so painful for your competitor to come
across that fault line, into your side. And so,
a great example of that would be Olay, at
P&G, and it's in the book, when we did the
repositioning of that. The competitor that
could have killed us, absolutely killed us,
was Estée Lauder with Clinique. If they would've
brought Clinique into the mass channels... Because
we were doing a Clinique kind of thing, in the
mass channels, rather than the prestige. Prestige
is like the first four of the department stores,
which [inaudible 01:03:51] or Sephora, or Ulta.
If Estée Lauder would've taken their Clinique
brand and brought it into mass, they would've
killed what we were doing. Simple as that.
And in fact, Clinique was the biggest brand
in all of skincare, we became the biggest brand in
all of skincare, and they didn't do it. Why? Are
they idiots? No, they're not, Estée Lauder's super
smart. But Estée Lauder also has Bobby Brown,
and Mac, and the Estée Lauder, its own brand,
and a half a dozen more, all in prestige,
and the prestige channel, if they'd have
taken Clinique, and taken it over into mass,
would've done what? Shot them in the face. Killed
them, right? They would've been just apoplectic.
And so, Estée Lauder had to stay... If that's
counter-positioning by Helmer's terms. They had
to stay there. Was that stupid? No, they're
still, with all of their brands combined,
the biggest in skincare. But Clinique
has lost leadership to our brand that
they would've considered kind of nothing. Oil
of Olay became Olay Olay ProV, Regenerist,
all of these higher priced products than they
could ever imagine being sold in the mass channel.
But our biggest friend was, in some sense, their
distribution channel, which would've killed them
if we... Literally. They would've just punished
them so, so, so bad that they didn't do it.
I love that I'm learning all this strategic
thinking about makeup and skincare,
I also love just the idea of you leading
strategy for skincare and makeup brands.
Yeah, no, I got Proctor &
Gamble into color cosmetics.
So funny. [inaudible 01:05:51] love that.
I don't know if you're following the AI
Google stuff that's happening, where
there's search engines competing with
Google by just answering the question
versus giving you a bunch of blue links?
Yes.
And there's this question of, we'll Google
Shift because people seem to really like it,
versus they're making trillions of dollars
running ads when they share blue links,
and it's this super innovator's
dilemma position they're in.
Yeah, no, no, I am very interested in what's going
on in AI, and I'm writing some stuff on that. But
it's hard. I've seen the inside of this for many
of my clients, it is super hard when the guts of
how you make money is under threat, and you just
don't want that thing to go away. The big auto
OEMs make money selling cars with ice engines,
it's simple as that. And there's no surprise,
they've been doing it for 100 years, they're
way down the learning curve, they have scale,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. And so, these damn
electric vehicles are kind of no fun. And so, the
Google situation you've described, I think it's
similar. But my general advice is always the same,
which is, it can take a while, but in the end the
customers will triumph. And A.G. Lafley, my friend
who I co-wrote the book with, great CEO, was
very good on this. And one of his big customers,
big [inaudible 01:07:27] customers came to him and
said, if you don't stop cooperating with Amazon,
we're going to de-list all your products.
Big threat. Big threat. And A.G. just said,
"If customers want to shop there, we just can't
not be where our customers want to shop. And so,
if you feel you need to do that, you're going to
have to, because customers want to shop there,
and we are not doing that. But what are you
offended by, that we're doing there?" And
they said, "Well, you are allowing them to ship
products to their customers from your distribution
centers." And A.G. just said, "Yeah? Do you want
to too?" And they were like... And he just said,
"We don't do anything special for them that
we wouldn't do for you, they ask for things
that you don't ask for because of their business
model. But if you come to us with ideas of how we
can help you serve our joint customers better,
we're all in. But we're not boycotting a place
that customers have shown they want to shop," as
long as it's an honest, if Amazon was sleazy and
dishonest or whatever, but an honest, upstanding
place where customers can get our products.
And so, that's where I'm at, which is, you may
have to scramble like hell, you may have to
suffer from economic downturn, but if you think
you can... I always think of it, I don't know if
you did this as a kid, Lenny, but when we went to
the beach on family trips, we would, I have four
brothers, we would build... Plus then a baby girl
later. But we would build sand castles and try to
hold back the tide, this would be in Florida or
California, and we'd try and hold back the tide,
and we'd come the next morning to see if our
castle... And it was always gone. It's gone.
But we'd keep trying doing it, and it's sort of
like, you can't hold back the tide. Maybe you
can for a while, but you can't forever. So, you
just have to figure out where are the customers
going. And if they're going someplace...
And Vanguard did this, Jack Bogle,
the late Jack Bogle, he died now, a couple of
years ago now, he did not like ETFs. He said ETFs
are not as good for customers as mutual funds.
And he had all sorts of good reasons for that,
but the index ETF business started to grow like
crazy, and Jack had to relent and say, I don't
think it's good for them, but they want it, and so
they went whole hog into it, and are the leading
index ETF provider, as well as the index mutual
fund provider. But for a while they weren't,
but he realized it was the tide, and he was
attempting to hold back the tide. So, good luck.
Good luck to you on that. So, to me, if Google
thinks they can, because of their power and the
fact they've got a multi-trillion dollar market
cap, and they've got a near monopoly position on
something, they can hold back the tide.
You see, the water finds a way to flow.
Think about Microsoft and its monopoly on PC
operating systems, or it's near monopoly on
PC operating systems. And I would argue
that they abuse that kind of monopoly. I
often asked people, when's the last Windows
update that got you as a customer excited?
Yeah, Windows 95.
The answer, I think is really
clear, Windows 95, right?
Yeah.
Because that's when he took the graphical user
interface that he bought rights to from Steve
Jobs and put it on, so you didn't have to do
backslash backslash... You could actually point
and click. That's a long time ago, last time
I checked, that's now almost 30 years. And so,
they just abused their customer. Is their
share of PC operating systems much lower
than it was then? No. But that's not the right
measure of share. The right measure of share
in my view in that industry is your share
of minutes spent staring at a smart screen.
That's what the share of operating systems
that you should care about. And so,
what kind of smart screens do people now stare
at most? Most? And what other one do a lot of
people stare at who really like them? Pads.
And so, if you added up all those and said,
what do you think... So, what's their share
of smartphone operating systems? Microsoft?
Last time I checked it was 0.4 of 1%. Yeah, so
effectively zero. How about pads? Apparently
it's 4% there. So, their share of people staring
at a smart screen has plummeted. Plummeted. Why?
Because water finds its own level. People said,
there are these other ways of getting around this,
and I'm going to take those ways. And I think the
degree to which people use their smartphone for
more things, as the function of that smartphone
is advanced so much faster than your PC operating
system, because more people are using it.
So, that's what I'd say to Google. I don't
care how painful it is, water flows downhill,
the tide comes in, and you cannot stop that,
even if you're one of the most powerful
three firms on the face of the planet.
And it may take time, but
eventually the customer tide pulls,
that's a, I think that's really important.
But yeah, start now. If you
don't start now, it's too late.
Yeah. I want to end with one very tactical
question for people, that may feel overwhelmed,
they're just like, oh my God, I don't know
what we're going to do, this is so hard,
all strategy stuff. You have this
really cool idea called betterment,
I think you wrote a media post about it, thinking
betterment over perfection. And it gives you a
first step of like, okay, here's a way to move
forward. Can you just talk about that approach?
So, for me, strategy, this thing called
strategy, with people, oh my God, oh my God,
how am I going to do strategy? Whatever. I just
think of it as a problem solving tool. And what
problem should you attempt to solve? You should
attempt to solve something where your current
outcomes that you're getting are lower than the
outcomes you wish you were getting. That's what
I call a gap. There's a gap between those two. And
you should just conceptualize it as, your current
outcomes are a natural result of all the choices
you've made interacting with the competitive
environment. And so, you should reasonably assume
that probably those outcomes aren't going to get
a whole lot better, because they are the way
they are for a good reason. So, you're going to
need to make a different set of choices to make
that gap go away. That's what I would work on.
I would just ask the question, what is
the single most painful gap currently
that I'm facing? Customers used to do this, and
they're doing this, I can't find this kind of
resources, our distribution channel has abandoned
us... Whatever is the most painful thing,
and then just tackle that. And say, what
different choices could I make? And I'd say,
use my cascade. Could I change where I'm playing?
Could I change how I'm winning? Could I change my
capabilities? Could I change my manage systems, in
order to achieve a different aspiration? And so,
don't try to solve the problems of the world,
or even all the problems of your company,
that's perfection. Betterment is making that gap
go away. And guess what happens if you make that
gap go away? You can turn your attention to the
next gap, and the next gap, and the next gap.
And if you do that all the time, you're always
working on the next gap, the next... They'll
get smaller and smaller over time. I don't know
if this is a great analogy, but I was dean of
a business school for 15 years, the guy who won
the professor of the year award more times than
anybody else, and did it sort of teaching
tough courses, often executive MBA courses,
and the like, had a simple formula for doing
it. Which is, he taught second-year courses,
and second-year courses happened to be 13 two hour
lectures, or sessions, [inaudible 01:17:10] or
another. He just polled the students on what they
thought of each session as they went along, and
regardless of the reason, regardless of anything
else, simply chopped number 13 every year.
Because in some sense, it's the biggest gap,
the gap between what the customers, students,
wished for, and were getting. And he would just
replace it with something. He would try something
else, and replace it with that. And you'd say,
and that gets you professor of the year every
year? And the answer is yes, betterment.
Because if you're teaching for 25 years
and you just keep doing that every year, every
year, the course keeps getting better and better
and better and better and better and better. So,
betterment, it doesn't make purists feel awesome,
but I'm not here to make purists feel
awesome, I'm here to help people get better.
This makes me think about your water
metaphor too, of just water eventually
finding a way through. [inaudible 01:18:26]
iterating, [inaudible 01:18:27] things better.
Yeah, lots of what I think
about in strategy is natural,
if you will. I try to ask, how
does the world generally operate,
and is what we're doing consistent with the
way the world generally operates or not?
Roger, this was so much fun, we covered
everything I was hoping we'd get through.
I think we're going to help a lot of
people with the way they think about
strategy. Is there anything else you
wanted to just leave listeners with,
or say before we wrap up and let you go? We
covered a lot, so there may not be anything left.
Well, on strategy, there's one piece
of advice I'd say. People often ask
me about people who are natural strategists,
or they say, I'm not naturally good at that,
I'm more of an operational guy or gal. And what
I tell them is, I have never met this mythical
beast called a great natural strategist. And they
often throw back in my face, Lafley. They say,
look, Lafley, he was known as a strategy genius.
And I say, yeah, but when I interviewed him in
depth about his background, for a paper I was
writing, what I discovered was when he was in
the Navy, as a whatever, I don't know, probably
25-year-old in the Navy, he had a job where he had
to think about strategy, and was testing things
out, and doing things, and the like. And then,
I realized that he had been practicing strategy
for decades before he became the CEO, decades.
And so, he just had more reps when he became
CEO than almost anybody else that I've ever met.
There's another guy, [inaudible 01:20:15], ex-CEO,
now he's gone on to a higher level of Lego brand
group, would be similar. So, great strategists
that I have met have all one thing in common. They
just practice. And anybody, there's no such thing
as a person who is willing to practice strategy,
who will end up saying, I'm operational,
I don't do strategy well. Which links to
our last thing about betterment. Just work on
making different choices to solve problems.
Not problems that I say, I'm not going to define
your gap, it's one that you feel in your heart,
I wish this were better. Work on it, if you
do that, you'll be a great strategist. So,
be encouraged, don't be discouraged. And the
worst thing to do is to wait. People say,
well, I've got all these operational concerns
right now, and then I'll get to strategy later.
You'll never amount to anything. Nobody
who says that ever amounts to anything.
Wow. I love this, I love how empowering it is,
I love the real talk. Roger, you're
awesome. Thank you so much for being here.
You're most welcome. Thank you for
making it a fun journey for me.
I learned a ton, and that's always a
good sign, and it was a lot of fun.
Well-
Thanks, Roger.
Good.
All right. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening, if you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to the show
on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us
a rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
Lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.