Watching you operate on Twitter,
you're just breaking this wall
between the PM and the customer.
The moment the customer felt compelled enough to
go out of their way to talk about some problem,
that's a unbelievable gift. I will leave
a meeting to just get one message back
to them. If you're text message
friendly with five or 10 of those,
you are going to have so much
direct signal that is infectious.
Many people told me I need to
ask you about picking metrics.
Well, what was the value that we're trying to
produce for the customer and can we measure it
from their perspective? And okay, how do you
know you have product market fit? Charts that
showcase things are going up into the right
on one hand and then tweets on the other.
You started at Stripe
something called study groups.
We show up four to eight people total
pretend to be some company with some
outcome problem. Rule one is you do not
work at Stripe and rule two is we're not
here to solve any problems. This is just
about practicing empathy for the customer.
Today my guest is Jeff Weinstein. Over the
course of his six plus years at Stripe,
Jeff was the product lead for Stripe's payment
infrastructure teams. We helped scale Stripe
payments to hundreds of billions of dollars in
volume a year. He also led PMs and Teams on a
number of zero to one bets at Stripe, and most
recently took on the scaling of Stripe Atlas,
which as of the day this podcast launches allows
you to incorporate a new company in a single day,
including handling 83B elections, incorporation
documents, getting your EIN, share purchases,
and all the things that used to take weeks or
months before a company could begin operating.
At this point, one in six new Delaware
corporations are started on Stripe Atlas,
which blows my mind. This episode ended up
being the longest in my podcast history because
I wanted to basically do an archeology of an
incredibly effective and admired product leader.
We spent the entire conversation digging deep into
the many skills that Jeff has built that enable
him to consistently build successful and beloved
products. We get into his go-go- go plus optimism,
long-term compounding philosophy of building
products, how to think about and operationalize
product craft and quality. He shares a popular
program that he started at Stripe called Stripe
Study Groups that I think you should steal.
We also talk about how to effectively talk
to customers, how to know if you have product
market fit for your new product, how to pick
great metrics for your team, what he's learned
about getting shit done at a big company. Also,
advice that he's gotten from the founders of
Stripe and so much more. This episode is for
anyone who's looking to level up their product
building chops in every way. If you enjoy this
podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow
it in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube.
It's the best way to avoid missing future episodes
and it helps the podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you Jeff Weinstein. Jeff, thank you so
much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you Lenny of Lenny's Podcast.
I knew what to expect, but it's fun
to see the first name and the podcast all
line up. I really appreciate you asking.
So I wanted to start with a quote that I found
from you that I think gives a little perspective
into how you think and how you approach the
world. So here's the quote. "Very frequently
I would do poorly on tests in school and then
the professor would say very reasonably, 'Hey,
I think you should bump down a level to the
previous semester's pace,'" and you said,
"I actually know that, that's why I'm in
this class. I want to be in the class that
I'm potentially the worst at." This isn't how
most people think. This isn't how most people
operate. Usually people want to get good
grades, they want to be at the top of their
class. Clearly you have a different approach
and a different mindset. Where did this come
from for you and how did this shape the way you
think about product and the work that you do?
Some of it was just the fact that I wasn't
particularly good at the class and had to
rationalize it for myself in some form.
So in retrospect that sounds highfalutin,
but at the time I just wasn't particularly
good at the classes I was in. But I think
it comes from growing up. I went to a pretty
hippy-dippy K through 12 school in Baltimore,
Maryland where we were really asked to think
about why we were in school and to pick any of the
courses that were of interest to us outside of AP
programs or grades or any particular requirements.
You really got to choose your own path. And I
recall one particular class in high school, which
was somewhat a science class, but it was called
the History of Science, and we actually walked
through and studied all of the, at the time,
best understood ways the world worked in science,
but then later were turned out to be wrong, right?
In the 1500s we believed X, Y, and Z. In the
1600s we believed A, B and C. just very
confidently. In 1500s we thought something
and then the 1600s we thought something very
different. And so this class was quite impactful
on me where we spent an entire year studying
things that are not true. It was fascinating. That
particular teacher employed another trick on us
during that class, which was it took the tuition
fee of our school and divided it by the number
of hours and wrote the cost on a ticket and then
handed us in the beginning of the year. Tickets
for every single one of the classes and he would
stand at the door and you would have to give him a
ticket at the end of the class that he thought it
was worth it. And just like that practice of deep
intellectual understanding of how people evaluated
something at the time and choosing for yourself
to spend the time on it by just the physical
act of handing that ticket to the teacher.
That really clicked for me. And so when I got
to college and it was a real college university,
people are coming from often quite more rigorous
backgrounds of things that were true. I was a
bit unprepared and I remember actually taking
a microeconomics class that was quite advanced
and had a close friend and we studied exactly
the same information. We sat and looked at the
same cheat sheets, we practiced the same quizzes,
we read the same books, and he got the top
grade in the class and I got the bottom and
that's from where that quote came from where
the professor said, I think you should bump,
potentially bump down. I was like, "I already
know that stuff. I'm interested in this topic.
I'm going to try to improve, but look just because
I'm significantly worse than the other kids in the
class that has little to do with if I should
leave." And he was particularly cool with it.
This episode is brought to you by Pendo, the
only all-in-one product experience platform for
any type of application, tired of bouncing around
multiple tools to uncover what's really happening
inside your product? With all the tools you need
in one simple to use platform, Pendo makes it easy
to answer critical questions about how users are
engaging with your product and then turn those
insights into action. Also, you can get your users
to do what you actually want them to do. First,
Pendo is built around product analytics, seeing
what your users are actually doing in your apps
so that you can optimize their experience. Next,
Pendo lets you deploy in-app guides that lead
users through the actions that matter most.
Then Pendo integrates user feedback so that
you can capture and analyze what people actually
want. And the new thing in Pendo, session replays,
a very cool way to visualize user sessions. I'm
not surprised at all that over 10,000 companies
use it today. Visit Pendo.io/Lenny to
create your free Pendo account today
and start building better experiences
across every corner of your product. PS:
you want to take your product-led know-How a
step further, check out Pendo's lineup of free
certification courses led by talk product experts
and designed to help you grow and advance in your
career. Learn more and experience the power
of the Pendo platform today at Pendo.io/Lenny.
Today's episode is brought to you by Cycle. The
AI-powered feedback platform for product teams.
Is your customer feedback, a tangled mess of
Slack threads, survey responses and overflowing
inboxes? Wish that you could know what your
customers really need? Cycle unifies all of
your customer interactions from support chats to
user research, gong calls and app store reviews
into one neat collaborative space. Cycle's AI
then extracts actionable insights on autopilot.
Cycle will learn what you're building so that
it can label incoming feedback automatically.
That means you'll get a full voice-of-customer
report without manually triaging feedback.
Then simply you Cycle Ask to dig deeper into any
topic and generate custom AI-generated summaries
across your entire feedback repository. What makes
Cycle different is the way that it lets you close
feedback loops in each release. Feedback is not
used just as a way to prioritize what to build,
but also as a tool that creates trust with all
stakeholders. Sign up for a free cycle trial
today at cycle.app/Lenny and put your feedback
on autopilot. That's C-Y-C-L-E.app/Lenny.
It's really interesting that you went to this
liberal artsy hippy dippy school as you described,
which a lot of people bash on. Why spend all
this college money and time on a liberal artsy
education and you ended up being really successful
in a very technical, highly analytical data-driven
company, and it's interesting that that experience
still helped you succeed in this other path.
It did take a change though because I started
in... English was my selected major in school,
but then I kept playing with computers and I
kept liking math and I looked at the roles of
the backgrounds of the people who were running the
types of companies I loved. At the time Facebook
was getting super phenomenally successful. Apple
was already on their up and up again and everyone
who was leading those places had technical
backgrounds and I liked computers a lot,
so I added computer science as an engineering
degree midway through school. So I had to take
the real science classes with the pre-med kids
and the rest of it, and I did similarly poorly,
but I did end up with a computer science degree
and a liberal arts degree. So it was a journey,
but I had to make a pretty big switch
in the middle to get on that path.
I asked you if there was one thing
that you'd love to get across in
this podcast. I asked you what would it
be and here's what you said. Here's the
first item on this list that you sent me,
"Go, go, go ASAP plus optimistic comma,
long-term compounding approach." Can you
just talk about what you mean by that?
Yeah, there's two things going on here. So I
see the world as immediately we have just such
opportunity to take action in front of us. We can
be optimistic and go, go, go as soon as possible.
I think that a lot of life is you get as much
furniture as you've room in the house. We will
do the work the night before it's due, so let's
just make it due tomorrow. Can we turn tomorrow
into today? So just optimistically seeing if we
can just inject energy to go, go, go has produced
surprising results and I think it ignites in
other people that same interest and then it feeds
off each other. And that's I think really in my
bones from growing up. And then I added over time,
had to learn this longer term, compounding, more
strategic mindset where some of the things we want
to accomplish, be it at my startups in the past or
at Stripe, they can't be solved in an afternoon.
They're going to require layers of infrastructure
and services and applications and UI and
partnerships that really look like that iceberg
drawing you see where you just see the top,
but then there's the whole thing underneath
and I've had to learn over time to pair
my instinct of like, "Let's get
it done today, let's move forward,
let's see what we can get done. Let's make
some mistakes, let's try it out." With,
"Where are we going? What needs to be true over
time? Where can we always invest? What will we
never regret spending time in?" We'll never regret
spending time making the latency of our payments
APIs at Stripe faster. We'll never regret making
it more reliable to send 83B election mails to
the IRS. Like we'll never regret those things.
So let's just always compound those capabilities
over time. Then the trick is how do you mix this
go, go, go attitude with a long-term compounding?
That's something I still struggle with, but I
try to purposely balance it more than I used to.
It's such a good way of summarizing just how
to be successful in a lot of things. Go, go,
go ASAP, stay optimistic. Focus on long-term
compounding growth. Is there an example of
that in action? I know we're going to talk about
Atlas a bunch, but I guess is there an example of
that working for you or a product you worked on?
I work at Stripe, which is a infrastructure
company. We build things that help businesses
do online commerce in various forms, and I've
had a few roles at Stripe. I'm in our beautiful
office here in South San Francisco, one of which
was the product person that helped us decide how
we were going to go global and how we were
going to offer multiple ways for people to
pay. It turns out there's more than just credit
cards in the world. There's small hundreds of
ways that people will naturally want to pay for
things online and as a business you're going to,
of course, just want to accept whatever it
is people want to pay with. And for the first
seven or eight years of Stripe, well prior to my
being here, the incremental country ads and the
incremental new payment methods was relatively
flat over time and that was surprising to all of
us who worked here because the world wanted
it and we had a lot of people working on it
and we were working very hard, but it wasn't
producing returns in the way that we wanted.
And so actually the optimistic as soon as
possible go-go attitude was not working. No
matter how much energy we poured into building
Thailand payment methods or UK bank transfers
or an in-person payment system in Latin America,
we just couldn't rack up points and get it done.
So we had to step back and say, "Well, what is
the world going to look like in 10 years? What
was going to need to be true and how can we start
to go there now?" Which meant going a lot slower,
building internal platforms, sending people around
the world to start to build these payment methods,
uproot their lives, pay for their apartments,
get them on airplanes, start using these payment
methods actually in the world. And so it really
our line flat line for a while and we're like,
"Okay, is this strategy working? Is it not
working?" But then over time we start to see it
switch to nonlinear again and go from whatever
it was, 10 payment methods at the time.
And now Stripe accepts over 100. So we got to
50 really quickly and then skyrocketed to 100.
And I remember there being a meeting where we
said, "Well, maybe we should just lock everyone
in the basement and see if we can get from 10
to 50." That would be the intensity startup go
attitude. But we looked at the individual
components of what it meant to get this
done and how long we wanted this to be true
for and we had to go a lot slower. That was
a very formative decision where you had to mix
the go, go, go with the long-term compounding.
Awesome. Okay, so let's start to delve deeper
into some of the specific seals that I hear
you're incredible at and that I've seen you
be incredible at on Twitter and LinkedIn and
things like that. So the first is craft, craft
and quality. I'm told by many people that you
have a very strong obsession with craft and
user experience and quality and even more so
I'm told that you teach people at Stripe how
to be obsessed with craft and quality and user
experience in a very systematic way. I feel like
this is something a lot of people are starting
to realize is really important and or are trying
to get better at, either personally or at their
company. So first of all, let me just ask why
is this so important to you? Why do you think
craft and experience and quality is so important?
Why do you put so much emphasis on it yourself?
I think I'm really working backwards from failures
in the past and avoiding them. And so maybe just a
quick story. I started a company several years ago
based on just a personal pet peeve of mine, which
was I was a SQL analyst. Many you listening might
have written SQL in the past, maybe the robots
write the SQL for you now, but you still need to
write SQL yourself. And every single time I wrote
a SQL query, I wanted to run the same subsequent
analysis. I wanted great version control, I wanted
all the cool stuff that GitHub had for code but
for writing data code. And so my friends and I
built a little Python tool which basically let you
run our style queries. It lets you draw charts and
pivot tables quickly and sharing all this modern
SaaS application stuff. But applied to SQL a few
years ago and we turned that into a company.
We got some progress, but then there was this
moment one day where we had maybe a couple 100
customers and we had an error where we basically
by accidentally shut down the service and it
was bricked for 10 or 20 minutes. And at the
time we were hustling in our little dinky office
to get the application back online. And we really
were proud of ourselves about how reasonably
quickly we did and people went back to using
it. It wasn't a super long outage and we didn't
lose any data. We were just high-fiving each
other. And we went about our day and about
a year later I realized that that was a...
I missed a huge moment that I should have pounced
on, which is that during those 20 minutes,
our customers weren't furious. They weren't
emailing us like crazy, they weren't texting us,
they weren't trying to find us on Google
Maps and knock on our door and say, "Hey,
I need this thing back online immediately."
We heard a couple comments from them,
it was little murmurs. And I didn't realize at
the time that was the signal that we did not
have product market fit. And I ended up wasting
many more years on that project. And wasting is
a big word. We built amazing software, people
liked it, we were able to sell the company.
It helped many of us learn how to really build
software. But I'm really trying to avoid that
situation again. And I think craft is a dessert
that you get after the meal of does your thing
solve a real problem in the world and are people
clamoring, needing it badly? And that's really my
obsession is in finding problems in which people
will pause their entire day to solve. They will
leap through the computer to be like, "Oh my God,
I have that problem. Do you have a solution?"
And if you focus on that style of product
development and we can get into just how do you
listen for that and then turn that into product.
Later, you might get the opportunity to really
provide craft and beauty and touches and moments
and delight. But certainly there is no amount of
craft, there is no amount of beauty, there's no
amount delight or touches you can add to a thing
that will solve the problem we had at our startup,
which is that people didn't really need this. And
that's the biggest error is picking something in
which people don't really need it. And then going
through these practices of trying to make it great
when maybe it shouldn't exist in the first place.
I think a lot of people see all these
tweets and messages about just obsessed
with the craft of what you're building and
you can easily lose sight of... Nobody even
cares about what you're building. It could be
the most incredible experience ever designed,
but if it's not something anyone
ever wants, it doesn't really matter.
People don't really get out of bed for their
second problem. They get out of bed for their
first problem. And you have to carefully listen
and not pitch your customer or your prospective
customer as you're trying to figure this out.
And I think this advice, not even advice just
style applies to small companies, big companies,
anyone which is people don't want to be pitched.
I'm sometimes on a UXR call with a very
well-meaning person or a founder who has
a new product that they want advice on or they
want to find customers. And the first thing that
they start talking about when we get on the call
is, "Hi, I'm the CEO of X, Y, and Z company. We do
one, two, and three. I want to show you a demo."
It's like, "Hold up, I'm a customer. I have..."
What a wasted opportunity you've just done here.
I have so many problems, you're guessing ahead of
time, what is my top problem and now that
you've anchored and limited to the pitch
you're going to miss, you very likely going to
miss the burning problem that they have on the
top of their mind. And it's not the customer's
job to interrupt you and say, "Hey, could you
stop your pitch? I want to tell you about my top
problem." And you can see this down the stream,
which then companies who launch things, put craft,
have a great launch, raise money are then later
gone. And it's because they built something that
wasn't solving a burning need. And I think you
can stem it all the way back to they were just
pitching rather than sitting in silence and just
waiting for their customer to just open their
heart out about what's the most burning thing.
And sometimes I'll prompt our customers, I'll
say, "Hey, do you mind just opening up your email?
What's in there?" Or, "If you weren't talking to
me right now, what would you be working on?" Or,
"Hey, last week, what grinds your gears? What
are you not looking forward to?" Or magic wand,
"What do you wish you could just have off your
plate immediately? Forget Stripe, forget about
thing, work on just in your whole life. What is it
that you do not want to be doing?" Or, "A massive
opportunity you wish was just one door away?" And
it's a little awkward because they don't know why
you're asking that kind of question, but then you
just sit there in silence. And for the most part,
if you have amazing customers who are
smart and ambitious and are trying to
build their own business, they're going to want
to offload their hardest thing to somebody else.
If you've earned trust along the way, and
certainly not pitching is a great way of earning
trust. You're just listening. We've learned a
lot at Stripe from that. And that's where you
can start to find adjacencies, right? "Well, hey,
I don't know if Stripe could really help me with
this, but wouldn't it be cool if we could identify
if the person signing up on our site wasn't
fraudulent or is who they say they are or isn't
a bot, or are they really a dog on the internet?"
And we're like, "We keep this as the major
complaint from all of our customers, but we're
not an identity company." It's like, "Well, I
guess now we are because all of our customers who
are trying to build their business all have this
problem." And so via silence, you can just create
your roadmap pretty quickly and drop a lot of the
long UXR, long survey, long build cycle approach.
So I love where we're going with this. This is
where I was going to actually talk about next
is just your ability to talk to customers
and user research. It feels very unique,
watching you operate on Twitter, you're
just sharing your email constantly,
getting on calls with people constantly. There's
this, you're breaking this wall between... That
a lot of people imagine there is between the
PM and the lead of a team and the customer.
You're not relying easy research. You're not
waiting for someone else to do this work for
you. Talk about just why and how you do this.
I think there's so much to learn from just how
you operate in finding opportunities, picking
problems to solve by talking to customers.
It's where the business comes from is customers.
It is not a long shot hypothesis about why to talk
to them. It's like if they love your stuff, they
will tell their friends and pay fair prices for
the product. We're so fortunate through the
internet that people announced themselves as
being interested in a topic. Sometimes they're
interested in it by posting on Reddit a long
thread or a screenshot of a customer service
interaction that bugged them or hopeful that
from their dorm room in country X, someone else
in the world has solved the same problem. And
the internet has given us all this absolutely
magical forum that you can just yell out the
window and then billions of people could actually
listen to what you said out the window. Now,
that's not all the time true for all people
in all situations, but dramatically more
true now than ever before in human history.
And so the fact that people wouldn't be listening
to their customers and really jumping through the
computer to talk to them surprises me. It's like I
always sometimes think, "Do they have some other
strategy? Are they so confident in what they're
building that they don't need to hear directly
from the people who will be using it?" And I think
some of it is my own fear that I'm going to
make the same mistake I've made in the past,
which is build something that people like they're
using but isn't solving a burning enough problem
such that they're going to stop their day, they're
going to tell their friends, we're going to be
able to sustain the company economically over a
long period of time. And that really just comes
from hearing people's most burning problems
and then just jumping through the computer
and talking to them takes a little bit of nervous
gumption, like walking up to a person at a bar or
cocktail party and saying, "Hi, my name is Jeff."
It can be a little awkward, but then you get it.
It's a rush once it starts to work. And once
you get the iterative loop that they're excited
to talk to you, they have problems, they see
you as a trusted, not salesy, not pitching,
not narrow-minded to just my product and
my position, but I'm here to hear about all
of your problems and see where we can help.
Not promising we can help solve everything,
but let's listen. That is infectious, both between
the customers and internally. And so I'm able to
bring more people into that practice. At Stripe,
I'm able to quickly grab an engineer and hop on
a call. I can forward a message over to a Slack
group. And they know that because the customer's
speaking directly, it somewhat trumps everything
that's happening during the day. We could go to
our meeting where we're going to guess what the
customer wants or we could talk to them directly.
And you have to use a little bit of art to decide
which customers you want to listen the closest to.
But even at Stripe's scale, where we're dealing
with many millions of businesses and many hundreds
of millions of consumers on the other end of
those businesses, you can pattern match relatively
quickly. What are the styles of customers
that represent where the world is going, the
most ambitious, the most technical, the fastest
growing, the most detailed. And you don't need
10,000 of those people to talk to. If you're text
message friendly with five or 10 of those, you are
going to have so much direct signal about where
to go that you forget how you did it in the past.
I love these. So I'd love to learn more about
these tactics that you've found helpful.
So you've shared this idea of silence,
talking to someone and just being silent,
and I forget the phrase you used, but just like
ideas emerge, like your whole road map can emerge
from that silence. So let me share a few of
the things you shared so far and I'm curious
what else. Two is tweeting just like, "Hey,
I'm looking to improve Atlas right now. What
bugs do you have? Here's my email address."
You talked about text messaging, just like,
"Hey, can I get your number? And I'll just text
you when I have questions." If there's anything
else to add to these, that'd be awesome.
And then what else have you found? Just
ways to actually get to a customer and
find opportunities that are important.
Speed is an important one, which is just reducing
the time between the moment the customer felt
compelled enough to go out of their way to talk
about some problem. They're busy, there are snacks
to eat, they have families, they have other things
to do. There's a lot going on in the world, a lot.
Your dumb product, it's amazing that they
would spend any of their time discussing it
at all. I mean, most of the time if you don't
like something, you just move along. You just
apathetically, silently move forward in
the world. And so the fact that someone
took their finite time to succinctly with
curiosity, communicate to the world or you
about your product, that's a unbelievable gift.
That should be P-zero alert level intensity. And
so I will leave a meeting, I will change what
I'm doing to just get one message back to them.
Even if it's, "Hey, I got this. I'm about to go to
dinner. Can I hit you up tomorrow?" They're like,
"Oh yeah, thank you. Awesome. I can't even
believe you responded." That puts us in the
camp of on the right trajectory where they're
going to feel that they have a almost secret
portal between this big brand of a company and
another human who's just actually curious...
... brand of a company and another human
who's just actually curious what's going on,
that's night and day. And it's also, fun fact,
tip, when people are really hot on an issue and
it could blow up on social or they're going to
start becoming a detractor, we make mistakes,
we have SLA breaches, we have errors, you're
going to want to get on that stuff fast. And in
those situations, my bar for how we will respond
to those folks is not to just solve the problem,
but it is to turn them into a promoter,
and most of the time we're able to,
even if there was a pretty relevant issue.
I remember one time at Atlas, we had this
bug in which for a handful of our legal
docs, they were handing out let's say,
25 shares rather than 25% of the shares. We
dropped the percentage sign, and thankfully
a founder noticed this in the docs and tweeted
about it. My heart paused and I was like, "Oh no,
this could be a really serious issue." And we
were able to fix it and regenerate the documents
relatively quickly for everyone that was impacted.
And I was thinking to myself, "Wow, we really let
this person down. We have one job to do, which
is to get their company right and we didn't."
And that person was incredibly gracious about
the situation and said, "Anytime you want me
to just read your docs, I'd be happy to. I have
a law degree. I care about this topic. I want
to brainstorm with you about ways that Atlas
could do more document creations." I was like,
"Wow, I can't believe I was in this sort
of defense position, and now we've gained
a friend in the world who can be eyes and ears
and brainstorm with us." And the team maintains
a really close relationship with that person as
they do with many, many founders who use Atlas.
And so, just again, we're so quick to put
the outside world in this other camp where
we need to touch it with kid gloves and treat
it as a big blob and a cohort and a statistic,
when it is a human with a problem who likes
snacks, who is busy, and it's fun to do and
it turns out to be an incredibly easy,
fast way to figure out what to build.
There's a bunch of stuff I want to follow up
here. One is, people may be hearing this and like,
"Oh my God, I'd be overwhelmed with feedback
and people to fix problems for and bugs and
texting of people." They're just like,
"There's so many people that potentially
I'd have to be interacting with." How do
you try to narrow that down? I know Atlas
is a very highly adopted product. There's
a ton of people, there's probably bugs,
often people sending you feedback. How
do you pick the people to zero in on?
I think there are two parts to this. One, what a
problem to have. Of all the problems in the world,
"I'm overwhelmed by customer interest," is
on the top list of problems I want to have.
I think most entrepreneurs would purchase that
problem as a state. And so, if you're in it,
I think, take a deep breath and look at the
sunrise or sunset and just enjoy the fact that
you've built something that is meaningful enough
that people would spend their time. Again, there
are amazing snacks that they could be spending
the time on otherwise, so that's a huge deal.
And then two, you need the art. There's
an art and science to picking where to
go deep. I will happily respond to folks
with, "I really appreciate that. Do you
mind sending me a screenshot or a video?"
And some of them don't. Okay, that's fine.
You kind of get a sense of quickly looking at how
they wrote about it or just pattern matching how
detailed they were, or how much they seem that
they want to engage and kind of balance it that
way. Otherwise, you can tell folks, "This
is really awesome. Do you mind sending me
an email with three to five bullet points about
the details of how you got to this issue?" And
that's not a 30-minute meeting. You don't need
to blow up your whole life to get on the phone
with them. It's not a huge homework assignment
to them, but it's enough structure that it will
self-select those who want to go deep, and then
from there, you really do owe it to them to follow
up if they're going to be that detailed. And
at that point, you really have made a product
friend for life and you'll kind of continuously
go back to them. So you have to kind of tune it.
I also will bound some of these efforts, so I'll
just completely make up one day a program. So,
"Hi, Stripe's doing a bug-finder program." I made
that up as I was driving to work one morning,
tweeted it, was curious if anyone would send
anything. "We'll be taking videos for the next
three days to go super deep." And people are
like, "Oh my goodness, I would love to be part
of the Stripe bug-finder program. May I apply?"
I'm like, "Oh, it's very selective. But yes,
of course for you." It's just giving people
permission through a program, even if it is
deeply arbitrary, I find helps with bounding it,
and then later I can follow up with the world,
"Hey, we ran our first program, we got 65 videos,"
which we did. "We found dozens of issues," which
we did. It was an incredibly valuable use of our
time and it really came from just a single tweet.
Something I saw you mention somewhere is
that you only pay attention to feedback from
people that are paying customers and ignore
everything else. Can you talk about that?
People who build things for people tend to be
empathetic and interested and curious folks who
have friends, and then those friends want to use
your stuff because they know you and they like
you and they'll have good feedback. But you need
to figure out, is that actually your customer,
or is that your friend trying it? Who is actually
your target customer exactly? Not a company or a
segment, not digital natives that are X big.
I'm talking about Sarah in this department,
who has these tabs open and just faced this
problem and needs to solve it by 4:00 PM.
That level of specificity. If that's your
customer, and I'm talking mostly about B2B,
which is where I spend a lot of my time as the
social network, B2C stuff I have less intuition
on, they're very willing to exchange money for
solving their problems, incredibly so. Oftentimes,
if you listen with enough silence, they
might even say, "I'll pay you money to solve,
blah." If you sit there long enough in silence.
And so, you could listen to your friendly friend
who you got to play with your beta version
and they'll say they liked it and they will
click around. But that is extremely different from
Sarah, who has the actual problem and is willing
to pay. And it is so tempting to go down the first
path with the friend group that I sort of needed a
rule, which was like, "Okay, rather than..." I was
like, "Well, don't pay attention to that quite as
much. Really pay attention to, who is your target
customer and are you in a fast iteration cycle
for them and are they telling their friends?"
But that wasn't enough, because people are so
drawn, myself included, drawn to the friendliness
that I just set a rule, which is, "We discount all
of that feedback from our friends to zero." That
is not of interest to us. We don't even write it
down. It's just not part of what we're talking
about at all. We are only interested in Sarah,
our target customer, and can we get her to solve
whatever the problem is as quickly as possible,
as jangly as possible and go from there?
And then the paying part is a forcing
function because again, even with Sarah, because
you're paying attention to her and solving her
problem a bit, she'll say, "Of course, oh, this is
great. I want feature X, Y and Z. Can it do one,
two, and three?" Naturally, she would say that.
But if you said, "And by the way, this thing is
$10,000. We'll happily refund your money 100% the
second you don't like it," she might say, "Whoa,
whoa, wait a second. Yeah, I like this thing, but
not $10, 000. For $10,000, it would need to solve
X." And you're like, "Oh, there it is." That
was actually what the thing that was of value,
and we were all kind of dancing around
this. It's useful, we're on the right track,
and because I've fallen down that path
myself so many times, I just set a rule.
This is great. I was actually going to ask.
This technique of using silence, to help
people actually practice it, you just shared this
quote of, "For you to pay $10,000 it would've to
do X." That's a really cool line to use. Is
there any other advice there of just how to
practice this idea of creating silence to help a
potential customer share what they actually need?
I encourage people to take an improv training
class or two, just to get people out of their
skin a bit. By the way, this advice applies
to big companies also, not just small ones.
And we have issues, and I hear other larger
companies have issues where a big company will
say, "Hey, we're an enterprise and we're going to
pay you this big contract. All you need to do is
build features one, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, and go through security steps,
A, B, C, D, E, F, G." And this siren song of the
big three-year contract of your first enterprise
buyer, even when you're already big, you
can go from Fortune 1000 to Fortune 500 to
Fortune 10 to Fortune 1. There's always
more. There are so many stories of the
rug being pulled in the middle and they never
actually use it and the contract never lands.
Same in partnerships. And so, I would say the same
thing, which is, "If we're super serious about
this, send us $1 million. Wire us $1 million.
We'll happily wire it back anytime you need it,
but let's actually put some stake in the ground
about the value." And I find that in the cases in
which they're like, "Whoa, wait a second, no,
absolutely not. We can't commit here." That's
really a good signal because you're about to spend
a huge amount of time building something that
might not ever be used, and that's the majority
case I hear. Or you might get the opposite, which
is, "Sounds great. Let's make sure our teams are
trained on it faster. How can we get you to our
office to explain it? We need it to really work
with this system we haven't talked about yet. And
now that we're paying, we want it even faster."
And so, I find that it puts a fork in the road
towards faster success or avoiding the non-success
case. And even at Stripe scale, I've heard our
founders somewhat push this methodology on
us, where one from the outside might think,
"Well, it's a 8,000 person company. Surely they
have just regular ways of building things for
larger customers, and we too need these style of
commitments if we're going to go off roadmap."
So a big lesson you're sharing here is
essentially, make sure people are ready
to pay for something that they're asking
for. That is the ultimate sign that they-
And by the way, ready to pay is different
than paying. Significantly different,
significantly different. I've also thought
of, "Well, as long as they're ready to pay
and they said they would pay and they look at the
contract, we should feel good." That is not the
same as paying. Paying is an independent group
of people saying, "My problem is burning enough
that I'm willing to exchange something I have
that has value for the promise of what you're
going to do." And now it's a real commitment.
That is extremely different than ready to. So
I will often be on the phone or video, whatever
with a founder and I will have them practice
charging me. I'll just say, "Hey, I'm just
a friend. I'm trying to help you out. It's a
little bit self-serving because I work at Stripe
and I want to get feedback on our products."
I'll say, "Feel free to sign up for any invoicing
or payment service. I don't really care which
one. You're welcome to choose Stripe if it's easy
enough for you, I'd love to hear your two cents,
and send me an invoice or a payment link
for $1 right now, right now. That way,
when it comes time to actually charge your first
customer, it won't be your first time. It won't
feel weird. You'll have already done this, you
already have a dollar in your account, you already
have your logo on the top right of the invoice.
It'll feel great." And I probably could go through
my email inbox and just see $1 receipts to random
people because I'm just so convinced that the
difference between paying and willing, ready, I
thought they would pay is night and day different.
Yeah, there's this term, willingness to
pay that I feel like it should change,
as you're saying, to just cross
that willingness to even just-
Paying.
Paying, exactly.
Yeah. And we can refund the money. There's
no issue at all. Just other tricks on how to
get people going is, ask them about their regular
life as a human, "What did you do yesterday?" And
they'll be like, "Oh, at work?" I'm like, "Or not.
Whatever." And people, they'll start to spill,
they'll just start to spill and eventually they'll
get to their biggest problem pretty quickly.
Let's talk about metrics, going in a
different direction. Many people told me
I need to ask you about picking metrics and
the importance of metrics and how you think
about metrics. So let me just maybe start
with a question of, just why do you think
picking the right metric and why are metrics
so important in building successful products?
I somewhat walk around with the belief that
the product manager's responsibility is to produce
product market fit. And okay, how do you know you
have product market fit? Charts that showcase
things are going up into the right on one hand,
and then tweets on the other. So metrics like
quantitative and qualitative, and I really see
them as deep siblings and equals, you really need
both. It's not oh, OKRs versus something. There
are some things you want the texture of the person
on video showing how complicated a thing was. And
then also, we're trying to make an economically
viable system that we can run at large scale and
you can't keep all that stuff in your head and
need to measure it. And so, I think metrics at
their best are a numerical representation of
the value we're providing for the customer.
One could measure anything. You can just start
counting events and log lines. We've made it
incredibly cheap to count stuff. And so, now
we have this big privilege of choosing what
to measure. And I really just try to map it all
the way back to, "Well, what was actually the
value that we're trying to produce for the
customer and can we measure it from their
perspective?" Whereas I think it's natural,
both because when you work inside of a company,
you're just thinking internally, but also the
way that the metrics are collected inside your
application to be more internal-oriented. How many
people logged in? Okay, that's a fine measure,
but how many people accomplished what they
were trying to do after they logged in,
is not just necessarily sitting there as a
single event in your database. You have to
think about it a bit. Another reason why I spend
a lot of time crafting a small number of these
metrics is, they force trade-offs and decisions.
So we could all sit around all day and say, "Hey,
I heard all these customer problems, we should
build X, Y, and Z." And another person could
absolutely reasonably say, "Well, I heard from
these customers, we should build one, two and
three." And they're all true. We could have a lot
of success in both, but the majority case is that
we don't build either and we sit around and
argue and bicker and we go slowly. "What are
we going to do to naturally, organically every
day, orient a larger group of people in the right
direction and see if our tactics are generating
progress over time for a customer from their
perspective?" And metrics on the left and a series
of tweets on the right is a pretty great combo.
Here's an example. A couple years ago I had been
working in our payments group at Stripe for a bit,
and then I started working on some of our
banking and incorporation services. In Atlas,
when I started working on it, it had had some
success. It had already existed for four or
five years prior to me spending time on it. But
when I started to look at the support tickets,
people were pretty unhappy frequently. They had
a DocuSign stuck in their email box. They needed
a co-founder's address, but they didn't know
their co-founder's address. They couldn't log
into the dashboard to figure out their 83(b)
manual filing instructions. And we saw this
basically in the first week of spending time
on Atlas. I was just like, "Just show me all
the support tickets. Are they happy support
tickets? People writing in being like, 'Oh,
I love this service, it's absolutely fantastic.
Can you just do A, B, C more for me?' Or are they
sad support tickets?" And they're like, "Oh
my God, they're all sad support tickets."
And so, we're just asking ourselves, "Well, why
would someone recommend Atlas to a friend?" I was
like, "Well, it would have to accomplish A,
B and C activities for them. It would have to
get their company, it would have to handle getting
their tax ID from the IRS. It'd have to handle all
the downstream administrivia." But surely, if
they had a bunch of support tickets at the end,
they're not going to go tell their friends to
use this thing. We could measure all of the
intermediate parts, we could measure the success
rate and the frequency of incorporation services
and we do all those things, but if you looked
at the support tickets, there's just no way if
you had a support ticket, you would recommend it
to a friend. And so, we suggested this metric to
ourselves, companies that have no support
tickets through the incorporation service.
The whole process, from the moment you start the
application open, actually the first page load
at the very beginning, all the way through the
process waiting for the government, waiting for
the IRS, and we give you two more weeks to write
into support. We give an extra buffer two weeks.
And if you get through that whole thing with no
support tickets, that's a yes. If you have any
number of support tickets, that's a no. And we
just looked at the percentage of founders that
were going through the service with zero support
tickets, which is very different than looking at
an average, right? You could have the average
as 0.3, but that doesn't necessarily mean that
they're getting to 0.2 is going to cause them
to tell their friends more. And we looked, and
only 15% of founders were getting through Atlas
with zero support tickets through that metric.
And I just thought, "Okay, well let's just drive
that number way up, and let's look at the support
tickets aside what people are needing and we'll
bake it into the product, and presumably it'll
fix it. People will like that more and then tell
their friends." And over about 18 months, we took
that number from 15% to 85. We basically just
flipped it. And you can look at the market share
plotted on the same timeframe and it's the same
shape. And I think you have to find a measure
by which it speaks directly to what the customer
wanted, and that if you accidentally leaked your
dashboard to them, your customer would be ecstatic
to learn that that's what you were measuring the
whole time. If we were to showcase the internal
Atlas metrics, which we often just screenshot
and publish, I think they'd be pretty happy
to hear that we were spending all of our time
making sure that none of them had support tickets.
And it was incredibly encouraging and motivating
to the engineers on the team because we could
just assign them a topic. "Hey, look at all
these support tickets. Why don't you come up with
the product spec, the scope, the solution? Oh,
want to learn more? Just reply to the support
ticket email, figure out what they need." And so,
we kind of turned all of the engineers on the team
into PMs to go and one issue at a time, figure
out what needed to change and build products for
it. And that's where we pushed forward on 83(b)
elections, automating it, sending in the mail
for folks. We built our own signing service.
We turned everything into a click. We did just did
sort of the obvious things we saw in the tickets,
but as the PM, I was able to just sort of,
not on autopilot, but really sit back and have
content full conversations with engineers who
were bringing solutions and ideas for product,
rather than one person going through all of the
potential ideas, scoping them and assigning them.
And because it was based in what people were
saying and wanted, it was very motivating for
everyone on the team. So somewhat long answer,
but figuring out something in which every day
we can wake up and look at the same metric
and with some confidence know what to do,
is so much better than, "Let's figure out what
to do each month, and starting from scratch."
I think this is amazing and important advice,
just the power of a single metric that everyone
on the team can understand, rally around and use
to prioritize the work they're doing. I've seen
exactly the same sort of impact. Funny enough,
Airbnb, one of the teams actually had a metric
sort of like this, basically reducing the people
contacting Airbnb with support issues. But what
ended up happening is, their team started just
making it harder to contact support because
they're like, "Maybe they don't need to contact
support about all these trivial issues, so maybe
let's encourage them to figure it out themselves."
Is there anything you've learned about to try
to avoid these kind of second order effects
that are of perverse incentives of a metric?
We look at multiple metrics, but we will optimize
around one and you have to use your own judgment
to look at some of these countermeasures and pick
them. We would also, that would sort of be our
overarching metric for a year, but then we would
pick specific tactical metrics about how we would
accomplish it. So just an example that both is how
we solved a problem, but also it's just a style of
metric that was useful to us. Of course, some of
these support tickets included things like, "I'm
waiting to hear back from Atlas about, if they're
going to approve my application because Stripe is
required for very good reasons to evaluate certain
business types, or sanctions, lists and the
worldwide products." So there is some, should be
incredibly quick, but there is a bit of a review
process, and of course if you were not hearing
back from us, you would be upset because you're
trying to make your company immediately, "This
is ridiculous. Let's get back to us quickly."
And so, we knew that one of the reasons that
people were writing to support was like, "Hey,
what's up with my review? What's going on?" And
we knew that our tactic was just to drive up how
quickly we got to a final decision on folks and
to reduce the number of overturned rejections,
where someone writes back in saying, "Hi, come
on, I'm totally just making something reasonable.
What's up? Why did you reject me?" And so, we
would pick these overarching single metric,
which was the companies with zero support tickets,
but then we would have a specific KR that was
owned by an engineer, which is the tactic that
we're going to do. And so, we would not allow
ourselves the perverse tactics to sort of just
casually exist. We would choose which tactics
we're going to do and then set a metric for it.
And the other reason I love this metric is,
it's a cohort metric by which you're trying
to drive something up into the left. Sometimes
people will get excited about a chart that goes
up into the right, it's kind of a meme, "Oh,
that's going up to the right." I'm really excited
about charts that go up into the left. So you have
to figure out some optimization that you're trying
to maximize. And so, in this particular case of
this risk review, we would look at, "Hey, for
the cohort of customers that started last month,
how quickly did we get them to their final risk
review by number of days since they submitted?"
And so, you want a chart that looks a lot
like, "Here we go, right up to the top."
Because you want 100% of your customers to get
their final decision as quickly as possible.
Wouldn't you know it, when we looked at
the chart, it was doing this. And so,
each month we would just make it a little better,
a little better, a little up and to the left,
up and to the left, up and to the left. And now
basically 100-ish percent of people get their risk
review within an hour, from a long tail taking a
long time. And so, we would constrain the tactic
through a metric and then watch it through an
optimization function. And then when we got to
a point where we were happy with the target, we
could put down the tactic. That's another really
useful thing about metrics, you can decide when
to stop a tactic because you get to some level of
success that you're comfortable with and you
can always choose to pick it back up later.
So there's some really cool lessons here of
just how to pick a good metric. Just to kind
of maybe summarize what I'm hearing is, you
kind of worked backwards from essentially NPS,
like, "Why aren't people recommending
Atlas?" You found, "Okay, well people
that are complaining and having issues
with support and running into problems,
most likely are going to be detractors,
not going to want to recommend Atlas,
so let's have those really ambitious goals.
Eventually nobody has a support ticket/let's
just track how many people have zero issues." And
then you identify, "Okay, what's driving a lot
of these support tickets? It looks like this risk
timeline till they get to this certain milestone,
let's make that our goal for the next quarter
or whatever, and let's focus there and then
make an impact." And then I imagine move on to
other levers within this bucket of zero context.
You have to pick the right metric for your
audience in... I wouldn't wouldn't fully export
that metric to everyone. That was not a terrible
one to export, but in the founders choosing where
to get started mindset, again, this isn't just
deeply spending time listening to your customers.
They all ask their friends, "Hey, how did you
start your company?" They want to talk to an
older sibling of sorts about how it went. And so,
we decided that our go-to-market strategy would be
to delight our current customers such that they
would tell their friends. And other businesses,
that's always somewhat useful, but you can also
reach people with billboards and Google ads and
other types of upsells. That's very difficult
in the moment that someone is starting a company
that's sort of a National Geographic, can you get
the picture of the bird at exactly the right time?
How are you even supposed to go find people
who are about to start companies? Thankfully,
they have this practice of just asking their
friends. And so, if their friends loved it,
they're going to just recommend it. And that has
the metric and the tactic and the go-to-market
all lined up, rather than sometimes in cases
you might hear someone say, "Well, let's make
the product quality better." Well, we all make
the product quality better, but why? Why is this
actually going to move what our customers want,
and the business board? And when you can line them
all up, it can be quite beautiful, especially when
you can see it month-over-month for a long period
of time. One other metric I think that I would
export to anybody, is if you are unsure what
to measure, we have this, I don't know if we
stole it from somebody else or if we came up with
internally, whatever, is just users having a bad
day, where we will just emit a log line anytime
we think that a user bumped into a problem.
So maybe they hit a 404, or maybe their
payout was one day after the ETA, or they
had more than 10 payment declines, you can kind
of brainstorm again or just listen to customers,
what would cause you to personally have a
bad day, and then just emit an event when
that occurs. And then you could just make a
stacked bar chart of all the bad day reasons
and the frequency by which they're happening,
and it's eye-opening to see those frequencies.
And it's kind of a metric I hadn't thought about
until Stripe's scale, in which you just don't
know what's happening until you emit the log
line and count it. The frequencies could be...
... emit the log line and count it. The
frequencies could be kind of mind-blowing. And
I think for almost any scale business, if you are
bored one day and you're not sure what to measure,
just make a user having a bad day chart, emit
a log line and count it as a bar chart and then
anybody else can add their own bar chart on top of
it. And so, it's become a way for teams to scale
their understanding of users through metrics
by just saying, "Hey, look, anytime anybody
has an idea about why a customer is having a bad
day, just emit a log line, put it on this chart,
and then we can choose over time which bad
day reasons we want to burn down and hopefully
just eradicate them, not just minimize them.
But it gave us kind of a background noise counting
system for where there are problems and anytime
there's an incident or some customer issue,
the first thing I think is, "Ooh, I wonder if we
have a bad day reason for this." And if we do,
I actually feel okay. I'm like, "Oh yeah, it is a
bad day for this customer." I wish I didn't have
it, but at least we're aware and we can evaluate
it against other bad days that we want to burn
down. What does sometimes a little bit grind
my gears or gives us an opportunity is like
when we didn't know about that bad day. And it's
a surprise to us too, that is for me is immediate
action. It's like, okay, cool. We have to figure
out a way to count this bad day. We got to get it
on the chart. That way we can make an informed
decision about when to invest improving it.
And I love this idea. I haven't heard
this before. So the idea is just make a
list of what happens to a potential
customer that would cause them to
have a bad day. What are some examples
for Striper Atlas that you guys have?
Are you a Stripe customer, Lenny?
I am with my newsletters. The payments go
through Stripe. I check my dashboard every day.
Cool. So what would be a bad day for you?
Oh, I see some silence happening here.
It not loading. The numbers taking a
long time to show up. Something
being completely off in there,
not being able to log in. The silence
is good. I just want to keep going.
The question is how much to the audience
is how much of the silence will we edit
out before it goes live? But this is what I'm
talking about, right, is I could guess them,
right? And as you were saying those,
I know the URL of those charts. I know
the login one because I feel that too. So I
play with Stripe all the time and then you
get a two FA too frequently and come on, I had
the same cookie. I was just here yesterday. So
we count all that stuff and try to make it
better over time. But I'm so excited when
someone brings me a new bad day I hadn't thought
about yet because that's like product cabinet.
I love it. And your advice here is this doesn't
necessarily have to be your goal or metric. It's
just watching this thing that could lead
to a lot of interesting ways of operating.
A couple other just like quick metrics things
because it's a bit of a... I don't know,
some people like cycling or something. I guess,
I like metrics. People get a really nice bike.
I want a really great metric. Picking metric
titles that make you feel something. So we could
have called that measure of companies, number of
companies that do not send a support ticket over
X period and Y period with min... You sometimes
see these charts where the metric itself named
itself. This is just companies with zero support,
that's it. And the brevity and the focus and the
customer mindset built into the chart name can
become currency inside the company. It's like,
oh, I'm working on making this chart go
up and it feels good to just say the name
out loud rather than some complicated
underscores and mins and maxes and the
database field name is still in the chart title.
These are aesthetic choices, but I think make
dramatic differences in the cultural willingness
for people to buy in and get excited about it and
reduce the need of a product person to just
remind everyone every day why they're doing
it. It's like the metric is motivating us because
it's a motivating thing to talk about. And then
lastly on metrics is there's just good hygiene
that people should bring to their measures.
Percentages shouldn't have 41 significant digits
if only two of the digits are relevant. You should
keep all the measures of your dashboard on the
same X-axis. These are just stylistic things that
increase the frequency that people want to just
wake up every day and open the dashboard and look
at it. And that is so powerful if your whole team
is looking at the same set of information that has
the heartbeat of the customer every single day.
In fact, we can measure at Stripe the usage of
our dashboards by team, and so we can see which
teams are themselves looking at their own metrics
and that is an incredibly useful predictor of
how on the same page they are and how customer
obsessed they are. So I just think it's not
an area that's sort of behind the scenes,
bean counting reliability is the machine hot.
You can make metrics that mean something to the
customer and you would be proud if they were to
be screenshot and put on the internet and be like,
"Wow, I feel like that company is taking
their promise to me seriously. And I can
see myself on those metrics as a customer."
That's where we're really shooting for.
So [inaudible 01:08:19] back
what you just said there,
which I think is a subtle point potentially,
is just making the dashboard look nice,
like the hygiene of the naming conventions
and the decimal points and the chart. In
your experience, you find that
really powerful and important.
A couple of years ago, Stripe did internal work
to make an internal metrics kind of dashboard
system. And we have a special place called Go
Metrics. Many people use a go/service where
you can just quickly go to a URL. And again,
I have to sometimes do a rule rather than a
policy. My rule is if it's not on Go Metrics,
I'm not going to look at it. So if people can
send me one-off queries or charts or screenshots
or presentations or emails of charts and data,
but that is in the wind, we can't interrogate
the query metrics are almost always wrong. For
many weeks, we didn't quite get the definition
correctly. You have to live in the metric for
quite a while before you really believe in it.
And so, if you're always looking at some one-off
version, it's just very difficult for it to
rise up to the level of importance that is
a thing we should trust to help us decide what to
do. That's an incredibly high bar. And so, I just
find you have to look at it frequently enough.
And if you're going to look at it frequently
enough, it means it needs to be in a discoverable
place. You almost go through a couple stages of
grief about it because we'll kind of put a metric
up in a place and everyone initially is like,
"Wow, this is great. I was so excited to finally
see this." And then a couple of days later,
"I don't quite understand it. What does it
actually mean? I saw this other metric from
this other angle that kind of makes it feel
counterintuitive that it's like this." And
then you kind of look into it, "Wait a second,
we've been counting it wrong the whole time. Oh,
no." And then you look at it the third week
and it's a completely different version and
then you hope that we forget about it and
maybe we'll go onto something else and nope,
we're not going to forget about it. Week four
comes around, you're like, "Wait a second. Okay,
this is..." Then the team meeting starts, "Hey,
just a reminder, let's just bring up the metric
again, not a screenshot of it. Go to the URL."
And just that level of frequency and specificity
and ritual around it is what brings it into
the decision-making culture. And again,
we treat it the exact same as we do tweets.
It's the quantitative and qualitative right
next to each other. And because you're
putting that amount of attention to it,
you can't have a 1,000 metrics. We just don't
physically have time the day to bring that level
of care and understanding to so many things.
So then it forces you to know so many things
you could care about down to a small number of
things that you really must care about. And again,
that practice goes back to do you really
understand what your customer wants? And so,
for all these tactics, it's about finding out
what your customer wants and then different
versions of how do we sort of know it's
true over time and our tactics improving?
It sounds so simple when you describe it that way.
This episode is brought to you by Anvil. Their
document SDK helps product teams build and launch
software for documents fast. Companies like Carta
and Vouch Insurance use Anvil to accelerate
the development of their document workflows.
Getting to market fast is a top priority for
product teams. And the last thing that you
or your developers want is to build document
workflows from scratch. It's time-consuming,
expensive and distracts from core work.
You could stitch together multiple tools
and manage those integrations. Or you can use an
all-in-one document SDK. Most product managers
will tell you paperwork sucks. Anvil's document
SDK helps teams get to market fast, incorporate
your brand style and give you back time to focus
on your company's core differentiated features.
For your users, paperwork often starts
with an AI powered web form styled and
embedded in your application. From there, you
can route data to your backend systems and to
the correct fields in your PDFs via API.
Complete the process with a white labeled
e-signature. The best part about Anvil is the
level of customization their SDK provides.
Non-technical folks love Anvil's Dragon Drop
Builder and developers love their flexible
APIs and easy to understand documentation.
Build documents software fast with Anvil,
that's useanvil.com/lenny to learn more or start a
free trial. That's useanvil.com/lenny. Kind along
these same lines, there's something that I've
learned you started at Stripe to help people
obsess with user experience and get quality
to where it needs to be and move a lot of
these metrics, something called Study Groups.
Talk about what that is. I'm very curious.
Okay, let's imagine we understand our customer,
we've understand their burning problem. We've
built a solution that's in their hands,
they're using, it's hopefully better than
their alternatives and they're starting to
use it and we have some real traction. You
could still measure the success, you could still
look at the tweets and then, of course, you go
to pick it up yourself and you're like, "Wait a
second, this thing is horrible. How did it get so
bad?" Anyone who's built a product that has gone
over the horizon of it's actually in production
and being used for a year or more as you go to
iterate on it, especially when you're in a larger
company and there's multiple teams and multiple
products going on, there's just some entropy in
the world that causes these things to go bad. I
actually have a hard time naturally explaining it.
You kind of think to yourself, well, it's code.
It just must be running the same every day. But
somehow you do enough things in a row. And
what was once a smooth end-to-end flow for
accomplishing a test or a customer is all of a
sudden some Byzantine complicated broken mall
where all the doors are busted and you have to
know exactly the way to get through the dashboard
to solve your problem. "Wait a second, I thought
this was great just a second ago." And many of
us have experienced that. Now, okay, what are we
going to do about it? Well, one is it is really
difficult to take time during the day to allow
yourself to even know that this is true. Because
if you're working on one particular team, you're
going to have some next thing you're shipping,
you're going to have your customers, you're
going to be doing great product work.
Meanwhile, your current thing kind of starts
to rot in the world and decrease all the trust
you've earned to build what you're building
now. It is actually difficult to decide, well,
what hours during the week am I going to block
off from my future progress to see it from the
customer's perspective today? And there are
various techniques to try to incentivize or
to structure a group of people to do that. Stripe
has a thing called friction logs as well, which is
a single individual will pretend to be a customer
and go through a product experience end-to-end and
write it down. And that has been quite successful
at Stripe for very motivated people who can block
off the time and have the wide enough context to
do a complicated thing end-to-end and have the
time to write it up and the position the company
to send it out as a critique potentially to not
just your own team but in a whole organization.
So that's actually a pretty high bar to crossover.
So I was kind of brainstorming what could we do
to make this more fun and have the frequency which
we're looking at our own products dramatically
increase? And we kind of iterated few through
ideas. And I landed on this thing called Study
Group, which is basically a random group of people
inside the company. They might not work on any
particular team. They might not all be PMs,
just like literally anyone who wants to
sign up, a support person, a sales person,
someone who's on our events team, an engineer
and our infrastructure stack. Anybody can sign
up for a Study Group. We show up maybe four
to eight people total. We pretend to be some
company with some outcome problem. Maybe we
want to accept money in person at an upcoming
farmer's market, or we want to run a multi-country
global business where we have software
that another business would use to run their
business. If it was something quite complicated.
We could pick any motivating goal. And there
are two rules to Study Group rule one is you
do no longer work at Stripe. You do not work
at Stripe, not pretend, don't work at Stripe,
not try to forget you do not work at Stripe,
you've never worked at Stripe. You work at... And
we make up a name of the company, Dolphin Aquarium
Industries, and we will pick a CEO of the company
from the group amongst us. And okay, Jenny is the
CEO. "Hey, Jenny, what do you want to do today?"
"Well, I want to sell in-person tickets to the
Dolphin Aquarium." It's like, "Cool, where would
just start?" So we actually embody the customer.
We will not break character, it's a little bit
of the improv thing and as the kind of maestro
of Study Group, I will firmly but kindly, if I
hear you use any internal Stripe knowledge, which
is natural to do, because, well, you worked on a
team and you know where that button really is.
And the docs link goes a little bit to the wrong
place, but if you click the other link, you'll get
to it. If I can see you use any internal Stripe
knowledge, I'll just pause and say, "Hey, let's
redo the sentence or redo what we did with no
Stripe knowledge. As a reminder, you don't work
at Stripe." And it takes us a couple of times,
but people really get into it and all of a sudden
we'll start making up characters and the CEO will
be like, "Oh, Tim, you're our designer. Where
are we going to get the color palette?" All of
a sudden there's a person who's not a designer
in real life is now all of a sudden having to
practice the empathy to be in a customer's
position. And because we're going to be doing
it for an hour, hour and a half at a time, you
actually start to believe that you don't work
at Stripe and you work at Dolphin Aquarium
Industries and you start to really feel it.
So that's rule one. You don't work at Stripe. And
rule two is we're not here to solve any problems.
We're not here to critique, we're not here to
solution or suggest, we're not here to file bugs.
All of those things is recorded. We can do that
later, whatever. This is just about practicing
empathy for the customer and going through the
product. And we have done more than 25 of these at
Stripe thus far in just this year, last few months
of 2024, more than 250 people have participated in
the Study Group. And it is deeply eyeopening for
those involved. The responses are sort of business
emotional, not super emotional, but just, "Wow,
I can't believe how hard it was to accomplish X,
Y and Z. I thought we were amazing at blah." It's
like, "Well, we actually are still pretty good,
but we need to get back towards amazing" or
Wow, "I didn't even know that internally people
wouldn't know that our products did 1, 2, and 3."
And this has become so internally popular that
teams have adopted for themselves. And so, we've
kind of franchised Study Group internally already
where different teams will run it. But I think
we're going to continue it because I think a
little bit is coming out of the pandemic.
People just want more group activities. I
think some of it is the slowness by which we do
it. We're not rushing through it. Which another
reason I appreciate your podcast as well is let's
really get into the details and not be rushed for
time. You forget that you have a meeting
at the end kind of amount of time. No one
is to blame or defensive because it's not your
product at all. It's a random group of people.
We don't even introduce ourselves about what team
we worked on. We're just all here as participants
to embody the customer. And then I think lastly,
a reason why it's worked, and these are many of
these just been actually super surprising to me.
I wouldn't have been able to prick ahead of time,
is it's just fun. People want to make up
the name of the company. They're excited
about what Dolphin Industries would sell. A
person who's not a CTO in real life gets to
pretend to be a CTO and there's little theatrics
to it, but it has been different enough from our
other approaches for a company like Stripe,
which is already pretty focused on this topic,
that we think that there's enough legs here that
we're going to keep it and kind invest in groups
pretending to be the customer and going through
it painstakingly slowly rather than only demos or
only writing, which has other benefits, but misses
the participation of a larger group and more fresh
eyes. So it's been fun and we named it Study
Group. I guess, I named it Study Group because I
wasn't sure it would be initially. So I just came
up with something that sounded cutesy, but gave
me enough leeway that we could kind of adjust
it over time. And this is where we've landed.
It's fascinating that there's so much theatrics
and ceremony necessary for a product team and a
company to find out these things about their
product. You would think people are like,
"Oh, we know how onboarding looks. We
know all these things," but basically
what you're saying is you don't,
and you need to do these sorts of
things in order to really know what
your product is like these days.
The customer does not live in our walls. They
aren't. They're not here. They don't know our
lingo. And it is just so natural for our internal
mindset and lingo to flow into the application
over time. And you need some counterbalance to
get there. And I think it has to be an unnatural
counterbalance. It used to frustrate me actually
more like, "Wow, why aren't we doing this?" Well,
we're actually doing great work to move
something forward and we have our local
optimizations. It'd be difficult to get to
this level of specialization that multi-product
companies are trying to do without that level
of focus on a per team basis, but then you need
something unnatural to help us bring it back.
And so, I'm constantly looking for non-punitive
fun ways objectively to get more perspectives from
the outside in. If it's breaking the fourth wall
to get on the phone on Twitter, if it's looking at
a metric of users having a bad day, which is just
like counting what's happening, you can't argue
with that. Or a random group of people just kind
of scratching their head trying to find a button,
those are truths in the world that we're trying to
make sure are inputs to all of our teams. And
if you don't have those inputs, I can totally
naturally see where the entropy of the world leads
you to have Frankenstein bad products, even when
all the individual parts are well oiled and run
by great people. So you need something unnatural.
There's an interesting trend and thread through
our talk so far broadly, there's just an obsession
with making something great and awesome. And
then a layer below is just an obsession with
the user experience being as great as possible.
And for a lot of PMs, there's not a direct line
between make the experience as amazing as possible
to growth and revenue and success and things like
that. And it feels like for you and for Stripe
broadly, there's this innate implication. If
we're making the experience better and better and
better, we will grow. You're nodding your head a
little sideways a little bit, so I'd love to hear
just your thoughts on just this obsession with
experience and user issues. But we also have to go
to the business. What are the metrics are moving?
If someone else has a strategy for moving revenue
that isn't getting it from customers, I want to
know about it because it's so hard to get it
from customers. If there's some faster path,
please tweet me and tell me about it because this
is very hard, a lot of work to do. So if there's
something else, I want it on the table, but I
often find it's part of the product experience.
So maybe it's internal sales tools. We can
do a Study Group about our internal sales
tools process and our deal desk and our margin
structure. We can do a friction log on our third
party vendor process or a migration service
or the way an ecosystem partner helps deploy
our services into a big enterprise. Nothing
is sort of off limits from product. In fact,
I was chatting with a friend who runs the company
and they were small company on the verge of
product market fit starting to feel, customers
starting to pull and they're like, "Oh, but our
self-service funnel, it's so leaky and we have
all this support coming through self-service."
First of all, congratulations, unbelievable
that they're going through your product,
even attempting self-service and contacting
you. The majority case would be no one tries
or they try and fail and don't contact you.
So again, what a problem to have. And two,
they wanted to minimize the support. In
that particular case, it's like, "Well,
what's actually in those support tickets?
What's in those sales? Those are really sales
contacts." They're like, "Oh, they want to
learn more about how they get started." They
want to know the expertise about... This is a
particular company, it's a healthcare related
company. They wanted to know the healthcare
choices available. They wanted to know how
to migrate from some old system they had to it.
I was like, "That's the product. The thing you're
talking about is the product." Turn those moments
during your self-serve process into not self-serve
and make the product experience be let's get you
on the phone. And now when they get on the phone,
they know the first name of the person
they're talking to because they have it
from the onboarding forum and all of a sudden
it feels like you are still in the product,
but it's not software. Now it's a person, but it's
a person backed by internal software, which knows
as much as they can about the customer and what
they want. And I was really inspired by Fidelity,
which is a big financial institution where many
people listening might have switched jobs and had
to move their 401(k) or something like this from
job A to job B. Maybe in some universe it'll be
three clicks, but not today or certainly not when
I tried a couple of years ago. You got a call and
go on a phone tree and all the shenanigans, and
then I got on the line with someone from Fidelity.
They're like, "Hi, Jeff. They knew about the old
company. They confirmed my address." They said,
"By the way, this is not a digital process yet.
We're going to FedEx you an envelope and inside
it is going to be the thing for you to sign.
Here's going to be exactly where to sign. Here's
a picture we're going to sign. We've put another
envelope inside that envelope ready to go. And so,
you just take the papers from envelope one, sign
them where it says and put them in envelope two
and put it back to the [inaudible 01:29:16]."
It's like, "Wow, that is product." That is a
product experience where I think some people
would say, "Oh look, the product experience
has to only be in software." So I feel when
people think, oh, product quality and craft
has some limit towards business value, there's
some asymptote that you have to be like, well,
kind of product plate time quality is over. We
need to talk about business. It's like, let's
figure out exactly what is causing the business to
happen and make a product, even if it doesn't look
naturally the same as our SaaS, software, browser,
mobile, whatever versions. I think we can see the
entire experience as it. And from there, I include
the sales process, I include the support process,
I include tools that help with compliance and
everything else. And again, if people have a
way to make all those things bad and lead to great
increasing revenue over time in sustainable ways,
I want to know about that because that sounds so
much easier than the version that we're trying.
I love that and clearly it's worked for
Stripe. Just one last question. I want
to talk about Atlas and dive into just
like what is Atlas and how is it doing
and things like that. I know there's some
new stuff coming that you're going to share,
but one last question about Study Groups. How
do you decide what product you're going to pick
to do a Study Group on? And then what is the
expectation with the result? I imagine there's
a PM sitting around like, "Oh my God, I just
got this 10 page report on all the problems."
So initially, I just made up a list of stuff
that I thought would be fun to Study Group to
kind of kick it off. And now, because it has
a bit of an internal brand and it's exciting,
and people who have gone to a Study Group
say nice things about Study Group there,
they actually proactively say, "Hey, we should
Study Group blah," or "We're launching something
next week. We should Study Group it before
it goes out the door." Or now I actually just
have a huge backlog of things to Study Group
based on what people want. And now we're again
franchising it. So we're going to have Study Group
captains and people run their own Study Groups,
and so we can really scale this behavior. But
we did our first Study Group of an internal
tool recently. And so, that I think is going
to catch on just anything at all can be Study
Group. It just takes about an hour and a couple
of people and you open up the Zoom and that's it.
And then for expectation wise, look, it
is so tempting to put more regulation on
something. Okay, well, everything coming
out of this program needs to be scored and
rubricked and have SLAs. That is extremely
reasonable. As some of these next steps,
we do notice things that are of serious issues and
we have some formal processes inside of Stripe for
elevating bugs to certain priority levels that get
tagged and have SLAs for teams to acknowledge and
review. And so we kind of funnel the outputs
of a Study Group into our already existing
formal processes rather than having some new
special thing that's going to bother a particular
team. I will say though that it is difficult to
watch one of these Study Groups and if you are
the team involved in some piece of it and not want
to act on it, because seeing your fellow teammates
struggle to use your thing in some way is more
motivating than the customer because you can kind
of always say to the customer, " Well, they didn't
really know," or "They have some special setup."
Well, they didn't really know or they have some
special setup. You probably shouldn't say those
things, but you can kind of rationalize it,
whereas a group of people incentivized to have
actually accomplished it, who got together to do
so painstakingly slowly not being able to do so if
that's not what excites you as a product person
to want to solve, this thing's not for you. But
then again, you have your own organization
system, you have your own things you need
to ship and study group doesn't have a mandate
that comes from it. We have our own. It's more
of a cultural piece of information that is very
high signal and then people tend to use that high
signal for good prioritization. I will say though,
that we have added the SLAs to certain bug levels
that begin to match a bit of our incident process.
So in an incident strike, like in many companies,
pencils down, fix the problem, severity levels,
non-negotiable Slack rooms happen, war rooms, all
that stuff. You don't want to do that with every
single bug, but we have a rubric of craft related
tags for our bug system. And if it is a sort of
a P0 bug, which is not an incident, right, it
doesn't mean to put down your pencils. You do need
to acknowledge it at Stripe within seven days. And
even if it doesn't mean to fix it, it's like a
person looks at it and says, "Hey, we're going
to do it or not do it." That's a still pretty
strong bar for a non-incident related craft issue.
It feels just at Stripe, there's this cultural
focus on we want to make the product great, we
want to make the experience as great as possible.
A lot of companies, it's just teams. We have this
goal. We're not going to do anything that isn't
driving this metric and goal that we have. And
I think for teams like that, it's hard to hear
just like, oh, someone's going to send you all
of these problems that you experience. There's the
negative version where the founders goes through
the product like a CO of a larger company, just,
oh my God, look at all these problems. You need
to fix these immediately. And a lot of times it's
completely distracting from the things they need
to do, the goals they're trying to drive, things
that really, really matter that the CO may not be
thinking about. And it feels like you're trying to
find this balance of here's problems that exist.
You don't need to fix them. You probably should.
Here's the most important stuff. But also there's
often you find a correlation between make the
experience better, you're going to do better.
There's a huge amount of trust here involved in
your colleagues, which is we want to provide teams
great information and the best teams welcome that
information. It doesn't mean that it comes with a
auteur opinion from the outside world that says
you must do X. We have a rubric on some of the
craft related bugs, but again, we let the teams
relabel them. And so maybe it's actually not a
P0 from their eyes and that's the trust we put
in the teams. I think that the failure mode is
when you don't look. And so we need unnatural,
safe, fun lore that gets us out of our chair and
into the customer's mindset. Best is if it's you
and you're your own customer, okay. Second best
would be sitting right next to the customer in the
outside world and then like, okay, fine, I'll take
a third best, which is pantomime the customer and
enforcing you don't use any internal knowledge. If
you have practices in those three categories,
I'm comfortable with the failure modes.
I love that. This is definitely going to
be the longest episode I've ever done,
which is exactly what I expected
and I'm happy that we're doing this.
Everyone go 1.75X or something.
I like when people are like, oh, this
episode is really good. I had to slow
down to 1.75 or something. How are
you even listening at that speed? No,
it's 1.0 speed. That's what this episode needs
to be. There's two more areas I want to spend
some time on. One is Atlas. We've talked a
lot about on the surface of Atlas. I want
to help people understand what the hell it is
and the stuff that's happening there. And two,
I want to talk about getting stuff done at
a big company, something that you've done
at Stripe and I hear you have a lot of good
advice on. So first of all, what is Atlas?
We've talked a bit about it. What's the best way
to understand what Atlas is and who it's for?
In 2016, a bunch of Stripes were traveling the
world, Stripes is what we call teammates here,
and they're just hearing stories from
entrepreneurs around the world. And
you would hear this unbelievable story from
incredible entrepreneurs who have a laptop,
which is that they'd have to fly to the United
States on an airplane to make a US company in
order to get access to use financial system,
to raise money from US or global investors,
often to take USD or to charge US customers. And
you could have sat around and said, huh, is that
illegal? They don't live in the US. Can they have
a US company? Absolutely. The US loves this. It is
incredibly encouraged for people from around the
world to make a US company and many people do.
Now, why did it require an airplane, right?
And so you start to hear that kind of thing
at a coffee shop amongst someone with a laptop
who has access to the whole internet. And that
is a burning problem. Right. That is not a tier
three issue. I am not able to run my business
without getting on an airplane should be sending
alerts off in your whole psyche that you have
discovered something important. And so I wasn't
at Stripe at the time, but I'm very thankful that,
I was running my own startup at the time. I was
very thankful that the people at Stripe decided
to try to tackle that problem. And so Atlas
is a way to start a company in a few clicks,
and we think that's an incredibly big deal
because while there are smart humans across
the whole planet, the opportunity that they have
is not uniform. But it's a little strange because
it's all the same MacBooks and it's a little
strange because it's all the same IP addresses
and we all have plenty of bandwidth and smarts.
And so what can we do to dramatically lower the
barrier to great people solving problems? And
we've found over and over again that increasing
the ease and simplicity and decreasing the cost
and complexity tends to lead to just more of that
thing. And we have a fundamental belief that there
should be more startups and they're not finite.
And that belief comes from both just a core hope
because there are so many problems in the world
that don't seem to be being solved fast enough by
our current institutions and larger companies that
we think will actually, we need entrepreneurial
energy to tackle them. And then it's also comes
from experience of seeing it happened. Instacart
signed up for Stripe with a Gmail address and then
Covid happened and they delivered critical
food to everyone when people were reasonably
not allowed to go to the grocery store easily.
So you just don't know what the next Gmail address
is going to do. And so in Atlas, we radically
try to simplify the process of getting a company
started and that mission has taken us to just
solve more of the problem over time. And so over
the last few years, for those who have either used
Atlas or have started a company or maybe follow
along on Twitter a bit, you might've seen just
a progression of complexity that used to exist
being automated. And so a big one that we did
about a year ago was this 83(b) election, which
is this absolutely Byzantine silliness system by
which you have 30 calendar days to send a one-page
document to the IRS that could radically change
the economics of how you are incentivized as a
founder. And this is not one of these greedy
loophole. The IRS in the 1980s made this IRS
rule in order to spur more entrepreneurship.
They want this. And the only issue is they
made it extremely difficult to accomplish. You
have to send a snail mail in to an IRS address
in a particular format, in a particular way with
no verification that it happened at all. And if
you do it 31 calendar days, there's no redo.
Okay. Now again, if you're a product person,
you hear the founders terrified all day long
about this same issue, just alarm bells in your
head whole time. And so I had experienced
it for myself as a founder several times,
and I also just heard story after story and
I just put on my to-do list for the team,
we are going to solve this 83(b) election thing.
And there are very good reasons not to do it
because it comes with potential huge liability.
Don't want to screw it up, it's snail mail.
You're really going to monetize this. It's a
competitive advantage to do it. You can kind of
argue yourself not to do it in a million ways.
But again, back to the mission of just taking
all of this complexity and turning into a single
click. It was obvious to us and we got started on
it. Infrastructurally, we've been automating these
steps and when this podcast airs, I guess today,
it will be true that when you go to start a
company on Atlas, it will just be a single click.
You go to type in your friend's names,
what the name of the company will be,
it'll tell you if it's available automatically
or not. You can split the company up 50, 50 or
whatever you want to do, fill out a few things
and you click go and then like a burrito coming
to you, like a pizza tracker, we will just handle
all of the downstream activities that used to be,
hey, remember to come back in and purchase your
shares. Why am I purchasing my shares? I'm just
getting started. Why am I writing a check for $10
and putting into a bank account that I can't even
open yet? And then I have to wait for that to be
done to get the 83(b) [inaudible 01:44:09]. All
of those steps are now just handled
in the background so that we can get
you ready for business in a day or two.
And so this is our vision. So you can
quit your job on a Sunday night, get the
Sunday scaries, I'm done with this thing,
and on Monday morning fill out this form and the
next day be able to run a billion-dollar business
because we will have automatically handled getting
you access to banking systems, to payment systems,
to handling all the equity paperwork,
filing your 83(b) election where you can
just shift from having worrying about the company
starting process to just building and shipping.
And you'll just get kind updates in the
background. Cool, the IRS is giving you a
tax ID. Cool, your 83(b) election is filed. Cool,
all the founders have their equity and you're
ready to go on the cap table. And we've done this
by deeply integrating with the governments and
deeply integrating with banking partners where
we can get you access to the financial system
before the IRS and the other governments come
back with their sort of official yeses because
we take care of the problem in the background by
which we're faxing, phone calling, filling out
forms on your behalf. And so we just want to take
all that complexity and just erase it so that you
get the same thing the YC group gets when they
start, that checklist that they go through. We
just have the robot do exactly the same thing.
And so in some ways it is a really big deal in a
big ship because it completely automates the
company starting process. But in other ways
it's an incredibly incremental step that it's
taken us three years to get to where we had to
systematically automate the internal steps, each
one and now we've done the work to wrap it all
up into one button. And you can just watch
how your company's doing in the dashboard.
Well, first of all, congrats Jeff and
the Atlas team on shipping this. I know
this is a big milestone and
it's been a long time coming.
Yeah, Atlas was actually a little reasonable
before we decided to do all this work. It's
like why do this next step of completely
automating it when it was actually fairly
straightforward before. Atlas has above 80 NPS,
which is quite high. Apple is in the low 60s,
AirPods is 75. I love my AirPods. So Atlas
in the 80s with almost 50% response rate is
quite high. And so we still chose to do another
year of work to automate all of this work behind
the scenes because we see that companies are
charging their customers sooner when they go
through this automated process versus waiting.
And it's a little strange. You just started your
company. Well, what does it really matter to
wait an extra seven days or 20 days before you
can really get going on business? Those are
really fragile days which you're building.
And to some of our conversation earlier, that
amazing feeling of getting your first customer
and being in it with them and money actually
exchanging hands and getting that relationship.
If we can slide that forward in the
world by a couple of days or weeks,
which we're seeing, like half the time
it takes to get to your first customer,
just shave a whole week off of your company
and you can kind of see GDP being born sooner.
And went my whole life knowing that okay, GDP is
not finite and it can grow, but I've never really
seen it and now I've actually seen it grow faster,
sooner. And I think anything we could do to just
move that forward is going to inspire and lower
the bar for more people to be an entrepreneur
because they'll see how satisfying that can be.
And another stat, which really
was interesting to me recently is that we have
seen since doing much of this automation work,
that more solo founders are using Atlas than ever
before. And I think it's because you can just do a
lot more on the internet as a founder with no-code
tools and everything else and get going. Very cool
to see that bringing the best of the internet and
making it available worldwide can be correlated
with more people becoming entrepreneurs.
And I think we should just keep doing that.
It's incredibly inspiring and I think this is
going to be a huge deal. It's hard to think
about how many, what sorts of changes in tech
could transform how many companies are started
and how many companies not just started
but actually happen because to your point,
you may start and they're like, nah, nevermind a
few days later if it's still stuck in some queue.
Totally. And then you don't know where these
things are going to go. We have the sort of
cohort of 2024 startups in Atlas got to $50
million in revenue twice as quickly as the
cohort in 2023. And so we kind of also think
sometimes, oh, it was the pandemic that pushed
everything online. Those are our best years.
It's like we're seeing the earliest cohort
charts of new startups just cracking up into
the right. And that's very exciting because
you also hear sometimes, well the funding
market is down and valuations and this and
that and the other. That is much more of a point
in time capital analysis and much less business,
like just how businesses are working day to day.
It's really in the revenue that is representative
of their futures and that looks amazingly bright.
And then of course these companies go off to do
pretty wild things. Companies that have started
through Atlas, there's been 55,000 of them to date
are doing $5 billion a year in revenue. I think it
actually resets their expectations of what other
tools will be in the future. It's like, well, if
it was so easy for me to get my company started,
well why is it so hard to do banking?
Well, thankfully there are some great
services for it, but I think if we can
push people towards expectations higher,
then they will want to make their companies
better and we'll just all benefit from that.
How much of this is based on you guys
sending faxes and sending mail yourself,
like I don't know how much you can
talk about the behind the scenes,
but is there a lot of, through this
ops element to automating some of this?
Atlas is in total 10 people, which is I think
a relatively small group for the role that it
plays in the wider startup ecosystem. And we just
don't pick up work we can't automate because we
know that we need the leverage. And so we're
not going to put ourselves in situations in
which we have to compete to be the best. We're
going to put ourselves in situations where we
can automate it and be the only, and that's a
different mindset. So in terms of why we picked
up 83(b) election as a topic, when we made that
decision, we made a commitment that we're going
to do this forever. We're going to do this
forever. This is a piece of infrastructure
for the rest of the internet. That is a very
high bar to set as the thing you're going to do.
And so we're happy to take our time. This is
part, versus like go-go-go versus the long-term
compounding. Go-go-go was when we assigned one
engineer, hey, it's your job today to send one
piece of paper to the office with this third party
mail service. Why? Doesn't matter. Today, just
send a single piece of paper to the office and an
incredible engineer, and she went on to lead all
of 83(b) election work. She sent it. And the proof
of just receiving the piece of paper at the office
that we had just sent yesterday is incredible
proof. Right. We're like, well look. I mean,
the 83(b) election is just sending this piece
of paper to the IRS, like we just did it. Right.
That go-go-go as soon as possible was
extremely useful because it's just like,
look, this exists. We can do it. Come on. On the
long-term compounding part, we were extremely
serious about how we picked our third party
vendors, and backup vendors, and what promises,
and SLAs, and reporting systems, and alerts, and
playbooks, and backup processes, like it's in a
very intense amount of internal structure we use.
But again, we have to look at where the value is.
The value is in making sure it happens. Does it
need to be us sending the mail? Does it need to
be us talking to government? Not necessarily. And
we have chosen to work with third parties and many
backup third parties as well because one, there's
expertise in the world of physically printing and
sending mail that the 10 of us are not going
to today become experts in. And two, I think it
also causes us to build better software in that
we now need to evaluate if something's actually
working because it's happening externally.
Whereas when you build it yourself, again, you
have this natural feeling, well, we built it. It
must be working. Oh, later we'll add alerts. Later
when there problems, we'll figure out playbooks.
Well look, when it's a third party building it,
you're like, wait a second. What happens if they
screw up? Like cool, we better figure that out.
We better OCR all the results. We better do all
these check sums, we better... And it would be
awesome if we could always treat our internal
work that way, but because it was external,
it forced us to be more rigid where we needed
to be rigid and create interfaces and kind of
commitments. And again, we work with a bunch of
great third parties and back up third parties to
execute this. And each year we write a document
called Should We Do This Ourselves? And we look
at the other nine of us around the room and go,
of course we shouldn't. Let's go on to something
else. So again, we're just really stitching
it together, but ensuring that it happens.
Awesome. Okay. I was imagining fax machines just,-
There are fax machines occurring.
There are fax machines occurring,-
Not in the Stripe [inaudible 01:54:38].
And there are phone calls being made and there
are robots waiting on phones on hold as well.
Oh, amazing.
There's quite a lot going on.
AI is here. I saw a stat that one
in six new Delaware corporations
are now started on Stripe Atlas. That's absurd.
Yep. I'm very excited to tell you when
it's one in five, but it is not today.
Okay, sounds like we're close.
We're on our way.
Sounds like we're close. The other stat I have
here is that the fastest growing cities for
startups. Here's what I have, I don't know if you
know this, but Boulder, Shenzhen, and Las Vegas.
They're everywhere. One of the, it's like stat
we kind of came up with a little bit last year
that I'm just personally deeply obsessed with is
founding teams in which the co-founders are in
multiple countries. So we kind of nickname this.
Again, it's like giving things a good title,
headlines. Cross-Border Founders. Wow. More
than 20% of multi-founder teams have at least
one founder from another country. That is
astounding to me, that the internet could
bring people together like that. And I think
that's going to provide more perspectives,
more solutions will be local and global.
Just all perspectives are great. And again,
I think the Atlas team itself represents
this. We were very intentional of how
we built the Atlas team. It's majority
women and we have more diversity to hire,
but we're just very intentional to make it a
team that had diverse perspectives. You've been
on teams that don't have diverse perspectives of
any type. They are so much worse. There's no real
science necessary here. We just enforce that. We
had the opportunity to build this team that way.
And it was really important to me that it
represented a world we wanted things to
look like and to represent. And it just had to
be very intentional about it because I've made
mistakes in my career previously where my startup
was all men when we sold to box one of them. And
on each hire it was harder and harder and harder
to hire someone of a different background. Just
naturally folks didn't want to join that type
of team. And that was the last time I've ever
going to make that mistake, which is that early
the candidate poll must match where you want the
team to go. It's not a down funnel problem, it is
an up funnel problem. And where you have to just
make sure that for each role you're comfortable
with the distribution of people and backgrounds
in your candidate pool and go from there.
And I think that is one of the reasons why
that 10 person group is so effective, is it
has just a lot of diversity and perspective.
Another skill Jeff Weinstein is incredible
at that I wasn't even aware of. We're going
to add them to the list and I actually saw a
photo of the team and I noticed that. And so
great work. Is there anything else on Atlas
that you wanted to share before I get into
how you actually made Atlas happen at a company
like Stripe that has a billion things to do?
We just want to hear about what's hard for you.
If you look back in your emails and if you started
a company recently, you're starting a company
right now, the whole world is counting on you
to pick a customer, solve their problem 10 times
better than their alternative, get it to them,
charge for it, become economically viable and
build a great business that provides great
services. We are not counting on you to become
experts at this silliness of administratively
running your company. Imagine life without
Google Docs where you'd have to hire an IT
person to run your IT back end on employee three.
You'd have an IT person or imagine the world
without AWS for EC2 or S3 or any of these cloud
services and you're racking computers yourself.
You're just absolutely not going to try as
many things. We just see the company structure,
the structure, bringing people together to be
like that, and we want to automate more and more
and more of it and turn it into software. So we're
looking for the next things to work on. We have a
couple ideas, but we expect to turn more of groups
of people working together, that administration
into software. And I think it's just going to
unlock huge amount more people choosing to do it.
Interesting. I'm so curious what that ends up
being. If you really think about what you're doing
here, if you believe that entrepreneurship and
innovation and technology make the world better,
you're creating such an unlock to
allow more of that. And like I said,
I think it's hard to imagine and think of other
examples that could be as transformative
and impactful as just making this process.
It's funny because I go back to again, I also
hear from founders, entrepreneurs like, oh,
I can't think of an idea. Like, ah, I need a
startup idea. And yet everything in the world
is broken. And I also recall my first startup
early 2010, 2012 ish, I joined a friend's
company. That was started at the same time that
the Stripe founders started Stripe. And that is,
I think about that a lot because with the same
information, knowing how hard it was to accept
online payments, I chose to work on something
else where they didn't. They worked on making it
easy in seven lines of code to accept payments
online, which turned out to be really useful.
So I really encourage people to be very sensitive
to the problems that they see and just not let any
little hiccup go unnoticed. And I think Atlas is
really a manifestation of that, which is, let's
actually look at every single thing. You went from
hobby to economically successful operation and
which of any moment along the way you shouldn't
have had to do. And we think those things
are a fair game to play with in any topic. I think
that there are many more gigantic businesses,
important things to be solved sitting in plain
sight. I can't see them always, but when you hear,
if you sit in enough silence and you hear the same
people complain about problems, you too might find
something as big as online payments are hard,
which was sitting right in front of all of us.
And I think it's important to note, it doesn't
necessarily have to be a venture-backed,
venture scale company. Right. There are many, most
businesses in the world are non venture-backed,
venture scale billion-dollar companies.
You can build a profitable company.
It's kind of funny. We've all put this
badge of honor of giving away a lot of
your company. People really love owning a
lot of their company and being successful.
So you just got to pick the right
capital structure for your business.
And again, the amount of money that has been
generated of the companies that started through
Atlas, you said $5 billion, basically
that's the GDP of Atlas. That Atlas is,-
And that's like revenue per
year and that's growing,-
Per year.
Yeah.
Yeah. And obviously a lot of it would've happened
anyway, but still it accelerated. It's probably
growing faster. A lot of it probably
never would've happened otherwise. Yeah.
We ran a survey a little bit ago, we need to
rerun this, where we just asked people would
they have started their business without Atlas.
And about 20% of people said they wouldn't have
or wouldn't had then. And again, these things are
fragile. Right. And it's not all Google employees
leaving their job to the build something.
It's people from every possible background,
every possible role, every possible job,
every possible age group who see problems
and can solve it. So it's dramatically
more fragile than people think.
Well, great work, Jeff, and team
Atlas and Stripe in general.
Fun.
Let's talk about one last thing. There's so
many more things I still want to
talk about. Maybe we'll have a,-
We can go quick. Yeah, we
can [inaudible 02:03:08].
Make it 2X speed. So Atlas is basically a zero to
one product. I know you didn't start initially,
it was there, but you took it from, I don't
know, maybe you took it from 0.5 or something
to one in 100 now, and a lot of people
struggle with starting things like this
within larger companies. Like Stripe's a large
company, right? It's like a very innovative,
well run company, but it's also a large
company. And clearly you made shit happen,
you and your team. What kind of things have
you learned? Actually, let me read a quote.
Here's a quote that kind of describes you being
good at this from one of your former colleagues
who will go unnamed. "Jeff is really good
at cutting through the BS. You hear so much
about frameworks and all this complicated
stuff that people talk about, NPM circles,
one of the most straightforward, obvious things
probably right. I get so annoyed after calls with
Jeff sometimes because I know he's right about
something. I banged my head against the wall for
months." And so talk about just what you've done,
what you've learned about getting stuff done.
Talk about what you've done, what
you've learned about getting stuff
done at a large company. What do you need to do?
Not having things be your idea I think is
really powerful. I just talked to 50 customers
who all yelled the same thing. Here they are in
varieties of quotes and forms and the rest of it,
and you put some three bullet points of strategy
around why it's important, it's going to help you
win more market share, and the rest of it and how
you can do it well. Cool. What else could we want
to do? Maybe somebody has something where
51 people have the same burning thing, but
the majority failure mode is we do nothing. That's
the majority failure mode. So one, aligning people
with deep customer stories story boarding some
solution visually with a Sharpie and not a pencil,
not Figma initially, not high or low fidelity. I
can never remember which one is the detailed one,
but Sharpie. What is the unconstrained
perfect solution to this burning problem?
That's Pixar-style storyboard. You don't need to
be a designer. You can just draw stick figures
on a piece of paper or whimsical or whatever you
want to do. And with those things, if you're not
asking for the sun and the moon on headcount
and team size to make some forward progress,
who could stop you? Let's get some first version
working. It was very motivating to get that single
piece of paper in the mail, which was blank,
to kick us off on the 83(b) election. Again,
by the time this podcast airs, we'll have
crossed 10,000 83(b) elections filed,
and we will have done them all 100.00% on
time. With the burning use case, why customers
are going to need it, why we can do it cheaply,
effectively, safely over a long period of time,
and here's the way to get tangible, forward
progress quickly against the stick figure vision,
but with something in the browser or one version
of it. Let's just get one thing working one time.
I find proof of existence to be an incredibly
powerful proof, rather than proof by theory or
proof by debate. It's like, "Look, we did it one
time. Hey, I'm holding the piece of paper." Pretty
motivating. If we just printed out the right
information, we'd be done. You're like, "Okay,
actually there's a lot to do other than just
that," but it really pushed us forward. Cutting
through a little bit of the red tape is about
momentum and making each step not such a big
deal and asking for less permission. Then of
course, once you have a little bit of that
under your belt, you're going to naturally be
trusted with taking more of those kinds of bets.
Paired with some of the things we talked about
earlier of everyone's looking at the same place
about the metrics, everyone can watch the success.
We don't need to do big, internal updates with
long-winded PowerPoint presentations and scrambles
the night before. You can just go to the metrics
page and see how we're doing. That brings so much
trust to the group that people start going from,
"Why do we have this Atlas thing that doesn't
really produce so much money. It's charging
companies when they don't have money. We're a
big payments business. How do you even compare
these things?" To "Wow, look at the progress
that they're making against the mission,
and look at its impact on the curves."
And you start to root for it more.
I think that's how we got it there. I will say
one other thing, which is that making something
economically viable is extremely important.
I am probably the fourth person to run Atlas,
and it's quite a pantheon of people prior
to me, including the founder of Mozi,
which is a compliance startup, Watershed,
which is this amazing climate reporting tool,
also led Atlas, Patrick McKenzie, patio11,
for many folks who [inaudible 02:08:46]
Wow, what an alumni group, this collection.
We owe ourselves a dinner. We owe ourselves
a dinner. Quite a group. And now we have a
new person. I technically no longer lead
Atlas, so we've hired up a whole team,
which is really exciting. And Hayley Halvarsson,
who's joined us about a year or two ago,
she leads Atlas now and you can find her
on Twitter. She's fantastic. We swap jobs
over a course of a year, just one month at
a time, the roles. And so she worked for me,
then I worked for her, and she's gone
off to hire some amazing people to run
Atlas. So it's really quite a privilege
to have these people lead it over time.
But it was really important for us to communicate
why we were going to run this in an economically
viable way, and I think that applies to all
products and all businesses. It's like, "Look,
if you're a customer acquisition-style
product, showcase why this is the best
customer acquisition for the dollar for the
company. If you are a margin-generating,
moat-creating, ecosystem-growing portion of the
business, then your metrics have to show it." So
you can't just have half the story of just the
product quality and the tweets. You have to have
the economics. Who else is going to put this much
energy into this style of product and that gives
us confidence that we should invest it in the
long term? Because alternatives can come and go,
and I super encourage there to be more Atlas
alternatives. That'd be great for founders,
but I think over the long term, it'll be
difficult to do so because of the business model.
There actually was an alternative at one
point, AngelList, and then they're like,
"No, Stripe is killing it. Let's
just send everyone to Atlas."
I had worked on Stripe payments for a while, and
I had just started on Atlas, and I think that
same month AngelList announced that they were
doing incorporation and banking and cap table
all together, which was exactly what I wanted to
do. I was like, "Oh shoot, did I sign up for the
wrong thing? AngelList is such a smart group
of people, so customer-oriented, great brand,
I love many of the people that work there, they
work with some of the best legal minds, and they
have the RUV setup. There's so much awesomeness
here." I was like, " Should we really compete?
What should we do here?" And we thought about it
more and more like, "Look, in the very long term,
this company-starting process is going to become a
efficiency cost problem, and there's so much long
tail complexity with dealing with multiple
financial institutions, multiple government
processes, all of this legal complexity, and
it's difficult to charge a lot of money for it
because it's hard to charge people money when
they haven't even started the business yet."
We looked at it and said, "Look,
we're going to keep this long-term,
compounding approach because we think that this
is where it's going to go." And it was a zero
interest rate environment at the time. AngelList
built a phenomenal product. I looked at it with
nothing but admiration and happiness, but it also
smarted and hurt. We kept building, kept building,
kept building, and I got a phone call one
night, on my wife's birthday before we sat
down for dinner, and it was Dan at AngelList,
I hope he'd be comfortable telling the story,
who I love. Incredible product mind and he led
product over AngelList for startups. He said,
"We're going to get out of incorporation.
This is not going to be our focus
going forward. Do you want the business?"
That was like a year and a half after they had
really gone out, or maybe two years after they'd
gone out, or something like this. I was like,
"Wow." We had kept such an open relationship
with them. We had paired with them on legal
constructs. We had discussed 83(b) election
openly. A lot of people were like, "I can't
believe you're talking to the competitor."
Look, we all share the same mission here. Yes,
we're competing, but are we really all better off
from treating each other at arm's distance? We
had a shared Slack channel. We discussed when
the Delaware was slow on incorporation. One
time is because they were playing softball and
they had an afternoon off. That's a real story,
and we've discussed it. AngelList was incredible
in how they evaluated it. We're evaluating
different partners, but because of our working
relationship and the quality of your product,
and they saw we were going with 83(b) election
and the intensity of that, they just put up a
webpage that said to get started with AngelList,
if you need a company, go right over to Atlas.
That was a really amazing moment because I
respected them so much and I looked up to them so
much that they would mutually beneficially choose
to do that. And everybody was excited and happy,
and customers are happy, and it's been an
incredible relationship since, in which you
can start on AngelList, go through Atlas, and then
all of your information is automatically populated
into AngelList automatically. We've since rolled
that out with several other partners, Mercury,
Carta, others, but AngelList really led the
way there, and we maintain a great relationship
with the team. It took a while, but it really
reproved to me that they're not competitors. It's
alternatives, and if you care about your customer,
you care about their alternatives, and if you care
about the mission, you need to all work together.
Look, there's some friendly competition, of
course. We all want to win, but in the long term,
I think all parties are significantly better off.
Wow, that is an awesome story. I don't know
if you've shared that anywhere else. There's
so many lessons there that I could spin off
on and... Not worrying about competition,
staying heads down, just solving customer
problems, staying close to your competition,
not being afraid to talk to them, sharing
advice with each other, just building the best
possible product. I don't know, there's
a ton there that's super interesting.
I couldn't really draw it up any better, and
I think the world is better off with more
specialization, and it's a pain in the butt to
do these incorporations. I think you want more
specialization and more partnership, and I think
a lot of companies are starting to do that now.
Let me go back to the lessons you shared on
how to build something new at a big company,
then we can wrap up. I took a bunch of notes here,
and these are awesome and they actually resonate
a lot with Mihika, who came on the podcast,
who's at Figma, been the person building a lot
of zero-to-one stuff. So it's nice that there's
these trends that are coming up again and again.
One tip is storyboard the ideal. With a Sharpie,
draw out, "Here's this exciting vision of what
this could be if we were to pull it off without
constraints." Unconstrained, powerful vision. Two
is solve a burning use case. Make it clear
this is a huge problem for a lot of people.
There's probably stories you share there. Show
tangible forward progress like, "Look at this,
we made this progress, we made this progress. Sent
ourselves a piece of blank paper. Look at this,
it's a huge milestone." And have momentum, and
Mihika talked about this. Keep the fire alive.
Keep the fire alive, show momentum. We're making
progress. This metrics moving up into the right.
Then there's a milestone... Felt like you
had an early milestone of like, "Look, we
made progress," and then also, have the business
case, basically. "Look how much we could make and
look what this could be if we were to succeed."
Anything you'd add there? Anything you'd correct?
Bringing the earliest customers into the room with
your team as soon as humanly possible. We would
just invite a founder to the team meeting. We
would pipe all their feedback into a Slack channel
automatically. We have all the NPS scores going
to a channel, and anytime it's not a 10 for 10,
we follow up directly. Constant engagement with
a customer creates the momentum where it doesn't
need to be the product person or some other leader
saying, "We need to do this. Follow me." It's,
"Oh my gosh, the world needs this. Let's
figure out how to do it even faster."
And a tip that the team has tried, and this
is well since I've been involved day-to-day,
is literally inviting customers in to design the
product, which I'd actually never heard of. "Hey,
we're thinking about what happens after
incorporation now and what can we do
to help founders after they've set up their
company? What would be magical there?" We just
invite founders in, into a Whimsical, a piece
of software I love. It's a really easy learning
curve to create visual diagrams. And rather than
doing a UXR about it, we just say, "What would you
hope this dashboard would have?" And they'd grab
a thing, and they start typing, and they start
drawing what they want their dashboard to be.
Why were we guessing beforehand? I now scratch
my head. I'm several years into a decade-plus
building things and I was like, "I doing this by
myself. Why didn't I just assign it to the people
who are going to use it in the first place?"
Now look, that doesn't always work because not
all of your customers are going to be product
designers at heart, but more of them than you
think, and I think it's giving your customers
write access, and not just read access, to
your company is incredibly powerful. I think
I had not quite seen it so directly where you
just actually designed what they want, but I
saw a diagram of something we're working on right
now. I was like, "Wow, we haven't even had design
look at it." They're like, "No, actually the
customer drew it." Great. Why were we guessing?
I think you have an unfair advantage where
your customers are founders and oftentimes
have product skills and design skills,
but I love that [inaudible 02:18:43].
It's true, but I will really push,
because you don't need a hundred of them and
you'll find somebody somewhere who knows.
You just got to sit in a little more
silence. They'll raise their hand.
There's a quote you shared somewhere that relates
to what you just said that your dad once said,
"You can screw up a sentence if
it begins with 'The customer.'"
That's true. Yeah, my dad runs an IT business
in Baltimore to help other businesses with
their computer systems. Growing up, I would
literally, physically clean the keyboards
of his employees and dust the mice. But
yeah, he's very, very customer-oriented,
where I get a lot of it from, and my mom's a
painter, so I think there's some combination
of talents or interests there. He would take it
one step further, and he sometimes physically
bring a chair over in a meeting and say, "The
customer is sitting here," and you'd have to
pretend. Then he would fake talk to the invisible
customer. "Based on what you've seen today at the
meeting..." I saw him do this one time. "Based
on what you've seen today at the meeting, are
you more likely to pay your bill or less likely
to pay your bill based on what you witnessed?"
That's a little intense on the pantomime, but
I think the point gets across that... Again,
because it's so natural to think internal,
if you begin the sentence physically with
"The customer" then start your sentence,
you just have a much better shot at it.
That's an amazing story. Very a study
group-ish, like an early prototype. Jeff,
we've covered so much ground. I have two
hours more worth of questions, but we need to-
Let's lock.
We need to cut it off, I think. Is
there anything else you wanted to
share or leave listeners with before we
get to a very exciting lightning round?
Really excited about whatever you're building out
there, thinking of building. My email address is
incredibly easy to find. My Twitter handle
is incredibly easy to find. Do not hesitate
to send me cold emails. My love language is
Loom videos of bugs, but feel free to send
anything you have off the top of your head. I
respond to good cold emails. Don't hesitate.
What's the email, real quick, for people?
If finding my email address is your issue? It
can't possibly be, but it is my first initial and
last name at basically everything in the world,
though my handle on Twitter is jeff_weinstein,
but gosh, if you can't find my email
address then you got a bigger problem.
Okay, we'll link to it in the
show notes, as well. With that,
we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
Here we go. What are two or three books
you've recommended most to other people?
I know a lot of people on this podcast recommend
high-output management, but it should be swap the
Bible out for it at all the hotels in the world,
in the little drawer. Put it everywhere. You can't
go wrong, though. It is an incredible clarity of
how to spend your time as a leader, a manager of
other people, a very high bar for how evaluating
your work as the sum everyone around you. That was
very clarifying to me that it's not an individual
effort, it is the sum of everything I'm involved
in is how to measure it. So that's definitely up
there. A nice pair to that book, as a amuse-bouche
afterwards, is Orbiting the Giant Hairball: A
Corporate Fool's Guide to Surviving with Grace,
I think, is the full exact title by Gordon
MacKenzie, which is the story of a illustrator at
Hallmark, the greeting card company, and it turns
out to be a, again, bureaucratic, slow-moving
organization that, over time, added rules and
policies and rules and policies and quelled
creativity and innovation, which is surprising
at a greeting card company, but it existed. So
this is his incredibly well-drawn book, as you'd
imagine, with beautiful illustrations about how
he orbited the hairball of the organization
to inspire others, keep himself engaged, and
to bring creativity and excitement and trying to
pull people off the hairball as he orbited it. So
I think it's a fun afternoon read with beautiful
illustrations about how to stay sane at big
companies and where to be a little goofy and take
the advantage and gravity of the hairball, but not
be succumbed by it and to be able to orbit it.
Those two are really fun. I will say one other
one I like... Because we haven't talked about
strategy here, there's been more getting
stuff done and some other tactical things, but 7
Powers, and I know you had the author recently on,
which was awesome. I won't explain the book,
you just watch the podcast of it, but it walks
through many of the business powers and moats
a company can have. I ran into the author...
Hamilton Helmer.
Hamilton Helmer, yes, thank you.
What a cool name.
Very cool name. Alliterative. At the Box
lunchroom one time, where I worked at Box,
they acquired one of our companies, and I was
like, "Any luck finding the eighth power?" He
was like, "I'm looking, I'm looking," as he
ran off with his sandwich. One other funny,
somewhat embarrassing moment about that book
is when I was applying to work at Stripe, I was
in some email conversation with our CEO, Patrick
Collison, who is quite well-read and enjoys books,
and I was trying to showcase, " I like books a
little bit," though not at any level of him. And
I had mentioned I just finished reading
7 Powers, and I recommended it to him,
but it joke's on me because he's quoted in
the foreword that I had skipped. So he was
very kind to let me know that he had read
it and he is quoted in it, so I was like,
"Oh shoot, maybe I won't get the job." But I got
through that part, at least. So those books have
spoken to me. Do you have a favorite power, by
the way, Lenny? Do you have a favorite power?
His favorite power is counter-positioning.
I also like that power a lot because I think
it's the one you can that really changes
everything about how you build your company,
so that's the one that always
stands out to me. How about you?
I like counter-positioning also,
and Atlas with going cheap and
that audience is counter-positioning, but
I really enjoy process, the process power,
because it is very difficult to, as
an organization, get good at anything,
and if you could do that over a long period of
time in a sustainable way, you have a power.
This is the nerdiest chat I've ever had. Which
is your favorite 7th Power? I love it. But on
that power, I asked him about it. He makes a
really strong point there, that rarely is it
actually a power for people. They think the
way we execute is going to be our advantage
and rarely is it actually a power. Usually
people can copy it, but when you nail it...
That's even better, because then if
your competition thinks they have it-
Yeah, exactly.
They won't invest than the other one.
So I like it even more, for that reason.
I love it. But I was going to say with
Patrick Collison being quoted in the book,
not only was he wrote part
of the forward or was quoted,
he basically credited 7 Powers of
helping build Stripe. No big deal.
Totally.
This lightning around is going great.
This is a very microcosm of our whole
chat so far. Second question, do you
have a favorite recent movie or TV show?
How To with John Wilson. It's on
HBO. For those who haven't seen it,
not really giving away anything because it's
just wild when you watch it. You can't give
it away. This videographer has found footage
where he's just walking through Manhattan,
and other parts of the country, but mostly New
York, with a camera for 10 years, just filming
intensely weird things. And if you've spent
any time in New York, there's plenty to film.
Then has put together this narrative afterwards
about certain topics like how to make risotto
or how to take out the trash or how to...
It's a way of seeing life through the eyes
of these vignettes, diving down and really
understanding people, and he does it through
this incredibly dry humor of stitching together
this video footage to tell a different narrative.
And I think some of it is that we used to live
in New York, and I love living in California,
but I miss that frequency of strangeness, and
you can see that through that TV show. Fantastic.
Movie? I recently watched The Quiet Girl,
which is a film about a young Irish girl
who is from a dysfunctional home and has
this opportunity to live with a family
friend who have more opportunity for her, more
empathetic to her, and it showcases, again,
how fragile things are. It's a very intense
film, but there's something beautiful in how
much opportunity was in front of this young
girl. It is a tearjerker, but a great one.
Do you have a favorite product you
have recently discovered that you love?
I love my computer. I'm fast at my computer.
Being fast at my computer helps me just go from
intention to just out in the world. I've fallen
back in love with Raycast, which is an automation
tool for those who have watched the journey of
Spotlight and Quicksilver and Alfred and all
these automator services. Raycast seems to have
cracked the nut on automation, nerd complexity,
but also UI ease and some nice touches and loads
quickly, does the basics. It's fully programmable,
extensible, just a huge fan of Raycast.
And then I think for product people,
if you don't have CleanShot installed for
screenshots, you're behind the curve. Being
able to take a screenshot and blur particular
things or point at stuff or have arrows and
lines and have that be second nature, fast,
instantaneous is so useful to be able to
communicate what you're seeing. When I get a new
laptop, it's Raycast first and CleanShot second.
Wow, I am going to download CleanShot immediately.
Yes, it's extremely-
I've not heard of it. I've been
using Skitch as my blurrings.
As much as I appreciate the Skitch folks,
CleanShot is an incredible piece of software.
Amazing. I'm going to do that. All right, two more
questions. Do you have a favorite life motto that
you often come back to, share with friends
or family, find useful in work or in life?
I don't even realize I say "Go Go Go" a lot,
but I do. I actually say it and write it so
people I hear that they'll later say, "Go Go
Go" back to me. I'm like, "Huh? Don't I say
that sometimes?" "Yes, you say it a lot." So
apparently, "Go Go Go" is one of them. I also-
I love that.
Say, "Let's make some mistakes," when we're
brainstorming something or sitting at a sushi
restaurant and talk sushi guy or gal, to showcase,
"Let's be creative. Do whatever you want. No
pretense. I'm not evaluating anything. Let's
make some mistakes." It's just a weird thing.
They're so good. I'm going to use
that for my podcast guests. "Let's
just make some mistakes. Don't worry about it."
At that point, everyone's like,
"What? Okay, fine. Sure. Cool."
I like the combo of those two, "Go go go, let's
just make some mistakes while we're going."
You have to use it in certain circumstances and
not for the five nines of reliability
on our API, but it does have its place.
Final question. You worked with Patrick Collison
and John Collison for many years. I'm curious
what the most useful feedback or advice you
have heard from them or learned from them?
On my first month working here, which
I guess is six, seven years ago now,
they had put me in charge of our
payments infrastructure services.
That's all the backend systems that communicate
with the financial system and all the internal
APIs where we build the external APIs and products
on top of, so quite a lot of stuff. I knew nothing
about finance. I knew nothing about the scale
that we're talking about. They entrusted me,
somewhat insanely, with that responsibility. On
the first month we had our quarterly business
review where... The normal quarterly process,
and I was like, "Okay, cool. I'll do the next
one. I'll write the next one." I've been here
one month. They're like, "No, you write it. It'll
be even better that you write it." It's like,
oh my God. It's forcing me to have to, in the
fourth week, have that catalyst to understand
the whole business and with the permission,
because I was going to have to write this doc
about how we're doing. The company had been in
existence for seven years before I got here.
It was already at some reasonable scale.
It was an intense operation, and I remember
writing the first draft and sending it to him
because it was... I didn't want to send... He had
pushed me to do it a bit, and I figured I'd give
him an early draft and he wrote back, "This
doesn't sound like you yet." The willingness
to entrust a new person to provide their own
perspective and bring it into a very formalized
document like that was an impressive... That
really spoke to me, and I rewrote it completely,
and I made it sound like me, and I've
tried to make things sound like me since.
John's is more of a gut punch,
I'll say. I reported to John,
the co-founder. Maybe nine months into reporting
to him, I would run around with a clipboard.
I was a little bit manic of getting a lot
done. A lot going on at Stripe at the time.
We'd have a one-hour one-on-one, I'd
be listing all of the things that we
had accomplished and the problems we have and
where we need escalation help and where we're
stuck and all this that and the other. Lots
of stuff. I had checklists and physical paper,
flipping it over a little bit frantically. And he
said, "You are one of the best people I've ever
worked with at solving problems three through 100,
but I need you stuck on problems one and two."
Oh man, that hurt. I was like, "Oh, shoot." I am
productive on the non-hardest problems and I was
trying to mask, not on purpose mask, but who wants
to be stuck on something so hard when there's so
much else to do? From then on, I would show up
to him with problems one and two and not talk
about problems three through 100. Even if we were
working on them, we would just not talk about them
and we would get stuck on problems one and two.
That was phenomenal advice, which I was like,
"Oh, shoot, I'm going to be fired." But
it was really a deeply impactful sentence.
Wow, what a powerful, great, helpful... That's
great advice [inaudible 02:34:10] right there.
He really looked my soul and-
Yeah, I love this.
Like a street fighter style or something.
But to your point, very impactful and helpful.
Yeah.
Jeff, we did it. The archeology is complete.
I appreciate the time, Lenny. It was
fun. I don't do too many of these,
so I'm curious to people's feedback
and really appreciate the questions.
Amazing. Jeff, thank you so much for being here.
Appreciate it, Lenny.
Bye everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you can
subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also, please
consider giving us a rating or leaving a review,
as that really helps other listeners
find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
LennysPodcast.com. See you in the next episode.