What if the product manager came to the
meeting with prototypes? What if you come
to the design team and instead of a PRD, you
actually already have your mocks? With AI,
it's super feasible for a product
manager to come to a meeting and say,
hey, I already have some ideas here. I wanted to
mock them up this way. They're probably wrong,
but at least the starting point now
looks a little bit higher resolution.
For people that want to say pivot
their career to be an AI PM,
what helped you move in that direction?
It's almost counterintuitive, but I actually
think it's probably easier now to break into AI
product management than it was before. There
are these incredible videos that are being
put out right now on YouTube on how to build
an app in an hour, that would not have been
possible even a year ago. Before you actually
probably needed to have more of a foundation
and background in machine learning to get a shot
at one of these companies building AI products.
What have you seen separates the typical
AI product manager from say the top 5%?
Really the question you have to ask yourself is...
Today my guest is Aman Khan. Aman
is director of product at Arize AI,
and over the course of his PM career, he's
focused on building products in the AI space,
including at Spotify on the ML platform team and
roles at Cruise, Zipline and Apple. He's also
very intentionally stayed an individual
contributor, which feels like a trend,
especially with the rise of AI tooling making
PMs much more productive and companies cutting
back on management layers. And so in our
conversation, we go deep on these two topics,
how to get into AI and how to become an AI product
manager? What the different types of AI product
managers are? How to thrive as an AI PM? And what
Aman has learned about how to be successful and
continue his career as an individual contributor
PM long-term? When I asked people on Twitter and
LinkedIn who their favorite individual contributor
product manager is, Aman was near the very top of
the list and so I was really excited to get him
on the podcast and to learn from his experience.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. It's the best
way to avoid missing future episodes and
then helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you Aman Khan.
Aman, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Amazing. Thank you so much for having me,
Lenny. It is truly an honor to be here.
So let me give a little context on
this conversation. I put out a call
on Twitter and LinkedIn asking people
for their favorite IC product managers,
and you came up near the top of the
list across both Twitter and LinkedIn,
so I knew that I needed to meet you. And you're
super interesting in a couple of ways. One is if
I think about the Venn diagram of some of the
most interesting trends in product right now,
you're kind of at the center of AI and
staying IC, an individual contributor,
for a long time. And my sense is a lot of PMs are
thinking about how do I get into AI and how do I
do more AI work. Two, there's this trend of just
ICs, super ICs, less managers, and you've been
doing AI for a long time, you've been an IC for
basically your whole career very intentionally.
So with that, there's a few things I want to
spend our time on. One is how to get into AI,
how to become an AI PM essentially? Two is
how to thrive as an AI PM? And three is how
to thrive as an IC outside of AI, but I know AI
plays into that? Broadly, how does that sound?
Yeah, that sounds great. I think that
was a crazy moment of just seeing
how many people piled onto that, those
posts, and then some of our discussion
back and forth on this thread. And
I thought it was super interesting,
it was this combination of product and AI
where just happens to be, I think where the
space is headed or what seems to be catching
so much attention. So yeah, I'm super excited
to dive into that and try and share a little
bit that I've learned along the way as well.
This episode is brought to you by Pendo, the
only all-in-one product experience platform for
any type of application. Tired of bouncing around
multiple tools to uncover what's really happening
inside your product? With all the tools you need
in one simple to use platform, Pendo makes it easy
to answer critical questions about how users are
engaging with your product and then turn those
insights into action. Also, you can get your
users to do what you actually want them to do.
First, Pendo is built around product analytics,
seeing what your users are actually doing in your
apps so that you can optimize their experience.
Next, Pendo lets you deploy in-app guides that
lead users through the actions that matter
most. Then, Pendo integrates user feedback so
that you can capture and analyze what people
actually want. And the new thing in Pendo,
session replays, a very cool way to visualize
user sessions. I'm not surprised at all that
over 10,000 companies use it today.
Visit Pendo.io/Lenny to create your
free Pendo account today and start building better
experiences across every corner of your product.
P.S. You want to take your product-led know-how
a step further, check out Pendo's lineup of free
certification courses led by top product experts
and designed to help you grow and advance in your
career. Learn more and experience the power
of the Pendo platform today at Pendo.io/Lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta.
When it comes to ensuring your company has
top-notch security practices, things get
complicated fast. Now you can assess risk,
secure the trust of your customers and automate
compliance For SOC II, ISO 27001, HIPAA and more,
with a single platform, Vanta. Vanta's
market-leading trust management platform helps
you continuously monitor compliance, alongside
reporting and tracking risk. Plus, you can save
hours by completing security questionnaires with
Vanta AI. Join thousands of global companies
that use Vanta to automate evidence collection,
unify risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go to
vanta.com/Lenny. That's V-A-M-T-A.com/Lenny.
Let's start with getting into AI PM, becoming an
AI PM. There's this term that we hear a lot in
AI PM, it's like bootcamp certifications
become an AI PM. What's the simplest way
for people to understand what that means
other than just it's a PM that works with
AI? Is there something more concrete that
you think about when you see that title?
So product manager is responsible for
bringing together design, engineering,
the biz dev people, operations, sales, what have
you at the organization and going and shipping
impact. So you're responsible for representing the
customer and ultimately getting to a solution to
solve their problems. I think in addition to
that, the AI component is, I really break it
down into maybe three flavors of AI product
management. So the first is AI platform PMs,
and that's kind of where I find myself. These are
people who are building tools for AI engineers.
So for context, I work at a company called Arize.
We're a observability and evaluation platform for
artificial intelligence. We've been around for
a few years, we started with machine learning
and ranking, regression, classification models,
basically any recommender system or black box
you might find in an application. And we've
slowly been translating and pivoting over
into broadly speaking, any type of AI. These
days, it's a lot of large language models.
And so I think that with the rise of all of these
tools that are being built on top of Open AI's
APIs or Anthropic APIs, basically any tools
on top of the large language model providers,
it's actually pretty clunky. These interfaces are
pretty new. We've only really had people building
on top of large language models for a couple of
years, and so the whole space is really nascent
and the tools that you would use to build on
top of and understand is my app doing the thing
I expect it to do, is really, really early.
So that's the space I'm focused on around
enabling AI engineers to understand the impact.
And if you're an AI PM at another company,
one of our customer companies, you understand
that when you go to leadership, that my app is
actually doing something and doing what
I expect it to do on the end business.
I think on top of that there's also AI product
PMs. And AI product PMs are really the flavor of
PM where the core product is centered around AI.
And an example of that would actually be something
like a ChatGPT. Actually, another good example
would be, you had Raiza on, and NotebookLM is a
really great example of that too. What I mean
by that is, the core experience is enabled by
the model underneath the hood. That's sort of
the secret sauce. You have these researchers
and engineers really pushing the boundaries
of technology forward in AI and then your job
is really to package that technology and make it
consumable for either a business or enterprise or
a consumer to really utilize that tech in some
way. So that's sort of the AI powered PM role,
where the core competency, the core tech is
really what you're packaging and distributing.
I think the third type of PM here is really the
one we were talking about a little bit earlier,
which is this concept of you're an AI powered
PM. And to that end, I think that you're going
to be enabled by AI technology across the entire
stack of the role you might already be doing as a
product manager. And we'll get into a little
bit what that means as well, have some ideas
and thoughts around that. But really what an
AI powered product manager in my mind does is,
you're not really responsible for building the
core model from the ground up. Maybe you don't
have the access to the resources or research
teams that you might have a Google or Open AI,
but you can still utilize large language
models, or models of any kind really, to build
an experience that is best for your customers.
And that's really I think where a lot of PMs
will also start trending towards as AI becomes
more pervasive from a technology standpoint.
It almost feels a little bit like AI will be as
common as the database to some degree for SaaS
applications. And so I think that's really where
if you really break it down, I kind of see in the
future, in the near future, most PMs are probably
going to be one flavor of an AI product manager,
either building tools for other PMs or other
companies that are deploying AI. Maybe you're
behind one of the cutting edge models that's
going to go and be the next NotebookLM,
or you're building around a transformer of
some kind or a GPT model that's doing some
part of the work that you would want
to do to solve a customer's problem.
Let's actually make it even more real,
what are some tools you use in your PM
work to be more efficient and productive?
I'm obsessed with Cursor, I'm obsessed with
Replit. These are tools I use all the time
to just really build a prototype and try to
understand myself what's possible. That is
super enabling for a product manager to show up
with a functional prototype. It's not going to
be the thing you go and ship in production,
but at least the buttons work and maybe it's
wired up reasonably correctly to tell a story.
There's a really great tool, a lot of folks might
be familiar with Vercel if you're trying to create
a landing page. So Vercel now has a starting point
called v0, which allows you to type in a prompt
and get a really beautiful landing page on top of
that. And it doesn't have to be just a landing
page, if you prompt it correctly and iterate
with it, you could actually get a pretty good
working UI as well. So I think that gives you
a good starting point for some of those initial
mock-ups you might be having with the design team.
I also think if you're designing interfaces,
you might want to use AI for graphic design.
Perhaps you're trying to come up with a logo
or you're trying to come up with something
that resembles almost like the user story you
want to tell in some way and make it like a
visual user story. I think that becomes so much
more approachable with tools like Midjourney,
or even DALL-E and it's really at your
fingertips to how well can you prompt
this thing to get you the output that you want.
So to me, it really depends. I think if you're an
experiences company, you might trend a little
bit more visual tools, like image generation
might be really powerful too. So that's one
example. And then I think even for 3D modeling,
there's some emerging tools there. I'm definitely
not the expert on that domain, but there's a
lot in terms of if you're building physical
products, that's gotten a lot easier as well.
Okay, awesome. I want to come back to where
we started here. So you've shared three types
of AI product managers. We've been focusing
on the third, which I wanted to get to and I
love that we went there, which is just how to be
more productive, efficient, better as a PM using
all these amazing tools that now exist. The
first two are, just to refresh folks' memory,
one is becoming basically an infrastructure
PM. That's something that you're doing,
basically building the base models and
tools. And then the other is building the
UX and actual consumer experience of a product
that happens to integrate AI to make it better.
So I'm guessing when people think AI
PM, that's probably where they're like,
I want to build products that deeply
integrate AI. For people that want to
say pivot their career to be an AI PM, what
helped you move in that direction/what would
you recommend folks try to do and learn to be
able to get a job in one of those two buckets?
I feel a little bit like an outsider on
the space myself. I wasn't related at all,
the field I studied was mechanical engineering.
I didn't really take computer science courses,
I had to learn a lot of that on my own. And I
didn't take machine learning or AI courses either,
I don't have a PhD or master's in the subject.
But coming back to both types of product managers
you just described, there's the AI PM who's
building infrastructure for other AI engineers,
and there's the AI power product manager
who's building AI products really.
And I think in both cases, you care about
the end customer. At the end of the day,
you really want to be in love with the problem.
I know that you said that, that was a great,
great quote in my mind as well of, if you're in
love with the problem, you are trying to push the
boundaries of what's possible with technology to
solve that problem. And for me, I really became
obsessed trying to help really technical users,
AI engineers, data scientists, with problems that
I thought were not super challenging, like how do
I build a dashboard to understand how my model is
working? That can't be that hard to do. And then
as you get deeper, the complexity starts to emerge
in that part of the stack and you have to realize
you pushing, you're actually responsible for
pushing technology forward in some ways. You're
trying to see what's possible and keep pushing the
space forward to solve that customer problem.
I think the same thing is true for AI product
managers, meaning you're really trying to design
the best customer experience and really solve
your customers' problems. And I think if you are
obsessed with that and you spend time just trying
to realize, what would an ideal experience look
like that I'm trying to solve, you'll find tools
along the way to help unbox really that problem.
So I think if we take an example of that,
let's imagine that you're working for a company
that might be having customers that have customer
support problems or people coming in with
complaints. And when you think about the
surface area of customer support, it's not that
great. You usually have to type in some questions
with a chatbot that's routing perhaps incorrectly,
[inaudible 00:16:13] some document to go solve a
problem. Or if you're trying to call in, you have
to describe your problem, but you're not really
sure if you're being heard correctly. It might be
super long wait times. And if you're the product
manager of that experience, I think an ideal
product experience really looks like a customer
reaches you with a problem and you're able to
really solve that problem for them. And it doesn't
really matter what's in between, you want to
reduce the friction of that as much as possible.
And so now when you think, okay, let's assume
that I'm starting with a phone call, there's
a ton of tools that are starting to emerge. And
I think a really cutting edge one from the last
couple of weeks has been Open AI releasing
a real time API. And the real time API is
basically a voice API where you can provide some
text and almost have this real time experience
with a bot that is actually AI generated. And if
you're a consumer, you can even try that out in
the application yourself. You can open up ChatGPT
and if you're a Plus subscriber, you can try this
cutting edge sort of voice chatbot experience.
And why is this interesting? Because if you're
a consumer and you're trying out technology and
you're trying out AI technology and trying to
push the boundaries of what's possible, I think
you can have that light bulb aha moment of,
I can take this thing that kind of feels like
it's early but it could be something here,
and go take it to my team and say maybe
it's possible for us to use this thing.
And so I think that's really what this whole
space is about. I want to underscore that,
you are really driven by your own curiosity.
And your curiosity can push you in a lot of
different directions in terms of the types of
tools you might want to pick up for yourself or
even implement in your own product. So I think it
truly is this opportunity for people to see what
drives them and try and find the tools that
really help make that experience possible.
To pull on this thread a little bit more, say
someone wants to apply, I want to be an AI PM,
there's two questions here. One is, what do you
recommend they specifically learn skill-wise,
technical-wise, to have some chance at becoming
an AI PM? If that's a thing versus just like,
hey, just you're a PM, build awesome
products and they happen to integrate
AI. That might be the best solution. If
that's your advice, definitely say that.
I think you're hitting on something on
a point that's super relevant to today,
which is it almost feels really competitive now
to be in tech and to be a product manager. And
the struggle is really to your point, what
are the skills I should have to really even
apply for this role in the first place? And
then how do I stand out as an applicant? I
feel like these are maybe two distinct things.
You want to start with a foundation of what is
machine learning, what is AI? What's the
knowledge that has really powered this
evolution in technology? And you want
to keep driving in that direction with
what are your interests? So there's really two
dimensions, you're trying to understand, okay,
what are the things I need to know, and then
how can I use that in the problems I'm trying
to solve or the industries that interest me?
So I think there's this propensity of you want
to be driven by that curiosity. So you could
start with your fundamentals of looking at
videos on YouTube of Andrej Karpathy talking
about the foundation of LLMs. It's this great
amazing resource. He put out this video a
little while ago. It's about an hour long,
but you could put it into NotebookLM, maybe get
a more succinct version. But the idea is that you
can really understand the technology in terms of
how it works and what the boundaries are. And then
I think that the other dimension is just trying
to use the tools to figure out yourself how can
I push the boundaries of what's possible? So
I think the combination of those two things
are really what drive the skill level here.
Maybe to bring this back to an earlier point,
there is no program, there's no college degree
on product management, so there definitely isn't
a college degree on AI product management.
And so I think the way that you stand out
is through showing interest in the space and
building your own skill set and skill stack
around what is the foundation of AI and how do
I apply it to the industry I'm interested in?
And that's actually related to the second point
of how do I stand out as an applicant? And it
feels like this moment where you can actually
go and have almost like a portfolio of products
that you've tried to build and maybe they're
just prototypes, but they really help you stand
out to a hiring manager that might be deciding
who's the person I want to bring on board.
And maybe to zoom out for a sec, as someone
who's been a part of the hiring process for
AI PMs before, I think the hiring process is
really designed to understand three things
about a person, and that's can this person
do the job I'm hiring them to do? Are they
excited to do the work that we do here, and
do I like to work with them? And so I think
by having this portfolio where if you have that
foundation of AI and ML of at least being able to
describe what the technology can do, and then
you have this portfolio of products, you're
actually answering both of those questions for
the hiring manager even before they talk to you.
So you're shortcutting the process by showing
them how you think and how you like to spend
time and what your interests are and hobbies
are. And then all you have to do is really
nail that phone interview. And as long
as you match the culture of the company,
I think you've actually shortcuted part one and
part two, which is what most interview processes
are designed to do, which is why they're this
sort of, you have to go talk to three different
people to see can you do marketing, can you do
engineering, can you do core product management?
And so that's really my advice is really,
you could start with building your skill
stack and starting with the foundation up,
let your curiosity drive you and then turn
that into a portfolio that you can
use as an applicant to stand out.
So what I love about this is basically, I
wouldn't say the hack to get hired as an AI PM,
but just the way you will come across
as clearly this person is worth paying
attention to. You've actually built
things with AI like actual products,
especially now that it's much easier to do as.
You can use tools like the ones you mentioned,
Cursor, v0, Replit. You can storyboard out your
ideas using the stuff you mentioned, Midjourney,
DALL-E and things like that. So I love that,
it's super tactical. So it's almost like if
you're applying for an AI PM role and you
don't have products that you have built
and ideally put out into the world,
you're not going to have a good time.
I actually think it's probably easier now to break
into AI product management than it was before. So
let me hit on that point a little bit more, which
is before you actually probably needed to have
more of a foundation and background in machine
learning to get a shot at one of these companies
building AI products. They required a depth of
knowledge in machine learning and types of models,
and you were probably more deeply involved in
what should the training data look like and the
split of the data and how do I launch this thing
and all of this infrastructure. But really now,
an AI product manager is someone who's building
experiences around or for other AI product people.
And so an example there would be, there are
these incredible videos that are being put
out right now on YouTube on how to build an
app in an hour. And I credit Greg Isenberg,
he's really pioneered some of this
format of he'll show up and just like,
here's how I built a product within 45 minutes
and how you use the same tools we just described.
And I have this tongue in cheek example a little
bit too that's pretty relevant, which was I was
trying to describe Replit to someone, to a friend
of mine, who actually was basically saying,
I don't really have time to learn another tool
right now. It feels like there's so much in the
space and I think there's really nothing better
than just showing someone what's possible. So
I open up my phone and Replit, you can just go
to as a URL on your phone. And what you can do
is type in a prompt to their Replit agent
and it will literally build a website for
you and host it within a matter of seconds.
And what's really funny is I just built this
example of build me a signup page for this
newsletter. And it did actually a pretty
reasonable job on first pass, but there's things
you want to do to keep iterating on it. So then
it prompted again, oh, make it look a little bit
nicer, use these colors. And within five minutes,
I had a working prototype for a signup
page that I built on my phone. That
would not have been possible even a year ago.
And I think the way that the technology is,
trending is things will keep getting easier,
and as a product manager, your curiosity is
going to keep pushing you forward so that
you can be the person out there saying, hey,
did you see this cool thing that I just pulled
up? And you're really the one that's almost the
expert on what's the cool new thing that you
can go and apply at your company. So I think
that's really part of the role too, is being
interested, genuinely curious of the space too.
I'm really happy you shared that. And it reminds
me, I'm just going to go on a tangent here, I want
to get your take on this, I had this kind of hot
take a month ago or so, there's this sense that
as AI tooling emerged, that product managers are
screwed. Why do you need product managers when you
could just build things, engineers could use all
these tools, designers? What's the point of a PM
in a world where AI can just build things for you?
And I realized it's exactly the opposite,
that you may not need any other function if you
have a PM, because if you think about it, what
are these AI tools amazing at? They're amazing
at building things. You tell them what to build,
they build them. The hardest part becomes
knowing what to build, finding opportunities,
problems people need solved, and then articulating
it very clearly to an AI tool, what to build. And
then having the taste and sense of what is good
and great and what will work in the market. And
that's exactly the job of a product manager.
So I'm curious to hear your take if you agree
with that, basically that PMs are the best
positioned function to thrive in this world?
Yeah, I totally believe that. I think that
there's a feeling that executives might have
or VPs of companies might have of like we need
to get into AI, but the challenge is that there's
this inclination towards doing the same thing
that's working so far. And so I think the role
of an AI PM in this type of organization is really
to be the representative of how can we use these
tools to their highest leverage. And so if you
combine the earlier notes of, you know what this
technology is capable of, you know the customer
problems deeply, you're the representative of the
customer at the company, you're really in the
best position to get the point across of what
should go and get built. And I think that's a
really powerful position to be in at a company.
And then I'll actually build on one of the
core product skill sets that you mentioned
on your podcast too, which is influence. And what
these tools really allow you to do is up level,
like max out that influence, meaning you can now
communicate ideas, coming back to the prototype
note to design, you can communicate ideas to
engineering, and you can communicate ideas
to the higher ups at the company around
what should go and get built. So I think
when you're able to translate the idea to the
person that you're trying to communicate it to,
these tools are really incredible at that. And
I think it allows an AI product manager to be
super high leverage. So to me it's like, I totally
agree, being an AI product manager feels like the
highest leverage position you could be in at the
company right now, especially in the age of AI.
Awesome. Okay, I'm glad we agree there. And what
you just mentioned, we were talking about Mihika
before we started recording, and one of her
superpowers and we'll link to her episode
is that she is designer engineer PM, she can
just do all of it. And that partly has been
why she has been so successful at Figma
and influencing leadership to build these
products that they were like, nah, I don't
know if we need a slides product. And so
now everyone can be a Mihika basically that
you can build and design as a PM. So anyway,
I think we've gone down that road far enough.
I want to shift a little bit to talking about
how to thrive as an AI PM. Say you got into
this role, you're building with AI tools,
or you're building platforms for folks to build
on. Let me ask this, let me try it this way. What
have you seen separates the typical AI product
manager from say the top 5% AI product managers?
We talked about what are AI product managers,
how do you build AI powered products around
what the fundamental technology is? I think
there was this really interesting moment
where about two years ago, actually almost
roughly to this time, ChatGPT launches,
and I think everyone who tried it out was pretty
impressed by a couple of things. The interface was
super easy to use, it felt really intuitive.
The model was pretty capable, it felt almost
like human-like. Of course that was actually an
earlier model than what's even available today,
and when you look back on it's almost like
looking at the old iPhone or something. You
kind of have to have this moment of, wow,
that was really impressive at the time,
but now if you try to use it, you're like,
this thing sucks. It doesn't even do half
the stuff. You get conditioned to the
technology continuing to get better.
But when that moment happened and it did kind of
feel like this iPhone moment around AI products,
it was really interesting to see what happened
next. And what I mean by that is we sit in the
landscape at a place where we get to see where a
lot of other companies are building. So we have
customers that are super well known, household
brands, Spotify and Instacart and these sorts of
companies that people love and use every single
day. And what ended up happening was we talked
to a lot of folks of like, well, what are you
doing around building around this technology,
this really game changing sort of shift
in AI? And the first thing that everyone
seemed to build was actually another
ChatGPT, but on top of their own data.
And for some reason everyone gravitated towards
this particular use cases. All the AI product
managers I knew were like, oh, we're building an
internal chatbot on top of our knowledge base,
and it's going to be able to answer questions
and it's going to be great. And when you look
at the products that were built, how much usage
do they really have is I think not very well
understood. Was that the right thing to do?
So coming back to your earlier question,
how do you go and thrive as, be a top 5% AI PM,
versus maybe an AI PM that isn't as stellar? I
actually think it's coming back to that earlier
point of don't do what everyone else is doing.
Just because it feels intuitive to go and
replicate this interface that feels really
great and everyone's bought in because they're
familiar with it, you really have to think,
is this the thing our business needs right now?
Is this the problem that we need to go and solve?
And I think if you look deeper at that, you'll
actually find that the interface for AI might
look really different. It won't necessarily look
like a chatbot. It might look like you're trying
to optimize or speed up a part of the process that
humans have to do today that you can make their
life easier. And for us, that was data analysis.
We have to look at a lot of data to make decisions
within our own company and so we decided to try
to automate that. We did also ship a small chatbot
just to understand how the tech work, but on top
of that, our interface around AI looks so, so
different. And I think that a lot of the cutting
edge experiences around AI kind of look like that
too. They don't really always resemble chatbots.
And I think that that's really the question
you have to ask yourself is, what's the right
interface when I'm designing a product like this?
So what I'm hearing is, if your team is building
something that's very similar to some other,
to a foundational models product
for example, probably a red flag,
probably not going to be a huge opportunity.
So optimize for things that feel different
and new. Anything else you want to
add there? Because I have a question.
Yeah, I think that's almost like a point of
what do people do for the last two years,
and now there's this moment of this actually
happening again. And this moment is happening
around the term of AI agents. I think if you
really look at it, I actually bring up Yuriy's
point again because I was listening to that
episode, I thought that was so insightful of
he gets so many emails every single day of, we're
AI for this, we're building an AI agent for that.
But again, you're sort of trying to fit this
technology to solve a problem that, you're not
really describing the problem. You're describing
the solution, an AI agent to do something.
So if you look at it, I'd really ask yourself,
does it make sense to build an AI agent within
our company or is it just better to allow
the foundation model companies to build this
agentic layer within their technology? And
then your job is to make that experience so
amazingly seamless in your existing product, that
it doesn't even feel like AI in the first place.
And I think that's really powerful. That's the
area where product managers can truly innovate.
Because let's be honest, you're probably not
going to have these cutting edge researchers
that can go and design a model from the ground
up or maybe design some new technique to build
a next agent framework. But what you can do
is take that technology and find a way to
apply it in your organization, and that's where
I think the role of the AI PM really stands out.
This episode is brought to you by Paragon, the
developer platform for building native customer
facing integrations with third party apps. Our
native integrations on your product roadmap,
whether it's to ingest context from your
users' external data and documents, or to
sync data and automate tasks across your users
other apps, integrations are mission-critical
for B2B software products today. But building
these integrations in-house cost an average
of three months of engineering according
to the 2024 State of Integration Survey,
which results in difficult roadmap trade offs.
This is why engineering teams at Copy.ai,
AI21, and over 100, other B2B SaaS companies use
Paragon so they can focus their efforts on core
product features, not integrations. The result,
they've shipped integrations seven times faster,
all while avoiding the never ending maintenance
that comes with rolling your own integrations.
Visit useparagon.com/Lenny to see how
Paragon can help you accelerate your
product's integration roadmap today and get
$1,000 in credit on their Pro and Enterprise
plans. That's useP-A-R-A-G-O-N.com.
I imagine a lot of product leaders
are hearing this and be like, thank God
I need everyone on my team to hear this,
because I am guessing every PM and every company
is looking and proposing all these ideas, all
these AI based ideas just because it's like, oh,
we got to do AI. Here's an idea, here's an idea,
and there's all these people chasing AI products.
And so I think this advice is really important,
and this has come up a number of times,
people just try to keep reminding folks,
focus on the problem you're solving and AI is a
tool to solve it, not AI for blank just because.
How have you found ways to find really
interesting, actually good ideas for
how to leverage AI within your company or
companies you've seen?? Is it hackathons?
Is it like we have our goals and just make
sure there's AI parts to a solution? Is there
anything practically that you find helpful
in finding good ideas that are AI oriented?
There's three things you could do in your company
that I think will really, if you try to implement
this tomorrow, you'd probably start seeing
those ideas coming back. So the first one is,
you actually brought up an earlier point of how
do I measure, what should I be measuring here?
And I think that PMs gravitate towards metrics,
and I actually think that every AI PM actually
needs a metric. And every PM within a business
is tasked with moving some business metric,
but there actually isn't one for building
prototypes with AI. Which is really interesting,
I've talked to so many companies and I'm like,
how do you measure what the impact is of AI within
your business? They're like, oh, well we're
not expecting it to move a business metric,
it's not moving revenue. So then how do you really
measure if what you're doing is working? And I
think that's where you need a metric of how
many shots are you taking in the first place?
And that kind of ties into the next point which
is ,I think hackathons are great. I think that
getting people to be hands-on in the first
place, it really removes that feeling that
this technology is not approachable. So
the goal is really to get everyone in the
organization to try to use this thing.
And I think that's really actually a
great position for an AI PM to be in as well.
So oftentimes, I think there's this aversion
sometimes to hackathons because it's taking away
from company time, but what you can do is try to
come with some ideas of problems to be solved
and then see how can I use AI to actually solve
those problems? What you're going to come
out with is maybe a list of 10 problems and
nine of them you try to apply AI towards and it
doesn't work. It's like, this thing doesn't work
as well as I thought it would, or it's like
you're trying to get a very specific answer,
but AI doesn't actually do a good job of that.
I actually have an example here of we actually
did our own hackathon a couple of weeks ago, and
the engineering team had all these ideas and one
of them was this Slackbot that actually alerted
a person that was on call for a problem. So we
thought it was going to be so simple, if someone
posted on a support channel, hey, I'm having a
problem with this thing, the Slackbot would take
that question and actually ping the right person.
We thought, oh, this is going to be great. This
is a perfect use case for AI and we'll give access
to this table and we'll look at problems, we'll
classify them, and then ping the right person. It
turns out that's actually a really hard problem
to do, because there's so much context that is
missing in, well, this person was working on this
problem two weeks ago, but now they're working on
this other project and some other team took over.
And I think the challenge there is really
identifying the right problems to
solve in the first place. And a good
intuition to build around that is through
hackathons, through coming with problems,
and then seeing where the ideas actually stick
versus where they actually aren't super great.
And then I think the last point here is
really obsessing about the details of the
user experience in the first place. And you were
looking for problems to go and be solved with AI,
but I think part of that is really looking at
what are successful AI products today? And you can
probably try a few, name a few, but a good example
of that might be, and really if I zoom out,
the goal is really to find experiences where AI
is actually magical and what do they get right.
So an example of that might be there's this funny
anecdote of, what a lot of people are trying to do
with AI is automate the job away entirely. And
there's this story of Betty Crocker actually
launching this cake mix where all you have to do
is mix water and you could kind of bake a cake
with just one ingredient. All you needed was this
cake mix. And it turns out that actually tanked
their sales. So all you have to do is basically
change the instruction so that all you have to
do is add eggs. And that one thing created this
effect where their sales skyrocketed, because they
realize that customer actually wants to have
a little bit of control over the experience.
And you can see that even now if you've been able
to take a Waymo or a self-driving car, the car is
fully self-driving, but you can still control the
air conditioning, you can still control the music,
and so you want to leave some knobs and levers
for your customer to feel like they're still
in control of the experience. And that's
kind of like the Ikea effect applied to AI,
people feel more empowered when they actually
have an impact on the end experience versus
everything being taken care of them.
So that's just one insight we realized
from looking at successful AI products versus
ones that try to automate everything away. And
I think if you're looking at the space, you're
going to find so many more examples like that.
That's such an important point, that even if
you can build a product that is fully automated,
you may not want to. And that Betty
Crocker example is really interesting,
it reminds me of Blue Apron and all these food
making. I have a friend who told me that he cooks,
he's cooking a lot these days and
just finding all this time to cook,
and then turns out he's using Blue Apron.
It feels to you like you're cooking and
you can tell people, hey, I'm cooking
a lot, but it's not quite the same.
Yeah. But actually if you don't mind, I could
probe on that. That's a really interesting point
with Blue Apron, because if you look at that
product, what's the problem that they're trying
to solve? Are they trying to get people to be fed
or eat food? I don't think so actually. I think
if you're really trying to solve that particular
problem, you'd probably build something closer
to like DoorDash, which is just you press a
button and food shows up. And Blue Apron on
the other hand, is trying to get people to feel
like they're getting closer to cooking or feeling
closer to the experience of making something.
And I think that's sort of what really
amazing AI products do as well. They're
making your experience or the product,
AI makes your product easier to use and it brings
the barrier to creation down. And I think that's
really what it's good at, not necessarily
just trying to automate the problem away.
Such an important point. Again, coming
back to your main point here is just
focus on the problem you're solving and
AI could help you solve it, may not.
Okay, we went on a tangent from advice you
were sharing on what separates typical AI
PMs from top 5% PMs, and what else
you got? What you got on that list?
Actually, I'll steal this one a little bit from
our friend Kevin Yien, who I think he had this
advice when he was on your pod, which really
resonated with me actually at a personal level,
which is you have to be able to walk and chew
gum. So as an AI PM, your job is not to go and
ship AI products, it's to go solve customers'
problems. I think we've come back to that a
little bit. But you're constantly going to be
pushed by your team and your company to go and
solve a business metric, move a business metric
in some way. The goal though is to make space for
the other things we were talking about, which
is prototyping, you trying the tools firsthand
yourself, making space for your team to have
hackathons and try the tools themselves as well.
Breaking down product experiences that are really
great. So as an example, we did a teardown of the
NotebookLM product just yesterday as part of our
company. So we live-streamed it, and we're going
to do this probably every week or two where we'll
take a cutting edge AI product and have a webinar
around it and try to break down how it works.
And the goals there are to really understand
the space better ourselves. But by the way, none
of those three things are going to move your KPI
or business metric. So I think I come back to that
point of you have to be able to walk and chew gum.
You have to continuously deliver customer value
while also creating space to iterate and fail and
find the experiment that you tried to launch
and people really excited about may not work,
but in the process, you learn something.
And that's I think a really powerful takeaway,
which is to really stand out as an AI PM, you have
to accept this technology is changing really fast.
You might think it's going to do something great,
or maybe you have a bad product experience. I
think you had a point earlier as well, which is to
be a really great chef, occasionally you're going
to have a bad meal. I think that's going to be the
same thing here with your AI product diet. You're
going to try some bad experiences, you're going
to have some failures, but the goal is to keep
iterating. And that's how AI gets better, I think
that's how companies can deploy AI better too.
So don't give up on the North
Star. Just find ways to make space
to have AI propagate within your organization,
and I think really stellar AI PMs do that.
I feel like as a metaphor of walking
and chewing gum, doesn't communicate
the difficulty of Kevin's, now that I think
about it, of what he's trying to describe.
Doesn't feel hard to walk and chew gum,
I wonder what a better metaphor would be.
Yeah, well I think it's-
Dance and bubbles. Maybe gum bubbles and dance.
Yeah, I don't know why that is, that's
the expression, but it's always meant to
describe something hard that you realize
you can't do more than one thing anyway.
Anyway, we don't want need to solve it right
now. So I want to talk about being an IC,
being successful as an IC. Before we get to that,
is there anything else along these lines that you
think would be really valuable to share or
get into about how to be successful as an
AI PM specifically that we haven't touched on?
I know we've talked about a lot of things now.
Your organization might want to do something and
you're trying to get them to do something else,
and that's really the challenge in this type
of role is, there is so much buzz, there is so
much excitement around AI, that knowing what the
right thing to build is really what this job needs
to convey. So I think when you take all of that
signal and you try and put it together and solve
that customer problem, that's really what being a
successful AI PM is at the end of the day. I think
that's the hard part about the job, but also
maybe the most important impactful part of it.
I love that. Okay, so let's put AI to the side for
a moment, but not totally off to the side. Imagine
we're going to touch on it in this next area,
and this next area is talking about how to be
a really successful IC. You've very consciously
decided to stay an individual contributor and
not move up the ladder of product management
and director and VP and all these things. And
there's a specific skill set that it takes to be
successful and to thrive as an IC PM. Most people
either can't move up the chain and become really
successful ICs long-term, or they don't want to,
or they don't even think it's an option. So here's
my question here. What are some of the biggest
habits, mindsets, lessons you've learned about
how to be really successful as an IC long-term?
When I think about my own career journey
here, so much of that comes down to what
drives you personally, and I'm just obsessed with
solving customers problems. And so to do that,
that might mean I have to spend a lot more
time trying to get into the weeds and get
into the details. So I think that there's
really three areas, three things that come
back to me of what the hard part about being
an IC PM is and how you can break through that.
I first want to set the tone a little bit which
is, being an IC PM is really hard. I made a point
earlier of, it's become easier to break into
product management to some degree if you can
use these tools, and now you have all these tools
at your disposal to go build the next prototype,
but I think the bar just got higher for product
managers within a company and what the impact
needs to be. And by the way, that's always going
to compete with being able to jump on a quick
call last minute or try to unblock someone, or
have some internal stakeholder discussion to
figure out what to go do next. And so I think the
challenge is, you have a really hard job, there's
constant signal, things are constantly changing,
how do you really power through that? So I think
that there's really three things I think about
there, which are energy, waiting versus wandering,
and then amplifying the signal to make a decision.
So maybe to even just kick off, energy, I really
think about this as, this was maybe one of the
most important things I realized working with
our CEO a little bit over a year ago, which was
energy can count a lot when you're not sure which
direction to go. If you show up to a meeting
and you bring a little bit more of that energy,
you'll find that a lot of friction tends to go
away, versus if you show up and you're a little
bit down or a little bit not as enthused about
an idea, people pick up on that. And we're still
dealing with people today, and I think that
even if you just change that mindset a little
bit of bringing a little bit of that extra
energy, you'll find that that can actually
break down barriers and the conversation feels
like it's flowing. It feels like a dinner table
conversation versus a hard conversation, even
if it might be something about something tough.
So I think to me, there's this concept of,
you might still be faced with this challenge
of I'm not sure what the right decision is, and
I'm struggling to really do this analysis and
really get something going. I think accepting
that that happens to everyone, it sort of feels
like a product block as opposed to a writer's
block, if that makes sense. Where as a writer,
you might be trying to get to that next paragraph,
and as a product manager, you're really trying to
get to that next idea or that next milestone.
So I can give you an example there as well,
which is we had this moment a little over a year
ago where we were not sure which direction to take
a product feature. And we were faced with
this decision that felt pretty existential,
which is how much do we want to invest in LLMs
and the new wave of large language model tech
versus what our existing customer base was. And
it wasn't immediately clear what the decision
should be. And so the energy I just brought was,
I'm just going to be our outbound salesperson and
just start writing LinkedIn messages to people
that have the title AI in their LinkedIn profile.
So I just went on LinkedIn and literally just
started finding ways to get them on a phone call.
So I'd write some copy and iterate on it, and
I had to sit with our sales team to understand
how do you do this? I maxed out my five LinkedIn
messages a day, what are you trying to do here?
And I think what that really accomplished was
sort of two things. One, I did learn a little
bit of what goes into this role in terms of how
to message our problem and product more in a way
that actually got people engaged? But two, it also
demonstrated to the team that I was willing to get
into the details with them. I was willing to spend
time even when I was trying to push on our day job
of building a product and keeping it growing.
And I think that counts for a lot when the team
is already feeling like they're not sure which
direction to take something. And so just being
that player coach and just having that mentality
of showing up, bringing the energy, can move the
bar so much higher for the whole team to operate.
So that's the example I give of, you're kind of
like being LeBron James, you're coaching people,
you're drawing up the play, but you're also just
trying to be as involved in all of the tough
stuff as well. And I see that happen, I think that
really comes from leadership from our CEO as well,
he'll be tired, I can tell, but it's just when
he shows up to a meeting, he just doesn't show
it. You just have to kind of bring that energy.
So what I'm hearing is there's
two things you're sharing here,
which is awesome. So one is, there's actual
energy in a meeting of staying positive
and energetic. And then two is actually
just doing the thing to figure help solve
the problem, getting into sales, becoming
the salesperson potentially, reaching out,
doing customer development in your own, kind of
going rogue a little bit. In that first bucket,
what does it look like to bring the energy?
Is it just volume? Is it just being bright?
I actually think this depends a lot on the
person. I think that's actually a personal
thing. So what I mean by that is, for
me, that might mean I'm showing up,
I'm super enthused, I'm bringing my version of
energy. But to other people, that might mean
smaller things like just asking how someone is
doing, trying to keep the tone of the meeting
more positive, I think to some degree. So to
different people, that might resemble different
things. But I actually think this comes back
a little bit to an earlier point of, humans
are really good at picking up on these subtle
signals with other people. And you want to just
be putting out this subtle energy where people
feel like you are engaged, you're in it 100%.
So I think that's part of it, I think it's
the idea's for other people to feel like
you're bringing the energy level of
the room up versus bringing it down.
I had a PM I was working with at one
point that is the epitome of that.
Every meeting he walks into, he's
just like, solve some problems,
let's do this. He comes in just positive and
energized and that just changes the whole feeling.
I remember this early Lyft anecdote, I have
some friends from the earlier days at Lyft,
and I think this may have been in the self-driving
car division, but they would literally, I'm not
even kidding, this was their ritual where they
would actually end the meetings with the phrase,
make it happen. And I thought that was
so powerful, because it's so simple,
but it's like, all right, we're going
to do this. It was one of their values,
and we walk away from a decision
and we're going to make it happen.
And I think even just as something as small
as that could be a contribution back to the
culture for your team. And maybe there's
a point there of building culture too,
you get to determine the culture of the people
around you. You get to build a culture of the team
and that can really work its way up. There's top
down culture, there's values, but you get to kind
of drive what people in the room are feeling. And
I think that's really, really powerful. Especially
in the role of a PM where everyone looks to the
PM for making a decision or solving a problem,
even if it's a tough one to make, but you get to
drive the energy that you're bringing to that.
Absolutely. Okay, so your first piece of advice
for doing well and thriving as an IC PM is
essentially that energy can count for a lot. That
if things aren't actually going smoothly, you can
pull people through that by bringing energy, which
is both meetings and being positive and energizing
folks in discussions, and also just doing the
work yourself to get to the core problem and
helping people see that you're actually putting
in your own effort and time to solve the problem.
Yeah, and even just to riff on that
second point, I think that there's this
component of when you are doing the thing with
someone and you pair with them on a problem,
you have a lot more empathy for what they
do as well, because they'll describe to you
what's challenging or what's hard about that
job. And I think that there's this feeling that,
at least teams I've been a part of, where there is
no job that isn't important. And so you as a PM,
I think if you're spending that time with someone,
that means that you're learning something from
them and you're learning, having empathy for what
they might be doing day in and day out, but you're
also pushing back and contributing and trying to
make the whole team push along better as well.
Awesome. So let's keep talking about
other things you found helpful in
helping you be really successful an IC PM. You
mentioned this term wandering versus waiting,
maybe we go in that direction
or if there's anything else.
Actually, I think this one is so, so powerful,
which is the concept of waiting versus wandering.
And to me, this is super relatable again from
the standpoint of trying to figure out what to
go do next. So we talked about energy, bringing
energy, but that still doesn't actually solve the
problem of where should we go. That's just the
latent energy you're going to bring to solving
a problem. But at the end of the day, you as
the product manager have to figure out where
do things go? What's the problem to be solved
and how do we solve it really for a customer?
And there's this thought exercise, this zoom out
of, it kind of feels a little bit like if you're
all at a camp where you're trying to figure
out, okay, where do we go send the scouts to go
take the rest of the camp and move things along?
And there's definitely this inclination towards
executives and companies, especially broader
companies, to do what's been working so far,
and that can often mean let's just wait and see.
And I think that's super interesting from the
concept of AI, there's this feeling of should we
wait and see where things go or do we go and try
and figure out what direction to move our team?
And most companies might lean towards waiting to
see how things pan out. And we're seeing that even
with AI, they're like, oh, we'll just wait for the
next Open AI model to come and then we'll go build
a product around that. I keep hearing that there's
this rumor of some other model or we're going to
wait and see. But I think at the end of the day,
there's times when waiting might make sense
to see what technologies get built initially,
but then there's also this component of
wandering and trying to figure out where
should we go? Where should we take the team?
And to me, I actually think the role of a PM
is to be that wanderer. And I have this story
of, there was this moment in the company's
history where I was grabbing a beer with one
of our engineering managers and he was like,
look man, I'd show up and I'm like, maybe I
wasn't bringing 100% of my energy at this end
of the workday. And I was like, I'm just not
sure where to take things and what we're doing
right now. And it was so interesting to hear
his perspective of, in his world, everything
was actually going pretty reasonably well. It
was like, we kind of knew, he had his roadmap,
he knew what to go build. He had the next feature,
the next three weeks of sprints planned out or
something like this. And he was like, oh, the
team's actually doing really great, the morale is
really high. And yet on the product side, we were
confused, we were really unsure about what to do.
And I think it can be hard to be that wanderer. It
felt really tough to be out there in the unknown,
just trying to find any sort of signal that we
could bring back and say, okay, here's where
we need to go and take the next features and
the next part of the company. And that part
was really tough, but I actually think that's
where, to an earlier part of the discussion,
where an AI PM can really stand out is in being
a natural wanderer and naturally feeling a little
bit like their role is to push the boundaries
of what the company thinks is even possible.
And to do that, you sometimes have to be
in this space that feels really squishy.
And I remember talking to our founders
of. I'm not sure what we should be going
and doing next. And it was actually
really reassuring to hear from them.
I remember having this conversation and
Aparna, our chief product officer was like,
that's what building zero to one really feels
like. It kind of feels like you're not sure
what the right decision is or where the right
direction to go is, but at the same time you
know when you get there. And so you just have to
keep wandering and iterating until you feel that
drag of the product pulling you in that direction.
So I think there's just this feeling comfortable
with not being sure what the right decision is and
just wandering and trying to figure things out,
while the rest of the camp might have to wait
and see what that next move is. So that to
me I thought was this really visceral feeling
of, where do we go? Where do we go from here?
My takeaway here is if you're feeling like you
have no idea where your product is going to go,
maybe be okay with that. And in your experience,
you eventually find the path as you wander. And
with AI tools making it much easier to prototype
and design an ideate, in theory it makes that
a little less stressful because
you can actually just try stuff.
And I think that's the amplifying the signal with
through the noise with AI. The signal can be super
sparse you get back at times too. And then what
you can do is there's really powerful tools,
we use Gong for instance to understand what
are maybe prospects or really engineers,
to me it's like potential customers, what are
they talking about? What is their pain point?
And I can't go be in 100 meetings every single
week, but what I can do is take those transcripts,
and we literally did this, we fed them into
some of these large language models that have
super long context windows now. And what you can
do is actually pull out what's the most common
problems that come up? Having a conversation
around that can be really powerful too.
Now you can do it with voice too, so you can
pull all of that in. Maybe you want to turn
it into a NotebookLM episode, but what you can do
is actually just find ways to find signal through
the noise. And that kind of gives you an ability
to almost have a superpower, because you can be
in so many places at once and use technology to
your advantage to get that signal back. So I would
really try to find ways to scale yourself
up with AI and come back with that signal.
Anything else along these lines of things
that have helped you be really successful
as we wrap up and approach our
very exciting lightning round?
Product management can feel pretty serious,
there's some big decisions that weigh on your
shoulder. But honestly I remember having this
discussion with one of our board members actually,
and he's a serial entrepreneur, he's taking
companies public, and it was like, what advice
do you have for me as a PM early in this company?
And I was so surprised by the feedback he had,
which was just have fun. And I think if you
let that drive you and you keep learning and
you're keeping this curiosity and building
products for customers that you care about,
it's just going to help you go so much further.
And I just think it's just more fun to be high
energy, it's just more fun to really care
about the thing that you're working on.
And I think if you're constantly learning
and having fun, you're going to iterate
so much faster too. So that's really my
note is, just have fun along the way,
it really is about that journey. And sometimes
you're wandering, but have fun with that too.
I love that so much and it resonates
so deeply with me as I've shared a
couple of times on this podcast to folks
that listen probably have heard this,
but I'd have this little Post-it that I put right
in front of me as I do podcasts that just says,
Have fun. And it's like the lamest little Post-It.
Is it really tore it up at
this point from, or is it like?
It's like I just bent a Post-it in half and just
road have fun on the edge and then it just sits
here. I don't know, Post-its are meant to stick
to stuff, but this is how I decided to use it.
This also came up recently in this episode that
I think is going to come out right before this
around public speaking, this course that I took
Ultraspeaking, the biggest piece of advice they
have is speaking should be fun. So just think
about how do you have fun while you're doing this,
even though it feels really scary, and that
works really well. So I really love that.
It's just more fun than not having
fun. It's like a really silly line.
It is. And even if it's very stressful and scary,
just reframing it too, how do I have
fun. Most cases, the end of the world,
the end of my career, or the end of something
really serious, most of the time you can have fun.
Totally, yeah.
Awesome. Well Aman with that, we reached our
very exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
Ding, ding, ding.
There's a ding that comes that we overlay. So I
always have to resist not saying ding, ding, ding.
I know. Yep, I'm ready. Let's do it.
First question, what are two or three books
you've recommended most to other people?
I really love A Short History of Nearly Everything
by Bill Bryson. That book to me is so interesting
because I'm a bit of a nerd around science,
I used to read a lot of fiction growing up
too. And I think weirdly enough, Bill tells
this story of the history of science really
and how we know the things that we know, and
he kind of tells it from the perspective of
learning about the scientists that discovered
these things. So for instance, you learn that
Newton was kind of an asshole to the co-workers
he had, or Darwin wasn't maybe perceived as such
an amazing scientist at the time. And a lot
of these scientists, their discoveries don't
become famous. It's almost like being an artist,
where you realize the relevance of a scientist's
discovery years later at times. And people don't
get credit for things that they discovered.
So to me, it was really interesting to one, read
more about the scale of the universe and how long
we've been here. And I think it just puts a lot
of things into perspective of our time here,
how we spend it. And even the age we're living
in now with AI, it's such a blip in the cosmic
scale. And then you also get these really fun
anecdotes from scientists along the way. So
that one I recommend to almost everyone,
because it's a pretty easy read as well.
And then I think another one, which is
maybe a little bit more in the career lens,
is this book called Designing Your Life, which is
written by actually one of the founders of IDEO,
and these folks are Stanford professors in the
Design Lab. And what's really powerful about this
for me is it's actually pretty practical. So it
comes with exercises that I remember I did myself
as well when I wasn't sure which direction to go
in my career, that helped me really figure out,
the most powerful exercise and take away from
this book for me was basically in the first
or second chapter I think, you write out one
page on the meaning of work to you and what
does work mean? Is it a way for me to make
money? Is it a way for me to feel fulfilled
with what I do or how I spend my time? And then
you write out one page on the meaning of life.
And what's really powerful is it's really, really
hard to do those two things, and then you have to
find the overlap between the two. And I think that
exercise is so clarifying and I recommend it to
anyone when they feel stuck in their career,
because it can at least, coming back to the
energy point, can give you a direction to go even
if you're not sure how to get there just yet.
And so I love both of those books because they're
really shifting from a perspective standpoint.
I love that second book, I read it and it was
really meaningful to me. But it's been long
ago and I forgot it now, but I remember it was
really great. And so I'm glad you brought that
up. Next question, do you have a favorite
recent movie or TV show you really enjoyed?
I don't usually binge watch TV. To be
honest, I am not a binge watcher. But
it's been a little rainy in New York lately,
so we've had a little bit more time inside on
weekends and I've been obsessed with the Tour de
France documentary on Netflix. I don't know if,
have you've seen that? I don't even know if it
gets pushed up that highly in the Netflix algos,
but I think it's super cool. One, I love
cycling, so for me it's like you really
realize that competitive level of cycling is
just such another level that I even realized
or gave credit to. And then two, coming back to
the characters in the story, I think they're all
just so interesting to hear what motivates them
to be at this extremely high level. It's actually
the same producers as Drive to Survive, which I
know people really got into as well around F1.
But yeah, highly recommend it and it's intense.
I'm going to start there. I didn't realize what I
was going to get to, but it just ramped up in more
and more intensity and yeah, really enjoyed it.
Is there a favorite product
you recently discovered that
you love? Maybe an AI product, maybe not.
So I think we talked a little bit about AI
products that help you prototype. Replit is
incredible, it's so easy to use, v0. And these are
all really, I think they create really polished
products at the end of the day. But the product
that really, that I've been using and having a ton
of fun with is Websim. I think it creates this
almost playful version of the prototype in the
first place you might be trying to build, or just
something so crazy and wacky and zany that you're
not even sure is possible. And it's so hard to
describe, I remember I saw a presentation from
some of the founders at Websim at an AI meetup
here, and even they, when they were showing how
to use the product, they literally just went on
Reddit and they were just looking at the Websim
sub-Reddit that has so many posts on it, and the
presentation was just them looking at the top
three or four and trying to describe what they
saw. So I've just been obsessed with it lately
just to push the boundaries of what's possible.
I also do have another product as well. Initially
when I thought about this question, I
was like, what's the product I've been
using the most lately? And this one's going to
sound kind of weird. But I'm a little bit old
school and I actually like you, I like to write
notes in physical notebooks. And so I am always
looking for like, oh, what's a really practical
notebook to use? And this was really weird,
but I was recently given a notebook from actually
an AI meetup here, and I opened it and it's made
from recycled apples. And when you open the
notebook, it smells like apples, which is really
interesting because I didn't think that that would
impact me as much as it did. But it created this
interesting feedback loop where I just really
love using the notebook, because when I open it,
I have this positive experience immediately.
It's like sensory experience immediately that
it's like, oh, it just smells so great. And then
you want to keep using it and coming back to it.
So I thought that was really interesting to
create this feedback loop in my head of I
enjoy using that notebook now. I'm not sure what
that means when I run out of papers in this one
if I'm going to buy another, but that was really
funny. I didn't expect to like that one as much.
You're making me hungry, I can almost smell it.
What is the brand of this notebook
in case folks want to look it up?
It's called Appeel, A-P-P-E-E-L.
Amazing. I need it, I need that. Two more
questions. Do you have a favorite life motto that
you often come back to find useful in work or in
life? I feel like you're going to have a good one.
There is specifically one that I ended this
essay that I wrote a while back with called,
I read a bunch of self-help books so you don't
have to, and I share it with my friends. It's
literally just called that, that are not sure
what to do when they're in that next phase of
their career as well. And the quote is from
Steve Jobs which is, "Your time is limited,
so don't waste it living someone else's life."
And I thought that was so powerful, because when
you think about it, I feel like there's a lot of
career pressure for some people to get that next
job or start a company or do something super
crazy. And at the same time, I think what's
been really powerful for me has been to reassess
what my goals are and what life I want to live,
and not feeling the feeling of what other people's
projections of that life are. And so that quote in
particular has always been something I've come
back to, which is what sort of life do you want
to live? And thinking about that really deeply
and making decisions along the way based on that.
I truly love that sentiment. And it came
up recently in another conversation with JM
Nickels. But let's move on, actual final
question. So as I was researching you,
I was Googling your name, and when I
Googled your name, there's a cricket
player very prominently comes up. Curious
how much that bothers you that there's this
cricket player that is number one on Google
in many ways? Tell us about how that feels.
Oh my God. This is going to sound crazy, but
literally, I was thinking about this yesterday.
It's going to sound crazy. The immediate thought
that came to mind was, my parents really didn't
optimize my name for SEO. And the only thing
I'm going to do now, and I think about when
I have kids, they're going to have some unique
names, because it gets so much harder. You have
to type in Aman Khan San Francisco or Berkeley
or something to get that to pop up. So yeah.
So it does bother you, is
the take away here. Okay.
We'll iterate all that for the next.
Or this is a goal, I feel like you
have the chance to beat this guy.
Totally, right? Or maybe another way to look
at it is if we still keep using search engines,
and it's funny because my partner works at Google,
the future might look like what if we're using
LLMs more? It kind of gives me a second shot here
to be part of the training data set in a way.
Amazing. I love the silver lining there.
Aman, this was amazing. I think this is
going to be helpful to so many people trying
to get into AI, trying to thrive as an AI PM,
or just wanting to stay down the IC
track. We went through so many things,
my notes were very long and we touched
on basically everything. So thank you so
much for being here. Two final questions.
Where can folks find you if they want to
reach out and maybe follow up on some of this
stuff, and how can listeners be useful to you?
LinkedIn is probably the best
way. I'm not super active on X,
though might spend a little bit more time there,
but LinkedIn easily. And then to that note,
how can listeners be helpful? I think my goal
is to try to be as helpful for folks that are
trying to figure out how to get to this next
part of their career, whether it's involving
AI or they want to pivot into it or they want
to thrive as an AI product manager. So love to
hear stories of people that are interested in
this part of their career or this career path.
I think the thought I'll leave people with is
I'll respond to anyone that messages me, but
I do have one condition there, which is if you're
cold emailing, cold messaging, kind of coming back
to how to stand out, I think there was this note
from John Dory, spoke at the college I went to,
and he put his email up on the board and his note
was, "I'll email anyone who emails me as long as
you send me your top three favorite books, movies,
podcasts, or videos that impacted you in some way,
and I'll do the same for you." And so I
actually did that, emailed him and got
back his top three as well. So I want to carry
that forward and would love to hear from folks,
send me your top three whatever pieces of content
they might be, and I'll do the same for you.
That's an amazing collection you're going to
build. I want to see all these things too.
I love that idea. It's almost
like a mini lightning round,
what a clever idea. Aman, thank
you so much for being here.
Thank you so much, Lenny. This has been
awesome. Really, really had fun with this one.
Same for me. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe
to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also, please
consider giving us a rating or leaving a review,
as that really helps other listeners find
the podcast. You can find all past episodes
or learn more about the show at
LennysPodcast.com. See you in the next episode.