I think when you're running a marketplace, you
tend to sit in your ivory tower a little bit,
looking at stats and thinking like, "If only
we could get people to do X, it'd be better for
everyone." I certainly did that in my career. I
think that's missing the point that we're humans,
and I think sometimes we act in ways that are
non-deterministic or counterintuitive. But my
take is I'm a huge believer in market forces
and empowerment, so provide guardrails for what
a good experience is in your marketplace, set
a clear bar for quality, and provide the right
coaching and tools for supply to be successful,
and then take a step back and see where the
gaps are and invest more in hands-on tactics
just to close those gaps more specifically.
Today my guest is Ben Lauzier. Ben was
VP of product and growth at Thumbtack,
where he rebuilt the product team
and Thumbtack's growth strategy,
re-architected the revenue model, and helped
3X Thumbtack's growth within three years. Prior
to Thumbtack, Ben was at Lyft for over six years,
where he was employee number 30 and led product
and growth for the driver's side of the business,
and at one point reached 1% of U.S. workers
driving for Lyft every month. He currently spends
his time advising marketplace teams and founders,
teaching a reforged course on marketplace growth,
and most recently started a healthcare company
called Nurra that connects you to a care advocate
to help you navigate the healthcare system in the
U.S. In our conversation, we go many layers
deep on the many key elements of building and
scaling a marketplace business, including
what to focus on pre-product market fit,
how to know which side of the marketplace to
prioritize, what product market fit looks like,
how to track liquidity, what causes most
marketplaces to fail and how to avoid that.
And a bunch of examples of really clever growth
strategies, especially on the supply side, and
some really interesting stories about how Lyft was
able to compete with Uber early on with one-tenth
of the resources. As a bonus, Ben also shares
insights into how the European product market
is different from the U.S. product market, and
what he encourages European companies to change
in order to operate more effectively and be more
innovative. This episode is for anyone building or
thinking about building a marketplace business. If
you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting
app or YouTube, it's the best way to avoid
missing future episodes and it helps the podcast
tremendously. With that, I bring you Ben Lauzier.
Ben, thank you so much for being
here. Welcome to the podcast.
Thank you so much, so good to
be here. Thanks for having me.
It's absolutely my pleasure. Okay, so you are one
of the most knowledgeable and experienced product
leaders in the world on building and scaling a
marketplace company, and so I want to spend the
bulk of our time talking about and essentially
extracting as much wisdom out of your brain on
how to build and scale a marketplace business
so that founders and teams that are struggling
with building their marketplace company, or just
thinking about building a marketplace business,
can save a lot of time and a lot of
pain. How does that sound to you?
That sounds amazing. That's a high bar, but
I will try to live up to your expectations.
I'm confident we will hit that bar. Let me
start with just setting a little context,
and for folks that aren't super familiar
with what is a marketplace business,
they hear this term marketplace company,
what's the simplest way to understand
what makes a company a marketplace
company and a marketplace business?
I mean, like you mentioned, I love marketplaces. I
think I've been building and scaling marketplaces
for I think almost 15 years now, and I feel like
they add just such a fascinating dimension to
the challenge that we work on as PMs, and it's
this hidden dimension that you uncover when you
work on marketplaces. And I think on paper what
makes a marketplace is pretty straightforward,
it's two or more sides that are distinct from one
another, and they provide value to each other,
and then you have an intermediary trying to
facilitate that exchange of value in the middle.
So, that's pretty simple explanation. I think in
practice it's always a little bit more nuanced
on the fringes. You have all those interesting
dimensions, like how involved is the intermediary
defines how managed the marketplace is. So,
something like Craigslist is super hands-off,
unmanaged, and something like Lyft
starts to be more into the semi-managed
where the platform significantly shapes the
transaction in this exchange of value. So,
I think that's how I see it, but there's all those
fascinating variations of marketplaces, I guess.
This episode is brought to you by Eppo. Eppo is a
next generation A/B testing and feature management
platform built by alums of Airbnb and Snowflake
for modern growth teams. Companies like Twitch,
Miro, ClickUp and DraftKings rely on Eppo to
power their experiments. Experimentation is
increasingly essential for driving growth, and for
understanding the performance of new features. And
Eppo helps you increase experimentation
velocity while unlocking rigorous deep
analysis in a way that no other commercial
tool does. When I was at Airbnb, one of the
things that I loved most was our experimentation
platform, where I could set up experiments easily,
troubleshoot issues, and analyze performance
all on my own. Eppo does all that and more,
with advanced statistical methods that can
help you shave weeks off experiment time, an
accessible UI for diving deeper into performance,
and out-of-the-box reporting that helps you
avoid annoying prolonged analytic cycles.
Eppo also makes it easy for you to share
experiment insights with your team, sparking
new ideas for the A/B testing flywheel. Eppo
powers experimentation across every use case,
including product, growth, machine learning,
monetization, and email marketing. Check
out Eppo at geteppo.com/lenny and 10X your
experiment velocity. That's get E-P-P-O dot
com slash Lenny. This episode is brought to
you by Paragon, the developer platform for
building native customer-facing integrations
with third-party apps. Our native integrations
on your product roadmap, whether it's to ingest
context from your users' external data and
documents, or to sync data and automate tasks
across your users' other apps, integrations are
mission-critical for B2B software products today.
But building these integrations in-house cost
an average of three months of engineering,
according to the 2024 State of Integration survey,
which results in difficult roadmap tradeoffs. This
is why engineering teams at Copy.ai, AI21,
and over 100 other B2B SaaS companies use
Paragon so they can focus their efforts on core
product features, not integrations. The result?
They've shipped integrations seven times
faster, all while avoiding the never-ending
maintenance that comes with rolling your own
integrations. Visit useparagon.com/lenny to
see how Paragon can help you accelerate your
product's integration roadmap today, and get
$1,000 in credit on their pro and enterprise
plans. That's use P-A-R-A-G-O-N dot com.
You've mentioned managed marketplaces and just
how that becomes something marketplaces start
to think about more, I want to get back
to that because a really important point.
But just to even clarify this point, a key part
of a marketplace is that the company doesn't own
the supply. That's in a sense what defines their
marketplace versus they're just selling stuff.
Totally. Yes, yes. And I think again, you have
companies that claim to be managed marketplaces,
I think depending on how you want
to look, with investors perhaps,
you'll pick one angle or the other, but that's
where you get into gray waters. But yeah,
the marketplace implies this concept of two
independent and supposedly autonomous parties
that you help connect and provide
this exchange of value for them.
Awesome. Okay, so let's come back to that,
because that's a really important topic and
it's something that every marketplace trends
towards or thinks about is just like we're
going to control the supply, we're going to manage
it, we're going to maybe own it in the future,
but let's get back to that. So, you
work with a ton of marketplaces,
you've built a bunch of marketplaces. What do
you find is the biggest struggle to building a
successful marketplace business? The
most common problem people run into.
I think there's two types of challenges, I
guess there's when you're talking about creating
a marketplace, and then there's when you're
talking about scaling a marketplace. For creating
a marketplace, I see many founders that are
pre-product market fit, super eager to nerd out
on marketplace dynamics. They're super excited to
launch a marketplace, we all are, and they want to
talk about supply and demand, they want to look at
all kinds of ratios. They show me economic papers
and ask, "How could we apply this principle to my
company?" And here, my advice is generally always,
"If you don't have product market fit, and if
you don't have a good enough growth strategy
for at least one side of your marketplace,
just forget about all this marketplace stuff."
Focus on this core exchange of value, go deep
with one side of the marketplace and see if you
can rely on some crutch, some hack for the other
side for time being. And you see companies like
Airbnb and Thumbtack doing this with Craigslist
pretty early on to jumpstart their growth as just
countless examples, but don't get distracted by
this shiny and cool intellectually challenging
idea of working on the marketplace, and nail
the basics of your product market fit at first.
So, just to spend a little more time
there to make this even more real. So,
you're saying that pre-product market fit,
before you find that anyone really wants
what you're building, focus on figuring out a
way to grow one side of the marketplace. So,
maybe just two quick follow up questions. How
do you know which side to focus on initially?
And can you give an example, I think Thumbtack may
be a good example of this, of how they did that?
Which side to focus on is there's different
approaches to this, but generally people will pick
the hardest side. And so, I'll take the example
of Thumbtack, because we're going to talk about
it. So, Thumbtack is a home services marketplace
to help you find plumbers, electricians, and the
harder side there was demand. There's supply, and
you can look for, you can open the yellow pages,
you can find plumbers somewhere, but the hardest
question was can we go out there and can we find
people who want to do something in their house,
who have projects that need to be done? What is
the core growth strategy for us to acquire those
people, to find them? And what kind of retention
can we create? Can we create a delightful
experience for them to come back to our platform
and want us to take care of their home for them?
Pick the hardest side is my advice. And then,
how some companies do this, again, I think there's
a lot of different ways to do this, but a common
advice is find a way to jumpstart one side. Find a
way to hack one side, play one player mode is what
it's also called sometimes, but try to find a way
to tap into existing channels that have one side
of your marketplace already latent. And so again,
you have countless businesses that if you've been
built off of Craigslist, I think Thumbtack was
partially one of them, and the idea was like,
"Hey, we can find all those great pros on
Thumbtack. When we have someone who wants a job,
'Oh, you want your kitchen remodeled?' We
can, behind the scenes, go and post a job
on Craigslist and then we'll bring on all the
contractors who are browsing Craigslist looking
for jobs, we'll bring them to our platform."
That's an example of how that you worry about
the core value proposition of can we get people
to come back to the platform? Can we create this
delightful exchange of value? Are people trusting
us? Do we have the right checks in place to make
sure that you are hiring the right person? What
will make you come back? And once that's done,
then you can focus around how do I build a
flywheel on the supply side, and how do I
manage and how do I make sure I have enough
plumbers per market, or something like that.
When you say find the hard side, how do you find
that? Any advice you can give founders and teams?
In general, I would say intuitively the teams
know, especially the teams are in the weeds,
they know. They know, "Well, yeah, we can get
X. But what we really struggle with is getting
students to look at this." That's your sign. And I
think sometimes it takes someone else to make you
think about it, to reflect like, "Actually, yes,
you're right. This side is obvious. We know how to
get it, we just don't have the right supply for it
and we don't know where to find the supply." Boom,
that's the side that you should be focused on.
Then you find a way to add source to demand,
subsidize it, find some other way,
and focus on this side that you have
no idea how to grow. You should have a
reliable growth strategy for the side.
In my experience, it's almost always the
supply side is what you need to work on,
because once you have awesome supply, people
are going to be really excited to tap it. Like
Uber drivers, Airbnb homes, professionals
on Thumbtack. Is that your experience too?
Yes. I would say supply is the hardest side
maybe like 80% to 90% of the time. Yeah,
I totally agree. I was trying
to think of counter examples,
but I can't think of one.
I just know that there are.
There's one I know, which is
Rover, based on research I did,
because it turned out it was really
easy to find people who want to walk
dogs and watch dogs for 50 bucks an hour
or whatever. It was a very easy value prop,
and so they had a waitlist, they had just
so many people. Also, TaskRabbit is the
one I know about where they had so many people
wanting to be taskers, whatever they call them-
I was going to mention TaskRabbit as
well. I heard of that as well, yeah.
Okay. And then you talked about there's a core
part of figuring out how to grow that part,
how to grow the hard part, generally the supply
side. You shared a couple examples. Are there
any more clever things you recall that you
might be able to share of just ways people
grew supply early on that could inspire people
that are trying to figure this out right now?
Yeah, I think there's a couple of common tactics
I would say pretty early on that I think companies
rely on. So, we've talked about jump-starting
one side of the marketplace with, it may be
with Thumbtack and Lyft, also leverage job boards.
You have also a lot of companies building value
added services pretty early on as a core way
of retaining supply pretty early on. Like let's
build a really compelling basket of value for
this supply, and this is going to be the thing
that appeals everyone. So, OpenTable did this
really well with all the restaurant services,
other things that I've seen people use really well
early on or converting your supply into demand
or demand into supply pretty early on, so Lyft,
we tried that. It actually didn't work at Lyft,
but I know other marketplaces have
been pretty successful with that.
Just to make sure people understand that
one, it's a really interesting one is,
in the Lyft example would be
convincing drivers to become riders,
convincing riders to become drivers, and mostly
the latter, convincing riders to become drivers.
Yeah, exactly. In our case at Lyft early
on, we had a waitlist on the demand side
because we just couldn't onboard enough
supply. And so, we had this idea of having
a pop-up. Instead of saying no drivers
available, it would be like, "Hey, sorry,
all the drivers are taken. People are making 50
bucks an hour right now, do you want to hop on
your car and drive?" And we had some conversions,
but it felt a little distracting to the overall
experience and it wasn't a huge driver of supply.
But I know that for Uber it actually was. I think
they had a relatively meaningful amount
of supply coming from [inaudible 00:15:27]
Wow, how does that make you
feel that Uber figured out a
better way to approach this and
made it work? That doesn't feel-
And it's a different audience. You would think
that the Lyft passenger and driver is more
likely to flip back and forth between the two.
I don't know, I don't know. [inaudible 00:15:47]
Yeah, a PM at Uber outdid you guys. Oh, no.
Yes, on a couple of other things.
Interesting.
And we outdid them on a few
other things [inaudible 00:15:55]
Okay, okay. That's right. So, essentially what
we've been spending some time on here is just
when you're starting a marketplace, figure out
which side you need to drive, because that's
what will unlock this opportunity. There's a hard
thing that nobody's ever done before, and most of
the time it's build a bunch of supply that nobody
has done before, and there's all these tactics to
do that. And all of this is, as you coming back
to the main question I asked, we've gone on this
awesome tangent, is pre-product market fit before
you even know this is a thing. Spend time most of
the time building supply to see if demand,
customers actually want this thing. Right?
Exactly. And then I think there's a different set
of challenges. The other pitfall that I see is,
so pre-product market fit, people tend to be
distracted by those marketplace dynamics like we
talked about instead of doing what we just talked
about. For companies that have some sort of scale
and product market fit, to me the place where I
see people getting tripped up most often is the
concept of marketplace liquidity or how to match
the health of a marketplace. To me, liquidity is
how marketplaces win. It's this measure of your
ability to match buyers and sellers efficiently,
it's how quickly and efficiently people can find
what they're looking for on your platform. So,
you can picture a Venn diagram. One circle
is this is what supply wants to sell,
and another circle is this is what
demand wants to buy, and your liquidity
is the overlap between those two circles.
So for, let's take the example of Lyft or Uber,
because we talked about them. It might be for all
the people who open the app with the intention
to book a ride, how many of those actually
turn into a ride? And this metric liquidity,
it's a direct multiplier on the efficiency
of your marketplace. It's literally at the
center of your vision, it's why you exist as
a marketplace is to connect the two. And it's
also the ultimate engagement loop. The more
supply you have, the more choice people have,
the better the services, the more likely it is
that it turns into a transaction and the more
likely it is that they come back. And so, it's
really this incredible circle. And what I see
is people missing how critical this component is
in the marketplace, struggle to define it for the
business, and most importantly struggle to build
an actionable playbook against it. Like, "Okay,
how do I manage this? Okay, it's important,
but what do I do about it?" Basically.
Is there a metric you recommend people
specifically look at to understand liquidity?
I think the metric that I like the most is
a predictor of liquidity. So your liquidity
might be, it's typically a measure of demand
utilization. It might be looking for something
on there, maybe how many of those searches with
intent actually turn into a transaction. So,
it's your field rate of your intentful demand
typically, and that's really indicative of the
net output of your marketplace. And so, that gives
you a sense of the health of your marketplace, but
it can be influenced by a whole bunch of different
factors. So, if you think about for Thumbtack,
it can be influenced by if there's a snowstorm
out there, if the competition is bidding,
there's a whole bunch of exogenous factors that
come into play. And the metric that I think is
slightly more actionable is a little harder to
define, but so much more helpful in my opinion.
It's what I call a market health metric, and this
is basically think of your proxy that is the best
predictor of your liquidity. So, I'll use the
example of Lyft. You have your liquidity is your
demand utilization, it's how many app opens turn
into a ride, and what predicts this? What will
predict you and deciding to book a ride? For Lyft
and for Uber, it was ETAs. So, we knew that if
the closest driver was at least two minutes away
from you or closer, then we had hit a ceiling,
you were more than X person likely to convert and
book a ride. If it's more than two minutes, if
it's five, then maybe you check at Uber, maybe you
walk, maybe you take the bus. If it's two minutes,
it doesn't make a big enough difference,
you're just going to book the ride anyway.
So find this threshold, find this predictor that
tends to plateau that correlates strongly with
retention but with also the transaction
happening, and that's the metric that you
can predict. That's a metric that's so much more
actionable for teams to work against. If you're
a supply team now you can think of, "Okay,
I'm adding 100 supplies into the platform.
I want to know if it's actually reducing ETAs
in this case," or I can look at correlations
like this and limiting some of the effect of
those exhaustive factors that I mentioned.
Awesome. So, essentially watch fill rate
is the term used that a lot of people love,
which is just people with intent converting.
So, the Airbnb example is exactly the way we
did Airbnb is we looked at people that are
searching with dates as intentful users,
and then how many of them convert to a booking.
So, that's basically what you're trying to get to,
and your point here is that's kind of the output
metric. That's what you want to move, but in order
to move it, there's something that is the biggest
lever to moving fill rate. And in your experience,
and I've seen this exact same thing, it's usually
amount of supply. Do you have enough good supply?
And so, in the case of Lyft is do you have enough
cars? Do you have enough homes, do you have
enough plumbers on Thumbtack? And that's usually
where you can actually impact fill rate. Sweet.
Yeah, exactly.
And that becomes the goal of the team,
that becomes the focus of the company,
basically drive that up in all the little markets
you're in and all the categories you're in.
Exactly. Yeah, completely.
Awesome. You mentioned this idea of product market
fit and the things change, pre-product market fit,
post-product market fit. Classic question,
I'm curious if you have any insights here,
just what tells you that you've climbed that
hill of product market fit, that you might
have product market fit, or you definitely
have product market fit in a marketplace?
It's hard because to me, the two are most
independent. Maybe this is a hot take,
but I feel like product market fit is independent
of your marketplace dynamics. You might have a
great product, and it provides amazing value to
both sides, but you have yet to crack the flywheel
on the supply side for how to bring those people.
You don't have the right product channel fit,
for example. And so, this will have a massive
impact on the dynamics of your marketplace.
And so, to me, my answer would tend to be
pretty classical, it would be like measure
your product market fit the way you would
for a normal company. So yeah, it's a bit
of an art more than the science, but I like the
classic if we were to take this product away,
what percentage of users would be significantly
disappointed or have no other solution?
So, questions like this I think go to the heart
of how valuable is your solution to users,
and you can do this on the supply side and
the demand side. I think here my advice is
typically to consider that you have two product
market fits essentially. You want to make
sure that you have a compelling enough value
proposition on both sides of the marketplace,
and very often at the beginning you find product
market fit on the demand side, but you realize
it's not compelling enough for your suppliers
because your margins are too high or something
like that. So, realizing that you have both
those things, but I think you can measure them
in a way that's relatively traditional, and
that's independent of marketplace dynamics.
I love that. We actually just had Sean Ellis
on the podcast talking about that exact survey,
the Sean Ellis test of asking people how
disappointed would you be if they left,
if the product didn't exist. And I just love
that you keep coming back to this point that
I 100% agree with, that most of the challenges you
have with a marketplace business, 90% are the same
challenges you'll have with a non-marketplace
business. And people over-focus on, "Oh,
I need to think of this like a marketplace,
and all the marketplace science behind all
this stuff." And really it's all the same stuff
every founder is dealing with product market fit,
except you have two sides of it growth
strategy, but you have two sides of it. So,
I love that you keep going back to that.
Something that I definitely want to touch
on is when people are thinking about starting
a marketplace company, what are signals that a
marketplace is a good model for the idea? Because
I think a lot of people come into and be like,
"I want to build a marketplace. Oh, I'm going to
connect these two sides. It's going to be great,"
and there's no marketplace in this
business, in this vertical. What are
signs that marketplace dynamic and a business
model is right for an idea versus no, it's not?
No one ever say like, "Oh, I'm going to build
Airbnb for X," it's not something that people
say. I think the signs that come to mind are
one, higher fragmentation. I think you want
this long tail of buyers and sellers without a
handful of big players controlling the market,
because this is where you can provide value by
doing this job of aggregation. I think you also
want a relatively uniform set of needs. That
means that it can be, like your supply can
be commoditized to some extent. This is what's
so tricky, by the way, about services, service
marketplaces like Thumbtack, because unlike eBay,
where sellers, they just want to sell very clear
and distinct inventory, on Thumbtack you have
electricians who only want certain types of jobs,
but they only want it if they're available
that day. And they might take a job and
cancel it because something better comes up.
And so, this makes for a very fuzzy definition
of supply, and you have very different set
of needs. One electrician wants something,
the other one has a very different perception of
the same unit of demand, and that makes it very,
very difficult. So, it's feasible, but I
would say that is not a compelling attribute
for building a marketplace. So, a relatively
uniform set of needs. And the last one I'd
mention is a high enough bearer in the matchmaking
or the creation. I think how hard it is for people
to find each other today, and how much effort
do they have to put in to vet each other,
I think is another great sign. The higher
it is, the bigger the opportunity because
it means you come in, implement the right
processes to simplify this exchange of value.
Awesome. I'd love to know if there's any examples
you can think of, of bad marketplace ideas that
people have tried, but I'll summarize the
three points you just made, which I love. So,
these are signs that this is a great opportunity
for marketplace business, that there's a lot of
fragmentation on both sides. There's not just
a small number of companies or customers on one
side or the other, because if there are, why do
they need you? There's five airlines or whatever,
you don't need a marketplace to match with an
airline. Then two is there's uniform needs,
the needs are basically consistent.
I just want to stay in a home, I want
a car to take me somewhere, I want a plumber.
And then there's a barrier, there's complexity
to the matchmaking and helping someone book
the thing, work with them. Finding a car,
I imagine is like, I'm not going to just
flag down a car. There's challenge there.
I'm not going to just go and ask someone, "Can
I stay in your home?" There's challenges there.
Exactly.
Awesome. Are there any examples
of companies you've seen that are
just like, that will never work as a marketplace,
or here's a funny example of a marketplace
that tried to be a marketplace and it's not ...
I don't have a great example of that, but I
can give you a tangentially related example
of a marketplace that I don't want to throw
anyone under the bus. I respect the company
and the effort, but Sidecar at the time
was another ride-sharing company competing
with Lyft and Uber, and there's, I'm sure a
whole bunch of lessons there. They ended up
closing, but I think one really interesting
direction that they took pretty early on to
differentiate themselves was, in my
mind perhaps very naively a mistake,
they decided to give complete control to the
user where as a user you had a whole bunch of
filters. You could decide, "I want a car that's
at least 2015 or newer. I want a driver that's
at least this or newer." And so, I think the
theory was reasonable on paper. It was like,
"Hey, let's give people more control over it."
But you have those other players out there,
you have Lyft and Uber, and people feel forced
in this standardized experience, "We're going
to compete by giving you the choice, you get to
decide the experience that you want." I think in
reality, it just fragments your marketplace even
further, and you have this hyper fragmentation in
your marketplace, and I think it hurt their SLAs
quite drastically. If you think about the ETA,
when you ask explicitly you're like, "Yeah,
sure, I want a newer car," and you slide it to
2020 not realizing that you just lost 10
minutes because now we had a great driver,
but they have a Honda Civic from 2018,
and it's not the special that you wanted.
So, I think people who build marketplaces tend
to want to give a lot of control to the users
because this is what users want, or this is what
comes up oftentimes in user feedback like, "Oh,
we have those two distinct group of users. Those
ones, they really want new cars. Those ones,
they don't want new cars." And so, naturally you
have a product team that builds the toggle to get
the new cars, and I think the mistake is that
you unknowingly fragment your supply in a way
that has a much more meaningful impact on the
health of your marketplace than you suspect.
I think this is another awesome example
of don't over listen to users and do what
you think is going to be best for the business,
and this is not even a marketplace lesson. It's
just generally you don't want to give users more
options than they will need to be successful and
happy. And I think Sidecar did that because they
were trying to differentiate from Lyft and Uber,
like, "What can we do differently?" And they're
like, "Oh, let's give people all these options."
I think they even let drivers choose the
price that they're offering their ride at,
which made it extra complicated. They're like,
"Oh my God, all these cars at different prices,"
but I respect their attempt because they
were just the third wheel, no pun intended.
Ironically, it's almost the opposite advice that I
usually give to companies who struggle with market
health, it's if you have different verticals, try
if possible to open up your supply walls. Your
user is telling you like X, but try to give them
something that is tangential to what you think
they want, because odds are that they are actually
fine with it. There's this amazing example from
Thumbtack, it's the smoke machine example. So
Thumbtack, now they specialize a little bit
more in home services, but a few years ago they
were also doing a lot of events. So, you had DJs,
you had photographers, and a lot of people
were hiring for wedding DJs on the platform.
And one of the checkboxes was a smoke machine,
and it turns out a lot of people are checking
this. You're like, "Yeah, hell yeah,
I want a smoke machine at my wedding."
And unknowingly to them, obviously, only 5% of our
DJs had a smoke machine, and so you would carve
out 95% of our supply. And if when we talked to
users, they were like, "Oh, no, no, I don't care
that much about the smoke machine. I didn't
realize that this was automatically going to
remove half of the supply." And so, work on ways
to make this checkbox affect the ranking but not
the actual filtering is a great example of how you
can listen to your users and tweak the experience,
but simplify their cognitive load by knowing
like, "Hey, we know you prefer a smoke machine,
but we're intelligent enough to know it's
probably not a deal breaker for you."
I love that example. The other thing that I think
is important to talk about briefly is when you're
thinking about building a marketplace, a lot of
times they fail because the business model just
doesn't work. I think about a company like
Cherry that tried to do Uber for car washes,
and in theory there's a smart idea of
I'm going to just do on-demand car wash.
The problem is no one's going to pay what it
costs to do that, to a car wash person shows
up and washes your car. I think cleaning is
another example. There's also just like going-
Exec is another one that comes to mind.
Oh Exec, yeah, where it's just like
someone come does stuff for you.
Something, yeah.
Yeah. And so I guess, is there anything you
want to add there? Just like this is another
reason your marketplace might fail? And maybe
just let me expand on this question. Just what
are the most common reasons marketplaces
fail in your experience? And I think it's
important to say most marketplace ideas
fail, just like most startup ideas fail.
Yeah, most ideas period fail, I think. Yes.
Most ideas period fail, same. Coming back to
most of the things you're going to struggle
with are the same things that every company
struggles with outside of marketplace.
So, let me just ask, is maybe specifically
within marketplaces or even just broadly,
what are the biggest reasons
that marketplaces fail?
I think a few things come to mind. One is this
concept of liquidity that we've talked about. So,
you need to kick off this flywheel, you need
to build enough of that density within your
marketplace. And depending on the business, you
can take a lot of time or money, and without the
right diagnostic framework you can end up running
out of both. And so it's like, that's the same
one, and I felt this at Lyft, I've seen this at
other companies, this rush like, "Wow, we have to
get to this point, otherwise we know it's a losing
battle until we have enough density for both sides
to have a good enough experience." The other one
that I see is ignoring one side. So, we talked
about doing that when you're early on, but I see a
lot of larger companies operating for too long as
one-sided businesses. Many large marketplaces
only thinking about their demand side funnel.
So they run ads, they get clicks, they turn those
clicks into dollars, and they try to get enough
supplies that intuitively the experience
is good enough for users. And my advice is,
if you're doing this you're missing out on half
of your business. And the trick is marketplaces
are very laggy, so once your network effects start
to die down it turns into this moment of panic of,
"Oh shoot, we forgot about half of our
users. We forgot that sellers are people too,
and they're all leaving, and now we need to
completely transform our product to save the ship,
and to create a compelling value proposition
on their side." So, that's the other thing
that I see is businesses realizing that they are
marketplaces with true marketplace needs too late
in the game. And the last one is quality. I think
we talked a little bit about the quality before,
but it doesn't mean that you always need to have
the best quality in your marketplace, but being
a marketplace implies a level of curation.
You need to be intentional about the quality
that you aim to provide, and I think a lot
of companies don't have necessarily that
intentionality and you have this constant push of
supply, "If only we'd lower our bar a little bit,
we could get more supply." And so until you end
up, we've all experienced this at some point,
you found some e-commerce website, you look for
something and there is also like, "Oh my god, this
looks super shady," because all the sellers don't
look that great. That's a quality problem. And so,
you need to be intentional about your quality and
I think that's another area where companies fail.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta. When
it comes to ensuring your company has top-notch
security practices, things get complicated fast.
Now you can assess risk, secure the trust of your
customers, and automate compliance for SOC II,
ISO 27,001, HIPAA and more with a single platform,
Vanta. Vanta's market-leading trust management
platform helps you continuously monitor compliance
alongside reporting and tracking risk. Plus,
you can save hours by completing security
questionnaires with Vanta AI. Join thousands
of global companies that use Vanta to automate
evidence collection, unify risk management,
and streamline security reviews. Get $1,000
off Vanta when you go to vanta.com/lenny.
That's V-A-N-T-A dot com slash Lenny.
Kind of as a segue from that idea of quality,
I want to talk about managed marketplaces,
managed supply. So, I think the reason quality is
such an issue for marketplaces is because you do
not own the supply and control the supply your
marketplace, you're not just selling something,
quality is innately going to be a
challenge. Airbnb doesn't own homes,
Uber doesn't employee drivers. They can't
even legally tell them exactly what to do
because their contractors, so quality is always
this ongoing challenge with marketplaces. So,
there's always this push towards making it more
of a managed marketplace. We give people a lot
more instruction, maybe they own some of the
supply, maybe they invest a lot in training,
all that kind of stuff. And in a perfect
world, not unlike an idealized world,
quality will be best if you own it. But then
you're no longer marketplace, your business
model sucks. I guess just any thoughts on
marketplaces that are considering becoming
more managed? Any advice on when it makes sense
to move towards that spectrum, and how far to go?
I think when you're running a marketplace, you
tend to sit in your ivory tower a little bit
looking at stats and thinking, "If only we could
get people to do X, it'd be better for everyone."
And I certainly did that in my career. I think
that's missing the point that we're humans,
and I think sometimes we act in ways that are
non-deterministic or intuitive. I'll mention
another example, but we'd originally sell leads
to pros like plumbers and electricians. And of
those leads, obviously only a fraction would turn
into actual jobs and revenue for those pros. So,
we also saw that those pros were always great at
converting leads into jobs. And so, naturally we
thought that we could provide a more consistent
experience for customers and for pros by improving
their ROI and selling bookings directly to those
pros. It's a common marketplace move, going from
some version of lead to a direct booking.
And digital, great. We knew we were going to
improve their ROI by something like 20% maybe, and
we launched this and pros hated it. They hated it
because they actually subconsciously, they liked
the thrill of the sale. They loved this contact
with customer, and they sometimes completely
overestimated their ability to close the customer.
They were like, "You took all those phone calls,
they kept me busy. I felt like I was hustling,
I was about to close this customer." And so,
no matter what the data says of like, "Oh, we
increased their earnings by 20%," the pros don't
feel this way and it's the right to feel however
they want. And we saw the same thing at Lyft when
trying to make driver earnings less volatile,
we had to fight a lot of that perception and a lot
of that peak end effect. So, my call-out here is
any attempt at control can be really tricky
and backfire in ways that are unpredictable.
You also touched on employment classification. In
the U.S., when you talk about controlling supply,
all the lawyers are like, "No, no, no, that's not
something that we do." Because if you control your
supply, then there can be legally classified
as employees and be entitled to a whole bunch
of benefits. So, my take on this in general is
I'm a huge believer, and it really depends on
the type of company I should say, obviously, but
my take is I'm a huge believer in market forces
and empowerment. So, provide guardrails for
what a good experience is in your marketplace,
set a clear bar for quality, and provide the right
coaching and tools for supply to be successful.
And then take a step back and see where the
gaps are, and invest more in hands-on tactics
just to close those gaps more specifically.
So, lots of coaching tools that Lyft, Uber did it,
like most marketplaces provide some sort of
coaching. You have a review system perhaps,
you have stars for your sellers, for sellers who
fall below the threshold then coach them, provide
them the right tools, the right guidance, what is
the standard that you have on your marketplace and
help them meet that bar. And for people who fall
through the gaps that you have, then that's when
you invest in more hands-on tools. And this is
one of the things that we did at Lyft also with
the rental company that we spent up. I'm happy
to tell you more about that, that's interesting.
I'd love to hear about that. Before we hear that,
is there any marketplace that has been very good
at upleveling quality without becoming managed,
that did this really well that you can think of?
Yeah, there's a talent marketplace called Toptal,
and they are specialized in this. They have a
really high bar for quality, they claim to only
have the top 1%, top 3% I believe, of talent
there. And they have a really amazing set of
checks and processes. This funny story from them,
but apparently they advertise something maybe a 3%
pass rate for their talent, so they only on board
like 3% of the people who apply. And allegedly
their actual pass rate is even lower than that,
but they thought that if they actually advertise
the actual number it would sound fake. And so,
they actually say 3% because 1% would sound
like too ridiculous and it would discredit
their talent. So, they're one company that does
a tremendous amount of work for vetting quality
early on with a ton of different checks,
but also maintaining that quality. So,
throughout with the right coaching tools,
with education and things like that.
That's a really good example. And so,
basically they just vet and only approve
high quality supply in their case. It's
mostly engineers, right? I think on Toptal?
Correct. Yes, it's mostly
engineers, designers, I think.
Which you can only do if you have so much supply
that has so much interest in becoming part of your
platform, but that's a really cool example.
Basically it's just only allow really high
quality supply. Let's hear this rental car story,
so this is Lyft trying to do rental cars, right?
Correct. Yes, yes. Yeah, so this is a little
bit of context. I was leading the driver's side
of product at Lyft, and General Motors had
invested half a billion dollars in our last
round of funding. And this was Christmas Eve,
I'll always remember, I got a call from Lyft
CEO and General Motors CTO, and we decided
to build a rental company essentially. And
the reason for it was really fascinating. GM had
all those vehicles that were coming off of lease,
and that they were forced to sell at auctions
they didn't really know what to do with. And
from our perspective, we had this massive
supply gap. We've talked about this before,
but we had this huge supply crunch, we were
growing super fast and couldn't hire drivers
fast enough, couldn't onboard drivers fast
enough. And when we looked at the market,
we realized that 50% of the job seekers and
welfare recipients in the U.S. don't have a car.
So, that was our supply gap. This was a huge pool
of people that we just couldn't tap into because
they didn't have a car. And so, by renting cars
we could essentially manufacture our own supply.
We could dial this up and down, we could be very
surgical about how many vehicles do we bring in,
which markets do we bring this in, at what
price? We could even offer to pay for the car
if they drove 30 hours a week and completely
transform the lives of those people, now we
allow them to have true mobility. They can go buy
groceries, they can go take the kids on vacation.
So, a huge win-win for everybody with
something like this. And I think in few
months we had built a rental company from the
ground up, and within 18 months I think we were
the fourth-largest rental fleet in the U.S.
But all of this stemmed from this gap that we
saw of like, okay, it's not about controlling
the drivers in general. It's about like, okay,
we want to be surgical. We want to control the
quality of the cars on the platform. So, we talked
about that, that's a great example. In the markets
where we thought the vehicles of quality was too
low, we knew we could onboard more rental vehicles
that were more recent to raise the average age of
a vehicle on the platform. So, it gave us more
control in a much more surgical way, I guess.
So, it's not that you are
launching a rental car service,
the idea was add supply and give drivers
a car so that they could become drivers.
It was a bit of both. We actually launched, it was
we had vehicles that drivers could rent from Lyft,
and to drive on the platform, and also to drive
for their personal needs essentially. But yeah.
Got it, okay. And then, did this actually
work and have impact? Was this a good idea?
Yeah. Yeah, it had a tremendous impact.
Like I mentioned, I think we scaled this
exponentially to become, I think again, the
fourth-largest rental fleet in the U.S. because
it was so effective for us, both because we
had the right amount of control, but also those
drivers were incredibly loyal to us. We had a
whole bunch of other incentives that we could do,
we could offer to pay for the car but only if
you don't drive for the competition for Uber,
and only if you drive at least 30 hours a week.
So, this again provided us with, again, much
greater retention, much higher engagement, and was
a real incentive for us but also for the drivers.
Awesome. And maybe the reason it's most
interesting is this is along the spectrum
of a managed marketplace. It moves closer
to you guys are paying and covering costs
of cars. It makes it less just like this
simple, highly efficient marketplace.
Exactly, yeah. It's the marketplace version of
maybe your black car fleet owner has their fleet
of vehicle and they have people. So, this
was the marketplace version of doing that.
And it's also just a differentiator,
because GM and you guys were close,
and so you had this lever that say Uber didn't
have. Amazing. Another area that I know you
spent time on that I think is really interesting,
and I think it'd be helpful to people to hear is
the mentorship program, and the ambassador
program that you had at Lyft, and how that
helped you scale much more quickly than other
folks were able to. Can you share that story?
Pretty early on at Lyft, this was 2014, 2015
maybe, Uber was basically 30X our size. They
had 30 times more revenue, more people, more
liquidity, everything you can think of. They
were growing like crazy, and we had a bit of
this existential moment, as you can imagine,
where we were wondering how we're supposed to
compete with that. And we had to be super clever,
everything that you did at the company had to
be 10 times more efficient per person than the
competition just to survive. That was the bar,
just not to die, and put a lot of pressure on us
but we basically found a clever way of onboarding
drivers at a fraction of the cost and resources.
So, let me give you a little bit of context on
how the onboarding flow worked. So, at the time,
the last step to get onboarded as a driver was
after you background check and your driving
record check came back, you had to do a visual
inspection of your car, a quick test drive, some
light training, and we would check your documents.
We would check that you are the person with a
driver's license and all those things. And Uber
at the time would launch a team on the ground,
they would go and open an office and they would
have DMV-style group onboarding sessions and car
inspections. And we did this as well in our first
three to four markets, but you can imagine the
overhead and the lead time. You had to go and
you had to find office space, sign the lease,
hire employees, you had huge, huge lead time.
And we thought about it, and at the time a huge
competitive differentiator for us was our brand.
As a passenger or as a driver, why would you use
a platform with lower liquidity? As a driver, you
had lower earnings guaranteed. As a passenger,
you had longer wait times. Why would you use a
service like that? You do because of the brand,
because of its values, it's how it makes you feel.
And so, we had the pink mustaches at the time,
we had this very strong brand identity. I think
a lot of that has been lost now, but we also had
this amazing community of drivers who were fierce
advocates for the brand. And so, what we did is
leveraging this community and building essentially
a soft onboarding supply engine where we would pay
our best drivers $35 per mentor session, and a
mentor session was essentially replacing this
onboarding flow. So, it was basically another
driver looking at your vehicle to check all
your documents, take photos of your driver's
license and all that stuff, and take you on
a short ride along. And the benefits of this were
absolutely mind-blowing and kind of unexpected for
us on all sides. First, the mentors were our
very best drivers, and they were evangelists
for the brand. So, what they did was they would
share personal tips on when and where to drive.
Oftentimes they shared their contact info. And
this created tremendous leverage and social proof
for those new drivers who were on the fence about
taking strangers into their car. It's actually
quite funny because we had the brightest minds
in the company writing the best marketing emails
and copy, like, "Hey, hop on the car and drive
this Saturday." And you had all those drivers
and all those mentors like, "No, no, don't listen
to those Lyft guys. Here's what you should do. Go
on Tuesday at 2:00 PM, text me, I'll tell you
where the good spot is, and this is how you're
going to get rides. This is how you're going
to get rich and make a lot of money." And this
recognition lever was just so much more powerful
than anything we could be telling you. And so,
very, very efficient activation lever for the
new drivers. For us, also incredibly scalable.
We could fly a small team to rigorously vet and
onboard maybe like 10, 20 top drivers, and then
they'd fly to a different market, and we would
let the rest of our drivers be onboarded by those
mentors. And even for those mentors, for those top
drivers, it was an incredible recognition lever.
For them, if you were a 4.9 driver, you had enough
rides, you had a chance to make it into being a
mentor, and this provided additional earnings
opportunity for you. If you did two mentor
sessions in an hour, you could make 70 bucks
an hour. You could take a break from driving
if you're tired, and just do some of those. It
felt like getting promoted at a job. And so,
it actually had a huge impact on the retention of
our very best drivers, which was unexpected. So,
a lot of really, really interesting benefits,
and we actually lean into this and built a
couple of really fascinating variations of this
for a while, but this allowed us to match most
of Uber's footprint with a 10th or a 20th of
the resources at incredible speed, I guess.
That is an amazing story, and it's such
a great lever that I totally agree,
I don't hear people using and I wonder why. So,
what I'm hearing is it was cheaper, the drivers
were making money. I imagine the drivers trained
by the mentors ended up being better drivers,
that's what we saw at Airbnb, hosts that came in
through a referral ended up being better hosts,
for whatever reason. And you're saying
basically, this is what allowed you to
compete with Uber at a much smaller scale
and much less money raised. Amazing.
Exactly.
You said there's a couple of variations. Is
there anything interesting there to share,
just things that you built as a
follow-up based on the success?
So, the next step in that journey was
basically we were growing like crazy,
but now we had cracks in like the activation
phase, but now we had a whole bunch of people
dropping off in the funnel before activation]. So,
they didn't enter their SSN, they didn't enter the
right info for us to run all those checks in
the previous steps of the onboarding flow. So,
we built a team of hundreds of account executives,
and their job was just pick up the phone and call
those drivers. And so, we had the same aha moment
of like could we get some of our best drivers to
do that for us, and empower them to be a part of
this? And so, we did this and we launched another,
like I said, role. We called them recruiters. And
so, as a recruiter, as a driver, you could just,
if this was quiet on the road, you could just
hop on your phone and you would have a mini
sales dashboard where you could claim leads.
And this was a driver who had dropped off in the
funnel, and you had a telephone number, you could
just call them and text them. And same thing,
those guys were outperforming our
very best of trained salespeople,
because it's not like, "Hey, it's Ben from
Lyft. Hop on the road, please." It's like,
"Hey, my name is James and I'm a fellow driver
as well. Lyft told me that you have a incomplete
application. Do you have any questions? Do you
want me to come to your house, we can do this
together?" And we would pay them 20 bucks per
person that they converted to activation. And so,
something incredibly scalable for us, another way
for us to reward and recognize our best drivers.
And it also provided a really interesting way
for us to smooth out the supply and demand.
The problem with a marketplace like Lyft is
that you have this big spike. Everyone wants
to drive on a Tuesday at 2:00 PM, but everyone
wants rides on a Saturday at 2:00 AM. And so,
how can you manufacture demand during those low
utilization times? This was a great way to do
that. Now you could wait on the road and still
make money while just sitting in your car while
waiting for the next ride. So, this was another
iteration of this model that was really cool.
Amazing. That is so cool. I just know the
feeling of being on a team, coming up with this
idea and the thing working must feel so great.
Just like, "Holy shit, look at this. Look at all
these cool things that we can do with our supply."
Something I wasn't going to get into, but it might
be interesting just to hear if you have thoughts
on this. So, I've been a huge fan of Lyft from the
beginning, I used Lyft the very first weekend it
came out in San Francisco when there was like five
drivers. It was like a beta test, I was friends
with someone that worked at Lyft early on, and
it was just like, "Man, Lyft's the best." I was
like all Lyft, Uber sucks, I hate that. I want to
give it the fist bump or the mustache. So great.
Today though, I was just looking at market caps.
So, Uber is worth $150 billion, Lyft is worth $5
billion. I'm curious if you have thoughts on just,
it feels like Uber has won at this point, and I
don't know where Lyft goes. I know your heart is
with Lyft and you worked at Lyft for a long time,
I know it doesn't feel great to see how things
have played out necessarily. I'm curious just to
hear your take on just what do you think Uber did,
if you look back, that allowed them to basically
win? And where do you think Lyft goes from here?
What do you think happens with Lyft? They're
still worth 5 billion, it's still a huge,
amazing, successful business, but
just where do you think things go?
Yeah. I think it all went south when I left
the company. I'm just kidding. No, and again,
I have to call out the fact that I haven't been
close to Lyft, and their business and strategy
for many years at this point. So, take this with a
grain of salt. This is my very naive perspective,
but I think to me, perhaps the biggest blow
to Lyft's business was somewhat inherent,
like the vision. Lyft's vision was always anchored
around transportation, people of transportation.
The founders were deeply passionate about moving
people, they were passionate about transforming
the way people move around in a city. They wanted
to just change how cities are designed, how roads
are designed. And so, that meant investing
in dynamic shuttles and things like that,
and there's a lot of experimentation that
went to that. But it also meant that Lyft
never invested in things like food delivery,
or goods and parcels, and things like that.
And I think that crushed them during COVID
essentially. I think Uber had, I think at
some point their slogan was moving in bits and
atoms, or something like that. But I think it
implies this notion of being a logistics platform
for assets in the world, for transporting people,
for transporting things, for transporting ... And
I think they built, they invested lot in trucks
and food delivery, and all those really exotic
things that Lyft had never any intention to invest
in. Not even because of the lack of resources,
but because this was in part a distraction from
our vision. We wanted to change how people move
around in cities, we wanted to reinvent public
transportation, we did not want to be a DoorDash
competitor and help you get in donuts during
COVID. And a huge part of it also was leaning
heavily in shared rides. And so, this was like,
again, how do you reinvent public transportation?
It's like every car is a dynamic bus,
and now there's a bus line. The bus line is always
running, it's always by your house. So, a lot of
our investment I think in thinking went in that
direction, and the last thing that people wanted
with COVID was to be in a car with five strangers,
but what people wanted is food delivered to their
house. And so, I know that the business had a
huge blow during COVID, whereas I think Uber
was able to rebound much more quickly because
of how diversified the business was. And so,
it's funny now because I think Lyft actually
killed shared rides, which was just so core to
their identity. They were the first ones to launch
this. And so yeah, the new COO I think killed the
shared rides, which actually I'm really sad about.
But yeah, so I think it indicates a very different
vision now, a very different direction for the
business. And yeah, that's my take, I guess.
Interesting. So, essentially COVID really effed
them because their strategy was always about
transportation, and when nobody needs a ride
and people want food, strategically Uber made
a really good move expanding into food delivery,
which I think was a bigger business than rides for
a long time. I don't know where it's at today for
Uber, and Lyft didn't have that, and it's hard to
recover from a time like that. So, it sounds like
it's a combination of strategy was pointing Lyft
in a certain direction, and circumstances
in the world just made it really hard-
And losing me me.
And losing Ben. So, you left in 2019, March
2019, and is that when they went public?
Not for the IPO.
Yeah, and it's all downhill from then. And then-
I'm telling you.
... during COVID actually, when there was a
big bump, which I think when people started
riding again, and then it went down again.
So, I think there was a correlation there,
so there we go. That's the thing, don't ever fire
Ben, don't let Ben leave. That's our take on it.
I was not fired, yeah. Just to be clear.
Okay, just different ways you might
leave a company, don't let it happen.
I know, I'm kidding.
Okay, so there's two more things I want to spend
a little time on before we close up. One is your
work in Europe, so you're a product leader in
Europe, and I want to hear a little bit about what
it's like to be a product person in Europe. And
then two, I want to hear about the startup. So, at
this point no one can actually fire. You have your
own company that you're running, and I want to
spend a little time here. Usually we don't spend
time on this sort of stuff, but you're working
on something very cool that I think is going to
be really helpful to a lot of people in a really
meaningful way. So, I want to spend a little
time there. But before that, so you're living
in France now. Before you started your company,
you were interviewing for CPR roles in France,
you work with a lot of French companies, European
companies. I'm curious what you've noticed might
be different in the cultures of tech companies
in France and Europe in general versus the U.S.
It's been really fascinating, I think. So, my
entire career has been in the U.S., and I'm
just starting to understand what that European
and the French market in particular looks like.
And my read so far is that product management has
really exploded I think in Europe in recent years,
but the market dynamics are still quite different.
In the U.S. I think you have this inherently very
liquid and dynamic market. I think, this is
my interpretation of it, but I think it leads
to greater ownership and accountability
for people and product at all levels. So,
product managers and leaders, they join a startup
and you're immediately in charge of a relatively
meaningful piece of the business, with genuine
autonomy oftentimes. It doesn't always happen,
but oftentimes I think that's the case.
And if things don't work out, well, there's
this expectation that you'll be managed out.
There are countless memes on LinkedIn about the
tenure of CPOs at tech companies to illustrate
that. I think in France the market is much less
liquid, so it's incredibly difficult to change
jobs, and it's very expensive to fire someone in
France. So, it seems to lead to two effects beyond
the obvious job security. One is, I think PMs tend
to have less autonomy and ownership, and a little
bit more like micromanagement. And there are also
less business owners than they can be in the U.S.
And I see founders and managers struggling to let
go of control a little bit more, again because
it's understandable in a way, you don't have
as much of a control as you do in the U.S. And
so, you see a lot of really fascinating effects.
You have startups who tend to wait a little bit
longer before hiring, especially in product. The
art of product a little bit less of a thing.
You have a lot of amazing PMs in France,
but the recognition of the craft is a little bit
different outside of the people who practice it.
And you have a lot of real interesting outsourcing
also, you see startups and companies of all sizes
actually relying on great product studios, like
Mozza, to build end-to-end products from the
ground up. So, something that's been really,
really interesting. Another side that I see is
this dominance of business over tech in France.
There isn't as much of a cult of technology and
software engineering in France as there is
in the U.S. And so, the French Ivy League
schools are business schools, like HEC, and
the most highly valuable skill that you get
is soft skills around management and business.
It differs from the stereotype of the CS degree,
Stanford dropout that you have in Silicon Valley.
And I think because of a few of those things that
I just mentioned, less liquid job market, but
also less liquid financial markets, the last
thing that I've observed that's interesting that's
also around ownership I guess, is equity is much
less meaningful in France. So, of the product
leaders that I talked to, most of them consider
their equity to be virtually worthless. None of
them know of anyone who's made a down payment
on a house thanks to their sort of equity.
So, it's seen as a nice bonus, but it's not
the token of ownership and the promise of
future wealth that it can be in the U.S.
when you join a startup. For exec roles, I think
it's often sub 10% of their total compensation,
whereas in the U.S. it's very often more than
50% of your compensation will be equity. So,
that's been interesting in terms of the dynamic,
but it's also been real interesting to just see
how vibrant the startup culture is here in
France. You have a truly exciting innovation
happening, especially in AI. You have a lot of
French companies at the forefront of this, like
Mistral AI and Hugging Face, and things like that.
And also how it's been exciting to see how the
government is leaning into that as a catalyst for
this innovation. I think the French government has
dedicated something like $2.5 billion in funding
to support French AI excellence by 2030. So,
they're running a lot of internal government
incubators to try to disrupt some of the
government functions from the inside, and they're
hiring top talents to do that. I've met some of
the people working on this, it's just really
fascinating. It makes me super excited about
what a federal startup task of reinventing
[inaudible 01:04:38] would look like. So yeah,
it's been really exciting to see the whole
space and how it differs from the U.S.
Fascinating. So, I know there's also AI
regulation that feels really strange in Europe,
but think that's EU based,
not like France specifically.
Yeah.
Yeah, that people are not excited
about. There's just a lot of fear of AI,
and so there's a lot of regulation talk in Europe.
I'm a big Android guy, and a lot of the
features like Gemini and all this is only
available in the U.S., and now that I'm in
France I see the difference a little bit.
Interesting. So, the cultural
differences you spoke of,
do you think they're rooted in the
fact that people don't move jobs often,
or is it culture? People just don't learn to
work in the way that people learn to work in
the U.S. in the product role? What do you think
is the root of why things are so different?
I'm not quite sure, it's a good question.
My take, and I think this is I'm sure very
naive and reductive, and I know this is
one of my core principles, so I'm sure
I also have a tunnel vision on this a little
bit. But to me, one of the biggest difference
that I see is really around this concept of
ownership and accountability. Whereas in the
U.S., and again, I saw it, I'm sure you saw it
at Airbnb, you see it at a lot of companies,
not everywhere, but a lot of companies will
hire you, give you a big chunk of the business,
and it's up to you to prove yourself out.
Where you have six months, you have a year,
it's up to you to show impact. I think the French
employment model is less conducive to this type
of dynamic, because employment is much more rigid.
So, you have much less of this hire now and prove
yourself out, it's much more of prove yourself
beforehand. And if you've made a bad hire than
as a founder, you become perhaps a little bit
cagey about your vision. You want to be more
hands-on because you made a bad hire. It's not
like someone perfect, then he'll make you work
but it means you'll be more hands-on in the work
of PMs daily, and perhaps we'll think like, "Oh,
maybe I don't need product managers who want
on my vision, I'll hire project managers," or
something like that. So, it's perhaps slightly
more conducive to those types of dynamics.
And you're saying that's in part because it's
harder to fire people in France and in Europe?
Yeah, I think so. It's not just
about firing I think, to be clear,
I just think it's culturally the market
seems like a lot less liquid and dynamic.
So, people don't move around as much,
they stick around for a long time.
Yeah, exactly. Yeah.
Got it. And it sounds like there's
also just a cultural difference of
founders innately are much more, "I am in control,
and I'm not going to hire people and trust
you to take this thing on. I'm just going
to run the show." It's basically Paul Graham's
founder mode is already instilled in everyone.
Maybe yeah, maybe that's a little bit. And
I think also it's this culture of business,
so very business-centric sort of culture.
And again, it makes sense, the markets,
you have less venture capital, you have less
equity in the financial markets as well. And so,
when you raise funding you need to have a strong
business case. The business case is at the center
of your habits. Whereas I think oftentimes in
the U.S. you have, again, it's a little bit
stereotypical, but it's a very tech
or product-centric view of the world,
or it can be a very tech or product-centric view
of the world where it'll be like this product,
this is the vision of the product, and sometimes
even the business model will follow. And in
France, I think the business model has to be
front and center perhaps for you to be able to
raise venture capital for you to be able to even
exist. So, it means it attracts a lot of business
minded entrepreneurs, much more so perhaps than
tech-minded or product-minded entrepreneurs.
Got it. If someone wants to help their company
in Europe and France operate more closely to
the way companies in the U.S. operate, do you
have any advice for them? I know you talk and
work with a lot of companies in Europe, what
do you help them change and see differently?
Yeah, it's a great question. I haven't fully
cracked that, and think it's a really hard
question. I'll give some sort of small pointers
that have helped at least some of the companies
that I've talked to. But the one is equity, I
think there's a desire from a lot of the founders
that I talk to, to give equity to employees,
but because it's not in the culture yet I
think employees also have an under-appreciation
for equity. Like, "Well yeah, it's nice, but I
don't know what's going to happen. I just work for
the CEO anyways." There's less of this sense of,
again, ownership that you can have in the U.S.
And so, I think leaning into that and investing
in education around equity, the case is
also in the U.S., I'm convinced 80% of
people just don't fully understand their
equity. But I think leaning into that,
especially in Europe, to help people
understand the value of their equity,
help them by telling more about the story of the
business, the trajectory of the business, why it
matters for their future equity. I think anything
along those lines I think can help cultivate this
greater ownership mindset, I think for people.
And then yeah, I think another big piece again is,
at least to me this is a big recipe to
successful product teams, is to develop
teams that revolve around this concept of
ownership and accountability teams that are
clearly owning a huge, or it doesn't have
to be huge, like a slice of the business,
not feature teams like shipping maybe guests,
but teams that have clear accountability with
consequences, but also clear ownership
and leeway to do their best and to thrive.
Again, I usually don't spend time on this sort of
thing, but I just think that what you're working
on is extremely cool, and I think it's going to
be really meaningful to a lot of people. And so,
I just want to spend a few minutes giving you
a chance to talk about what you're working
on now. You started a company, is this
your first company that you've started?
It is, yeah.
It is first company.
First real company. Doesn't accept
projects, but first company.
Yeah, there's a LC, there's a C corp, or yeah,
it's like filed. There's paperwork. Amazing.
Talk about what you're building, how people
know how to find it if it's right for them.
Yeah, I have to say entrepreneurship has been a
very humbling journey. I think the zero to one
is way harder than anything us have done so far,
and I feel like when you're used to building and
scaling products within companies, you take for
granted, at least I did, I take for granted that
the problem space has already been validated.
You have some brand equity, even if you launch
a new vertical, there's an existing user base,
there's a validation of the broader problem space.
I think going to truly zero felt, at least to
me, super overwhelming and lonely, but also super
exciting with tons of condensed learnings.
It's been a really interesting journey. So,
what brought me there is my wife started to have
some health issues about three years ago now,
it's partially why we decided to move to
France last year just for a couple of years.
And she's had this undiagnosed condition
and chronic pain, and we saw just how much
of a nightmare it was to manage her care and to
navigate the healthcare system in the U.S. So,
we'd wait three months for an
appointment for a neurologist,
then did see her for maybe eight minutes. Average
appointment time in the U.S. is between 10 and 12
minutes. They'd dump a bunch of jargon, say
like, "Hey, tests all look normal. Sorry,
you should just go see this other specialist
instead." Would wait another three months,
see another specialist. And with a lot of
anxiety, a lot of pain, as you can imagine,
all those things, you have another eight
minute slot with someone and you're like,
"Oh, why didn't the neurologist do this test?
I can help you, let's make some sense." And so,
it ends up being incredibly isolating. The
whole time we just felt completely alone.
It was just like us and Google, we felt we kept
getting conflicting advice from doctors, and I was
spending all my time researching specialists, what
solutions to consider, spend all my nights reading
through research papers to [inaudible 01:12:48],
"Hey, what is the academic consensus on this
particular treatment that the doctors don't seem
to know about?" And throughout this whole process
it felt like no one really had her back, no one
within the medical system was fighting for her
the way that your family doctor might have fought
for you 20 years ago, knowing everything about you
and being like, "Lenny, let's talk about this. I
know your uncle had this," or there's this sort of
a sense of advocacy that came from your family
doctor that just doesn't exist today. It's not
uncommon for doctors to have thousands of patients
that they see just a few minutes each year.
And so digging into this, we just realized it's
not an isolated case. You have nearly half of
Americans have at least one chronic condition,
or have to deal with some sort of complex health
issue largely on their own. You see a lot of those
large online communities revolving around chronic
conditions or chronic pain, and trying to make
sense of it and advocate for themselves. And I
think I want to be clear, in my mind the problem
is obviously not about the practitioners, it's
systemic. It's just growing financial pressure
from private equity firms, it's just countless
other factors. But you see the physicians
being overwhelmed, overworked, burning out,
and you see that pressure just only increasing, I
think. So, I basically spent the next six months
just talking to hundreds of patients, and doctors,
and experts, and what we built is basically a
platform to help people fight for their health.
And so, we want to close the gap between patients
and the healthcare system. There's this
critical layer of the system that's missing,
I think, people are navigating life-threatening
or debilitating conditions largely with Google,
and at some point you just get tired of fighting
for yourself. So, we connect people with complex
conditions, typically with their own health
advocate. So, it's essentially like their
own health assistant. They're available
24/7 to help you navigate your care. So,
we find appointments for you, we help you prepare
your appointment, we make sense of a diagnosis,
of test results. We spend hours researching
solutions and potential treatments, and just
more generally we do everything we can to help
you just better advocate for themselves basically.
And now we launched in the U.S. a early version
of this few weeks ago, and the engagement has
been really, really, really mind-blowing so far.
And we're helping cancer patients, people with
a lot of those niche chronic conditions, and
literally harassing the doctor's office like,
"Hey, we still haven't received that referral."
All the things that you just get tired of doing
when you're dealing with so many appointments,
and when you're having to manage a condition
like this. And our mental model is what would we
do if this user was our partner or our parent?
You'd likely spend all night combing through
research. You'd call all the providers in the
state to be like, "Hey, who has an appointment?"
Because there's no PT available for the next two
months. We'll find you a PT available sooner.
So, we're building the engine to do that at scale
essentially, and make people feel like they're
not alone and that someone is fighting for them.
Super cool. It's sad that we need
something like this, but we do,
because the healthcare system is so not ideal.
And so, it's basically someone in your corner
that's just, it's like in the inside that
knows how these things work that is there
to help you through the process. What's the
company called, where do people find it?
Yeah, it's called Nurra Health, and
our website is Nurra, N-U-R-R-A.me.
Awesome, and we'll link to it in the
show notes. And just to be clear,
I'm not an investor, I'm just excited about
this thing. I think a lot of people need
this. Just to loop back to what we've been
talking about, it's not a marketplace. How
would you describe this business in
relation to marketplace companies?
We're ignoring the marketplace
dynamics. I'm following my own advice,
and I'm one jumpstarting one side of
the marketplace, the health advocates
were like jumpstarting this side for now, and
we're only focusing on what I think is going
be the hardest side for us, and it's going
to be demand. How do we find those people?
How do we create the right value proposition
for them? So, that's what we're focused on.
And so, in the future there may be a
marketplace component, is what I'm hearing?
Yeah, exactly.
Interesting. Very cool. Ben, is there
anything else that you want to share,
mention, leave listeners with before we
get to our very exciting lightning round?
No, no. Thank you.
Well, with that, we've reached our very
exciting lightning round. Ben, are you ready?
I'm ready, let's do it.
All right. First question,
what are two or three books
that you've recommended most to other people?
I'll give you books in different directions.
One is Misbehaving: The Makings of Behavioral
Economics. I'm really interested in behavioral
economics, I love this intersection between
economics and human psychology. It's a
great analogy for product, so that's a great
introduction to this field. The second book that I
recommend a lot is Range: Why Generalists Triumph
in a Specialized World, by David Epstein. I've
always felt curious about a lot of things, but
it's made me feel like I'm decent at many things
but I'm good at nothing. I'm very good at nothing.
And so, even in my career I see all those pianists
who are like machine learning gurus leading
conferences on weekends that are contributing
to think tanks, I just felt like a generalist.
So, if you feel this way, this is a good book
to make you feel a little bit better by yourself
and your imposter syndrome. At least it did for
me. And last one, nothing to do with business,
but Immune, by Philipp Dettmer. This is the
creator of the YouTube channel Kurzgesagt.
I don't know if I'm pronouncing this right, but
it's a science channel. If you're even remotely
curious about how your body works, how your immune
system works, it's an amazing book that's really,
really fun to read, super entertaining, and
just great biology and fun book, I promise.
I've been trying to get the author of Range on
the podcast, I have not had success yet. So,
if anyone knows him, his name
is Epstein? Is that right?
Yes. David Epstein.
David Epstein, please connect me. I would
love to have him on the podcast. I really
love his message of just, basically it's the
most successful people, or is it that you
should be a generalist or that you can be very
successful as a generalist? Is that the message?
You can be very successful as a generalist. Yes.
Yeah, great. I completely agree.
That's been me too. Next question,
do you have a favorite recent movie
or TV show you've really enjoyed?
TV show? I haven't seen anything
lately that's been mind-blowing,
but I'll share an old new one. I've rewatched The
Last of Us recently, and it's an old favorite.
I love the TV show. I like the game, I played
the game many years ago, and love the TV show
When the heck's the next season coming up? I'm
excited for that. Because
I know the game has more-
2025.
2025. Oh man, so long. Okay, good to
know though. Next question, do you have
a favorite product you recently
discovered that you really love?
Maybe a little bit behind the curve on this one,
but I've been loving the Arc browser. I
don't know if you use it, but it's been-
Oh, I love Arc. It's my number one, my
main browser. Absolutely, I love it.
Amazing. All right, so yeah, you know
all about it. Yeah, it's been really fun.
Yeah, just the onboarding of the
Arc browser is such a lesson in
onboarding. They do such an amazing
job. It's like that alone is a great
thing to do as a product person,
just see how they do onboarding.
I was like, I've been using Chrome for
12 years, or I don't know how many years,
it feels like such high friction to change
my entire life. In eight seconds it was done,
it felt like home. I was like, "Wow,
this is way faster than I expected."
Two more questions. Do you have a favorite motto
that you often come back to or repeat
yourself, share with friends or family?
I don't have anything particularly philosophical,
unfortunately. I lived in [inaudible 01:20:16] for
a few years. I live now in the French Alps, so
I have a frame with a John Muir's quote, "The
mountains are calling and I must go." I feel like
this is, it's my grounding place. The mountains
are my happy place, and so I don't share that work
often. I don't peace out in the middle of meetings
like, "The mountains are calling, I must go."
But it's been a grounding motto, I guess, for me.
That's beautiful. My nervous system
relaxes just hearing that quote,
and I know you live in a mountainy
part of France so you've done it,
you've listened to the call. Final question. You
live in France, the Olympics were just in Paris.
Did you go to any of the games? Did
you watch any of the games? Anything
stand out to you about the Olympics that
were not so far from where you are now?
Good question. I did not see any live events,
unfortunately. Perhaps the highlight for me
was I'm a big mountain biker, but in the
biking realm I love the Men BMX event where
all three men on the podium were French,
so this was a great moment for France.
I didn't even know that was an Olympic sport.
So, it's a BMX, like dirt bike kind of race.
Yeah, yeah.
So cool. Amazing. Ben, thank you so much
for being here. Two final questions,
where can folks find you online, and what
else are you doing that people can check
out if they want to learn more? And
how can listeners be useful to you?
Yeah, you can find me, two things that are
perhaps helpful for people out there. One
is I have a Reforge course if you're curious
about marketplace, if you want to dig deeper
into marketplace growth, I have a course on
Reforge. We're about to do our fifth or sixth
cohort I think now. It's been going really
well, we've been working with tons of really,
really cool marketplaces, going much
deeper into some of the topics that we
just talked about. So, if you're interested
in marketplaces, I would say check this out.
And on that real quick, is the customer ideal,
is it founders or is it like PMs at larger
marketplace companies? Who is this perfect for?
We've had both founders and PMs, and
like a heads of product, but it's my
strong recommendation it's people that have
product market fit. Per our conversation,
if you don't have product market fit,
wait a little bit before enrolling in
this course. Focus on your core business before
worrying about the marketplace dynamics aspect.
And then I cut you off, there's something
else you were going to point people to?
Oh, and just Nurra, the company that
we're building. Anyone that you know,
or if you yourself have chronic or complex
conditions, and if you feel like you need
help managing your health and navigating your
care, would love to help or share what you need,
and how we can help you. And our
website is Nurra.me, N-U-R-R-A.me.
And then how can listeners be useful to you?
If you have advice, if you
know anyone in the space,
if you're interested in learning more about
this, if you have advice, if you have learnings,
if you know anything about this I would love to
hear it. If you have hot takes about marketplace,
if you disagree with any of what
I've said, I'd love to also hear it.
I love it. Ben, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you so much for having me, it's been a
dream come true. Finally, I'm on this podcast.
Same. Same for me, Ben. Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If you
found this valuable, you can subscribe
to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also, please
consider giving us a rating or leaving a review,
as that really helps other listeners
find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.