The first time I ever met Elon was
over FaceTime. He was just like,
"Do you want to just come hang out?
You can swipe left or swipe right."
You're known for at Twitter someone that turned
the culture of the product team and Twitter in
general from a very stagnant, nothing-is-changing
product to shipping all the time.
We wanted to change the lack of
ambition, the lack of creativity,
the lack of customers feeling that
the product had changed at all.
Here's a list of stuff that your
team shipped while you were there,
Super Follows, Communities, newsletters,
topics, Fleets, testing reactions,
edge-to-edge photos, Twitter Blue,
Spaces, and obviously, live video.
The sacred cows are like their own roadmap. What
are all the things that you think we're
not allowed to change? Let's start there.
This was all relatively quickly.
I was like, "I might flame out
completely, but Hell if I don't try."
Today, my guest is Kayvon Beykpour. Kayvon was
the beloved and longest-tenured head of product
at Twitter and also GM of the consumer business at
Twitter up until the day that it was sold to Elon
Musk. He landed at Twitter through an acquisition
of his company, Periscope, which was the world's
largest live-streaming platform, which ended up
inspiring Instagram Live, TikTok Live, Facebook
Live, and basically every other social network
getting into live video. He sold the company to
Twitter in 2015, continued leading Periscope for
a number of years, and then moved into leading
product and then the entire consumer business.
In our wide-ranging conversation, Kayvon shares
what it was like getting Elon up to speed
at Twitter, what it was like to be fired
from Twitter, which actually happened during
his pat leave. He also shares all kinds of
lessons and stories from transforming Twitter's
internal culture from a risk-averse, stagnant,
product org to one that was shipping major
features regularly. We talk about how they
used acquihires and up-and-coming hungry
product leaders to lead new initiatives
and break through many of their sacred cows.
We also get into jobs-to-be-done, Elon's layoffs
of most of Twitter's staff after the acquisition,
his lessons from building and shutting down
Periscope, and also building consumer products
in general, and so much more. This episode is
full of stories and lessons and a bunch of stuff
that you haven't heard anywhere else. With that,
I bring you Kayvon Beykpour after a short word
from our sponsors. And if you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's the best
way to avoid missing future episodes,
and it helps the podcast tremendously.
This episode is brought to you by
Enterpret. Enterpret unifies all of your
customer interactions from Gong calls to Zendesk
tickets to Twitter threads to app store reviews,
and makes it available for your product team.
It's used by leading product orgs like Canva,
Notion, Loom, Linear, and Descript to
accurately integrate the voice of the
customer into your product development process,
helping you build best-in-class products.
What makes Enterpret special is its ability
to build customer-specific, adaptive AI models
that provide the most granular and accurate
categorization of all your customer feedback,
and also connect customer feedback to revenue
impact to help product leaders confidently
prioritize things that will actually move
the needle for your business. If you want
a custom model built for your organization so
that you can automate your feedback loops and
prioritize your roadmap with confidence, get
in touch with the team at enterpret.com/lenny.
That's E-N-T-E-R-P-R-E-T.com/lenny.
Today's episode is brought to you by OneSchema,
the embeddable CSV importer for SaaS. Customers
always seem to want to give you their data in
the messiest possible CSV file, and building a
spreadsheet importer becomes a never-ending sink
for your engineering and support resources. You
keep adding features to your spreadsheet importer,
the customers keep running into
issues. Six months later, you're
fixing yet another date conversion edge case bug.
Most tools aren't built for handling messy data,
but OneSchema is. Companies like Scale AI and Pave
are using OneSchema to make it fast and easy to
launch delightful spreadsheet import experiences
from embeddable CSV import to importing
CSVs from an SFTP folder on a recurring basis.
Spreadsheet import is such an awful experience
in so many products. Customers get frustrated
by useless messages like error on line 53 and
never end up getting started with your product.
OneSchema intelligently corrects messy data so
that your customers don't have to spend hours in
Excel just to get started with your product. For
listeners of this podcast, OneSchema is offering a
$1,000 discount. Learn more at oneschema.co/lenny.
Kayvon, thank you so much for being
here, and welcome to the podcast.
Thanks so much for having me,
Lenny. Great to meet you finally.
It's amazing to meet you. I think this is going
to be quite a unique and interesting podcast. A
big thank you to Scott Belsky, illustrious
former podcast guest for introducing us.
When he introduced us, the one thing
that he told me is that "Hopefully,
Kayvon will share the story about our time
getting Elon up to speed at Twitter." I would
love to hear that story. I bet other people
would too. Are you able to share that story?
When all the drama went down with Twitter and
Elon ended up buying the company and after
the eight months saga of legal back and forth
ended up actually taking control of the company,
there was that first two-day period where it
was complete chaos at Twitter with the sink
and Elon spreading his tentacles trying to find
out who are the people that he wants to keep and
what are the projects that are interesting. In
the midst of all that, Scott ended up getting
contacted and being asked, "Who should Elon talk
to?" Scott recommended that Elon chat with me.
So, the first time I ever met Elon was over at
FaceTime where Elon was just very curious to ask,
"Hey, you were at Twitter for a while. You
seem to have done some things. What should
I be digging into, and who I be talking
to?" At the end of that conversation,
we ended up arranging an in-person meeting where
Scott and I went to Twitter HQ to actually meet
Elon. I think this was day two of Elon having
brought the sink in. So, we had this really
bizarre, wild, but really fun experience of
walking into Twitter HQ, and in my case, walking
back to Twitter HQ for the first time after having
been fired, which was a very strange experience
for me, and we walked into the building.
I was scurried through the back door because I
didn't want to make a scene and make it ... There
was a lot of rumors around is Kayvon coming back,
and I just wanted to avoid all of that. So, it
was just a very weird experience of being scurried
through the elevator and through the back door
and go to this massive conference room, which we
had on the second floor of the 110th building.
In that massive conference room, it was me,
Scott, Elon, and then at the very, very end
of the room, Walter Isaacson, who by the way,
I had a hard time. I knew I recognized. I'd
never met Walter in person, but I was like,
"Is that Walter Isaacson?" But he said nothing
the entire time, and we had probably a two-hour
conversation talking about the past, the future
of Twitter, the good, the bad, the ugly. At the
very end of the conversation, Walter came
up and introduced himself and was like,
"Hi, I'm Walter. Can I get your information just
in case I need to ask any follow-up questions?"
And I was like, "Oh, shit. I guess that whole
conversation was on the record. I don't know."
So, it was a very surreal experience for a
bunch of reasons, including just being weird
for me since I was very conflicted about coming
back to Twitter, even physically in the office.
But I must say it was really fun. It was fun
talking to someone. Obviously Elon, I'd never met
him before, and he's one of the most successful
entrepreneurs of our time. So, that was exciting
to go into that meeting. Also, I had been spending
so much time dreaming about Twitter and trying
to mold Twitter in a direction that I thought was
compelling and working with a team of people to do
that, and to meet someone who also had a similar
ambition, but obviously, in different ways ... He
had his own dream for Twitter ... but it was
really bizarre and unique and surreal seeing
that glimmer in someone else who was like, "Yeah,
I also just bought this thing, so I can actually
do whatever the Hell I want. And by the way,
here's some crazy dreams I have for doing it."
It was just a really ... As someone who had had
their own dreams for the product, witnessing
that it was really unusual and cool. I think
that's probably what Scott meant when he said,
"You should ask Kayvon about that," was that I
think we both kind of recognized that something's
about to happen here. Obviously, you have this
very public spectacle of someone essentially
having a takeover of a public company, but all
of that stuff aside, also, you could tell Elon
was scheming and cooking up, "What am I going
to do with this?" It was cool to see that.
That's an amazing story. I love the Walter
Isaacson component of it. Do you feel like
you made a dent on his approach and way of
thinking? Obviously, he made a lot of big
radical changes. Do you feel like you made a
dent in his view of where Twitter should go?
I don't know. I certainly don't think I've
made any impression on how he should run
the company. I think that's Elon's going to
Elon in his way, and I think he certainly has
had some radical moves in terms of how he's
running the company, the decisions he made,
how many people he let go, how the company is
structured, the culture, and all that stuff is
like ... We didn't even talk about that stuff.
I think what we spent time talking about is I
shared my perspective with him of people I thought
who were exceptional, who were at the company,
and if I was in his shoes, who I would spend
time with and embrace. Most of the people
that I mentioned are still there, which is
awesome, and they seem to be A, empowered,
which is great, and B, having fun, which is
awesome. So, hopefully, that stuff is useful.
We spent a bunch of time brainstorming products,
and I had my set of projects that I was very
passionate about because we'd given birth to them.
I think a bunch of those projects, it seems like
Twitter's still investing in and putting a
lot of energy behind like Community Notes,
which at the time was called Birdwatch. But I
always felt really bullish on that being the
future of essentially how content is moderated
on Twitter, just because it was very clear that
the way we were handling content moderation
among many other flaws just wasn't scalable.
Spaces and Communities and the Creator Program
of helping people make money on the platform,
those are projects that we started over the
year-ish prior to Elon taking over. My hope,
having left the company and having had
a new leader come in, was that those
things would be given more oxygen. It's
been awesome to see that those have been
continuing to grow and be molded in different
directions. Yeah, I think in that sense,
I hope that our brainstorm was useful, but for all
I know he doesn't even remember the conversation.
I freaking love Community Notes. It's such
an amazing product. Let me ask two more
dramatic-oriented Elon Twitter questions just
to get these out of the way. The first is you
said you were fired. I don't know if you've
shared that publicly. People always wondered,
I think, what happened. I know you tweeted
during your pat leave, "I'm leaving Twitter,"
and no one really knows the story as far
as I know. What actually went on there?
It was weird, to say the least. Honestly,
it took me some time to come to peace with
it because it was frustrating and surprising. I
guess the story of what happened starts with Jack
resigning. Jack resigned in ... It was like
November of 2021 at the end of the year. The
board chose Parag to be the CEO of the company,
and I've had a long relationship with Parag. I
respect him, but I had mixed feelings about that.
To his credit, Parag very quickly addressed one of
the biggest things that I was really frustrated
about in the last three years essentially of my
time at Twitter. One of my biggest points of
feedback and points of consternation was the
structure of the company in that we had a
functional organizational model, meaning
we had a head of consumer product, me, we had a
head of revenue product, Bruce, we had a head of
engineering, we had a head of design, we had head
research. It was a functionally run organization.
And the combination of that model and the type of
leader that Jack was wasn't working in my view.
I think if you're going to have a functional
organization, you need to have a GM or a CEO
who's extremely leaned-in to tiebreak and resolve
conflict and make sure the team is moving quickly.
And Jack, for all of his amazing qualities, just
wasn't operating that way, and so you had a group
of highly opinionated people that often disagreed
and would create either the need for consensus or
deadlock. That just was driving a lot of people
crazy, including me, and I think it really held
us back from living up to Twitter's potential.
Anyway, all of that was super frustrating for me,
and the combination of that and a dramatic change
in leadership with Jack leaving and Parag coming
in, I wasn't feeling too stoked. Parag to his
credit, when he became CEO, quickly changed that
and shifted the company to be a GM structure. And
he promoted me to being the GM of consumers. So,
for the prior three-ish years, having
been responsible for growing Twitter's
consumer product, I was only responsible
for the product management team. I didn't
have engineering or design, and that honestly
was difficult. It's very difficult to change
culture with one hand tied behind your back.
Still no regrets. Had a lot of fun. I think
we had some impact, but it was frustrating. So,
Parag changed that. The irony of this, by the way,
is he was one of the biggest proponents of the
functional structure. When he became a CEO,
he changed the structure, promoted me to be
the GM of consumer, and I was, at that point,
one month ... This is one month before I went
on pat leave because my daughter was due.
So, I went into my paternity leave being
like, "All right, I'm going to give this
a shot. We'll see. We'll see how this goes," as
Parag addressed the biggest frustration that I
had with the company and how it was being run.
So, I had some trepidations but went into my
pat leave feeling optimistic. Mind you, this was
all before Elon was even part of the picture. He
had not become a board member. There was no news
about him having beef with the executive team
or for that matter, trying to buy the company.
So, I went on pat leave maybe a week and a half
before our daughter's due date. Three weeks goes
by. In that three weeks, Elon joins the board,
leaves the board, makes an offer, has a short
dramatic feud about whether that goes through.
And also during that time, my daughter was
born. Some drama at the hospital for us,
but a week afterwards, we come home.
Mom's healthy. Daughter's healthy.
The day after we get home from the hospital,
Parag called me and said that he was letting me
go and that he was taking the team in a different
direction. That night, Twitter signed a term sheet
with Elon to sell the company. So, a lot happened
in a very short period of time, and the reason
that Parag gave is exactly what I shared publicly,
which was that he wanted to take the team in a
different direction. The only other thing he said
is that given that new direction, he thinks that
the things that I'm good at, Twitter doesn't need
anymore. And the things that Twitter needs are not
particularly in my skill set or in my interest.
He wasn't particularly expressive about what that
direction was, but that was the reason he gave
me. That was a huge bummer for me for a bunch
of reasons. One, I love the company. I love the
product, and also it just sucks to leave not on
your own terms. And two, I was just confused. The
timing was very frustrating and confusing for me,
not least of which because I had just come
home from the hospital while on paternity
leave. But also because at that time, especially
the fact that Elon was buying the company was ...
Well, I was conflicted, honestly. I was
very excited because Elon is someone that
I looked up to immensely, and you just look
at the things that he's achieved in the world
and you can't help but be inspired by
that. And two, Twitter for all of, I think,
the impact and progress that we had made, had a
lot of challenges associated with its governance
and the fact that it was constantly vulnerable
as a public company. So, there's just always this
drama associated with Twitter as a public company,
even a private company before that, that made it
extremely hard as a builder to get shit done
and have the product live up to its potential.
One of the benefits of this particular takeover
was that Elon offered a path towards solving
all of that. It was like, "Oh, cool, now you've
got one owner who happens to be, by the way,
extremely opinionated about the product and a
voracious consumer and creator of the product."
I think there was an incredible opportunity in
that that now you have this organization and this
product and this incredible ecosystem that can be
devoid of all the political bullshit associated
with being a public company. Now, it has this
conduit to just living up to its potential.
So, it was a bummer to be removed from that,
I suppose, without having any agency myself.
That was very a long-winded answer to your
question, but that's what happened towards
the end there. Like I said at the beginning,
it took me a while to come to terms with it
and to be at peace with it. I did eventually.
Listen, there's a huge silver lining of I spent
the first year of my daughter's life with
her and my family. My wife Sarah had left
Twitter eight months prior to me leaving, and so
when's the next time we could all be together and
have time and space to just enjoy each other and
our new family, and frankly, to avoid a lot of
the drama that ended up ensuing that not a lot of
people could have predicted? The deal was on. The
deal was off. It is just a whole lot of drama
that I got to miss, which is the silver lining.
Then it was confusing there for a bit because
when Elon did end up buying the company,
in that conversation that I had with him, it
was definitely ... I was conflicted about do
I want to maybe spend some time working on this
still? Elon was very cool about ... He actually
used this phrase at the end of our conversation,
which I still find hilarious. He was just like,
"Do you want to just come? You seem like you
care about the product, and you don't have dumb
ideas. Do you want to come hang out?" And I was
like, "What would my job be?" And he was like,
"Don't know, just hang out, and you can swipe
left or swipe right." He used the swipe right,
swipe left Tinder metaphor, and I thought
that was hilarious coming from him.
For ideas that come up just like, "Here,
I have this idea [inaudible 00:19:41]?
No, like swipe right on whether you
want to be here or swipe ... He's like,
"We don't have to make this a thing. Just do you
want to hang out and work on the product with us?"
That's so funny.
So, I ended up deciding that actually, I'm just
ready. I'm ready to move on. I spent enough
time at this company, at this product
trying to shape it into something
that I was passionate about. I
think it's someone else's turn,
and especially Elon. If you buy it's your
turn. You can do whatever you want with it.
So, that was conflicting for a bit, but
I would say towards the end of the year,
it was pretty clear in my mind that I was ready to
move on and start thinking about other problems.
What I think about is there's always this
tension being a PM at a company with a very
strong-minded, product-oriented founder,
and I feel like you would've been in the
epitome worst possible situation there,
where you're a product leader between
Elon and the rest of org. So, I think
it probably would not have worked out.
I'm not sure I would've been able
to articulate it as succinctly as
you did just now, but I think that is
the feeling that I had that it's not my
place anymore. I don't have a canvas to try
and exert my dreams on this place. I think
Elon took that mantle, and I'm excited to see
what he going to do with it is the feeling I had.
Yeah. You've touched on this. You're
known for at Twitter someone that
turned the culture of the product team and
Twitter in general from a very stagnant,
nothing-is-changing product to shipping
all the time, all kinds of stuff. So,
here's a list of stuff that I've gathered your
team shipped while you were there. Twitter Blue,
which is I think called Premium now, Spaces,
Super Follows, Communities, newsletters, topics,
fleets, being able to see Instagram photos in
line, testing reactions, edge-to-edge photos,
tons of UX improvements, and obviously,
live video. What did you learn about how
to change a product culture from a company
that's very risk-averse and essentially just
not shipping a lot to taking big, bold bets
and becoming a lot more open to new stuff?
Trying to drive culture change is both one of the
most challenging things and rewarding things. For
the first year of my role ... There was a chapter
of my time at Twitter, maybe just to backup,
that was just leading Periscope. In that first
chapter of maybe two years, I was not really
involved with Twitter stuff all that much.
That started to change when we really tried
integrating Periscope with Twitter, but chapter
two of my time at Twitter was when I became the
head of product. That first year of being the
head of product was one of the most difficult of
my career not because the work was difficult, but
because it was so politically and bureaucratically
exhausting to try and change culture in a
way that just there wasn't alignment around.
It comes back to the point I was making earlier
around the organization of the company was
functional, and so it is one thing for me to have
some ideas and a plan and a strategy that I felt
compelling. But when you have to essentially
drive consensus amongst your peers across the
other functions, that's a different game. That's
not execution. That's politics and consensus
building. I both can't stand that stuff, but I
think ... This is going to sound like I'm tooting
my own horn, but good enough at it and I have
enough patience at it that I invested the time and
the energy. I think a less patient person wouldn't
have bothered and would've thrown their hands up.
I think honestly, a lot of it just comes down
to I had practice. At my first company that I
started in college with one of my best friends,
Joe, who I ended up co-founding Periscope with,
we got acquired by a big, public, ad tech
company called Blackboard, and we were 19
at the time. We got thrown into a public ...
I was a senior executive at a public company
that was not your quintessential tech company. It
was even more difficult to get things done. So,
through the four years I spent there,
I learned a lot about how to navigate
that type of environment.
It all came coming back
when I was given the product role at Twitter.
That first year of changing culture was like-
... product role at Twitter. That first year of
changing culture was like walking through mud,
and it was really difficult. But I think when
we started building that alignment and building
excitement that like, oh, actually maybe we
should be taking some bigger swings, and when
we started seeing through the execution against
some of those plans, I think it ended up, it got
easier and easier. It becomes addicting. I think
people end up feeling like, oh wow, maybe these
sacred cows we had didn't need to be so sacred.
And so I think after that first year, it became
a lot more fun. It was still difficult,
but it felt like we were all swimming
in the same direction a lot more. But I think
my takeaway there is you can't change culture
without having alignment from the top. It's
difficult to change culture when you have a
pocket of a company trying to advocate for change.
So I think we got there in the end. We didn't move
as much urgency as I think we drove. We were
not fast enough, we were not bold enough. I
was consistently dissatisfied with what I was
achieving and what our team was achieving. But
I think we did make a change. Twitter was
an organization that had a lot of sacred
cows and became very [inaudible 00:25:24] in
its ways. Literally the first two years I was
at the company, the stated product strategy
for Twitter was refine the core. It was like,
we're not making any big bets here, team. Our goal
is to keep turning the knobs that are working.
And listen, as much as I was kind of throwing
stones from the sidelines through that period
when I was in Periscope land in our separate
office a few blocks away from the mothership,
that focus actually did help the company for
some period. The reason why Twitter went from
stagnant to declining DAU growth to growing DAU
again is because they refined the core. This is
when they went from the reverse chronological
timeline to the ranked timeline, and the year
after that was a lot of knob turning. It was like,
how do we make these recommendations better? How
do we make our push notifications more relevant?
Now, that is not an inspiring product strategy.
That does not result in the product feeling
materially different or adding new capabilities,
but it did return the company to user growth.
And I think that the fact that it did actually
calcified the organization's reticence to
take any risky bets even more. So it was a
very interesting predicament because when I
got into the role, the goal wasn't to change
that progress. We wanted to continue reaping
the benefits of refining the things about the
product that were working really well. What
we wanted to change was a lack of ambition,
the lack of creativity, the lack of customers
feeling that the product was changed at all.
Because you would hear people, I mean, one of
the beautiful things about working on Twitter
as a product is that you have literally customers
being injected into your veins. Every single day,
whatever you change about a product or whatever
you don't change, they're telling you what
they love and what they hate. And it is both
exhausting and exhilarating. It is one of the
most ridiculous luxuries of product development,
is working on a product that many people use and
therefore you get that much feedback around.
And it was a very common thing for us to hear
people say, "What are you all doing over
there? The product hasn't changed in eight
years." And that was horrible to hear, and
I felt it too, as a critic on the sidelines,
as a user who wasn't an employee who eventually
became an employee, I had the same feedback. And
so that was my mission. I was like, I am somehow
ridiculously in this fortunate position that I've
been entrusted some responsibility here. I might
flame out completely, but hell if I don't try. And
so that was both fun and exhausting, like I said.
But it was as simple as starting with we are
voracious users of the product ourselves, and if
we aren't, by the way, that's its own problem. I
think that in order to build something wonderful,
you have to be a customer of the product. And
sure, I'm sure you could point to businesses and
products where that's not the case, and I'm sure
there's a flaw in that philosophy somewhere, but
I've always believed that one of the best ways
to build products is to be a customer yourself
and to find your own pain points and to build
a product that you want to use. And so that's
actually not that hard to do if you're a user of
Twitter and you can think critically. It was ripe
with opportunity. And so it was actually really
fun and amazing to be able to craft a plan that
started to take a swing at some of these things.
And the other thing I'll add to this is that
there were so many sacred cows at Twitter that
the sacred cows are their own roadmap. It's like a
built-in free roadmap of like, all right, what are
all the things that you think we're not allowed to
change? Let's start there. Everything from moving
from reverse chron to a ranked feed, that was
a sacred cow. Text and 140 characters, that's a
sacred cow. Not letting anyone control any tweets
that they see on the platform. The notion of Lenny
owning his reply space was anathema at Twitter.
It's just like if a tweet gets, if you get an
at mention and you don't like it or it's abusive,
we're not touching that. We can't annotate tweets
with [inaudible 00:29:30], all that stuff,
those are all sacred cows. And the process
of starting to address those one by one reveals
a lot of the cultural hesitations that existed.
So yeah, I'll never forget one of the first
features, and this is such a tiny feature
that we worked on after I started the role,
we were building this feature called hide
replies. It still exists in the product today.
If someone replies to one of your tweets,
in the tweet details area as a reply to one of
your conversations, before you had no ability,
the only way you could address unwanted content
was reporting it. So that was like Twitter
acting as policemen and policewoman, completely
unscalable and challenging, especially in the
context of someone replying to one of your tweets.
And so we wanted to add a feature that let you
hide a reply to one of your tweets, and it's not
impacting what people say. It's not impacting free
speech in the sense of you can still broadcast
whatever you want, but if you're going to come
into my reply space and say some shit that I
don't want to see in my feed, I should be able
to hide that. Tweet what you want, but don't at
mention. You can't scream in my face basically.
And I remember we had a PM on our team who
was leading this feature who a few weeks
into this project mentioned to me that she
had had a conversation with someone on the
engineering team that told them, "Don't work
on this feature. This is bad for your career.
This is not going to launch, and you don't want
to work on this. You don't want to be seen as
having worked on this." Because it was so kind
of anathema to we can't let people hide replies
to their tweets. And I just remember hearing that
and my blood was boiling. That is the most, it was
such an interesting representation of the culture,
not just hesitation to try new things, which by
the way, that product might've failed. And that's
fine, but it doesn't mean you shouldn't try.
But to go so far as to dissuade someone
else who was excited about experimenting
with a hypothesis to see if it could help
customers on the platform and telling them,
"Don't work on this. It's bad for your career."
As a microcosm for some of the cultural challenge
we had around trying big, bold bets, which by
the way, this wasn't even a big, bold bet. It
was such an innocuous thing to try. But there
was a lot of that and it made it very difficult
without some sheer force of will and also just
a lot of effort. So there was a lot of that.
Kayvon, there's fractals of stories that I could
infinitely follow. There's so much interesting
stuff here. One that just stands out is this
idea of the sacred cows become your future
roadmap. It's like flipping it from here's the
thing that we're all afraid of. No, this is not
what we should be doing. I think that's really
interesting and could be a lesson to people.
The other is just, I love this point you made
about the growth was most accelerant when you're
just focusing on the core, that's what actually
... Like optimize, people bash on optimizing the
existing experience and just micro-optimizing,
improving, versus trying to take all these big,
bold bets and experiments. Obviously, that's
also valuable. But I think it's really
interesting that that's what reignited growth
and was responsible for growth for a while.
And continue to be, by the way. One of the
lines that we had to maneuver was creating
a portfolio of bets where some of them were
not speculative at all. We knew that if we
continue to invest in ML and getting better
with recommendations in the main feed and
through notifications and things like improving
the onboarding flow, it was rife with opportunity.
You'd have really dumb things happen. We
would learn. There was one just bizarre
and incredible meeting we had where we finally
had got more rigorous around instrumenting our
onboarding flow. And we found that in a
couple countries, like we had a bug with
our SMS verification flow where we wanted to
verify users who were signing up with a phone
number and our telco integration to send SMS
verification cards just wasn't working. And
so a huge percentage of people signing up in the
UAE and other countries just couldn't use Twitter.
And so of course at the scale that we were
operating in with hundreds of millions of users,
you need to be able to refine the basic building
blocks of the product, and that's going to lead
to reliable growth. But we wanted to balance
that with a portfolio of other bets and product
improvements that would materially add new
capabilities. And that was a balance that I
don't think existed. And by the way, I don't
think we nailed it either under my tenure,
but it was the driving force of what I wanted to
achieve, was to create a better balance that would
result in evolving the product and introducing new
capabilities. And so that's what we tried to do.
In terms of what actually helped turn things
around, things that I kind of gathered from
what you shared so far, one is just building
a little momentum, having some quick wins of
new products that people start to get excited
about. So creating more excitement down the,
oh wow, we can actually try new things. There's
also, it felt like there's a sense of trust
that you built with Jack and execs of just
like, okay, we can actually trust this team.
Also, it feels like because growth started
up, there's probably a sense of like, okay,
we can try some new crazy ideas. It feels
like another part of your strategy was
[inaudible 00:34:56] hires and bringing
in these entrepreneurial folks to take
the lead on some of these big ideas. Can
you talk about that? Was that something
you actively thought about and was
that a big part of the impact there?
Totally. Yeah. So I think a couple things. One,
the only thing I'd add to what you said in terms
of the ingredients, it was also just storytelling
and just repetitive storytelling around this is
the vision, these are the bets we're making.
Here's why. And you can't just tell that
story once. I'm talking internally, by the way.
There's a whole other component of this, which
is externally how do you tell, especially for a
product like Twitter where it's a consumer product
that hundreds of millions of people are using,
and you have many constituents, you have users,
you have advertisers. And so it was very important
for us to tell the story of here's what we're
doing and why. Here's why you should believe in
us. And by the way, give us all your constructive
criticism too, because we're listening and
we're going to build that into ... So that
storytelling was really, really important.
And this is oversimplifying the world,
but there's two types of internal team members.
There are people who hear that story, who have
been a part of the organization who's been slow,
or maybe they've been outside the company as a
user of Twitter, and they're like, I'd never
really want to work there because it doesn't
seem like a particularly ambitious product
company. And one of two things happens when
you hear that story. Either you're inspired and
you're like, yeah, we can finally take a swing at
making this product better. And maybe I wasn't
interested in working in this company before,
but I mean, this is an iconic product, and to
have an opportunity to reshape it is really
exciting. Or again, oversimplified world, but
there are people who are very pessimistic and
maybe aren't excited by that vision. Let's just
stick to what we know works. We're not going to
take any big swings. That's a waste of time.
I think one of the really important things
about driving cultural change at the leadership
level is you've got to identify whether someone's
on the wagon or off the wagon and either quickly
convince them to get on the wagon or if they're
not on the wagon, they shouldn't be there.
And that's something that we were terrible at,
and we didn't have the organizational
structure to be able to enact that.
The wagon is they're excited and bought
into this vision and want this to happen?
Correct, and contribute towards it. And off the
wagon is like you're not at the company. And we
didn't have an organizational structure
that could allow for that, nor frankly,
the fortitude. I include myself in this. I
feel like I've learned a lot about how to
make that determination. So I think we were
terrible at that. And Elon is the whatever,
if that's a spectrum, Elon is the
opposite spectrum of that. His
tolerance for people who are not aligned and
his tolerance for low performance is famously
extremely low. And I think it's one of the things
that when I say A/B test, it's very interesting to
see the extreme to which he has operated.
And I think I've learned a ton around,
we didn't have the organizational structure
nor the fortitude to be swifter, and that made
cultural change way slower. We still were able to
change the culture, not as much as we should have,
and certainly not as quickly as we should have or
efficiently as we should have. Because by the way,
a lot of high performers who are aligned with that
desire to change and build, they don't have the,
there's not like an equal distribution of
patients. If you're extremely talented and you're
dealing with organizational shit, you're going
to go find someplace else that lets you do your
craft and have impact. So it's very difficult.
But anyway, going to your question, one of the
things we found that was a really effective way
of accelerating cultural change and also helping
drive some of these product initiatives that were
particularly speculative was doing small acquires.
And really the benefit of that was, A, you
bring in a founder type who is an entrepreneur,
who drives urgency, who has ambition, who's
ideally savvy enough to also work in the context
of a large organization, which sometimes
is a totally different skillset. I mean,
it is a totally different skillset. And a
lot of our most ambitious bets that were
the riskiest and most misaligned with how the
product worked or there was no easy staff to
build on top of, a lot of those bets were driven
by founders who we basically acquired and said,
"Here, you are going to run this."
And they believed in it. They were
able to rally a team around them, and it's all
the attributes of a startup, but with the canvas
of a product that hundreds of millions of people
use and more resources. So Spaces, Communities,
Community Notes, called Birdwatch back then,
these were all projects driven by ... Fleets,
as well. These were all projects that were run by
small teams led by entrepreneurs who we acquired,
like Keith Coleman runs Community Notes, last
Birdwatch. He actually was my predecessor. We
acquired his company so that he could be the
head of product. And then when he moved on
from that role, he was extremely passionate
about this idea of crowdsource moderation and
letting people annotate misleading content on the
platform without Twitter acting as a policeman.
And that was a very speculative bet that by
the way, a lot of people thought, most people
thought was a terrible idea. We gave Keith a
little silo to go build this vision, and then
it was our job to make sure that bet didn't get
suffocated in the context of a big organization
that would otherwise have not had patience for it.
All of the community effort or the creator efforts
started with Super Follows and tipping, and all
these things were led by Esther Crawford, whose
company we acquired and who had her own couple
of viral moments with the Elon acquisition. But
she's a phenomenal leader who, again, is a perfect
example of balancing that entrepreneurial startup
muscle with the savviness to be able to get things
done at a large organization. Fleets was run by Mo
Oladam, who's an entrepreneur, and Communities
has gone through a few iterations obviously and
still is in the product, but John Barnett and a
team of people who we acquired from Chroma Labs.
So I think that that story of acquiring hungry,
ambitious founders and giving them responsibility
and latitude is a success story of Twitter's. I
mean, I'm a beneficiary of such a bet as well.
My company Periscope was acquired, and I was given
the responsibility to eventually lead the product
team. So I feel like that we ended up realizing,
both through the company's history and through
learning, that this is actually a very effective
way to drive cultural change and to deliver impact
because you need a special type of person to be
able to both operate within the existing structure
and change the structure, to know when to use
the system and to know when to fuck the system.
And I feel like my whole life has benefited from
other people taking bets on me like that, to the
point that even I was like, "Really? You sure you
want to?" And so I think I've enjoyed trying to
pass the buck and do that for other people, and
I've never regretted it. You always, taking a bet
on people and especially throwing them in a deep
end, which on paper they may be unqualified for,
I think is one of the best ways of driving
change. And by the way, supporting growth,
you've learned so much more when you're thrown
into the deep end than in other contexts. And so
I think it's fantastic, it's an expensive strategy
if you're going to go buy a bunch of companies,
but it's a great strategy for the situation
that we found ourselves in at Twitter.
It feels like every big bet was one of these
companies from the list that you just shared,
and I'm glad you shared Periscope, obviously.
That's a great example, too. I guess maybe just
a follow-up question here, is there anything
you learned about how to do this well? I know
you talked about maybe creating a little silo for
the team, because so many companies acquire and
acquihire and they just go nowhere.
So I guess just a two-part question,
just like what are some tips for how to do this
well at a company? And then, two, you also,
we were talking offline about this previously and
I think it's a really interesting point, that a
lot of companies staff based on who's available
versus who is right for the role, and let's wait
until that person is there for us to bet on
this. Can you just talk about lessons there?
That last one is a huge pet peeve of mine
that I feel like we learned the hard way,
and particularly it's a common pattern I think
in highly functional organizations where you
have different people making decisions on how to
staff projects, and there's nothing inherently
wrong with that. But I think in the situations,
in the situation we found ourselves in where we
had this sort of cultural evolution that we were
going through where some people just didn't agree
with the things that we were prioritizing,
they were begrudgingly going along with it,
but you would end up in a situation where the
combination of that sort of cultural shift
and strategy and the fact that the way teams
were being staffed was not, there's ultimately
no single decision maker other than the CEO and
Jack is not going to get in the weeds and debate
a staffing decision on the team, resulted in a
situation where oftentimes we'd have projects,
like the one I mentioned about hiding replies,
where there wasn't even an agreement on the
team about whether this was a good idea and
whether this is worth trying or how to do it.
And imagine, it's hard enough to build something
from nothing. It's even harder if the team doesn't
believe in it. This is to the point of just being
toxic. The startup would never succeed if all the
people who are working on that startup aren't to
the point of being perhaps irrational obsessed
with that idea. And still willing to see truth,
you need to be able to see whether the thing is
working or not, but if you don't believe it in the
first place, I'm not betting on that succeeding.
And so this was common, and sometimes not as
extreme as the examples that I mentioned, but
I think one of the lessons I learned, and it's
quite intuitive actually, is you need to staff
projects with the team of people that are
well equipped from a skillset standpoint,
but more importantly have an obsession with
the idea they want to pursue. It's going to
make them work harder, it's going to make them be
more creative. It's going to make them have the
sufficient level of ambition and desire to will
this thing into existence. Because every project,
whether big or small, there is an element of you
need to will this thing into existence because
it's hard. The only way you're going to get
through that pain is by having that desire, and
I think a very easy cheat code for an organization
to employ is to say, if you're going to work
on something, especially if it's speculative or
risky, staff it with a set of people who believe
in it and really want to learn whether this solves
a customer problem or not. Because if you don't
have that ingredient, it's going to drag everyone
down and it's just not going to be as successful.
This episode is brought to you by
Heap, the product analytics solution
that shows you everything users do on your
digital product, website, mobile product,
or other digital services. We all know a great
digital experience when we see it. It's intuitive,
it anticipates your needs, and it makes it easy
for you to do your job. If you're trying to build
that kind of experience for your users, you need
up to date, reliable information about what your
users do in your product and why they do it.
Want to know how your users behave across
platforms, what keeps them coming back, what
they're doing that you're not even aware of? Well,
I have some great news for you. Heap captures
all of this user activity for you automatically
and then gives you definitive answers to all
your questions about user behavior in seconds,
not weeks. With Heap, it's easy to prioritize
the product investments that improve conversion,
engagement, and retention. Visit heap.io/lenny
to get started with a demo. That's heap.io/lenny.
This kind of touches on something I wanted to
touch on, which is jobs-to-be-done. This is
maybe one of the most recurring controversies of
the podcast, is jobs-to-be-done amazing or is it
really bad and not something you should do? We've
had many guests share their opinions. I feel like
at Twitter, jobs-to-be-done was implemented so
strictly that it burned a lot of people out on
it. It's like, oh my, this is not anything anyone
should ever do. I'm curious, just your lessons and
experience of just with frameworks in general, the
jobs-to-be- done specifically, maybe even OKRs.
I've only seen one interview on your
show that covers this. Sriram was
particularly spicy when he talked about
jobs-to-be-done, which is unsurprising
because. I spent a lot of time talking
to Sriram about jobs-to-be-done. I mean,
I guess I'll just start by saying
I was not a fan of how we leveraged
jobs-to-be-done at Twitter. I thought it
was exhausting and not particularly helpful,
and so it's a particularly sore subject for me
because I was sort of charged with defending it
and rolling it out. It's hard to do that when
you don't really believe in something. But...
It's hard to do that when you don't really believe
in something, but to me the critique is less about
Jobs-to-be-Done though there are many critiques of
it and more about every framework at its limit is
followed to such a religious extent it's just
unhelpful. You need to have nuance in how you
leverage these frameworks. Otherwise, you lose the
forest through the trees and you end up following
a process for the sake of following a process.
And that's what happened with Jobs-to-be-Done.
So I think that's my real critique of it.
It's not the... I mean listen, the premise
of Jobs-to-be-Done and my most charitable take on
Jobs-to-be-Done, which is actually useful is that
it forces you to look at things through the lens
of customers and understanding what their needs
are and understanding what their true alternatives
are outside of the narrow lens of your product.
And I think that's just healthy product thinking.
You don't need a framework called Jobs-to-be-Done.
You don't need to think about milkshakes in
order to be able to do that. It's like you
could employ common sense or you could leverage
something like Jobs-to-be-Done, to be able to
force your mind to think of things through that
lens. So I think that's my charitable view on
what Jobs-to-be-Done can help you do, but as a
framework into and of itself as a sole governing
principle of what to build, it's just not useful.
By the way, in the same way as, and I think
Twitter had this problem as well prior to our
detour around Jobs-to-be-Done, if the only way
the organization is trained to think about what to
build and what not to build is OKRs, it's equally
unhelpful at the limit because sure, you can have
a good sense of what you should build to drive
metrics, but by the way, you might be focusing on
the wrong metrics or that might not help you have
the right balance of things to build. That
might not help you see when the things that
you're building are actually hostile to customers.
So just as an interesting example, the thing that
I remember about your interview with Shriram,
if I'm not mistaken, I think he mentioned,
and I love Shriram, I'd be happy to debate him
about this on his podcast, but he mentioned one of
the examples I think was the Amazon. When you get
order confirmation from Amazon, they intentionally
bury the order details. You have to click the link
and authenticate to go see what you ordered. I
don't give two shits what metrics that drive for
Amazon. That is one of the most customer hostile
things I experience in my daily life. I order a
lot of things from Amazon. I hate the fact that
I can't search my email to see what I ordered.
And so I think the problem with these frameworks
is that you lose nuance and ultimately,
and this is where I agree with Shriram,
he actually mentioned this on your podcast as
well, you need to be able to make trade-off
decisions that balance what's right for the
organization and what's right for the customer.
And sometimes based on how you devise your
frameworks, your metrics aren't actually
aligned with the customer's benefit. Like the
Amazon example, and we had many famous examples
in Twitter's history, which were the same. One of
our key metrics that we always optimized Shriram
growing was DAU and we had obviously the rank
timeline did wonders for growing DAU and it
was a great experience for many customers, but we
often had features that would not lead to a good
customer experience and the team would just be
blind towards leaving hostile customer experiences
in place because it was good for metrics and
aggregate. And the famous example of this is
we had this toggle, which we called Swish very
affectionately, but it was like a sparkle icon.
Before you could switch between the
rank timeline and the following,
that reverse chronological timeline,
which is still in the product right now,
it was just the toggle. You would press a button
and it would turn your feed reverse chron,
which very few people use as a percentage of
our users. But you had power users who really
cared about having a reverse chronological
timeline and we took so many baby steps on
the evolution of this product. The very
first baby step was you press the toggle,
it turns you to reverse chron and then we would
pull the rug out from underneath you and make the
experience go back to the rank timeline after,
I don't know, 24 hours or something like that.
Oh, wow.
And the reason that the team felt strongly about
keeping it this way is it was better for metrics.
Why? Even if Lenny wants a reverse chron feed,
we knew that he would spend more time in the app
if we put them in the rank timeline and this
was the number of debates that we had about
this because the team understandably was like,
"This is good for metrics", but at the same time
you'd have customers being like, "I fucking hate
this experience. I'm telling you I want reverse
chron. Stop randomly changing it for me."
Instagram has I think gone through their
own struggles with this as well. They tiptoed
their way towards ultimately giving people
control and the difficulty in making product
decisions comes down ultimately to making these
trade-off decisions and you have to look at
things through the lens of the customer. You
have to balance that with what's driving the right
business outcomes. And sometimes those things are
aligned and sometimes they're not, and the answer
isn't any one framework. Sometimes it's just good
old-fashioned judgment and product taste. And so
that's where my take is different. I don't think
the issue is Jobs-to-be-Done, although I'm not
the biggest fan of Jobs-to-be-Done. The issue
is just having the right nuance and ultimately
the right leadership to be able to weigh these
things and see when your frameworks are not
actually helping you make the right decisions.
I think that's really important advice and
I love hearing the details if I actually
think about this stuff. Actually finding
this balance is very hard in practice.
I'm curious if there's something you could
recommend or have learned about how to know
when you've gone too far with a framework
like signs like you have implemented this
to religiously and maybe you should
be thinking a little more broadly.
There's two, I think, simple and obvious ones.
One is if the result of your framework is that
subjectively bad decisions are being made, then
something's got to change. Assuming the person
who's making this assessment has good product
taste, which is in of itself subjective obviously,
but my personal view on this would be in the
role that I had, if I saw that our organization
was being incentivized to make decisions that
to some non-trivial degree of the time were
just bad decisions that I don't like as a
user, I can't stand by as a user or builder,
then something's got to change. Either bad
judgment was made in following the process or
the process was wrong, or if that framework,
it didn't even lead to the right debates,
then that's how you know. Either you have
an incentive problem but the team did what
they were incentivized to do or that there was bad
judgment and that's a different problem obviously.
But I think in the situation we found ourselves
in where the team was again understandably hyper
focused on driving DAU because that was the
strategy for so long. It left so little room for
even taking ambitious bets that in the short term
wouldn't drive DAU, like some of our bets that
I still to this day believe in hurt DAU in the
short term, but you had to squint and believe
over time would improve some metric DAU or
otherwise, like a product like Spaces. In
order for Spaces to be actually used, you needed
to make sure that when Lenny starts a Space that
people would join. And how do you get people to
join Lenny space when they're used to having an
asynchronous feed of tweets? Well, you can send
push notifications, you can occupy really trying
real estate at the top of the app that lets
people know, "Hey, Lenny's live right now. He's
in a space, there's people here, come join."
Guess what happens when you put a bar at the
top of the app that tells people when they're
live? You move tweets down, you move ads down,
DAU goes down, revenue goes down. And so if you
have an organization that's just hyper focused on
the thing that matters is driving DAU quarter over
quarter, then that doesn't leave enough room for
nuance to accommodate new speculative bets that
might hurt one metric, but over time have other
consequences that are positive and beneficial,
like enabling an entire new vector of content
creation and conversation on the platform. I guess
the other answer to your question in terms of how
do you know when the framework's not serving you
right? When you start imagining and planning for
a bunch of bets that the organization then
sees is disincentivized to make successful,
then something's got to change.
Either your strategy is just not
the right strategy because it doesn't abide by the
frameworks or the framework needs to accommodate
the fact that actually we're going to try some
things that in the short term either might not
show up as blips on our DAU radar or are going
to help some other metric that's important. And
so that took us some time to get, and we tried a
variety of schemes to make that work. Community
Notes, the project that I was mentioning Keith
started, we intentionally structured that like a
startup. It was literally like we made a seed
bet on Keith and his team and we were like,
don't worry about the OKRs. We're not going
to judge you on the basis of your OKRs.
And there's some pros and cons to that. A
lot of our projects worked that way. Fleets
started that way. Community Notes started that
way and some other projects started more part
of the core organization because they were
so intertwined with how we were the nature
of the product that it just made sense to...
Separating it was going to do more harm than
good. So you just have to figure out based on
how execution is going, whether you've got the
right framework and you've got to be willing
to make adjustments when it's not working.
That's actually really helpful. The two that I'm
taking away here is how often are you feeling
bad about the features you're shipping? Like
they're bad for users and you think they're bad
for you as a user potentially. And the other is it
keeping you from taking big bold bets that don't
necessarily drive the metrics you're focusing on.
Okay, so before I let you go, I want to spend some
time on Periscope. I don't know if everybody
knows the history and story of Periscope.
Basically it was the biggest live video
streaming platform in the world and I imagine
inspired basically every other social network to
build a live-streaming platform, Instagram live,
Facebook, TikTok, obviously Twitter. So I
want to spend a little time here and see what
you learned and also just broadly consumer
products, but first of all, I hear there's
a story with Kobe Bryant and Periscope about him
using it in some form. Can you share that story?
Before Periscope launched publicly, which it
was in March of 2015, I want to say, we had a
small beta that grew to maybe 500 people in total
before we actually released the app publicly. And
in that time while we were still in beta, I was
trying to personally onboard every single user
and I had a shtick that I did, which was we'd get
them in the app and I would start a broadcast. We
had a feature called Private Broadcasting
that we basically built for this use case,
which is someone joins, I'm going to go live and
they're going to join and I'm going to show them
how the app works. And we were spending
a lot of time in our office, so Kobe,
Chris Saka actually invited Kobe to the beta.
And so Chris connected us and I did a private
broadcast and Kobe joins and I was like, it was
like 10:00 PM in the office and my routine was
like, let me just walk around the office
talking through the mechanics of Periscope
through the lens of this demo of like, "Hey,
let me show you around the office and here's
how the chat works and you can tap the screen to
send hearts and if you want me to do something,
go to the room over there, just type
it in the chat and it'll come up."
And sort of showed one of the things that was
unique about Periscope was it was a one to many
broadcasts, but still low latency enough
that it felt like a FaceTime so you could
have the bidirectional communication between
multiple viewers and a broadcaster. And so I
was teaching him how to use the chat and showing
him the office and he was playing with it and at
one point through the end of the demo he posts a
comment that was like, "Why the fuck would anyone
want to watch someone else stream live?" And I
remember my heart sank and I started fumbling
through like, "Well, we think it's cool."
And before I could even get the words out,
he posted like, "I'm just fucking with you,
bro. This is incredible." And I just remember
it was just such a surreal moment that has, I'll
never forget, I mean Kobe's a legend obviously,
but to have him essentially troll me while
also putting a point on what was cool about
the experience and that was bidirectional
and something he commented on to cause the
broadcaster to change their behavior or change
the experience, it was a really ironic full circle
of showing off how the product works. But yeah,
it's one of my favorite early Periscope stories.
Oh man, if I kept doing that, the manual
onboarding, I'd be like, "Who's coming?" Just
always worried that someone else fancy is going
to join. You never know who Chris Saka is getting,
who he's talking to. That's amazing. Okay, so
it's been about 10 years, I believe, since you
sold Periscope and about six years ish since you
stopped running at as CEO, something like that.
Now as I shared, every single platform basically
is doing this. They added live video streaming.
I'm curious if there's anything you learned
about just competing with these major platforms.
Well, there's a few reasons why Periscope failed
ultimately and why we shut down the app. Obviously
Periscope, the technology and the mechanics still
lives on because you can go live on Twitter, you
can watch live broadcasts on Twitter, you can do
audio conversations on Twitter and all of that is
the Periscope stack. Still there, which is awesome
that the legacy lives on in a different form
factor. The reason that the Periscope app failed,
it really comes down to a few things. One, we did
not address the core problem that retention wasn't
good. Our poor retention was mapped by just an
incredible surge in top-line user growth. And for
Periscope, it was interesting because every month
or two we would blow up in a new market that would
just bring along an incredible surge in usage.
We blew up in the US, we then blew up in France.
We then blew up in Turkey. We then blew up in the
Middle East and you had these incredible surges,
but underneath that surge, the core product had
retention issues and we ultimately just did
not, we didn't spend enough time prioritizing,
addressing those. And in fact, we shipped product
changes that made those retention issues worse.
Compounding that was the fact that one of the
theses behind our acquisition, the Twitter
acquisition, was that we would leverage the scale
and the community and the product mechanics of
Twitter to make the product grow faster and also
become more durable. And I think that's connects
to one of the reasons why I feel like one of
my learnings and one of the things that we knew
but just failed to execute on was that I still
am very skeptical that there can be a consumer
product that is just focused on live video, like a
generalized synchronous live video application for
short form video I don't think can be durable on
its own. I think you have to surround that product
with enough features and capabilities to allow
a community and an ecosystem of users to be able
to stay in touch with one another asynchronously
and synchronously. This is why a lot of the other
products that you mentioned that incorporate
live capabilities and we're shameless about
copying. What was working about Periscope,
they're surrounded by a scaffolding that
lets people also stay in touch with each other.
Asynchronously Instagram, it's an asynchronous
product that has synchronous features like live.
Same with TikTok obviously. And I think we were
in this position where it was a live only product.
You are connecting with your audience and having a
great time when you're broadcasting live, but
you're not using the product to keep in touch
with that community when you're not broadcasting.
How often throughout the day would you broadcast
live from your phone? And mind you, this is
different for products that are live. There are
live consumer products that focus on a specific
vertical like whatnot for selling or Twitch for
gaming that have very different properties that
make it more durable as a standalone live product.
But Periscope was really in this consumer
generalized live-streaming from a phone land,
and I think it was just not durable to
have the product be live only. And the
time it took us to integrate with Twitter was
way too long. And there was reasons for that
that come down to just how distracted Twitter
was with its own roadmap and refining the core
and they just had other fish to fry basically.
And all of that leads us to competition because
at some point Facebook woke up and decided this is
cool and we need to go build this. And I obviously
wasn't there on the inside, but legend has it,
Mark says, "Hey, you 300 people, stop what you're
doing. Go basically make live exist in our product
as a first [inaudible 01:04:56] experience."
Oh, wow. I didn't know that.
And if you have that level of organizational
effort put on building something that by the way,
you don't have to spend any time wondering
what the product looks like, just go copy
these features basically and make them work. And
they did a lot of other savvy things too from a
partnership standpoint. We had a lot of prominent
streamers that ranged from influencer or just
creative people that became known on Periscopes,
all the way up to celebrities like Kevin Hart and
others who were prolific Periscopers
that Facebook just went and bought out.
They were just like, "Cool, we're going to pay you
a bunch of money to stream exclusively with us."
So they hit us from all sides. They had the entire
company put their effort towards building live in
a way that was cohesive in the core product first
with Facebook and then Instagram and then also
attacked it from the creator as well. And we
were too slow and it was very painful to think
about because it was like many other insights that
Twitter had early. Twitter had the right insight,
but botched the follow through. I'm not pointing
fingers, I blame myself for that just as much,
but there's a pattern where Twitter is really
great at spotting meaningful consumer behavior
changes. They spotted Vine and acquired
Vine, botched it, spotted Periscope,
botched it, spotted Instagram by the way,
before Facebook tried to buy Instagram,
Twitter was trying to buy Instagram, and there
are other reasons why that didn't fall through,
but it's interesting to me, it's one of the
interesting aspects of Twitter's history.
They were phenomenal at spotting meaningful
changes in consumer social behavior,
and actually putting their money where their
mouth is in terms of trying to follow through
on bringing those bets in-house, but then botching
the execution. And so that was one of the things
that was really motivating for me when I was in
my role leading product of Twitter was I didn't
want to make that mistake and we didn't end as
up buying anything like Vine or Periscope and
keeping the product. We obviously bought lots
of small acquirers, but we did obviously have
a bit of a story with Clubhouse that ended
up with us building Spaces and competing
with them. But anyway, that was a long, rambly
story. Hopefully that answered your question.
Yeah, there's so many. Again, it's all these
fractals of thought threads I want to follow
and ask you about. Real quick on the Vine and
Periscope point, I was going to ask this. Twitter,
as you said, had the opportunity to win in
video in so many ways. Vine was amazing,
killing everyone, loved it, and then it's
fades away. I guess, you already shared
a lot of challenges Twitter had with executing,
shipping, Secret Cows, things like that. Is there
anything specific with video? Was it just like,
oh, this is not actually a huge priority and we're
just going to ride it for now and that's why it
didn't work out? Or is there anything more that?
No, it's even more like pathetic than that 'cause
I think Twitter did believe in video, but it made
this classical mistake that we also unfortunately
recreated with Periscope, which was they had the
insight around short-run video, they bought Vine.
They then competed with Vine internally. So Vine
was a separate organization within Twitter,
separate office obviously in New York and then
Twitter rather than integrated holistically
into the product and pour gasoline on it,
they built a native Twitter video feature that
was a different stack, different team. It became
what you think of as Twitter video now. It's
like the most simple active uploading video
and all the professional video tools called Media
Studio that let publishers like ESPN put content.
All of that was basically built as a separate
team, separate organization, separate product
that was competing with Vine. You had two visions
for short form video that were manifesting, and
that's the quickest way for things to get messy.
And of course the separate startup team is going
to get, you're not going to be able to make
good on the vision of buying the company
and integrating it in all the right ways if
you compete with it internally. And we had a
similar thing happen with Periscope. We were very
focused on Periscope with separate organizations,
separate structures, separate app. Periscope at
the time primarily was focused on UGC live video.
So user-generated content being streamed from a
phone. Twitter then decided to get in the premium
live video business very famously with acquiring
rights to Thursday night football, the NFL. Guess
what happened? We competed internally rather than
have a cohesive technical and product vision for
how to embrace live video across the spectrum
of UGC and premium live video, Twitter put a
separate team in charge of premium with a separate
product, separate technology stack. And so you had
two ways to manifest live video on the product.
It was like UGC live video, which was awkwardly
not even really implemented well with Twitter
at the time. And then premium live video, which
had totally different UX, total different team,
totally different architecture. And by the way,
the company put a tremendous amount of energy
and investment in talking about Twitter being
a place to watch the NFL. And meanwhile you had
this burgeoning UGC ecosystem, so this was like
we're making the same mistake all over again.
Now, luckily in the Periscope case with a lot
of persistence and impatience and table pounding,
we eventually fixed that mistake, but we wasted
a tremendous amount of time. It was just a lot of
headbutting in politics and eventually it took us
a lot of time to technically reintegrate things
together and now it's clean and awesome, right?
ESPN can go live with behind the scenes content
at Wimbledon and it's the same technology stack
and the same user experience, the powers, Lenny
going live from his iPhone. But I think that was
one of the reasons why it was an example of failed
execution that ended up wasting time, resources
and just leading to a subpar product experience
that other companies I think have avoided making
such mistakes. Facebook being a prime example,
as frustrated, I am with them as a competitor
for having really taken over the use case for
live video. Got to hand it to them, brilliant
execution, have a lot of respect for them. So we
made sure to not make that mistake moving forward.
I imagine there was reason for that. Partly I
imagine this calcification of just like, we can't
get you done, we just need to start a new team
and do this thing. I imagine it always comes from
like, oh, this makes sense. And then you realize,
okay, this was a terrible idea down the road.
Yeah, it's that and also leadership. When you
don't have unified leadership around these things,
you end up making decisions that are in
conflict with one another. They're just
need a highly opinionated person at the top
that avoids that kind of messiness from a.
That kind of messiness from a
product and engineering standpoint.
You mentioned Clubhouse, so I think what's
interesting is one, many people copy Periscope as
a product. I don't know if you'll describe it as
copying, but it feels like spaces very inspired by
Clubhouse. Do you have just a current philosophy
on when it makes sense to be super inspired by
another product and build it into your existing
product versus like, no, you should not do this?
I think it's always about doing the right
thing for the customer. Everyone has always
been shameless to be shamelessly inspired by
other people's ideas. I don't think there's
anything wrong with that. I think copying
ideas can be done in poor taste and can be
done with taste. I think some of the people
who copied Periscope did so in poor taste,
can't blame them. I wouldn't have done it the
same way, but it worked. So you can't say it's the
wrong thing. I think that it's possible to take
ideas in good taste and take ideas in poor taste.
And I think with Clubhouse, we actually had
been working on audio. Audio was one of those
bets I mentioned that we structured
very separately with a team of people,
many of which were the former Periscope team,
that when we wound down Periscope, I felt very
strongly that there was still something to the
idea of synchronous conversations. Because one
of the famous things that I think we botched
with Periscope is that we always... Our dream
and our vision for Periscope and how we talked
about it was was a mechanism for teleportation.
You could see through someone else's eyes and be
teleported somewhere else. It was like that was
the story we told ourselves. That was the thing
that inspired Periscope. And to a certain extent,
a lot of people did use the product for that way.
You could go see what it was like someplace in the
world where it was something amazing happening
or civil unrest happening or some important
moment happening with breaking news or otherwise.
But it turns out the vast majority of our users
were not using Periscope that way. It wasn't
a rear-facing camera experience where you were
showing someone the world, the vast majority
of people were using it to just talk to other
people. They were bored or they were lonely and
they wanted to just have a conversation with other
people. And it turns out video and audio is a very
interesting way of doing that that allows for more
nuance, more long-form conversation, more in-depth
conversation, especially in contracts to Twitter,
which has mechanics to really incentivize quick,
snappy broadcasts that don't lead to much depth.
And so when we shut down Periscope, we were
like, man, we really need to enable a new
form of conversation on Twitter that has some
of those properties. And so we had a team that
was working on a project that we sort of
code named Hydra. Hydra because there were
multiple heads on this monster and those
heads are participants in a conversation.
And so well before Clubhouse was on the
map, we had many different iterations
of both video and audio only experiences that
just didn't feel right, weren't working right,
but we felt like we were onto something. And when
Clubhouse came on the map, it really re-centered,
it put into focus a user experience that felt a
lot more right and now give them complete credit
for that. Paul and Rohan and that team did an
exceptional job crafting an experience that
really enabled that mechanic and that premise
of enabling these longer form conversations to
shine. And so we did shamelessly seek inspiration
from what they had done and what had worked and we
put our own spin on it. The execution of Spaces
within Twitter I think has some similarities,
but also really took advantage of the mechanics
that you had available to you in Twitter. It's a
different product. And so we took the ideas that
we felt were shortcuts to making the experience
work and then we put our own spin on it. And
so I have no problems with what we did there.
And having had experienced the pain of not
moving quickly enough with Vine from the
outside and Periscope having lived that
experience, we were not willing to not be
the winner with this use case. It is one of the
projects I'm most proud of that we worked on at
Twitter because we were very radical in our
execution. Hydra went from this tiny project
that six people were working on that no one knew
or care about to, we made Spaces as the number one
priority of the company literally above any other
project period. And we put a bunch of people on
accelerating that product and making it come
to life within Twitter. And a lot of that was
having felt the pain and burn of fucking this
up with Vine and Periscope. And so I'm really
proud of our execution. And it was also really
energizing. I hope for the company to see that,
wow, we pulled that off. So yeah, it was good. It
was nice to have that full circle experience and
also nice that, personally, I love that aspects
of Periscope continue living on within Twitter.
I did not know that. That is extremely
interesting. Speaking full circle,
when I joined Clubhouse the first time, Paul was
there introducing me to Clubhouse and exactly the
way you described Periscope, so I feel like he
drew some inspiration from you one step back.
Paul's amazing. I feel like we're kindred spirits
and I could see... It was one of the things I love
about that team is just you could just feel how
palpable their excitement was and their passion
was for what they were building. Another universe
we could have worked together more closely,
but I think what they built was incredible and
we took inspiration from it for sure. Yeah.
So you've built some of the most successful,
most beloved, most used consumer products.
You continue to help other founders with their
product. I'm curious just if you have any advice
for how to get better at building consumer
products in terms of maybe craft a product,
product sense. What have you learned about what
it takes to build a successful consumer product?
The best cheat codes for getting better at
building products is just being a voracious user
of products. And just trying new things, feeling
out what works well, what doesn't, what you like,
what you don't like. There's just no replacement
for that. It's such an effective way of honing
your own taste and seeing what's superficial
but not useful, what's ugly but useful,
what's beautiful and useful. And you hone that by
having practice and building muscle memory. And
so I think there's not a lot of science to it,
I think. I mean obviously science can help you
become more effective at lots of things.
But I feel like I've just always been very
curious about trying new things. I'm a very hungry
consumer of new things that people are building
and I'm not quick to judge. I'll try it even if
it seems dumb because sometimes things that seem
dumb at the beginning become very meaningful.
And so it's always been a very helpful cheat
code for me. And it's also just personally
interesting. Every tool, even the silly ones,
people put their heart and soul into it and it's
like an expression of themselves and it's always
interesting to see that, to see people's creations
and to learn from them and see what you like,
what you don't like and how you might create
something of your own that borrows from that.
So if I could give people any advice through
the lens of what's worked for me, it's that.
Speaking of trying new things,
what are you up to these days?
I'm building something in the consumer space. I
started the company with a couple of co-founders
late last year. We're not quite ready to
talk about it yet, but hopefully you'll be
hearing from us pretty soon. But it's really
nice to be back building something again,
particularly building something with a small
team again after seeing the opposite extreme
with a really large company. We've just talked
about lots of large company things. But yeah,
hopefully you'll be hearing about it soon.
Oh man, I think this is breaking news.
So mysterious and exciting. Kayvon,
is there anything else you wanted to
share or leave listeners with before
we get to our very exciting lightning round?
No, no, I think we've covered quite a bit.
We have. We have indeed. With that, we've reached
our very exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
I'm going to take a sip of
water and then I'll be ready.
Okay, here we go. First question,
what are two or three books that you've
recommended most to other people?
I love reading sci-fi. I just feel like
sci-fi and mystery books are so healthy
for jogging the imagination. And so some of
my favorite books are by Neal Stephenson,
I love Cryptonomicon. I love Reamde. I love a
book called Name of the Wind by Patrick Rothfuss,
which is more like a fantasy book, but I just
love escaping reality and thinking about sci-fi,
thinking about fantasy is just, it's helpful
for the soul and helpful for the imagination.
So those are some of my favorite reads
because it helps me. I feel like in some
weird circular or wandering way, it helps me be
more creative and imaginative. And by the way,
that's true outside of reading as well.
Some of the content that has shaped me,
I feel like and help motivate my curiosity and a
lot of things I built is sci-fi TV, right? Star
Trek is incredible. We used to use as a metaphor
for what Periscope was, we would think about Star
Trek. It'd be really cool to be able to teleport
or get beamed somewhere else in the world and
we're not smart enough to go build that device,
but what's the closest approximation to that that
we can realize through software? Live streaming.
So I think that kind of literature or content
has always been inspirational for me and I think
getting that through books is really healthy.
On that note, is there a favorite
recent movie or TV show that's
inspired you in addition to
Star Trek back in the day?
I mean the most recent movie I saw in
theaters was Dune Two, and it was incredible.
I just saw that.
It's insane. I also thought Oppenheimer was... I'm
a huge Nolan fan. Oppenheimer was captivating. To
have that level of high octane in a biopic
consistently for two and a half hours is
so hard to pull off. And I thought it was
exceptional. TV shows we're watching Tokyo
Vice right now, which I really like. I think
one of the best TV shows I've watched recently,
I mean Succession was amazing, but
maybe I'll pull a less popular one,
which is Devs also in the sci-fi realm. I think
it was a Hulu show. But if you're interested
in tech and AI and you want great acting in
Nick Offerman, Devs is a pretty amazing show.
I haven't heard of that. Have
you seen 3 Body Problem yet,
by the way? It feels like it's
squarely in your wheelhouse.
I haven't seen it yet.
Okay.
And it's funny, some content people are
talking about it so much that I kind of
want to not watch it now because I feel like
it's really hard for shows to live up to the
hype when you're mid-hype cycle. So I haven't
gone around to it yet, but it's definitely on
my list. I know it's the type of show that
I would love, but I just haven't gone.
Okay, great. Do you have a
favorite interview question
that you like to ask candidates you're hiring?
The thing that I find is both very illustrative
and helpful is just asking people to talk about
something they worked on that failed and talk
about something they built that succeeded
as well. But I think you just learn a lot
about self-reflection and their passions.
But particularly their self-reflection.
If they talk through something that they
really cared deeply about that didn't
work and why didn't it work? What were
the takeaways? What did you learn from it? I
think it teaches you about how willing people
are to take risks. It tells you have they
experienced failure, what they learned from
failure. And so I think it's always, you
just get to know someone really well. It
ends up in a well-rounded understanding
of a person, if you can dig into that.
Is there a favorite product you recently
discovered that you really like?
I love Proplexity. It's really interesting to me
how Proplexity is a product that fits in your life
and replaces a product that is so ingrained
in people's behavior, which is using Google
search for some set of use cases. And it's just
really incredible to me how quickly Proplexity
took that over. It is very hard actually to
rewire your muscle memory if you're used to
using Google for searching for 15, 20 years or
whatever. It was just amazing to me how quickly
my go-to became Proplexity. And frankly, it's one
of the only non-development tool AI products that
actually has retained. A lot of people try and
consumer AI products that just aren't really,
haven't retained. But Proplexity
is one that it's a daily driver
for me. It's on my home screen and
I love it. I'm very impressed by it.
Also a huge fan.
Yeah. Here's a bias one, my wife is actually
working on a startup called Particle,
and they're the news experience with AI. And what
I love about what they're doing is that for the
first time they're like they've rethought what
the form factor and the unit of content for news
stories should be. Articles are a failed format,
is my belief, and certainly their belief. And
so they've really come up with an elegant
and engaging experience for understanding
what's happening in the world in a way that's
purely powered by AI. And it's awesome. Again,
hashtag biased husband, but it's amazing. It's
in beta right now. You can sign up on the wait
list. The URL is particlenews.ai. They're
letting people in on beta. If you sign up,
use coupon code hashtag #KayvonLenny. That's
not a real code. But yeah, so that's amazing.
So that would be my second pick.
I'll give you a non-software one,
which is actually a board game that I ran
into, that I was gifted actually for my
birthday. And it's called Crokinole. Have
you heard of this game called Crokinole?
I have not.
So Crokinole is Canadian. I think it's a Canadian
board game and it's amazing to me because I've
never seen a game be captivating to all age
ranges. I love it. I play with my friends. My
parents over Christmas were obsessed with this
game. My daughter loves. It's a physical game.
You flick a puck, like shuffleboard style,
but miniaturized with a totally different
set of mechanics. And it was just like seeing
this game captivate, people of all age ranges
was mind-blowing to me and it's really fun.
So maybe a curveball answer for you there,
but I think those are some of the products that
I've been really enjoying and appreciating lately.
These are awesome answers. What's the
name of that game again? I'm going to-
Crokinole.
Okay. I don't don't know how to spell it,
but I'm sure Google will help me figure it
out. We'll link to it in the show notes.
C-R-O-K-I-N-O-L-E.
Great. I love the K in there. That
makes it really fun. And by the way,
I think it's also Particle.news looking
at it. It's so cool. It's basically bullet
points of news items and then it links
to all the articles that have written
about it. So it just summarizes, here's the
things you need to know and it's beautiful.
Yeah, basically they consume and aggregate
everything that's happening in the world
by among other things, ingesting
articles and then crafting these
story modules through them that are
summarized by AI. And then they let
you actually interrogate the news and ask
questions. So leveraging LLMs and tool calls,
it's able to actually help you understand
what's happening in the world. And they also
are building a social layer as well. So it was
very cool. I'll definitely get you in the beta.
This is actually amazing timing, because I
was a huge fan of Artifact, the news app,
and they're going away, so this is the next news
app, so thanks for sharing that. Okay, two more
questions. Do you have a favorite life motto
that you often come back to or share with people
that you find useful in work or in life?
Something that definitely shaped my work ethic
and how I work that came from my first boss
actually. When I was 14, I had a summer job
basically replacing and doing maintenance
on fire extinguishers. So I would drive into San
Francisco, my boss would pick me up in his truck,
we'd go to big commercial buildings, hospitals,
high rises, and we would take all the fire
extinguishers in the building, hundreds of them
to the garage, empty them, fill them, tag them,
inspect them. And that was my first job. And I
don't even remember if I was getting paid. I was
probably getting paid very small amount, but it
was just first work experience. And I remember
there was this moment that I had finished dealing
with my extinguishers and I was just sitting in
his truck twiddling my thumbs doing nothing.
And my boss came up to me and was like, when
you've got nothing to do, sweep never sit around.
And it was so funny, it was just very tiny moment,
but I've never ever forgotten that. When you
got nothing to do sweep. And it had such a
profound impact on my work ethic of there's
always something you can be doing to move
the ball forward and being productive and being
impactful. And I'm so grateful that Fred, my boss,
had that moment with me. It was like, I don't
even think he understands how impactful that was,
but it felt so much a life motto, but it
definitely stuck with me and shaped how I work.
I love that you shared that story. I found
that quote and story in GQ Magazine turns
out is where you talked about this and I was
going to ask about it and I didn't and I'm
glad you shared it because I love it.
Final question, we're going to go full
circle. Scott Belsky, you're friends
with him. What's something people
would be surprised about or don't know
about Scott, that might be interesting?
Well, I'll tell you one funny story and then I'll
first tell you something I love about Scott. Scott
is a great example of someone who I think has
driven immense cultural change at a massive,
legendary company in Adobe obviously. But the
number of transformations that Scott oversaw and
led and contributed to at Adobe are incredible.
And I'm sure having a fraction of this experience
at Twitter, I can appreciate how difficult and
challenging and rewarding that was, right? Going
from package software to cloud, going from non-AI
to AI, going from discrete tools to an integrated
suite that worked really elegantly together.
I think Scott oversaw a lot of this stuff and
it's pretty incredible to see that transformation
have been so successful at Adobe. So I love that.
I guess a funny story about Scott that people
might not know, I consider him to have been the
first Periscoper. So Scott believed in Periscope
before it was Periscope, before we had turned it
into live video, we had a previous version of our
beta that was static photo sharing, same vision,
same concept, but the product was called Bounty.
And it was like you put a pin somewhere in the
world like the Tokyo fish market and someone would
respond with a photo of what it looked like there.
I didn't know that.
Our vision was still to help you see through
someone else's eyes, but the first manifestation
was really static and had this marketplace
dynamic, and it took us a while to get to the
point where we were like, press a button,
go live and have it be live video because
by definition it's real time rather than static.
Anyways, before we built any of that, when we were
playing with the idea and Scott was encouraging us
to go in this direction, I remember probably the
second time I ever met Scott, we did it FaceTime
and he was at the TED conference, I want to say it
was in Vancouver, and just to illustrate how cool
it would be when he accepted the FaceTime and he's
like, "Cool, and I'm going to take you on a
Periscope." And he flipped this camera and started
walking around the TED conference and basically
pretending like he was prototyping the product,
but using FaceTime. And it was such an amazing
experience because having an investor essentially
encourage you down a product direction by
showing rather than telling, it was such a great
encapsulation of how supportive Scott was and
inspiring Scott was as one of our cheerleaders.
And I respect him so much for everything he did to
help Periscope make happen, and also for betting
on us, because he was one of the first people
who said yes to investing. He didn't know us,
he just believed in us. And that helped everything
else come together. And yeah, he's amazing.
What a mensch.
We've got to get him back on the podcast. The
story reminds me of your Elon's story, where
he FaceTimed you, and it also makes me think
about your lesson of building consumer products,
just using it, being obsessed
with it, Scott, just like,
here's what it could look like. And actually
using the product, not just talking about.
Yeah, he's a great example of that as
well. He's definitely a gracious user
of all tools and products, and that's why he
has really great, really great product sense.
Kayvon, you're amazing. This was so
freaking fascinating. There's so many
nuggets here. Can't wait for folks to hear this.
Two final questions. Where can folks find you
if they want to reach out and learn more and
maybe follow up on anything if there's things
you want to follow up on potentially? And
then, how can listeners be useful to you?
People can find me on Twitter/X/whatever we're
calling it these days. My handle is @kayvz,
K-A-Y-V-Z. And yeah, if you're of this
podcast and you're working on something
cool and you need some help or advice
or you're looking for an angel investor,
don't hesitate to reach out and would
love to try what you're building.
Amazing. And also check out Particle.news.
There you go.
Support the wife.
Exactly.
Amazing. All right, Kayvon,
thank you so much for being here.
Thanks Lenny. Great to meet you.
Bye everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.