I think it's so underappreciated, the
turnaround that has happened within
LinkedIn. I check it at least 10 times
a day. What was the strategy behind it?
I start backwards. It's like what is
the potential here? If you start from
the premise that LinkedIn ultimately is
a platform for economic opportunity that
sits on top of a very strong social graph. Almost
every aspect of economic transaction is possible.
Is there anything tactically
that would just like, wow,
that really made a big dent in people wanting to
come here and post, share interesting content?
To really set the new purpose for it,
which was this is not a springboard for other
products. This is not a traffic jumpstart,
it's not an upsell feed. It's really about
people that matter, talking about things
that I care about professionally. The first
thing we did was really making AI first.
How do you actually on the ground help people
shift their perspective and think AI first?
So it wasn't like, "Oh, we have this cool
technology, what can we do with it?" It was
like, "Let go of what you've built. Go
back to the objectives you were trying
to solve and now with this technology,
how can you do that objective better?"
There's so much I want to dig into here. Is there
anything else that you think would
be interesting or useful for folks?
AI is the ultimate matchmaker. It's underutilized,
it's misunderstood, it's really about...
Today my guest is Tomer Cohen. Tomer is chief
product officer at LinkedIn overseeing all teams
responsible for building and creating LinkedIn
products and experiences, including product
development, design, business development,
content creation, and customer operations.
During his tenure at LinkedIn, Tomer was head
of the mobile team, led the effort to revamp
the LinkedIn feed and to many people surprised,
made it extremely interesting in a place I check
regularly. And he was also at the center of
shifting LinkedIn to an AI first mindset,
which started way before AI became cool. In our
conversation, Tomer goes inside the strategy
behind the transformation of LinkedIn's feed and
how they approached making it a place that people
wanted to check and make it much more social.
We also get into the one mindset that Tomer
credits for helping him rise so quickly
within LinkedIn. Also, why Tomer's most
repeated mantra is, "We might be wrong, but we
are not confused." And so much more. This episode
is for anyone wanting to see what great product
leadership looks like and wants to be inspired to
think bigger. A big thank you to Shira Gasarch,
Dan Roth, Josh Redfern, and Sparsh Argawal for
question suggestions that made this episode so
interesting. With that, I bring you Tomer Cohen.
Tomer, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you for having me.
Absolutely, my pleasure. So as I was preparing for
this podcast, I reached out to a bunch of people
that have worked with you and asked them what I
should ask you on this podcast, and interestingly,
every single one of them said this one thing that
I need to ask you, which is about this phrase that
apparently you use all the time. So first of
all, can you guess what this phrase might be?
I have a few. Sometimes
people call them Tomerisms.
Tomerisms.
But probably I might be wrong but not confused.
That's the one. Amazing. Okay,
so let's talk about this phrase.
I don't say it so much anymore. I
think it's ingrained into the cultures.
I was going to say that.
When they think of me, they
think of this sentence already.
Those are the ultimate things where you
don't need to say them as much anymore. Okay,
so the phrase again is, "We might
be wrong but we're not confused."
Exactly.
Let's talk about this. So what
does this phrase mean and why
do you find it so powerful
and important to say often?
Yeah, by the way, it's a simple phrase, but it
has in my opinion, so much depth into that and
ultimately something I really believe in. It's
rooted in clarity and principles that ultimately
lead to leadership. And the first time I got the
inspiration from it was from a startup founder
I met many, many years ago. Their company was on
the brink of failure. They had their last attempt
and they decided on a path forward and after
they decided on a path forward, he was still
seeing people hedging in different directions
and it led into this confusion in the system
where we decided people are still hedging, they're
still trying out things they thought could work,
and he realized that unless they basically
all pull through in the same direction, there
is no chance they'll be able to be successful.
Now, pulling through in the same direction doesn't
mean you're going to be successful, but this
gives you a chance of success and that confusion,
the system only luck and save you. So that was
when he shared that, that was very impactful
for me. I think it's a good one for life as
well. And for me it comes down to two main
parts. One is clarity of thought and clarity of
execution, and they're both equally important.
This episode is brought to you by Gamma, an
entirely new way to present your ideas powered
by AI. If you hate designing slides and dread
that feeling of staring at a blank slide, Gamma
is here to help. Just upload your PRD and turn it
into a beautiful ready-to-present presentation in
seconds. Gamma works with all types of formats
from Google Docs, PDFs to PowerPoint. You can
even drop in a link to your favorite Lenny's
newsletter post and turn it into a presentation
for your team. Gamma has become one of the
fastest growing AI web products in the world,
adding 20 million new users just this past year
and is setting its sights on becoming the modern
alternative to PowerPoint. Whether you have design
skills or not, Gamma can save you hours of time
synthesizing your ideas and shaping your content.
Visit Gamma.app and use promo code Lenny to get a
free month of Gamma Pro. That's G-A-M-M-A dot app.
This episode is brought to you by WorkOS. If
you're building a SaaS app, at some point your
customers will start asking for enterprise
features like SAML authentication and SCIM
provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in,
making it fast and painless to add enterprise
features to your app. Their APIs are easy to
understand so that you can ship quickly and get
back to building other features. Today, hundreds
of companies are already powered by WorkOS,
including ones you probably know like Vercell,
Webflow and Loom. WorkOS also recently acquired
Warrant, the fine-grained authorization service.
Warrant's product is based on a groundbreaking
authorization system called Zanzibar,
which was originally designed for Google to
power Google Docs and YouTube. This enables
fast authorization checks at enormous scale
while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases.
If you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features like
single sign-on SCIM or user management, you should
consider WorkOS, it's a drop-in replacement
for Auth0 and supports up to one million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
WorkOS.com to learn more, that's WorkOS.com.
On the clarity of thought. What I find people
to be attached to, especially when you build
an environment with a lot of alpha types is that
they get attached to being right or wrong and that
really creates a lot of lingering in the system, a
lot of confusion and they're still stuck to their
ideas. And for me, I get attached to clarity
and focus. I think that's much more important.
That's why I think when I say I don't mind being
wrong, it really comes from a humble place. I
would rather go forward with everybody in the same
direction than necessarily try to hedge all the
time, which will give me no chance of success. The
way we start, we do this in our product gens right
now, is we actually spend some significant time on
what is the problem we're trying to solve for, but
not high level, not like, hey, we want to launch
this product, we want to launch a video product.
It's exactly what type of video you're trying to
launch for which audience, what is your unique
criteria, what are you trying, what is very
nuanced about what you're trying to solve for?
Ideally, once the time you see the problem,
you know exactly the problem you're trying,
you actually can imagine that mountain. It's not
just a mountain, you can see exactly the road,
you can see exactly the end of the base
camp. But then when you move to solution,
I love solutions that are based on first
principles. That they have, there's a principle
thinking about it, there's opinions about it.
If you talk to folks who work with me, they'll
tell you, I push a lot for what is actually your
opinion, what is your potentially controversial
opinion and the best principles have teeth.
So saying that we should build a simple product
for me is useless. Who doesn't want to build a
simple product? But saying that I'm willing to
sacrifice or trade off this, that's where I get
excited. I'm like, okay, that's a very strong
opinion. Let's go into that. Why were you willing
to trade off those type of vectors to make it
happen? And one thing that I saw also in clarity
of thought was this, is I came to the US in 2008,
I came from Israel. Our hobby in Israel is to
argue. So we argue a lot, it's our love language
in many ways. And I come to the US and I notice
people say a lot like I don't exactly understand
or I'm not exactly clear on this, and it took me a
long time to realize they're actually disagreeing.
They're just masking it with a layer of
misunderstanding and a good mentor of mine said,
"Hey, just push back. Are you disagreeing or
misunderstanding? If you're misunderstanding,
let's spend the night. Let's get to a point where
you can articulate my point of view in your words
and I can do the same, but if we're disagreeing,
let's stop. Why are we spending? Why wasting time
just arguing it through?" So those became really
powerful. That's on the clarity of thought,
clarity of execution is even more important
because many organizations actually reach a
decision, they don't act on it, which it's one
of those shocking things. They decide this is
a top priority, but it doesn't make its way into
the organization. And I'll give you an example.
Somebody will say, "Hey, my top priority for my
business is this initiative." And then I'll say,
"But most of your engineers are working on
this migration." And they'll say, "Yeah,
we have to finish that." I'm like, "So
why don't you say the migration is my
number one priority?" It's like, "Yeah."
It's like, but that's exactly what you're
doing. You have to make sure that what you're
sharing as a priority is actually manifested
in your resourcing. Then I'm like, "Hey,
this is your top talent. Why is your top
talent working on some moonshots that are not
in your number one priority?" And they're like,
"Yeah." This is where you start finding
that really it doesn't really translate
into execution as well and you can solve so much
by just making that sure that focus is there.
So the big lesson here is to push for clarity
and push out anything that is unclear, confusion
either in thought and also in execution. One of
the folks that I talked to that worked with you
about this phrase, Josh Redfern, he said that this
phrase became really liberating for him, which is
really interesting to hear because it forces you
to make a call and to be aligned and make sure
everyone is on the same page. I guess thoughts
on just why this concept is so liberating.
It goes back to little alpha types or type A
folks who are just so attached to not getting
it wrong. When you need to move forward
and it's not about being right or wrong,
it's really about not being confused and making
sure everybody's pulling in the same direction.
That is actually really liberating. And when you
know that the whole idea is to have a Socratic
conversation about what you're trying to do, then
coming to the table with some kind of half-baked
ideas or actually not an opinion, I think
actually brings into a conversation of feedback.
But you have to manifest it through, if you
just play this through but then you potentially
playing the right or wrong game, that's really
poor. I also think it's the best way to learn.
If you don't know exactly what you're doing,
how can you learn back from why you made that
decision? So if you had a clear understanding,
ultimately it's a growing organization. This
is not a one-off project. We're going to build
many projects in the future. So if you're not
sure about what we're trying to accomplish,
how can you know what you learned from it?
I love that. So the idea here is
make it very okay to be wrong,
but make it not okay to be confused and
not clear about here's what we're doing,
here's why we're doing it. Everyone's
aligned exactly on the same idea.
How can I have a product conversation if I'm not
sure what you stand for? It's really hard to have
a Socratic conversation, really hard to have. If
you ask folks how many time you left a meeting
in corporate, it could be a startup or larger
companies and you are not sure exactly what was
the problem discussed or what are next steps. More
often than not, they'll raise their hand. That for
me is a waste of building time. So actually that
agitates me in another great way, but when I come
in and I'm proven wrong or there's a strong
challenge or argument, again that's a little
bit my love language, I actually enjoy those.
I think we leave the conversation much better.
You said there's some other Tomerisms, what
are some others just that you can share?
This is, again, this is classic to building
large organizations, but I actually believe in,
especially when it comes to products,
to really set ambitious goals but then
try to over-deliver on them, really set
what are you trying to, there's almost
like the opposite where people are
underplaying it and over delivering,
I don't understand what you're trying to do. For
me it's like we are here to make an impact. We're
here to really set our goals to something really
massive. And when I'm trying to visualize this,
I see a mountain, you see the peak and the peak
exactly how it looks like, you see base camp,
you know how to start and maybe the
middle of the mountain is kind of blurry,
but you'll figure this out. But at least you know
the peak you're trying to share, share the peak,
share where you're headed to and I think it's
just a much more exciting way to build product.
It's a much more inspirational way for folks to
be part of the product process kind of thing.
I was just chatting with Vlad who worked at Airbnb
for many years. He was actually my former manager
at Airbnb and he reported to Brian for a long time
and we talked about this trait that Brian also
is really good at, is just setting crazy high
goals. 10 X the goal that you thought you had
and what would it take and it worked really well
for Airbnb. So I love that you're doubling down
on the same idea. Is there an example that comes
to mind of one that you, some ambitious goal you
set internally at LinkedIn that people are like,
"No way," and then it ended up being effective?
Actually there's a lot, when I think about our
LinkedIn feed and thinking about when you started
off, it was hard to imagine what that product
could be because it was more of a promotional in
nature product and I was like, no, is going to be
a place where millions of people and not just tens
of millions will come daily. And that's insane.
That makes no sense based on the numbers today,
but I don't start building from the numbers
today. I start from [inaudible 00:15:04] I start
backwards. I'm like, what this could be, what
is the potential here? So how many professionals
exist in their role? How many of them would love
to find a place to share and engage with content?
And this is my starting point. I start from
there. So I don't start from the existence to
set my ambition. I start from what this could be
like based on really inspiration and excitement.
Again, it's not detached from reality completely,
but it's also not hooked to it. But then Basecamp
could be a good start. You're not asking you
to make it the next day, but if you don't have
that ambition, there's no way you're going to
hit that. There's just no way. And there's so
many products across LinkedIn. LinkedIn is a
20 plus year old company that many folks did
not give it a chance in almost every phase of it.
And I think if anything, it's one of those that
just keeps getting better and better every year.
And part of it is you keep the landmark on. This
really has the potential to do so much for so many
people. It's really an economic platform. So if
you play from that, one billion members, that's
actually pretty small where we can actually go,
I'm so happy you went to this example. This is
exactly where I wanted to take the conversation.
I was very much in the camp you described of
LinkedIn, how could LinkedIn possibly become a
place that I want to go and browse a feed and
post content? As you probably know, for the
longest time it was felt like this cringey place
as you said, where everyone comes and promotes
themselves, "Hey, I got a promotion or here's
my company's new launch." And I think it's so
underappreciated the turnaround that has happened
within LinkedIn. I use it, I'm a multi-day,
multi-Dow user. I check it at least 10 times a
day. Most of my traffic to my newsletter comes
from LinkedIn, not Twitter where people think,
it's absurdly underappreciated and it's I think
underappreciated what it took to make this happen.
And when I saw you guys starting to try to make
it a place people post content, I was like, no
way, this is not going to work. Why would people
want to share stuff on LinkedIn? And it's
working, it's amazing. So I want to spend
some time here and just try to go inside the
strategy that you guys put together to here's
how we're going to make this happen. Come,
we've shared, you have this peak of here's
what we could become. How did you actually turn
this around? What was the strategy behind it?
Yeah, by the way, I'm glad you're finding
great audience and traffic on LinkedIn. I think
your content, actually, your content is exactly
what we're trying to build for, it's expertise,
it's advice, it's people you can learn from
and it's also the views that really matter,
not just the volume that matters. I think if we
take a step back, there's so much conversation
about zero to one products or scaling products,
but you don't have much conversations about minus
one to one products, like turnaround products.
And I think there's obviously the perception
of the market you have to deal with, but
people I think in minus to one products,
at least from my experience and we had a few
at LinkedIn, pages is another one, helping
businesses build their presence on LinkedIn. What
you find is it's actually, most of the time it's
internally harder to do because there's so much
entrenched flows and processes and metrics that
people are using on that specific area.
So you almost have to change the inner
workings of the system to make it work.
Going back to the analogy of the mountain,
if you start from the premise that I deeply
believe in is that LinkedIn ultimately is a
platform for economic opportunity that sits on
top of a very strong social graph. Then really
almost every aspect of economic transaction is
possible and knowledge transaction is one of the
most powerful economic transactions you can have.
It's the biggest accelerant for an experience and
we were always very strong at helping people
get a job. We have seven hires per minute,
but as we were building more and more knowledge
and part of it was we bought LinkedIn,
we bought Lynda to make it LinkedIn Learning a
while back. Today we had 140 hours of learning
every minute on LinkedIn happening across the
feed and LinkedIn Learning, it's pretty powerful.
And the transformation to the LinkedIn feed
was exactly like you said. We actually were
the first company to have a social feed, but
I think we started wrong. So we started with
basically activity feed. So it was like
who changed what, who changed the job, who
connected to who. It was more of like a tracking
your network feed and it became more promotional
in nature. So in a way just letting that be just
naturally just moved into more of a promotional
type of feed. And what we've done is we've shifted
dramatically into building, actually this was one
of the things I was excited about. So after I was
leading the mobile team, there was no feed team,
there was no unified feed team, there was no
feed PM to an extent, I asked to do this role,
nobody cared about it. I really believed in it.
I have strong conviction about what I could
do there. And I asked to do this role
and we assembled the team around it and
one of the main things we've done was
to really set the new purpose for it,
which was this is not a springboard for other
products, this is not a traffic jumpstart for,
it's not an app self feed, it's really about
people that matter talking about things that
I care about professionally. It's about knowledge
exchange. It's about how can I get the right views
to the right experts in a way that actually helps
them build a reputation and build their business.
And then we started from there backwards. So
it was basically setting that ground for that
mountain peak that was nowhere to be imagined
at the beginning and making our way backwards.
The first thing we did was really making AI
first. So the AI team back then was completely
centralized. It was not part of any product team
and we brought it together with one unified AI
first team. And the belief I had was ultimately
the engine of the car was AI and that was almost
like de-prioritized or delegated to a team that
was not unified in objectives. So bring that in.
And then I spent most of my time on objectives and
algorithm features and data training, which led me
into my passion about training product people
to be a first product people. And that was a
big transformation there, really shifting and we
had incredible AI team, but they were completely,
actually, it was a confused operation. They were
building something for a whole different purpose
and we were trying to aim to that mountain peak
and they were putting in a different direction.
No bad intent, that's what they were told to do.
So bringing it together into this SWAT team
was the first thing that actually was extremely
powerful, but then became the hard work. You
have a product that works in a certain way and you
almost want to change its DNA altogether. And it
was very hard because whenever we were trying
to run experiments that were mass in scale,
I told you everybody was relying on the feed for
their traffic. It just scared the whole system
because numbers were shifting up and down and
teams were freaking out about meeting their goals.
And then I realized that was just spending my
time in escalations instead of actually building
a great product. So what I did was I carved out
two million members and I said, "Those are my
members. I'm going to focus on building that
mountain peak. I'm going to build for them."
Full liberty and doing whatever, it doesn't hurt
numbers, giving the scale and really focus on
building a great experience for them. And it
wasn't overnight and it wasn't over a week,
but over the course of months we've seen
dramatic behavior change for those members,
almost like secluded, like a country
of people that were seeing a different
experience of LinkedIn. And once we saw that
you actually had strong evidence that wow,
if I bring this in, we don't need to spend
time talking about how this pie gets slotted
between different teams. We can actually grow the
pie. The experience just manifests itself in a
whole different way and that was a big change
internally. It wasn't overnight, but it was
really powerful in getting everybody around
to see, wow, we have this cohort that is doing
extremely well, which was a randomized
cohort and then how we can bring it out.
I've also done some crazy things. We've done
some negative tests to prove some stuff out,
test for the sake of learning. When you
run something that you can show that if
it's just a promotional feed and you played it out
organically over time, engage with the tier rates.
We ran some really important ad tests as well,
but we're really shown separate, almost like we
carved out the different product and we showed
that this could work and then we brought it out
to the main experience for everybody else. And
then that was, I would say the inner workings of
minus one to one. Then the scanning part really
became when we started to focus on professional
opportunities. So when people actually share, how
do they get the right views into the experience?
We don't compete for volume, we're not in the same
category of Meta in terms of the skill there, but
we will compete all day long for the right people
seeing your content. In fact, I think in many ways
that's the most powerful part of LinkedIn. How do
we make sure that it's professionally productive
and safe conversations? How do we trade off bad
engagement all day long? In fact, when we started
shifting the AI objective from click through
into more downstream conversations, spammers
actually took notice as well. So they were jumping
over the LinkedIn bandwagon, so we had to spend a
lot of time removing bad activity from LinkedIn,
but that's been the evolution of this process.
That is amazing. There's so much
I want to dig into here. Okay,
so this two million user carve out that
you did, basically everyone was just like,
what the hell are you doing to our metrics
and goals? You're causing all this trouble
for the business. Why is this team hurting
our metrics? So that was basically a group
that those two million users are the only ones
that saw this new updated feed and were they
removed from everyone else's metrics so they
weren't fluctuated as much or was it just?
They could be kept in the overall
because it wasn't as important.
It was a small percent?
Exactly.
Okay. Got it.
But for us, they were like the world we
were basically able to prove with them.
Got it. Okay. That's so smart. Okay, so
basically you just decided we're only
going to move your metrics a little
bit, worst case if we stick to it.
I felt that I tried for a few months to play
on the overall experience with everybody,
but it was really hard, almost
like impossible because you have
an organization that is so tied into how
things work that I was just hitting walls
after walls after escalations
and it was just unproductive.
And this is before you were a chief product
officer where you could have just said,
"We will take this bet. We know
this might hurt metrics short-term"?
Yes.
Okay, got it. That makes sense. Okay,
the other piece, so just like lessons
I'm taking away from trying something like
this that's an ambitious bet within a company,
is put a PM and a team on it with
a goal that feels like a core part
of the success of just like somebody's
ass is on the line to doing this thing.
Always.
Always, with focus on this one problem.
And then there's the way you described
there's this goal for this feed, but how
did you actually try to turn that into a
goal or metric or a KPI, what was that
in the end, was there something there?
Yeah, this is an interesting one, one thing we've
done actually because the feed is the first thing
you land on. I can't just count how many folks
engage with the feed because then I'm counting
bypassers kind of thing and bystanders that
are actually coming into the experience. So we
actually started to look at the more, we go a lot
into active, engaged and high value engagement.
So we go downstream, we kind of put the onus on
looking at more downstream engagement there and
we build that as the feed engagement. So really
trying to show that we're not just counting some
overall whatever it is [inaudible 00:27:09] or
sessions at the top level. That's not really
helpful because any shifts can help there, but
really setting targets for that. There's obviously
it's a marketplace, so there's the creation side,
there's the consumption side's, there's making
sure that's healthy and engaging.
There was so much we went into that,
but I think the best thing was it's almost like
you carve out. I think when you do minus one to
one, it's really hard unless the CEO says
I don't care about how the company performs
for the next two years, we're going to go for
it. If you want to keep the site keep growing
and the experience keep growing, carving out and
almost like sending very specific unique metrics
but then could easily be extended out once you
show it was in retrospect the right way to do it.
And then to give people a glimpse into the
way your brain works to identify this is a
big opportunity. So you talk about just like
I see there's a lever that we're not investing
enough in and I see this big opportunity
to grow of LinkedIn. How did you decide I
need to go and bet on this thing and lead this
team and I think feed is a huge opportunity?
I start from beliefs a lot. So I start from
what do I believe this could be or where I
actually came to LinkedIn this way. In fact my
biggest change in my career was when I moved
here and I shifted to more like what do I care
about? What am I excited about? What do I have
conviction on? I think it's really hard to be
a strong product leader without having strong
conviction about something. So I start there
and in fact coming to LinkedIn as an example,
when I came into lead mobile, LinkedIn was a
desktop first company, then mobile team was
an offshoot of entrepreneurs. I came from
a startup that I ran and it wasn't a big,
it wasn't, it was like, okay, I
want to do mobile, I guess fine.
It's like noise at this point. Same with
feed. And same when I shifted into ads,
I felt really strong about the ability to flip
that into a great way for companies to grow.
So for me it starts with a conviction of where
things could go, what do I believe in? I believe
LinkedIn can be an incredible superpower and daily
use case for every professional in the world. I
believe knowledge sharing and knowledge exchange
is the most amazing way to grow your career and to
grow your business. So that needs to be a strong
pillar of the experience, what didn't exist before
and what is better than the feed experience,
the home [inaudible 00:29:32] to actually build
it. So I don't get attached to what did not
work in the past. That's not, I don't know,
maybe it's a mistake sometimes, but that
doesn't stop me from thinking about the future.
How do you actually make time to think like this?
A lot of people are listening. They're just like,
"Okay, I want to think about what could
this become?" Is this just the way brain
works? You're always thinking what could this
be? Do you set time aside to think quarterly
or yearly, what could this be
if we really made this amazing?
It's a good question. I haven't thought about
it. It's like a process I do. I don't sit time
aside for this, but I'm very reflective. I try
to focus, love the conversations on the dream,
what ultimately are we trying to
achieve? I think LinkedIn has a
great process called vision to values that
started from our former CEO, Jeff Winner,
which is like if you said this is for company
or for a product, which is if you're successful,
what change would happen in the world? Which I
love. It's just a great phrase. It's just a great
empowering phrase. So I actually tend to spend
a lot of my time there. I'm also very optimistic
in nature. Again, sometimes it's probably,
I'm not best for any role perspective. You
want somebody a bit more pessimistic about the
future, but I tend to lead with beliefs versus
evidence. I try to prove my beliefs with
evidence, but I don't lead with evidence.
Awesome. Okay. And then maybe just one more
tactical question about this shift that I
wish I could spend hours on because it's so
interesting, the success you had making the
feed so engaging. Is there anything tactically
that would just like wow that would really made
a big dent in people wanting to come here
and post and share interesting content,
like a feature or a part of the strategy
that really made the feed social?
I think the lesson would be, for me that
was the biggest learning going into AI
first that gave me the why is AI so core and
why I got to make it a priority all the way
to my role today to make sure the rest of the
organization thinks AI first. The understanding
is is that in a marketplace, if I'm able
to satisfy your need on the other side,
then it's magic. So ultimately it came down to AI
is the ultimate matchmaker. It's underutilized,
it's misunderstood, it's run separate from the
team. And in a marketplace it's all about value
exchange. And if I'm able to do value exchange
really well, then people will come back and they
do and they engage and actually they come
back even more and they spend more time.
So for me it was that depth into AI first as the
engine that moves the whole organization forward.
Got it. So essentially making sure
the content you are seeing is the most
engaging you could see based on using
AI to make the algorithm really smart?
On both sides. If you are the creator, if you're
the person sharing, remember this was a while
back, I think it was about the former Olympics
and person shared an article on LinkedIn about how
they should not call it Olympics, they should call
it the commercial Olympics because it's all about
commercials and less Olympics. And then they sent
me this amazing screenshot about how NBC execs
who were covering the Olympics were rearing the
post, this first to them was gold. It was like,
"Oh my god, my content is influencing, people are
seeing it, people that matter." So that was really
key. Making sure that when you share something,
you share your expertise. The right people on the
other side are relevant to your content and they
see it. That could make your day or your week or
actually it could make your living in many ways.
And then on the receiving side, when I come in,
it's the things I'm excited about seeing.
It's the things that are relevant, the reason
your content resonates so much with other people,
I can actually take your podcasts and I can apply
them at work. What could be a better way to learn?
I'll give you another example, which was very,
very recent. I met with a known professor in this
field and he shared with me how over the last year
and a half he started using LinkedIn because
somebody told him, "You have a great content,
why don't you just post it?" I was like, "I don't
want to post on social media." I'm like, "Oh,
LinkedIn is different, share on LinkedIn."
And he was like, "I post daily. I have so
much content over the years, I post daily."
And he was like, he basically told me this is
unbelievable in terms of economic opportunity
I'm getting. He's like, "I'm getting speaking
engagements that are roughly half the salary I
make in a year here at the university. Just by
people seeing this content and getting to
the right people. I was invited to advise
prime ministers on their investment strategy for
the country and I've been teaching for 20 years,
but this platform just completely elevated
my ability to reach and influence people."
That's the magic and that's the value exchange
and that's the kind of matchmaking at scale.
Amazing. That's an awesome story. This episode
is brought to you by Merge, product leaders. Yes,
like you, cringe when they hear the word
integration, they're not fun for you to scope,
build, launch or maintain, and integrations
probably aren't what led you to product work
in the first place. Lucky for you, the folks
at Merge are obsessed with integrations. Their
single API helps SaaS companies launch over 200
product integrations in weeks, not quarters. Think
of Merge like Plaid, but for everything B2B SaaS,
organizations like Ramp, Dorada and Electric use
Merge to access their customer's accounting data
to reconcile bill payments, file storage data to
create searchable databases in their product
or HRIS data to auto-provision and deprovision
access for their customer's employees. And yes,
if you need AI ready data for your SaaS product,
then Merge is the fastest way to get it. So
want to solve your organization's integration
dilemma once and for all? Book and attend
a meeting at merge.dev/lenny and receive a
$50 Amazon gift card. That's merge.dev/lenny.
I want to shift a little bit in talking about
this AI first mindset that you've touched on a
lot. So you talked about how at the beginning of
this investment, you've already been focused
on AI before it was as hot as it is today,
and I've heard from many people that you're
really big on getting people to shift to this
mindset of being very AI first. Clearly it's
worked really well at LinkedIn. I'm curious
just what that actually looks like. I know you
could be like, "Hey guys, we got to be AI first,
AI, AI, AI." But it's different to actually
make people really think differently. How
do you actually on the ground help people
shift their perspective and think AI first?
I can spend days on this. This is so
important. It's actually so important for me,
it's a key focus for me. Actually to your point,
long before it became cool to talk about AI in the
last two years, and in fact I think I've learned
this on myself. So when it comes to the feed,
I took the role of the AI product leader, it
didn't exist in the company. There was no person
that was ever from a product perspective thinking
about AI. I think it start with the belief,
like we talked about before, I think every
technological revolution has dramatically changed
the way we build. And AI arguably is the biggest
one in our lifetimes. And when I say AI first,
it's not about a tech, it's a mindset. It's
a start with strategy. It is rare. Maybe now
you'll see it, but it was rare two years
ago to see anybody in their strategy talk
about the role of AI and how they build with AI.
Then it goes to the product and then the talent
itself you hire, do they actually think this way?
The analogy I would give to people is imagine a
river rafting boat and you have everybody on the
sides holding the pedals and adding accuracy,
adding speed, but there's the guide on the
back and they're holding those two pedals.
Those two pedals navigate pretty much the boat
and those pedals are AI and the guide better
be you. And in most cases in companies the guide
was somebody else, it wasn't the product leader.
So then the question is, if AI actually
is directing your product or success and
it's the biggest factor and you as the product
leader is not the one holding those two pedals,
what are you doing? And then I realized that it
was a bit of a lack of education in that, there
was actually most product users used to think of
AI as this black box, magic spells that they don't
know how it's working so they're delegating.
And obviously that's as far from the truth as
possible, but there's so many ways to unpack it.
When it came to the feed where I push for example,
more specifically for the teams, he doesn't stay
as an AI first, there's the objective. I would ask
him, "What is the objective of the algorithm?"
I would challenge you to ask folks more in the
folks who are leading products specifically
with algorithms inherited built into them,
what is the objective of the algorithm and can
you write it down for me on a board? They should
be able to do so, ultimately it's a mathematical
formula and then it's like what features have you
added to the algorithm? And this is not user
features, this is specifically what parameters
to learn on and then what investment do you
have in data collections and fine-tuning?
Now everybody talks a big game about
fine-tuning but again, two years ago,
fine-tuning was something that the product folks
thought the engineering team was supposed to do.
No, it's the whole organization. In fact, you can
build a whole strategy just on data collection and
fine-tuning and your product will see tremendous
success or you can delegate it and it will never
happen. So in many ways that was bringing into
the fold, in our phase one, which really started
around 2016 for me and every team I went to, the
AI component was the area I spent most of my time
on. I hired people for that. Product leaders,
I spent most of my, back to how do I spend my
resources, most of my resources there. And it
was my top priority all the way from strategy
to talent. And ultimately with the last couple
of years we've seen this metamorphosis of AI and
this incredible new wave and we've done a pretty
big change there as well over the last two years.
I love this. So I took some notes on what you're
talking about. So the big message that I'm taking
away so far is as a product leader, you need
to think about things that you thought the
engineering leader had to think about or the
ML engineer was thinking about things like what
is the objective of our algorithm? What are the
features that we're building into it? What is the
data collection strategy? How are we fine-tuning
it? As a PM, you should be asking these questions.
In fact, you should go all the way to
infrastructure. You can have massive lifts in your
product outcomes and goals if you probably enhance
your infrastructure. How many product people talk
about the infrastructure they have? Not many.
Influencers, those are things ultimately your
goal is to win with your products and build a much
more experience to your members and customers.
Literally just changing the infrastructure
on top of what you build. That could be the
biggest lever than you building another button
or experience for your members on the top of it.
So say the PMs at LinkedIn, are you encouraging
them all to, how is AI integrating into what
you're doing? How do you just set this up
so that teams do this well within LinkedIn?
Yeah. So coming into this role in early 2020,
we basically established an AI academy. Every
PM had to go through training just like we did
mobile in 2014, we moved the whole organization
to be mobile first, so everybody had to go through
this process. I spent a lot of time in my reviews
on the AI strategy, the objectives. We make sure
there's actually AI practitioners on the product
side who are strong, who can teach. So we in
waves started to build more of expertise and
distinguished leaders across that can actually
bring this learning across the board. And then
in fall 2022, when we all know what happened, at
least a few months after, but we started early,
we completely changed our entire almost product
operations and portfolio so we can focus on
this new wave of AI with LLMs in the front.
So LinkedIn has been working with AI very closely
since the early days, but mostly as a matchmaker.
So it was the matchmaker for our marketplaces.
Somebody looks to hire this dream candidate and
then you have a candidate looking for the dream
job and AI would be the one doing the matchmaking.
We talked about the knowledge sharing on the feed.
It happens in our commerce platform as well. But
AI, I was in the background so I never saw it,
it was making those matches. And then with
the new level of AI, we actually brought
AI from the back of our marketplaces
really as the matchmaker to the front.
And one of the things we've done
there was really asking the teams
to completely revisit their entire roadmap.
This is fall of 2022, the world will learn
about ChatGPT for several in March 2023. So we
had a nice beginning there in terms of getting
started. And the goal there was let go of
what you've built, let go of your roadmap,
go back to the drawing board with what are you
trying to solve for, back to that idea of clarity
on your problem statement and now tell me
what's the solution. That's very much AI first.
It reminds me, so one of the folks I pinged about
you, Shira Gasarch, she used this quote about you,
"Maybe you were made for such a time as this."
And it connects to a lot what you're talking
about where you've been thinking a lot about.
And back then it was called machine learning.
It wasn't called AI for a long time and
now it's AI. The fact that you've been on
this so long is just a perfect synergy for
now. It's working its way into everything.
Here's an example that I think sometimes to
bring it to people in a more visceral way if
you've been building products, product leaders
are used to very much dictate the experience
they're building. I want this experience to
be exactly like this. I want the member to
come from here and this is the options
they have and I want them to be able to
select this and this will be my default and
I want the onboarding to progress this way.
And I think this is one of the biggest shifts
with this when you become an AI first leader,
is that there's a realization that you
don't control the experience anymore,
you control the ingredients. It's almost like
being a chef at the restaurant and you're used to
deciding every part of the dish. You're deciding
everything from the ambiance to the temperature of
the broccoli and then this new technology comes
in and say, just give me the ingredients, give
me the guidelines of how you cook and now I'll
take care of it. I'll take care of it for you.
For many folks, this is a very scary feeling,
they're not used to letting go of the control.
Obviously you build safety guards and responsible
AI around it and that's super critical. But at the
essence of it, AI is not deterministic. So giving
it the rope to learn and do that experience for
you ultimately would become much, much better.
You have to have that belief going into it.
Along those lines, I'm curious if there's anything
you do to avoid, everyone's like, cool AI into
everything and then all these stupid things ship,
then no one wants. I saw this hilarious meme of
like, oh wait, we built a kind of dumb artificial
person. Let's integrate it into everything. Now
it's everywhere. Is there anything you've learned
about just how not to ship stuff that isn't great?
I can tell you what we've done here and we've
failed a lot, but we learned so much along the
way. When we started it in fall 2022, literally
started with me calling the leaders coming to
the room and we talked about, okay, let go of
your roadmaps, like what we've done, great,
but I want to let go of the roadmaps and I want
to instead go back to what you're trying to solve
for and let's meet in a couple of weeks and
tell me how you're thinking differently about
what you're trying to solve for knowing we have
this technology in a role for us. So that was a
starting point around just setting out some ground
and principles around it. But we didn't start with
new objectives to solve. So it wasn't like, "Oh,
we have this cool technology, what can we do with
it?" It was like go back to the objectives you
were trying to solve and now with this technology,
how can you do that objective better?
The second part is we actually allowed
teams to run to really inspire creativity. I
didn't want to contain them. I wanted to get
them really excited about the potential here.
And even some things we're building duplicates
for a while of similar ideas but done differently
because part of it was I was learning. I was very
excited to see what people would come up with
and see how they can do it. And there was no
playbook for building this really, really well.
And in many ways we were writing the playbook.
Prompt engineering became a playbook internally
for us, which every day was amazing. How do you
cognitively reverse engineer the brain a little
bit? That was incredible. In fact, a lot of things
we've learned so much ahead of the market and even
shared with OpenAI and shared with Microsoft. But
then after that period of just everybody
getting excited and building, we basically
brought it down and we did top-down got it.
So we basically picked back to the objectives
we had out of everything that we've seen, those
for us look like the best four biggest best we
want to want to aim for and we want to converge
resourcing across it. So no more everybody's
building whatever they want. We also, capacity is
also constraint. Cost is a constraint. We want to
start bringing them together. So we really much
allowed people to, I would say in many words,
diverge. But then I would say several
weeks after converge, but we had a lot
more excitement and understanding about how this
thing works and what we can actually do with it.
Love that advice. Basically give
people a bunch of time and space
to explore and experiment R and D and then
as a top-down strategy, pick through this.
The top-down, we were like, there was literally,
usually I do product jams for every multiple
topics we have throughout the quarter. I
just did every week. I just reviewed the
five bets we had on a reputed basis, nothing
else. Because it was so important for them
to understand that this is what I care
about and we had to be focused about it.
It feels like that space to explore and go
crazy is important because otherwise people
at the company are going to be like, "Oh, I wish,
there's so many, this thing I want to try with AI,
we should try it." And they'll just be pissed
because they don't have time to work on it.
It's a great point. It wasn't my intention,
but I love that you're saying it. It's a great
point because I think it gives them that. I
was actually, for me sometimes almost in a,
maybe too much, but I try to focus on learning.
I was trying. I knew just going like this,
we weren't going to learn a lot, but having
people come back and trying different things
and slightly going crazy and pushing the
boundaries, we would learn so much. So for
me it was learning, but I love the motivation
around, also allowing them to have the energy.
It relates to another point that a recent
podcast episode I had with Brian Chesky where
he introduces chaos sometimes when things
are feeling too comfortable, when roadmaps,
everything's calm, everything's
on schedule. He's just like,
"How do we do this in one day versus in
two weeks? Let's just see what happens."
Yeah, because I think people get, there
is just inertia, people get into their,
it's human behavior, people get into
their lanes, they start to feel really
comfortable within the lanes, and then
they don't know that there's a different
way to do things and you have to almost
externally invoke that or trigger that.
If we think about just your career arc, I'm
zooming out a little bit. You helped create
the mobile experience on LinkedIn. You built
the feed initially and now you're in front of
AI. I could see why you're so successful
at LinkedIn. I was talking to folks about
your career arc at LinkedIn and you basically
went from senior PM to senior PM number two,
to group PM to director, to senior director
to VP, to CPO in not that many years,
it's a pretty meteoric rise. I wanted to spend
a little time here and I want to maybe start
with the question of just if you could give one
specific piece of advice for someone looking to
advance in their career based on what you found
to be really effective, what would that be?
I realized everybody's in every stage in their
career and they have different ways to think about
the role then what they need. Maybe I'll just
share about my journey, what worked for me instead
of giving more of a general advice. First of all,
I feel super fortunate I'm building. That's what
I love doing. I love building, I love working with
builders. Sometimes I'm like, I get paid for this,
this is insane. But I love my craft and I love
getting deep into it. So in many ways I think
the things I'm excited about is the things
I'm doing. When people are starting off,
I usually really focus on learning from great
people. People you talk to or have amazing
mentors and managers. Some of them don't even know
there were every mentors. It's not like a mentor
officially. I try to pick up things from people
all the time, and that's been just a remarkable
experience working with great people.
And in many ways, a lot of those great
people actually allowed me or empowered me
to take on some bigger challenges. So I can
see forks in the road where if it wasn't for
that person saying something very specific,
probably would've done something differently. And
it just made me think a lot. So I really tried to
absorb learning from great people. But by far,
for me personally, again, this is very personal
versus generic advice, it was when I moved here, I
was an engineer for many years before I moved here
for graduate school in 2008. And I always loved
building, that was there from a young age but when
I moved here, I realized my career path was very
much dictated by one thing. It was like, what's
most in demand? What's most challenging? And how
do I do that? It was very childish in many ways.
It was not dictated by me, it was in a way
dictated by society. So what's the toughest
engineering role? What's the best company to go
into? What's the best army unit to serve in? And I
fell a lot along the way, but I always kept going.
And then when I came here, there was a really big
challenging for me personally around what do I
care about? What matters most to me? And that was,
again, it's very personal in many ways. It
was very much for me, an impact on learning
and actually how do I create impact more broadly?
And I shifted 180 in how my thought process used
to go. It was less about what was out there
and exciting and in demand and challenging
and it was more about where did I have strong
conviction on, what was I passionate about and
where did I feel I could make a dent and learn?
And that was my path forward. So after school
with a student visa and massive school debt,
I decided to start a company which was not a
very intelligent decision based on my economic
circumstances, but I didn't care. I was like,
this is my new path. And then I got into LinkedIn.
I didn't apply for a job. I met with who was in my
role today, Deep Nishar, at that time and we
talked and I said, "This is how I think this
is how LinkedIn mobile should be built." And he
was like, "Okay, how about you come and build
it?" I was like, "Amazing." So I didn't apply to
LinkedIn and then at LinkedIn I was always like,
this is what I want to do, this is what's
exciting for me and this is the dent I think I
can make and this is my plan for it.
I don't know if this is a recommendation
for everybody, but for me it's worked really,
really well. It was really pursuing the conviction
I had and my excitement and bring that to the
fold with people. I do think that in products,
in building product, if you're not genuinely
excited about what you want to build,
you don't have conviction about it, it's going
to be very hard for you to make a big impact.
That's also a similar theme from my most
recent podcast with Vlad of just, if you don't
actually buy into the mission of the place you're
working on, you're not going to have a good time.
Yeah. Say for product people, it's a very
fortunate position. I always tell people,
if you're in one of the most fortunate positions
you can have, because if you just measure thing,
for you, just measure based on your career and so
on, people are going to evaluate you based on your
actual work. It's a very special place. Nobody
cares about your title, who cares? It's not. Maybe
the company name for some people matters, but for
the most part, it's about the impact you created
with the products you've built. If I think about
somebody's resume, I think if it was a product
resume, it would be the products you built and
the impact you had with it. I don't care about the
companies you worked at, I don't care about the
logos, I don't care about the titles. Slightly,
again, not to overextend, but somebody, it's
almost like an artist, right? It's like whatever,
a musician, it's the albums you took out and how
well they did. And I think for product people,
it's a very fortunate place to be that you
get measured based on the impact you had.
It sounds like a LinkedIn feature idea right
there. I feel like if there's any company that
could make that happen, it'd be you guys. So
some of the takeaways here essentially is try
to index towards what are you actually excited
about and motivated to work on and driven by
versus where it's the most amazing company
to work at are the most challenging problem.
Yeah, I think sometimes great companies have
great opportunities for you to have dent at scale,
but you need to be the one doing it. If
you are thinking about, I don't know,
a title or that did not, once I did the
change into my excitement around impact,
that's been at least my yardstick. When I look
at people that I talk to or interview internally,
the first thing to my mind to me
is like, "What did you build and
what did you learn and how well did
they do?" That's what I care about.
I imagine there's also people on the
other side where all they do is work
on things that really exciting to
them and they could use a little
pushing towards the other direction of
what's actually important in the world.
100%. If you tell me, again, everybody
has their different, if you tell me,
"Hey, you can work on something super exciting,
but it's on the fringes of the company or you
can work on something which is a bit more grindy,
but it's on the core of the company." The
latter, no doubt, for me, impact first.
And just listening to the story you've
told of the things you decided to focus
on as a clear example that you saw, hey,
there's this huge opportunity in the feed,
I'm going to go tackle that or mobile.
So I think there's a lot of, it's kind
of this Venn diagram is what I'm taking away of
just what's important, what am I excited about?
Yeah, this for me. Yeah.
Awesome. Okay, so I note you got to run relatively
soon, so we're going to get to our very exciting
lightning round. But before we do that, is there
anything else that you think would be interesting
or useful for folks to know or leave them with?
I know we covered a bunch of things already.
Yeah. One thing that actually I've now built
it into a podcast, but something I'm really
excited about is I don't think there's one way of
building. Remember when the Steve Jobs biography
came out, everybody read it. Oh, that's the
way to build and that was unique to him. And
one of the things I love a lot is when I look
at great builders, they're all very distinct,
they're all different. And I used to do this
thing internally, I used to invite product
builders of different disciplines and have
a fireside chat with them. And I saw people
across the company join not just PMs or designers,
but folks across and I build that into a podcast.
I love your podcast. Mine is very different.
It's more around what is their edge a little
bit. This is from the co-founder of Pixar, Ed
Catmull, to the CPO of Canva or Spotify, Roblox,
but all the way to a chef, Dan Barber, who's
the number one chef in the US for many years.
And it's just everybody has their craft
and they do it differently. It's called
BuildingOne, I'm excited about it. It's
a little bit of a plug right now, Lenny.
Please. Yeah. Where do people find it?
Let's blow it up. It's called BuildingOne?
BuildingOne on Apple or Spotify.
Perfect.
It's short and it's really about showing
you different disciplines from a chef to
an animation director. And really the
main learning there is everybody builds
differently and you can be very successful, but
it's very authentic to how they are personally,
and it's how they push their craft to the
limit. It's how well they've done their craft.
I love that. And something I super believe is
just the power of focusing on your strengths and
the things that make you a little different
versus trying to become good at everything.
100%.
That's so cool. Okay, BuildOne.
We'll link to it in the show notes.
BuildingOne, yes.
BuildingOne. BuildingOne. Okay. Amazing. And
it's on all the podcasting platforms. Okay,
great. With that, we've reached a very
exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
Yes.
All right. First question is,
what are two or three books that you
recommended most to other people?
So I have this [inaudible 00:58:58]
continuously, actually it's these three.
I love that you have them right there.
I can just tell you about them but-
They look very [inaudible 00:59:04]
back there. Don't [inaudible 00:59:05]
I'm not going to destroy my study. So I love
fundamentals. I love studying from fundamentals.
So if you're somebody who starts in your career,
my fundamental books is One Mindset. It's about
growth mindset. It's about basically the ability
to continuously grow over time in one sentence
is the whole idea is our skills, our abilities
are malleable, we can completely develop them,
we can build expertise and craft and mastery
and it's really a mindset change. And Carol
Dweck wrote the book, was also my wife's
manager, and that's how we got into that.
That's awesome.
So that's like our second religion at home.
Second book is Thinking, Fast and Slow by
Daniel Kahneman. I love behavioral economics.
When I think about products, I think I always
start from people, what is the member expectation?
What are they trying to do? And this is the Bible
for behavior. So if you're building front end
products or even you're thinking about how you
rally organization, it's an incredible book.
Every page is like a stopper. You have to stop
and think. And then lastly, and on the fundamental
side is High Output Management by Andy Grove. It's
like there's so much basics to doing good manager.
It's like I think after you read this book,
your managerial skills should start from a
B. and then you can over time become an A.
But beginning to a B is just a level of putting
the effort in and knowing the best practices.
So I think those are all fundamentally great
books that I really like to give to people.
That's awesome. I love that they're
right there behind you. Is there a
favorite recent movie or TV
show you've really enjoyed?
Yesterday I saw Bluey, you know Bluey?
I've heard of Bluey. My kid
is not old enough for it yet.
Oh, you're in for a treat.
Okay.
I love Bluey. So Bluey is this animation series
from Australia and what's beautiful about it's,
I can watch it with my six-year-old, nine-year-old
and 12-year-old, and we're all going to enjoy it.
We're all going to laugh at the same point
but at the nuance of the jokes. It's like
when I think about a product, the way Bluey
is built, it's built for the whole family,
but it's built as layers. There's layers of
dialogue and points that they're trying to
get across, and it's all packaged together into
one experience. So for me, it's amazing that I
could sit next to my six-year-old daughter, we
would both laugh at this, it's a sweet animation
kind of thing, it's like a family of dogs. And
she would laugh at the nuance of the point,
at a different nuance. For me it's like that's
a genius creation of how you build a product.
Speaking of Ed Catmull, the Pixar
does that really well as well.
Totally.
And I feel like the story of Bluey is
really incredible too. It's just like a
random little independent group and they
just are making tons of money with it.
It's just amazing. The dialogue there is one,
it's slightly edgy but not too edgy. It's
exactly right. It's just exactly right.
Okay. Makes me want to watch it. Okay.
Do you have a favorite product that
you've recently discovered that you really
love, whether it's physical or in digital?
So I like playing guitar. It's amateur, I'm not
that good, but I love playing it. And there is a
combination I've done recently I really like,
there's a Spark Amp I have, which allows me to
play with effects easily, but that's not what
I use it for. I can tune my guitar based on the
specific song I like. See, if I want to do Pink
Floyd or Metallica or Nirvana or David Bowie,
I can get that tune easily. I don't have
to be an expert. I can just download the
tune to my guitar, which is so great.
And then I couple that with the, it's
called the Ultimate Guitar app, and basically
it doesn't give me the chords and the tabs,
it gives me the other instruments, so I
can get the drums going. I can get the,
it's a violin going, whatever that is that's going
in the band. As somebody who does not play so well
and plays for itself and nobody's supposed to
listen to how I'm playing because it's really
just a way for me to enjoy my time. It's just
an amazing, I would never get into any band,
so this is the closest I can get to get
to a band. So I love that combination.
I wish we could close this podcast episode with
you playing your guitar, but [inaudible 01:03:26].
I don't know if that will
help the ratings of the show.
No, man, that's amazing. Okay, two more
questions. Do you have a favorite life motto
that you often repeat yourself, find really
useful in work or in life, share with folks?
From growth mindset there's a motto that I
really like. It's called becoming is better
than being. It's like the moment you think you
achieved something is the moment you start to
deteriorate down. It's like we're really trying
to grow as human beings. We're trying to learn,
we're trying to evolve. Product is a
good example. I think the moment you
think you actually mastered it is the
moment that you become obsolete. So I
love the idea that becoming is a better goal than
continuously trying to reach some kind of level.
Love that. Final question, just to come back
to LinkedIn. Is there a fun feature of LinkedIn
people don't know about or should check out?
Is there anything new that's like, oh, that's
something you should try or that's something that
might surprise you about LinkedIn these days?
Maybe I'll give a couple so I don't have to pick
the best right off the bat. But one right now,
we're heavily invested in video and it's doing so
well for those creators. We talked about it like
immersive video we can actually come in. We talked
about for us, video is obviously a best practice
right now in the industry, but on LinkedIn, the
right views really matter. So highly encourage
creators to think about their video play at
LinkedIn. And then I think what we call our
coach experience in some cases is so powerful.
For job seekers out there, we have people hired
on LinkedIn, there's like seven folks hired
every minute. Job seeking is a lonely journey.
I was actually in a session recently
meeting with job seekers and I was
talking to them and one started crying
midway into the session because they said,
"I cannot share my journey with anybody because
I feel like I'm alone in this. People don't get
how hard it is. I feel very accomplished, but I
can't get the job. And I wish there was a buddy,
I wish there was something that I could talk
to brainstorm with who wouldn't judge me,
who would just be trying to help me
without paying hundreds of dollars to
a coach of some sort. I don't have that money."
And in many ways, when we walked him through the
job seeking experience, the coach experience,
we build this coach aspect where you can go
to any job and you can riff on the job with this
really new realities LLM that is tailored to you,
personalized to you, private to you, everything
from your fit to how to best apply, to consulting
about different opportunities, to comparing this
to others, to feeling supported. So when we talk
to people around, we always, I love to measure
the impact of our work by emotion, when we talk
to job seekers after that, it was basically
the sense of I felt supported. In many ways,
getting to that ability to remove the loneliness
is amazing. It's a little bit like people need to,
we're making it more and more visible and more and
more ramped to everybody to a certain point. But
that's a really powerful way to just humanize
the job seeking experience for everybody.
Awesome. And to find that it's just,
is it called LinkedIn Coach or?
It's in the job. So if you go to the job tab
on LinkedIn, actually just a few weeks ago,
we just put it on the top. So you don't
have to go to the specific job and find it,
you can just start there and engage with it.
Awesome. Just to give a quick plug to
a future podcast that's coming out,
there's this book called Never Search Alone,
that we're going to have the author on the
podcast soon. And it's all about the same idea of
having a buddy that helps you search for a job.
Yeah. When I think about the future
of AI in the sense of belief,
that relationship is going to be sacred,
the relationship between AI and the human
is going to be [inaudible 01:07:10].
Do you know what Nomophobia means?
Nomaphobia? No.
Nomophobia.
Nomophobia. No. Being afraid of something.
It's the anxiety of being away from your phone.
I have that.
I think we all. I think we're in
for AI-nophobia at that point,
where you're going to get to a point
where AI is going to feel so intimate,
so personal that it would actually feel
concerning to you to be away from it.
Oh man, there reminds me of Friend.com,
which just launched in a really fun, I don't
know if you saw Friend.com, their launch video.
No, I did not.
Oh, man. Check out Friend.com. It's
like a digital friend that just is
with you all the time and you're
talking to him and it's an AI.
Oh, we're just getting started. There's going
to be, we're in for incredible revolution there.
I'm excited and scared at the same time. Tomer,
thank you so much for being here. This
was amazing. You're awesome. Two final
questions. Where can folks check out stuff
that you're working on? You have a course also,
you have a podcast, so just give
people a sense of where to find that.
Awesome. So obviously I'm on LinkedIn, reach
out anytime. I read everything people send
to me. I don't always reply to everything, but
I read everything sent to me. And then if you
want to go deep on AI first, I have two courses,
they're free. I think it's a phenomenal way for
you to build or starting to build your expertise,
especially if you're in product. It's a great way
to go deeper and not just stay on
the high level parts of things.
Amazing. We'll link to all those
things in the show notes. Tomer,
thank you so much for being here.
Lenny. Thank you. It's our pleasure.
Bye everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
Lennyspodcasts.com. See you in the next episode.