You were famously the first PM
at Slack and then you ended up
transitioning into executive coaching.
For me, the impact was about making this
work sustainable so that we're not burning out
or selling out, but actually able to pursue
these hard goals that we have in startups.
What we're going to be talking about today is
your personal magnum opus, the output of
10 plus years as a founder and operator
and seven plus years as a coach.
The core idea is ask for what you want.
Turns out when you actually ask for what you want
out loud, you're much more likely to get it.
You're hired.
How do you know that this
is something you need to be working on?
If you're more in the people pleasing camp,
maybe you're used to not asking at all. You're
hoping that people are reading your mind. And
if you're sort of more in the control freak
camp, maybe you're used to ordering people
around and saying, "Go do this now."
How do you know what you want?
Complaints are great inspiration. Every
complaint implies a dream. Let me envision
a better future. Let me think about
what's an effective way to actually
move towards that. See what it's like to not
be sort of living in fear all the time.
Today, my guest is Kenneth Berger. Kenneth
coaches startup leaders to help them avoid
burnout and live the life that they want.
He was the first product manager at Slack
and spent over 10 years in tech before
transitioning into coaching. His core focus
with leaders is to help them learn how to ask
for what they want. This sounds really simple,
but as you'll hear in our chat, this one skill
is at the core of so many of the struggles that
people have in their career and in their life.
Kenneth shares a ton of very tactical advice
to help you figure out what it is you
want, how to overcome the resistance
that comes with asking for what you want, how
to actually ask for what you want effectively,
why the most important step is hearing the
response that you get when you ask for what
you want and all of the things that will change
in your life if you get better at this one skill.
Kenneth also shares the story of him being fired
three times from Slack, which is hilarious. With
that, I bring you Kenneth Berger after a short
word from our sponsors. And if you enjoy this
podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow
it in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube.
It's the best way to avoid missing feature
episodes and it helps the podcast tremendously.
Let me tell you about a product called Sidebar.
The best way to level up your career is to
surround yourself with extraordinary peers. This
gives you more than a leg up. It gives you a leap
forward. This worked really well for me in my
career, and this is the Sidebar ethos. When you
have a trusted group of peers, you can discuss
challenges you're having, get career advice,
and just gut check how you're thinking about
your work, your career, and your life. This
was a big trajectory changer for me, but it's
hard to build this trusted group of peers.
Sidebar is a private, highly vetted leadership
program where senior leaders are matched with
peer groups to lean on for unbiased
opinions, diverse perspectives and raw
feedback. Guided by world-class programming and
facilitation, Sidebar enables you to get focused
tactical feedback at every step of your career
journey. If you're a listener of this podcast,
you're already committed to growth. Sidebar is
the missing piece that catalyze your career.
93% of members say Sidebar helped them achieve
a significant positive change in their career.
Why spend a decade finding your people when
you can meet them at Sidebar today? Join
thousands of top senior leaders who have taken
the first step to career growth from companies
like Microsoft, Amazon, and Meta by visiting
sidebar.com/lenny. That's sidebar.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Webflow. We're
all friends here, so let's be real for a second.
We all know that your website shouldn't be a
static asset. It should be a dynamic part of
your strategy that drives conversions. That's
business 101. Here's a number for you. 54% of
leaders say web updates take too long.
That's over half of you listening right
now. That's where Webflow comes in. Their
visual first platform allows you to build,
launch, and optimize webpages fast.
That means you can set ambitious
business goals and your site can rise to
the challenge. Learn how teams like Dropbox,
IDEO and Orangetheory trust Webflow to achieve
their most ambitious goals today at webflow.com.
Kenneth, thank you so much for being
here. Welcome to the podcast.
Yay. thanks for having me.
I love that, yay. That should be a
tradition that everyone goes with. I love that. So
we originally met when I was doing a post on being
a first product manager at a company. You were
famously the first PM at Slack, and then you ended
up transitioning into executive coaching, which
is what you do now. What we're going to be talking
about today is something that you described to me
as, quote, your personal magnum opus, the output
of 10 plus years as a founder and operator, and
seven plus years as a coach to startup leaders.
And the core idea is simply asking for what
you want, which sounds really simple. So let
me just start broadly just why have you
found that this skill, this one idea is
so core to so many of the challenges that
people run into in work and in life?
If I had to answer in one word, it would be
integrity. I think that it's one of these funny
things where everyone thinks they already know
how to ask for what they want. We all ask for
what we want. We order our coffee in the morning
and we all think we have integrity. No one walks
around thinking, "I'm lying to myself all the
time or lying to others certainly." And yet
we tend to fool ourselves a little bit. When it
comes to are we really pursuing the things that we
want in life? And I think to me, the flip side of
that is sort of the reason that the stakes around
asking for what you want are so high because we
can't guarantee we're going to get what we want.
But if we're asking for it regularly, if we're
listening to the response, we're expecting the
nose we get from the world, then we can get the
sense of, "Yeah, I'm honoring what's important
to me. I'm honoring the world's response and I'm
moving forward towards what I want." And if we
don't do that, "Well, then we're fooling ourselves
that we're actually moving towards of what we
want." There tends to be all these unexpected
secondary and tertiary effects that come out of
that of stress and frustration, and unhappiness
because of course, asking for what we want,
pursuing what's important to us in life is just
one of the most important things of fulfillment,
of what's important in achieving our purpose.
What are just some challenges that people have
in their life and career that are just rooted in
doing this badly? Not asking for what you want,
not knowing what you want.
For me with clients, I think
what I'm often looking for are just kind of
this sense of being stuck because everybody
has got frustrations. Everybody gets nervous at
work sometimes. But if we're in the same stuck
place week after week after week in our coaching
sessions, probably you're trying the same thing
and not getting any different results.
It's that definition of insanity thing.
So really I look at that and say, "Okay.
Maybe you're asking for what you want."
Maybe. Although often people aren't. But even
if you are, you're probably not achieving it.
You're not getting the results that you want.
So why are we not learning from that? Why are
we not moving forward getting new data, trying
something new, actually treating it as a sort
of iterative development discovery process?
So I think that stuckness is one thing. And I
think the other thing I look for is interpersonal
conflict, right? Because I think that one mode
of not asking for what you want well is holding
back and not really saying it out loud. I think
another really common mode is coming with a lot of
entitlement of, "You know what? You better do what
I say. I'm your boss. You're my report. You better
obey or agree," or whatever it is. And of course
the danger of that is interpersonal conflict.
Even if you are their boss, that's a really
disrespectful way to come into the conversation
and it's an obvious source for a lot of issues.
Before we get into how to learn to do this better
and more of why this is so important, is there
an example from your career where you did this
really badly or you didn't ask what you want?
There's so many examples. I think we will
eventually get into the story of how I was
fired from Slack. But I think for me, the thing
that always came up was just being attached to
being right. And I think a lot of us get into this
boat. We enter into a meeting and we're sure from
the first moment, "I'm right and they're wrong."
And I think that especially in product management,
we're supposed to be the holders of this vision
for what the product should be. And so it's easy
to come in with a lot of conviction and not
really a lot of openness to other ideas.
Often what I try to introduce people to, and I've
learned all this stuff the hard way, believe me,
is it's fundamentally disrespectful to go into
a meeting already deciding that you're right and
the other person is wrong because you can't know
that for sure. There's always a new perspective,
new data that could come in. And so you want that
conversation to really be a back and forth. And if
you're coming in with this really ingrained
sense of righteousness, you can't do that.
There's no way to have that conversation.
I think you may have already answered this
question, but I think it's really important is
how do you know that this is something you need
to be working on? How do you know like, "I really
need to pay attention to what Kenneth is about to
tell me?" You said one is you feel you're stuck
in your career, something you're just not making
progress, and this could be the answer. Or you
said there's interpersonal conflict and you're
just having a lot of conflict with people.
Are those the two answers? Are there more?
I think those are great things to look for.
I think it's also good to look for a sense of
things being high stakes, because I think part of
what can create a lot of conflict and difficulty
in these situations is a sense of this is life
or death. And that was certainly how it was when
I was a founder of, "Okay, normally..."
When I was at Adobe, it's a big company,
they're going to be fine either way, no matter
what I do. Right? I can be easy going. Let someone
else have their way in the meeting. But when it
was my company, when it was my vision on the line,
I didn't feel especially flexible. The
stakes seemed really, really high.
This is the success of my idea, of my vision, my
reputation is on the line. And so I think often
when the stakes feel high, we're kind of focused
more on the fear of what we don't want to happen
than on actually achieving what we do want. And
that's a really critical distinction because
if we're running away from our fears, it doesn't
necessarily mean we're getting anywhere meaningful
for what our desires are. And so that sense of
high stakes that often we can get, whether it's in
interpersonal conflict or being afraid of asking
for what we want, that can get us really focused
on the fears rather than focused on the goals.
There's a question I was going to save for later,
but it's something that's very top of mind for
me is knowing what you want. How do you know
what you want? There's basically knowing what you
want and then asking for what you want. I like
equanimity in my life, and so I often don't ask
for what I want or push down maybe what I want,
or I don't think about what I want. I
just want other people to be happy.
I'm curious what people can do and what I
can do to get better at knowing here's what
actually want, here's what would make me happy
and fulfilled? What are some skills there I could
work on and other people can work on?
Well, first of all, I'd say you're very
far from alone there. I mean, I think
the people pleaser coping strategy is
one of the sort of most classic, and it is
effective, right? In the short term like, "Oh,
you can feel safe and calm when other people
are generally happy with you." And the cost
tends to be long term in terms of am I really
pursuing the things that are important to me?
So one of my favorite techniques here is this
concept they call dream behind the complaint.
Because you're right that we tend to not be that
great always at really dreaming and envisioning
and saying, "This is my dream of what I want out
of life." That can sound really scary for people,
but we're very good at complaining. Usually people
are very good at saying, "Oh my God, there's this
thing happening at work, it's so annoying.
Or there's this person that really bothers
me so much, why are they always like this?"
So the magic of that complaining is that every
complaint implies a dream. It implies
a better world where that complaint is
resolved. And so often that's the tool that
I'll take people to first to say, "All right,
great. Let's complain. Right? It feels so fun and
good and releasing to complain, and let's look at
what that implied world is behind that complaint."
What is this vision? And then to really check,
"Okay. Let's imagine you get that. That's the
world of the future that you get. How does that
feel? Is that big enough or is it kind of meh?"
Are we like, "Oh, my dream is that I get to speak
up a little more in meetings?" It's like, "Well,
that's probably not a hundred percent of your
dream. What's really behind that?" And so I think
that check can help you sort of level up to say,
"Is this really an inspiring dream for me
that's going to motivate me more than those
fears that might be hiding in the background?"
And on the flip side, with entitled people,
you can also get really unrealistic dreams
where I might say, "Okay. So it sounds like
what I'm hearing is that your dream is that
everyone obeys you and automatically agrees
with you no matter what." And they sort of say,
"Ah, I don't know if that's quite my dream."
And so if your dream is so embarrassing to say
out loud, you can't even really own it, maybe
that's not the right dream. And so that checking
whether it actually feels inspiring, but also sort
of credible and possible is a good way to find
that middle ground where, "Yeah, this dream is
hard. I don't know that I'm going to get it, but,
damn, it's worth trying. I want to go for it."
I love that for someone that wants to try this on
their own and help themselves get better at this
without you being there, what is it that you
do? Is it you dream about what would make you
happiest? Is it complain and see what's at the
root of it? Is it just imagine a world where
you're really happy and see what emerges.
Specifically for articulating what you want
because that's the first step of the asking for
what you want process. It really is as simple as
that of let's start with what you have consciously
in terms of what you want. And if you have
trouble, then we can try looking at complaints
and starting to articulate a vision out of that.
But to me, really what's interesting about asking
for what you want is that on the surface it's very
simple, right? I mean, the steps I outline are
articulate what you want, ask for what you want
intentionally and accept the response and then
try again. Because it's an iterative process.
We're learning from the response and what it
tells us because the response is usually no.
So really what tends to be hard there, I mean,
that's a straightforward process. It's not rocket
science. What's hard there is the resistance.
The parts of us that are not so excited about
that, that thinks asking for what we want is
scary and articulating a big dream that we
might not get is really scary. Because god,
what if I don't get it? What does that mean
about me? Am I a failure? Or what does it mean if
I respect the no? What if I ask for my big dream
and someone tells me I'm not going to get it?
What does that mean? How am I going to feel?
So working through all that resistance is
really a lot of what tends to be tricky
about asking for what you want because
otherwise it's articulate, ask, accept.
Okay. You're getting into where we're going
to go. Before we get there. Final question.
This idea of dealing with, no, I think this
is the other big blocker for people is like,
"Oh, that's so scary to ask for something I
really want or ask for something big that is
really important to you." What is it that
you advise there of just getting over this
fear of just asking for what you want?
So I have a more expansive definition of no
than most people, I think, because for me it's
not a yes unless it's a hell yes. Because you
really want enthusiastic consent. Not just,
"Maybe, kinda. I'll try. We'll see. But yeah,
absolutely, let's do this." And I think that often
it's so tempting to settle for something less than
that to say, "Oh, well, okay, we'll give that a
try." And that often comes to bite us later on
because we accept this thing that short of
a hell yes. And then we realized later on,
"Oh yeah, they weren't really in."
They didn't show up to the party or
they didn't deliver on time because my CTO said,
"Yeah, I think maybe we can deliver by May 1st."
And then May 1st comes and surprise, surprise,
your milestone is not done because you didn't
go for that hell yes. And so I think part
of what I encourage people to do is, one,
to really hear anything short of a hell yes
as a no. So it's not a bad thing. Mostly the
world tells us it's actually really great data.
It helps us figure out what are we going to try
next? What are we going to try next, try next,
try next? Because that's going to help us learn
how to actually get to that hell yes.
And part of that asking process is of
not settling for it, but actually asking and
saying, "Hey, I'm hearing maybe you're lukewarm
on May 1st as a date. What would be a hell yes
day for you where you could say, absolutely,
we can deliver on that?" And that way we're not
making them wrong for saying no. We're saying,
"Of course you get to say no. Everybody gets to
say no whenever they want. But let's get to a hell
yes. What would it take for us to get there?"
That's a really helpful framework and phrase to
use is just what would it take to get to hell
yes? Not just what would it take to get to you
feeling comfortable with this? What would it
take for you to just agree to this? It's more
a hell yes. And your point there is hell yes
is when they actually fully agree. Oftentimes
people kind of like, "Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah."
And then they don't actually follow through.
Some people call this a whole body yes
because sometimes your head is saying yes,
but your heart is saying no or your gut is
saying no. And so I think you can really feel
in your body when you've got a hell yes, when
all of you is fully in and ready to do this.
And this applies to, you're giving
examples here of just getting like
aligning a deadline. I imagine the same
skill applies to everything in relationship
questions and friends and family and work.
It does. And it is something universal, but I do
think of it as being particularly relevant to my
work with startups because I work primarily with
startup founders. Because with startups you know
that mostly they fail. We all know the numbers on
that. And so to me, there's a perspective you
have to take if you're going to operate in the
startup world of being okay with not knowing that
you're going to get the outcome you want. A lot
of people, we operate in a safer world where we're
more clear exactly what the outcomes are going to
be, but if you're a startup founder, you've got
to be okay with, "I'm just going to go for this,
and I know I probably won't get it. But it's so
meaningful to me, I'm going to go for it anyway."
And so to me, that's not just about
the big picture of running a startup,
it's about really anything you might want in life,
because that's such a useful perspective to say,
"I know I'm not going to get it. I know I'm
not guaranteed to get it. I'm not going to be
attached to that. I know people aren't obligated
to tell me yes, but I'm going to go forward
anyway because I want it and that's enough."
So let's actually get into the skill of learning
how to actually ask for what you want more
effectively. You already described three steps,
so maybe just describe them again
and let's just walk through them.
The first step is articulating what you
want. And we've gone into this a little bit,
but to me, I think that the key places
that people tend to have missteps here,
or one in this phrase, it's fine. I think of the
"it's fine" cartoon with the flames and the dog,
I think it is. But I think a lot of us fall into
that trap of saying, "You know what? I'm fine. I
actually, I don't need anything. I'm good."
And again, this is tempting, right? Because
it's so nice to have this idea that I'm fine,
I don't need anything. And in a certain way,
that's a nice attitude because yeah, we're not
guaranteed anything, so it's nice to be okay
with the status quo. But for those folks, often
what I'm encouraging that do is to really tune
into the parts of them that maybe aren't so fine
like, "Gosh, I'd prefer it a little bit if things
were this way or yeah, I'm a little bit bothered
by this, or I'm a little bit nervous about this."
And so kind of tuning more into those subtle
emotions that are pointing them towards, "Sure,
I'm okay with the status quo, but I want something
more." And so helping them articulate that in a
clearer way where they can want something without
being attached to having to get it. The other
extreme of this is people who articulate these
sort of wildly unrealistic goals. So this is the
founder that just wants everyone to agree with
him all the time and to obey him immediately.
So for those folks, it really tends to
be more about saying it out loud. Once
you say it out loud, it is clearer. That's not
really what it's about. And so for those folks,
I tend to ask them to go deeper to say, "Yeah,
I know you're not a control freak. You don't
want everyone to think exactly what you think.
What's it really about? What does that get you?"
And so often it goes from being this more kind
of objective external goal to being a more kind
of social emotional goal of, "You know what,
I just want to have a team that feels really
aligned around me and we're just ready to go
for it and we've got each other's backs."
That doesn't mean we agree with each other all the
time or that we're a hundred percent aligned in
everything, but it doesn't mean there's a certain
feeling that I have when I go into work. Even
though I don't know that we're going to get what
we want or that everyone is going to agree.
Do you have any examples from your time
you could share of someone articulating
what they want and figuring out how they
articulate, how to articulate what they
want just to make it even more real?
To me a lot of the classic examples are
around feedback. Because I work with a lot
of founders who are not the sort of classic
control freaks. They're super nice and their teams
love them and they love their teams. So for them,
it can be really hard to deliver hard feedback,
to deliver negative feedback and even more to
actually create consequences. Because the thing
about accepting other people's no is that, "Sure,
they can always say no. Everybody gets to say no
whenever they want, but there are consequences."
And so the classic thing I see with the
nice founders is they're really afraid to
actually create consequences when people are
not living up to their expectations. Right?
When they're not aligned with the culture, they're
not delivering in the way that the CEO wants them
to be delivering because it doesn't seem that
nice. They're like, "Oh, I think of myself as
nice and of being so kind and of people loving
me." And it's like, "Well, that doesn't mean that
there aren't consequences for their actions."
Part of really respecting them is respecting
that they can make the choices they want and
they're grownups enough that they can deal
with the consequences of those choices."
Can you even get more concrete there? Is it
we need to hit this date, or are there
going to be big problems? Or is it like,
"I need you to hire this large of a team?"
I don't know. What is it that they're
not articulating that they later realize,
"Oh, here's what I need to articulate."
So I think sometimes it is about alignment,
the disagree and commit. So I see that a
lot of founders saying, "Hey, I'm super
respectful of your differing opinion here,
and I totally validate you and I appreciate you.
Thank you so much for sharing that." But they're
not willing to go that extra step and say, "Yeah,
but this is the call and I need you to actually
follow through with that. I understand that might
be disappointing or frustrating or what have you,
but part of the expectation for this role
is that you can roll with disagree and
commit sometimes when that's necessary."
That's an awesome example. I fully get that
and I could see how scary that is to a lot
of people. One is just coming to terms with,
"This is what I actually want to be doing, but I
just don't feel like I can because it's going to,
I think, upset people." Okay. So what else can you
suggest people do to help identify what it is they
want and articulate what they want? So you talked
about pay attention to just like, "Oh, this would
be better. If this changed, I'd be happier." Or
things would probably run better. That's a really
cool example of how to think do that because
easy, just like, "Oh yeah, if we actually can
make a decision in this meeting, that'd be really
cool." Maybe we should try to do that and ask for
that. Is there any other tips and approaches
to helping you figure out what you want?
It always comes back to integrity. And a great
way to do an integrity check is to just look
have I fully expressed myself? And so I think
we've talked a little bit about charting your
feelings as a piece of that of like, "Yeah, am
I really tuning into how annoyed I am or how
frustrated I am or how nervous I am?" Because
if I haven't fully owned those feelings and
expressed those in whatever way is appropriate,
then probably I'm not fully in integrity.
I think saying what you have to say is a piece
of that too. "Gosh, is there something that I
keep thinking about and I'm just like
three or four days, I'm just like, man,
I really want to say this to this person." At this
point, you're probably out of integrity because
there's something deep in you that really needs
to say this, right? And so to me, articulating
what you want is really about mindfulness
is about checking for all these things.
What is the part of me that's not fully expressed?
Because it doesn't mean I'm going to get what I
want or that people are going to give me all
my dreams immediately, but it feels so much
better to have it out. That sort of suffering that
fear usually comes from holding it in and saying,
"Oh, having these stories of I'm not allowed
to say that. It's not appropriate to express
that I'm bored in this meeting." Versus
saying, "Probably a lot of people would be
grateful if we said out loud, 'I'm bored in
this meeting.' Let's move things along."
This episode is brought to you by Vanta.
When it comes to ensuring your company
has top-notch security practices, things get
complicated fast. Now you can assess risks,
secure the trust of your customers and automate
compliance for SOC2, ISO 27001, HIPAA and
more with a single platform, Vanta. Vanta's
market-leading trust management platform helps
you continuously monitor compliance alongside
reporting and tracking risks. Plus, you can
save hours by completing security questionnaires
with Vanta AI. Join thousands of global companies
that use Vanta to automate evidence collection,
unify risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go
to vanta.com/lenny. That's vanta.com/lenny.
Okay. This is a great segue too. Now I have
a sense. I need to change this. This needs
to change. I'm just scared to say this, to bring
it up, to change the way people are operating to
ask for what I want. What advice can you
share for people to actually do this?
So for asking what you want, I think the really
important tweak here is asking intentionally
because I think a lot of us are stuck on a certain
track that's comfortable for us when we ask. And
so if you're more in the people-pleasing
camp, maybe you're used to not asking at
all. You're hoping that people are reading your
mind and just magically knowing what you want.
And if you're more in the control-free camp, maybe
you're used to ordering people around and saying,
"Go do this now." And so for both of those folks,
it's not about... I think if you ask any of them,
"Is this working for you?" They'd say no. Of
course, it's obvious from an effectiveness
standpoint, it's not working well, but
they more just haven't embraced that
you can do it a different way that they
only really see one way of doing it.
So part of asking for what you want effectively
is really just recognizing the rut that you get
stuck in and working through all those
narratives that make us resist asking
it a different way. Because often the people
who don't want to ask have a story that says,
"This is too risky. Or it's not worth it. They're
going to say no anyway, so why even bother?"
So these are all very common things that people go
through, but then they end up not actually asking
for what they want. Now, actually expressing who
they are and what they stand for in the world.
And that has a really serious cost. I think
that we tend to tell ourselves the story, "Oh,
this is fine. I'll be fine." Versus owning, "I'm
going to be living my life not asking for what I
want." Do I really want to be at my funeral and
have people say, "Oh, Kenneth played it safe.
He didn't really go for his dreams, but he was
nice. No one was ever mad at him." That's not
what we want people to say at our eulogies.
No. That's good motivation. Okay. So say in this
example you gave of like, "I need us to make
a decision. I know I'm trying to keep everyone
happy, but we need to make a decision." Do you
have advice for maybe phrases of how to approach.
You talked about making intentional. How do
you actually go about doing that? Is it the
way you communicate it? Is it something else?
How do you actually do this without pissing
people off and also just risking too much?
Even implicit in that question, to me that's that
question of, "Oh, how do I do it without being any
risk of ever pissing anyone off?" That's a piece
of the resistance right there. And so this is a
great example of the type of work that we have
to do, right? Because in theory, asking is easy,
"Oh, you just try some way and maybe people are
pissed off and maybe they're not." But probably
it's going to be fine and you'll have the chance
to try again and iterate and work from it.
But often we get stuck so we don't get to go
through those levels of iteration because we want
to make sure we're going to get the outcome. We
say, "Oh, well, I'm not willing to ever piss
anyone off ever. And so I'm just going to be
stuck at this step because I haven't figured out
what's going to guarantee me." And of course,
there's no guarantee. We can never guarantee
that people are going to feel a particular way.
So part of asking for what you want effectively
is actually bringing some compassion for yourself.
Of course, we all want to be sure that the way
we ask is going to be effective and no one is
going to be mad at us and we're going to get
all of our dreams come true. But we don't get
that. I wish we did. That would be nice. But is
that worth not pursuing your dreams in life?
Such a good point about what you identified
and the way... I think a lot of people that
think about it, it's just like, "I'd always
do this without causing anyone any pain or
risking anything going wrong." I think that's,
to your point, part of it. So you talk a lot
about founders. You work with a lot of founders,
a lot of listeners here are not founders, they're
product managers, ICs on teams, other functions
that don't have "power". Is there anything that
you suggest these folks do differently or think
about this differently or is it kind of the same
thing? In the end everyone has power in some way.
How would you think about this if you're just,
say, a product manager, individual contributor?
I think one of the most important balances in
terms of the asking step is both asking clearly,
but asking with great humility. And this actually
works whether you're in a position of power or
not because I think a lot of folks will go so far
to the end of humility. They say, "Well, I'm not
going to say this out loud at all." But in fact,
if you're willing to say, I really disagree with
this product decision and I would really prefer
that we make this different decision. I know it's
not my call and I'm just one opinion and a lot of
people are going to see things differently
and that's fine, but it's important to me
that you know that. So what do you think?
Are you willing to reconsider this?"
That's such a great approach. It's very
not scary to say that. It also, I think,
highlights something I wanted to touch on is I
think people have a lot more influence and power
than they think they do. Say a PM on a team
disagrees with a plan for a product. People
actually care about your opinion and you could
actually change things. But just telling them,
"I think this is a bad idea." And you often
don't. Is that what you find, that people
have a lot more influence than they think they
do? Anything along those lines that comes up?
You're giving me deep goosebumps because I
think this is a really underappreciated thing
in terms of asking for what we want because
especially in the PM world, we're trained to
look for data. We're not just going to state an
opinion. We're going to say, "Oh, the AB test
said this. Or 30% of our users do this, or the
ROI on this is X." And data is great. We love
data for a reason of course. And I think people
forget about exactly what you're highlighting,
that your relationships matter, and that just
your opinion because you believe something or
because you want something often that's enough.
Because guess what? You're in a relationship with
these people you work with. They care about
you. You have some sort of leverage with them.
And I think that often people go the other way
and say, "Oh, I've got power. I'm going to try
and leverage it." But actually, if you go the
other direction and you're humble and you say,
"I know I can't make you do anything, it's not
my call to make. But man, this is really what
I want. I'm just going to put it out there and
ask." That I think it feels really vulnerable
and uncomfortable to not lean on data as a sort of
way of saying, "No, no, I'm right, so you should
believe what I believe." But just say, "Actually,
I don't know that I'm right. This is just what I
think and I hope that's enough on its own."
Do you find that that's actually a crutch a lot
of times to people not saying anything is they
don't have that data? They don't have evidence
and they just, "I shouldn't say anything. If
someone asks for why I don't have a great answer,
I just think this is what should be."
Totally. And I think there's a balance
there as with anything. Is ignoring data and
going in gut all the time, great? Probably not,
right? We use data for a reason, but I think
there are all these moments when we are making
a gut decision and having all the data there
means having the opinion set out loud. I think
often the dangers of people saying, "Oh, I
don't have data to back this up. It's just
what I think. And I'm not sure people are going to
agree with me, so I'm just not going to say it."
So we don't have the data of all those gut
opinions of these subject matter experts in
the room, even though that gut information to
me is just as important as anything we could
get from the SQL database or whatever.
Before we move on to step three, you talked about
the opposite of asking for what you want. This was
just step two is just complaining and being angry
later like, "I knew this project was going to
fail. I knew this was a terrible deadline. I knew
this design was not great." Anything more you want
to say along those lines of just like, "If you're
not asking for what you want, complaining is often
a sign that you should be doing that more"?
To me, complaints are great inspiration.
To me, I love radical candor, for example,
where I try to go a step further than
radical candor is to not just say, "Hey,
here's my feedback. Just wanted you to know." But
to say, "And I want something. I would like to see
an outcome." And so I think that to me it's all
about the effective framing that the complaint
is probably not going to be an effective way to
do it, but it can be great inspiration to say,
"Gosh, that complaining means I'm frustrated.
What am I frustrated about? Let me envision
that better future. Let me think about what's
an effective way to actually move towards that.
What's an effective way to communicate that desire
that's actually likely to get me towards a yes?"
And so when we actually embrace that sort of
frustration, annoying, complaining thing and
follow that thread down and think about how to be
effective that way, we can actually get something
really compelling and useful, but it requires
actually embracing that part of ourselves that
sometimes we're a little bit ashamed of like,
"Oh, I don't like that whiny part of myself. I'm
just going to push that one down versus actually
taking what it has to say as important data."
That's a really good point. I think that's
actually another blocker for a lot of people
is just, "I don't want to be a complaining person.
I just want to be like, let's do this. I'm in,
let's go. I don't want to be seen as a
squeaky wheel." Is there anything you say
there about as a resistance point for people?
Well, I'm a big fan of internal family systems,
which is this sort of psychotherapy technique
that really talks about parts and the sort of
parts of ourselves and the ways in which they
don't always agree with each other. Part of why
I love this approach is, A, because we already use
this language. We say, "Part of me thinks this,
a part of me thinks that." And really when I talk
about how to work through resistance, really it's
about embracing and validating all of our parts.
Because often we're really comfortable with one
part of ourselves that we think is, "Oh,
this part is virtuous and good and great,
and this part is whiny and bad, and not great,
and I don't respect that part of me as much." So
really to sort of ask effectively, we generally
need to embrace all these parts and really bring
in all the information they're bringing in because
if we ignore the part that's really scared to ask,
well, then we're going to stay stuck.
Versus if we come in and say, "Hey, buddy,
why are you scared? You seem terrified. What's
going on? Oh, well man, you think your whole
professional reputation has staked on this and
you're an imposter and they're going to find out,
and then you'll never work again? Well, of
course you'd be scared. That makes a ton of
sense." And by embracing that, instead of
ignoring that and being ashamed of that,
that is often how we soften those fears and
say, "I know that's scary, but we also know
that's not really true. You're not an imposter,
right? You're an experienced professional."
Man, there's so many threads we can't follow
here. This whole line of internal family
systems, right?
Mm-hmm.
That's its own podcast episode potentially. And
then imposter syndrome, we've touched a bunch
of different podcast episodes, but I'll avoid
going in that direction. Something you reminded
me of is we just had Carole Robin on the podcast
who taught this class touchy-feely at Stanford
for a long time, which is all about helping
people learn how to deal with other people,
which we never learned in life. It's like a
class, how to learn to work with other people.
I took one of Stanford's T-Group Weekends,
summer of 2020, I think a month after George
Floyd was murdered and was facilitated
by a black woman. And it was one of the
most profound transformative weekends of
my life. Because T-groups already people
rave about them. But having it at that point in
history with those people in the room, oof.
A lot of tears, I imagine.
It was crazy. I mean, it was really wild.
I feel like every single person that has gone
through, I think it's called Leaders in Tech is
the broader umbrella term. And Carole talked
about it. Everyone that has gone through it,
100% have told me that it's a transformative
life experience for them. And you had a bonus
transformational piece. So anyway, if people want
to check out that episode, I will include it in
the show notes. But the reason I brought it up is
Carole shared this framework for how to actually
give feedback in a way where people can receive
it that I'll just highlight here. I have it here.
And it's somewhat related to nonviolent
communication, which is what you touched on. And
she told me, actually, she taught this way before
nonviolent communication came out with their whole
philosophy. And it's basically when you want
to give someone feedback, the template is when
you do a behavior, I feel a feeling, and she's
big on like say actual feeling word not like,
"I feel like, or I feel that," blah, blah,
blah. And step three is, "I'm telling you this
because..." and then what you want them to change.
Do you find that sort of approach helpful?
I do. I teach the same thing. I
think sort of Carole's approach
and nonviolent communication, DBT teaches
a similar approach. They call dear man.
To me, what's DBT?
It's a dialectical behavioral therapy.
It's related to CBT. So there's kind of rough
consensus in the sort of personal development
world of how to ask. And really what they have in
common is around staying really factual because I
think that what can we know factually well? We
can know our thoughts, we can know our feelings
because no one else can know that better than
us. Maybe we can trust our eyes. What would a
video camera have recorded? And that's about it.
So I think often we get really distracted by all
these stories we have about the data, but
when we bring it back to that fundamental
core of this is what I think, this is what
I feel, this is what I've observed in the
world, it tends to make the ask a lot clearer
versus these stories like you mentioned of,
"I feel like you're an asshole." It's like,
"Well, that's a story. That's not a fact."
Yeah. I feel that is not the right way to say
I feel. What do you actually feel? No. Okay,
so let's move to step three. We've been going
on this whole tangent of therapy and stuff,
which is amazing, but let's make sure we
cover all three steps. So step one again
was articulate what you want. Step two is
ask for what you want. What's step three?
So to me step three is actually
the trickiest for most people.
So far, they're all tricky to me.
Oh yeah, they're all tricky, for sure.
The most tricky.
But step three is accept
the response. And it might seem so simple,
but it actually is kind of subtle. And so
one reason is that idea of sort of the whole
body yes or the hell yes. Because I think often
we really want a yes. And so we're very, very
biased to look for a yes versus accepting no,
"That was a no." If someone made this face,
that's a no. It doesn't matter what comes out
of their mouth. And so the challenge of accepting
the response is often that of hearing the no,
but not over accepting or under accepting it.
Because I think sometimes what people who are
really afraid to ask will do is they say, oh,
well, that was a no. So it's no forever and
I should never ask again. My dream is dead
and nothing is ever going to happen for me
again." And that's because they get so scared.
But actually no, that's over accepting. The no
is just from this person right now in the way that
you asked, which doesn't necessarily mean anything
about the next time you ask to a different
person in a different way, in a different time.
And on the flip side, in that sort of more
control freak mode, I think for them they'll
often skip over the response say, "Well, they
said no, but they don't know what they're
talking about." Or they're my direct report,
so they have to do what I say. So these are
all fundamentally disrespectful ways to operate in
this relationship. When we're talking about asking
for what we want, we're talking about influence.
So you need to have good relationships. You
can't be influential with a bad relationship.
So really accepting the response is about, yes,
I'm going to be genuine about what I want, but
I'm also going to genuinely care about you and
have deep respect for your ability to consent
or not consent to whatever the ask is. Because
I think the counterintuitive thing is that
often when we really respect people's no's,
it can actually be more influential, more
motivating. If someone says, "Okay. I'm not ready
to deliver this on time." Be like, "Okay. Well,
I'm going to give the project to another person."
I'm taking your no at face value. And they say,
"Oh gosh, well, I didn't realize that was going
to be the consequence. Maybe I can get it
done by that time." And so that way you're
not forcing them and you're not coercing them,
right? You're just saying, "No, you said no? So
that your no is no, and I accept that."
So it feels like part of the skill here is
preparing, is knowing. Some people just say no and
that's okay. That's part of the experience. Part
of it is if there's this not yet component... We
had Mihika Kapoor on the podcast. She has a PM at
Figma and she had this really great approach to
building new things within companies is just like
everything to her is not yet and no is a not yet.
And the way you phrased it is it could just be the
way you asked. It could be, maybe they'll agree
if you can figure out a better way to pitch the
thing. Is there anything more you can add there
about just this idea of it's not no forever?
Acceptance of the response is primarily an
emotional regulation issue because once we
get our emotions intact, it's just, is it yes or
is it no? And if it's no, which it probably is,
most of the time the world tells us no, then
the question is, "All right, what can I learn
from this? What am I going to try next?" And
so when we're able to emotionally regulate,
it's all very cut and dry, right? It's like,
"Okay. Here's data to tell me what to try next."
And so really, 99% of the challenge tends to
be all the feelings that come up for us when
we hear no. Because We hate hearing no. It's
so uncomfortable. And so part of the practice
of getting good at asking for what we want is
recognizing you're going to hear no all the time,
and that's completely normal and fine, and it
doesn't need to be something so scary or awful.
Easier said than done in real life. Is there an
example of either a client of yours... I know
you can't actually share specific details,
but I'm just curious if there's an example
that comes up of someone dealing with this and
getting better at it, or your own career.
I gave a talk about this sort of right after
it happened, but I was fired from Slack three
different times, which I feel like has to be some
kind of startup record. I don't know who would be
the record-keeping body for this. But now 10 years
on, I have different perspective, of course. And
so this was almost exactly 10 years ago, spring
of 2014 and I just gotten the job as the first PM
at Slack. It was already the hottest thing out
there. It was only a couple dozen employees.
I came in excited, but also a little insecure
because I had just come off my breakup with my
co-founder. I just wanted to put my head down
and do a good job. I was engaged at the time,
so Slack already knew I was going to be
going away on a bachelor or backpacking trip.
I have a wedding and honeymoon in the fall.
And so I came in naive and overconfident of,
"I've been a founder. I've worked on iconic
products. I know how to do this. I'm a pro.
I'm just going to go in and do the work."
So instead of getting really clear on what
does success look like here or what's your
culture or what are your expectations of me,
I just went in and made my best guess and went
for it. And lo and behold, turns out what I came
in with, that supreme overconfidence was not
what they wanted at all. They'd kind of been
in the trenches reinventing from the game to
Slack. They'd been through layoffs, really hard
times together. So they wanted someone to come
in humble and to earn their trust of this kind
of core team that had been together for years.
I just didn't get any of that. I wasn't hearing
that feedback. I wasn't hearing those nos,
and I wasn't articulating what I wanted.
What I wanted was really very basic. I just
wanted to figure out how to do a good job,
and I wanted to have a good relationship with
the CEO because I was working for him. And you
need to have a good relationship with your
boss. But the problem was in the first firing
anyway was I had not articulated those goals.
And so I shouldn't have been surprised when six
weeks into my tenure at Slack, I came back from
my backpacking trip with my bachelor buddies,
and I had an email in my inbox saying, "Hey,
you're fired. It seems like it's not working out.
Let me know how you want to wrap it up." So as
you can imagine, I freaked out. I loved this job,
I love this company, so I profusely apologized.
I said, "I'll do whatever it takes. I'm so sorry.
I'm going to be committed to turn this around."
And so early stage startup turns out firing
doesn't always stick. Monday morning, I had my
job back. But obviously things were not the same
as they'd been before because in the second era,
what I wanted was sort of better articulated more
clear, but all of a sudden that fear that had been
under the surface, that insecurity was now very,
very present every day because I was terrified
of was I going to get fired? Was I going to not
make the most of this opportunity? And so I
went fully into people pleaser mode. And so
that meant that even though what I desperately
wanted was to have this good relationship was
to be successful, build a great product.
I had a year of one-on-ones with the CEO.
I never, never ever asked for what
I wanted. I never said it out loud
because I was scared. I was scared of what the
consequences were. I knew there were a hundred PMs
standing behind me ready to take my job if the CEO
is ever a moment unhappy with me. I said, "No, I'm
not going to take the risk. I'm too scared of what
the consequences might be." And so I held all that
fear and all those desires of, "I just want to do
a great job. I want us to be awesome partners and
build this amazing industry changing product."
I never said any of that stuff out loud. I just
put my head down and I tried to obey. And so as
you can imagine, this didn't work very well. I was
feeling horrible day to day. I was terrified
of this guy I was working for. And so again,
I shouldn't have been surprised, but I was, when
I got fired for the second time. It wasn't quite
firing. But this time I'd come back from my
honeymoon and I had a phone call on Monday
that said, "Seems like product management is
not working out for Slack. We're actually just
going to get rid of product. You're going to
be user research. It's going to be fine."
And for me, I love user research, but that was
the beginning of my career. I was not interested
in going back to that. What was fascinating
was at that point, I was actually able to
articulate what I wanted there and was willing
to say it out loud. Because what I wanted was,
"No, let's keep me in product. I've got an idea
for how we can run it." So I wrote a proposal,
I sent it around to the management team. Turns
out, when you actually ask for what you want
out loud, you're much more likely to get it.
And so within a week, this new plan had traction
with the management team team and I had my old
job back again. Everything was fine except of
course it wasn't fine because now I was scared,
but the stakes seemed really high, and this is
where that deep imposter syndrome sit in. I was
like, "Am I even any good at this? Should I even
be in product management? Am I ever going to
work in this industry again? Is this going
to be my dark secret that I take to the grave
that Stewart Butterfield fired me three times?"
I think what I couldn't be with in that moment
was the no's, because I was getting no after no
after no after no from Stewart and the rest of
the management team saying, "What you're doing
is not working for us, right? Your ask are not
landing. You're not being effective in the way
that you want to be effective." And because I
wasn't able to hear those no's again, because to
that emotional regulation standpoint, I
couldn't handle the feelings of like, "Ugh,
maybe what I'm doing is not good enough."
So instead of pointing the finger at myself,
I pointed the finger at him. I said, "You know
what? Actually this guy, he's not such a great
manager. He's not so good at product. I'm the
one who was on the ground with the users. I
know what's right." Against all evidence to
the contrary, by the way, is this product
luminary, visionary, famous person.
So clearly not based on any facts,
but it was an emotional issue of I couldn't
deal with the reality of what I was doing was
not working. And so again, because I was not
articulating what I wanted, I was not asking
for it and I certainly was not listening to
the no's. I shouldn't have been surprised
when finally the third time it came down, and
this time it was serious because we had HR.
So it turns out once you hire HR, the firings
are final. And so I only made it to a year at
Slack and it was a year of just utter torture
because I spent that year being fully out of
integrity with myself. Never saying what I
really wanted, how I really felt because it
didn't feel safe. I was too scared. I kept it
all inside. And it took me six months or a year
even after that to really feel safe and okay
again. It was a serious decompression time.
My wife and I had a baby during that time. I was
on zero sleep. It was a rough, rough period. But
the irony is that when I actually came out of
that experience, the reality of it was extremely
simple. I hadn't articulated what I wanted.
I hadn't asked for what I wanted. I had not
listened to the no's in response to my non-ask.
And so of course I was unhappy with the result.
Why would I have expected anything
different? I wasn't the victim. Stewart
wasn't the villain. It was just ineffective
asking. And so to me, especially because I
was already on that path towards coaching,
that lesson hit really hard in terms of how
do we make this work more sustainable?
We stay in integrity with ourselves even
when it's hard, even when it's scary, even when
we don't know exactly what the outcome is going
to be. And so that's really the story of how I
became a coach, of seeing exactly how much I'd
screwed up at Slack and seeing how much I had
suffered and how much a lot of people suffer
in these similar circumstances. All you have to
do to turn it around is ask for what you want.
So this is why I'm so passionate about this
stuff because it can sound so fluffy to say,
"Oh, focus on integrity. Honor your desires.
No, it's real life stuff of a year of suffering,
of pain, of fear." I don't want other people
to be going through that and that's why I'm
so passionate about this stuff.
Wow, what a story. I love that it's
kind of a microcosm of everything we've talked
about. You've did all the things that you teach
people to avoid.
Exactly.
And I think what's interesting is you went
through these three phases. Interestingly,
at the beginning, your first phase was you
were not hearing the no's, but it was rooted
in this confidence that you're a founder, you're
awesome. They're so lucky to have you. I know what
I'm doing, get out of my way. And then the third
phase, you also, the issue there was you weren't
hearing the no's, but it was more from fear of
being fired again. And so it's interesting that
there's these different reasons you're not
hearing what people are actually saying.
Totally. Well, and to me, the first one is about
articulation as well because I think that if
in the beginning it articulated that, "Yeah, I'm
confident, but actually I want to do a really good
job and I want to have good relationships.
So let me think about intentionally,
how do I create those outcomes?" But because
I hadn't articulated that's what I wanted,
it didn't even occur to me like, "Oh yeah, I need
to do some intentional relationship building,
figure out some metrics for success."
It was an early stage startup. There
wasn't a ton of sort of process or structure in
place, suffice to say. And so if I wanted that,
I needed to create it myself, but because I hadn't
articulated that any of that was important to me,
I just flew by the seat of my pants and it took
failing to get some data to say, "Ooh, yeah,
maybe I need to look at this more closely."
I imagine you've gone through this exercise many
times, but say you were to do it again, what would
you do differently and what do you think would've
happened? Do you think you would've stayed there
for many, many years, had a product at Slack at
this point? Just imagining that reality, what
would you have done differently? And then what
would you have imagined have turned out?
Well, I mean obviously broadly, I would've
asked for what I wanted and what I wanted was I
wanted to do the best work of our life. I wanted
to have a deep professional partner in the CEO and
the rest of the product and management team. And I
wanted to produce great work that people loved.
And that was part of why I was attracted to the
culture and the mission and the company.
And so this is what's tricky is of course,
that's what I would've done. Now, do I
know what the outcome would've been?
No, I might've been fired even sooner. They
might've said, "No, this is not working out.
Let's just be done here." So that's what's
tricky about this is it really isn't about
the outcome. Of course, asking for what you want
makes you more likely to get the outcome you want,
but you don't do it for guarantee of a certain
outcome because no one can promise you that. You
do it so you can stay in integrity with yourself
and not suffer through all this. Because at
least then I would've said, "You know what? It
didn't work out. At least I'm not sitting here
suffering. I can get another job at another
startup. It's not the end of the world."
And I think that the mistake we make is pretending
that it is of saying, going into fight or flight
and saying, "This is a severe existential
threat to who I am and my safety in the
world," versus being like, "I'm disappointed.
I wish it had worked out, but it didn't."
That's a really profound point that this practice
isn't necessarily to just have everything work out
beautifully and to get the things you're looking
for. It's to feel like you did, which you could
have and to feel integrity with yourself that you
did what you needed to do and you're not going to
regret something down the road.
Indeed.
I'm going to take a quick tangent down the being
the first PM route real quick. There's a lot of
people that think about being the first PM at
a startup join as the first PM. I imagine you
work with people asking for advice along these
lines. It's classically a very challenging role.
Many people don't last. Many people follow your
trajectory where it's like, "Oh, shit. What have
I done?" Any advice for people that are a first
PM at a company or startup or thinking about
that role?" What can you tell them to help
them be successful or at least not suffer?
To me, it really is about the relationship with
the CEO or with the founders because that's the
root of a lot of the issues that come out of that
scenario because it's not always you. In my story,
I think it was primarily about me, but I also
work with a lot of founders who are going
through really tough things. My clue to people who
report to a founder is to say, "Imagine if you're
confused about how your founder is behaving.
Imagine that they're terrified all the time,
and see if that makes their behavior more clear."
Because it is scary to be a founder. Everything
is on your shoulders. And I think a lot of
people do feel that sense of high stakes all
the time. And so I think being real about
that of what is the state that the person
or the people you're working for are in and sort
of working within that versus sort of pretending
that it's something else or wishing that it were
something else is the path to having a healthy
relationship. Because if you don't have a healthy
relationship with the person you're working for,
you're not going to get anything done. You're
not going to succeed in any meaningful way.
I love that framework of how to think about why a
founder is behaving in a certain way. Just maybe a
last following thread there is just what should
people look for to help them understand if the
founder and them are a good fit, if they're going
to have a good time working with that founder? Is
there anything just like questions they might ask
or ways of operating that are useful to understand
like, "Okay, I think I'll be okay with this
founder in this company as the first PM or not.
I think it's a hard thing to generalize about,
but to me it really is about understanding
expectations. I guess this is a predictable coming
from me, "But what do you really want? Because I
think that often the founders put together a job
description, but then they're faced with a real
human being who has real human subtleties and
things they're good at or not so good at." And
so being very, very clear about expectations
and of figuring out collaboratively a way to
work together that's effective to me is there's
no guarantees of course, but it gives you a more
sure path to having a productive relationship.
It's actually something that I recommend to a lot
of founders for maybe their first 10 or 15,
or 20 employees of just have a relationship
design conversation with each of them when
they're first hired. Because I think a lot
of us come in naive the way I did, assuming, "Oh
yeah, I'm just going to come in and do my thing
the way I've always done it. It's going
to be fine." Versus coming in and saying,
"I actually don't know how I'm going to operate at
this company. I have range like anyone has range,
and I don't know what this company needs and who
else is here and sort of what my role and what
my place is going to be within these other
people. And so by really understanding that
intentionally and not from a place of performance
management, you're already doing this poorly,
you're in big trouble. But what is the best way
to work together given who we have now and what
we want and what we need? Let's figure it out.
Coming back to our core topic, is there anything
that we didn't cover, anything that I
should have asked you about the skill,
the art of asking for what you want? Anything
else you want to leave listeners with?
I do want to mention something that I hear a
lot from founders when I talk about the piece
of working through resistance because I think
a lot of them say, "Oh, you want me to let go
of fear and focus on what I want? Well, I
mean, I've been running from fear my whole
career. That's how I'm so hard-working and I'm so
smart is I'm always afraid I'm not good enough."
Am I going to be able to do this job without
fear hounding me every step of the way? I just
remember the first time I heard this, it broke
my heart, and now I've heard it dozens of times
I'd say. So I mean, it really is. I think
it's a belief that sits deep in the hearts
of a lot of us high achieving Silicon Valley
tech types of, "My fear of not being good
enough is what drives me to be great."
And I just want to come out here and say
there's other ways to motivate. You can motivate
based on joy, based on vision, based on your
inspiration in this vision of what you want.
I think a lot of folks I talk to are skeptical
understandably because operated a different
way their whole life and all I can really say
is try it. Try following an inspiring vision
that's really meaningful to you and just see
what it's like to not be living in fear all
the time because it is a big difference and
it's really meaningful. It matters a lot.
So is the fear there that if they ask for what
they want, they'll get what they want and they
let go of this drive to prove themselves? And
is that the fear? How is it that they move
away from that need to prove themselves?
Well, I mean that's a longer story. I
would say managing our own fear as a
sort of lifelong practice. I'm not going to
claim I'm anywhere near done with it. But I
guess I'd just say that I think part of the
big shift I see in personal development for
people I work with is from saying, "Oh, no, my
fear is good. I need it. It's keeping me safe."
To saying, "Fear is for when there's a tiger
chasing you and there's no tiger chasing me."
I'm sitting in my office in a desk chair on a
zoom call. There's no real danger here. And so
fear is not particularly functional. And so when
they start realizing that, the practice becomes,
"Oh yeah, I'm feeling afraid." But I'm reminding
myself there's not a tiger in the room. If I
really want to get things done, achieve my
goals, I need to focus on vision on what I
want to achieve in the world, not on avoiding
all these fears. So that's the short of it.
Amazing. It reminds me, we have a
chat... I had a chat with Matt Mochari,
and we spent a bunch of time on dealing with
fear and overcoming fear. So folks want to dig
deeper there. They could check out that episode.
Just maybe one more question before we get to our
very exciting lightning round. I want to take
us to Contrarian Corner, classic contrarian
corner. I'm curious if there's anything that you
have a contrarian opinion about, something that
you believe that most other people don't.
For me, I'm not a big believer in discipline
that I think some folks come to coaching
looking for a drill sergeant and say,
"All right. Shout at me and tell me to do better."
And I start to say, "That's not how I operate."
Because it's not the discipline doesn't work,
but it's like people-pleasing. It's a short-term
coping strategy. Discipline will get you in the
gym for a week, but it's not going to get you
in the gym for a year. The people who are in the
gym for a year are doing it because they want to.
There's actually something that's motivating for
them in that. It's not just, "Oh, I hate this,
but I'm going to go anyway." And so I try
to be really clear with people about that,
that I'm not going to be the drill sergeant
because it's unsustainable. Someone shouting
at you is not going to get you moving towards
what you want in life over multiple years. It's
days or weeks or even hours thing. And so I really
look for a higher bar to say, "Let's look for true
long-term sustainable motivation," which means
relying on vision, pursuing what you want.
I love that it all ties back to knowing what
you want, asking for what you want, and then
dealing with the answers that you get.
I am a broken record admittedly.
Amazing. Kenneth, is there anything else you
wanted to share or leave listeners with before
we get to our very exciting lightning round?
No, but just thank you for letting me share
this stuff. It really is my life's work
and I'm very passionate about it and I
hope it's helpful for people. I'm going to
be writing more about it on LinkedIn.
Okay, amazing. We'll point people there.
With that, we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
I'm ready. Let's do it.
First question, what are two or three books
that you've recommended most to other people?
Well, I already mentioned Radical Candor. I
think that is for sure a modern classic and
I think that whole idea of challenging
directly, but caring personally is very
much aligned with what I'm talking about,
right? Because you need the relationships
and you need to actually speak your truth. So
I love Kim Scott's writing on that stuff.
We had a Kim Scott on the podcast. Folks want to
dig deeper there. We'll link to that episode. I'll
let you keep going. Sorry for the interruption.
Yeah. I mean I mentioned before, but I actually
took Jonny Miller's Nervous System Mastery
course. I just wrapped up. So you've had
lots of great personal professional
development thinkers on the podcast,
so thank you for introducing me to them.
I'm so happy to hear that. We'll link to
that episode as well. I love that. What
a circle of life we've got here, guests
following other guests, taking their courses,
joining the podcast. What a happy world.