So you've built one of the largest and
most respected data teams in all of tech.
For me, analytics is a business impact driving
function and not purely a service function,
not just answering the why, but answering
the, "What do we do now that we know this?"
One of your colleagues told me that you
are incredibly good at defining metrics.
Retention is a terrible thing to
goal on. It's almost impossible
to drive in a meaningful way
in a short term. Ultimately,
you want to find a short-term metric you
can measure that drives a long-term output.
You mentioned the early team.
I felt extreme ownership.
Yes, you are a data scientist, but your
goal is to figure out what's happening.
And if that means that you're going to
pick up the phone and call customers,
then that is what you're going
to do to roll up your sleeves.
Today my guest is Jessica Lachs. Jessica is
Vice President of Analytics and Data Science at
DoorDash, which has built one of the biggest and
most impactful data teams in tech. She's been at
DoorDash for over 10 years and was the first
GM at DoorDash responsible for launching new
markets. Previously, Jessica founded GiftSimple,
a social gifting startup and began her career
in investment banking at Lehman Brothers.
In our conversation, we go deep on how to
build and scale your data org, including why a
centralized org model is so effective. What to
look for when hiring data people, how to pick the
right metrics for teams to align incentives and
drive the right sorts of outcomes. Examples
of how the data team at DoorDash has helped
the business make better decisions, a bunch of
great stories about the early days of DoorDash
and a ton more. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in
your favorite podcasting app or YouTube.
It's the best way to avoid missing feature
episodes and helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you Jessica Lachs. Jessica,
thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you so much for having
me. I'm very excited to be here.
So you've built one of the largest and
most respected data teams in all of tech.
I've heard from a number of people that look to
you for advice when they're trying to build and
scale their data teams. And then DoorDash in
particular is an incredibly complex business.
There's three or maybe even four sites to the
marketplace. There's this operational element.
From the outside, it just feels extremely
complicated and wild. I imagine from the
inside it's even more wild. Let's talk about some
of the things you've learned about building and
scaling the team. You have a fairly contrarian
perspective on how to structure data teams. This
was referenced when we had Elizabeth Stone
on the podcast too. She approaches data the
same way. So I'd love to hear just your take on
how to structure data teams within companies.
This episode is brought to you by Webflow. We're
all friends here, so let's be real for a second.
We all know that your website shouldn't be
a static asset. It should be a dynamic part
of your strategy that drives conversions.
That's business 101. But here's a number
for you. 54% of leaders say web updates take
too long. That's over half of you listening
right now. That's where Webflow comes in. Their
visual-first platform allows you to build, launch,
and optimize webpages fast. That means you can set
ambitious business goals and your site can rise
to the challenge. Learn how teams like Dropbox,
IDEO, and Orangetheory trust Webflow to achieve
their most ambitious goals today at webflow.com.
This episode is brought to you by Anvil. Their
document SDK helps product teams build and launch
software for documents fast. Companies like Carta
and Vouch Insurance use Anvil to accelerate
the development of their document workflows.
Getting to market fast is a top priority for
product teams, and the last thing that you
or your developers want is to build document
workflows from scratch. It's time-consuming,
expensive, and distracts from core work.
You could stitch together multiple tools
and manage those integrations or you
can use an all-in-one document SDK.
Most product managers will tell you, "Paperwork
sucks." Anvil's document SDK helps teams get to
market fast, incorporate your brand's style, and
give you back time to focus on your company's core
differentiated features. For your users paperwork
often starts with an AI-powered web form styled
and embedded in your application. From there,
you can route data to your backend systems and
to the correct fields in your PDFs via API.
Complete the process with a white labeled
e-signature. The best part about Anvil is the
level of customization their SDK provides.
Non-technical folks love Anvil's drag-and-drop
builder and developers love their flexible
APIs and easy-to-understand documentation.
Build documents software fast with Anvil,
that's useanvil.com/Lenny to learn more or
start a free trial. That's useanvil.com/Lenny.
There's two main things that I think are important
when you're structuring a team. The first is I
believe that analytics should have a seat at
the table just like engineering and product
and the business folks, the operators. For me,
analytics is a business impact driving function
and not purely a service function. I think
there are analytics teams at other companies
where they are answering people's questions,
maybe even through Jira tickets, we're building
dashboards. That was never really of interest to
me. That wasn't the team that I wanted to build.
For me, it's about finding opportunities, about
having a point of view on the decisions that we
should make, not just answering the why
but answering the so what. "So what do
we do now that we know this?" And so that's
definitely one thing as far as my point of
view on building a data team. I think the second
thing which may be a little more contrarian is
I think there are people out there who think that
analytics should be embedded into business units.
I strongly disagree. I believe a central
model, a center of excellence is superior
and I'm happy to talk about why, but that's
something that I feel quite strongly about.
We've tried it or I shouldn't... well, we've
experimented in the past with the alternative,
so putting it into a business unit and it's
just much more problematic and I think the value
you get from a central model is far greater
than some of the things that you might lose.
Yeah, let's definitely talk about it.
And just to make sure people understand,
when you say central versus embedded, is that in
terms of reporting lines, in terms of their goals?
It's a great question. So mostly it's in terms of
reporting lines because I think on the goal side,
that is something where we have the same goals
that our partner teams have, and I think that
that's actually an important part of a successful
central model. So when I say central model,
it just means that for marketing analytics,
marketing analytics is part of the broader
analytics team. It does not sit and report
in through marketing. Just to clarify.
Got it. So the reporting functions at some
companies, there's the head of marketing or
some partners to the head of marketing where
the data, say, analyst or biz ops people or
data scientists would report potentially
to them and that's it. And they're not as
connected to the core, to the rest of the data
team, the rest of the analytics team versus-
Exactly. Yeah.
Yeah.
So you'd have a bunch of smaller, of course, data
teams that sit embedded within the functions.
And I understand why business leaders like
that. You're embedded within the function,
so you're a part of the team. That ownership, that
camaraderie that comes with that, I think you can
solve for that. But I do understand that that is
a benefit. I think the other benefit of course is
the business leaders control the roadmaps so
they get to dictate the work. They know that
they have help and resources in that area when
they need them. So that certainty, that control,
I totally understand the value there, but I think
that those are two things that you can solve for
if you know that those are the biggest issues
with a central team. So for us, we have a central
analytics team, but we are divided up into pods
that map perfectly with how product engineering,
operations marketing are structured as well.
And so our team de facto has these folks
embedded with our partner teams, even though
the reporting structure is up through a central
org through me. And that helps the team to
feel like they are one team, both in terms
of the analytics team feeling like it's one
team, but also to use the marketing example,
the marketing folks are one team and because
the analytics shares the same goals as the
marketing leaders, your incentives are aligned
to work on the most important things and your
success is their success and vice versa. So I
think that that's been really a happy medium,
but still preserves all the benefits of a
central org. And there are a lot of them.
I want to hear about them, but I think something
that some people may think when you say essential
org is like a silo data team that sits there and
they're like a service org a little bit within
the company. It's like, "Hey, I need some
data help." And you try to convince that,
"Hey, I need some help on this thing."
And that's not what you're saying.
Oh, no. No, no, no. That job seems terrible. I
don't want that job. No, to the earlier point,
we have a seat at the table. We are business
partners, we are thought partners with our
product counterparts, with our engineering
counterparts, with our ops counterparts,
and we again, share the same goals and
have the same initiatives that they do.
And it's just our job to come at it from
a data-driven place. We bring to the table
insights on things that we've noticed, deep
dives that we do to understand the problems
that we're trying to solve better. If we need
to grow, what are the most efficient ways to
grow? What are the trade-offs that we have to
make? Where are their pockets of opportunity?
That is what I expect my team to be able to
bring to that table, the proverbial table,
that we want to see that. And in order to earn
their spot, that's the deal. We get the seat
at the table and we need to earn it by bringing
opportunities that we all can go and go after.
Awesome. So in a sense, it is embedded. They're
embedded in cross-functional teams across the org,
but they report up to essential
org to you essentially in the end?
Yeah.
Cool. What are some of the
benefits of this approach?
Oh, there's so many. Okay, so the first thing
is a consistent and high talent bar. I think
this is something I saw when we would have some
pockets of analytics folks embedded is having a
consistent bar for talent in terms of what we're
looking for, what are the technical skills,
what are the soft skills? And being able to
evaluate candidates with that same bar, using
our same rubric. You just get more consistent
and higher talent in my opinion. I think
that's number one. Number two is actually growth
opportunities. So if you're siloed, you may be the
most senior data person within... I keep picking
on marketing. But you might be the most senior
data scientist within marketing. Where do you go
from there? I think when you have the central org,
you're able to see if there are growth
opportunities in other areas within the company.
And so that really helps folks to stay engaged
because they can look at new problems if the
problems they've been working on for several
years are getting maybe boring and they want
something new, there's an opportunity, move
from marketing over to merchant analytics.
And then I think similarly, if there isn't a
promotion or room to grow, if you want to be
a people manager and there just isn't a people
management role within your functional area,
well, you've got 10 other ones to look at and
maybe there is that opportunity. So I think it
helps with the growth opportunities for the team,
which helps to retain talent. So that's a second
thing. The third thing is just consistency of
methodologies and metrics. So you don't have
sales that was as defined by one team and sales
as defined by another team. You just have sales
and everybody is using the same metrics, the same
methodologies, and you're able to improve your
methodologies with input from more people.
And rather than recreating the wheel,
building the same churn prediction model on six
different teams. You can instead build one and
have the input of six different teams. I think
that's definitely another benefit. Also helps
you just scale because you start to see the same
problems across teams and so you're like, "Ooh,
this is an issue that we need to get ahead of.
This is something we need to automate," or, "This
is something that we need to improve upon," or,
"a problem that is going to grow as our business,
as our teams scales." So I think it helps
you see around corners a little bit more.
And then just lastly, there's a team culture
brand. I think that's really important,
not just externally for recruiting top talent,
but the team is really proud to be members of
the analytics team. We have a unique culture
of learning, of sharing. You have someone you
can go to talk about your challenges. You have
someone who can peer review your work. I think
just having that team culture that we have is
really important. And it's a lot harder to get
when you have the individual silos, particularly
in an earlier stage when it's a smaller team,
you just don't have as many people around.
Everybody wants to have friends at work and
we're creating an environment where
they can find like-minded data nerds.
It makes me think about Airbnb's first data
team. I don't know if you know Riley Newman
well, but he built Airbnb's first
data team and it was actually an
analytics team. They called themselves
the 'A-Team' on the point of culture,
and that always felt a lot of fun and
they loved being part of that team.
Yeah. We have the same, but now I feel a lot
less special for coming up with that name.
Oh, you called it A-Team also?
Yeah, we got the A-Team, yeah.
And then I think they moved away from it when
there was a push. Now we're data scientists,
we're not analytics or analysts.
And that was like, I don't know,
10 year ago, like [inaudible 00:15:08]
data science. We're data scientists.
We'll always be the A-Team.
There's so many threads I want to follow
here, one that's a tangent, but something
that I think a lot of people struggle with is
you talked about how you want your data team,
your analytics team to be proactive, to
find opportunities, to give you ideas,
to help you figure out what to build, not
just answer questions. At the same time,
there are many questions that teams need to
get answered. Do you have any advice for just
how to set up a team where they both find time to
explore, dig, show opportunities and come up with
big ideas and also, "Hey, we just need to figure
out the funnel conversion on this thing," or "Hey,
what do you think? What's happening
in China right now?" Thoughts there?
Yeah, such a good question. I think it's something
that never gets easier. You have to be very
intentional to carve out time for exploratory
work for deep dives because as you mentioned,
there are always more questions and more work
to be done than hours in the day. And so I think
being intentional about it and setting goals for
your team around finding these insights through
self-directed work is an important mechanism for
holding ourselves accountable to that goal because
it tends to be the first thing that goes when you
get a lot of inbounds, you're like, "All right,
well, let's deep dive on something that I don't
know if it's really something. It could be high
ROI, it could be low ROI, I don't know." So
the expected value is lower than this known
thing that I can deliver and make someone happy.
So I think to prevent that time from just slipping
away, you really have to be intentional. We
would do hackathons for our team to carve out
days to just go and look into these really
interesting things and find opportunities.
And I think we have the support of our business
partners because so many great insights have come
from these deep dives and it really has been
some of the work that drives future roadmaps.
So they're always really great at allowing us to
have this time and actually encourage us often
to have this time for some self-directed
work, to go find the next big opportunity.
If there's no answer that comes to mind,
that's totally cool. But is there an example
of one of these insights that someone on the
data team came up with that led to something
big for DoorDash that you're able to share?
So one interesting example was from a hackathon we
did a couple of years ago where we were looking at
referral as a channel for consumer acquisition.
And when you compare that channel to others,
it was below average in terms of the engagement
you'd see from consumers who came through that
channel and the payback period. And rather than
just lowering spend on referrals and moving right
along, we really wanted to understand what
was happening. And so during the hackathon,
we did a deep dive into referral. We actually
tried referring each other. We tried committing
referral fraud, creating new accounts to
get around rules. And we uncovered a lot
of fraudulent behavior through this deep dive. We
ordered so many cupcakes to the office. I remember
using referral credits because you had to place
an order to be able to get the referral bonus.
So we would create the account, place the
orders, and we just kept ordering cupcakes.
And what we noticed was that referral as
a channel was a bit misleading when you
would look at the average in terms of payback
and that it was really a bimodal distribution
and you had one group of really great consumers
who were referring other really great consumers,
and the payback on those consumers was really
strong. In fact, if that's all you saw,
you would spend a lot more on that channel.
And then what was happening was you had this
other group of consumers that were not as good
people who were posting referral codes online
and getting people who were just in it to get
free discounts and credits. And we had at that
point in time, pretty lax fraud rules. And we
didn't have caps on these things. All of which
came about from this deep dive where we found
that this group of consumers was really a drag
on the efficiency of this marketing channel. And
so I think that's an example of a few things that
we like to do at DoorDash. One being these deep
dives and taking the time to really understand
the problem and then ultimately make a bunch
of recommendations for what we should do,
including better fraud checks, caps on referrals,
et cetera, et cetera. But also how the average
can be incredibly misleading. And so looking at
distributions and trying to break down what you're
seeing to find ways that you can optimize
in ways that you can gain in efficiencies.
That's an awesome story, great memory to come up
with that one. So this is a really good example
of a way to carve out time for the data team to
think long-term, think look for opportunities,
find big ideas. So the hackathon is one idea.
Imagine many data people are struggling often
to push back on asks that are just like, "h, we
need to know. We just need this one thing. Here's
a question, just answer this one question part."
Do you have any advice to data to get better at
pushing back? Sounds like a bit of cultural like,
"We have time, we need to work on these bigger
things." But just any advice for data leaders or
data ICs to find time for these sorts of things?
Yeah, saying no to someone is never fun. I
think as a self-proclaimed people-pleaser,
you don't want to say no, especially when it's
something you can do and you know that you can
very easily with maybe an hour's work, make
someone happy. I think it's really important
to establish a culture and for leadership
to really establish the rules of working
and that operating model so that some of the
junior folks aren't forced to always have to
say no. And I think one of the ways we do that
is through our goaling. So because our goals
are the same as our business partners,
we're able to pretty easily say, "Hey,
we've got a limited amount of time. These are
our goals. What are the most important things
that we are going to work on this week or this
month in order for both of us to hit our goals?"
And so when something comes up to be able to say,
"Hey, this data poll that you want me to do, is
this more important than these other three things
that I was going to be working on? Yes or no?" And
I think sometimes people don't necessarily realize
the trade-offs, and when you make them apparent
and you put them front and center, they realize
that, "Oh, actually, you know what? That asset's
not important. That can wait." So I think that
that's definitely something I would recommend,
which is always share the trade-offs. Don't
suffer in silence with, "How am I going to do
all four of these things?" Bring it up and say,
"Hey, this is what I was planning to do. If you
want me to do this extra new thing, then one
of these other things is going to have to drop.
I personally don't think that your ask is more
important than these three things, but maybe
there's new information, maybe there's context I
don't have, so let's talk about it." Rather than
just being like, "No, I won't do that." That's
not a great approach either. I think having the
conversation and constantly reevaluating your
prioritization to make sure you're working
on the most important things or your team is
working on the most important things is really
good hygiene to have with your business partner.
So some teams do that through a weekly standup
like, "Here's what we're going to do this week.
Do we like this prioritization? Do we not?" Some
folks do it less formally than that. I think
you got to figure out what works for you. But
to the earlier point, it's a conversation with
your engineering partner, your product partner,
your ops partner, you're all on the same team,
you're all trying to achieve the same goals and
you're all incentivized to have your analytics
team working on the most impactful things.
This advice is great for any role basically.
And if I were to summarize it to a couple words,
it's just prioritize and communicate what your
priorities are and then align on the
trade-offs of shifting your priorities.
Every once in a while you
just throw one over and say,
"You know what? This is quick. I'll do it." At
least I do. I think sometimes just knock it out,
build some goodwill. I think that that's also
important. But usually it's not something
you can do in five minutes and in that case
it's that ruthless prioritization for sure.
And then there's also the side that you
talked about of just show that you can
provide value doing these things that are
longer term, like prove your worth. "Hey,
look at all these opportunities
I found for our team over time,
I should keep spending time on these
other areas," versus the on fire stuff.
Exactly.
When you're hiring people for your team,
I'm curious what you look for and you
think is incredibly important that maybe
other people aren't prioritizing as much.
What do you focus on when you're hiring?
Yeah. So everybody needs to have a certain set of
technical skills. I think that's a non-starter. We
have a technical bar, we do a technical screen.
So I think that's table stakes. There's some
really unique characteristics that I've noticed
when I look at some of the top talent that I've
had on the team or have on the team. I think
the first thing is just curiosity. You can't
teach curiosity, or at least I haven't found
a way to do it. If somebody else knows how,
please let me know. Somebody who is just
self-motivated to pull on the threads when they
find them. So they don't just answer a question.
They're like, "Hmm, this thing seems a little odd.
I'm going to dig in and look. Even though I could
say I'm done, I answered the question, I did the
thing I was going to do." The person that has
that curiosity, something seems off, something
doesn't really make sense and goes and proactively
looks into what that is. That is just so valuable.
So I really look for that curiosity and that
self-motivation to do it without being told.
How do you test for that? How do you do that in
an interview and get a sense
of if they're good at that?
One way you can do it through the questions
you ask is have something that is not quite
right within the case that you're presenting
and see if people notice first and foremost.
And even if they don't, if you point it out
like, "Where do they go with that?" I think
that that's something that you can test for.
I think you can also ask for examples that for
these folks typically will highlight this,
they'll talk about, "I noticed this thing,
and so we decided to investigate." So I think
that there are ways that you can get that signal
through the interview process, but it's really
hard. I think testing for hard skills is a lot
easier than testing for soft skills. And
I think in some of the questions we ask,
we'll ask a question with the idea that we're
assessing something separate than what the
question is necessarily asking. And I think that
this is one example of where that really works.
You said that you give them a case.
What does that look like? What is
the actual approach to how you do this interview?
Our interview process has in the early stages a
coding exercise. So we do our technical screen
and a shortened version of a business case.
So real world problem solving. Typically,
it's something actually from DoorDash history,
like a real problem that we had to see how people
can problem solve on the fly. I think that that's
an important skill to be able to have, which is,
how do you take a problem, break it down,
talk through it. A little bit like some of
those consulting cases that you hear about,
but something that's really rooted in real
problems. And I think you can learn a lot from
those types of cases where, yes, you get to see
how people handle ambiguity and structured problem
solving, but ultimately most people get something
wrong. They make an assumption that's wrong
because well, I would hope that the interviewer
knows the business better than the interviewee.
And seeing how people react to being told they're
wrong is a really important signal in my opinion.
Seeing how people respond, how they're able to
take new information and pivot, how they're able
to make a decision. So that's another thing that
I like to see in cases where, hey, you may not
know the real right decision. You might say, "Hey,
I could see it going one way, I could see it going
the other way." But I always push people to say,
"If you had to make a call right now, what
would it be?" So are people able to have a
point of view without full information because
that's life. Sometimes you have to just pick
a direction and make a decision even though
you don't have perfect information. So I like
to see some of these softer skills and how
they manifest throughout a case interview,
even if it's not specifically what I'm asking with
the literal problem we're solving in the case.
Along these lines, but in a different direction.
You don't actually have a deep data science
data background before you got into this
stuff. I know you had some art background,
you had an art portfolio back in school, and
I think a lot of people wouldn't imagine that
for someone being head of analytics for a company
like DoorDash. I don't exactly know the question,
but I guess is there anything there that you think
would be interesting for people to know or hear?
Yeah, it's funny. I joke that I have a job
I'd never be hired for because I don't have a
traditional data science background. And I know
that Elizabeth Stone on her podcast with you
talked a lot about her non-traditional background
for a CTO. So hey, maybe there's something to it.
But I became a data scientist out of necessity. I
completely self-taught in terms of SQL and Python
and I did it because there was a need at DoorDash
for someone to help figure out what the right
goals were, how we set those goals, how we were
performing different markets early in the DoorDash
story, so 10 years ago at this point. And I think
I just gravitated towards that type of work and
Tony recognized that superpower in me even though
I don't have that formal training. So yeah,
I'm a bit of an artist for fun, but I guess
a data scientist in practice or for career.
But I think that that non-traditional background
has been a great thing because I'm able to hire
people who have the technical skills that I don't
have, the folks with PhDs in statistics and the
data scientists, machine learning and otherwise.
I am able to hire those folks and yet keep them
really focused on driving business impact because
my background was on the finance side, and so
I've always been a pragmatist. And for me, the
purpose of our team is to drive business impact.
And so the mix between the technical skills of the
smarter people that I've hired, the smarter than
myself, and my grounding in driving business
impact has been a really great partnership.
That's quite an inspiring story for
someone that is just starting out and
doesn't necessarily have a lot of experience
in data, but also just generally. I think
this is a really cool example. You could
be successful in a field that you don't
have a ton of background in. I'm curious
what you think it was in you that allowed
you to succeed in this and get to where you
are today. What do you think you did right or
what is some habits or ways of thinking
that you think helped you achieve that?
First off, I have imposter syndrome like everybody
else. So it's not like I have this crazy sense of
confidence of like, "Oh, I can do anything."
I definitely have the same doubts that others
have. I think part of it was probably not even
realizing what I was doing. When you're at a
startup and things are moving quickly and you see
a problem, and I've always liked solving problems,
so I was like, "All right, how do I solve this
problem?" It was like, "Oh, well, I need access
to the data. I don't have access to the data. All
right, I'll ask an engineer to get me the data.
Well, this isn't going to scale. I can't always
bother an engineer, so how do I figure out how to
get the data myself? Well, let's learn Python." So
I think it happened organically and I don't think
I realized at the time what I was even doing.
And then I think if you think about things from
first principles about what you need right now
in front of you to unblock yourself or solve a
problem, and you just focus on that instead of
thinking about a global org that you're trying
to build. I think that that helps. So for me, it
was always about solving the problem in front of
me the best way I could. And if that meant I
needed to hire an engineer to report into me
through the finance org, then that was what we
were going to do and nobody was going to tell
me I couldn't do it. So I think it's a belief
in yourself, and ultimately it's just my desire
to solve problems and figure out what has to get
done is, I think, ultimately how it came about.
I love that so much. There's so many
elements there that I think a lot of
people can learn from. I feel like there's
also this underlying current of you're
just motivated for this to work. You wanted
DoorDash to succeed, and you're just like,
"I will do what I need to do to make this happen.
I need to solve these problems. I'm not going to
overthink. Do I have the skills necessarily
to do these things [inaudible 00:33:48]?"
Yeah, I think I'm competitive. I think
that's a trait that you find in a lot of
early DoorDash folks and current DoorDash
folks, to be honest, just wanting to win
and being willing to do whatever you
need to win. So roll up your sleeves,
do something that's not your job. I think back to
early days of taking out the garbage on Saturday
nights because it needed to get done. I think
that that was something that is ingrained in
our culture from Tony Xu, from our founder and
CEO, and I think that really resonated with me,
and I feel like I've always operated that way
as well. And I think that that helped me in
my career to be able to do what I've done
without really thinking about it too much.
Are there any other memories or stories of
the early days of DoorDash that would be fun
to share? Something that sticks with you of like,
"Wow, I can't believe that's what it was like?"
Oh man, there's so many, including so
many mistakes that we've made. But I
think something that really stands out to
me is before I moved to the analytics area,
I was actually a GM. I was the first GM at
DoorDash and I was in Boston in 2014 launching
the city of Boston when nobody knew who we
were. And we would wake up early in the morning,
5 A.M. and we would go out, it was the winter of
2014. We'd go out and we'd hand out promo codes
consumers outside of the [inaudible 00:35:30] in
Boston, and these promo cards would be attached
to kind bars so people would take them.
And the whole team, it was a small team,
there were four of us, but the whole team would
go out in the morning to do this. And I think
back to our sales guy, shout out to Joey G.
So Joe Graccio is our sales guy in Boston-
[inaudible 00:35:47] Joey G.
And he was gold on signing
merchants on the platform.
That was how he was gold. His
compensation was tied to that.
And yet in the morning when we would go out, he
was with us handing out promo codes because he
was part of the team because he wanted to win.
We wanted to grow the business. And I think that
that is just a great example of the culture that
Tony and the early employees and Stanley and Andy,
other co-founders really instilled in all of
us early in those days. So I think that that
ownership, that extreme ownership of the
outcome is definitely one of the things.
I think the other is just being very customer
first. And I say customer, I mean consumers,
dashers and merchants as all being our
customers. And the first time I ever went
to the office headquarters in Palo Alto, which
at the time was in an animal hospital. The first
time I went there, there was a huge site outage
and the whole company, it was like 20 people
at the time, the whole company jumped online to
do customer support, to answer the phones, to make
sure that folks were getting refunds for orders
that weren't going through, make sure the orders
that were out there were getting delivered, just
dropped everything and hopped on to do support.
And I was brand new, didn't really know
how to use the tools, and so it was like,
"How can I be useful?" And so back in those
days, we used to order dinner to the office using
DoorDash. And so in order to preserve about three
dashers who would've had to deliver food to us,
I was like, "I'm going to go out, go out dashing,
go get everyone pizza so that we could feed the
masses doing credits and refunds and do what
we had to to make sure that we were serving
our customers well." And I think that night
was one of the largest refunds as a percent
of our bank account that we had ever given out.
And I think Tony, there were two examples that
he's talked about where we just gave a lot
of money back to customers because it was
the right thing to do because our service
failed and we wanted to do right by them.
So I think that those are two stories that stick
out in my mind and really highlight culturally
what makes DoorDash unique and what I think has
been a really important part of our success.
It reminds me of the story that Tony and all the
early employees, and I imagine you did this just
like, "We're dashers," it's like a rotation where
you dash for a while. Is that part of the culture?
Yeah, so we have a program, a WeDash program, and
Keith Yandell, who's our chief business officer,
did your podcast last year and he talked about
this. But four times a year all the employees
go out and go dashing or do customer support, and
it's part of our culture that I love. I actually
go pair dashing, so I go together with one of
my colleagues. We've done it for years now,
and it's a fun thing that we do together
four times a year. Actually, usually more
than that. And it's important because you get
to use the product, you build empathy with all
the audiences. I think all of us order DoorDash
a lot, so we've built empathy with consumers. But
being able to go and understand what it's like to
go out dashing and when you're in the restaurant
going and talking with merchants and seeing the
experience from their point of view, I think it's
just incredibly important. And of course we find a
lot of bugs like, "Hmm, this doesn't work the way
it should, let me report this." So I think it's
also just great for catching bugs in the product.
This episode is brought to you by Attio, a
radically new type of CRM. There's a world
where your CRM is powerful, easily configured,
and deeply intuitive. Attio makes that a reality.
Attio is built specifically for the next era
of companies. It syncs with your data sources,
easily configures to their unique structures and
works for any go-to-market motion from self-serve
to sales led. Attio automatically enriches
your contacts, syncs your e-mail and calendar,
gives you powerful reports and lets you
quickly build Zapier style automations.
The next era of companies deserves more than an
inflexible one-size-fits-all CRM. Join modal,
replicate 11 labs and more, and scale
your startup to the next level. Head to
at attio.com/Lenny and you'll get 15% off
your first year. That's attio.com/Lenny.
I want to come back to a thread, something
you mentioned where you and a lot of the
early team had felt extreme ownership over
the company and that's why a lot of this
stuff happened. For people, every founder,
every product team, they're going to like,
"Yes, we need that. Let's make sure everyone
on the team feels extreme ownership." Is there
anything that you think that the early
team did to create that or is it hiring,
just pick people that will have that
feeling already, or is cultural?
I think it's both. It's definitely cultural.
I think it comes from the top and I think that
Tony exhibits this extreme ownership and looks
for it in others. So I think that helps. But I
think even today I expect of my team that same
extreme ownership over the outcomes. And so I'm
more interested in our team figuring out how
to solve a problem than the box that someone
fits in like, "I'm a data scientist and so
I only do these things." Right? It's like,
"No. I mean, yes, you are a data scientist, but
your goal is to figure out what's happening,
and if that means that you're going to
pick up the phone and call customers,
then that is what you're going to do." And I
think that expecting that and setting that as
the norm for the team, this ownership of the
outcome is something that we continue to do
at DoorDash and instill in everyone whether
you were early or just joined last month.
Is there an example of that that comes to
mind of someone practicing extreme ownership,
like a data scientist calling someone
or something along those lines?
Yeah, so I actually had a meeting yesterday
morning with the team that's working on some
of our affordability initiatives and we had
shipped something that we expected to work,
and it didn't. And instead of, "You can dig
into the data," to understand the segments of
consumers that you would expect it to work with
and those that it wouldn't, of course we did
that. But ultimately it was like, "I don't know
why." And that's where qualitative research is
superior to quantitative research, it's asking
for the context, to actually talking to people
to figure out what was the motivation, what
worked, what didn't for them. And so the team,
data scientists included, just sat and made phone
calls. And so they were talking about what they
found from those phone calls and that's going
to inform future decisions. And I think rather
than saying, "Well, that's what the qualitative
research team is supposed to do," it's like, "No,
no, no, that is what our team, anyone's team
is supposed to do because that's what's needed
to unblock us from this next test that we want to
run because we need to know what we are testing."
So I think that it happens every day. I think I
really love when I see team members go outside the
traditional bounds of what a data science role
might be and do some product management work,
do some engineering work. I think that that's
part of what keeps the job interesting. I
think it's part of what makes our team
special is that that is not only allowed,
it's encouraged, and probably also a reason
why we've had folks who've gone from my team
to the product org and to the ops org and to
the finance org is because they get to do and
experience parts of that job and get a good
sense for what that's like and then realize
it's something that they love. So I think it's
definitely something we encourage at DoorDash.
I love that. I want to move in
a slightly different direction.
One of your colleagues told me that you
are incredibly good at defining metrics,
which is so important to get right for a business,
especially when it's complex at DoorDash. And I
hear you're especially good at finding the
right metric to drive the right incentive,
especially when the business is really messy
and things like that. So I'm just curious
what you've learned about how to pick
good metrics and align incentives well.
I've learned a lot of things about metrics, mostly
from bad metrics. I actually think you learn a lot
from picking the wrong metric. Ultimately, you
want to find a short-term metric you can measure
that drives a long-term output. So people always
talk about, "Oh, we want to drive an improvement
in retention." Retention is a terrible thing to
goal on because it's almost impossible to drive
in a meaningful way in the short term, and yet
you want to be able to experiment and iterate
quickly. So what are the things that drive
retention? What are the inputs? So I think
it's really important to find the right inputs,
and then through experimentation test whether
or not those short-term inputs are driving the
long-term output that you're looking for. I think
that's one thing. I think keeping things simple
is another thing I've learned over the years,
maybe it's data scientists, but they tend to
love these composite metrics with a coefficient.
"We're going to wait this input at X and this
input at X+2." And then you end up with a
metric that nobody really understands that doesn't
actually mean anything. And you're like, "I don't
know if a 0.1 increase is it a lot? Is it good?
Is it bad?" So they're just hard to work with.
And so I always encourage folks, just pick
something simple, even if it's not perfect
and your composite would be more perfect. If
people understand it, if they have an intuition
around it, if it's something that people can talk
about across the company, it's going to be a much
better metric in terms of driving real outcomes
than your made up composite score that nobody
understands. So I think keeping things simple is
also really important. And then I think the last
thing I'll say is it's important to understand how
metrics across the company equate to one another.
And so we spend a lot of time quantifying things
in terms of a common currency. So for example,
if I were to lower price by a dollar, what would
I get in terms of, we'll say, volume? Well, what
if I lowered delivery times by a minute? What do
I get for that in terms of volume? And so now you
can make trade-offs between maybe your marketing
team and your logistics team because you have this
common currency that everyone can talk about. And
so we've done that. We've tried to quantify all
of the levers of our business, price, selection,
quality in common terms, so that if we have, say,
a dollar to spend, we know what we get depending
on where we put it, over what timeframe. I think
that that helps us make decisions more quickly
because we know what our options are. We know
we have our inventory of things that we can do,
short-term, long-term, and what we get for it.
So it definitely helps us to make decisions
more quickly and hopefully better decisions.
These are so awesome. I definitely want to
follow up on some of this. This is so good. So
maybe on this last one, which we did at Airbnb
also like, how does everything translate into
Knight's book and booking? Every decision we
make, what is the actual Knight's book impact?
And so I imagine in your case, I don't know if
you want to talk about these things. I imagine
it's transactions, or purchases, or GMB or
something like that, so I'm guessing is the
final metric. I don't know. Is that something
you talk about or you don't talk about that?
We measure things in terms of GOV, so
Gross Order Value, and also volume.
Got it. [inaudible 00:48:34]. Okay, so basically
every other metric that people are gold on as much
as you can translate, there's a model that
translates that into Gross Order Value and
volume? Awesome. So when a team is saying,
"Hey, we're going to change the onboarding
flow and impact conversion here." I don't know.
I guess what are some examples of other metrics
on teams that potentially translate into GOV
and volume just to make it even more real?
Yeah. So everything from the example that you
started with, which is an improvement in the
login flow, how many more consumers are getting
onto the app and ultimately placing orders. And
so you can translate that to, of course, orders
and GOV. But then something as interesting as
selling a Thai restaurant in Sacramento, we're
able to say, "What do we think that that gets
us in terms of GOV from the consumer by selling
that Thai restaurant?" So it's every area of the
business, it's mobilizing more dashers on
the road. What does that do to our quality
metrics in terms of delivery times? How
does that translate? So because of that,
we're able to figure out if we want to spend
the dollar or spend the time, the team's time,
on improving conversion or spending more money
in marketing or onboarding more dashers or
signing more restaurants or adding more grocery
stores. So we are able to look across the whole
business and figure out what is the right
mix of actions to take to achieve our goals.
I could see as you talk about this why this
is so important in a marketplace, especially
a multi-sided marketplace where there's always
trade-off decisions between supply investment
and demand growth and dasher growth. I don't even
know, my brain would explode trying to think about
all these things, so I get exactly why this is so
important to business. Okay. And then in terms of
the simple recommendation, I think when people
hear like, "Yeah, keep it simple," they're like,
"Yeah, yeah, we're going to keep it simple."
What are some things that point to, "This is
not simple," that tell you like, "No, this is
way too complicated. You should try to simplify
this metric even though it's not ideal. It's not
the perfect metric, but it needs to be simpler."
Yeah. So we had a score for merchant
health, which we tried experimenting with,
which was a combination of factors that we
had found would lead to a merchant being on
the platform and getting an order. So we wanted
to make sure that the merchant had active hours
on the platform and had images and had a full
menu that was accurate and robust. A number of
different inputs. And we created a composite
that weighted all of these different inputs.
And then we were like, "What is our merchant
health score?" And you were like, "It's 0.35.
It's not 35%. So what is that, that 0.35? I
don't know what it is." So instead of that,
we said, "What are the most important factors
in order... First, let's measure how many of
the new merchants are getting an order within
their first, say, seven days on the platform.
And then let's look at how many of our merchants
are doing these things we know are important. So
these inputs. So let's goal our team on getting
merchant photo coverage up. Let's goal the team
on making sure that we have open hours, accurate
hours." So yes, someone might say it's simpler to
have a composite metric, but it was so hard to
understand what it was and how to move it that
it became meaningless. And ultimately moving
to something that was simpler to understand,
even if it meant having three metrics instead
of one, it ultimately was better for the team
because folks knew what they were trying to
move. And so yeah, maybe we missed number four,
five and six on the list of things, but you got
one through three and that's 95% of it anyway.
So once we get success with that 95, then
let's talk about figuring out the other 5%.
It's so funny because this is exactly
what we went through at Airbnb, we had,
we call that a healthy host. I led the
host quality team for a while and we came
up with this healthy host metric that was six
factors of a host, like the cancellation rate,
the review rate, their response rate and
things like that. And then we're just like,
"Cool, let's move this, let make more hosts
healthy." And then you end up like, "Okay,
which one do we focus on?," And, "Oh, what
about all these others?" And we ended up
basically focusing on one at a time. And so let's
just make that the goal for now and then rotate
through the different biggest [inaudible 00:53:28]
opportunities to move. [inaudible 00:53:30].
Exactly. I think in hindsight for the example
you give, which of those six things are actually
the most important? And if you're able to then
quantify which one matters most, you work on that
one first and you materially move that one and
then you work on the next one. You want to move
them all. But being able to prioritize and know
what you're going to get for a 20% improvement in,
say, your cancellation rate, that's where
analytics I think can add a lot of value.
Because yes, ultimately you'll get to all of
them, but the way you do that and the time can
have a meaningful impact on your growth. If you
can target the most problematic things first and
solve those, you get more bang for your buck
and that compounds over time. And so doing the
things that matter first and most quickly
is a competitive advantage in my opinion.
The other thing we found along those same lines
is rotating between different metrics is so not
efficient because you get good at, "We're going
to move this metric." And your team's like,
"Cool, we totally understand this
lever," like cancellation rate. We
become really smart at cancellation
rate and then three months later,
you need to switch to response rate and they
have to learn a whole new paradigm of how to
think about it. And it's just super inefficient.
So we found basically, just keep a team on the
metric until there's no more opportunities and
give another team one of these other metrics.
Yeah.
So many lessons. Okay. And the first thing you
said on how to pick a good metric about this idea
of short-term metrics that have long-term
impact. How did you phrase that again?
Yeah, so we find proxy metrics
for long-term outcomes.
Awesome. And it's similar to the simple
metric, and it all comes down to, again,
just like the metric should be something
probably, you can move, you can understand,
that's close enough to this ideal, perfect metric,
but isn't necessarily the entire ideal. Okay,
awesome. Anything else along these
lines of just picking metrics,
working with metrics that you've learned
that would be worth [inaudible 00:55:28]?
With metrics, we are often looking at the average,
and I think we talked about this a little bit
earlier, but making sure that you're looking at
the edge cases and your fail states is also
really important. And so we often will set
goals actually and create metrics around those
edge cases. So like the disaster deliveries,
the ones that go terribly wrong. So we
have this concept of Never Delivered,
which is orders that are never delivered. We're
really great at naming things at DoorDash,
and they're very rare. And so if you were just
looking at the average effect or the average
consumer experience, it would never come up. If
you were just measuring quality based on average
values of delivery times and lateness [inaudible
00:56:18], these wouldn't show up because they are
so rare, but they're terrible. They're terrible
experiences for consumers. They lead to churn.
They're incredibly expensive because you're
refunding an order or repurchasing food and having
to send another dasher to deliver that repurchased
food. So they're very expensive, they're costly
from a consumer experience standpoint. And I think
if you're not looking for these fail states, they
are often missed. So I think when you're picking
metrics, yes, you want to improve engagement and
you want to improve conversion, and there's a lot
of things that are averages overall that you want
to move, but it's so important to find these
edge cases in these fail states and actually
set concrete goals around eliminating
them because it can be really powerful.
So the tip here is actually make that a goal like,
never deliver at some team,
just keep cutting that down?
Exactly. So we have part of our quality analytics
team and we have product engineering and ops on
it as well. Their goal is to eradicate Never
Delivered. And in order to do that, you have to
understand why they happen. Sometimes it's human
error, sometimes it's fraud. And then figure out
ways that you can prevent them, that you can fix
them while it's happening and ultimately just
get rid of them from the system. And you're
never going to completely get rid of them,
but you can make a meaningful impact to make
them even more rare than a fraction of a percent.
Yeah. And I feel like people may be hearing
this and like, "Of course, why would you not
focus on terrible work experiences?" But I think
in most companies, they look at the big numbers,
they look at the averages as you said like, "Oh,
it almost never happens. Why do we even spend any
time on this?" And your point is, you should
actually spend time on these really terrible
experiences, even if it's a tiny portion
of your business. I guess maybe share why
that's important. Is it just because that
has trickle-down effects on the brand?
Yeah, I think it's a couple of things. So just
because something doesn't happen frequently
doesn't mean that it's not important. So
the Never Delivered example is a great one
in that this is leading directly to churn
and it's also costing a lot of money far
more than its frequency would suggest. And I
think the fact of the matter is is when you
have things that cause churn, you're losing
all of that consumer's subsequent orders,
and that is not necessarily observed. You're just
seeing one bad experience, you're not seeing all
of the lost orders because they're lost. And
so I think that sometimes this is an area where
the data doesn't show you the full picture. And
being able to quantify the impact on engagement,
on profitability, will make it stand out
as something that really, that you would
maybe miss if you weren't really looking for it.
And then I think the other thing is with something
like login errors, sometimes you don't see it
in the data because people can't even get into
the data. If you're not able to log in, you're
not making any purchases, you're not ordering,
and so you may not see it in the data that you're
looking at. And so that's also something that I
think is important for data folks to think about,
which is what data don't we have? What data might
we be missing? Where might there be opportunities
and things that we actually need to identify and
fix that we may not see? Because in this case,
with login failures, they're not able to log
in. They're not in the denominator, and so we're
missing out on them from the data set entirely.
Just a couple of more questions. There's
one that I skipped that I'm just going to
come back to. It's completely out of nowhere,
but I think it might be interesting is about
a global data org. So you run a global data
org, you have data scientists and analysts
and biz ops people all over the world, not just
the US. I'm curious just how is it different
managing data people in different countries
versus just the US? What's a big difference?
Everyone always asks about the differences. What
I am surprised by is how similar things are,
how similar people are, the data scientists
themselves, but also consumers and dashers
and couriers, as we call them at Volt. There's a
lot more similarities than differences. I do think
that when you built a business in the
US and then you introduce new countries,
having different currencies and different
languages adds complexity that you weren't
necessarily familiar with. I think similarly in
EU countries versus non-EU countries in Europe,
there's different regulation. So that adds a fun
layer of complexity. So I do think that it adds
complexity to the problem set, but ultimately
so many of the problems are the same. It feels
a little bit like going into a test having seen
the answer key. And so for me, there are problems
we've encountered at Volt through Volt analytics
where I'm like, "Oh, we've had a similar problem.
I have an instinct for what the answer
might be. Let's still test because there
could be differences cultural or otherwise,
but I feel like I know where we're going to
end." And then sometimes there are problems
where it's new for one reason or another,
and it's exciting because you're like, "All right,
let's see if things are different here." Let's see
what ideas might work in a Volt country that don't
work in a DoorDash country and vice versa. So I
think I tend to focus more on what's the same,
and then I'm pleasantly surprised when I find
things that are different because that keeps
you on your toes and keeps things interesting.
I'm going to take us to AI Corner. This is
a segment we have in the podcast where I try
to understand how people are using AI in their
day-to-day and in their business. I'm curious
if you've found some really interesting
way of using AI ideally in... you can go
in either one of these directions, and how you
or your team work day-to-day using AI tools to
make you more efficient, or integrating AI
into your product, making DoorDash better.
Yeah, I think that there are opportunities
in both. I think one of the things I'm really
excited about is actually the former. So in
helping to make the team more productive,
we do something called Office Hours at
DoorDash, the analytics team. And it's
something that we started eight years ago,
and it was a way to provide support for teams
that at the time we just didn't have the bandwidth
to support. So we would go, in the early days,
we'd go sit in a room and we'd say, "Come on
in and we'll help you with anything you need
help with. We'll help teach you SQL. We'll help
look at some of your work. We'll be a thought
partner. You could just come learn what we're
working on." Whatever it was. We would do two
hours every week of Office Hours at different
times to be friendly to different time zones.
And I think one of the things I'm excited about
is being able to really empower some of the folks
that are still coming to Office Hours for one
thing or another to be able to use AI to help
edit queries on their own for example, to be able
to say, "Here's a query. I want to make this.
Please adjust this to our grocery business so that
I can see the GOV for grocery." And so working to
build these tools that will help not just our team
in terms of time saving, and also to be honest,
folks are going to use it on our team, but really
to be able to empower non-technical users to be
able to do things on their own and not have
to take up bandwidth for the analytics team.
So essentially it's a chatbot that
anyone in the company can talk
to you to get advice on how to write SQL
queries, query data and things like that?
Yeah.
Is there a clever name for
this chatbot per chance?
So it's not clever. It's called Ask Data AI,
and that's named for our internal Slack channel
that used to be the open Q&A for people
to ask data. So it's not at all clever.
But it's clear.
But again, it goes with the theme of very,
very specific naming conventions that we have
at DoorDash; Never Delivered and Ask Data AI.
I love it. Just clarity above all else.
That's something I've learned from an
editor that I work with. Jess, is there
anything else that you want to share or
leave listeners with? For folks that
are trying to build their data teams,
make their data teams more efficient, is there
any final wisdom nugget you'd want to share?
I think the only thing that I want to reiterate is
that you don't necessarily need a formal training
in whatever it is you're building. And I think
that also goes towards the folks that you hire
onto the team. And so I mentioned earlier
that we've had a lot of folks go to product
or go to ops from the team. What I didn't
mention is how many folks we've actually
had join the analytics team from partner teams.
So whether that was from engineering or from our
ops team or marketing or finance, we are a net
importer of talent as opposed to a net exporter
of talent. And I think that that's because my
own experience coming over from operations,
from being a GM and making that transition
into analytics, I find that I'm drawn to
other folks who want to make a similar transition.
Now again, you have to have the technical skills,
and most of these folks have acquired these
skills on the job, whatever job they are
doing at DoorDash before they transition to the
analytics team, or they had maybe some formal
training in school. But I love seeing the folks
that make that transition and actually want to
join the analytics team, even if they're not a
career or data scientist. I think it creates a
really unique environment where you have folks
on the team from different backgrounds with
different expertise who can teach each
other things. So I can teach you how to
build a discounted cash flow model in Excel,
and I can learn how to make kick-ass slides
from someone who has a background in consulting.
And I can learn about common gotchas in statistics
from someone who comes to us with a Master's or a
PhD in statistics, and we've got our econometrics
folks and we've got our economists. We just have
a group of people with different backgrounds
who can all teach each other how to be better.
And we're not all carbon copies of each other.
What I'm hearing is you try to optimize almost for
a lot of different complementary skills
and very different backgrounds almost.
Exactly. And also people who have experience at
different size companies. I think I love folks
from startups who have that hustle and grit, but
I also love folks who've seen what scale looks
like and can help us see around corners as far as
what problems we will encounter as the business
is growing. And I think it is not just about a
diversity of skill and a diversity of background,
it's also diversity of prior company
and stage. That can be really a unique
way to think about structuring your team
so that you get the best of both worlds.
Amazing. Well, just when you thought we were done,
we reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
I am. Let's do it.
Let's do it. Okay. First question,
what are two or three books that you've
recommended most to other people?
I tend to read fiction, particularly historical
fiction, and I love spy novels. So I think my
brain is always in problem-solving mode even
when reading. A recent book that I read that
I enjoyed was The Rose Code by Kate Quinn, and
it's about women code breakers in World War II,
and I really enjoyed that. But rather
than recommending a book... I guess I
did just recommend a book, but rather
than recommending another book, I am
going to recommend the Libby app and
supporting your local public library
because I love the library and I love Libby,
so I'll give that as my other recommendation.
Beautiful. Very on brand with sharing
economy, company stuff. Libby. Cool. Okay,
next question. Favorite recent movie or TV show?
Yeah, another one. I don't actually watch a
lot of TV, definitely don't watch a lot of
movies. In fact, haven't seen some of the movie
greats. I get yelled at a lot by my friend. "I
can't believe you haven't seen that." I tend
to re-watch things, so series from the past,
over and over again. I think it's just like how
I shut my brain off. So I've recently re-watched
The West Wing, which is one of my favorite
shows of all time, probably for the 50th time.
Oh my God.
And Alias, which was a Jennifer Garner
series from the early 2000s. Also,
Spy. So I'm noticing a theme. I think
I really love the spy genre. But yeah,
I've watched those. They're both
great, but not at all current.
Perfect. Perfectly acceptable.
Do you have a favorite product
that you recently discovered that you really love?
This is a bit of a curveball. So Korean
sunscreens. So I burn really easily, so I have
to wear sunscreen and I love Korean sunscreens.
I was introduced to them by a friend of mine,
and they're just far superior to what we have
in the US. So I highly recommend people give
Korean sunscreens a try, particularly there's a
Beauty of Joseon on branded sunscreen. It's just
amazing and is delightful to wear, which is
important when you have to wear it every day.
I've been trying to wear more sunscreen as I age,
and so this is a really good tip.
Was that a brand you recommended?
Yeah. So Beauty of Joseon is the brand.
Beauty of Joseon.
There's another brand, Isntree, which also
has a great sunscreen. But I'll be honest,
almost every Korean sunscreen I've tried is great.
Okay. I'm Googling this as soon as we get off. Do
you have a favorite life motto that you often come
back to and share and or share with family
and friends even more [inaudible 01:11:39]?
I do. So there's a John Steinbeck quote, which
I'm not big on quotes, but I like this one,
which is that, "It's a common experience that
a problem difficult at night is resolved in
the morning after the committee of sleep has
worked on it." I find that that's something I
really live by. First off, I love sleep and I
try to get as much of it as possible. But the
other thing is that if I'm stuck on a problem
or if I am writing a response to something
like a tense issue or an emotional issue,
often I find that if I put down my thoughts,
go to sleep, check it in the morning,
I end up with a better outcome. So
all of a sudden you have a new perspective
and clarity on a problem you were stuck on,
or you realize that you weren't clear in the way
you were communicating your thoughts because you
were emotional about something and you're
able to put together a much better response
to an e-mail or to whatever problem you're
handling. So sleep can solve lots of problems.
I love sleep as well. I'm always telling my wife,
"Let's go to sleep." Like, "Okay, I'll
be there soon." I love that advice. Okay,
two more questions. Who's influenced you most in
your career? Is there someone that comes to mind?
So I think two answers, a multi-part answer. So I
think first my career has been in male-dominated
industries and I've worked with just some
incredible women who've really influenced
me. When I was a banker, there were two senior
bankers, Vanessa Roberts and Gina Tarone at
Lehman Brothers where I worked. And they were just
so incredible. They were just so good at their
jobs and I found that really inspiring.
And then at DoorDash, Tia Sherringham,
who is our GC, and Liz Jarvis-Shean, who leads
comms, are just dominant in their fields. And I
think that that's really empowering and have been
big influences on me to just see strong, powerful
women kicking ass and that helps me believe
that I can do the same. So that's one answer.
And then the other answer, sort of cliche, but
my parents. My mom was a statistician at the
UN before she got married, and she actually
chose to stay home and raise three children,
so I'm the youngest. And when I was
in, I think it was elementary school,
decided to go back to school, switch careers
and become a nurse. And so the fact that she
embarked on this completely new career in her
forties after 15 years as a stay-at-home mom and
my father supported this. I think that that was
really, really influential and was probably the
first time I saw that you can do whatever you put
your mind to, no matter your age, no matter your
circumstances. So that was really influential and
I don't think I've ever told her that. So hi, Mom.
Hi Mom. Thank you, mom.
Yeah, I think that was influential
for my career. Definitely.
That's a beautiful answer. Fun fact,
I worked with Liz at Airbnb. Your person
you just mentioned in the comms team.
[inaudible 01:14:57]. She is great.
She's amazing. Final question.
So when you joined DoorDash,
imagine it wasn't obvious that it was going to
work. I imagine it was still like, "This was a
crazy idea. Maybe it'll work, maybe not." Is
there a moment you recall where you're like,
"I think this is going to be a big success?
I think this is actually going to work out?"
To be honest, I went into DoorDash because I
wanted to learn for the experience. I thought
it was interesting, problems with interesting
people. I never thought too much about whether
it would work. I of course wanted it to work
and was very competitive and wanted to win. I
think there's two moments that stand out.
One was when the third party market share
data showed that we had become the number one
player after, I think we started at number four
or five. And I think that that was really
exciting to see the trajectory and to see
us gain in category share. That was exciting.
I probably didn't see it until months after it
had happened because we don't spend a ton of time
focusing on it, but I do remember somebody wanted
to include the graph in some presentation,
some sales material, and we're like, "Oh,
we're number one. That's incredible. We used to
be number five." So I'd say that that was one.
The other one that stands out was, the first talk
I gave in a lot of these startup talks in the
early days in Boston, and I'd asked the audience,
"How many of you have used DoorDash?" And there'd
be like three people who would raise their hand.
And then it was a few years ago, maybe 2018, 2019,
and I was giving a talk and I asked the audience,
"How many of you have used DoorDash?" And almost
everyone's hands went up. And that was actually
pretty memorable for me because in my mind,
we were still the small startup that no one had
heard of where I had to over enunciate the D's
in DoorDash. So people didn't think I worked for
Jordash, the nineties' denim company. And so that
was pretty meaningful to me when just so many
people had used the product or were consumers
of DoorDash. It was pretty exciting. And I still
get excited. I saw DoorDash mentioned in a book
recently that I was reading. It was like,
"We're in the book." So those little things
when you become part of the cultural lingo
that I think are really, really special.
Well, I'm a very happy customer of DoorDash. I've
never had a Never Deliver. It's always there,
sometimes a little late. Usually it's perfect.
Thank you for everything you do. Go team DoorDash.
Two final questions. Where can folks find
you online if they want to follow stuff
that you do? I know you've been doing more
writing on LinkedIn and things like that,
so just help people understand where to find
you and how can listeners be useful to you?
Yeah, so as you mentioned, to find me
LinkedIn, I don't have a huge social presence,
but I am on LinkedIn and I am currently writing a
series of blog posts about my experience building
a global analytics org at DoorDash. Some
of the lessons I've learned over the last
10 years. So definitely check those out.
And as far as your second question of how
listeners can be useful to me, I guess read
the post on LinkedIn and I'd love to hear
what people think, whether you agree with my
point of view or not. That being said, be nice.
I want honest feedback, but I want kindness
as well. So yeah, just engage with the content
and let me know what y'all think. I think I do
have a broader ask, which is just to encourage
folks listening to TruthSeek, something I take
seriously at DoorDash. It's a company value.
But there's a lot of misinformation out there and
it's often up to us as individuals to figure out
what's fact and what's fiction. So I have a plea
for folks to do your best, to search for the truth
and speak the truth, and I think we'll all be
better off for it. And of course, use DoorDash.
Of course.
Yes, there are three things that listeners can do.
You're at DoorDash.com. That was awesome.
I love that last point as well in addition,
to use DoorDash. Jessica, thank
you so much for being here.
Thank you for having me. It was a lot of fun.
Same for me. Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much for listening.
If you found this valuable, you can
subscribe to the show on Apple Podcast,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.