I want to start with a quote by someone you
may know, Paul Graham, "Much of what's novel
about YC is due to Jessica Livingston. If you
don't know her, you don't understand YC."
My three co-founders were deeply technical, but
I would look at other things about founders.
All these little social cues.
Your nickname was the Social Radar.
Every interview, everyone always
turned to you and they're like,
"Jessica, what does their social radar say?"
I would look at, do the co-founders get along? Are
these people committed? And if a founder would
get defensive, that was always a bad sign.
Is there anything else along the Airbnb
story that would be interesting to share?
He hated their idea, and Paul tried to get Brian
and Joe and Nate to change it. But I remember
specifically Joe brought out the cereal boxes, the
Obama O's and Cap'n McCain's, and I just thought,
oh my God, they're going to work hard to do
whatever they can to make this company succeed.
You just talk a bit about this idea of just making
shit happen, showing signs of being hustlers.
Do you sort of need that desperation.
You have to burn the boat.
Today, my guest is Jessica Livingston. Jessica
is the co-founder of Y Combinator, the first and
most famous startup accelerator, which since 2005
has funded over 5,000 companies, including over
200 unicorns now worth over a billion dollars,
including companies like Airbnb, Stripe, DoorDash,
Coinbase, Dropbox, Instacart, Reddit, the list
goes on. Jessica is also the author of one of
the bestselling books about startups, Founders
at Work, and hosts the Social Radars Podcast.
She lives in England with her husband, who you may
know, and her two sons. In our conversation, we
dive deep into Jessica's superpower of being the
Social Radar. She got this nickname in the early
days of YC because she can read people incredibly
well. This becomes a huge unfair advantage when
you're evaluating and investing in early stage
startups and founders, but also becomes useful
in every part of your life. There's actually a
quiz that I'm going to link to in the show notes
called Reading the Mind in the Eyes that I suggest
you take to see how you do, and it'll give you a
sense of how well you are at reading people.
Jessica got a perfect score, just as an example
of her unique talents, reading people's emotions
along with her superpower and tips on how you can
develop your own social radar. We also talk about
her fabulous podcast called The Social Radars,
some wild early YC stories, including how the
interview with the Airbnb founders actually
went down, and so much more. If you enjoy this
podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow it
in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube.
It's the best way to avoid missing feature
episodes and it helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you Jessica Livingston.
Jessica, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Thanks, Lenny. I'm glad to be here.
I want to start with a quote by someone
you may know, Paul Graham. So he wrote, "A few
months ago an article about Y Combinator said
that early on it had been a one-man show. It's
sadly common to read that sort of thing, but
the problem with that description is not just that
it's unfair, it's also misleading. Much of what's
novel about YC is due to Jessica Livingston. If
you don't know her, you don't understand YC." I'm
hoping with this conversation we help a lot more
people understand you. Kind of an implication of
this quote that I wanted to ask you about is
that there's an implication that you've never
gotten the credit that you deserve for starting
YC, for helping YC become what it's become. I'm
just curious what that's been like for you.
It's sort of a hard question. It is true,
I was one of the co-founders of Y Combinator, and
yet I'm often sort of left out of news articles,
Wikipedia people want to take my entry off of
Wikipedia all the time. I'm not as notable and
I'm sort of like, "Gosh, I'm a founder of Y
Combinator, author of a best-selling book on
startups. What does a girl have to do?" But
it is what it is. It's the external views,
and it doesn't matter to me. Do you know what
I mean? People within YC know what I've done,
the Y Combinator alumni know what I've done, my
friends and family and people I respect in the
Silicon Valley community know what I've
done, most of them do. So that's fine.
But it is true, I've often been sort of erased,
and in some cases it's annoying because it's
a lot of people who have a certain narrative
about Y Combinator that don't want me to exist,
I'm maybe making that up a little bit, or
the people that don't want me to be part
of the narrative are the ones that think that Y
Combinator, it's run by white men, only invests
in white men. And gosh, if there was a woman on
the founding team making choices of who to fund,
that would undermine their narrative. So I
think sometimes that's what happens too.
Fascinating. Just a convenient
story to tell sometimes.
This episode is brought to you
by Enterpret. Enterpret unifies
all of your customer interactions, from Gong
calls to Zendesk tickets, to Twitter threads,
to app store reviews, and makes it available
for your product team. It's used by leading
product orgs like Canva, Notion, Loom, Linear, and
Descript to accurately integrate the voice of the
customer into your product development process,
helping you build best-in-class products.
What makes Enterpret special is its ability
to build customer-specific adaptive AI models
that provide the most granular and accurate
categorization of all your customer feedback,
and also connect customer feedback to revenue
impact, to help product leaders confidently
prioritize things that will actually move
the needle for your business. If you want
a custom model built for your organization so
that you can automate your feedback loops and
prioritize your roadmap with confidence, get
in touch with the team at enterpret.com/Lenny.
That's E-N-T-E-R-P-R-E-T dot com slash Lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Anvil. Their
document SDK helps product teams build and launch
software for documents fast. Companies like Carta
and Vouch Insurance use Anvil to accelerate
the development of their document workflows.
Getting to market fast is a top priority for
product teams. And the last thing that you
or your developers want is to build document
workflows from scratch; it's time-consuming,
expensive and distracts from core work. You
could stitch together multiple tools and manage
those integrations, or you can use an all-in-one
document SDK. Most product managers will tell you,
"Paperwork sucks." Anvil's document SDK helps
teams get to market fast, incorporate your
brand style and give you back time to focus on
your company's core differentiated features.
For your users, paperwork often starts
with an AI-powered web form styled and
embedded in your application. From there, you
can route data to your backend systems and to
the correct fields in your PDFs via API.
Complete the process with a white labeled
e-signature. The best part about Anvil is the
level of customization their SDK provides.
Non-technical folks love Anvil's drag and drop
builder, and developers love their flexible APIs
and easy to understand documentation. Build
documents software fast with Anvil. That's
useanvil.com/Lenny to learn more or start a free
trial. That's use A-N-V-I-L dot com slash Lenny.
So at YC, your nickname was the Social
Radar. Your podcast is called The Social
Radars. I haven't seen you talk too much about
this skill anywhere else, and that's what I want
to spend our time on together to better
understand the skill that you've built of
being this social radar. How does that sound?
I will try Lenny, I will try. I don't talk much
about it because it's hard to talk about.
I don't understand. It's hard to put into
words exactly what it is about me, but it's
true that my nickname at Y Combinator was
the Social Radar. And I think it was because my
three co-founders were deeply technical people,
and I was not. But I would look at other things
about founders. When we'd have these 10-minute
interviews, I would look at, do the co-founders
get along? Are these people committed? Do they
really know about their product? Do they
care? Are they going to quit their job?
Or are they telling us that they are going to
quit their job, but really aren't? All these
little social cues that I'd try to pick up on.
And in a lot of cases, red flags about them that
I'd add to the decision-making process. And
so that's why they called me the Social Radar,
and it just sort of stuck. And it's because I
love people and the dynamics and understanding
what's motivating people. I just love it and I
love founder psychology, founders personalities.
I am absolutely fascinated with it.
I love it. Okay, so we're going to try to unpack
as much as we can with the context that you're not
exactly sure if you're able to articulate exactly
how this power of yours works.
Yes.
There's this line you wrote somewhere, and
Paul's written this, and other people, that
every interview that you all did early on at YC,
everyone always turned to you and they're like,
"Jessica, what do you think? What does their
social radar say?" Can you just talk a bit about
that role that you played in the early days of
YC of kind of seeing that side of candidates?
Well, in the early days, especially before I knew
a lot, as much as I know now, about startups and
founders, early on, I was learning a lot in the
first few years. And in the first few years,
it was just the four of us. So I would
be in charge of going out telling people,
"Wait here while we do the interview, come on in."
I'd be in charge of the stopwatch that would time
us. And I'd say, "Okay, our time's up." And it was
very administrative, and I would observe. Paul,
Robert and Trevor, my co-founders would be
asking them all sorts of questions about their
product and their technology and blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah. I would occasionally ask questions,
but I'd usually remain pretty silent. And so I
don't think people even really noticed me. But
I would be just watching them and sort of trying
to observe as much as I could, not understanding
sometimes even the technology that they were
talking about. I let my co-founders do that.
And then after, we'd be talking, they'd look at me
and they'd be like, "Should we fund them? Jessica,
should we fund them?" And sometimes I could
tell based on the conversation whether they
thought that the technology was good or
how they felt, and sometimes I'd say,
"Absolutely we should." Or sometimes I'd say,
"Guys, I'm a little nervous. Did you see how
that founder interrupted the other founder and
wouldn't let the other founder talk?" Because my
three co-founders sometimes wouldn't notice this.
They'd be so caught up in the conversation they
were having about the technology, especially
Paul. Paul would get really into things. And
sometimes I always tease Paul, because one of his
defining qualities is that sometimes someone would
have an idea that he'd get so excited about that
by the end of the interview he'd be giving them
ideas about how to grow their product and what
they could become. And they'd sit there saying,
"Yeah, yeah, that's a great idea." And then he'd
say, "Fund them." And I'd say, "Whoa, whoa, whoa,
Paul, you can't just fund this because you love
the idea. Let's take a step back and let's look.
Like these two founders are working at Google and
they don't say they're going to quit. That's not
good." And I'd point out these things that I
had observed. But I mean, we always agreed. It
was very rare that we wouldn't agree on funding
something. We were usually on the same page.
I see. It's interesting that you talk about these
behaviors, co-founders interrupting each other,
or being kind of aggressive here and there. Some
people believe that's okay for founders to be like
this. A lot of successful founders, Elon, for
example, Steve Jobs, who are kind of assholes
a lot of times, I imagine, and I've read part
of the reason you thought about just the type
of person is you're trying to build a specific
culture in the early days of YC and you're going
to be around these people. So maybe can you
talk a bit about just why those elements were
important to you and why'd you look for those?
I've definitely heard that Steve Jobs could be
an. I've heard stories. But I think I would've
funded him because he's so incredible and he was
so smart and so interested in the product and
knew... I'm very persuaded by people who know
what they're talking about and love their product
and are domain experts. But I did consciously,
especially early on, less so later on, early
on, I did sometimes tend to say, "I really think
this person's an asshole, I do not want to fund
them." And we often wouldn't. And very early on
when we were just funding 10, 20, 30 startups
a batch, sometimes I have been known to say,
"I don't know if I can have dinner with them every
week." It was that point. And I don't think we've
ever regretted any of those. It didn't happen all
the time, that was rare. But life's too short, and
I wanted to be able to work with these founders.
And as it turns out, it was sort of important
early on in weeding out explicit assholes because
that was the basis of our Y Combinator community,
which is now thousands of founders. Now, of
course, all the founders aren't all running their
company anymore, but I would say most all of the
founders bring something useful and valuable to
the table. So if you ask a question on Bookface,
on our forum for founders, someone is going to be
there to help you. And it's amazing. And that all
started very early on, there was this culture of
older batch mates helping newer ones, and this
pay-it-forward mentality where everyone helped
one another and rooted for one another and made
introductions for each other. And I think it's a
big part of our Y Combinator community now.
So I wrote down a few of the things that you
mentioned you look for, and you looked for
in the early days. So let me just share a
few of them and let's spend a little
more time here. So you looked for,
did the founders get along? Are they committed
to the idea? Are they ready to quit their job?
Are there any red flags? So is there anything
else that you remember you spent a lot of time
thinking about or looking for then or even now?
There's looking for in the application and then
there's looking for in the interview, and now we
have software that looks for all of the red flags
in the application that I used to do by hand. In
the application, I'd look for just weird things,
like was there a huge gap in the equity
allocation? Did one founder have 99% and
one founder have 1%? That's weird. I'd want
to dig in on that. That doesn't feel right.
Are they going to quit their job? Are they going
to move to Silicon Valley? What are their current
shareholders? Is like 90% of their company already
owned by someone else? There all these weird
things that we like to just flag. And we wouldn't
necessarily not fund someone because of them,
but it's just more data. So that was in the
application that I'd look through all of those.
But in the interview I definitely was sort of,
one thing I remember I would always look for was,
when you'd have a conversation with
us, a lot of times, Paul especially,
but Robert and Trevor, would really be getting
right into the idea and questioning you,
and how do you know this? And what about
this? And if a founder would get defensive,
that was always a bad sign, always a bad
sign. The best founders would say, "Gosh,
I have thought about it and here's what I
figured out." Or, they just have this almost
a tennis match and a conversation rather than
closing up and feeling like, oh, this person's
interrogating me. You could just sort of, the
open-mindedness, the flexible-mindedness of people
was really important. I'd get really excited
about domain expertise. Like my co-founders,
we all loved that. If someone was fixing their
own problem in a broken industry, we loved that.
Definitely, I'd look for co-founder relationships.
And again, I'm not saying I was always right,
but you could tell if... One founder, I'll give
a story, one founder, once we asked a question
and one person started to respond and the other
founder put his arm in front of him and said,
"I'll answer that question." And it was just so
weird that he wouldn't let his co-founder speak.
We'd have situations where we'd call people
like hackers in a cage, where it's kind of
obvious there'd be a business founder, business
person, who had clearly convinced a programmer to
join the team. They were given, the programmer was
given, very little equity and just we called them
programmers in a cage, like hackers in a cage.
And sometimes that works out, I'm not saying it
doesn't. But I'd always try to observe, okay, does
this hacker in a cage have any say in the company,
the direction of the product? That sort of thing.
Because the programmer needs to have opinions.
It's so funny. I love this metaphor. And I
totally get what you mean. I want to unpack
a couple of these, because this is exactly where
I was hoping we'd go. So this idea of looking for
defensiveness and being open to change and being
flexible, why do you think that was so important
to successful founders? Why did you look for
that? Why was that a predictor of success?
Several things. First of all, being defensive
is really bad, if you're a startup founder,
because you're always going to get people who
question you. And it's your job to educate them,
if it's a new area, you're doing
something presumably pretty new,
you're always going to have people who question
it or say, "That product's already out there,
why is yours better?" You have to educate them.
You don't want to be defensive about it. Also,
a lot of times, the first idea isn't bang right
on, the right idea, and you have to be open-minded
and maybe adjust it in a certain direction.
The famous PayPal story, how it started off
being the PalmPilot, or money transfer. And money
transfer between the PalmPilots or whatever. And
then all the customers were using a janky version
on the web, and they were begging for this to be
on the web. And finally, the founder said, "Oh,
I see what most people want this for." You have
to be open-minded to see what direction really is
what your users want. And so if you find someone
is defensive, usually they're not open-minded.
The other thing is that the best founders will
want to learn from other people and listen to
other people. You talk to the Collison brothers
and say something, they ask you a question,
they're listening to your answer. So many founders
think, oh, I can't learn from anyone. But the best
founders are always listening and having spirited
debates about things. I mean, that's part of the
process. And so I think when someone's defensive,
it's just a bad sign. So I would look for that.
I loved when I'd find someone sort of showcase
that they'd make something happen
no matter what; they're scrappy,
they're hustlers. I remember... Can I tell
the story about the Airbnb interview?
Please.
Okay, because that was definitely
one I'll never forget. That was one that was clear
the founders were really good. The market had just
crashed basically with all the banks going out
of business and everything. And so we were only
funding startups that we felt had really scrappy
founders and could be cockroaches, meaning could
live off of very little amounts of money, or
could charge customers and make money. And we
didn't fund that many people in that winter '09
batch. So we're being very strict with ourselves,
very disciplined about things. And the Airbnb guys
came in, and I just remember they had a contagious
amount of energy. They just had an energy about
them the way that they talked about their product,
which was crazy at the time, staying in someone's
bed or airbed. In fact, it's a famous part of the
story, we hated their idea and Paul tried to get
Brian and Joe and Nate to change it. So we didn't
even like the idea. But I remember specifically
they brought, at the end, Joe brought out these,
the cereal boxes, the Obama O's and Cap'n
Crunch's or Cap'n McCain's or whatever.
Cap'n McCain's, yeah.
Yeah, Cap'n McCain's. They were saying that
they went to some Costco or something and bought
off-brand Cheerios and off-brand Cap'n Crunch's,
took them out of the box, put them in this new
box, glue-gunned it shut. And I just thought,
oh my God, these guys are really going to
great lengths for this. And for some reason,
it was silly, but it really appealed to me.
They're going to work hard to do whatever
they can to make this company succeed. And even
though we were skeptical about the idea, I think
we definitely made the right bet on the founders,
and it was just very clear in that interview.
I'm so happy you shared that story, I
was definitely going to ask about it.
It's so funny because I've heard that story
at least a hundred times working at Airbnb,
they tell the beginning of Airbnb every chance
they get at every all-hands. It's like a recurring
theme. And it's great to hear that basically it
went exactly the way they describe. Oftentimes,
there's a myth around what happened, but
that's exactly how they describe it.
No, it was definitely a whole crazy story and how
Paul called them to accept them, and they were on
the 280 or something or the 101 and the reception
went down. And so he didn't hear if they were
accepted or not. Did he tell that part?
No, I haven't heard that part.
Oh yeah, that's part of the story. And they
had to keep driving to get to talk to Paul
again and find out that they were accepted.
Oh, yeah. It was just a crazy interview.
The element of the story I'm also curious about
is, the way Joe tells it, is he had the box in his
backpack. And as they were walking out, Paul or
you is like, "Hey, what's that? What's that cereal
box doing there?" Is that how it went, or is it
more like, "Hey, we have this cereal thing."?
I don't think Paul and I looked in his backpack
and asked. I think there was definitely some
pressure on Joe not to show us the cereal
boxes. I think Nate was really down on that,
especially. And I think they were walking
out the door and they're like, "Hey,
we just brought you a little something." I think
Joe did pull it out, and we had an extra minute or
so around the cereal boxes. That's how I heard
about the glue gun story and everything. But
I think Joe had been reluctant, but he did it
at the end and I think it was a good call.
That's so funny. And after that meeting, what
was that conversation like between you and Paul?
Was it just like everyone's like, "We definitely
got to do this."? Or was it like you being like,
"Hey, these guys are really interesting."?
No, I think we all liked them. We all liked
them. But I remember saying, "We have got to..."
I just remember being like, "We've got to fund
these guys. I don't know about the idea. Maybe
they'll change their idea, who knows? But they
seem really great." Again, the energy level
and the passion with which they spoke about
their experience hosting, because they'd been
around struggling, but had been a company with
an idea for a little while before they applied
to YC. We were there basically their Hail Mary,
their last resort for them. And so they could tell
us about their story about how they hosted the
people at a conference, and there was definitely
some magic to it, which was convincing.
Is there anything else along the
Airbnb story that would be interesting
to share while we're on that topic?
I mean, the only interesting thing as it
relates to being the social radar is that there
were just some interviews that I remember because
I just thought, this is great. These founders
are so good. I'm totally convinced. What they're
working on might not work, but I feel like it's
so worth the bet based on these founders. And
that happened. There were definitely a couple
other of our most successful companies that I
clearly felt that way about. You just feel
like they know what they're talking about,
they thought about the problem. They're not
solving this problem because it's sort of the
problem du jour or fun and exciting. Some are very
unsexy problems like when Parker Conrad applied
with Zenefits, unsexy HR stuff, benefits stuff.
But he knew how broken it was and was trying to
fix it. And I love stories like that. There was
one story in terms of... The one time I did sort
of persuade the rest of the group to fund someone
was, do you know the company GOAT, the sneaker?
Absolutely.
Okay. When Eddie and Daishin applied,
they were not doing the sneaker company, they were
doing this group sort of book-a-group-dinner at
a restaurant with people you don't know as a
way to meet new people. And for some reason,
I loved the idea because I thought maybe
it could be a secret dating, like a Trojan
Horse for a dating sort of site. But I really
loved the two founders. And one of the reasons,
again, they had this passion about their idea, but
they had had this cream puff company before that
they had run, and they just told these stories
about how hard it was and all this stuff. And I,
for some reason, just thought, these are hustlers.
These guys are scrappy. They're going to make
this succeed. And they didn't make that company
succeed, but they pivoted and made GOAT succeed
and it's doing really, really well. And I remember
that one I definitely had to convince... I mean,
not that Paul, Robert and Trevor didn't like
them, but I think they really didn't think
the idea was that great or just sort of were
meh. I was like, "We have to fund them."
I love sharing these stories. If you have more
to share, please keep throwing them out there.
So a few things I've noted so far, of things
that you look for, and I think it's important to
note this is very early stage evaluation where
the founder and the team is, it's incredibly
important, because the idea often shifts.
Oh, yeah. This is as early as it gets, Lenny.
Yeah. Oftentimes, just an idea, I imagine.
Yes.
So a few things, so far, things that you found
to be really valuable to look for. One is this
idea of just making shit happen, showing signs
of being hustlers, just getting shit done,
Obama O's, things like that. And then I think
along the same lines, just passion for this
idea and just like almost charisma. Is that how
you think about it? Or is it just like...
I hate using the word charisma because there are a
lot of charismatic people who are full of baloney,
and are just doing a startup because it's a cool
thing to do now. And I wouldn't want anyone to
get fooled by charisma. There has to be some
substance behind that charisma. Of course,
we all love talking to more charismatic people
than less, and I've certainly talked to my
fair share of totally uncharismatic people,
but sometimes they're really good founders
too. If they know what they're doing and care
about the user and are fixing a problem that
they have a deep connection to. So I don't
want to say someone who's charismatic, but
it definitely helps because, as you know, as a
founder, you have to do a lot of sales and you
have to recruit people and you have to convince
investors to fund you and you have to convince
users to use your product and all of this stuff.
So it does help being charismatic, definitely.
Okay. So there's being super hustler,
making shit happen. Domain expertise,
something you've mentioned a few times. Just
like having deep domain expertise in an area,
and I think that's probably where they probably
don't pivot oftentimes, where they've actually
have experience in that specific problem.
They might pivot a little bit, they might pivot
a little in terms of the actual solution.
They might be trying to solve a problem
and the first attempt doesn't really work.
I haven't mentioned earnestness though.
Oh, do tell.
Earnestness is one of
the most important because earnest, sort of to
me, is bucketed with authenticity. And to be a
successful startup founder, you have to care so
much about the problem you're trying to solve,
the users you're serving and being earnest about
it is so key to success. There are so many wannabe
founders, so many people doing it because it's
cool or they think this idea is cool, but they
don't really, deep down, have what it takes. And
I think we always try to fund earnest people.
What does earnest look like in practice?
And how does that come across?
I think it means being sort of humble about... And
if you get asked a question in the interview and
you don't know the answer, they say, "I don't know
the answer to that. I'd have to think about it."
Or, "I don't know the answer. I've given it some
thought and here's what I have come up with." And
they're just honest about things, and they're not
trying to do the whole smoke and mirrors thing,
which we've definitely gotten people
like that, that avoid the question
or are doing it for the wrong reasons.
I remember there was one group that were
45-year-old men and they were building an
app for teenagers in fashion. And I remember
just thinking, we were asking them, "Why have you
chosen teenagers in fashion?" And it was so clear
that they thought they could make easy money,
and it wasn't because they cared about fashion.
It wasn't because, "Oh, I have a daughter who's
really into fashion and I've seen this need." It
was just like, they made up the idea. And that
is not earnest, that is not authentic to me.
You talked about it, so there's this earnestness
you look for, also not being defensive. There's
this also spectrum of confidence and people
believing in what they're doing. Do you have
any thoughts on just how to find that?
What does that look like when they're too
defensive versus they're just confident and
then they know what they're talking about?
Confidence is good. You definitely want
confidence. It's hard to... I think you
can see it when you experience it. Like someone
who's confident in answering your questions but
isn't defensive, there's definitely a difference.
And I don't know, this is why I'm saying it's sort
of hard to articulate these things, but confidence
means you can say, "I've thought about that and I
don't know the answer." That's confidence.
And they'll say, "But here's what I do to
try to figure it out. Here are my plans to
address that." Confidence, I should have put
that upfront because that's very important,
especially when it comes to fundraising,
you cannot go into an investor meeting lacking
confidence. You can come into YC's interview
lacking confidence, but we will then help you in
the next three months to gain more confidence.
And by the way, one of the things we do to
help people gain more confidence is to make
them believe that their startup is a great
investment, to help them create a startup
that truly is possibly going to make money or at
least worth being a good bet. That's the thing,
early stage, the best you can offer is like, "I
might not succeed, but I'm definitely a good bet."
And we help them with their product, we help
them with their ideas, and we help them that,
by demo day, they can get up on stage and
legitimately say, "We're a good bet and
here's why. Let me tell you about our idea."
And so we definitely help with confidence.
Awesome. A couple other things you mentioned
earlier, just to unpack a little bit. So being
committed, something you look for, and co-founders
getting along. In terms of committed, I imagine,
these are very practical things. How are
they actually going to stick to this? Are
they actually excited to work on this?
Maybe talk about that a little bit.
We all know how hard startups are, but I think
you don't really know how hard it is until you
actually do it. A lot of people would start a
startup still having a job at Google or wherever,
and they do it on the side. I do recommend,
if people are just getting started and don't
want to raise money yet, starting it on the
side is a great way to get going, but at some
point you have to commit, you have to burn the
boat, because we found that founders who were
still getting a paycheck and health insurance,
once the going got tough, they did not quit their
job. And you sort of need that desperation
like, "I have to make this startup succeed
because it's my job." Not like, "Oh, I'll just
stay at Google." You need that. And we found
that founders who weren't leaving their jobs,
it was just not working out. Or that co-founder
would always wind up leaving the company because
they didn't want to actually leave their job.
And that's fine, there are people that can't
leave their jobs for financial reasons. That's
fine. You just shouldn't be starting a startup
if you're not going to be prepared to leave your
job. So that's the leaving of the job thing.
And the co-founders getting along, oh my. I
spent a lot of my time at Y Combinator when I
was there all the time, full time, mediating
co-founder disputes. And so many startups
died or had near-death experiences because the
co-founders didn't get along or broke up. It just
happens all the time. And so that's why I think,
during interviews, I was desperately trying to
search for any clues that the co-founders didn't
get along, or if they blatantly contradicted
each other. But you could also tell if they
were answering, finishing each other's sentences.
I love co-founders that have a history together;
either they went to school together, they
went to college together, work together,
maybe they're siblings. Because when you have
a long-term relationship, you trust each other
and you know each other's weaknesses, and you're
usually on the same page with your aspirations and
everything. It's really scary when two founders
get together just to start the startup and don't
have any history. Massive red flag. Sometimes it
works out like in the case of Dropbox, Drew and
Arash both went to MIT, but I think they didn't
know each other before they started Dropbox, and
it worked out. But most of the time it doesn't.
So we've talked about co-founders getting along,
looking for defensiveness, domain expertise,
the sign of making shit happen, earnestness.
Is there anything else that we've missed that
you look for in the founders that tell you
maybe we should, maybe we shouldn't?
Relentlessly resourceful. Paul wrote a
whole essay on that. Every founder is
different, I never try to say, "Oh,
this person doesn't have this. I'm not going
to fund them." You always have to... Everyone's
different. But I mean, you're an investor.
I'm curious, do any of these things surprise
you or do you care about these things too?
No, absolutely not. Absolutely. And I actually
try to avoid pre-seed and early stage because I'm
not amazing at it, maybe. This is why I want to
learn how to build my social radar skill.
Oh gosh, okay.
Yeah. Tough. It's so tough. It's like
so few things actually work out.
Well, it's because you don't have a lot of data.
If someone is just applying with an idea, you
have very little data. You can look at where they
went to college, what have they built in the past,
that's always a great predictor of their
ability. And so on the YC's application,
we ask them, "What project have you worked
on before?" Or whatever. But it's really
hard to tell when you're the first investor.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta. When
it comes to ensuring your company has top-notch
security practices, things get complicated fast.
Now, you can assess risk, secure the trust of
your customers and automate compliance for SOC 2,
ISO 27001, HIPAA and more with a single platform,
Vanta. Vanta's market-leading trust management
platform helps you continuously monitor compliance
alongside reporting and tracking risk. Plus,
you can save hours by completing security
questionnaires with Vanta AI. Join thousands
of global companies that use Vanta to automate
evidence collection, unify risk management,
and streamline security reviews. Get $1,000
off Vanta when you go to vanta.com/Lenny.
That's V-A-N-T-A dot com slash Lenny.
When did you first notice that you had
this social radar-ish skill and you're
better at this than other people?
Paul used to always call me Detective
Livingston. Before I was a social radar,
I was Detective Livingston. I cannot help myself
noticing weird things, just dumb things, like if
Paul had on a yellow T-shirt and then an hour
later came in with a blue T-shirt, I'd be like,
"Why do you have a blue T-shirt on?" I have
to understand what happened in that hour where
that T-shirt is different. Or people's what, their
relationships, what drives them? I was always like
this, and I think it goes back to my childhood.
I spent hours and hours on the phone with people,
with my girlfriends, dissecting situations,
and then all through high school, and college,
I mean the amount of time we wasted discussing
social matters with people, and boys, and things
like that. It was just frightening how much time
I wasted, but I just was genuinely interested
in it. And what drives people and why did this
happen? I don't know if I ever noticed I did this,
but it was just, my point is, it's always been
a part of me. And I definitely notice and having
an aversion to phony people. I always have.
I've never been one to fall for someone who's
super phony and tried to have them as a friend or
anything. I just can tell, and ugh, I hate it.
Do you feel like it's almost all genetic
or do you think there was something in your
childhood that pushed you to be good at this?
I don't know. I really don't know. So this is why
I think I'm going to be a bad guest, because I
can't give a practical understanding. I mean,
I don't really think... I can't say
other people in my family are like that,
and I can't say that it was part of my upbringing.
I just notice these things. I don't know. I should
be paying attention to other things, but I'm not,
but I'm paying attention to this. I'll give you an
example with you.
Please.
So I looked up your bio to read a little
bit about you, and I loved the Dalton
Caldwell Podcast. I listened to that.
Fourth most popular of all time.
Dalton's was?
Yes.
Oh, go Dalton. That's awesome. Yeah, it was
really good. I learned a lot from it. I love
listening to Dalton. But what I really want to
know about you is, on the release that you sent,
or on the instructions for this podcast, you
said, "There might be some edge cases where
your podcast isn't good enough to go out. We just
want to warn you." And all I could think of is,
what prompted that? There has to be a story
of what prompted that. No one else would pay
attention to that, but I'm just so curious. It's
so weird. I'm just a weird person like this.
Yes, I did add that. There's a story, basically,
it was just an episode that wasn't amazing and we
didn't have that caveat in the prep beforehand,
and it felt bad to tell the person.
See, I knew it. I knew that that had happened.
That's exactly right. Is there kind of a way
you've thought about honing this skill over time?
Once you kind of got a sense, "Hey, people keep
telling me I'm really good at this." Is there
something you've done to help strengthen it?
No, but one of the things I do try to do is sort
of reinforce. Sometimes I'll have a feeling about
someone, maybe we fund them, maybe we don't. I'd
sort of like to know what happens a few years
later. I like to follow up. There definitely have
been some situations where I haven't liked someone
that we funded and it's taken 5 to 10 years before
they failed. And in some cases, for a bad reason.
Where I'll say, "Oh, thank God, I was right about
that. I did have this feeling." Or, "I knew they'd
be successful." Like the GOAT guys who I was
saying before, there was definitely a period when
Grubwithus, their first startup wasn't doing well,
and they were starting, that maybe some people
would've given up on them. And now I can say, "I
was right about them. That feeling was right."
So I do try to sort of follow up with some of
the really strong gut instincts that I had,
to see if I was right. Often, when I have a gut
instinct, it's like a negative thing. So we wind
up not funding someone. So I really need to know
if that person went on to be super successful.
And I will answer your question right now, there's
no one that I had a strong dislike for that I sort
of said, "We should not fund them," that has
gone on to be a super success. Thank God.
Wow, interesting.
I mean, it doesn't happen all the time that I
really put my foot down, but sometimes I have.
And this feeling, is it like a visceral body thing
for you? Or is it like intellectually,
you notice, "Hey, this guy's interrupting
her and this person doesn't..."?
More intellectual. But it does come
from inside. I don't know how to hone it.
It has to come naturally. You have to have a
natural interest in people. And so I'm sometimes
not listening to all the words and I'm sort of
just observing them, I don't know.
Have you ever been tricked by someone
where you didn't see something you should
have seen? Is there anything there?
Oh, yeah, for sure. I can't really talk about
the times I have been tricked just because I
don't want to say anything really negative about
people, but... Well, there was one example that I
do feel comfortable sharing. Ilya Lichtenstein of
MixRank. Do you know the guy that stole billions
of dollars in Bitcoin from a crypto wallet?
Do you not know this crazy, crazy story?
Please share.
I think he's in the joint now. He was
definitely convicted of this, and his wife, and
they stole billions of dollars. And I definitely
don't remember thinking anything bad about him or
thinking he could be that kind of person. So that
definitely, there've been some doozies like
that, where, did not see that one coming.
Oh my God. I think what's extraordinary about
the fact that that happens rarely is that your
interviews are 10 minutes long, and so you
have very little time to actually find all
these things. And plus, the actual product and the
idea and growth strategy and all these things.
Well, you find a lot can come in reading the
application. That's a lot of legwork at the
beginning. You read the application. But then the
10 minutes is kind of as long as you need, in most
cases. Because we found when they were longer,
like 20 minutes, you'd know in 10 minutes and
be twiddling your thumbs trying to get through the
interview for the next 10 minutes. So we kept them
short so we could interview more people. But there
have definitely been cases where we've interviewed
people, accepted them, and then very soon
afterward, we're sort of like, crestfallen like,
"Oh, these people are very limp. What were we
thinking?" Definitely, we've been tricked in that
respect all the time. Or, "Oh gosh, they seem so
impressive in the interview and now they're just
posers who can't really do anything." Definitely,
I'm tricked all the time in little ways. Or,
I didn't notice two founders didn't get along
and then one co-founder goes missing a week
into the program or something crazy. There's all
sorts of crazy stuff like that that happen.
I think in the game you're playing, I would
expect some things to slip through.
Yeah.
You said that there's
been kind of an operationalization of some of
the things you used to look for in founders,
now that you're not actually in the process.
Is there a Jessica-as-a-service sort of thing?
What kind of stuff have they built that
looks for the sorts of things you used
to look for in the interview process?
No, it's all just stuff in application that
automatically flags certain things. I actually
don't remember all of them, but it's just, all
it is, is a, "Please pay attention to this, reader
of the application." It's not, "This disqualifies
anyone." It's, "Just please pay attention." And
those are things like I mentioned, a really crazy
equity structure, founders not quitting their
job, things like that, that it's important that
someone is voting on them and then interviewing
them knows. Because I would often, some of the
questions I'd ask at the end of the interview, I'd
say, "It looks like you have 90% of the stock and
your co-founder only has one. Can you tell us
why that's the case?" And maybe they could make
a case for it, who knows? But at least I'd ask.
So the flags just say, "Pay attention to it."
Amazing. So if we were to zoom out, in early
stage investing, the main thing you need to
get right and evaluate as the founder, the social
radar skill that you've had from childhood is such
an incredible advantage in doing this well, and
you could basically say YC is what it is because
of this unfair advantage that you all had in the
early days. I'm guessing many people listening to
this are like, "We need a Jessica on our team.
We need to build this skill ourselves. We need
to figure out how to integrate social radar into
our process." I know you're going to hate this
question, but just, do you have any advice for
people that want to try to build the skill, get
better at this, notice some of these things?
I really think that our advantage was that my
three co-founders were deeply technical people.
And I think a lot of investors back then weren't,
didn't have that background. And I think that that
background really helped YC choose good founders.
So I don't want to make it sound like it was
that big of a deal, but advice? Advice for how to
hone... I mean, I think just try to pay attention
to subtle cues. If you really feel like, gosh, I'm
so clueless about these things, try to just tell
yourself, "Okay, I'm going in to evaluate these
founders, evaluate this investment opportunity. I
know I'm bad at these kind of judgments. I'm going
to remember, do they seem like they get along?"
Because there are no trick questions. I don't
have any trick questions that you could ask, or
it's just paying attention. Have a conversation.
Do they understand their product well? Are
they defensive? Maybe have your own little
checklist that you think about. You don't have
to have it written down, but you think about,
and then afterward, you spend some time thinking,
were they defensive? When I asked them why this
is better than the competitor, how did that go?
Or ask them, maybe do have some questions, if you
don't know how long they've known each other,
ask them that question. "How did you two meet?
Have you ever worked together before? How's it
going?" Just be a little bit more conscious about
asking these types of questions to reveal some
key information for your investment decision.
That was an awesome summary of a lot of the stuff
we talked about. If anyone ever doubts that you
are very good at this, Paul tweeted this quiz, the
Reading the Mind in the Eyes quiz, that I took,
it's incredibly hard. You basically see a bunch of
eyes and you're supposed to judge their emotion,
and it's really hard. And you got 36
out of 36, which blows my mind.
I did nail it. I do have to tell
a funny story about this.
Please.
So Paul, sort of late at night, and he emailed me,
because I had gone to bed, but I had my thing,
and he emailed me. He's like, "Check out this
quiz. I got 25 out of 36. What can you get?" So I
got my computer out because I was like, I have to
beat Paul. And I did it, and it was really hard.
They'd only show the eyes and then it would say,
what is this person thinking? Are they happy, sad?
But some of them were really hard to distinguish.
Are they irritated or are they angry? It's kind
of hard to tell the difference between irritated
and angry. And I remember looking into these
people's eyes saying, "What are they trying to
communicate to me? Are they irritated with
me or are they mad at me?" Kind of thing.
And as I went through, it would tell you if
you got it correct. As I almost got to the end,
I was like, "Oh my God, this is going to
be a near-perfect score. I have to nail
this." And when I got 36 out of 36, I was like,
"Yes." And I told Paul, he tweeted it. We then,
a week later, had this YC event in London, and
I swear to God, about 10 people came up to me
to talk about this eye quiz and how they had
not done well, and what was my secret? It was
very amusing. I never thought that anyone
would think it was that interesting.
I love that there's this thing that totally shows
this skill you have that is better than everyone
else. I took it, all my friends have taken it
after that tweet, and the highest we've gotten
is 31 of all the people I know.
Really?
And I think when people take it, we'll
link to it, they're going to be like,
"How can you get 36 out of 36? Impossible."
You have to look into their eyes and say,
"What are they trying to tell me?"
I hope you're not trying to tell me
you're full of shit with your eyes.