If you do the hard path and it doesn't work,
actually you still win because you've now done
something hard. You've probably worked with smart
people. You've learned something along the way
that is valuable. I meet lots of job seekers.
I go, what are you doing to try to find a job?
Are you really learning anything from sending
out 10 resumes a day? Why don't you look at the
API Docs and build something? Even if you don't
get a job at Shopify, you've learned something.
First, I want to talk about another theme,
creating intensity in your organization.
Everyone says, "Oh yeah, work hard
and do more hours when you're young,
whatever." I'm like, "What if
you just did more per minute?"
The more I dig into the Shopify
way working, the more fun stuff I
never expected emerges. There's been
a drive to delete code and simplify.
We have a Delete Code Club.
We can always almost find a
million-plus lines of code
to delete, which is insane.
I found this great quote from you,
"Not everyone can look stupid in public over
and over, but I believe it's my superpower."
I have been in many situations with
many sharp people who have said to me,
that's the stupidest fucking
question I've ever heard. My
goal there is not to annoy the person,
but it's to understand the content.
I was looking at your LinkedIn and
your career history, and I noticed
that you've worked for a different
billionaire every decade of your life.
They're mostly different people, but they're
similar in one thing is that they haven't...
Today my guest is Farhan Thawar. Farhan
is Vice President and Head of Engineering
at Shopify. Shopify is an incredibly
interesting company because they have
over 10,000 employees who are fully remote, and
even though they were founded almost 20 years ago,
they continue to operate with urgency, velocity
and have very first principles, ways of thinking,
which translates into them seeing record usage,
blowing away their earnings calls just recently,
and building a beloved product. A lot of this is
thanks to Farhan, who in our conversation shares
very specifically what he's done to maintain
intensity and urgency within the engineering
team. Including their meeting cadences, the
counter-intuitive power of pair programming,
how they run meetings, how they cancel
meetings constantly and so much more.
He also shares his experience with indexing
towards choosing the harder option when you
have multiple options to choose from and
why that ends up making your life easier.
He also shares a bunch of great hiring advice and
a bunch of hiring stories which are going to blow
your mind. He also talks about their engineering
intern program where they're going to hire over a
thousand engineers just for their intern program
in 2025. I've had a lot of people on this podcast
from Shopify, but that is for a very good reason
because this company and its leaders have a lot to
teach us about how to run an incredible business
and build an incredible product. If you enjoy this
podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow
it in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube.
It's the best way to avoid missing future episodes
and it helps the podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you, Farhan Thawar. Farhan, thank you so
much for being here, and welcome to the podcast.
Thanks for having me.
As I was preparing for our conversation,
I talked to a bunch of people that you've
worked with over the years, and
there's basically three themes
that kept coming up over and over and over. One
is hiring, two is creating intensity in your
organization, and three is choosing the hard path.
First of all, does that resonate? Second of all,
does it sound good to talk about these
three themes in our time together?
Yeah, I mean, I have ideas on where
all three of those things came from,
and I think that it is something
that if you looked back on my career,
I've hit points on each of those things,
but I don't think at the onset I knew that
that's what I was doing, but it turns out
in retrospect, that's what I ended up doing.
Perfect, so this is the Steve Jobs.
Everything looking backwards it all connects.
Yes.
Today's episode is brought to you by DX. If you're
an engineering leader or on a platform team,
at some point your CEO will inevitably ask you for
productivity metrics, but measuring engineering
organizations is hard, and we can all agree that
simple metrics like the number of PRs or commits
doesn't tell the full story. That's where DX comes
in. DX is an engineering intelligence solution
designed by leading researchers, including those
behind the DORA and SPACE frameworks. It combines
quantitative data from developer tools with
qualitative feedback from developers to give you
a complete view of engineering productivity and
the factors affecting it. Learn why some of the
world's most iconic companies like Etsy, Dropbox,
Twilio, Vercel, and Webflow rely on DX. Visit
DX's website at getdx.com/Lenny. This episode is
brought to you by Persona, the adaptable identity
platform that helps businesses fight fraud,
meet compliance requirements, and build trust.
While you're listening to this right now, how
do you know that you're really listening to me,
Lenny? These days it's easier than ever
for fraudsters to steal PII, faces,
and identities. That's where Persona comes in.
Persona helps leading companies like LinkedIn,
Etsy, and Twilio securely verify individuals and
businesses across the world. What sets Persona
apart is its configurability. Every company
has different needs depending on its industry,
use cases, risk tolerance, and user demographics.
That's why Persona offers flexible building blocks
that allow you to build tailored collection and
verification flows that maximize conversion while
minimizing risks. Plus Persona's orchestration
tools, automate your identity process so that you
can fight rapidly shifting fraud and meet new
waves of regulation. Whether you're a startup
or an enterprise business Persona has a plan for
you. Learn more at withpersona.com'Lenny. Again,
that's with P-E-R-S-O-N-A.com/Lenny. Okay, so
let's start by talking about the hard path.
Okay.
Advice that I've heard you share with
people often is when they're trying
to decide amongst a bunch of options
is to choose the harder path because
that makes life easier down the road.
Share this advice why it's so important,
where you learned, where you developed
that this is the right approach.
But the short version is that if you have a
choice and you choose the easy thing and it
works great. If you choose the hard thing and it
works great, you did more work, but if it doesn't
work and you chose the easy thing, you've actually
not learned anything because you chose the... You
haven't done a lot of work, you haven't probably
worked with the smartest people because they're
not usually around on the easy path, and what
happens is you've gone through this exercise
and now you're like, I've kind of lost. I lost
the choice, or I was trying to do something,
it didn't work out for me. But if you do
the hard path and it doesn't work, actually
you still win because you've now done something
hard. You've probably worked with smart people,
you've learned something along the way that is
valuable, and I can give you a quick example.
So I meet lots of job seekers and they're like,
I go, "What are you doing to try to find a job?"
I'm like, "I'm sending out 10 resumes a day." I'm
like, "Okay." That sounds kind of easy, and are
you really learning anything from sending out 10
resumes a day? Versus I would say to them, "Hey,
you know all these companies you're interested
in, Shopify might be one of them. Why don't you
look at the API Docs and build something, build
a Shopify app, build an admin extension, build
something on top of Shopify." Even if you don't
get a job at Shopify, which is maybe your goal,
you've learned something, you've built something,
you have things in your GitHub repo now and you
can show people. You're learning about the
product that might translate to a job you
might get somewhere else. So I think that even
though it's harder, right? Of course, you can't
every day build an app on a different platform.
Maybe you can once a day. You will learn something
in the hard path. And the same thing happened
to me in taking hard courses. I would get worse
marks, but I ended up meeting smarter people
in those courses because they were there for
the same reason I was because the content was
hard. And so that's something that I've just
realized in my life that if I do the hard thing
and I just naturally tend towards doing that,
I ended up doing... I went to Waterloo and
I did a minor in electrical engineering on
top of computer science, and when I did my
MBA, I did a minor in financial engineering
because the smarter people were in that
path and they're still my friends today.
So building on the last point you just made,
people could hear this and think, okay,
if it's harder, that's going to be the right path.
Sometimes harder is still a bad idea. For example,
joining a terrible company that's extremely
frustrating to work at or building, I don't know,
a house in a really dumb way, but it's just
really hard. What else do you find is important
to think about when you're thinking it's not just
harder, but also XYZ should probably be true?
Yeah, one real one is of course the people,
because I find that my path has always focused
on trying to pick the best learning journey.
Where can I learn the most? And for me,
everyone's different. Some people might learn
better from books or the domain they're in,
but for me, I learn a lot from people, and
so I try to put myself in those harder rooms
on purpose. There was a time when I was doing
my MBA in financial engineering, by the way,
and I'm a tech guy and still a tech guy, and
all these people were going into finance jobs.
There was a point where somebody said to me, "Why
are you in this class?" Because they knew that
I was doing it for fun, and so it was because it
was the learning journey. And so I would say a big
part of it for me is yes, there's the how do you
win even if you lose, because if it goes poorly,
you can still come out of it with skills, but
if you actually take the hard path, you'll have
these intense working relationships with smart
people that again will continue on in your life.
And that also just forces you to be in this
constant state of uncomfort by going into these
rooms and saying, "I don't know anything,"
and it's harder. And I agree with you. You
don't want to do dumb things like, oh, let's
just do this thing in a dumb way. That's not
what I mean. I mean, let's try to do the hard
thing that we can learn from. And by the way,
it happens to be on the path. It's just is
it might take more manual work or it might
not be the way most people do it, but we
think we can learn more from that path.
Speaking of that, I found this great quote from
you, "Not everyone can look stupid in public over
and over, but I believe it's my superpower and I
try to make it my whole team's superpower too."
Yeah, I mean, it sounds funny, but again, I'm
the one who's always trying super dumb things
and sometimes they work, and even my wife
hates that I try these things even at home,
right? I'll just like, what's an example? It
might be a new washing machine and I might try
some weird mode with some clothes, and I'm
like, "Oh, you ruin the clothes." I'm like,
okay. But now I know that this mode should not be
used, but maybe I would've uncovered that there's
some super fast, quick wash that I can do in 20
minutes that now saves us 40 minutes of wash time
every single time we use the washing machine.
So there's things like that, but I will ruin
lots of clothes trying to do that, but the
same at work. We'll try things and sometimes
it can lead to disaster, hopefully not, but
you can imagine people trying to like, oh,
let me try this new configuration of GCP and
maybe we'll get some benefit, but maybe we'll
take Shopify down. We don't want to do that.
So you want to have some sort of guardrails.
But there is something around trying dumb things
and saying dumb things. Half the time, by the way,
when I say something dumb, people go, "I had the
same question." They just were scared to say it.
So for folks that may want to, because
I feel like this skill is so hard,
but so important, being okay with
failing, being okay with looking dumb,
is there something you tell people to
help them build this other than just like,
I'm genetically good at this stuff? What helped
you become comfortable with being wrong and
failing before you were a big shot exec where it's
like, oh, he's fine. He knows what he's doing.
I don't know. I mean, I kind of grew up working
in retail and people come into the store,
and then I would say, "Hey," and you're working on
commission, and they're not always buying stuff,
and if they don't buy it, you don't
make any money. And so maybe just the
fact of going up and forcing myself to
talk to people and then trying to get
them to, and maybe you spend an hour with
a client and then they don't buy anything,
but you're getting that reaction of a bunch of
negatives, and all you have to do is say, okay,
and just go to the next customer. You can't
really well on it and be like, oh my God,
my whole day is ruined. But instead, you have to
learn from that and say, "Okay, let me try this.
Let me try that." And it's not easy, but it was
a way to build up some confidence and people say,
this telemarketing, or there's a bunch of
things you can do to get a lot of rejection.
Cold calling is another one, and that can lead you
to actually building up resistance. I don't know
if I'm genetically better at it or not. I just
think that I literally don't care if I look dumb.
I've always said the dumb thing, I'm not doing
things on purpose to get nos, which by the way,
is part of some sales training, which is go and
get 10 nos. But I haven't done that. But I have
been in many situations with many sharp people,
business people, successful people who have
said to me... Turn around and said, "That's the
stupidest fucking question I've ever heard." I've
definitely had that happen to me. And I'm like,
"All right, let's move on to the next question."
I love that attitude and I think that's key
to it. It's just bounce off of it and not be
crumble and I think it's empowering for
folks to hear from someone like you that
has done so well that people tell you that
is the dumbest question I've ever heard-
Oh yeah, still.
Still. Okay.
Yeah. So how about this? That I heard that's
the dumbest fucking question. And then recently
I heard, I've already explained this to you
three times because I kept asking and I didn't
understand, and literally I got this message back
saying, "I've already explained this to you three
times." I'm like, "Okay, I still don't get it." So
my goal there is not to annoy the person, but it's
to understand the content. And actually, by the
way, I say these were messages, I saved them. I
literally screenshot it because I'm like, remember
this? It doesn't matter. I'm trying to learn.
One more question along these lines. I was
looking at your LinkedIn and your career history,
and I noticed that you worked for a different
billionaire every decade of your life.
So there's a guy named Joe Lemond in your twenties
and Chamath in your thirties and Toby this decade,
maybe yourself next decade, if things go well.
Other than what you've shared or maybe it is what
you've shared, is there a thread across these
three folks that have been really successful
that you've learned from that maybe is consistent
across them all or even just specific to each one?
It's interesting because again, this is looking
back, you're like, wait a sec, I didn't plan it
this way. There's no way you could plan it, right?
I'm going to work for a different billionaire
every decade. That's not how it works but
they're similar. They're mostly different people,
but they're similar in one thing is that they
have an irrational view of what the world should
look like over the next decade or so. They're very
long-term thinkers, very rational in that they'll
look and say, "Hey, in 10, 15, 20, 25 years, this
is what the world's going to look like." And I'm
not good at seeing that vision, but I'm good at
trying to move towards that vision 1% a week. And
so the melding of the two, I know where I'm good
and I'm good at pushing the ball forward. And if
they're good at the long-term vision, we can both
align to say, "You're good at this thing. I'm good
at this thing. Why don't we merge forces?"
And so that is something that has resonated
with me is like, how do I find these irrational
all progress depends on the unreasonable man.
How do I pair with these people because I'm
altogether too reasonable and there's no way
for me to become unreasonable, and so I have to
merge with these people. And so that is again,
something that I specifically have sought out. And
even when I was starting my own company in 2015,
I actually sat down and wrote a list of all
the unreasonable people that I knew in Toronto,
and I went down the list and met every single one
of these entrepreneurs to figure out are we API
compatible and could I work with them? And I ended
up picking one of them and starting a company.
That is an amazing story. So first of all, I
just love this insight that being aware of this
is not a superpower of mine and I'm not going
to try to build it. I'm going to find someone
to merge with, and connect your APIs together
and be the person that builds it, not the person
that envisions what to build. I think that's
awesome because a lot of people... I need to
get good at all these things. I need to become
the best at vision and strategy and execution
and collaboration and then all these things. And
so I think alone, this isn't really interesting
instead it's just recognize your strengths and
weaknesses and double down on your strengths.
Yeah, it sounds funny, but me and you talked
about it that a framework I wrote down,
which I tweet out, me writing that down changed
how I picked jobs forever, right? Because I had
this lull after my first job in between where
I was trying to figure out why nothing felt as
exciting as my first job. And it turns out
that it took me to sit down and be like,
what do I actually care about? And people can get
confused. I get confused all the time, by the way,
by things that are not on my framework. So for
example, a good one, title, company, money,
all these things can confuse you because you could
have somebody say recruiter messages you and says,
"Hey, by the way, here's a new job and here's the
compensation." You're like, "Oh my God, this is
exciting." And if you don't have a written down
framework of the things you actually care about,
it's very hard to be distracted. So very hard
not to be distracted. You get distracted by
that. So instead, I look at the framework and
go, does this align with my framework? Right?
Actually to the point of, I actually sent my
framework to a recruiter one time and I said,
"Hey, this thing," because they kept
going back and forth to me and I go,
"Hey, this doesn't align with my framework." So
it really saves me time from not being distracted,
but it also forced me to think about every
year I can reevaluate what I'm doing and
look at the framework and say, "Is this true
to my values?" Now, my wife will say this,
that I'm like a robot. When I realize
that my framework is being violated,
I will resign instantly and I've done that before.
So without even having another job or anything,
I just go like, oh, my framework is being violated
and then resign. There's this thing where I know
what I enjoy working on, and that framework
helps me find it. And so I encourage everyone,
anybody looking for a job I always say, "Write
down a framework. You can use mine as inspiration,
but figure out what you care about and make sure
that what you're working on lines up with that."
And this framework is the questions to ask about
where to go work. That's your framework. Okay,
cool. We'll link to that so folks can check it
out. The example of you resigning when it didn't
meet your framework, is that a story you're up for
sharing? Is there something to learn from that?
Yeah, sure. So this happened when I was
at my previous, a few companies ago,
we were running a mobile company called Xtreme
Labs. That was the one that Chamath was the
major investor in and so we worked with him
directly. And what I realized was... And so
that company was amazing. We worked on it for
many years. It was a mobile app development
company. We got to work on mobile apps for
the biggest brands in the world, Facebook,
Twitter, Instagram, Vine, the NFL, NBA, Bloomberg,
Slack, you name it we worked on those mobile apps,
and this is right when the iPhone and Android
were really gaining steam in '09 to 2013 era.
And then we eventually got acquired by Pivotal.
And over time, my role at Pivotal, Pivotal,
and Pivotal Labs changed from, hey, I was
running the biggest office in the world. I
was running the biggest pair programming office.
I'm a big fan of pair programming to one in which
we were really trying to attach consulting to
the product. And I ended up being a field CTO,
which really, I mean it was fun to learn about
that world, but it was different than what I was
doing. And so if I looked across my framework, it
was violating all the things that I was trying to
work. I wasn't working with the smartest people
anymore. I was on IC. I wasn't learning as much
as I could be learning. And so I wasn't on this
and I wasn't having a lot of impact. I was like,
oh, wait a sec, this is completely not
aligned. And then I just told the team,
"Hey, I plan on resigning." And that, by the way,
led to great other things because I'm an investor
in new companies that have spun out from there
and it was a great experience. I'm just saying
it at the time, lended me to say, "Hey, you're
not actually focused on the right things."
I want to come back to Xtreme Labs. I know
there's other stories there that are interesting,
but first I want to talk about another theme
of things that people often raised when I asked
them about you. And this one is intensity, and
it's specifically creating intensity in your
organization and the value of that, the power of
that. I've seen that the way you describe this
and I love is how do you expend more kilojoules
per hour versus spend more hours on work. So
talk about just why intensity, first of
all, is so important to an organization.
Yeah. So I think there's a few things. One, I have
this fundamental belief that one hour is one hour.
It's the same hour. If you spend an hour or I
spend an hour, it's the same time that goes by.
And if I just expend more calories in that hour.
Let's say we both work nine to five. If I can just
get more done in the nine-to-five, we have both...
The time has elapsed the same for us, but I just
got more done. And that allows me, of course,
then I'd be like, "Hey, I'm going to take my kid
to soccer and do other stuff." We can still do the
same things out of work, but during work, I just
want to try to get as much done as possible during
the time versus expanding the time and I can give
you an example. I used to work at a company
where it was like I worked 12 hours a day, but
I was playing foosball in the middle of the day.
And then we'd go for a coffee break and you do
these things. And of course, the time expanded
to 12 hours versus trying to compress into
that eight-hour day. And pair programming is a
great example because, so it's such an intense
activity. Two people on one machine, you can get
so much done when two people are working together,
not being distracted by the internet and
distractions, and just focus on writing
the solution to the problem at hand. And it's so
tiring that usually when people switch on to pair
programming, they sleep 10 to 12 hours a night the
first few nights because it's so intense. You're
working so hard. But for me, that intensity
actually leads to extraordinary outcomes even
if you don't have to put in more hours. I think
most people, you probably hear this all the time,
everyone says, "Oh yeah, work hard and do
more hours when you're young, whatever."
I'm like, what if you just did more per minute?
Like quickly get through things. I think there's
another unintuitive fact is that people who are
really good can actually output high-quality
collateral quickly. So take a person who is good
and extremely good, the extremely good person can
actually get a lot of output in a short amount
of time, and the person who's good might take
longer. I think there's a time variance there that
people don't think about. So you can not drop the
quality too much, but get the time down by 2X, 3X,
right? Parkinson's Law of scale instead of, if I
give you an hour to do something, a really good
person can get a high-quality output in one hour.
I want to talk about how you create an org
that operates this way, but specifically,
you just mentioned pair programming. I
know that's one of your favorite tools.
Talk about why this is so powerful when you
recommended... I think as an outside observer,
it's like two engineers on the same
code. Why wouldn't we do things half as
fast? Talk about just why you're a big
fan of pair programming specifically.
It is the most underutilized management tool in
engineering, bar none. It is just not used as much
as it could be. So pair programming, for those
who don't know, it's two people on one computer.
So two keyboards, two mics, two monitors, but one
computer, they work together and if it's remote,
they use it. You can use a tool like tuple,
which we use, and you can just remotely be on
one computer, and you're totally right. The famous
tweet about pair programming is, wait a sec,
we have two engineers on one computer, won't they
write half as much code? And the answer is, oh,
no, no, they'll write even less than
that because it's not about lines of
code. The throughput limiter is not hands-on
keyboard. It's not like we're both sitting
there and the limiter is like us trying to
get through the keystrokes onto the screen.
The limiter is where is the good elegant
solution? How do we think through the
problem and build the right solution for the
problem at hand? Tobi famously built a lot of
Shopify paired programming, and what he would do
is he would actually set a timer and him and the
CTO Cody would pair program for one hour. And
if they did not finish the problem in one hour,
they would delete all the code and they would
keep the tests and they would start over. And then
what their thinking was, if we were not able to
articulate and write the code for this feature in
one hour, we must be on the wrong design. We must
be building the wrong thing and so they delete
all the code, kept the tests, and then wrote it
again. And sometimes he'd be over by one minute
and he would still delete the code and start
over because his thinking was the right elegant
solution should be able to be written in one hour.
And so pair programming, I mean, that's an extreme
version of it, but even at Pivotal Labs, if
your pair was sick that day and you wrote a
bunch of code, the strong version is your pair
would come in the next day, delete all the code
that you wrote, and then you'd write it again the
next day. And again, what better time to rewrite
code than right after you've written it because
you now know the problem domain? And by the way,
it sounds like a waste of time. It sounds like
I'm just deleting code but the reason is that
code lives a long time. Code is a liability and
the right solution, the usually shorter lines,
more elegant solution tends to appear after
you've done a bunch of pathfinding. And the
only way to do that pathfinding is start and
then delete and then start and be like, oh, no.
Now I know. Delete. And it's super hard to delete,
by the way, because we're humans and we have this
sunk cost fallacy, so it's hard to delete.
But if you can do that, you will actually land
upon a much, much better solution. And of course,
pair programming has high, high rates of learning
because you're just sitting beside... You're not
only whether it's tuple or remote or directly,
you learn keystrokes and you learn how somebody
thinks about a problem. You go back and forth on
the talking, and yes, you will write probably less
code, but you will move faster along the path of
delivering value for your customers than you would
if you did it on your own. And there's all these
studies that show happiness is higher, knowledge
transfer is higher, less silos, intensity is
higher, all the things. And at a price of 20%
or something of what you would normally do.
The analogy I have is the underhanded
free throw in basketball, statistically
known to sink more baskets, but looks
dumb and nobody does it. Literally,
Shaquille O'Neal, I'm not that big a basketball
fan, but I read this about Shaquille O'Neal,
who's a Hall of Famer, and they said, "Why
don't you throw underhand?" Because he was
notoriously bad at free throws and he
goes, "It looks dumb." Even though he's
paid millions of dollars a year to do this
thing. It looks dumb, doesn't want to do it.
I remember those Shaquille O'Neal years when
he had a special free throw coach, and
I remember them talking about this-
... When he hit a special free throw coach. And,
I remember them talking about this and he's
like, "No, I'm never going to do that."
"I'm never going to do it." Because
it looks dumb. And by the way,
go back to the beginning of the interview. I
don't care what looks dumb or looking stupid,
we're going to do this. And so, actually, I ran
the biggest pair programming shop in the world.
On that note, so what percentage of shop
Shopify do this? Is this how y'all operate?
Yeah. So, Shopify, I mentioned that Toby and Cody
did this at the beginning of Shopify. And the cool
thing about pair programming is, and in my old
world at XtremeLabs is that we knew exactly what
to build, because we were building mobile apps
that were almost like contract manufacturing.
We're like, "We have an iOS version. Can we build
an Android version?" So, we quickly were able to
say, "Here's the spec. Go quick." Shopify is such
a different company, right? We are a pathfinding
company. We are trying to find the right thing
to build. And so, pair programming may or may
not make sense all the time. Like Pivotal
and Xtreme, we were doing 40 hours a week.
Shopify is much more of a four to eight
hour a week pair programming culture,
where you're gathering together on a problem
and saying, "Hey, let's pair for half a day,
or let's pair every Wednesday." And we use that
tool in our arsenal to move quickly down a path.
But a lot of other time is spent pathfinding and
trying to figure out what to build, and trying
to convince field be like, "Hey, we're going
to go down this path. Oh, now I know exactly."
And sometimes, by the way, 18 months later, we've
now figured out all the things and that's the time
we should delete everything and start over. And,
that's something that we will do at that point.
And so, you don't want to be pair programming
for 18 months. You want to be wayfinding and
pathfinding. And then go, "I see the matrix.
Let me just delete everything and now build it."
Because the learning is what you're going for. We
have all the learning, now let's write the code.
Got it. So it's basically, when
the code, you're pretty sure this
is correct and it's really important
segments of the code base pair program.
Yeah. And then also we do a lot of pairing during
an incident or a way to figure out together,
work with somebody and say, "Hey, I'm not
really sure and let's jump on a call together
or jump on a tuple and go down the path." And
say, "Let's figure out together what's going on."
I can't help but ask AI, how does
that impact this way of working?
So, AI is super interesting. What's happening
right now with an AI copilot like GitHub Copilot
is it is your pair programmer. So, you now
can feel like you're pairing actually without
another human. You can pair with the AI. And so,
what's happening too is that you're seeing people
use Whisper, like they're talking to Cursor,
and they're talking through Whisper to say,
"Okay, let's build a new React component that
does this." And they're talking and then it's
building. "Oh no, that's not what I meant.
I meant doing this." So you can actually
not even have to type, just using voice, go
back and forth with your pair programmer.
I would say, that's amazing. I would still contend
take that experience and add two humans together.
So you've got an AI copilot and humans, because
what's happening is generating code. And the two
humans can look and say, "Oh, I know what it's
trying to do." And, either delete the code,
because you have inspiration and write it
yourself, or just take the suggestion and
move it forward. But, I love today's world of
AI copilots, because you never have to code
loan on your own right? You never have to code
alone. You can try a different language now,
because the API and the syntax is much
easier to pull forward. And so, all of
those things are a win for engineering and a win
for everybody who wants to build any software.
That makes a lot of sense. Basically,
everyone's going to be a pair programmer-
Yes, exactly.
... In the future. Okay, I want to come back
to what else you have done at Shopify to create
intensity. And I think, again, it's important to
highlight the intensity is meant to, "How do we
get more done in the time we have and then
go home?" Not just work all day every day,
weekends kind of intensity.
Yeah. So we have a few things that we have going
for us, right? So one, we have this tool called
GSD, which stands for get shit done, which you've
probably heard from maybe talking to other Shopify
folk, which is this notion of weekly updates to
the whole company on what's happening. Again,
Parkinson's law at scale. If you ask people
every week, they want to show progress every
single week. So that's one way I talked about
pair programming as well. The other thing we do
as a company is, we used to have twice a year
was our cadence, Black Friday, Cyber Monday,
or we had an event in the summer. And now, we do
six-week reviews. So, teams have this notion of
every six weeks actually coming together and
walking through the roadmap, the resourcing,
and what they're working on with their
immediate leadership, but then also, with Toby.
And so, what's cool about that, and by the way,
it's a huge time investment, right? We all get
into a room, it's happening tomorrow. So Tuesday,
Wednesday, Thursday, a bunch of us will be in the
office together and we're going to go through
every project in the company, and we're going to
talk about the project, the resourcing, how it's
going, and we're going to make changes. And again,
that creates intensity, because you want to show
what has been done, what have you learned since
the last six-week review. And, we find six weeks
is a very good cadence, because it's short enough
that you can remember the context and it's long
enough... Six weeks is long enough, especially if
you have, let's say, a team of a dozen engineers,
you can do a lot. And not only that, you can do a
lot in a day, but this is a check-in point.
And what I've noticed too with intensity is,
let's say, we get a review and there's some
feedback we get in that review. We don't wait
until the next six-week review, right? The next
day we are building things, we are iterating,
we are tagging people. And then, by the next
week's we're like, "Here's the trajectory."
Right? Actually, I want to get that Elon shirt
made, "What have you done this week?" Because,
Parkinson's law is real. It sounds funny, but I
keep bringing this up, but whatever time you allot
to something will be the time it takes, right?
So, if you're doing something monumental, I don't
know, you're doing a reorg or something, right?
You can do it the slow way. "Let's sit down,
and plan, and roll it out." And it's probably six
months in most companies. Shopify, this is a week
or two. You sit down, you're like, "Hey, this is
the bones of it. Let's bring some more people and
think." But then, it's going to start leaking.
So we just launch it. Right? And, we do the same
thing with lots of things. We just try to move
more quickly and get out of the... We don't do
change management, we just land it, and then go,
"Hey everyone, it's a volatile company. This is
what's happening. But this is how we get things
done quickly." And then, move on with our lives.
Wow, there's so much there. I have been through
the six-month reorgs. And, I think that context
you just shared of, "We're at a volatile
company, we're changing things. It's not going
to be smooth, but we think this is for the best."
It's just the culture of Shopify. It sounds like,
"We want to keep moving fast. We know this
isn't going to be the smoothest thing,
but we just know this better to make
the change at this point versus wait."
It's how Toby increased the resiliency in
the company. He would walk around in the
old days when we had a data center
and just unplugged machines, right?
Chaos monkey.
Yeah, chaos monkey. You're right. But that
actually works, because it just says, "Hey,
by the way, shit's going to break. And so, let's
be resilient to that." And so, same thing here.
"Hey, by the way, someone's going to move your
cheese. It's fine. We are here to create more
entrepreneurs in the world. We're not here to
have a six-month change management roadmap. And,
that will just actually hurt the speed at
which we can deliver value to merchants."
So, on all the things you shared, so
there's weekly updates. So the weekly
updates are each person shares what they're
working on for the week. Is that the idea?
Each project.
So, each project, it has an update, it might have
a video of, "Here's the experience." It'll have a
obviously a bunch of writing on what's changed
since last time. We have a process called OK1
and OK2, which is like, OK1 is typically at
the director level where they're like, "Okay,
I'm aligned with the direction that this
is going at." Or, "I'm not aligned." And
they can make changes. Then, when it goes to
OK2, it's typically the VP level of the area,
who's now looking to say, "Okay. What you're
working on actually aligns with the overall
architecture. But by the way, have you looked
at this context? Maybe you haven't seen this,
this is happening, or the industry." And so,
you're trying to align at that level. And then,
again, like I mentioned, every
six weeks we go through with Toby,
and he's an intense guy himself.
And so, a lot of it is like, "Hey,
why is this taking so long? Are we overthinking
it? Are we not trying to move forward on this
thing, because we're blocked on something? Is
there some piece of infra?" Actually, I'll give
you a good example. In one of the reviews from
last time, there was an interesting AI problem
we were trying to solve with LLMs that required us
to have a very large output context window. And,
most of the LLMs today have a very small output
context window. But in the review, right,
we have shared Slack channels with all the LLM
folks, right? I messaged in the open AI channel,
I messaged in the Gemini channel, whatever. And,
within an hour we had increased the context on
a bunch of major models and we were able to move
forward through the thing, just because I asked.
And so, that's an example. It didn't take another
six week review, but it increased the intensity,
because the team was like, "Oh, we were blocked
because we thought we had to now chunk up this
data and do this thing because we had smaller
output context and we thought we could do a big
input context, but we'd have to do this caching."
And, it was like this whole thing. I'm like,
"Well, did we just ask them if we get
bigger?" And then, they were like, "Oh,
we don't have this as undocumented, but we'll
just enable it right now for Shopify." And so,
that created the intensity of the team to be like,
"Oh, we can now quickly get unblocked." So that's
the example of just moving quick and trying to
just, again, ask a dumb question. I'm like, "This
is probably not possible, but..." And then, they
came back and said, "Oh yeah, we can do that."
That's a great example. And, as you're describing
the ways that you create intensity and velocity
within Shopify, it's interesting that what you're
listing is a bunch of meetings and check ins,
which to most people would feel like, "Why
do we need so many..." There's all this like,
"Less meetings." And I know you guys famously
cancel all your meetings and that's a whole
thing we can talk about. But, it's
interesting that more check ins and
regular check ins allow you to move
faster. I imagine it's partly because
it just makes sure you're not working on
things that are unnecessary, and dumb,
and not going to be used. And it's just continue
to refine, these are actually the most important.
I mean, it's a combination of trust but verify,
right? Because don't forget, the goal of the
check-in is not for you to be like, "Ha, ha, I
caught you not doing your work." It's not like the
Dilbert boss, "Hey, did you do your thing?" Right?
Even when I look at the Elon text, which is like,
"Hey, what did you get done this week?" It
wasn't to try to catch Parag in a, "You didn't
do anything or you did a bunch of useless stuff."
It was hopefully to pair on the problem, meaning,
when I ask somebody, "Hey, did we move forward
on this LLM project, because we now have this
larger context window?" And then, they came back
and said, "Oh, here's what we learned." So then,
I can then look at the answer and say, "Oh,
so now, have you thought of this? Have you
tried..." It's a way to pair on the problem.
So, we have this word, everybody talks about
micromanagement as a word, and we don't
actually think it's a dirty word at Shopify,
but the reason we don't think it's a dirty word is
because it's not just, again, Dilbert boss saying,
"Where did you do the thing?" It's like, "Hey,
can I work on this problem with you? And if I
work on this problem with you, I got to see where
you are pretty often, and then give you advice,
or you're going to share context with me,
because I'm not in the work every day."
To then come back and say, "Oh, based on what I
know and what you know, can we move this in this
direction? Maybe that's better for merchants."
I don't want to overuse the pairing paradigm,
but it is really much like, "Can I pair with
you?" And I learned this actually very early
in my Shopify tenure, because Toby would have
these one-on-ones with me and I'd be like,
"Toby, you don't have to waste your time, man.
You hired me. I got this." Well, he goes, "Oh,
you misunderstand why you're here. We are here
to work on problems together." And I was like,
"Oh, I didn't even think..." I thought he
hired me to take problems away. He hired
me to work on problems with me. That's
completely different than what I thought.
I love that. Okay. One thing you mentioned
is meeting thing. For people that don't know
what you all did with meetings, I think it
might be worth just sharing that briefly,
because it's awesome and something
a lot of companies can learn from.
Yeah, sure. Actually, the funny story
about the meeting Armageddon, is that,
I was messaging Toby prior to me starting
at Shopify about meeting Armageddon. And so,
I actually think I had a little hand in him
doing this before I got to Shopify. I was like,
"Hey, have you seen..." I think it was
Dropbox, "Have you seen a Dropbox is doing
and Meetingageddon? And so, he was like, "This
is super interesting." This is years before I
started. So, I think it's funny that it
ended up being a real thing. But here's
what we do. Once a year at a random time,
we will delete all recurring meetings that
have more than two people, so not one-on- ones,
and are internal people only, so not interviews
or external partner meetings. And then, we have
a two-week moratorium where you're not allowed
to add a reoccurring meeting. You can have a
regular meeting, but not a reoccurring meeting.
And the idea is that there's a lot of inertia
behind a recurring meeting. It just always is
there, and you know it's coming up, and it's
hard to delete, because you're like, "Oh yeah,
we talk about this thing every week." And so,
what we do is we just do a meeting reset. And,
I think, yeah, it's just called chaos monkey and
the admins go in and just delete everything. Now
what's cool about it is, it forces you to
rethink, "Do we need a recurring meeting?
Or do we just need one meeting? Or do we need a
different cadence?" That's one thing. The other
thing is it frees up so much crafter time, right?
One of the stats I track across engineering is how
many hours are individual contributors in meetings
per week? And we noticed that after we did... We
did two things by the way. And I have a spicy
second one for this, but the first one was we
deleted meetings. And the second thing we did
was we moved a lot of our Slack into Facebook
workplace, which I'll talk about. Those are
the only two things we did. And we saw a huge
decrease in the amount of time crafters were in
meetings. And then, we saw all kinds of other
productivity enhancements, because they were
able to have that flow time and work on things.
So, we're at something like three hours of
meetings per week for an individual contributor
at Shopify, which is phenomenal. Three hours a
week is amazing. I think managers is not that
bad. I think I tweeted this. I think it's six
or seven hours per week. That's not bad at all,
in order to get aligned. And then,
all the rest of the time is work time.
And how many hours was it before
Meetingageddon and Workplace?
Yeah, you're asking me a good question. I have to
go look and see. But, it came down by something
like 50 or 60%. It was something like five or
six hours for individual contributors and came
down to three. And then, the managers,
I think it was 10 that came down to 6,
something like that. But it was a huge difference.
And the only two things, like I mentioned,
were one was the Meetingageddon, the other one was
like this, and I can talk about this. This is a-
Yes, let's talk about this.
... Yeah. So, I mean, I love Slack. It's the
IM tool. Everybody uses it. But it can for sure
cause distraction. And so, what we did was
we moved all announcement information. So,
anytime you're sending a status update or
large group announcement, we moved all of
that to Facebook Meta Workplace, like Facebook for
work basically, which is now being deprecated. So,
we'll have to figure that out. But, it just moved
all this stuff to a ML feed that you can consume
differently than you would Slack, because Slack
is like I message you and you see an alert and
all this stuff, versus Workplace is like, "Oh, I
want to go and consume content from the company,
and get updates, and share updates." And so, that
reduced a lot of distraction as well. And so,
I'd love to figure out what the next tool for
us is, but it is probably something more like
a river of information that I can dip my
toe into, versus IM and chat everywhere.
That is super interesting. So,
specifically, things that are just
updates where you don't need a discussion,
you almost want to discourage a discussion.
Yeah, I mean, it has the commenting, but
it's not the same tool. And, by the way,
Slack is amazing, we use it.
It's just that for this thing,
it wasn't working for us. And so, we
wanted to move that somewhere else.
I feel like, the more I dig into the
Shopify way of working, the more fun
stuff I never expected emerges. I'm curious
what else is going to emerge. So we've been
talking about ways that y'all, and you
specifically, have created intensity,
especially in the engineering organization. And
then, you've also shared just broadly Shopify.
What else is on that list? What else have you
found helps create more kilojoules per hour?
Yeah, so again, I think there's nothing, I would
say again, start from the beginning, there's
nothing more than pair programming, because
literally you can't do anything else but be on
your computer. So pair programming is the number
one. I will say, the weekly cadence helps a lot,
right, which you mentioned. Again, which is
part of GSD, which is sharing the updates,
and then the six-week reviews, that does a
lot. On the other side, we also have a lot
of metrics and alerts that help us see when
potentially things might be happening in the
system that can allow us to be like, "Hey,
wait a sec, there's too many things going on
of this type. We probably have to sit back
and reset and figure out what's going on."
So one thing that happened, for example, was
we started seeing that it was taking a lot of
time to develop in our admin, like engineers at
Shopify developing in the admin. So we called,
what's called, a code yellow, which is before
code red. But code yellow is this idea of like,
"Hey, we're going to call a code yellow on the
admin." We want to make sure that the developer
experience inside Shopify is really good. It
should be easy to start up the repo. It should
be easy to make changes, it should be easy to see
the changes. And so, those are the things that,
again, we can create intensity, because this code
yellow allows the champion to tap anyone on the
shoulder and say, "Stop what you're doing
and come help this thing." Which is an
infrastructure layer thing. And by building out
this infrastructure, it allows you to go fast. It
takes longer to build infrastructure, but it
makes you go fast forever afterwards, right?
I'll actually give you an example of one of these.
So, we in 2020, 2021, the heyday of pandemic,
obviously, there was a crypto summer again
and crypto was going nuts. And we were sitting
back and saying, "Wow, a lot of our merchants
are now asking for NFT gating." NFT gating,
which is, "If you have the token, you can now
go into the storefront and see my products.
You can see my prices and you can check it
out, but only if you have the token." And,
we were getting a lot of demand from merchants
to be like, "We want to do this. We want to sell
an NFT. And we want our buyers to have the NFT to
have this great experience." And we're like, "We
agree. We want you to be able to do whatever you
want. And so, we want to build this for you too."
And, sitting with Toby, he's like, "You
guys are thinking about it wrong." He goes,
"How long would it take to build NFT gating?" I'm
like, "I don't know. Two, three weeks." He goes,
"Now, how long would it take to build a platform
layer, which exposes APIs so anyone could build
NFT gating in one hour?" I'm like, "I don't know.
Two, three months." He goes, "Do that." He goes,
"Because you don't know what they're going to
build on top of the platform." NFT gating is
one thing, one use case, but if you spend the
time to build out the infrastructure layer,
he calls it putting gas in the tank, if you put
the gas in the tank, people could drive on that
gas for a long time going forward. And so, he
goes, "I always want you to think about..."
And the key part was, "What can you build so
anyone could build this in one hour?" Right?
So, he does this thing to us all the time where
he goes, "Oh, this should only be..." He'll say
it and people get the wrong thing. He'll say, "Oh,
you could write this in a day." And what he means
is, "What has to be true so that you could write
this in a day? What infrastructure do you need?"
And, he actually develops this way. He will
write code against an API that doesn't exist,
because he's like, "You know what should
exist here? This API." He'll write the code,
he'll go back and forth and refine the client on
the server, and then he'll go, "This is correct,
the correct client code. Now, let
me go implement the server code."
And this is notion of building things as
infrastructure that sound slower today, because
it's going to take... It's two, three months,
instead of two or three weeks. But after that, the
things that people built on top, right, were so
easy to build, there were so many more scenarios
that were emerged. It's just a different way of
thinking about software. And, it's intensity in
a different way, it's intensity around building
this infrastructure layer, which we want to build
quickly, but takes two or three months, in this
case, but then can get everyone building on top
of our infra in a much, much quicker way. And of
course, who knows what can flourish from there?
It's interesting and it makes sense that so much
of the way you all think is about building the
best possible platform, versus the, necessarily,
best possible point solution for someone. And
it also explains why you spend so much time in
crafting really great code and pair programming,
because again, it's a platform for
other people to build stuff on. So,
I think, a lot of this is very useful,
especially for platform businesses.
No, exactly. And actually, you're making me
think of a stat. So, last year, maybe a tangent,
but I tweeted out that GitHub Copilot has written
over 1 million lines of code for Shopify. And
people are like, "Oh my god." And it got picked
up. And everyone's talking about it. And I go,
"I don't know why is everybody getting so crazy,
because what I want to see is GitHub Copilot
deleting 1 million lines of code." That's when you
know we're actually at this point where this is
close to an engineer. Right? And so, we famously
have deleted millions of lines of code this year,
because we were trying to focus on, again,
the sunk cost and rebuilding things elegantly,
or you don't need this anymore and rebuilding.
And I even tweeted out, I think someone said,
"Oh, Shopify is in the top 10 Ruby code bases in
the world." And I said, "I never want to see us
on this list again." We shouldn't be gunning for
number one, we should be gunning for number 100,
right? We want to be not on this list.
Right? Someone else can take the crown.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta. When
it comes to ensuring your company has top-notch
security practices, things get complicated fast.
Now, you can assess risk, secure the trust of
your customers, and automate compliance for SOC 2,
ISO 7001, HIPAA and more with a single platform,
Vanta. Vanta's market leading trust management
platform helps you monitor compliance, alongside
reporting and tracking risk. Plus, you can save
hours by completing security questionnaires with
Vanta AI. Join thousands of global companies
that use Vanta to automate evidence collection,
unify risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go to
Vanta.com/lenny. That's V-A-N-T-A.com/lenny.
Wait, talk about more about this. So, there's
been a drive to delete code and simplify.
What's behind that? What's going on there?
Yeah, so there's a few things, right? One
is, the more context you can fit in your
head around a code base. And you can never
really fit all of Shopify in your head,
because it's a big complicated set of tools we
give to merchants. But, the more you can simplify,
the much easier everything becomes, resiliency,
performance, reliability, maintainability, all
the illities become much, much, much easier when
the code base is simple. Now, all you need really
is the mandate of like, "Oh, well, let's look
at this code. And, if I could start this today,
would I really build this thing? Or do I now
have enough domain expertise to say, 'Oh no,
this is the right solution?' So can I delete
start over and build this more easily?" And now,
everything else becomes easy to build on top of.
And so, routinely, we have a delete code club,
we have hack days, which happens two or three
times a year, where there's always one team
that is focused on deleting code. They even have
a manual, "Here's how to find things to delete."
And, it's amazing. We almost always delete.
I don't know if this is good or bad. We can
always almost find a million plus lines of code
delete, which is insane. But, at the same time,
I applaud the teams for going after the cruft and
the code base. And everything gets easier, right?
Codelets loads faster. It's easier to understand.
This is why when I look at GitHub stats,
you shouldn't really look at... I
think Google put out and said, "Oh,
25% of all code is now written by AI." I'm like,
"Where's the delete? Where is the 25% of all code
is deleted by AI?" Right? This is where we have
to start thinking about it. Because, the right
code is never the volumous lines of code metric.
It's always something else. It's always elegance.
And that's where we have to think
about. So, it is something that,
as part of us being long-term infrastructure
thinking, we really do care about that.
I love this, in part, because it connects to
the topic we're talking about, which is speed,
velocity, intensity, smaller code base,
cleaner, better code base allows you to
move faster. I used to be an engineer actually.
But, both my engineering brain and my PM brain,
I love the idea of killing stuff that's
useless, fixing, making code cleaner,
and better, and more durable. In reality, very
hard for companies to prioritize this thing.
Is there anything you found that helps
you do that? You mentioned hack days and
weeks are one part of that. Probably helps
that Toby's an engineer and he understands
the value of this stuff. But I guess, for
folks that want to do this more, any advice?
Yeah. So actually, when we're building something,
we think of it in one of three buckets. We're
like, "Are you building an experiment, a feature,
or infrastructure?" And, once you bucket things,
you can say, "Oh, it's an experiment." You're
like, "Cool. This is not infra. This is like,
we're trying something to learn." And, by the
way, that might turn into an experiment or infra,
but it starts off as an experiment.
Now, if you're building a feature,
a feature is basically you're taking advantage
of an existing piece of infra, right? So,
token gating is the example I gave. If you could
now build that in one hour, you would probably
say, "Oh, we have the right infra below it."
But if you did what Toby does, which is, he's
like, "Here's the infra I wish existed. Here's
the feature. The feature might be quick to build,
but now I have to go and build the infra."
You're now slotting yourself into infra land,
which is like, that could take longer, but you're
now enabling it for a bunch of use cases. You
don't have to think about it at once, because you
may have people using your API in a different way.
So, I think you have to slot yourself. Now,
how do people get into this mode? It is super,
super hard. And, I would say, Toby is the secret
sauce here, because he pushes us to think about
things as infra almost all the time. I mean, one
of the things that annoys me the most probably is
that I'll always come to him and say, "Hey, we
can do A or B." And he looks at me and he goes,
"You know what I'm going to say, right?" I'm like,
"You're going to say go back and generate more
options." Because he doesn't like those. "I don't
like A or B. Come back when you have something
else." Right? Actually, maybe I'll tell you a
little anecdote. He has a story where he says,
"There are unlimited amount of wrong options
for any problem. There's probably 10,000 right
options, but everybody stops at the first right
one, instead of what you should be spending all
your time on, because the options that don't work,
you're not going to spend time on. But you have to
figure out which of the 10,000 options is the
right one and spend time in what are all these
right options? Don't just stop at the first one."
And so, when I come to and say, "A or B." I'm
picking two of the 10,000. And he's like, "That's
not what I... Go back and generate more options,
because those are not the optimal ones." So, he
is quite the philosopher on these things. And
it does really change the way the company works,
because he'll push you on these things. And then,
we over time learn to spot the same patterns.
And I learned to push my team on infra,
and deleting code, and making things simple,
because by the way, who doesn't want to get
free stuff? Right? Free performance, free, easy
to navigate code base, free maintainability,
free resiliency,, because now, we went and
did the hard work of deleting. It is hard. But
that goes back to the beginning, right? Choose
the hard thing. Don't just build the feature-
The beginning, right? Choose the hard
thing. Don't just build the feature,
go make the feature easy to build.
I feel like there's just more and more good stuff.
What else is there that might be helpful to folks
while you're thinking about it? And interesting,
I was reading your tweet where you shared a lot of
this advice, and you mentioned this briefly, but
I think it's important with pair programming, one
of the benefits is there's no multitasking. You're
not checking Twitter, Slack while you're working
because you're there being watched. And I could
see why that is more productive just innately.
Oh no, for sure. Again, like underhand
or free throws not only looks dumb,
it feels dumb. People don't... They feel
like they're wasting time sitting beside
somebody and being like, "Well, I could
be on my computer doing this thing." But
together they are building a machine.
Do you ever read the Undoing Project,
which is about Amos Tversky and Daniel
Kahneman, the famous philosopher.
By Michael Lewis, I think.
Behavioral economist. Michael Lewis. Exactly. And
he said the famous line was "Alone, we're okay,
but together, we're a genius." Right? That's a
pair programmer. That's like two people. You're
like, "Ah, we're okay. But together, we're a
genius." And that's exactly what pair programming
is. And hopefully me plus an LLM is a genius as
well, but that's the genesis of that thinking.
So I would say another thing that helps us create
intensity is demo culture. So as part of the GSD
updates, hopefully we encourage people to share
high fidelity updates, which is not just imagery,
but actually a demo. One of the things that can
go wrong with just their screenshots is you don't
really get the full experience. You can't tell
how slow things are or whatever, but with a demo,
so you can put a link. We have this tool called
Spin, which is an internal development environment
like a cloud dev environment where you can say,
"Hey, click here to try this on Spin, and then
you can try it and you can see how it works."
Or they say, "Turn on a beta flag in your own
store and then try it." And so this short circuits
a lot of misunderstandings, because you're like
"I'm going to try it." And you're not waiting
until the end, especially with a beta flag.
You're like, "Hey, it's in my store. I just
realized that I went in and now this page takes
20 seconds to load. Is that what you expect?"
You're like, "Oh, we didn't find this use case."
You're going to learn that much more quickly.
And that creates, again, intensity on the fidelity
of the feedback you're getting because famously,
some of our PM team will create a friction log.
They'll be like, "I am walking.." They'll just
create a screen share, create a video and go,
"I'm walking through. I turn on the beta flag,
I'm walking through this experience. Here's my
feedback on the experience." And you're getting
this high fidelity throughput coming back to you
that you're like, "Okay, let's fix these
things for next week's iteration and then
share another beta flag and say, 'Okay,
try it now. Try it now. Try it now.'" And
so you're not debating about status reports,
you're kind of debating about the experience.
So I'm trying to think broadly
all the things you've shared,
kind of how they fit together that allow you
to move this fast. And I just looked up a few
stats to give people a sense of just the size
of the company today and how successful it
has been as they hear the stuff we're talking
about. So you guys are about 11,000 employees,
something like that according to the Googles. And
you're hitting not necessarily all-time highs on
market cap because COVID gave you guys a big
boost for a while, but you're kind of coming
back to this insane valuation that you all
had during COVID. So it's essentially all-time
highs at a 10,000 plus person company moving
really fast, shipping constantly. People love
the product. And it feels like one key of what
you're describing is essentially this operating
rhythm that creates these check-ins that keep
people moving and focused on the right sorts
of tools and getting them quick feedback
if they're moving in the wrong direction.
And having the leaders pair with
those people on those problems,
not just checking in, but actually pairing
with them on the problems that they're
facing. So you get both the crafters
who are working on the stuff and the
leaders who may have broader context
working together to kind of unblock.
And it's so interesting that it's like,
again, people often are often like,
"We don't need meetings. Get rid of all
the meetings." You guys do that, but also,
there's a lot of power in strategic meetings
and check-ins. Another kind of bucket is just
the engineering environment, engineers
working with engineers, pair programming,
things like that. There's a tool you mentioned
for pair programming, Tuple, I think.
Tuple. Yeah. It's funny because we use it
exclusively, but we actually have this line
internally, we call it, Shopify should be a
crafters' paradise. It should be the place
where crafters come to practice their craft
and get better at their craft. Obviously,
resonates from a lot of the engineering crafters,
but it's not only engineering, it's UX and PM and
ML, all the places where you'd want those
people to actually have a great experience.
We want them to come to Shopify because we
believe this is the best place for that.
I love it. I just wrote a note down of just
how you set up your teams for success. Oh,
just avoid distractions. So I think the pair
programming helps the workspace, workplace shift
from Slack helps. I think you're also very firm
on their working hours. You basically don't let...
No.
No. Okay. [inaudible 00:57:04]
No, not really. Yeah. We're not super firm
on working hours from that perspective,
but we do have a lot of people on East Coast
time zones. A lot of stuff happens then,
but we do have people all over the world. But
I did mention we do have the check-ins and the
six-week reviews on the cadence. So that six
week cycle does give you a little bit of the,
what did you get done and are you blocked
mentality. And you can expect coming in a
couple of times and being like, "Hey, we
didn't get a lot done being unblocked."
For you to change your approach to go, "Okay,
I don't want to go to another review where we
didn't get a lot done." So what am I doing
this time to make sure we unlock a lot of
progress? And that check-in can give you that
ammo to be like, "Let's do this this time."
And you're also remote first as a company.
Yes.
Which I think is especially cool. Now a lot of
companies are going back to not remote. You guys
are staying remote. Why do you guys decide to do
that? What have you seen as a big benefit of that?
Yeah, so we have this remote, so I like to
call it 90% remote or 95% remote because
we have these intentional IRL experiences. So
every summer, we just started last year. Sorry,
this year. We're doing this thing called Shopify
Summit where we bring the whole company together,
get together and it's a combination of talks plus
hack days and it's a come together experience
like food and parties and bands. And it's a
super fun way to re-energize and rebuild your
trust battery over time. And then we have this
thing called bursts, which is, "Hey, you want
to work on a problem? You need to prototype,
you need to hack." People can just say, "Hey,
I'm starting a burst. We're going to have five
people. We're all going to go to Ottawa or Toronto
or Montreal or somewhere else and we're going
to talk about this problem and get together."
And so a combination of those two things mean
throughout the year, you can recharge. We have
the trust battery notion, which is how much
trust can you have between people and it can
deplete over time if you're remote. So then we
have offices which are like, come in if you want.
Like I mentioned, I come in once a week and now
Toby moved to Toronto, so now I'm in three days
a week. But it's like if you want to come in, you
don't have to, right? Today, I work from home,
but tomorrow, I'm going in. And that allows you,
again, to have those random interactions and allow
you to feel like, yeah, we're 90 plus percent
remote. But I would say the main reason is we
want to hire the best people in the world and
those people can be anywhere and just happens
to be that not all of them are near an office.
But again, with the bursting, here's a good
example. For Black Friday, Cyber Monday, I
encouraged all engineering leadership to come
to Toronto. We're all going to be in the office
watching the graphs. And then for hack days,
I try to get people to go to the ports, which
we have four of them, Toronto, Montreal, Ottawa,
and New York, which again are come in if you
want, but then get that IRL. And so it's kind
of a little bit of a combo. I wouldn't
call it hybrid though because you don't
really have every Friday you come in or don't
come in. It's more like, come in if you want.
There's so many things to talk about.
This trust battery metaphor by the way
is awesome. I've learned to use it also.
And again, it's just basically everyone,
your trust with someone is like, think
of it as a battery that can deplete and
grow and you should try to charge it up when
you can and then use that charge over time.
And it can be strategic by the way. I've seen
people use it as a... I'm pretty sure Toby says
he starts everyone at 50% and then he gets
to know you. And then I've seen people use
it as the opposite, saying, "Hey, look, this
team is hard charging. I'm going to start you
at a hundred. Assume that you already have high
trust, do the things, and only if you are doing
things that are off alignment, does your trust
battery deplete." So I've seen people use it,
the terminology as a shortcut way to
figure out how to work with somebody.
I love just how first principles you all are,
and there are so many things are so unique to
how you operate and clearly it's working. And
so I feel like we just keep going on and on. I
want to talk about hiring. I know you have some
pretty unique perspectives on how to hire people
that are awesome, but also, hire them quickly.
But before we get there, is there anything else
that you think might be really valuable to share
in terms of intensity, velocity, moving fast?
I think the personality of the leadership team is
quite intense. We have a lot of founders on the
exec team, which are impatient, intense people by
design. But even some of the non-founders are just
accomplished people who tend to be pretty, we all
have this attitude of impatience, and so maybe,
I don't even know if that's a learned skill you
can learn or if it just comes along with your
personality, like genetics. But we typically, even
at the leadership team, for example, we try to do,
here's my weekly thread of all the things that
are going on so that we can not only share,
but also show progress on things. And
then someone can jump in and say, "Oh,
this thing you're doing, it relates to
my thing that I'm doing over here." It
creates this notion of, there's a lot going
on all the time and we want to keep the vibes,
keep the energy high. So a lot
of high energy intense people.
It reminds me while I was at Airbnb, it felt
like no matter how well things are going,
it always felt like Brian especially is just pedal
to the metal. No matter how well things are going,
it's not going well enough. How do
we go faster? How do we do more?
Well, I would actually go further. I think if
you don't have two or three big projects that
are on fire, you're probably not pushing hard
enough because you're not really trying things
that are outside of your... If everything's going
well, are you really taking the risks you need to
be taking? So I think you have to over-rotate
a bit and there should be a few things on fire
at all times, not because you should create
that, but it should just happen because you're
stretching into new things that potentially
or you're going faster than you should have,
or there's a new leader you've counted on
early because all these things that should
create this thing of it might work. And so you
want to have a little bit of chaos at the edge.
I love that. And it may sound stressful and
why would I want that? Why would I want to
work with chaos and fires everywhere? But
in reality, if you don't, your business
is unlikely to become incredibly successful
and that is even more stressful and painful.
Correct. Yeah, it's like the opposite, right?
It's like this idea of people feel like the
comfort gives you stability, and really the
uncomfort gives you stability because now you're
constantly learning and that makes you more
robust against things that could come across.
Choosing the harder path, some might say. Okay,
let's talk about hiring. You have some
really interesting takes on hiring. One
that I've heard about is that you don't
like the interview process. You kind
of like to prefer not to interview and
do something instead. Talk about that.
Yeah. So throughout my career, what I've
noticed is that, and I'm sure everybody,
this is a dirty little secret, right? Interviews
are not a good predictor of performance. We
know this. We know this from studies. We know
this. Everybody at their company knows this,
where somebody interviewed well, wasn't as good
in the job or the opposite, didn't interview
well and then came in and was phenomenal. One
example I have from my startup right before we
came to Shopify was I hired two people for machine
learning. One was a PhD, taught at the university,
was like, oh my god, no brainer, was also
recommended by an employee. We're like,
"Oh my god, this person's going to be
great." The other person was a dude I
met at the coffee shop who had never had a
software job but was just so interested in
machine learning and person A, we let go within
a few weeks because not a fit for our culture.
And person B was at our startup and is still at
Shopify today and is a phenomenal machine learning
engineer who literally at our Christmas party was
like, "This is my first software job." We're like,
"How?" It was just so cute. And we gave them
both the shot. The key was I didn't use the
resume in either way to bias. We brought them
both in. We said, "Here's the environment." It
was all pair programming at my startup. And so
they pair program, and actually as an aside,
I really believe in pair programming when
I made people work in pair programming with
my own money. I paid for two people to be
on one computer. So that's how you know...
Less than half the code.
Yeah, exactly. Right. Less than half the code. But
anyway, so pairing. And it was pretty clear after
just a few weeks, I would say let's say up to
three months is the amount of time I give people,
that person A wasn't going to work out than
person B was. So what I really like to do is
use this race car analogy. If I told you, "Hey, I
want to go hire the best race car driver," there's
not really that many questions you could ask them
except for put them in the car. And so the same
thing happens with us is that of course, we have
to do interviews, but we do really spend time in
the 30, 60, 90 days to make sure that the thing
that they are bringing actually lines up with
what we need at Shopify. And you should also be
transparent with people because if it's not a fit,
it's actually good for them and you to
figure that out as quickly as possible
because they could be amazing somewhere else.
We mentioned the chaotic environment and fast
moving environment Shopify is, that's not for
everyone, but that's okay, right? We're not
looking for... We've talked about that we want to
be as the best 10,000 person company in the world.
We're not looking for millions of people. We just
need the best 10,000. And so if it's not a fit,
it's in your interest and our interest
to figure that out quickly so that you
can go somewhere where you will be amazing and
for us to have the people who will be amazing
at Shopify. And so job trials, I'm a huge
fan of, which leads me to intern programs,
what a great interview process because you now
have real work product from somebody for four
months. They get to see what it's like to be
at Shopify for four months. We get to see what
it's like for them to be at Shopify for four
months, and that can turn into a full-time gig.
And that's a great interview process because
you literally know exactly. You don't have to...
I'll give you a funny example. I think I've
heard a company where, "Oh, we have an intern
process and then afterwards, we interview them for
full-time." I'm like, "What are you going to learn
from let's say even eight hours of interviews that
you're not going to have learned from four months
of real work experience?" And so there's just
things like that. You just got to look at the
work product. And so I'm a big fan of job trials,
and in my previous companies, like you mentioned,
I almost didn't interview anybody. I almost just
said, "Come in and work." And it allowed us... We
had a much higher in the first 90 days, like
20% attrition before 90 days because it just
didn't work out. But those after 90 days, we
had less than 1% attrition because they knew
exactly what they're getting into and we
knew exactly how they were going to fit.
So in terms of the hiring process, you're
still at Shopify. You're interviewing people,
they're doing technical evaluations, things
like that. But it sounds like there's a very
strong setting of expectations. "We will
hire you, but we'll actually clarify if
this is a good fit in the first 30, 60, 90
days and we're going to do... We may let you
go and there's a good chance we may let you
go." Is that just the way you set things up?
Yeah, I think the way to think about, it's more
like we want to make the interview process as
close to the real job as possible because
by doing that, we can likely assess the
skills that you have in your interview closer to
what's happening in the job. So that's one. Two,
we have this interview step called the life
story where we try to figure out if, are all
the experiences you've had up until now actually
going to be... Does it show that you are a curious
person with range? Because if it does, that's
likely more of someone who's going to be a fit. I
had this famous line from somebody who said, "You
know what I don't like about resumes?" I'm like,
"What?" They go, "It tells you what you did, but
it doesn't tell you why you did those things."
And it's such an interesting insight.
Your resume should be a why, like why
did you go from this company to this? That's
the interesting part. Not that you are a PM
at Microsoft and a PM at Stripe. It's like, why
did you switch from Stripe to Microsoft? There's
something interesting there. And so the life
story is trying to pull that out. It's like,
why did you make the decisions? What did you do in
your past that was interesting? Are you curious?
I always thought... I read this great book, Range
by David Epstein. That book was maybe one of the
hardest books for me to read in my life because
every page I was like, "I don't believe it." I
kept thinking I was a specialist. I kept turning
the page going, "I don't like this data that keeps
showing that generalists are better." And then
by the end, I realized that I'm a generalist.
It took me so long to realize, and funny for me
because I ended up redesigning the compensation
system for Shopify, even though I'm an engineer.
So I still thought of myself as an engineer
through and through, even though I work
on recruiting and HR and all these other
things. But I think that that's what
we're trying to tease. And then yes,
in that first period, we actually have a
survey that goes over Slack that says, "Hey,
how happy are you with the person that you hired?"
And that should, in conversation with the person,
you should give them the feedback to figure out,
"Hey, are there things you need to adjust to
better fit in and make sure the expectations are
set up?" But then also, together with the person,
figure out, "Hey, if you're not feeling this,
let's find you either a different role in the
company or somewhere else because we want the
people here to have high impact." But that
person should have high impact somewhere, could
be at Shopify, could be in the same role, could
be in a different role, could be at a different
company. But that's a good thing for everybody.
And then do you actually do work
trials with new engineering hires,
or is that something you aspire to do?
Yeah, I would love to do it. It's hard to do
with the volume resumes we get, but we do do it
at scale with the internship program. So like
2025, we're going to hire a thousand interns,
and that is going to give me a thousand job
trials to pick the top X percent of
those to come to Shopify full time.
So just to double-click on that, so
you're hiring a thousand interns over
the course of the year. That's a lot. And
the idea there is these folks are actually
useful building useful things, and it's
an interview process for the internship.
Yeah, I think it's two things. One is
some people look at an internship program
as community service. Let's give back to the
community. Let's hire early talent. And I'm like,
"Hold on a sec. Are you telling me I could hire
a thousand people over the year?" And they will
come to work with an LLM and a brain because
they're growing up in the age of AI. They will
be useful to us because they come from a different
generation and they have, in our case in commerce,
they have a different experience about shopping
and AI and bots and chat and voice and all these
things. They'll be useful to us. We'll
teach them some stuff as well. And then
together we can decide if they might end up going
somewhere else, in which case, we have the Shopify
imprint on them going to whatever other company,
which is I think a positive, or they might stay
at Shopify and be useful over a longer period.
It seems like win, win, win. The other thing
that was cool is after I did that tweet, a
bunch of other CTOs messaged me and said,
"Hey, we're going to hire 1,001 interns to beat
you guys." And I'm like, "Great." Just from
that one tweet, if I can get the early talent
ecosystem restarted here after a really tough
last few years and layoffs, it's great for
everybody because now they're realizing that
they also realize that these people are super
valuable and they bring together a completely
different set of skills. And by the way, here's
a secret in pair programming, interns will always
be more intense than the full-time. And so that
also helps the flywheel of intensity go for it.
It all just keeps coming back. Did the
internship program emerge out of this
co-op system that Canadian schools have
and a Waterloo has a big co-op program?
Yeah, I went to Waterloo. And so yeah, hint,
hint. So I went to Waterloo and I did co-op and
I did intern programs there. It was amazing. What
a great experience, because what ends up happening
is you leave Waterloo with your degree, but also
with two years of experience because I did six
four-month work terms, 24 months, and you end
up walking. I think one of the big parts of it
is just interview skills because I interviewed for
10 plus jobs every four months, and I did that six
times. And so you come out having done lots... You
have a lot of interview experience, but you also
have work experience. And so just taking that to
the next level, Shopify has always had interns.
And what I felt like we needed to do was,
again, restart this notion of early talent
in the ecosystem. I would say one or two
big differences with our intern program.
One is we're making them come in three days a week
versus full remote. And the reason for that is,
and we're doing it just in three
offices right now in Montreal,
Toronto and Ottawa. And the reason for that is
because we want them to have a cohort because
early talent is different than you and I who've
been in the industry. We worked in office, we
worked out of office. We're more comfortable with
navigating partnership discussions and talking to
people in different companies. But these people
have not. They may have never worked anywhere.
And so to not have the IRL component would do
them a disservice. And so we specifically made
it in those ports and the people are traveling
by the way, they're moving to Montreal to do the
internship. It's great. And then if you're
a mentor or manager for one of the interns,
you have to at least see them like IRL
once a month. So we're kind of making
these experiences. And of course, they'll have a
cohort of dozens of people that will be with them
along the way. And so we think that'll just
make their experience better. And of course,
nothing like tapping someone on the shoulder and
be like, "Have you seen this era before?" And so
it's easier in an early talent situation. And then
of course over time, if they become full-time,
they can still come to the office. It's come
if you want, but they can also go full remote.
That is amazing. For folks that don't know
anything about these co-op programs briefly,
it's just basically while you're
in school, before you graduated,
during the summer, you go work at a company.
No.
Oh, during the year. Okay.
Yeah, it's during the year. So what happens at
Waterloo is, what I did was I did eight months of
school at the beginning. So two terms. My first
co-op term was summer, but then it was work,
school, work, school, alternating for
the whole rest of my time at Waterloo.
It's like semesters alternating.
Exactly. So every four months I did either school
term or work time. So I was doing work in January
sometimes and September sometimes. And it was
super good because again, it also allowed me
to be super intense at school for four months
and then go to super intense work experience
for four months. But yeah, it's a model that...
I was just at Waterloo this week doing a talk,
so I love that symbiotic relationship between
Waterloo and the employers, by the way, not just
Waterloo. Lots of schools do a summer program,
UFT and others, lots of schools in the states.
Fun fact. So total tangent, I had a startup
called Local Mine, started it in Montreal of
all places. I'm not Canadian, but moved there
for various reasons. It was awesome. And our
first hire was actually from the co-op
program. I don't know if it was Waterloo,
his name is Nick Adams. And he applied.
Just he saw our job posting, I think,
and were like, "What is a co-op?" And
he came to work and then he went back to
school, and then we hired him, and then
he ended up at Airbnb when we got a card.
There you go. So for us, actually, when I did
my startup Helpful, I had one or two engineers,
and then I actually literally just hired four
interns because you hired them in February for
May. And because I was doing pair programming, I
had to make sure I had four full times by then.
So I hired the interns in anticipation of
having the full times. And I literally had,
I think I was off by one week, so one intern had
no pair for a week, but then after that in May,
I had four full times, four interns,
and then they paired the whole time.
What a journey. I want to talk about just
one other topic real quick and then we'll
wrap this up. And it's around XtremeLabs. So
there's a bunch of stuff here. It feels like
it's just like this tech mafia of Canada that
a lot of incredible people emerged out of,
and there's a whole bunch of stuff we can
talk about. One fact I heard while you were
there is you had a hundred reports,
direct reports that reported to you.
A 120.
120 direct reports feels like
a complete nightmare to me.
Tell me why you decided to do that, if
you'd recommend that for other people.
Yeah, so what ended up happening there was we
started off small. It was 10 people. When I got to
XtremeLabs, I wasn't the founder, but I was very
early on and I just had everyone report to me. And
then as we grew, I just kept having those people
report to me and I was trying to figure out,
we talked about crafters and crafters paradise,
this idea of people don't really... Their managers
are useful, but I was trying to figure out
could I solve the problems that they needed
their manager for in other ways? So for example,
what should I be working on? I was like, "Okay,
well, we have product backlogs" or "I'm blocked
on something," or "I need feedback on the product
I'm building," or "I'm stuck on this technical
problem." I tried to figure out ways to not
have managers be the answers to those questions.
I'm like, "There should be another answer." And so
pair programming really helps you get unblocked
quickly because you have another person that
you can bounce technical ideas off of. Having a
product backlog can tell you what to work on. We
had demos every week, demos internally, and then
we had demos with the clients every week because
we were a contract manufacturing for mobile. That
gave them feedback on whether they were going in
the right direction. We had set working hours,
which made things super intense in the office.
This is again like 2009 to 2013. So all these
things didn't really need a manager. And what
I realized was what the unblocking thing needed a
manager. I'm blocked on this. Well, I said, okay,
if... I had all these directors. I did two things
famously. One, I had a lot of direct reports,
and two, I did not do any scheduled one-on-ones
because you can't have 120 direct reports and
do a scheduled one-on-ones because you're
never doing anything but one-on-ones.
So I said, "I'm going to be around a lot
because I don't have a lot of one-on-ones.
So we can do unscheduled one-on-ones."
And what that means is if you are blocked,
actually there's a famous picture where I had
this weird cube desk where it was like a circle
almost in the middle of the whole floor of
engineers. And I was always there because I
wasn't in a lot of meetings and people that were
blocked, they could just come up to me. Actually,
one cool thing about pair programming IRL is you
can look across and just see if it's working or
not. Because if two people are intensely on
the computer, you know it's working. If one
person is laying back or you're like, "It's
not working," so you can just walk up to-
It's working if one person is laying back or
you're like, it's not working. So you could just
walk up to them and be like, "What's happening?"
But they would come and ask me questions and I
can unlock them. Like, hey, we're blocked on
this. We don't have this API. We need money
for this machine, whatever. And so the unscheduled
one-on-ones ended up being a real clarifying thing
for me. Because I did scheduled one-on-ones
my whole career and I realized after leaving
Microsoft for three years, I'm like, where are
all those one-on-ones useful once a week for three
years, right? A hundred and fifty one-on-ones.
So the unscheduled ones were, though. I was like,
when I knocked on my manager's door and said,
"I have this problem, those were important."
So that's what I created at Xtreme. And the 120
directors, it just grew over time. I just didn't
think I needed managers. So I was like, let me
unblock these people on another way. And we came
up with other things to systems to unblock them
that didn't require a manager. And I just also
had a good memory. I knew exactly everyone's
skills and compensation. I knew all that off
the top of my head, so that helps.
The thing that I broke was actually,
this is Chamath. He came in and became our
biggest investors. He's obviously is a smart guy,
but he said the right thing, which is not,
this can never work, because then I would
go into defense mode and explain to him why it
would work. He just said to me, I'm not going
to debate with you whether this works or not,
but will it work at 400 people? And I said,
probably not. He said, okay, so let's change it.
And so we did then ended up putting a little bit
more of a structure, but I made a few people
directors and I forced them to have 40 direct
reports each. I said, we're just going to make
it still pretty flat. And then that did end up
working, because it still allowed them to use
the system to unblock people versus having to
do a one-on-one every week, or having
to talk about things that potentially a
system could unblock. And so I tried to
figure out ways to systematize things.
I love it. Just another example of doing
things differently, not necessarily just,
here's how it's done and I'm going
to do it that way and experimenting
with it. Even if you knew, okay,
maybe long term this isn't the way
it's going to operate. I imagine at
Shopify you don't have 120 reports.
No, we have fourteen or something. We do have
these guardrails where I think we say, Hey,
in engineering you should have between eight
and 20. There are definitely people who have
more and people who have less. But we do try
to keep things as flat as possible, because
we do believe that it doesn't make sense to have
three people reporting to and then to somebody,
and then they only have three people. You just
make a very deep hierarchy. We actually do see,
by the way, the farther you are from Toby, we can
see things in the survey results. The alignment
gets out of whack, and so you do actually see
that you want to be closer, you want to have a
flatter org in general, and that can be achieved
by just having more direct reports per level.
Makes sense. Okay, final question before we get
to our very exciting lightning round. We have
this recurring segments that I call Fail Corner
where generally people come on these podcasts,
they share all their successes.
Here's all the things that I've done,
right. Here's all the big wins.
And everyone feels like, oh man,
I wish I was always successful people. When
in reality, everyone that comes on has failed
many times. Is there a story of a failure in
your career that you could share that helps
people see that even folks like you fail, and
maybe what you learned from that experience?
I have a few. I'll say one thing by the way,
because I think I read this in Tim Ferriss's
book or in the podcast where he said, create a
failure resume and write everything down. And
I would not recommend doing this because I did
this and I got super... I'm like a high energy
happy guy. I wrote down, I have a note on my
phone called Failure Resume, and I wrote down
all the times I failed and it is depressing.
So I would not encourage people to do that,
but I'm happy to tell you about a few instances.
So well, one is actually I've been laid off
twice and people would not expect like, oh,
I'm doing this thing and I've been laid off
twice. And I think in both times it was
the right thing, it was the right thing
for the company, the right thing for me.
And I kind of used that experience as a way
to reevaluate and eventually came out with
my framework of how I want to spend time.
But that's maybe a different story.
I'll tell you about one at Shopify,
the first week that I started, 2019, we were
rebuilding our point of sale system, which now
does billions of dollars of GMB. But back then we
were like, well, let's rebuild it with a new UX
and a new technology platform. And it was my first
week and I'm the mobile guy, coming from Extreme
Labs. They're like, should we build this in React
Native, or should we build this natively on the
mobile platforms? And so I went through this
evaluation, spent a lot of time, blah, blah, blah,
and I came back with a hedged solution, which is
kind of dumb. I said, let's do iOS and Swift and
let's do Android in React Native. And the reason I
said that was I said, I want to learn about React
Native and I think Android's the harder platform,
so let's build that in React Native, but iOS on
Swift because that guarantees us a product in
market. And we didn't have any React Native apps
in market at the time. A year later we launched
the iOS version and it was a huge success. And we
then spent another six months building the React
Native version for Android and everything else.
And we realized pretty quickly that React Native
was the platform for the future. We were like,
oh my God, this will allow us to have one
platform. You could run it on the web as well, and
we could use the React engineers from the web to
work on it. It was a clear winner. By then, we had
also launched a shop app, which is React Native.
And so we learned a lot about this. And I went
back and I said, hey everybody, I made a huge
mistake. We just spent a year building this
thing. It's in market, but we're going to have to
rewrite. We're going to have to rebase back onto
this iOS version. And I think I burned 18 months
of time with a hundred engineers, literally from
the decision I made in the first week of joining
Shopify, and Toby, when I went to Toby and I told
him, I go, hey man, I think I made this mistake
and we have to do this and it's going to cost
us a hundred engineers, another six, whatever.
And he looked at me and he goes, you should tell
everyone this story. That's all he said. Not like,
hey, bad, good. He goes, did you learn something?
It was an epiphany for me, but he was like, this
is a learning org, and I totally failed and I told
everyone I failed and my mistake and everything
else, but he goes, just tell everyone because
he goes, do you know what mistake you made?
And first I was like, I don't think, like,
what mistake. He's like, you didn't take. He goes,
I will always come down harshly on people who do
not take risks, and you did not take a risk in
this case. But if you take a risk and it doesn't
work out, you'll never get in trouble, because you
took the risk and it was the right risk to take,
but he goes, but you didn't take the risk.
And so what I should have done, and by the way,
even now thinking back it would be super hard
to do, first week at Shopify, right, is take a
risk on a platform that we have not launched in
production app on, but he was correct in that we
should have, because we would've saved ourselves
so much more time. So yeah, total failure, sorry.
The product is super successful now and we're all
on React Native and even the Shop Green app is on
React Native. Everything's React Native, and we're
core contributors. It's all good. But I literally
burned I think 18 months of time for a hundred
engineers as my first decision in the company.
This might be the best example of
failure coordinator we've had yet.
This is a great example. Both
of them actually are, although
I'm wondering, okay, that felt like a
really good decision to me and it's-
It sounds like it, right? But
It wouldn't have been his.
But it's, obviously you don't want to just take
risks. There's a limit of a risk but informed,
I guess. Is there anything you missed
there that would told you this was the
right path? Because in hindsight, of course
we should have done this, but looking back,
what do you think you should have done other
than we should have done the risky path?
Yeah, I mean one thing about my career
as well is I don't really do anything
halfway. And when I started looking into React
Native, it was never just that I'm going, oh,
let me look at the docs and read and build a
thing. It's like I flew to Meta and met with
the React team. I became a core contributor.
I ran the React Native working group,
like we became release captains for React Native.
I knew that I was going to do all the things,
so I'm like, and of course in React Native
you can also drop down to native and do things
there that are not possible. So I think I hedged
incorrectly. I knew I was going to do all these
things and I should have looked at my own thought
process, say, if I do all the things, can I fail?
And I didn't take that into account
because again, I did five or six.
I literally, I put everyone together. I
was running the group, I was like release
captain. I would hang out with the React team and
Meta, we're doing all the things. We became core
contributors at React Native before we became core
contributors and react because of all the things I
was doing. And so I think just knowing that I was
going to go all out, I should have said, you know
what? This is not going to fail. And I didn't
have the confidence in that path, so I hedged,
right? Hedging is the worst. And I remember the
CTO at the time said, I'm wondering if I should
force you to go React Native. He literally said
that. And I said, I will do if you say that, I
will do it, but it would've been his decision. And
so he didn't do it. He didn't tell me to do it.
Okay, that makes a lot more sense. It's so
funny that Facebook had a similar
mistake early on in their career-
HTML5.
Yeah, exactly. I know. I don't know if you
were at Zuck's interview at the Chase center
that the Acquired podcast did, and he talked
about this where their market cap dropped
80%. They were about to go public. They
went with this app. No one thought they
could do mobile ads. And he's like, that
set us back a year and a half. He's like,
but based on all the pain he's gone through back
since then, he's like, that was not too bad.
Yeah, it's true actually, maybe what people
don't know is, I was at Facebook, XtremeLabs,
worked on the Facebook app and we worked on that
app. I was in the office when we submitted the iOS
app every single day that week, because it kept
crashing. And we had obviously direct access to
people at Apple, but we'd ship a new app on Monday
and it crashed ship an app on... Not just us,
but us, Facebook together. And so I remember
that whole HTML five fiasco from the inside.
I thought you would say you also told Facebook to
decide on the HTML5 app to set them back a year.
I did not. We happened to be there
when they were doing it. Yeah.
That's so funny. Amazing. Thank you for sharing
that. Before we get to a very exciting lightning
round, is there anything else that you
think would be valuable to leave listeners
with, either touch on something you've mentioned,
a last piece of nugget of wisdom,
or we just go straight to the round?
Yeah, I'll say something maybe embarrassing for
you. I've been using your performance management
framework from your first round review article,
not knowing by the way that it was you. I actually
found it, you being the famous Lenny podcaster,
but the old days, maybe the Lenny, the PM. And I
remember reading this a long time ago and just
copying, there's a Google link in there to a
Google Doc link with a template for a performance
review framework that I've been using for years.
Literally every review I've done at Shopify
uses that framework. And I was writing a
post to my admin about how we can use LLMs to
make it easier for me to write these reviews,
even though obviously you have to read it all and
go through it, but I was like, how can I generate
some of this with an LLM? And so I wanted to
send her the original article. So I went back
to the first round review, I found the article
and said, oh my God, it's Lenny, the same guy.
So I will say one thing that's interesting
about that framework is, I've used it now for,
like I said, six years here, is that, and I
don't think it's me. I think it's actually
the framework pulls out good information. I've had
multiple people in a review process tell me that,
when I deliver the feedback in, of
course the format, they would say,
wow, I've been in industry a long time. This
is the best performance review I've ever
had. And it's because the framework pulls
out good information. So congrats to you.
But I think it was funny that randomly I
was coming on this podcast and I just wrote
that doc to my admin two, three weeks
ago and realized it's the same person.
Well, how about that? I love that. I'll
also give credit to a four board guest
on this podcast, Vlad Loktev,
who was my manager at Airbnb,
and that's where I was inspired
to write about that framework.
Amazing.
So it trickles down to him and I
don't know where he boarded this,
he probably invented it. So credit to Vlad also
for that. Another fun fact along these lines,
I have another first round of repost about the
W framework, which is a framework for planning.
They do annual planning. And that's
one that I've slowly discovered many,
many companies use and they don't know
where it came from. They just call it,
oh, we have this W framework. Someone
flipped it and call the M framework.
But that's another one that has trickled into
the ether of tech companies, which is awesome.
Amazing.
With that, Farhan, we have reached our very
exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
I'm ready.
Let's do this. What are two or three books
that you have recommended most to other people?
There's one. So Toby has an annoyingly long set
of books that he recommends, and they're all,
not all, they're usually good, depends because
we're not totally in sync on fiction, for example.
But he recommended one to me that I think everyone
should read right now called Manna, M-A-N-N-A,
from Marshall Brain. It is a book, it's a book
about AI. And I think the most interesting thing
about it though is about a future in which the
AI tells the humans what to do. So it's this idea
of, imagine in the future you came into work
and the AI would tell you what emails to pay
attention to or what dashboard to look at because
something weird is going on. It takes that to
an interesting level. So I would recommend
reading that book. It's not long. That's fun.
I think another book that I recommend to
people, and it's a weird one to recommend,
but it's Business Adventures from John Brooks, the
famous, if you ask, I think it's Bill Gates, what
his famous book of all time is, it's this book.
And the cool thing about the book is that it is
not easy to digest for anyone with focus problems.
Paul Graham wrote the post How to Do Great Work,
and it's super long. The best part about
that post is that you have to be able to
read the whole thing. And so the same thing with
Business Adventures. I think each chapter is,
it's 12 chapters, 12 stories, no breaks in
between. It's just each one is super long. But
it just goes into a problem at such depth that
if you can maintain your focus to get through
the depths of each problem, you will just learn
something, just like that post by Paul Graham.
I loved that it was so long because
I sent it to people and I said,
the test here is can you read it? Can you just
get to the end? And not in a pejorative way,
like in a... If you can get to the end, you
will extract the alpha from this post if you
can read it all. So those are... Manna is like
the opposite. It's very easy and easy read.
I'm excited to read these. Next question. Do you
have a favorite recent movie
or TV show you really enjoyed?
A recent one was Challengers, the tennis
movie, with Zendaya just randomly I was at home
and I put it on and the cool thing about it
was more the cinematography and music. They
had this weird style, art house style, where they
would be talking and music would get super loud.
It was very strange, but a very, very good
movie. And then you saw, you said movies and-
Or TV show. Oh, TV show, anything like that.
Yeah, one of my all time favorites is probably
Halt and Catch Fire. I don't
know if you've watched that.
About the early tech industry.
Early tech. And I think there
was an Andreessen podcast where
he said this is the closest thing
to what a real startup looks like.
So Halt and Catch Fire like an all time
recommend, everybody has to watch it.
Do you have a favorite product that you
recently discovered that you really love?
I don't know if I want to be in the zeitgeist
right now, but the Meta Ray-Bans are amazing. And
the biggest thing about the Meta Ray-Bans was just
that I think I never got into it and I saw people
around me wearing it, but I only got into it
when somebody said I'd never take my AirPods with
me anymore. And I was like, oh, I can swap two
devices for one device. I always have sunglasses
and AirPods because I'll go for a walk or listen
to a podcast and now I can just have one device.
And this happened to me. I was in the summer, I
was at a pool party and someone called me and I
just took it from my sunglasses and people
were confused as where I was taking this
call from. But they are the right amount of
tech. They're in unintrusive, you can't tell,
they don't look like any tech. And then also I
was playing soccer with my kids. I have three
kids. I just turned the video on and I was
the goalie and they were taking shots and I
was watching them. They had no idea that I was
just recording. And it was such a cool moment
because I was in playing soccer with them.
I wasn't with my phone and I got to get this
amazing set of video that I would never would've
gotten. So I really liked the Meta Ray-Bans.
We had Boz on the podcast who leads a lot of
that work and he's got a to teach us. And I
put on Ray-Bans while we were doing the interview
just for fun. You could see my setup. Okay, cool.
Two more questions. Do you have a favorite life
motto that you find useful in work or in life?
Okay, I do. And it's on a lot of my profile
bios, and it is, everything you know is
wrong. And the reason I like that one, and
people always like, what would you put on
a billboard? And people always come back to me
and say, that's like they know that as my motto.
And the reason for that is it's this notion of
if all the knowledge you knew was incorrect,
could you from first principles build up a
view of the world? And that's kind of how I
like to think of things is that, anything could be
incorrect. Even things that you think are correct,
which is why, again, back to the, I like
to experiment. I like to look stupid,
because I'm always trying shit because I'm
like, I don't know if even though you say this
is correct, that this is going to work, right.
Actually, one example, my wife hates this is I
have a Tesla and I routinely will switch gears
without fully stopping the car, which you cannot
do in a regular car, but I'll be in drive and then
I'll slow down to drive back up into my driveway
and while it's moving I switch it into reverse.
And you never would know that that's possible
except for trying. And sometimes it
goes beep beep because you're going
too fast. And she hates it. But I'm always
trying weird things and so that's why I
say everything you know is wrong. Who knows
what's possible, just try different things.
I do the same thing with my Tesla.
I used to do it with a non-electric
car and my wife is always like,
don't do that. Screwing it up.
Yes, exactly.
I love that on an electric car, there's no
gear you're breaking, it's just software.
Exactly.
This quote reminds me of that you shared of
everything you know is wrong. The founders of
Airbnb always talked about just this point that
everything around you was designed somebody,
another human. There's not necessarily
that much smarter or insightful.
It doesn't mean what they did was correct.
Somebody else find some better potentially...
I think Steve Jobs had a similar thing like, hey,
you can design anything. Everything's
designed by people. I love that one too.
Yeah. Final question. So you told me the story
of this PhD you hired versus just a guy you
met in a college, sorry, in a coffee shop. I read
another similar story where you hired a waitress.
Yes.
Is that real? Okay, tell that story.
Yeah, so again, this is another long list of
reasons my wife is in annoyed with me, but this
is another one of them. Whenever we are out, I'm
always scanning and I'm always scanning people and
one, do I know anybody around, whatever. I like
to scan for people and I have a good memory for
faces. But in this case we were at a restaurant
and I saw a waitress doing a very, very good job,
an extremely, like she was running between
different tables, she was smiling her face,
taking everyone's order, making sure that there
was a thing happening in the kitchen. She was kind
of doing a phenomenal job of organizing the entire
crazy busy restaurant. And so in talking to her,
I said, what do you do outside of this because
you look like you're super. She's like, what do
you mean? I'm just the waitress.
And I said, well, would you like to,
this is XtremeLabs. I Said, would you like to
work at XtremeLabs? She's like, what's that? So
I explained it to her and I got her contact info.
She came into the office and she first started
off as our receptionist, so she moved from the
retail world into the office world, and then I
brought her on as my admin and she became one of
my recruiters. And I taught her how to recruit
and talked to people and she came in with me
to info sessions. And over time we actually
hired many more people from the restaurant that
were really, really good at their job. And what
was amazing was, one, she was organized but
not reorganized. I had to teach her at Google
Docs and G Suite and everything else, but she was
super smart but just never had the opportunity.
The coolest thing about this is that she ended
up being, she ended up taking over one of the HR
functions for us. And she had a college degree
and because of the work she had done with us,
she was able to parlay that into finishing,
doing one more year and getting a university
degree. And now she's a director of HR at
a company, which is amazing from, like,
she went from that environment to this environment
and a lot of her people, she pulled the smart and
intense people she pulled from that environment
also ended up on these amazing career paths. If
I see someone doing a good job, I'm like, what
do they do? How can I work with them? This is
one example of pulling somebody out of that
environment. I have lots of other ones where I
overhear someone in their designer or an engineer
and I try to hire them into my company as well.
Wow. That is such a good story.
I love that. Maybe restaurants
are the new feeder system for tech
companies. Did not think about that.
Yeah, I mean, everyone's smart at
something, so I was trying to figure out,
she was really good at this thing.
She'd be so good at something else.
Amazing. I feel like there's so many stories, more
stories to tell, but we're going to wrap it up and
let you go, farhan. Two final questions. Where can
folks find you a line if they want to reach out,
learn more, maybe apply to work at Shopify
and how can listeners be useful to you?
Sure, so Twitter's probably the
place I try to hang out the most,
X at FNThawar, and maybe I'll put that in the
show notes. And then listeners for me. I mean,
I love to be challenged. I'm sure that there
are people who are like, they heard something
that I said and they're like, oh, that's super
dumb. We do this instead. Or here's research
that says that that won't work. I would love to
hear more about these because I'm just again, on
a learning journey and if I did something stupid,
very likely I would like to learn a better way to
do things. So I would love for people to comment
and say, hey, this is dumb. You should try this,
or, that doesn't make any sense. I would love
to learn more. So that's what I'm looking for.
All right, well leave a comment in YouTube or
on the Substack post with what Farhan got wrong.
Amazing.
Thank you so much for being here.
Thanks for having me. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found this
valuable, you can subscribe to the show on Apple
Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite podcast
app. Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review, as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all past
episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.