hello Lenny con I'm Mika I'm a product lead at figma
and the founding PM for figma slides and I'm Yuki and I lead the product team at figma and today we are so excited to be chatting with you about how to do the
product review right by actually doing it a little bit wrong specifically we're super excited to take you behind the scenes and give you both the icpm as
well as the CPO perspective as folks go ahead and navigate this favorite ritual all right so I want to set a little bit of background and context on
product reviews it's part of back going through a brief history on product reviews right and presentations began as
oral Traditions next uh okay uh so over time they became digital and as part of that uh visual aids like slides and
projectors came next next next next
next and scene that that was an act don't worry I saw some people in the audience get real uncomfortable for a second uh but it was all inspired by my
own experience and one of my first ever product reviews with Travis uh when I was back at Uber and as you might imagine these reviews were quite intense and you can
get a sense of the vibes from that photo that someone had the audacity to take uh during such one such review um and in my very first review with him he just kind
of took over and the product review just basically became me flipping through the deck for him from one side to the next at one point he just said I'll just read
it myself and I was kind of his remote control and needless to say I didn't feel this was a particularly successful product review and sure Travis probably got what he
needed but I felt like I lost control of the narrative and I had trouble directing him to the areas where I needed him to pay attention and in talking to a bunch of
PMs and being on the other side as well I've come to realize that there are lot of product reviews that feel this way where they feel somewhat broken in some way and Mika and I believe that this may
be because PMS are often given advice about how to run product reviews that sound right in theory but in practice are very wrong
most PM things that product reviews are for making decisions that there are this forum where you need to choose between radical Choice a and
radical Choice B the only time that you could possibly get a green light to move something forward well we disagree with this we actually think that the most
important outcome that can come out of her product review is not just making a decision but building trust and winning over your key stakeholders and today we
are so excited to walk you through a little bit about why the things that you have probably been coached to do or are coaching your team to do ever since they
started out as a PM might actually be wrong and why some of the things that have traditionally been considered taboo might actually lead you down a path to
success and so let's start by taking the typical half an hour product review I mean the typical 25 minute product
review now at figma we use product reviews in the form of slide decks most of the time so that's going to be a lot of what we're talking about here but we
really believe that the takeaways are applicable to any forum and any conversation be it walking through a deck or even an informal conversation
huddled over a computer or in the hallway so a few minutes into a review normally the PM is setting the context when I gave my first product
review at figma I started screen sharing and was immediately surprised to get a ping from Dylan does anyone have the link so as I started kicking off the
conversation talking about why we were so excited about voting in fig jam and why we believed that this bet was really the one taking I kind of paused because
when I was looking through the file what I saw was Dylan scrolling all the way to the end of the deck totally ignoring what I was saying and so hopefully most
of you are familiar with Google translate today we're going to be walking you through something new exact Translate and we're going to be translating exec
speak into English and over time I came to learn that when Dylan was actually asking me does anyone have the link this was code
for what's the actual recommendation now having set some context maybe a few minutes later the PM often checks in with their attendees and
one common thing you might do is say hey I've been spending a lot of time talking I'm going to going to pause now and I want to see if we're aligned in an agreement on the problems the goals the
principles right something you hear a lot and often that's met with this really awkward silence right all the time exactly and the silence can mean a
lot of things many of you in the audience have probably been there as reviewers you're likely tuned out because the initial context didn't seem all that important or more likely if you're like me you're probably
multitasking doing slack on the side um or often it's just really too early to be able to say or aine because I'm just wondering is this a trap because
we're not entirely sure what it means to agree at this point in the in the review it could sound like great framing but still lead to the wrong recommendations so instead of abstractly agreeing I kind
of want to cheat I want to cheat and look ahead to see if I agree with the final recommendation before saying we agree at this stage of the review and so why does this awkwardness
happen in a meeting well we think it's because PMS are told that they should be spending some time really setting up these great setup slides making sure everyone has all the background and
context uh before uh before entering the uh before entering their review and so uh one of the things you know people are often told is well build up context right and so what ends up happening is
you know we see templates like this you'll see an agenda and it'll say okay here's the background the problems we're trying to solve the goals the principles and then the solutions and the
recommendation right seems like a really good template but the problem of course is that the spicy proposal is often buried at the very end so you spend all this time in the meeting building up
context that most people are kind of tuning out right or they don't know exactly how to react to or kind of mildly agreeing to and it's only the last few minutes that you get to the good stuff right you get these
interesting reactions whether good or bad and it's also possible of course that the framing and problems and goals are themselves spicy but it's hard to discern that before you actually know
the recommendation and so that's why we think that this advice is wrong or often misunderstood and so as much as it feels wrong from a storytelling perspective in
a review we really believe you should start with the punchline not to build up context and all the suspense but rather go quickly to the part that feels controversial the thing that will cause
everyone to pay P attention and actually engage in the conversation and so in other words instead of this gradual buildup towards the interesting part of the content starting as early as
possible with the stuff that motivates everyone to pay attention that might mean you get a violent reaction but that's a good thing so how do you actually do that so this is the bird's
eye view of one of the uh figma slides Vision de and the spicy stuff or the bits that are good and interesting are the yellow and pink SL these are the ones that go
into key Concepts as well as the great product thinking and thinking around differentiation so one of the things that I like to do is think of it as a stack right and say okay when do you
actually get to the good stuff is it within the first 20% of the deck or the first five minutes of a review that's a gut check I like to do and I like I to I like to ask my PMS to do it and this
sounds really simple but you'd be surprised how many decks actually are far more topheavy with the context in the background which ends up up setting this meeting up for
failure there are other subtle ways to do this as well uh take for example this typical title card right uh that grounds you in where you are in the deck it
might say something like audience or maybe more dramatically who is our audience right but it's so much nicer if they can just cut to the Chase and again get to the punchline because people
don't like having to guess and having title cards with a point of view means that people pay attention up front and if you're like me right and you get distracted you can quickly scan and glean the important parts and
immediately engage in the discussion and sometimes though you don't know what's spicy you don't know where you should be spending the time having the discussion and so one ritual
that we like to do in figma is actually have what we call this alignment widget where we solicit uh everyone's uh opinions and see where the misalignment might be so that a PM is spending the
time honing in on the areas where there's the most disconnect so that we can discuss spare so that's our first tip which is to tell your PMS not to spend so much time building up context because you're
going to bore everyone because even though it's the right thing to do actually a lot of people just don't even care so rather tell your PMS to get to the punch line first to get the violent
reactions early the next thing that PMS often try and do is to cover all their bases when they're pulling together a deck or a
dock they're thinking about how can they ensure that that each section is chalk full of new information but at the end of the day if you're saying everything chances are what everyone else is
hearing is kind of nothing and so we think that rather than covering all your bases what you should actually be coaching PMS to do is to make a meme and
go internally viral within the company so let's talk a little bit about what this looks like the original figma slides Vision
deck had two memes the first was in the title itself we used to refer to this product
as flies internally and in the initial Zoom meeting where we pitched this product it was really important to me that we didn't give it a generic name
like figma slides figma decks or presentations but rather in order to create a ground swell for this Bottoms Up initiative in order to but an
entirely net new product on our road map it was really important to me that someone across the company regardless of if they were a very tenur engineer or a
new hire on their first day of work heard this term and immediately wanted to learn more the term took off like wildfire
within the company the animation sync became the flan animation sync the layout work stream became the Fout work stream and when folks would hop onto zoom on a Friday afternoon they would
promptly wish everyone a Happy fly day my own mom got irrationally attached to the name flies and when it came time to name this product when we were
actually going to Market she was insistent that I please don't give up on figma flies when we actually went to Market in
June Twitter blew up and even though we went to Market with a pretty normal product this almost emotional and irrational
attachment that folks felt to this very quirky word meant that Twitter was blowing up there were thousands of impressions of people who were stoked to try this product because of this like
kind of cooky name and so as you're thinking about how to build a meme and go internally viral with your idea think about how you can create an internal brand and something that folks can
really latch on to the second meme was actually a stat specifically
that over 3.5 million people had made slide de and figma design over the last year now this is a stat that ensured
that we weren't only investing in this product because we had some interesting product ideas but that there was a real pain point a real user need here that
was currently being unsolved there were millions of folks going through acrobats to hack a product that was not purpose built for slide slide slides in order to
do so and so it was this meme that gave us internal traction and that made folks kind of excited about taking a bet in this space and stats and data can work
wonders and what I would encourage all the PMS in the room to do is not just think about what are the top five or 10 stats that folks need to remember but
what is that one thing that will tip your executive over the edge and so when we went to Market and when we announced figma slides this was
also the stat that got thousands of designers in the audience to raise their hands as someone who had gone through this pain point and nearly everyone was shocked to realize that it was so
prolific around them as well and so next time you're thinking about how to cover all your bases go ahead and make a meme all right so at some point later in
the meeting let's say 17 minutes in someone will ask a question that's unexpected and despite the PM asking that they like to field all questions at the end of course people like me chime in anyway
and ask a question that about something I'm wondering about and a classic PM response is to acknowledge the great question and then the ab absence of a immediate answer to
say they'll Circle back right you'll take an action item and here too there's some pretty subtle ways that trust can get degraded right while it's nice to be told that it's a great question it can
always be disappointing to hear that maybe it's the first time you you've thought about this very basic question or often people promise to Circle back at a later time frame right
and as an exec my immediate thought is to want that answer faster right waiting a week to get an answer feels extremely slow and frustrating and so the advice here is
instead of always just circling back and following up later which is probably what a lot of PMS do tell your PMS that they should be unafraid to at least share their gut
and so often you know we live in a world where uh people don't have the perfect information uh and therefore they don't share their assumptions during a meeting right and so we end up waiting until a
week after only to find out that we had very different assumptions in mind and now you burned a week and you're back to square one so if instead during the meeting you at least shared a rough idea
of your thinking even if it's imperfect you can get a rough sense of where everyone is at whether people are on the same page and knowing that early uh is helpful because you can immediately get to the bottom of the
misalignment versus waiting a week now when I was at Uber our chief product officer at the time Jeff Holden called this cutting out the weight space he
view the executive job to remove all this arbitrary amounts of time that people had to wait for others to make progress and now I know that often it's really hard to coax and answer like that
out of of people sometimes right A P might want to first run an experiment a study or Sprint before giving an answer and Jeff had a trick uh which I really
like where he posed it more as a thought experiment he'd tell us to fast forward to that day when the experiment is over when that Sprint is done and he asked what we thought we'd see at that point
and I like that framing a lot because it kind of lowers the stakes we all know we're guessing and uh it created much more of a safe space to share some rough thinking as part of that knowing and get
us align much faster so in short instead of telling your PMS to Circle back take that action item if they're unsure encourage them to share their gut even if the thinking is rough to save
everyone so much time and ultimately build alignment much faster now as a PM gets towards the end of their
presentation and only has a few minutes on the clock a common tactic that folks employ is to only talk about the really positive things
only talk about all the reasons that this would be an exciting investment why this outdoes all the others and more but chances are if
you're trying to go ahead and only talk about the good things you might actually have an executive who either asks you or in their head is thinking what are the
downsides and in exec speak they're actually wondering if you've thought about this deeply or worse are you hiding something the trust
kind of breaks and so while it's really important to treat these forums as a place where you're making a big bold
pitch perhaps even more important is to treat your idea with a little bit of skepticism so the official slides Vision
pitch which happened in Feb of last year was actually preceded by two other product review like forums the first was maker week which is
our internal hackathon at figma this was the Forum where I initially tried to get byy and for the idea I worked with the team walked around the New York office and convinced
a bunch of designers and Engineers to work on this idea and we hacked together a prototype in just one week we actually structured the demo just like a product review where the a
audence was the entire company and what was so amazing was that the chat absolutely blew up there were folks from around the company like Dylan who had
previously expressed skepticism about this idea who were so stoked in the moment and I thought that by creating this totally hype presentation by
creating an entirely net new product in just a few days we had done it we had gone ahead and created by and to go ahead with the idea I was shocked
afterwards when I asked if we had the green light and was promptly met with a no and that a zoom pitch doesn't really
do it in terms of getting the buy and you need to move something forward and so you know recalculated readjusted and moved into a more formal
product review setting where we reviewed the competitive landscape we talked about why and how figma should win in the story Stelling space how we were excited to build a tool that had the
visual control of figma and the interactive storytelling mechanisms of fig jam and how no other player in the market satisfied all the core needs and
as you can see flies had all these green boxes and in my mind I was like okay someone's going to look at this chart and be like obviously we must make this investment but at the end of the day
this was kind of stacking the cards and even though there were good ideas in this deck the answer to do we have a green light was still kind of a
no and so that moves us to the official Vision pitch which we've been talking through today and in this Vision pitch
it was not just a big bold bit pitch but also an area where we treated the deck with a little bit of
skepticism where we took the time to go out and spend weeks talking to users understanding their pain points and and a few tactical things that we did in this deck was that I basically
structured it such that every pain point was immediately followed by a solution and then a proof Point showing why this hypothesis that we had was either a
great idea or maybe a not so great one the second thing was for areas where we were pretty skeptical about which path to go down it's actually to your benefit
to be really honest about this and so for example one of the most kind of tedious trying questions for figma slides was thinking about how we would build a tool that allowed both non-designers and designers to have
their preferred toolkit and we laid out all these different variations the last thing we did was akin to what Yuki was talking about earlier which was basically preempt the
spice and make sure that you actually do have the answers for all the spicy questions that might be in your executive's heads and prove that you've done the work and the homework in order
to have an answer there and so big bold pitches are super important but so is a healthy dose of
skepticism all right so today we covered all the things that you might be told as a PM or even leaders in the room have been telling their PMS about how to approach reviews and all these on the surface are absolutely the right thing
to do but in practice so much of this advice can be misapplied and sometimes what seems wrong is actually more effective and I think it comes down to
the fact that in a review all the stakeholders are ultimately human beings who have short attention spans who get easily distracted are context switching
and need to be guided along and who are ultimately emotional creatures who are swayed by how the review makes them feel and so the best PMS know this the best
PMS take advantage of this and that's not all to say that we should we shouldn't focus on making decisions we absolutely should but really winning trust is what allows you to make
decision faster in the long R now let's talk about the biggest myth of
all as a PM you probably feel like this product review is Monumental like it is this holy secret Forum that is your only
chance to move a decision forward or get the outcome you need as a product leader you're probably coaching your PMS as to
how to make the most of those 30 minutes for me despite the positive feedback and hints of internal traction that materialized immediately after the
vision pitch I was still fixated on that green light on this like somewhat semantic thing and I reached out to Yuki right after the presentation asking if
this was a quote unquote formal green light the reality is that the stuff that happens outside of the product
review the days the weeks the months you spend building your product product with your team those matter so much
more and so the question really is can you use that product review to buy yourself the trust to do the thing that matters the most which is to
build and something that most people don't know is that at the beginning of this year we have three company priorities and fides was not one of them following Mika's review we were really excited about the work um and about the
vision but we weren't sure that now is the right time to to launch a new product given that we had all these other priorities and so Mika knew this and so what she tried to do was just make it
more real for everyone to go from a cool idea that a few people were exploring to an actual new product that we were willing to put the company behind and so one opportunity she found was for our
sales kickoff which is kind of our internal conference for sales and marketing and our biggest internal event of the year what if the keynote used flights and needless to say the idea to
have Kino in a completely uned product was not to it liking but we pushed through anyway and the product was barely ready and there were a lot of
bugs leading up to it um but the day of was perfect a perfect run and here this Chris our CTO and I delivering uh the resulting presentation apparently I
always wear blue sweaters on stage and at the very end of the presentation we had this huge reveal where the deck we had been presenting in
was made in flies all along and so while the initial product review bought the trust to explore the idea further getting the product to a point
where it could actually be used in this way brought the trust to bring it to Market ultimately five months later at
config fides did launch as the hero number four at the event and folks loved it and so next time we were thinking
about how to move an idea forward remember that it's the trust that will carry you all the way not just the
decisions last but not least if the only thing you were impressed by today was these slick animations that you are looking to integrate into your next
product review we have gone ahead and published The Deck on figma community it's open sourced at this link so you can go ahead and remix it take it to
your liking and build your own tips for how to how to do the product review right thank you so much for listening thank you all