Steve Jobs was not a technologist. He
was a pitch man. He was a brilliant
salesman. He was a fantastic marketer.
When products succeed, we forget the
extent to which marketing was actually
instrumental or decisive in their success.
You once said, "If you could imagine
a stand-up comedian doing a routine
about your product, then you're onto something."
You eed to preserve slightly
odd things. Rolls-Royce's were
the only cars which still had
a pedal on the floor. Famously,
Veuve Clicquot it's the one with a
yellow name. Idiosyncrasies count double.
Do you have any advice for early stage
founders to help build their brand?
Be consistent, be distinctive, and be famous.
When you are not famous, you have to find all your
customers. Suddenly you reach this magical escape
velocity of fame where people start coming to you.
Today my guest is Rory Sutherland. Rory is
vice chairman of Ogilvy UK. Author of the book,
Alchemy: The Dark Art and Curious Science of
Creating Magic in Brands, Business and Life,
and the founder of Nudge Stock, the world's
biggest festival of behavioral science and
creativity. Rory is both an example and a huge
proponent of thinking from first principles.
Through his speaking and his books, he encourages
people to not think logically when solving
problems, but to think psychologically using human
psychology to inform how you design and build and
market your products. Rory is full of amazing
stories and ideas and examples and inspiration,
which you'll get a sense of as soon as we start
talking. I don't even ask him a question and
he's already off to the races. This episode is
for anyone who wants to think more creatively,
help their team be more innovative and learn how
to create more magic in your world. Rory has been
one of the most requested guests on this podcast,
and I can now see why. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in
your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's
the best way to avoid missing feature episodes
and helps the podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you Rory Sutherland. Rory, thank you so
much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
It's a pleasure. It's an audience I don't
normally speak to and it's an audience which
I think is particularly valuable, particularly
important, but also actually probably could
benefit quite a bit from just a little bit
of extra psychology. Not least by the way,
a very simple observation, which is that do
not think that good products automatically
succeed or that bad ones necessarily fail.
The other thing I'd say is that timing is so
important that don't necessarily reject things
simply because they failed in the past. One of
the best products I've ever worked on in a
professional capacity was Facebook Meta TV,
the TV portal, sorry, Facebook,
the Meta [inaudible 00:02:46] TV.
Oh, I love the portal, yeah. Big fan.
[inaudible 00:02:49] by Facebook and I bought it
for about $120. It plugs into your TV. It allows
you to do obviously WhatsApp or Facebook or indeed
Zoom on your television with a fantastic face
tracking camera. It really is sort of $500
worth of equipment, which they were selling
for about $120. One of the best things I've
ever owned, I owned about four of them. When
I heard it was being discontinued, I bought
another one because I think they're so good.
And yet for reasons I fully I don't really
understand, apart from the fact that every single
review said, "This is brilliant," effectively as
a product, but the first seven paragraphs of the
article weren't saying, "This is brilliant." They
were saying, "Who would allow Facebook to put a
camera in their home?" And so basically, it was
nine paragraphs of privacy paranoia because you
can turn the thing off after all, you don't have
to leave it switched on, okay? But there were nine
paragraphs of privacy paranoia basically followed
by one paragraph saying, "As these products go,
it's brilliant." And yet we still don't have
video calling on TV unless you're willing to
plug your laptop in or do something pretty fancy
and complex. That seems really weird to me.
Let me actually read a quote from you around
what good marketing often looks like. So you
once said, "If you could imagine a stand-up
comedian doing a routine about your product,
then you're onto something. The urge to appear
serious is in many ways a disaster in marketing."
I'd love to hear your thoughts on that.
This episode is brought to you by Pendo, the
only all-in-one product experience platform for
any type of application. Tired of bouncing around
multiple tools to uncover what's really happening
inside your product? With all the tools you need
in one simple to use platform, Pendo makes it easy
to answer critical questions about how users are
engaging with your product and then turn those
insights into action. Also, you can get your
users to do what you actually want them to do.
First, Pendo is built around product analytics,
seeing what your users are actually doing in your
apps so that you can optimize their experience.
Next, Pendo lets you deploy in-app guides that
lead users through the actions that matter most.
Then Pendo integrates user feedback so that you
can capture and analyze what people actually want.
And the new thing in Pendo session replace, a
very cool way to visualize user sessions. I'm
not surprised at all that over 10,000 companies
use it today. Visit pendo.io/lenny to create your
free Pendo account today and start building better
experiences across every corner of your product.
PS you want to take your product-led know-how a
step further? Check out Pendo's lineup of free
certification courses led by top product experts
and designed to help you grow and advance in your
career. Learn more and experience the power
of the Pendo platform today at pendo.io/lenny.
Pendo.
Today's episode is brought to you by Cycle, the
AI-powered feedback platform for product teams
is your customer feedback, a tangled mess of
slack threads, survey responses and overflowing
inboxes? Wish that you could know what your
customers really need? Cycle unifies all of
your customer interactions from support chats to
user research, gong calls and app store reviews
into one neat collaborative space. Cycle's AI
then extracts actionable insights on autopilot.
Cycle will learn what you're building so that it
can label incoming feedback automatically. That
means you'll get a full voice of customer report
without manually triaging feedback. Then simply
use Cycle Ask to dig deeper into any topic
and generate custom AI-generated summaries
across your entire feedback repository. What makes
Cycle different is the way that it lets you close
feedback loops in each release. Feedback is not
used just as a way to prioritize what to build,
but also as a tool that creates trust with all
stakeholders. Sign up for a free Cycle trial
today at cycle.app/lenny and put your feedback on
autopilot. That's C-Y-C-L-E dot app slash Lenny.
I've had a conversation earlier today with
someone who's in the hotel industry and is in a
particular, without giving away where he works,
he's looking to reinvent the hotel. Arguing,
I think with some reason, that it's one of those
areas which is actually ripe for a good degree
of disruption. There's a complicated thing, don't
be too weird, okay? Don't be too strange because
if the consumer... There's a wonderful concept
from Raymond Levy course, the French designer
called maximally advanced yet acceptable. In
other words, there is a pace of change which
consumers will accept, and generally they're more
comfortable with evolution than they are with
complete reinvention. There are exceptions
to that. Well, actually even the iPhone,
let's face it was preceded by the iPod. It wasn't
a complete WTF moment. And consumers effectively
like to migrate their behavior rather than
reinventing their behavior. But nonetheless,
one of the things I always point out
is that idiosyncrasies count double.
The wonderful thing actually, years ago, back
in the 1990s, Ogilvy won the Jaguar account and
one of the things the creative director in
New York said is that one of the things you
need to preserve is slightly odd things. So
in a Jaguar of the 1990s, you turned on the
light above your head, the reading light or the
central light with a switch that was actually on
the central console. Every other car you reached
up and you flipped the switch. In the Jaguar,
you pressed the button at the bottom and the light
came on the top and the creative director said,
"Keep those things. Actually distinctiveness
really matters." And they were actually really
interested. They said, "Oh, that's interesting
you say that because we're actually planning
to get rid of it. We thought it was inconsistent.
For years, I don't know if this is still true
because I don't drive many Rolls-Royces,
but for years, Rolls-Royce was the last car,
now obviously now cars dip their headlamps
automatically, or you have an automatic setting,
but for years, Rolls-Royces were the only
cars which still had a pedal on the floor,
perfect for an automatic, not so good
for a manual, but they had a pedal on
the floor where you dipped and undipped
your headlamps rather than having a stop.
And those things, which I always cite things
like the Double Tree cookie when you check in for
example, a brilliant example of this, which when
you think about it was extraordinary in terms of
the attention it garnered. You probably remember
MCI the American phone... No, you're too young.
Yeah, I do. Of course I remember MCI.
You do? Okay. They have the concept of
friends and family where you nominated a
certain number of calls, a certain number
of numbers that you called particularly
frequently, and you got 20% off calls to those
numbers. I think it started off with 10%, and
I think they eventually ramped it up to 25%, but
actually most people, 90, it's a Pareto principle,
most people make 80% of their calls to probably
five or six numbers. Now, what was interesting
about that was it garnered [inaudible
00:10:21]. It was in a sense irrational,
but it garnered much more interest than if
you'd simply reduced the cost of calls by 15,
20% across the board because you have to stipulate
your numbers. And actually things that are
slightly weird things that have a little bit of
extra things that are slightly counterintuitive,
sometimes the right thing to do is to get
rid of them, sometimes you celebrate them.
And that's what I mean about the comedian. The
comedian notices things that are slightly weird,
notices things, and actually there was a great
comedy routine When Friends and Family Came to
the UK. It was introduced from MCI by a marketer
called Ed Carter to BT in the UK. There wrote
whole comedy routines about it, people going, "I
suddenly realized I couldn't think of the ninth
number," or, "It's basically my mum and nine adult
lines." This was the kind of thing. But those
kind of things, which actually they're a slight
little splinter on the attention. In other words,
it's something that slightly raises up from the
normal shape or it's the step that isn't quite
the riser. If you go down a flight of steps and
one step is slightly... The sender is slightly out
of whack. Those things have a place actually.
Famously Veuve Cliquot, the French Champagne
house, their labels ended up yellow by mistake.
I think there was some printing error and they
thought, "Okay, we have these stupid yellow limos
and we will send them to [inaudible 00:12:00] in
England. We didn't want [inaudible 00:12:04] by
selling them in France." And then the Brits said,
"Okay, by the way, that champagne, can you send
us more of the champagne with the yellow label?
It's going down really well." And they said,
"Okay, we're going to make it really yellow
now," just almost as a kind of wind-up, I think.
But of course, if you think about it, the entire
identity of that champagne, you can't remember
the name, it's the one with the yellow label.
And so visual distinctiveness and other forms of
what you might call UX distinctiveness, as I said,
don't go crazy weird, but there's this concept of
MAYA, which is maximally advanced yet acceptable.
There's a wonderful phrase which I'll share with
you, which was there's an English guy who went
over from the BBC for BBC 4, which is like the
PBS of PBS, okay? It's the really niche, niche,
educational hardcore factual British TV channel.
And he went to see if there are any programs to
buy from the Danish state broadcaster, and he
ended up buying a series called The Killing. He
bought the first season of The Killing went
for 24,000 pounds, so about $30,000 he paid
to run The Killing, which had aired on Danish
television about a year and a half earlier and
been quite successful in Denmark, but nowhere
else. And he paid 24,000 pounds, $30,000 and
aired it on BBC 4, and then it became hugely
popular, and then it migrated to BBC 2,
and then Netflix came along and bought the rights
to the series. You'll probably remember this.
So actually the Danish state broadcaster ended up,
he said, "There should be a statue of me outside
this Danish broadcaster because I ended up making
them tens of millions of pounds by both selling
the rights to the original series and also by
Netflix buying the rights to the basic storyline."
I said, "Well, why did you do that?" I said, "What
made you buy it?" And he said, great phrase. He
said, "Well, if you're British," true also if
you're American, by the way, he said, "If you're
British, the great thing about Scandinavians is
they're just the right amount of weird." So if you
think about it, if you have to watch something set
in Denmark and you live in San Francisco, it's not
like watching something set in Korea or Somalia.
You're not sitting there going, "What the hell
is going on here? Why is this man doing this?"
Basically, they're a bit like us, they're enough
like us that we basically figure out what's going
on, but they're weird enough to make it just that
little bit more interesting. And I think that's
part of the reason for the popularity of Scandi
Noir and Scandi Crime is they're the right amount
of weird, and I think that's true of product
design. I think with Raymond Loewe, I think the
thing was he made a fan, if I got the story right,
he made a fad that was insanely quiet and people
didn't believe it worked because it was just too
quiet. And years later, I remember that story
because there was a guy who had this extraordinary
machine learning and AI device that was being
used by engineers, and he was producing I think
it was an electric toothbrush or it might've
been a razor, it was either a men's razor, with
an electric motor, which was they could somehow
make it insanely quiet by using some weird machine
learning algorithm about what caused the noise.
I said to him, "Look, be a bit careful because
it's probably a good idea to make a razor a
bit quieter, but if you make it too quiet,
we genuinely won't believe it's working. Actually,
it's the crackly noise whether you rub it over
your face and it's the buzz of the thing and the
vibration of the thing that actually convinces
us it's doing a job. And you can overdo
this. You can over optimize for things."
I love all these examples you're sharing of
ways products stand out sometimes by accident,
sometimes intentionally. If I were to zoom
out and try to describe what you encourage
people to do, you basically are intent on
convincing people to think less logically,
to think less rationally, which I think is
pretty counterintuitive to a lot of people,
especially in business where they're
told, "Be more rational, be more logical."
I think what it is psychology is a branch of
complexity theory, and there are lots of things
in it which are nonlinear butterfly effects,
small things that have a huge effect, and there
are also lots of things which are, if you like
yin and yang. In other words, what I say is the
opposite of a good idea can be another good idea.
I always say there are two great ways to check
into a hotel. One of them is insanely high touch
and the other way is no touch. It'd be pretty cool
to check into a hotel where basically you just
walked in with your mobile phone and unlocked your
room. That'd be pretty cool. It's also pretty cool
if you go to the Mandarin Oriental in Hong Kong
that they take you up to your room, show you how
to use the television, the shower, I hope, because
that's always a baffling thing and that actually
make you a cup of tea in the room while you're
filling out the paperwork at your vast desk.
They're both pretty great ways to check into
a hotel. They're complete opposites, but they are
distinctive. I think understanding the fact that
what we're trying to do is we're trying to run the
world of business entirely to a reductionist kind
of maths and physics and finance model where
everything's linear and everything works in
straight lines and everything's proportionate,
and the opposite of a good idea is wrong,
and the past is a fantastic guide to the future.
We're basing our decision making on high school
maths questions. It always bothers me by the way
that intelligence tests are multiple choice. The
SAT is a multiple choice in the US I think, aren't
they? Very weirdly, a great aunt of mine actually,
who spent some time in the US I think at
Princeton, was actually involved with the
guy who designed those early intelligence tests.
By the way, she had her doubts. One of the things
she commented on was that basically if
they did an intelligence test in which
white academics didn't come top, they rejected
it as a measure of intelligence. So they found,
for example, I think that Native Americans and
African-Americans were, for instance, better at
memorizing poetry than white people were, and all
credit to my great aunt. They rejected this then
as a measure of intelligence because it didn't
fit their narrative. But the other thing that
bothers me, I'm slightly proud of my great aunt
for spotting this, calling this out as a bit
of bullshit to be honest, but the other thing
that always bothers me is that by definition,
multiple choice questions have a single right
answer. Theoretically, you could have multiple
right answers and you simply have to choose
one that is acceptable, but basically they've
got a right answer and three wrong answers.
That's how you do multiple choice questions.
But real life decisions aren't like that. You
can have multiple right answers, and also you
don't have all the information you need to answer
the question contained within the question. And
some of the information you have, which you
think is important, is actually irrelevant to
answering the question. So we have this when you
look at those intelligence tests, SAT measures,
IQ tests, they're all two buses leave a bus
station, one travels due north. They all have
an assumption of complete proportionality and
linearity. The buses are all traveling in a
straight line. You have to calculate what time
it is when the buses are a hundred kilometers
apart and there's a single right answer. And
all the information in the question is germane
to the answer that generally there isn't any
extraneous information which you have to ignore.
And there was a famous experiment actually, which
I think originated in France where they said,
"This ship stops, 27 goats get on, three sheep
get off, then they add 25 cows. How old is the
captain of the ship?" And what they found is
actually pretty intelligent kids would not give
the answer, "It is impossible to tell." They'd
assume that the information in the question,
because it's in the question, had to
be of use in formulating the answer.
And you can Google it because it then
appeared in a Chinese school exam and
it was a very interesting experiment done I
think by a French philosopher or psychologist,
which is what happens if you actually just give
people a load of data and then you give them a
question? Are they so habituated by high school
questions to assume that what's in the question
must therefore give you a single right answer? And
this is exactly what happened. If you look at real
life, i.e business decisions, which anything
that involves human behavior, it's simply all
those conditions that we are expected to look for
in something when we call it scientific. None of
those conditions are met, single right answer,
proportionality, the scale of the input being
proportionate to the scale of the effect, none
of those things are met in real world decisions,
and yet we select and promote people on their
ability to perform those artificial activities.
I'm curious if you've seen a company figure
out how to do this better. So you clearly
are incredibly good at out of the box thinking,
thinking incredibly creatively. All these examples
are examples of where something was not what
you would expect. Have you seen anyone actually
implement a way to operate where they allow
their employees and companies to think this way?
Yeah, I've across a few really interesting stories
of companies which have a much less top down. In
other words, it's a much more... You know how
in evolution, there's this theory of multi-level
selection, which is we don't just select for
individuals or genes, we select for groups, for
example. Two examples I've heard of anecdotally,
which are interesting, there's a British company
called Octopus Energy, which also has a software
division called Kraken, which it's effectively
a way of managing utilities in a much more
sophisticated pricing environment. And they have
extraordinary tariffs where if you charge your car
after midnight, you pay a tiny fraction of what
you pay the rest of the time. It's very much about
marrying supply and demand. The way they operate
is almost multicellular in that you have lots
of small autonomous teams. Their ultimate brief,
what the objective of the company is is very, very
clear, but actually they allow people considerable
autonomy within teams of 10, 15, 20 people in
terms of how they actually achieve their ends.
The second example is Shopify, where their
customer service teams are in groups of 10. And
Toby Shannon, who is the chief operating officer
of Shopify, modeled this on sports teams. He said,
if you look at teams of people in sport,
your typical sport will have somewhere
between rugby might be 15 and soccer is 11,
and cricket is 11. But generally teams have
those double-digit team sizes, and he thought
there was something meaningful about that.
And so although it meant in some
ways a much less lean structure,
because normally in a call center environment,
you'd have one person managing 100 people,
and you had effectively a team leader with a team
of 10. And what was interesting that emerged from
this is although he had to fight for this to an
extent, these people were extraordinarily happy in
their jobs and extraordinarily motivated, but also
kept each other motivated because the teams were
small enough where people felt debts of obligation
to their other teammates. In other words, if you
work for an organization of 100 people and you
pull a sick day, you don't really feel terrible
about it. But if your pulling a sick day means
the other nine or eight people have to work quite
a lot harder because you are not there, natural
human instincts of reciprocation and obligation
don't really scale up into... There's the Dunbar
number famously of 150 people, which is the size
of military units and Oxbridge colleges and so on.
And there's that famous Dunbar number coined by
Robin Dunbar once described as the number
of people you know where you could join
a conversation in which they were engaged
with someone else without it feeling weird.
Brilliant. And most people know about 150
people where effectively you're at a party,
you see friend X who's one of your dumb bar
number one of your 150 people talking to a
complete stranger, and you can go over and join
that conversation without feeling you're a bit
of a wallflower or being a bit of an idiot by
butting in. And that's the Dunbar number 150.
There does seem to be some number around sports
teams around 10. So that's a way of designing for
humanity rather than designing for the organogram.
And a third case would be talking to someone at
a very successful British online retailer called
AO, Appliances Online is what it stands for. And
he said something fairly similar in terms of the
brief to the staff is very simple briefs like,
"Treat the customer like you treat your
grandmother." And if you look at yourself
in the mirror, the shave test, and you come home
at the end of the day, would your mum be proud of
what you've done? They actually said not those
metrics of speed and efficiency and how many
deliveries did you make, but the way in which they
define customer service, and this would apply to
call center staff as well, is imagine, treat the
customer like you're talking to your gran. I said,
"There are lots of different ways you might talk
to your grandmother, you've all got different
grandmothers, et cetera," but basically everybody
knows what that means. And similarly make your mum
proud is effectively the brief.
And I think undoubtedly, there are
two great virtues to this, one of which is that
the metrics often actually get gained or they lead
to a complete distortion of behavior. The second
thing with metrics is that either people gain them
to their own advantage or they obey them, but find
them stupid. But the loss of autonomy that results
when you're simply chasing a few metrics. Imagine
what it's like to work in a call center where you
are basically incentivized to get the customer
off the phone as quickly as you possibly can.
The loss of autonomy and judgment, the tokens, I
think, and that is deeply depressing. It's deeply
demotivating. So a final case of that is Zappos.
We're talking to the fantastic guy who is I think
chief marketing or operating officer for Zappos.
You won't believe this. I think that he refused to
make speed a measure in the call center. He said,
"The call is as long as it needs to be to solve
the problem." And they had one extraordinary
outlier, which was something like a customer
service call, which was seven hours long. Now, I
think it involved a couple of bathroom visits on
both sides. I have no idea what the problem was
that actually takes that, but that was almost a
point of principle, that if it takes seven hours
to solve the problem, that's how long we spend on
the line. And so this business where in the urge
for quantification and the urge for what you might
call de-psychologization of problems, in other
words, you define them by entirely objective,
non-psychological non-emotional measures. We've
eventually created what I call Soviet-style
capitalism. It's deeply demotivating. It's
all about of quarterly targets. At least the
Soviet Union had a five-year plan. We've got
these stupid quarterly obsessions with revenue
for meeting our forecast for quarter two. And
effectively people feel it's like metropolis and
people feel fundamentally dehumanized by this.
And the persistent cost-cutting has effectively
destroyed much of the pleasure of the workplace
because there's no discretion. There's no
discretionary judgment allowed anymore because
someone saw any deviation from this imaginary
optimum as being a cost. And we go into work to
some extent, to exercise our humanity. And that
would include not only economics or reason or
logic, it would also include things like ethics,
for example, what's fair. And this attempt, the
great [inaudible 00:29:35] Canadian philosopher,
I didn't really know much about until I came
across him in a festival in Wales where he was
speaking called John Ralston Saul, who writes,
he writes actually, I wish I'd known about this
when I wrote my book because it is kind of...
This book famously called Pascal's Bastards,
Voltaire, sorry, Voltaire's Bastards.
And it's all about how effectively the
French in the French as distinct from the
Scottish enlightenment basically became
fixated with reason, which is one of what he
calls six human skill sets, ethics, memory,
instinct, creativity. He lists about six human
qualities. And what happened effectively with the
French enlightenment was that they became utterly
fixated with reason as a problem solving mechanism
to the exclusion of anything else. And he said,
"It's not designed to be used in isolation."
You've used this term psychological
psychology, psycho-ology a few times-
Psychologic and psychological. In other
words, there's a different mechanism for
logic and decision-making within the evolved human
brain, which is actually quite a lot more nuanced
and more sophisticated than the mechanisms for
decision-making that economists theorize because
it has to account for imperfect information, it
has to account for variance in outcome. It has to
account for asymmetrical information, and it has
to account for imperfect trust. So we've evolved
to effectively operate in decision-making under
uncertainty as Herbert Simon called it. And yet
most of the actual design of procedures that we
encounter are designed for effectively information
decision-making under certainty.
And that's a very special case,
which actually never applies completely, I
would argue, or certainly very rarely actually
occurs in the real world. It mainly
actually is found in economic models.
You have a really good insight into why we think
in this irrational, illogical way, which I love.
You talk about how if we were evolving in the
savanna, if an animal's very predictable and
very logical, they're a lot easier to catch. Can
you just talk a bit about that because I think-
No, things like the ability to behave
irrationally, okay, there's a claim, and by
the way, of all the negative reviews I get, they
weren't where I expected at all. There's about
three pages in the book where I basically say,
"Being a bit Donald Trump has its virtues," which
is that no one's going to dick with you because
they're not entirely sure what you're going to
do. Now, bear in mind this does not mean I'm
absolutely an uncritical admirer of the Donald,
far from it. But the guy has operated in the
new real estate scene for quite a long time,
and one of the things you've got to learn in
that business is no one's going to survive in
New York real estate if they can actually
predict what you're going to do. I imagine
that is not a world where being completely,
consistently logical, never losing your temper,
never walking away from a deal, et cetera.
You have to be able to play those game
theoretic kind of moves. And there were people
who basically encountered this thing. Maybe I
shouldn't put it right at the end of the book,
and I put it somewhere early on who were then
driven practically insane by this assertion.
But the fact remains that there are certain
circumstances in which the ability to behave
irrationally is actually at the meta level,
highly rational. The fact that, okay, if I'm
never going to fight back against anybody who's
slightly taller than me, it's very rational, but
I'm going to spend my whole life being dicked
around by people who are quarter of an inch
taller than I. Very rational, they're bigger,
stronger than me, never do anything to retaliate.
But no, okay, we have to have some degree of,
and Darwin spotted this, some degree of kind
of random number generator in our maker.
And the most classy example of this, which is
I learned from Robert Trivers, the evolutionary
biologist, is that when a hare is being chased
by a dog, it goes into this incredibly random
pattern of movement where it will zoop straight up
in the air. It will suddenly do a 90 degree turn
to the right, it will then suddenly double
back on itself at huge speed. And it appears,
I don't know how they find this out, that
it doesn't actually know what it's doing,
that there's a random number generator and the
hairs, I think it's called in submarine warfare,
it's called doing a crazy Ivan, where you just
execute crazy maneuvers. It was Russian submarines
when being pursued by American submarines would
do something called a crazy Ivan. And the hare
has the equivalent thing, which is basically it
just enters this random movement, high-speed mode.
And the point is, it can't consciously know what
it's going to do next because the dog would then
learn to anticipate what it was doing. It has to
be random, and it almost has to be unconscious
because the hare cannot give away any telltale
signs of what its next move might be. And so
if the hare knew what the next move might be,
it would actually start to reveal preparatory
muscular movements, which the dog could learn to
read. But there are other reasons why we need to
be irrational for far less controversial or far
less survival dependent reasons than this. For
instance, the exercise of social intelligence.
We have two very strong inbuilt. We don't
utility maximize. We have two very strong
inbuilt default modes in the human brain,
one of which is habit, do what I've done
before, and the other one is social copying,
do what everybody else seems to be doing.
And they make extraordinarily good sense in
evolutionary terms because an organism that had
to learn everything from first principles would
eat a hell of a lot of poisonous berries.
Rather than going, look, "I've always eaten
the yellow berries. I seem to be fine. I don't
have the shits. Let's just stick to the yellow
berries." Well, unless there's a massive shortage
of yellow berries, that's probably a pretty good
idea. Or equally, if you find yourself in a
new environment or new habitat and all the
other primates are eating the purple berries
and nobody's touching the yellow ones in that
environment, it is probably a good idea to copy
them because there's extra intelligence there.
In other words, I can learn effectively from
copying my past behavior or copying the behavior
of others. Actually, it's a fairly low cost way of
discovering low variance, low downside behaviors.
By the way, very interestingly, actually, it was
an AI which actually went into investigating what
would be necessary for more people to have solar
panels and more people to have heat pumps. And
it is not tell them the environmental benefits.
It is not tell them how much money they'd save
by having a heat pump. No. The single thing that
would persuade people to have more heat pumps is
if three people on their street had a heat pump.
Now, to an economist, that drives them practically
insane because they go, "No, no, no. The behavior
of your neighbors should be entirely irrelevant.
You should simply do the maths and calculate how
much you'd save, compare that against the return
you'd get in a high interest savings account and
then decide whether the heat pump is worthy of
the investment." But that's not how we work.
We're not prepared to be the first person with
the worst solution. With electric cars,
there's probably a very strong heuristic,
which is every consumer's learned, whether it
was computers or DVDs or cassette decks or fax
machines or actually washing machines, but going
back with anything electrical, it pays to wait
because they get better very quickly and they
get cheaper very quickly. So are people wrong,
therefore, not to make that decision? Well,
no. What they're doing is they're learning
heuristic from past experience, which by the
way, when it applies to anything with a plug,
it's been pretty much proven. I have friends
who bought the early flat screen televisions
and they paid thousands and thousands of dollars
for these things, and you go into their house,
you go, "God, that's shit." So an awful lot
of these things are instinctive intuition
that we've just learned to experience, and we
don't know what the future's going to bring, but
actually it's what you might call decision-making
based on a reasonable expectation of something.
This episode is brought to you by Coda, and I mean
that literally. I use Coda every day to help me
plan each episode of this very podcast. It's where
I keep my content calendar, my guest research,
and also the questions that I plan to ask
each guest. Also, during the recording itself,
I have a Coda page up to remind myself what I want
to talk about. Coda is an all-in-one platform that
combines the best of documents, spreadsheets, and
apps to help you and your team get more done. Now
is the perfect time to get started with Coda,
especially its extensive planning capabilities.
With Coda, you can stay aligned and ship faster by
managing your planning cycles in one location. You
can set and measure OKRs with full visibility
across teams and stakeholders. You can map
dependencies, create progress visualizations, and
identify risk areas. Plus, you can access hundreds
of pressure-tested templates for everything from
roadmap strategy to final decision-making to PRDs.
If you want a platform that empowers your team
to strategize, plan and track goals together,
you can get started with Coda today for free. And
if you want to see for yourself why product teams
at high-growth companies like Pinterest, Sigma,
Qualtrics run on Coda, take advantage of the
special limited-time offer just for startups. Head
over to coda.io/lenny to sign up and get $1,000
in credit. That's C-O-D-A dot I-O slash Lenny to
sign up and get $1,000 in credit. Coda.io/lenny.
Why is this so important? So there's many
ways to try to win in business. There's
like the typical approach, just let's
think and brainstorm and come up with
our best ideas. Your basic premise is
too many of these are just very rational,
logical approaches to a solution. Why is it so
important to think outside the box like this?
There's a joke in the UK it's less true that
it used to be because there was a famous actor
called Jean-Claude Van Damme, who was known as
the Muscles from Brussels. But the old British
joke 20 years ago was that there are no
famous Belgians. And it's a bit weird.
Why are there no famous Belgians? And
it turns out it's a bit like why there
aren't very many famous Canadians. And the
reason is, if you're a famous Canadian,
everybody assumes you're American. And if you're
a famous Belgian, everybody assumes you're French,
unless you're a painter from the Middle Ages,
in which case you're not called Belgian at all.
You're called Flemish. They are actually a lot
of famous Belgians, but everybody assumes they're
either French or they're called Flemish because
they painted in the 16th century or something. And
interestingly, for the same reason, there
aren't very many famous marketing campaigns
to launch new innovative products
because when a product succeeds,
everybody forgets the fact that it was the
marketing that was instrumental to its success.
When I say marketing, I mean in its wider
sense. I don't just mean the advertising, the
communication, the positioning. We tend to look
at great products. We go iPhone, the Ford Model T,
and we tend to go, "Everything was a bit crap,
and then Henry Ford came along, or Steve Jobs came
along and they had this invention, and everybody
immediately saw that this was brilliant, and
they went and bought it." I've got advertisements
from 1916 advertising the benefits of electricity
in the home. In fact, that was an advertising
campaign that went on for about 30 years. I spent
an early part of my working career in advertising
persuading people to get the Internet in the late
1990s, dial up Internet. Now, we forget all that
because when we look back, we concertina history
and we go, "There was no Internet. And then Tim
Berners-Lee came up with a web and everybody
wanted the Internet." No, it's 20 years.
The mobile phone was freakish because that
was actually driven by social pressure in part.
Even people who didn't really want a mobile phone
ended up having to get one because you looked like
a bit of an asshole when people said, "What's your
mobile number?" And you couldn't give one. And
also it became impossible to meet your friends
because they said, "Okay, I'm not sure which pub
we're going to, but we'll ring you on the mobile."
If you said, I haven't got a mobile, people will
go, "Well, sod you then." But most of these things
including smallpox vaccination, Edward Jenner who
basically came up with the cowpox as a vaccination
against smallpox, which was the absolute plague
of the 18th and possibly came from the New World,
I'm not quite sure, but it was absolute plague
of the 17th, 18th century, and he comes up with
his basic vaccination thing, huge opposition,
unbelievable skepticism, massive suspicion.
If you thought that anti-COVID vaccination
was something, this was on a par with that.
His marketing coup was getting the British
royal family to vaccinate their children. Now,
so what we're saying is that first of all, when
products succeed, we forget the extent to which
marketing was actually instrumental or decisive in
their success. Steve Jobs was not a technologist.
He was a pitch man. He was a huckster. I
mean this as compliments. He was a brilliant
salesman. He was a fantastic marketer. The tech
people at Apple didn't respect him. They said,
"I don't get what Steve even does. He can't
even code." But he was absolutely brilliant
at everything from product design to focusing
on a limited number to extraordinary taste,
to giving those presentations and selling
things as a magician, effectively making
everybody believe that Apple was capable of magic
and therefore you didn't need the skepticism.
Now, so first of all, marketing plays and timing
and luck, by the way, let's also include those,
these other factors play a much greater
role in both the speed of adoption and
the success of adoption of anything remotely
new, innovative. But in hindsight, we forget
the marketing and we never say, "Because of the
great marketing, I bought that product." We go,
"I bought it because it was a great product."
But we thought it was a great product because
of the marketing. We had to persuade people to
get interesting. We had to persuade people to
vaccinate against smallpox. Penicillin came up
against a lot of hostility in very early stages.
Also, let's not forget, we're only looking at the
successes. I think there've been great products,
which are genuinely intrinsically a good idea.
I mentioned Meta Portal TV. I'd also include
Google Glass. I'd also include the wine box.
I'd include the Japanese toilet. I'd include the
air fryer until recently. These are all utterly
brilliant things, but it took in the case of the
Japanese toilet and the wine box and Google Glass,
something about the timing or the marketing,
not the product. Something was wrong and the
consumer basically never bit. It never reached
critical mass. Somehow, they couldn't cross the
chasm of the early adopter. I still think it's
barbaric. I've got a Japanese toilet here.
I don't have one in my other little flat. I
think it's barbaric that the Western Hemisphere
dry wipes. The whole of the Middle East has a
bum gun. In Japan, your lavatory quite rightly
cleans your rectum with water as God intended,
and for some reason, we in the sophisticated
West are there with a dry bit of paper,
scraping it up over our anus. This is medieval.
Think about other things, house keys. You
compare how easy it is to get into your car.
You've got some keys somewhere in your person,
in your handbag, in your briefcase. You're
not really sure where the keys are. You walk
up to your bloody car and you open the door.
Your house, it's fucking 1720. You've got to
rattle some metal things to get into the house.
Why? House building, the way we build houses will
be recognizable to a Roman. The Romans never
invented the stirrup. Would you believe that?
They didn't actually have a stirrup for horses,
so you basically had to click on with your knees.
Oh my God.
How? Okay. So what's so fascinating, the wine
box by the way really fascinating to me because
in a logical... The Kindle has only really, it's
taken up. I thought when the Kindle and tablet
came along, I admit this, I thought, "Okay, well
that's the end of the flaming line for physical
books." In fairness, I travel a lot, so I have
quite a lot of eBooks because I can then pack
one tablet in my bag and I'm carrying a library
around with me, which on a long plane flight,
it's a lot better than having to pack eight books
and decide which one you're going to read when
you get there. But if you don't travel much people
seem to refer physical books, for example. People
like these things actually like what's that funny
Scandinavian thing you write on, that pad thing?
The Remarkable tablet?
Remarkable. Okay, people like that actually
because it allows you to do less. It allows
you to concentrate because you don't get emails,
you don't get distractions, et cetera. But the
wine box should have basically... It keeps for
weeks. It's got its own tap. You can have a
glass of wine in the evening without opening
a bottle and letting the other five glasses
go off. You're not forced to become a raging
alcoholic if you live alone, which you are with
wine bottles. All of these things, vastly better
keeping in the fridge. Didn't succeed. Entirely
psychological. In terms of logical products, and
it was fascinating. The Japanese toilet, why the
hell is that? I looked at you recently at the most
expensive flat in London, which is some place in
Knightsbridge, which is going for $110 million or
something and you're going to wipe your own ass.
It's 110 million for this place and the toilets,
now, I imagine if there's a Middle Eastern owner,
they'll go and retrofit some bum guns in there.
How flaming weird is that? Seriously strange. And
you realize that actually, I mean Google Glass, it
was a kind of marketing. They launched a bit too
soon. Then they only gave the bloody glasses to
developers. Now with the best will of the world,
developers probably aren't the world's coolest
people. They're not the people you want to have
walking around your bar wearing Google Glass. The
user imagery wasn't that great. And so you have
these really interesting phenomena. I would've
bought Google Glass actually even at the insane
launch price of about $1,000 because I would
really, really like being able to walk around.
Now, I don't know what I'm talking to you now.
I don't know what the time is. I don't know when
my next meeting starts. I don't know what the
weather's like outside. If I just had regular
in eye updates, a heads-up display for shit that's
going on in my life that just reminds me of stuff
I'd easily pay, without having to look at a
digital watch, which I've bought these bloody,
both Android and Apple watches, and nah. I might
as well get my phone out basically. I've got an
ordinary analog watch here, but actually having
something which you can wear, which just goes,
"Your next meeting starts in five minutes.
The guy you're talking to is called Lenny."
All that stuff would be really, really good. I
have no idea whether the Meta Portal TV apart
from this business of the privacy thing with
Facebook, but if any product deserved to succeed
in the pandemic for crying out loud, it was video
conferencing on your TV, and yet it just didn't.
The other thing I'd say is don't think because a
product's failed in the past that you shouldn't
try again, because you know that famous thing
that the definition of insanity is trying the
same thing again and again and expecting a
different result? That's not the definition
of insanity. That's the definition of a complex
system that actually quite a lot of Internet
ideas failed. Quite a lot of online ideas failed
because they were just mistimed. Because typically
some good ideas were too early.
Great little thing actually called the Chumby,
which I had about three of them, and they
were little Internet connected devices,
and they just cycled through little
screens, which would say... Little applets,
like little kind of... You're probably an iPhone
user, but what we call them Widgets on the screen,
and they go, "These are the trains through a local
station. They're on time, they're not on time,
they're running late. This is the weather. This is
the latest newsflash from the New York Times." And
they just cycle through that stuff and they'd sit
in a little cuddly little thing. I had about three
of these. I thought they're fantastic. But again,
I'll give you two examples of this about timing.
No, hold on. It's 1989. I sign out a mobile phone.
It's like a brick. It's made by Motorola. Sign out
a mobile phone from the office in 1989 because
I'm going to a meeting somewhere off site and
I need to be contactable. So you didn't have your
own mobile phone. No. The office had about eight
of them, and you signed one out and they were
kept charging in the office. You signed one out,
you told your team what your number was for
the day, and you set out to your trip. So I'm
walking down Oxford Street with this mobile
phone and someone rings me, so I haven't
got any choice. I have to answer it. So I'm
speaking on a mobile phone in Oxford Street,
one of the busiest streets in London in
1989, two people shout abuse at me from
passing cars for using a mobile phone.
A second case, let me see if I can date
this. It would be about 2000 and crikey, about
2003, 2004, there was a company started by some
American expats called Food Ferry in London, and
I think it was a hybrid CD-ROM. You actually had a
CD-ROM of most of the stuff, and you went online,
you ordered your groceries and they delivered them
to you. And I mentioned to someone, it would've
been the early two thousands that actually
ordered my home groceries on the Internet,
and they laughed in my face. Just literally,
they went over, they said, "Hey, you'll never
get this guy. He fucking orders his groceries
on the Internet." And this is my point I'm saying
is that there's this huge psychological hurdle to
changing behavior or to getting people to
adopt behavior which is slightly unusual.
One story, I then bought my own mobile phone. It
was '89 I was borrowing the phone. It would've
been about '95, '96 when I actually had my own
mobile phone, maybe '94. I'm trying to work it
out. And I'm on the top of a bus in London and
somebody rings me and they ring me from the
States. It's my friend Ted who was a biochemist
pen, I think at the time. And I said something on
the phone. I'm sitting on the top of a bus and
I said something on the phone, which made it
obvious I was speaking to someone in America.
It was like, "What time is it with you?" Or,
"What's the weather like over there?" Basically,
it was obvious I was making an international call
on a mobile phone at the top of the bus.
I actually thought there was a mild risk
of physical attack because that was such
an extraordinarily twatty thing to do. And
I suddenly realize this because I'm old. I'm
58. I suddenly realized that a lot of younger
people don't have the chronological context. They
just assume that there was no Internet, and then
the Internet came along, so everybody got it.
The smartphone was [inaudible 00:55:02]. The
mobile phone itself was not rapid. They've existed
for about 50 years. You had to be pretty rich, and
they mostly were in people's cars. I saw someone
with a portable telephone, I think in 1984,
and that was a really weird thing for someone to
have. They weren't fast. The smartphone was pretty
fast. I grabbed that. That was a freak exception.
Most of these things are really gone on slow,
and also if you get your marketing wrong or if
you miss time your launch, or if you just misjudge
some aspect of your launch psychologically,
you can take something which is intrinsically
a brilliant product, and it will fail to bite.
That's why I think this is really important
because we have survivorship bias. We only look
at the successes. No one's there going... Certain
things, the fact that we still open our houses
with keys for crying out loud, all that stuff.
I agree. I'm excited. I'm excited
for the Tesla version of keys.
Yeah, completely. I'm completely.
You've shared all these amazing examples of
products that are great but didn't work out.
Many of the reasons that that happens is
within a company it's very hard to share
and suggest silly ideas as you describe. And
you have this actually really cool suggestion
that I wanted to highlight, which is
first, share the logical, rational,
typical answer and then create
time to think about the silly,
crazy idea. Can you talk a bit about that?
Just how to operationalize this a little bit.
According to Herodotus writing in about,
what is it? I suppose the sixth century BC,
it was about the fifth, I should know
[inaudible 00:56:46]. The ancient Persians,
when they had to deliberate,
they debated everything twice,
once while sober and once while drunk.
And only if they agreed in both states
would they go ahead with the course of action.
Now, I don't know whether being drunk is just an
opportunity to come up with a better idea
or whether it's a question of does this
appeal to us rationally? Does this also
appeal to us emotionally? I don't know.
There's something really, really interesting
about having what you might call a two stage,
a double lock of decision making, which is
okay, there's this fundamental asymmetry,
which is creative people have to present their
ideas to rational people for approval. Okay, fine,
don't mind that. Never happens the other way
around. You never get engineers or accountants
saying, "Well, I think the answer is 3.75, but
before I go and present this, I'm going to share
it with some wacky people to see if they can come
up with a neater, more cunning idea." So that's
one issue. The other issue would be, talking
about products that failed by the way, Ford and
Edison collaborated on an early, I think the first
decade of the 20th century, an early electric car.
Watch this on Jay Leno's Garage, by the way. I
think that Jay Leno is a greater philanthropist
than Bill Gates. Bill Gates is quite useful
if you're in Africa, if you've got malaria or
something, but he's not much use to me. But Jay
Leno on the other hand, takes a vast fortune,
buys and restores amazing cars, and then shares
videos about them on YouTube. Now, that's great
if you're in Africa, and it's great if you're
me. It's fantastic. I obviously adore this guy.
Interestingly, the electric car, according to
Leno and according to other articles I've read,
was actually quite good. It was quiet, it was
unbelievably good acceleration, and the range
wasn't terrible. And for the time, the speed
wasn't bad. What killed it, interestingly,
user imagery. And the user imagery was because
it was quiet, you didn't have to hand crank it.
It didn't give off fumes, it didn't make a
loud noise. They were really popular with
women and they became stereotyped as women's
car. Meanwhile, all the people doing the jalopy
racing and the customization, all the farm boys
were using gasoline cars. Now, fast-forward,
what's so fascinating, fast-forward to 2025.
I'm quite pro cars. I've got two and my wife
has one of them [inaudible 00:59:20]. And I like
them both. I wouldn't go back to gasoline because
I think they're great. They're lovely to drive.
They're like a limousine and a go-kart. They have
very few moving parts. They're incredibly quiet.
They're just lovely. Just drive one and you'll see
what I mean. And when I write in favor of electric
cars, I get all these comments in the spectator
comments below of people who really hate them.
And when they write to me, what it boils down
to is they think, it's user imagery like Google
last, and actually there's a problem with all
tech products because the first people to adopt
innovative products tend to be slightly weird.
And weird people do not confer the reassurance
of social norms in the way that adoption by
conventional people does. If you've got your
weird millionaire, rich nutter and he's got a
wind farm and he's got a heat pump, it doesn't
make ordinary people think, "Oh, I must do the
same." Now what's happening here is I didn't
realize this, but all the people who don't have
electric cars see the people with electric cars
and go, "Smug environmental tosser who's looking
down on me because I've got a diesel and thinks
he's saving the planet even though you've had to
mine all this cobalt and lithium and whatever
to produce the battery, what a twat." Now,
interesting thing about this is that in very
few cases I can encounter, I can remember
is are the electric car owners actually very
interested in the environment? They're not.
Similarly, when you meet environmental people,
they don't have electric cars. They've always
got some crappy excuse, "Yeah, but my wife needs
to do the school run and so we decided we'd get a
diesel." I don't know why. But you meet these
people, you go to environmental conferences
and you say, "So you're really keen on the
environment. You've got an electric car?" "Well,
we thought about getting one, blah blah."
Meanwhile, all the people in Essex,
Jersey who just really like cars or really like
tech are people buying electric cars. It's got
almost nothing to do with environmental
credentials. And yet by actually imbuing
these electric cars with Prius style values
of smugness, it's actually a huge obstacle to
adoption because people just, "I don't want to
be that kind of person." Now, actually, okay,
when I had an electric car three years ago, there
are fewer charging points than there are now,
but what I noticed was really odd was that if you
wanted to charge in Billariki in Essex, imagine
New Jersey, imagine Trenton, loads of charging
places there. You went somewhere really woke,
you imagine, I don't know, Cambridge Massachusetts
or whatever, nowhere to charge. Cambridge England,
absolute desert for car chargers, Brighton,
which is like the most right on city on the
south coast of England, nowhere to charge at all.
But you went somewhere a bit bling a bit eh,
loads of chargers. I don't know the hell's going
on here. And to be honest what's happened is we've
imbued electric car owners with this holier than
thou aura, which causes other people to resent
them despite the fact that incredibly few of them
are really doing this for environmental reasons.
They may be happy to have zero emission cars. I
would like to get solar panels to charge my car.
Not really to reduce carbon emissions, but just
because it'd be really cool to have a car that
runs on the sun. I quite like solar panels on my
house, not really because I'm going to save the
planet, but I like at dinner parties or rather
lunchtime, to go to a picnic and go, "Oh look,
I'm getting two kilowatts of my app."
To be honest, that's the kind of... And
actually the reason most people adopt new
technology is peacock's tail, it's showing
off. The first cars weren't as good as horses and
carts. They were done to show off. They were done
for novelty seeking reasons or for reasons of
status display. And that's what rich people
are for. They provide the early stage funding for
promising ideas before they really reach maturity.
Famously, the argument is that birds evolved
wings as sexual display plumage before they
became large enough to function as a mode
of propulsion. So birds, which seemed to
have evolved from dinosaurs for the most part,
the logic is that they first of all got wings
as a form of sexual display. The peacock got the
tail, but most other birds did the display with
the wings to look cool because I think dinosaurs
had feathers, didn't they? I think I'm right.
Okay, so there was a sexual display thing going on
and eventually they thought, "Oh, actually I did
this to show off, but I can actually get to that
branch." And so there's that early stage funding
argument and what actually provides the early
stage funding for new promising ideas is quite
often slightly [inaudible 01:04:45] people like
me. But we've got to be conscious of the fact.
And also if you really evangelize new things, I
was an air fryer evangelist literally going back
over 10 years. 15 years ago I was like the John
the Baptist of air fryers and I'd occasionally say
to an audience of 500 people, "Anybody here got an
air fryer?" And there'd always be six people go,
"Yeah, best thing I've ever bought." And
it suddenly occurred to me that actually
in a way that actually annoys everybody else.
It's not people going, "Oh, these with air fryers,
they really like these air fryers. Maybe I
ought to look at getting an air fryer." Instead,
it's like, "These people are in a cult."
What you have to realize working in marketing
is that people in marketing are very high in
openness, very high in openness to experience,
very, very keen to stand out, very keen to be
distinctive. The majority of the population are
much lower on openness to experience. They're
much more driven by habit and social norms and
largely they want to fit in. They feel comfortable
when they fit in with the people around them. It's
a slightly unusual corporate environment where
people actually want to effectively play constant
games of one-upmanship with their workmates, which
tends to happen in marketing and other functions
and tends to happen actually at the higher levels
of corporations. But it's actually slightly an
unnatural state. You've got to be very careful
working in a marketing department or being a
person who works in marketing to continually
remind yourself that you're an outlier.
One of my favorite stories from your book
Alchemy, was the story of the Walkman and
how the engineers, basically, they had the
technology to add recording to the Walkman
and they're just like, "Hey, of course
we need to add a speech we can do it."
It would've cost 50 cents because apparently they
built the first Walkman on I think it was a thing
called the Sony Talkman, which was a dictating
machine which had both a speaker and it had a
microphone. And it would've cost 50 cents or a
dollar per unit of the Walkman to add recording
functionality. Of course later on, they did add
that, much later on when people were familiar with
the concept. But I think it was Marita, I think it
was Accio Marita at Sony who was the instigator of
the Walkman project, and he was the single driver
who said, "No." And they all got very upset about
this because they said, "Look, it costs nothing
and it doubles the functionality of the device."
And Marita said, "You don't want to double the
functionality of the device. You want the device
to have one function, which it performs very
well," what Don Norman will call an affordance.
You don't want any ambiguity about what
this thing's for. What this thing's for is
for listening to high quality music while
you're on a flight or on a train journey,
and it's for that. It's a personal entertainment
device and nothing else. Once people start going,
"Is it Dictaphone? Does it have a corporate
function? Should I use it to record concerts,
et cetera?" Once it's got more than one
function, people don't know where to
start. And so I thought that was an absolutely
inspired thing, which is actually in many cases,
less is more. In other words, focus attention
on one thing, the one thing that it does,
it's really good at that thing. You don't
have to worry about anything else. If you
want to do that thing, then this is the thing
for you. And if you don't want to do that thing,
then don't buy it. Very simple binary decision.
The second you introduce complexity into the
thing, logically greater functionality should
mean greater utility, which should mean greater
value. But sometimes as with the McDonald's
menu, that was an absolutely beautiful case
where they realized that, "Okay, it's partly
about speed, it's partly about simplicity.
It's partly about supply chain, but it's
also about choice reduction. Do you want a
big Mac? Don't you want a Big Mac?" Whereas the
American Diner, which was the proceeding thing
before the McDonald's brothers came and shook
it all up with I suppose this Detroit model
of production. The American Diner was, "How do
you want your eggs?" Substitutions, over easy,
sunny side up, poach, scramble, et cetera. The
whole thing was about customization. And so this
is what I mean. Sometimes customization is
a great idea. Sometimes it's the opposite.
I think Tesla's quite clever in the choice
architecture of Tesla's is just the right amount
of choice. You don't want one color and you don't
want one battery size, but equally they haven't
gone silly. There are two interiors you can choose
from two size of wheels, five colors, five basic
colors and two premium ones. It's about right.
That's about manageable. Whereas I had a look
at customizing the new electric Range Rover today
and it just, well, it drives you insane because
you suddenly realize you're going to be spending
basically the price of a house by the time you've
added all the stuff you really, really want.
You can't actually justify buying the vehicle.
Okay, so maybe a last question. We've
covered a lot of stuff at this point,
which makes me very happy. I asked people on
Twitter what I should ask you when you were
coming on the podcast and the most common
question came around branding for startups.
So say you're a startup, you're trying to
figure out how do we build a brand for what
we're doing? Do you have any advice for early
stage founders to help build their brands,
trying to get their brand over time?
Something they could do early on?
Very simple. Be consistent, be distinctive
and be famous. Now, often, we forget this,
advertising often talks about brand in this
incredibly nuanced way about differentiation
and this and that and the other. You've got to
be distinctive undoubtedly. You've got to be
consistent for obvious reasons and you've got to
stick at it visually without dicking around too
much. But actually the reason advertising agencies
never say, "We're going to make you famous is
because it sounds too obvious." Okay, well yeah,
obviously. Yeah, but let's not talk about fame. It
is. It's about fame in that fame fundamentally
changes the rules in completely non-linear ways.
So first of all, when you are not famous, you
have to find all your customers. Suddenly you
reach this magical escape velocity of fame where
people start coming to you and they start saying,
"Have you thought of using this for this?"
Of, "Actually, you didn't think of this
as an application for your product, but I've
actually got this, I actually use it for this."
And then you reach, these are levels of fame and
they compound over time. It's not linear, it's not
attributable. You can't really say... I joke about
this, there are people who can attribute their
fame to one single event, Monica Lewinsky perhaps
being good example or serial killers. All right,
okay. "If I hadn't killed all those people, no one
would've heard of me." There are people for whom
fame is attributable, but for most people it's
a whole what you might call amalgam of different
activities going back years. And actually in
many cases we ask consumers, "How did you hear
about this?" They don't actually know. They'll
always put TV or something online, but actually
they don't know how they heard about it. They
just heard about it. And we know that people's
brains react completely differently in terms of
their level of comfort with things they've heard
of before versus things that are completely
new. It's almost similar to the heuristic of,
is everybody else eating this? Have I eaten it
before and have I heard of people eating this?
It's part of that same package of right
in the motherboard at human psychology.
So fame is completely, it basically changes the
rules for everything. When your chief executive
rings somebody up, they probably call back. If
you're a famous company, if he's heard of you
or she's heard of you, she'll call back. If they
haven't heard of you, they probably won't call
back. What's that worth? What's it possible? It's
impossible to quantify the value of fame. People
come and work for you for less money. People
actually apply to you without you having to
find them. People stay longer, customers come to
you and give you the benefit of the doubt. You're
allowed to cock up once if you're famous. People
will give you, if you've got a great brand, the
best definition of a brand is from the guy who's
called Eric Johnson, I think, who wrote the book,
Blind Sight and he's also written a book called
Brands That Mean Business. It's a great book.
It deserves to be much more famous actually.
And there's a sentence in that book which says,
"Having a great brand means you get to play the
game of capitalism on easy mode." And I genuinely
can't think of a better definition than
that. Now, the point about playing on easy
mode is can you quantify the value of that?
Well, no. Because you don't know what your
score would've been if you were playing on
hard mode or psycho mode. I'm not a gamer,
but you know what I mean. Okay. Can you also say
which of your various activities contributed to
the building of that great brand? Well, no, you
can't because it's actually not even an amalgam
of things. It's actually a concatenation.
There are a host of elements here which are
catalytic. They're not linear. And that's the
other thing, which is that because it's not
linear, attempts to evaluate advertising on
short-term transactional metrics will always
grotesquely undervalue the contribution of that
activity to your ultimate business success. It's a
bit like when I first got a pension for the first
few years, brand building is a bit like a pension.
For the first few years I had a pension. Oh God,
I'm paying this guy a few hundred quid a month and
look, half it's gone in commission and there was a
lot of work and I'd rather have the money to have
an Indian meal. I don't know why I'm doing this.
Oh look, it's hardly gone up at all. What a bore,
what a waste of time. I thought that for
about three years. I'm 58 now and I've got
a pension and I go, "Where did all this money
come from? I don't remember paying this."
It really is like that. It's a compounding effect.
And everybody effectively, because we have finance
and ROI and all those things, everybody's
using addition, multiplication, subtraction,
and division to try and quantify the value of an
activity, which actually is about power laws. It's
not about that linear bullshit. It's really
about power laws and non-linearities and all
this kind of stuff. And so we are being judged
by the wrong maths. We're being evaluated by the
wrong maths and also we're being evaluated
over the wrong timeframe. And consequently,
my argument would be that at a very rough
estimate, an awful lot of marketing activity
is in reality four times as valuable. Four is,
okay, I'm plucking that number out of the air,
but four seems about [inaudible 01:16:25] is
probably four times as valuable as people think
it is when they measure its short-term
contribution. Could be more of course
I love that because over time it will build
and it compounds. It's like a drip. I love
the three points you made about how
to build a great brand consistency,
distinctiveness. What was
the third? It was be famous?
Yeah, consistency,
distinctiveness, probably clarity.
Clarity.
Just be famous.
Great.
Yeah. Some sort of clarity of promise, I think.
Amazing. Consistency-
I think a good brand is a promise, but also
the extent to which it contributes to trust,
which is that if you met a celebrity on the
street, I don't mean a serial killer celebrity,
I mean a famous actor. One thing you
wouldn't think about is are they going
to steal my wallet? Are they going to mug me?
Are they going to do anything weird? They may
have lots and lots of vices, but generally people
who have a lot of reputational skin in the game,
who've invested a lot in building up a reputation
over time are going to be much more cautious about
disappointing their customers or risking negative
feedback than someone nobody's ever heard of.
And let's be honest, I think it's even more
extreme in the United States than it is in
the UK. The relationship people have with
celebrities is kind of pervy and weird.
They imbue these people with superpowers. They're
actors. They didn't actually fly through the air,
but somehow people treat them with this reverence
because they're just famous. And the point is,
it's easy mode. If you are actually pretty
famous, you are playing that game on easy
mode because so many things which require
massive reassurance, due diligence, checking,
you take it to the board and three people on the
board have never heard of the company so they want
you to go back and check with so-and-so.
And then you walk in and you're famous,
the rules are different. When I say there are
also these inflection points like escape velocity,
I always say about Coke that Coke has
reached a magical level of fame where
it is your expectation that any shop or bar or
cafe or bistro style restaurant will stock it.
I can ask for this anywhere, and if
they haven't got it's their fault,
not mine. Now that that's really mega fame. But
equally in B2B, there's an inflection point in
B2B marketing, which is that if no one ever got
fired for buying IBM, we know the famous phrase,
if you appoint Pricewaterhouse or EY or
whatever to your audit and something goes wrong,
everybody blames them. If you appoint someone
nobody's ever heard of to be your auditor and
something goes wrong, everybody blames you for not
appointing Pricewaterhouse or EY. It's rather like
one of the reasons I fly with... I wouldn't go on
a business trip with Ryanair, even though they're
actually pretty good and they're very punctual,
is if the flight gets canceled or delayed and I
ring the client and say, "I'm terribly sorry, the
BA flight's been delayed." They go, "Oh, well,
never mind you did your best." And if I ring up
and say, "The Ryanair flight's been delayed," it's
not quite the same, is it? I haven't necessarily
tried. I've skipped on that. You see what I mean?
Yeah.
And so various things, it's not just what things
are, it's what they mean. And we use brands as
extended phenotypes to express ourselves
in all kinds of ways. So this is the other
thing with brands, it's not just a simple
consumer. It's not just a simple business
consumer relationship. There are all kinds
of things as what does the brand I use say
about me? It's do the people who know me
know what this brand means? It's no good
being a luxury car that only rich people have
heard of. Because in order to convey prestige,
it's necessary for you to know that other
people know that BMW is a prestigious car
brand and so on and so forth. So there are
lots of things here which are second order,
third order, non-linear compounding factors.
We just have to acknowledge this is a different
kind of maths and yet we're being judged on an X
minus Y equals Z maths. Doesn't make any sense.
Maybe as a final question, is there
anything you want to leave listeners with,
folks that are building product? Any
lasting piece of nugget or advice?
Try and do the psychological and the technological
and the economic for that matter. In other words,
the sweet spot is it works psychologically. It
works technologically and it works economically.
In other words, you can make money out of
it. People want it and it allows them to
do something significantly new by using some
clever application of tech. Try and use those
three things in parallel because I think what
most businesses do is they try and do things in
series and businesses borrow an awful lot from
the Fordist Taylorist production line mentality
of the process. And the process, we have to
pretend that the process is linear, but the
process of any kind of innovation or development
is not linear. They're loads of products, which by
the way have completely failed at first iteration,
and then someone sold them in a different way and
they then turn out to be completely successful.
The Pivot is an example of that. Famously Wrigley
started off selling soap powder in Chicago. Then
he started giving away baking powder free to
sell the soap powder, and then realized he'd start
making baking powder and selling that, and he gave
away chewing gum that went on the baking powder
as a gift. And then people liked the chewing gum
a lot more than they liked the baking powder. So
as a result, Wrigley became a chewing gum company.
But we're always trying to make this thing
linear because when we tell stories backwards,
we post-rationalize and we reverse engineer and we
reverse engineer our actions to make it all seem
perfectly linear and logical as a self-check. The
real process is never like that. And I think you
should have marketing. Marketing and innovation
are two sides of the same coin. As I often say,
you can either work out what people want
to find out a clever way to make it,
or you can work out what you can make and
find a clever way to make people want it.
And actually the greatest things manage to do
both. Simple as that. Don't do it one than the
other. Don't leave marketing to the last minute,
but equally work in parallel as far as you can.
Where can people find your book and
Nudgestock? Point them real quick.
Nudgestock.com. The book's called Alchemy and
it's got a variety of subtitles depending on
which country you're in. But if you
look for Alchemy by Rory Sutherland,
the audiobook is probably the best thing to
buy because I actually read it myself and I
rift a bit from that. But also available on
Kindle and from all good bookshops and quite
a few rotten ones. And there's also a book
I've co-written called Transport for Humans
co-written with Pete Dyson. If you're in the
transportation industry, I'd recommend that one.
Amazing. Rory, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you for that. Always a joy.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to the show on
Apple Podcasts, Spotify or your favorite podcast
app. Also, please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.