You're VP of product at Facebook. You're
director at eBay and PayPal. You're on
the board of Intuit. You've been the
CEO of Ancestry now for the past three
and a half years. This is a career
path that a lot of people dream of.
Some of the best PMs I have ever worked
with are terrible PMs for their career.
They just drift from job to job. "Hey,
should I take this role or this role?
How do I think about this?" But if I said
you had to write a spec for your career,
what does success look like?
How are you going to get there?
You wrote this awesome post about introverts and
how hard it is to be successful as an introvert.
The workplace is really favoring people who
can speak up. It looks like self-promotion.
I wouldn't want to do that because
it's self-promotion. But instead,
what if I called it educating about all the great
work your team has been doing? Helping people see
why your team should get more resources,
you have to actually share what you do.
Is there something that you believe that
you think most other people don't believe?
The most important career decision
you make is who you marry. Is this
person lifting you up or pushing
you back? You will have a much more
successful career if your home life is
in balance. It's like a yin and a yang.
Today, my guest is Deb Liu. Deb was VP
of product at Facebook where she spent
over 11 years and while they're created and
led Facebook marketplace, which is now used
by over 1 billion people monthly, she also led
the development of Facebook's first mobile ad
product for apps and its mobile ad network.
Also built the company's games business and
payments platform, including Facebook Pay.
Prior to Facebook, she was director at both
PayPal and eBay. She's on the board of Intuit and
for the past three and a half years, she's been
the CEO of Ancestry. I actually generally have
a rule of no CEOs on this podcast, but to me,
Deb is a great exception because she's a product
person at heart. In our conversation, Deb shares
a ton of tactical career advice, including
why resilience is so key to career success,
how to PM your career like you PM your product,
how to be successful in business as an introvert,
what she's learned about building multiple
billion dollars zero to one businesses within
a large company like Facebook and so much more.
Deb is so full of wisdom and I'm really excited
to share her insights with more people. If you
enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting
app or YouTube. It's the best way to avoid
missing future episodes and helps the podcast
tremendously. With that, I bring you Deb Liu.
Deb, thank you so much for being
here. Welcome to the podcast.
It's wonderful to be here, Lenny.
It's wonderful to have you here. You have had
such an incredible career. You're VP of product
at Facebook. You're director at eBay and PayPal.
You're on the board of Intuit. You've been the
CEO of Ancestry now for the past three and a half
years. This is a career path that a lot of people
dream of and honestly just like one of those
roles is a dream for a lot of people. And so
I wanted to start with just this question and
I want to see where the conversation takes us.
If you could give one specific piece of advice
to someone that's looking to do well in their
career or to do better in their career based on
what has worked well for you, what would that be?
Always be learning, and I tell this
to everybody, so I often tell people,
someone who's always learning is always going
to exceed someone who's the expert today. You're
going to find people... The one thing about school
is that we go to school and there's such a thing
as getting a hundred on the test, a perfect
score on the SAT, graduating with a 4.0. Well,
there's nothing like that in careers, right?
We think it's actually a non-linear experience
and there's always something better than you at
speaking or presenting or strategy or execution.
But if you're always learning, learning from
the best, getting feedback, you're always
going to get better every single day.
And that's what I have always held,
which is each job I took, I didn't necessarily
qualify for it. I wasn't necessarily the very
best at it, and so it became the student of being
better at that job. And once I mastered that,
I was a student for something else,
something else and something else. And
so I always balanced learning and impact,
which was you can have the most impact,
the job you know the best, but then you stop
learning. And if you're learning all the time,
you're not necessarily having impact.
So how do you keep going back and forth
and back and forth so that you're not going
straight up a lot or you're actually laddering
back and forth into different things where you're
having an amazing time where you know everything
and then you're the newbie again and learning new
things, and you're incorporating what you used to
know into what you're learning and the impact
that you have today and so on and so forth.
This episode is brought to you by Pendo, the
only all-in-one product experience platform
for any type of application. Tired of bouncing
around multiple tools to uncover what's really
happening inside your product? With all the
tools you need in one simple to use platform,
Pendo makes it easy to answer critical questions
about how users are engaging with your product
and then turn those insights into action.
Also, you can get your users to do what
you actually want them to do. First, Pendo is
built around product analytics, seeing what
your users are actually doing in your apps so
that you can optimize their experience. Next,
Pendo lets you deploy in-app guides
that lead users through the actions
that matter most. Then Pendo integrates
user feedback so that you can capture
and analyze what people actually want. And
the new thing in Pendo, session replays,
a very cool way to visualize user sessions.
I'm not surprised at all that over 10,000
companies use it today. Visit pendo.io/lenny to
create your free Pendo account today and start
building better experiences across every
corner of your product. PS, if you want to
take your product-led knowhow a step further,
check out Pendo lineup of free certification
courses led by talk product experts and
designed to help you grow and advance in
your career. Learn more and experience the power
of the Pendo platform today at pendo.io/lenny.
Pendo.
This episode is brought to you by WorkOS. If
you're building a SaaS app, at some point your
customers will start asking for enterprise
features like SAML authentication and skim
provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in, making
it fast and painless to add enterprise features
to your app. Their APIs are easy to understand so
that you can ship quickly and get back to building
other features. Today, hundreds of companies
are already powered by WorkOS, including ones
you probably know like Vercel, Webflow, and Loom.
WorkOS also recently acquired warrant, the Fine
Grained Authorization service. Warrant's product
is based on a groundbreaking authorization system
called Zanzibar, which was originally designed
for Google to power Google Docs and YouTube.
This enables fast authorization checks at enormous
scale while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases.
If you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features like
single sign-on, skim or user management, you
should consider WorkOS. It's a drop in replacement
for auth zero and supports up to 1 million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
workos.com to learn more. That's workos.com.
You talked about you got into a new job maybe
you weren't ready for and you had to learn on
the job. So either maybe share story one
of those experiences or just like how do
you actually do this? So someone's listening,
they're like, how do I learn? What am I learning?
We'll start with my career in tech. So I had
worked in consulting before business school.
I went to Stanford for business school, came out
to California, didn't know that much about tech,
but I really loved using eBay. So I interned
there my first year in business school and then
when it came to finding a job, I really wasn't
sure what we wanted to do, but we wanted to move
back to the East Coast. And so I wasn't looking
and I couldn't find a job. I think it was really
hard. It was 2002. And so I ran into Tim Wenzel
and Catherine Wu. So Catherine Wu was from Airbnb
as you might know her. And Tim Wenzel put together
the PayPal Mafia. He was the recruiter for PayPal.
Went to this table and I said, "Absolutely love
PayPal, use it all the time. I'm a big seller
on eBay," and he's like, "Do you want a job?"
I'm like, "No, I'm actually going back east.
"And he's like, "Just come in and talk to us." And
so I said, "Okay. Well, what kind of jobs do you
have?" And he's like, "I have jobs in product
and I have jobs in marketing." Now, I've taken
marketing class obviously in business school, and
I said, "I wonder what this other product job is."
So I look over at Catherine and I've seen her
around Stanford before, so she was a year ahead of
me and I said, "Well, what do you do?" She said,
"Product." I'm like, "That sounds good. I'll do
that." And that's actually how I fell into product
management. Well, I actually, and I'm embarrassed
to say faked my way through those interviews,
because during the interviews they're like, "Well,
what would you build?" And since I was an avid
user of both products, I could really richly say,
"Here's the product feedback I have. Here are the
new products you should build. Here's my feedback
on things that we should be doing differently."
And they said, "Congratulations." And they gave
me the job. And embarrassingly I went to the first
day of work and I said to Amy Clement, who was the
VP of product at the time, and I said, "Okay, I
literally have no idea what this product job is."
She showed me the ropes and she was
so incredible. She actually showed me,
she said, "All those ideas you had, all that
energy you've had around building these things,
we go do that. Let's go do it." And I said,
"Well, how do you do that?" And she said,
"Well, you write down what you want to build
and you work with the engineers to do it."
And I just remember thinking, "This is
crazy. I have no idea what I'm doing."
It was such an incredible adventure though.
Those first few years, I just learned so much
about the craft of building, how to really think
through product use cases, how to think through
what customers wanted, not just the customer of
one, myself, but really what true customers and
customer cohorts wanted. And so it was really a
time when I felt like I was really blossoming,
but I didn't come in with mastery. I came with
a curiosity and I think that's what made me a
great product manager was that I didn't have
a set way of doing things. There wasn't some
playbook I was trying to play. There wasn't some
framework, but instead I was willing to learn.
So one takeaway might be from this, the phrase,
fake it till you make it. Any thoughts on just how
to... I imagine many people right now are like,
"Oh, I'm trying to get a job as a pm. How do I do
this? That sounds great. I'm going to pass this
interview, figure out the job after I joined."
Coming in with humbleness was really important,
but during the interview process, actually,
I didn't realize this, but they asked me
questions as if I was a product manager,
as if I knew what I was doing. I think
when you have passion around a product or
passion around a company or around a business
model or around something, it shows. And so
it's not necessarily faking the enthusiasm or
faking the idea that you want to work there,
but you don't have to know how to write this
spec or PRD or briefings or anything like that.
You don't know how to do customer research
or do data analytics or read reports,
but instead show your passion around the product
itself, around the use case, around the customer.
Show who you are and why you care. I think
sometimes people just say, "I want a product
job." But you have to be able to fall in love with
the problem. You have to fall in love, not with
the product, but I said the problem, right?
The use case. What problem are you trying to
solve? And if you can do that, you can be a great
product manager even without a lot of experience.
That's an awesome piece of advice. So
just lean into the passion. First of all,
part of it is you have to be excited about the
thing you're trying to work on or thinking about
the company you're thinking about joining.
Sounds like that's a prerequisite here. We
have a podcast episode with Uri Levine who has a
whole book called Fall in Love with the Problem,
which is all about that same idea
actually for startup founders.
I'll have to read it.
Yeah, he always wears a shirt, fall in
love with the problem, not the solution.
Yes, is absolutely the most
important skill for a product leader.
Something else I've heard
you talk about in terms of
something that contributed to your success is
being okay with failure and just bouncing back
quickly versus avoiding failure. Is that
something that you can come back to a lot?
Well, here's what I noticed about everybody. I've
coached a ton of people in my life. I have managed
big teens and the people who are most successful
are not the people who had no failures, who were
lived charm lives, head up into the right careers
and got promoted every cycle. The people who were
most successful were the ones who actually through
adversity, learned to turn stumbling blocks into
stepping stones. They were the ones who got hard
feedback and then came back stronger because
now they learned what to do differently.
They were the ones who products failed,
but they said, "You know what? I'm going to turn
this failure into success. I'm going to take those
lessons and make this company stronger." When you
live a charmed product life, you always work on
everything that's easy. You don't actually...
Trees are strong because they bend in the wind,
because they're tested, because it's cold,
because it's windy, because there's conditions.
And that's how a tree goes grow strong and
tall over many generations. And I think
sometimes we think, "Oh yeah, I wish I lived
a charm life." And that is not what we want.
You want to have enough adversity that you learn
to overcome so that you can build stronger over
time and build resilience in your career.
I've seen that so much, which is the best
product leaders I ever worked with are the
ones that have the toughest stories, that had
the hardest feedback, but also the ones who were
able to bounce back quickly and make it happen.
We have a segment on this podcast called
Failure Corner where people share a failure
they went through kind of along the same
lines and something we learned from that
experience. Is there an example of that from
your career where a failure made you stronger?
Yeah. I remember there was a job that I really
wanted at Facebook and I'd been there for a long
time. I had been leading different teams. I was a
VP of product and then GM. There was one job that
I never got to do, so I got to do all the jobs
I wanted and Mark gave it to someone else. I
told him at the time when he gave it to the first
person who was amazing at it, I said, "If this job
were open, I'd like to be considered for it."
The job opened up later, gave it to someone
else. And I said to Mark, again, "I
really wanted that job." And he said,
"Not only will I not give you that job,
you'll never have that job at this company."
What?
He didn't say it harshly. But he was giving
me feedback about something which he did not
see me in that role, in a role that I really
wanted. And I had to decide each time like,
"What do I do with this information?" This is
my dream job. Actually, I decided I was going
to turn the job I had and the job I wanted,
and that's a choice. I could have said,
you know what? I can't have that job. I could go
do something else, but I didn't. I took the job I
had with the team I had and I turned it into this
thing that was going to be something we wanted.
And so I think sometimes it's not... I think that
that experience was a very humbling experience
because to be told no and then to say that
this will never happen was really hard. But
at the same time it was a reminder that you're
not right for every job even if you think you
are. And that you can take the raw materials of
what you have and turn it into what you want.
Are you able to share what those jobs were
that you wanted to get that you never got?
I never actually shared it publicly, but it's
something which I had always had a role where
I did new things for the company and there was a
role where it was running something which more of
an existing business, but I had always been kind
of the innovator, the new stuff person. I had
taken over so many new things. And so maybe that
wasn't the right thing at the right time for me,
but it was something that was really
incredible and a turning point for me.
Great segue to an area I wanted to spend some time
on which is building zero to one stuff within a
larger company. So from what I can tell you built
2 billion businesses within a large company,
Facebook marketplace, and then the ads platform
within Facebook and maybe more. I don't know,
the payments stuff, the games. I don't
know. Maybe there's billions of dollars
there I don't even know about. And
this is very rare and very hard,
and it's something we talk a little bit on this
podcast, just the skills to build something new.
I know with marketplace it was not something
people believed in for a long time. It took
a lot of work to convince people to actually
give it a shot. So I guess the question here
is just what have you found are key tactics to
start something new and allow it to continue to
exist and get to a place where people start
to believe it? What has worked for you?
So first, I didn't build the ads platform. I
actually built the first direct response ad
product company ever had. But we'll talk about how
that led to why direct response is a vast majority
of the ads revenue for the company. But one thing
that it was really interesting is that I really
saw my opportunity in Facebook to be somebody
that zigged when other people zagged. There
were amazing people who did a lot of the really
core products working on feed, photos, videos.
I came in actually on the payments team and we
worked on payments and eventually built games,
which was the first billion dollar business.
It was very successful. We worked with the
likes of all the game companies that
were on the Canvas games platform.
And it was just an incredible opportunity
to start from scratch and built something
really cool. We built Facebook credits, which
eventually became the Facebook payment system.
And then from there on I built the first
direct response ads product. And again,
leveraging the skills that we had, we had
a lot of relationships with game companies
because of my time and payments.
And so we just said, "Hey look,
what ad product do you want?" And they said,
"Actually, your biggest challenge is the shift
to mobile. Build us a mobile acquisition
engine." And we said, "That's doable."
At the time the company was very brand oriented.
Most of the ads... Actually almost all the ads
on the platform were brand and we were not even
on the ads team. So we actually worked on this
team called the platform team. We said, "Okay,
we'll build an ads product for the Facebook feed,
the new mobile Facebook feed." And suddenly it
became a billion dollar business within about 18
months, which was such an incredible journey.
We worked on the mobile advertising platform,
so basically the mobile ads network. That was a
great experience. And so each time I worked on
something, it was just... The thing that you have
to remember is the failure rate for something like
this is very high. You start something and the
amount of iteration... People think, "Oh yeah,
it's easy." You start something and it's linear
because you have all the resources of this company
behind you. But actually everything in the company
is like, "Let's do the most important thing."
These are seeds and we'll just let them... And
so if you do that, you have to know that you
don't get a lot of resources, you get a lot
of attention. And I appreciated that because
I think I work best when people aren't... There
is not a lot of scrutiny. I think sometimes large
companies, they say, "Well this innovation
team," and then they check in on them way
too much. They're like, "Week to week progress,
where are you going? What's your strategy?" But
so much as you know of building something new is
the iteration process. It's the failing a lot.
We actually tested five or six versions of the
ads product before we got it to take off and it
took months, and then we were on the verge of
death multiple times. In fact, I actually went
back to run the payments team while I was working
on that product because the team we had gathered
still want to continue working on it, but I
needed a second job back on the payments team
because they asked me, "We don't think this thing
is going to work. You should go run your old team
again." And I thought, "Well, I will do both."
And so I did both for a while until it really
took off. The thing that I think a lot of
large companies don't realize is that you
can love something to death. And so with every new
product, I'd rather do it out of the limelight,
do it with the minimal resources and have the
freedom to fail because success and failure
really is... In startups, failing fast
is really important or succeeding fast.
It's the long slog that makes it really hard. In
a company, you end up getting cut if you're the
long slog product. And so being able to just say,
"You know what? We're pruning this. We're doing
the next thing, the next thing." And then having
the time to iterate and grow is really critical.
So as a leader trying to do this and create space
for this, is there something you've learned about
how to allow for, "Don't over scrutinize us,
don't look at us too carefully. We don't want
to be in the limelight. Don't put too many
resources on this yet." Is it just like, "Hey,
Mark. Here's what I think." I imagine it's not
as easy as that. There's a lot of influence and
that kind of work. Is there any tactics that you
could share to create this sort of environment?
I think the most important part of the
environment is really patience. And again,
this is a portfolio strategy and I tell every PM
who... I used to do a new hire PM class and I say,
"Look, a lot of you are going to go into the
core product and your job is to grow X by 3
to 5% every six months. Growing engagement or
growing sessions or maybe growing video views
or whatever your metric is, you're trying to grow
something 5% and then you exceed expectations."
And I said, "And then a bunch of you are
like, 'I want to do something new. I want
to build something from scratch.'"
And I said, "By the way, a very,
very successful company for a new set of
products has a 50% hit rate. So half of
you are going to come back in a year and have a
different job because that did not work out. Do
you have the resilience to do that?" And I think
somebody, you enter a large company... By the way,
you can have an amazing career building core
products because that is an incredible journey
within... Because you learn so much
about the mechanics of what that takes.
And yet at the same time, I found a lot of
energy from doing something that someone
hasn't done before. And so I really enjoyed the,
"Hey, this thing could fail. Let's pivot. Let's
try to figure out. Let's prune this. Let's try
that." And not everything I did there succeeded,
but a lot of the things that are the lasting
products are once that gotten really big. And
so for me it was a greater reward and it
made a journey so much more interesting.
But for others, I think work on the core
product, learn the skills. It is absolutely
respectable as well. But if you choose to be
the person who works on innovation new products,
expect in a year, you might literally have
nothing to show for it, but the lessons that
you learned. And I think those lessons are really
precious and we often underestimate that too.
Along those lines, do you think it's a
good career move to do a zero to one thing
within a bigger company? Or is it often a bad
idea? Do you have any advice there for folks?
It depends. It depends on your personality
in the company. So the one thing I realized
about my role was that I did a lot of... I
had five different careers at the company
over 11 years. And so most people don't
realize that when you work on new things,
you're constantly adding to your portfolio,
subtracting from it, growing things, pruning
them. And so you could just work on so many cool
things except everything has similar... It's
like it rhymes, but it's not exactly the same.
So you learn the lessons of how to get things
done, how to get resource, how to get support
when the product is not working, how to not get
prunes in the next culling. And those are really,
really important skills. But I think for people
who are just starting out of the career, it is
a very high risk thing to do. So if you're very
early in the career, I encourage people just
learn the core skills first. You can learn the
core skills when there's a lot of stability. This
product is growing X percent, like 5%, and you're
going to grow at 10. That's amazing.
That is because you are there, you're
going to change your trajectory of the product,
or this thing has a hundred thousand users,
you're going to get it to 200,000. Those are the
kinds of things that are going to be successful
for you and you can put on your resume. But I
think it reaches a point in your career where
you have to decide, when am I going to take
the big swing? Because the big swings are
the things that you write your career stories
about. They're not just, I moved this metric X,
but I changed your trajectory in this way.
And so the big swings though have a lot of
failures along the way. And so you have
to understand you're making trade-offs in
that. I encourage everybody to take some time,
two, three years in their career when they're
ready for the big swing, where if it doesn't
work... If it works, you run the team, you run
this amazing product. It doesn't work, you can
always go back and go back to the core products.
It's interesting how your strategy here
is very similar to a product portfolio
strategy where as a team should have a few
big bets and then a lot of incremental stuff.
And it reminds me about this awesome post
called You Are in Control of Your Career.
And the argument in your post is you should
PM your career the way you PM your product.
So there's a lot of synergy here. So maybe just
diving into this post and advice around this,
how should someone be PMing their career, the
way they PM a product? What's your take there?
By the way, for your PM audience, I want to
say this, which is a lot of the greatest PMs
are the worst PMs of their careers. They love
products. They love the crafts. They love the
customer research, the data. They have plans, they
have timelines. And then when it comes to career,
they have none of those things. They just drift
from job to job. "Hey, should I take this role
or this role? How do I think about this?" But if
I said you had to write a spec for your career,
what's in there? What are your milestones?
What are the skills? What are the features
that you want to have of your career? How are you
going to get there? What does success look like?
You actually have metrics for your product, and
yet you don't have metrics for your career. I
coach a lot of people and when I coach them, I ask
them, "Well, where do you want to see yourself in
five years? Where do you want to go?" And half the
people have no idea. I think that's really tragic
because when you PM your career, it's about
intentionality. But I'll tell you the story
of my career and how I was the accidental PM and
then eventually... I told you how I accidentally
fell into PM, but also fell into so many of
the things that happened in my PM career.
And if I had to go back, I would think much
more deeply about what I want to accomplish.
So I ended up at PayPal working for a guy
named Dave Lee who reported to Amy Clement,
and then he left. And so she offered me his role.
I had only managed people for, I don't know,
15 seconds. I was two years out of business school
and I was definitely not qualified to do his job.
He was the director of product. I wasn't even
a director and I was running the team for eBay.
So basically the PayPal part of eBay, which
was basically half the company's revenues and
profits. Totally unqualified. I ended up in this
job and I do a good job. I ended up doing it for
several years. I built up the team and we have a
great relationship with eBay. Our team was very
close and we were able to actually build something
really lasting that worked really well. And then
I had a baby. And so this happens in a lot of
women's careers. I was turning 30, I had my son,
and I had to leave for six months.
So I handed my product to my successor,
Mike Woo and he ended up taking over.
He did such a good job while I was gone,
I didn't want to displace him when
I got back. And so I thought, "Well,
I'll go and look for another role." I couldn't
really find a product role I liked, I mean,
because there weren't that many product director
roles. And so I ended up in corporate strategy. So
I worked for the amazing Rajiv who was CEO at the
time. He since passed and I wrote his speeches,
worked on strategies, I worked on digital
goods and charity, and ended up building
that into a vertical for the company. So
charity, social commerce and digital goods.
And I thought, "Okay, this is an
interesting job." So I create the job,
have a couple product managers, wasn't really sure
where this was going, and then one day I was like,
"You know what? I'm not feeling this. I have a
child at home." I had gotten into what Cheryl
Sandberg calls that kind of between kids
situation where I was bored of my job.
I was working one of the VPs I worked with
and I resigned. I said, "I'm leaving tech,
just I'm going to stay home and maybe start
something small." He convinced me to hold off
and he said, I'll find you a job. He calls
me a week later and he said, "Found you a
job with Stephanie Tilenius leading the buyer
experience at eBay product." And I said, "Oh,
that sounds interesting." So I said, "Sure, as you
notice, I do not have a plan. I'm just drifting.
I'm so fortunate that I had amazing mentors who
gave me opportunities, but end up working for Greg
Fant and Stephanie Tilenius at eBay for two years.
I led the buyer experience. We did some really
good work there. And then went on maternity
leave again. And I get a call from a friend,
my old engineering manager from PayPal, "Hey, I'm
at Facebook. Do you want to come? You can't come
into product. You need a CS degree for that, but
we have a product marketing job open." I was like,
"Sounds good." Drop into Facebook. And so again,
no idea what I'm doing back in product marketing.
So I spent a few years doing that. Eventually
was invited into product and so on and so forth.
And each job that came along was organic, but also
kind of accidental. I see that happen in a lot of
careers, which is my story when you look back,
looks great. It looks like it all worked out,
but I had almost zero intentionality
in any of these. And I think that had
I had more agency and I thought about what
I wanted, I could actually measure is this
the thing that would get me further or not?
I ended up extremely lucky, but not everybody
does. And so I think having a plan allows you to
compare every decision. It's not like when you're
offered an admission to college, we're looking
at three different offers maybe with financial
aid or not, and you can make a decision,
"Oh, they're offering me this department,
but I can't get into this department." This is
how far it is from home. But jobs and roles or
nothing like that. Someone calls you one day,
"Hey, I'm at Facebook. Do you want to come? I'm
actually on maternity leave." And he's like,
"Just come talk to me." I'm like, "Why not."
And you end up dropping into different parts
of your life and I think sometimes by saying,
"Here's where I want to go and here's how
I want to get there," you can have such a
better career. And so I do encourage everybody
to do this and to think about what does success
look like in five years and how far am I from
that and am I heading in the right direction?
What's interesting is I also had a
similar path to you where I had zero
plan or intention or goal and also
just follow things and things worked
out. I wonder how often that happens and
I wonder if this idea of having intention
and planning a roadmap is something you
do if things aren't working out because
maybe there's some good to not overthinking
it and just following pull. I don't know.
Well, I think the problem is this with you and
me, Lenny, is that hindsight bias is a problem.
We made it because we weren't intentional
in a lot of ways, but for how many people,
is that true? For how many people who aren't...
You don't have a plan and you get there. I
always tell people, if you are sure what your
destination is, that's definitely where you're
going to end up. But if you actually aim in the
right direction, you can shape your learnings,
you can shape your roles you take, you can shape
your skills towards the place that you want to go.
When you talk about getting
this offer from Facebook,
usually those are like you
have three days to decide.
Yes.
And it feels like that's when
the things you've done ahead of
time of here's what I want would be most helpful.
Also, I think the thing about job opportunities
in particular is they tend to come serially.
It's only you presented these offers. It's like
one role is so different from another and they
often don't happen at the same time. They might
say, "Well, you have to decide in two weeks."
And then you say, "Well, there's this other
company I'm talking to and you get a lot of
pressure to say yes to this versus this."
And to really having a measuring stick is
this getting me closer or further away from
where I go? Can allow you to actually take
serial decision making to a place where
you're measuring against a long-term goal.
I did a meditation retreat once and when
you're meditating, there's this kind of
guidance of don't try too hard, don't
push yourself to go into a direction,
"Oh, I'm not doing a good job. I need to get
to this enlightened state." And instead their
advice is just push your cart in a direction and
think about that's the direction you want head,
but you don't need to grasp on to here's where
I need to land, here's where I need to go. And
I wonder if just having a thought of here's
where I want my career to go. I want to be
on boards in the future. I want to start
a company in the future. I want to become
a designer in the future. At least start there
maybe just like a direction that you're heading.
Yeah. There's a woman who I worked with
in product and now she's the founder,
very successful founder, and she said to me,
"I want to join the board of this Fortune 100
company." She told me the company, and I
said, "Okay, that's a lot." So she said,
"How can I get there?" And I said, "First,
it's probably going to take you 10 years
because look at who's on the board. I happen to
know a couple people on the board." And I said,
"Why don't I introduce you to one of them?
And they can tell you how to get there.
But the point is she knew where she wanted to
go and she said, "I'm willing to take it first
step today." And I said, "First, you've never
been on a board. You were very successful,
but this is not... There's so many steps before
you get there. It's like before you go to Harvard,
you have to graduate from elementary school
to middle school. You have to take the SAT,
you have to apply. I said, "Let's start from the
first step and let's break this problem down."
But I love that she knew where she wanted to go
and she's like, "Even if I don't make it there,
I'll be happier having made this journey." And I
love that for her. And I think she's still earlier
in her career, she has so much time ahead of her,
but it's really incredible to see her kind of on
this path and to know that that's her dream, and
that I can help her a little bit along the way.
It also relates very much to your idea of thinking
of your career like a PM thinks about their
product where one of the tactics is to imagine
the ideal scenario and work backwards from that
versus incrementally what's the next thing? What's
the next thing? So in this case, she was thinking,
"Here's where I want to head. Okay, what's the
next thing to get to that direction?" I love that.
This episode is brought to you by
Webflow. We're all friends here,
so let's be real for a second. We all know
that your website shouldn't be a static asset.
It should be a dynamic part of your strategy
that drives conversions. That's business 101,
but here's a number for you. 54% of
leaders say web updates take too long.
That's over half of you listening right now.
That's where Webflow comes in. Their visual
first platform allows you to build, launch, and
optimize webpages fast. That means you can set
ambitious business goals and your site can rise
to the challenge. Learn how teams like Dropbox,
IDEO, and Orangetheory trust Webflow to achieve
their most ambitious goals today at webflow.com.
Okay, going a slightly different direction,
I'd say the post that you've written that has
most resonated with me was about introverts and
how hard it is to be successful as an introvert,
and that basically have to learn to be
an extrovert as an introvert because
in business extroverts are most valued.
Can you just talk about of your insight,
what you've seen around this and how
and your advice to introverts like
me about how to be successful in
business, what you need to change?
Well, first, I love the book, Quiet by Susan
Cain. She talks about the power of introverts.
Unfortunately, the world doesn't see the way
the world the way she does. I wrote this post.
It was the secret bias no one talks about, which
is the workplace is really favoring people who can
speak up. And I tell the story of somebody on
my team who's just an amazing product manager,
and yet every time she came up for promotion
or calibration, people were like, "Oh,
what does she do?" And it was because she was not
good at broadcasting or explaining what she does.
I would take her to executive meetings and
she was really bad at answering questions
or talking. And so we would prep and prep and
prep. I just knew her skills and I could see
her every day moving the product forward.
But for some reason people... Because your
peers also have influence over people's ratings
and their promotions, and I was constantly just
trying to figure out how to get them to see
her brilliance. I asked her once, I said, "I
noticed that you never answer questions when we do
these presentations." She's like, "Yeah, because
I'm a processor. And by the time I process,
I feel like the conversation has moved on."
And so I really feel like the world, it's not
built for somebody like her who's a brilliant
product leader, but people couldn't see it. And
I realized that so much of what products and just
general leadership is, is not just doing the work,
but actually... It's not just having the product,
it's having great product marketing to go with
it. Let's call it that. Okay, so I've been in
product and I've been product marketing. You
make a light bulb, but you're selling light.
I really think about how that she was
making amazing number of light bulbs.
She was lighting up all the houses, but she
was not marketing the light. And I think that
was the thing that was really missing. Is
that fair? Absolutely not. There are a lot
of people who are born introverted. Is it fair
that a product manager who isn't introverted,
isn't extroverted is struggling with
that? No, but that's the world we live
in. And so it's one of those things
where you get to choose what you do.
First, I think for the individual is realizing
that you are your own best marketer. You have
to actually share what you do. If a great product
is out in the world, but no one is told about it,
did it exist? And so one of the things that's very
important is really to get that product marketing.
The second part is we should change our
workplaces so everyone can be successful.
And I think that that's a really important skill.
As more introverts get into leadership, they need
to actually change the world to make more space
for people like them as well. So one of the things
that I found was in my leadership teams over the
last several years, we had this thing where we
all vote, but we vote offline in a document and we
put a number in and then we put our comments in.
And that way everyone has an equal voice in
this document. And then when we talk about it,
usually, of course the extroverts speak first,
but everyone has a vote and we can actually see
what people's point of views are. And I love
that. I love that when there's something we
used to do at Facebook is we used to go
around in a circle and everybody would
give their opinion in a meeting. I do that still
today. I ask every single person as a business
leader at this company, would you do this?
And even I joke with our chief legal officer,
Greg, I say, "You are a business leader
and the lawyer. You can't just say, well,
legal advises X." I'm like, "But what would you
do?" And so nobody can take a backseat to decision
making. Everybody has a voice. So there's so many
of these kind of bias interrupters, things that we
can do to actually make the world easier for those
who weren't speaking up and taking 80% of the air
in the room. And I do think that we have to craft
a workplace where everyone can be their best.
In the post, you also talk about as much as
we want to change the way people run their
companies and think. I love your advice of
you also still have to learn how to speak
up and act more extroverted even though
it's not natural to you. Is that right?
I think we do a disservice when we say we're
not good at speaking up because it's a skill
like any other. And if I told you the difference
between your product being successful and not
being successful is you giving this presentation,
they're going to kill your product if you don't
sell this to the executives. You would figure out
a way to stand in front of those executives and
defend the freaking heck out of your product.
But why aren't you doing that every day?
And I think sometimes we forget that not
everything is as essential as they're going
to cut your product if you can't convince them to
keep it. But every day you're actually building
credibility for your team, getting more resources,
getting more people to talk about your product
inside your company, getting more press for the
product outside. All of those things combined into
momentum for your product. And don't you want the
best thing for your product and your customers?
So if you think about it that way, it's not,
well, I'm uncomfortable. I hear this a lot
where people say, "Well, you wouldn't understand.
I'm an introvert." And I'm like, "So was I." But
instead I just said, "Okay, this is a necessary
skill and it's a learnable skill. You don't have
to be comfortable with it. You don't have
to love it, but you just have to do it."
What about from another perspective of why
people don't do this, which is it feels like
self-promotion and it feels like icky like,
"I'm just sitting around promoting myself.
I don't want to be doing that." Anything
there that helps people get over that piece?
Well, I just remember I was talking to this
ERG group and I was asking about... There was
an upcoming calibration and self reviews were
due in a couple of days. And I said, "Well,
what are you doing for your self-review?"
And somebody raised their hand and said,
"Well, I'm really bad at self-promotion. What
advice would you have for me?" And I said,
"If you think your self-review is self-promotion,
you're just not going to do a great job at it."
What if I called it educating your manager about
all the great work your team has been doing? What
if I called it helping people see why your
team should get more resources? Suddenly
you're cracking open, you're changing the question
right from, "Oh, I was self-promoting to actually
I'm helping my team get more resources
and support." And suddenly she was like,
"Oh yeah, I never thought about it that way."
But I think often if you frame it one way,
it looks like self-promotion. I wouldn't want
to do that because of self-promotion. But at
the same time, if it's education, what if I said,
"I was talking to a PM who's really incredible.
I've mentored him and sponsored him for a long
time." And I said, "I don't understand why you
don't have more of a voice. You've learned
so much about the craft. You've done this
at multiple companies." And he said exactly what
you said which is I'm not really self-promoting.
And I said, "If you see it as self-promoting,
you will never do it." And so let's talk about
why you don't actually do this. And he said,
"I've seen a lot of people who are really
great on LinkedIn write these articles, but
they have nothing to back it up." And I don't
want to be like them. And I said, "Okay. Well,
you read my blog, you follow me on LinkedIn,
do you think I have nothing to black back
it up?" And he's like, "No, of course not."
And I said, "Well, then why do you put yourself
in his category instead of mine?" And I think
it was just a moment where we just came to an
understanding where he in his mind was like,
"I don't want to be that person. It's an empty
vessel that has no substance behind it." And I
said, "Do you think the things I write have
no substance?" But it was an interesting
conversation because he had taken this mantle
that it was self-promotion and that behind
what if people think I'm nothing behind it?"
I'm like, "I know you have something behind
this. I have been your manager. I have worked
with you for many years, but you see how just
reframing it has really changed his way of
thinking about it." Still working on him.
But I actually think he has so much to give and I
think he has learned so much about the craft, and
I wish that more product managers feel comfortable
that they have something to give to the world.
I think what you're saying right now will resonate
with a lot of people when they see people posting.
I feel the still of just like, "I don't want to be
this guy that's just posting nonsense on LinkedIn
just to get likes," even though it's kind of what
I do now full time. Hopefully it's not nonsense.
But it is all substance. So, Lenny,
we know the substance behind it.
I tried, but I think there's posting on LinkedIn,
posting on Twitter. There's like an innate just
doing this because I want to get attention
when often... And the way I started this is
just like things I've learned that I think are
useful, I'm just going to put them out there.
So just to double click a little bit, I think
this is a really powerful point. What actually
have you found helps people get over that? Is
it someone like you and his corner being like,
"You have really great stuff to share, you
should actually do it. Don't be as worried
as you are, as you think you might be."
Is there anything else that works there?
Actually what worked for me was I was working with
Bos and I talk about our relationship in my book,
but we made a contract when I started reporting
to him. And Bos, for those of you don't know, is
currently the CTO of Meta. At the time he was the
head of ads and then our team moved into his team.
And so I was reorged into his organization. And
as I said we did not have the best relationship
before that. And so we made a contract to work
together and I had written like, "Here's how I
want you to take care of my team. Here's how I
want you to support our products." And I wrote
them this long, my part of the commitment.
Then he wrote back, "Here's what I'm asking
of you. I want you to write and publish something
every month." I was like, "What are you talking
about? Why would you say that?" He said, "You
have so much to teach people. Just do it."
I said, "I don't really have that much to say."
And he's like, "Just trust me on this. You'll
figure it out." His advice was write what you
repeat. If you say something more than once,
just write it down. And then the next time
someone asks you, you can just hand them.
He has a great blog if you have read it. I just
normally thinking that is a weird thing for your
new manager to say after you had a lot of conflict
together before that. But he took my contract,
which was... By the way, he's like, "Oh, do
you want to codify this in some way?" I'm like,
"No, I just..." But every month from then
on, I would literally just write something
and it was my promise to him. And I did it
faithfully and I published it internally. So
I didn't publish it externally for a long time.
And then sometimes they would ask me if I want
to publish it externally for the company
and I would say yes. And so I did it for
years. I reported to him for years. And then we
switched managers. He moved over to Reality Labs
and then I had a new manager and I continued and
I continued this. Then I started doing a publicly,
and then obviously I wrote a book.
Because of him and his encouragement,
it got me to a totally different place. And
part of it was just the commitment. I now had
accountability because I knew he was watching.
I'm not actually sure if he was actually watching
every month. But I felt the accountability to do
this and I've done it every single month since.
So it's interesting that that's another
example of your manager giving you the
space slash forcing you to share publicly being a
really good lever to get someone over this fear.
I think sometimes just doing it gets you
over the hump. For example, my friend,
Ami Vora. She writes an incredible blog. You
have not read her Substack, you should. But
she's an incredible writer. She'd write all these
things internally and I said, "You should publish
this externally." Now she does that and it's
really great. And I think part of it was just
seeing her just put it out there because she
is one of the wisest career coaches that I have
and managers that I have ever worked with. And so
I'm like, "You have so much to say and to share."
So to see it out there, I feel like for years we
all got the benefit of it because we knew her.
But the world was not getting the benefit. So
in some ways just having accountability. So we
created a little accountability group to help
each other write, and it was just a reminder,
"Hey, did you do it?" And so I think it's
sometimes what's necessary to get over
that hump is either having someone forcing you,
like your manager who you made a commitment to,
or just having a friend to say, "Hey,
by the way, where's this month's post?"
Those things matter because now you got over
the hump of, "I have to do it." And now it's
just about how good you're going to make it
and how much time you're going to put into it.
Awesome advice. And by the way,
folks don't know we've had both Bos
and Ami on the podcast in the past.
Aren't they both amazing?
Amazing. And Ami's episode
is one of the most popular
episodes. More popular than Bos, CTO of Meta.
I know.
Who would've thought?
She has a lot of coaching wisdom
I think that everyone should hear.
Yeah, she's amazing. She has a
great Substack. We'll link to it
again in the show notes. We'll
link to your Substack as well.
Yeah, please do.
Go Substack. I want to move in a slightly
different direction. Talk about growth for a
little bit. You have a really nice perspective on
how to think about growth. I think a lot of people
think of growth as like, "Here's a magic bullet.
We're going to do this thing. It's going to go,
"Wow, we're going to win." And your
approach is, you talk about it, it's a
game of inches. Growth is a game of inches.
Can you talk about your perspective there?
Yeah. Sometimes we think it's like what is the
huge step function? But actually most companies
are like... We call it points of growth, right?
It's like if you can move things 1% a little
bit faster every single week, think about the
amount of growth you get at the end. And so
it's not just, "Okay, what's going to get you the
3X? You can get to 3X 1% at a time, 5% at a time.
Single digit growth. And sometimes it is the small
things that matter the most. And so we think about
product-led growth, it's really about finding
the aha moments, the opportunities. And sometimes
opportunities are things that seem really silly.
I heard the story at Facebook that one of the big
things was just adding the, next to
ads, they put the word create an ad,
was one of the biggest growth drivers. And that
was it just putting a link because people just
didn't know how to get to the ads flow. It was
things like that where you can actually bend the
curve of choices that you make. Same thing, each
of the growth teams I've ever worked on, it's like
really the small things adding up. It is a list we
used to work on payments growth and we had a list
of a hundred things we were working on hypotheses.
And then we would pick and we would grow them by
picking the first 10 and we would start working
on them, the next 10, the next 10, and we would
go through these sprint cycles. And the same
thing when we were growing the ads product as
well. Marketplace, each of them were just like,
"What are the small things that add up to big
things?" And I think sometimes we overthink it.
Instead, you probably have a hundred ideas. And
by the way, it is absolutely okay if the 80%
of them don't work. I tell people sometimes
we overthink as product manager if we just had the
perfect plan, the perfect battle plan, but instead
imagine you're a team and you can ship, I don't
know, let's say four things. But what if you're
a team that can ship 20 things with the same
with a 20% success. You get just as much output
and yet you know what doesn't work also.
What if you can move it from 20% to 30%?
Suddenly six things work, not just four things.
And so in the same amount of time you have all
the lessons of what didn't work, plus you're
getting 50% more output. And so you thinking
about growth as this engine of, it's a
learning machine of what doesn't work,
what you reiterate on, what you change, and you're
constantly getting better and better and better.
I think what you're saying will resonate
with a lot of product people where there's
always this like, "We're just doing a bunch of
optimization, incremental work. Still sucks,
boring. Let's take some big bets." And in my
experience, and sounds like in your experience,
a lot of the wins actually... And Facebook
is famous for this, just relentlessly looking
for ways to grow, optimize, optimize, optimize
because that's where a lot of growth comes from.
At the same time, obviously you need to
take some big bets and take some swings
and look for step function changes. But
I guess for someone that's just like...
I don't know. Is there any advice on
just creating that culture of like,
"It's okay to optimize for a long time, there's
a lot of opportunity optimizing"? Is there
anything you've learned there or is it just
bringing in a Deb and it has to be a top down?
I treat growth like, let's say,
a product marketing team. It is
an augmentation for a product that works.
So if you have a core product that works,
you have a team that's working on... So for us
at Ancestry, it's like search and hints of the
core. What is the mechanics? You want people
to add people to their family tree. You want
them to add stories, okay? There's teams that
make sure that the uptime is good, that the
hints are working, the search delivers results.
And you need those teams, you need those core
teams kind of functioning. But growth is actually
optimization on top. It is making it so that
you get to the search flow faster. The hints are
surfacing better, that people are accepting them,
that if we put the button here versus here, that
people are going to discover things faster. And
so it's really taking the core engine and actually
wrapping it around the user interface around the
experience, around the flows so that people can
get to it faster, they can have more satisfaction,
they can have more impact. And that's what I see
growth as. It's not the core product. It is the
cherry on top, making that product more accessible
and more usable and better every single day.
Along these lines, I think it surprised people
to learn. There's at least a hundred people at
our Airbnb just working on pricing,
optimizing pricing recommendations.
There's endless opportunity to just make
all these core components of an experience
better and better and better over time.
Okay. Last thing I want to talk about,
and this is completely unrelated to
everything we've been talking about
mostly, which is your 30, 60, 90-day plan.
So you wrote this post a while ago, just like,
here's a great 30, 60, 90-day plan when
you join a company. I've heard that many
people use this. It's really effective for
helping someone onboard and be successful.
And I think it's mostly for execs or is
this for just anyone joining a company?
It's for anyone.
Okay, anyone.
I created, it's actually when I joined Ancestry
because I hadn't started a real new job in 11
years. And I thought, I'm going to be a student
of how to land well. So I read a bunch of things,
I read and I decided I was going to adapt all
of those things into a summary and then I was
going to try it real time in my blog.
So in my blog I write, "Here's what I'm
going to do," and then I tell you what I did and
how it worked and some things. And then I actually
do a look back as to all the mistakes I made. And
so I did this live. It was not planned quite as
well as I would thought, but I put it together
and I wrote the 30, 60, 90-day plan and I have
a template. I always tell people it's focused on
listening and learning first and then doing. So
that's the crux of it, which is in those 90-days
it's like you got to get used to the environment.
You want to have some impact at the start. You
want to have a couple quick wins, but you want
to understand the lay of the land and you want to
listen because you have something to contribute.
But if you don't understand the language,
you don't understand the culture, you might
actually make huge mistakes. And so for the first
30 days, I did a listening tour. I talked to over
60 people in 30 days and then I summarized a
state of the union. Here's what I'm hearing,
here are the challenges people feel like we're
facing. Here's what people's wishlists are.
And by the way, one person sent me a wishlist of
five things and at that year, I think it took me
till year two to finish his five things. And
then I sent him a note. I said, "By the way,
the first time we met, these five things you
wanted to see, we just finished the last one."
And he's like, "I can't believe you remember." I
took extensive notes and I summarized it. I think
it's important because people want to hear that
you hear them. And you don't have to be a manager
or CEO to do that. I think people on teams often
feel like there's no outlet for the things that
they want to say. I encourage, especially product
leaders, especially if you're joining an existing
team, to listen really behind what people are
saying and then offer to help them do one thing.
So especially when you're meeting with a new
engineering team for the first time, actually
ask them, what is one thing I can do to help you
this week? I always say one thing, it's limited.
This week, so getting 15 new headcount. Probably
not going to happen. And it's like, how can I give
back? And suddenly you're building a reciprocal
relationship. And so a lot of this 30, 60, 90-day
plan is really to help you find your footing
and then to start having impact immediately.
Say you join a company and you're like,
"I'm going to do 30 days listening," and
then your boss is like, "No, we
need to ship stuff. Get on it,
ship this stuff." Is there any advice for
trying to push back on that, create space
for listening when there's deadlines,
things aren't [inaudible 00:53:56]?
I encourage everybody to get on the same page
on this 30, 60, 90-day plan with their manager.
So actually don't just keep it to yourself.
Share it with as many people as you can. So
I think it's very important that everyone sees
what you're trying to accomplish and what your
output is going to be. Because if you don't
know the output, is success there? The second
part is with your manager say, "Okay. I would
like to carve 20% of my time listening and I'm
happy to do this work 80% of the time."
Therefore every morning from nine to 10,
I want to talk to somebody in the organization.
Just make sure you say, "I will do a better job
and have more impact if I have this time to
make sure that I'm not accidentally making
mistake or I don't get a chance, I'm asking
something of somebody, but I've never met
them." And to really carve out space because
it's really important. Once you're in it,
people give you the new person card for
maybe a month or two and then suddenly
it's all the problems are your problems.
But what if you don't know what the problems
are? And so I always say diagnose before
you treat. So make sure you understand so
that you can help and deliver what your
manager is actually expecting of you.
I'm looking at your template. So just to share the
bucket. So first 30 days learning focus, second 30
days is aligning on vision for the future, and
the last 30 days of the 90 days is executing,
setting up, actually starting to get stuff done.
Awesome. Anything else along these lines of this?
The one thing about having a plan
also is that you don't feel rushed
to do something that you're not ready for
because I do think sometimes you feel like
you need to have impact. I always
tell people, "Do something small,
give back in some ways that people see you
making." But when you actually reflect,
one of the biggest things I could do was actually
reflect back to the organization, "Here's what I
heard from all of you. I'm listening, I hear
this and here's what I want to do about it."
And then in aligning it's like, "Do we agree
this is a set of problems we want to tackle?"
And then an execution is like, "Do we agree that
this is how we want to move forward?" And I think
that is such an important part of building
into a team. When you enter an organization,
you're also entering a team and you're part
of a dance that's going around. What role do
you play? And people are dancing around you and
if you actually make a mistake, you could trip
other people up as well. So really finding
your place in the dance is really important.
And as a PM, the way I always think about is
people won't assume they should trust you.
You're just this person that's coming in to tell
them what to do and so much of your first month,
two, three is building that trust with people
so that they can actually feel comfortable
listening to your guidance and not just like,
"Oh my god. This person is getting in my way."
And earning that trust, sometimes people really...
You'd be really surprised, a lot of people feel
like they're not heard and even just coming
in and listening is a trust building exercise.
Such a good point. As we wrap up our conversation,
just a couple more questions here. So first is
I want to take us to Contrarian Corner, which
is a segment on this podcast. And my question is
there something that you believe that you think
most other people don't believe? Something
that you think is a contrarian perspective?
I don't know if this is a contrarian perspective,
but I go to speak in a lot of universities. So I
speak at Stanford and I'm going to speak at Duke.
And I always tell people, especially young people,
the most important career decision you make is
who you marry. And it's not something we think
that much about, especially I started dating... I
met my husband when I was 18, my first weekend in
college. Started dating when I was 19. We had
no idea what our life was going to be like and
yet every single day like this week we had our
board meeting, I was in Utah the whole week. I
come home and he's taking care of everything.
You will have a much more successful career if
your home life is in balance. It's like a yin
and a yang. If something is out of balance,
it engulfs the other side. Both your job and your
home life. And especially, we have three kids.
Really balancing that is very hard over both of
us having demanding careers. It's not something
that's contrarian, but it's something which
we don't think about at all when we make that
decision. We think is this person fun to
be with? Is this person somebody we see
ourselves with? But my question is what is the
impact of this relationship on your career?
Is this person lifting you up or pushing you
back? Is this person someone who's going to be
your greatest cheerleader or are they going to
be the greatest weight on you? How do you think
that that's going to manifest itself 20 years, 30
years from now? And I think it's just something
I wish we thought about more and I encourage
especially young people to think about that.
Such a great point. What I want
now is a guide for vetting these
things when you're dating. Deb's guide to dating.
I need to write that. Although
I've only really dated him,
the one person, so maybe I am
like the worst person to tell.
But it worked, so you're maybe the
best person and now you look back.
That's right. That's right.
And here's the questions I asked that worked.
That's so funny. Okay, so before we get to our
very exciting lightning round, is there anything
else that you think might be helpful to share,
something you might want to leave listeners
with? Any other nuggets of wisdom or advice?
Well, there's one quote which I share, I
thought about when you were speaking earlier,
which is about people who are resilient, which
is life... This is a quote from Chuck Swindoll,
he's a Christian writer I used to read a
lot and it was, "Life is 10% what happens
to you and 90% how you react to it." And I just
looked him up recently and he actually published
a book with that quote. He actually had that
quote in a previous book from 20 years ago.
And I just think that's so important.
You don't get to choose everything that
happens in your life. So much is just,
it just happens, but it's the people
who choose a way forward to turn stumbling
blocks and the stepping stones. As I said,
"Somebody who actually says, 'you know what?
I didn't get the job that I wanted and I'm
just going to figure out another path,'
those are the people who have the most
successful and satisfying careers." They're
thinking when other people are zagging vice
versa. And I think that there are the ones who
are the most resilient and happy in the long term.
It's such a good circle back to one
of your first pieces of advice of just
most successful people are people that
are resilient and don't avoid failure,
but embrace it and find a way to turn that
around. I think it's such an important
point. It's so hard to do. I guess just, I don't
know, just to follow this thread a little bit,
is there anything that has helped you build that?
Has that always been the way your mind worked?
I imagine coaching helps this, helps people
with this." Is there anything just like that?
Coaching is incredible for that. We joke it's
work therapy, but really I think it's... For a
long time I saw failure as this catastrophic
thing. I was one of those kids who's like,
"You never got a B until..." Then I
got to college and I was like, "Wow,
this is harder than I thought." And so
I got two B's in college and I'm like,
"I'm never doing that again." But I was that
kid who always got the A, who got the great
scores. I just thought that my life would end if
I got a B which by the way is super unhealthy.
And looking back, I realized that work is
not like that at all. And every time I got
bad feedback I'm like, "This is catastrophic."
But if you look at feedback as an opportunity,
then it's very different. It's like this is a
gift. I would be crushed. Every time I get a
review no matter what rating I got, I would read
the things that people would say and I was like,
"Oh my gosh, I'm a terrible person." And I had
to really rethink that. And I think coaching,
leadership coaching has really helped me
through that to say, "No, how do you process
this and how do you get to the other side?"
And that has been so transformative for me is
to have that outlet to actually talk through.
No, no, no. What they're saying is not that
you're a bad product person, it's that you need
to do a better job communicating or connecting.
And I really struggled with that. I was very
transactional. I was not a connector. I was not
warm. I really struggled with relationships.
And a lot of the feedback I received for many
years is this relationship issue. And it took me
a long time to realize that people aren't saying
this because I'm a bad person or that they
hate me, but because they want to connect.
I was actually making it hard. And I think
sometimes we take things so personally that it
becomes kind of this thing. It is your white
whale. It's like the thing you're chasing,
but then what if you say, "You know what,
I don't need to do that. I don't need to
chase that. Instead I need to figure out what's
behind the feedback and what are they trying to
say?" And then actually change yourself
over a long period of time towards that.
I had similar challenges where I had this pretty
real imposter syndrome for a while when I started
doing well. And a coach was the key for me
to help me get over that and see that if I
made a mistake. Things wouldn't crumble. And that
it's very normal to make mistakes. Nobody will-
And by the way, I think perfectionism is
a curse we place on ourselves. And it's
a very dangerous thing, particularly for
product leaders because product managers,
you know things are going to go wrong. That's
literally part of your job. And yet when we
have perfectionism, it is a lack of trust in
our ability to bounce back and our ability to
actually adapt. But the more adaptable you are,
the less you have to be perfect every single time.
Just to leave people with a tactical piece
of advice, say they are like, "Oh man,
I need a coach," do you have any advice for
how to find a coach? How to explore that route?
So I actually wrote an article, because one of the
things I struggle with coaching is very expensive
often, and not every company provides it. My
husband actually works at a coaching company
called Sounding Board to make it more accessible.
But one of the things I encourage people to do is
there are other ways to get coaches. I'm
in a lean-in group and we are just like,
we support each other. I'm in a coaching circle
in YPO, so that's a group of CEOs. And I'm in a
number of these coaching circles, which give you
an opportunity to learn from each other and to get
pure coaching. And I think that's a great place to
start, especially early in your career when you're
seeing the same people making the same mistakes.
I think as you get more senior,
having an individual coach helps because the
situations are so much more unique. But I do
think that having that outlet, having a
place to say, "Hey, is it me or is this
situation not right? And how should I think
through this?" That's so incredibly important.
I'm listening to this book, or reading a book
called Listen right now that a previous guest
recommended. It's a parenting book and
it's about just the power of listening
and how much that solves many problems
with your challenges or with your child.
When your child is having a problem just
listening to them. There's a lot of power.
This came from a coach that was on the
podcast recently. [inaudible 01:04:31]
Sounds great. I'll definitely,
I'll read it or listen to it.
I know it's weird. I'm like reading, it's
called Listen. He's like, "This is the only
parenting book you need really. It solves all
the problems that we deal with." So anyway,
that was an awesome final nugget that
I'm glad we got there. With that though,
we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
Let's do it.
Let's do it. First question, what are
two or three books that you've
most recommended to other people?
So I love the book from Professor Jeffrey Pfeffer.
I speak in his class now that I read
it way before that, it's called Power:
Who Has It and Why. I love the book. He actually
has the more practical one, 7 Rules of Power,
which came out more recently. And so it's a book
that reminds us that power is not accidental,
that people often get it for different reasons
and how you should think about the playing field.
Another book is The Conversation, Dr. Livingston
wrote that about race in America, and I just love
that it's a very honest assessment of race in
America. It's hard to have that conversation
and I love that he uses a lot of facts
and encourages people to open up and have
conversations around it. And then the last one I
would say is, well, Susan Cain's Quiet. I adore
the book because I do have introverted kids.
I myself am introverted and just to read the
power of introverts as a reminder that we do have
amazing people who don't communicate the same way.
I love that it's a tribute to the success of
those. Even if our workplace is not adapted to it,
I do think we need to adapt to it so that
we can bring the best in everybody. But her
book is a reminder that there's
so much power even in silence.
The first book you mentioned Jeffrey Pfeffer,
he's been on the podcast. I think he may
have mentioned you in our conversation or-
I love Professor Pfeffer.
That was a fun conversation because I came into
it very nervous for what his advice would be
and then came up with it being
like, "This is great. This is-"
He is very wise,
He's very wise and just very,
"I don't care what you think,
I'm just going to tell you the reality of
the world." Oh man. Okay. Next question. Do
you have a favorite recent movie or
TV show that you've really enjoyed?
Okay. I know this is a fandom thing, but I love
Fallout. So I played the game Fallout 4 last year,
and then the show came out and it was
amazing. And I know that sounds so nerdy,
but it was incredible. And I know that video
game movie annotations tend to be terrible,
but it was so great and having played the
game it was even better. Is that super nerdy?
No, I watched Fallout. I don't
know anything about the game,
but the show itself was really fun. Just I
had no idea what I was even getting into. So
no. Acceptable nerdy level. I don't know if you
can get too nerdy on this show. Next question,
do you have a favorite product you recently
discovered that you just really like?
Well, so actually what's really interesting is I
never got into Twitter. I just couldn't figure it
out. Recently I really got into Threads and
I didn't think I would. I was like, "Well,
just post some stuff on it," but really I just
love... I could never figure out Twitter. You
follow the wrong person and the whole thing,
it's terrible. If somebody is posting too much
or too little, but there's something about the
Threads algorithm that's really worked. The first
few months wasn't quite there, but I just feel
like it's spot on and now I see the magic of it.
That's so interesting. I've seen
some stats that it's bigger than
X now slash Twitter and I wonder if
that's true. I got to look that up,
but I've seen more activity on Threads. So maybe
I need to go back there. I spent some time around-
Cheering from the sidelines that it's
successful because I use it a lot now. And
I guess I had never had a place for realtime
news and it's not exactly meant to be newsy,
but maybe it's just who I follow, but I love
just seeing like, "Here's five headlines you
probably missed." And I was like, "Oh." I know
they're trying to downplay politics, but I just
love that it feels like you get a glimpse of
what's going on in the world in five minutes."
Okay. Two more questions. Do you have a
favorite life motto that you often think about,
come back to, share with friends or
family find useful in work or in life?
Ooh, that's a good question. Well, actually,
I would say that it's very similar to the Chuck
Swindoll one about life. So we can use that.
Great. That's what I imagined because you
shared that one early on. And I imagine
that was going to be your answer. Final
question, you started Facebook Marketplace,
you built it. Now, it has a billion
users, more than that. What's the
most interesting thing that you have
bought or sold on Facebook Marketplace?
The best thing I ever sold on there was I sold
my minivan on it and in four days. I made my
husband do it because I wanted him to test the
product. We were selling our minivan and I'm like,
"Just try Facebook Marketplace." He's like,
"I don't know about this." And he's like,
"There's too many people contacting me. I needed
it to stop." So it worked really well for us.
I think I have bought so many things on
there. It's actually sort of embarrassing.
Recently, my daughter wanted the same desk as I
had for her new room and they no longer sell it
at Costco. And I found it for half the price
from a woman who was moving and she's like,
"Here," and I love it. So I bought probably
way too many things on Facebook Marketplace
actually. But it's a great thing. I
actually use it as a great rental for
kid stuff because you buy a kid's bike and
then when they outgrow it, you sell it back.
And the rental fee is almost free and I don't
have the store all of it. So I love every part
of it. I still am an admin user and I send
a lot of feedback back to that team still.
That's amazing. Deb, this was amazing. I'm
so happy we made time for this. Thank you so
much for coming on. Two final questions. Where
can folks find you if they want to reach out,
maybe read about stuff you're doing? Where's your
Substack and anything else people can check out?
Yeah, so debliu.substack if you want
to look. I post probably about once
a week. I'm on LinkedIn, I'm on
Threads, so please do find me.
And then the actual final question,
how can listeners be useful to you?
Well, I would just love to hear
what you heard from today that
resonated with you and what
you're going to do with it.
And how would they share
that LinkedIn or at Threads?
I'm happy to read your comments
or send it if you want to-
There we go.
... send it to me. If you've
actually subscribed to my Substack,
you can just reply to the
first email and then I get it.
Awesome. But the easy way, as you said,
are replying to YouTube comments.
There we go. Get people to YouTube,
click that subscribe button. Deb, thank
you so much for being here and thank you.
Thank you so much, Lenny. It's great.
Bye, everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.