Canva is bigger than Figma and Miro and Webflow
combined. You guys are generating $2.3 billion in
ARR and you're profitable. You're also growing
60% year over year and it's accelerating.
I run everyone through the culture of Canva. One
of those sections is on giving away your Lego,
finding joy in the other things of building
a team, passing on your experience,
helping other people do great writing or great
product building or great engineering.
When is this coaching concept?
I've never heard of this.
We don't really have managers, but everyone at
Canva has a coach. They're constantly working
with you to look at your skills, but also when
it might be time to move on to the next level.
I'm curious just how you think
about product management.
I didn't want to do product management like they
did at Google, and that's because of the different
cultures. I have seen product managers at
other companies who are very independent
of teams and that seems very weird to me. For
us, product managers are really connected.
It feels like Canva has just been this
non-stop up into the right all win,
all success. In reality, that's
never actually the case.
How many failure stories do
you want? We got plenty.
Today, my guest is Cameron Adams. Cameron is the
co-founder and chief product officer at Canva,
which is a truly incredible business and company.
At the top of the episode, I share a bunch of
stats. They'll probably surprise you about
the scale that Canva has reached these days.
In our conversation, we cover a ton of ground
including how Canva stays product obsessed, their
freemium strategy, lessons about building MVPs,
how Cam and the product team think about AI within
their product, also peek into their unique team
culture, their SEO and growth strategy, and also
peek into some of the stuff they just launched.
This episode is for anyone building or growing
a product or company, and I guarantee by the
end of this conversation, you'll be as blown
away with Canva as I am. With that, I bring you
Cameron Adams. And if you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's the
best way to avoid missing future episodes
and it helps the podcast tremendously.
Cameron, thank you so much for being
here, and welcome to the podcast.
It is so great to be here,
Lenny. I'm very excited.
I'm even more excited. I have at least a billion
questions for you. I'm hoping I get through at
least half a billion. There's so much I want to
talk to you about, but I want to start with a
warm and fuzzy question. Do you ever just take a
moment to reflect on the insane success of this
business that you've built? And before you
answer that, I'm going to share some stats
about Canva that I think are going to blow
people's minds. So think about the answer.
So I was researching Canva, all of this was
just... I didn't know any of this actually,
and I think it'll surprise a lot of people just
the scale that Canva has reached at this point.
Okay. So Canva is bigger than Figma and Miro and
Webflow combined both in terms of valuation and in
terms of revenue. You guys are generating $2.3
billion in ARR per year and you're profitable.
You've been profitable for about seven years
at this point. You're also growing 60% year
over year and it's accelerating, faster than
last year. I think this is all quite unheard
of at this scale. Do you ever just reflect back
on this and, like, "Okay, I've done well."?
When you say it all like that, it sounds pretty
amazing. I don't think every day you're cognizant
of that growth and that achievement, but there
are particular moments where you get to really
reflect, and for me, it's most of the time when
we bring the team together. Obviously now we're
in a pretty virtual world, hybrid in some best
cases. But when the team all get together and
we celebrate is when we finally have those
moments where you get to step out of yourself,
look at this huge sea of people and
realize what you've achieved together.
Probably the most recent moment we got to do that
was for our 10th birthday last year. So Canva is
largely centered in Australia. We've got lots
of offices around the world, but we had a big
birthday celebration in Sydney right on the harbor
there in front of the water and we had thousands
of people there, and we just got to look back on
everything we've achieved over the previous 10
years, and that was the pretty amazing moment.
What about just personally, you basically went
from a designer on Google Wave to a co-founder of
one of the most generational successful startups
in the past decade. How does that feel?
I still think I'm constantly growing,
I'm constantly learning stuff. I don't feel like
I've achieved a ceiling or being a massive smash
hit. We're always changing how we're doing things.
We're always doing things we've never done before
and we feel totally like a fish out of water. So
yeah, I've achieved a few things personally, but
I still feel like there's so much more to go.
That sounds right. I want to talk about the flip
side from the outside, like I described, it
feels like Canva has just been this non-stop
up into the right all win, all success,
just killing it all the time. In reality,
that's never actually the case. It's often really
helpful for people to hear a story of, okay,
there's actually this moment of this may be all
falling apart or a struggle for yourself. Is there
a moment that comes to mind of just like, "Oh,
man, this was really scary and hard for me."?
I think there's probably a few different stories
that would resonate with your audience because
there's like business kind of stories of how the
actual company's tracking. There's product stories
of stuff we launched that didn't go anywhere.
There's team stories where you're dealing with
people and all the different quirks that entails.
I think I'll choose a business story. There was
a moment around our 100 million valuation mark
where we were putting together around... We had a
lot of existing investors who were really keen to
invest. This is probably our third or our fourth
round by this stage, and it was all looking
good. There was a particular investor who was
really to lead out. We were fine with that. They
were doing due diligence, got to the stage where
every other investor in the round had signed
on. They were super excited. They'd wired the
money into our bank accounts already. They'd
signed all the long docs but lead investor.
And about two days before they were due to sign
and get all the money into our account, they came
back and said, "Look, business is going great,
but essentially we think we can get a better deal,
so we're going to cut your valuation by 50%." It
was a huge surprise and totally screwed up the
entire round. All the other investors were like,
"What the hell are you doing?" My co-founders,
Mel and Cliff, pretty much jumped on a
plane that night to go to Silicon Valley,
rallied around a whole bunch of other investors,
found a new lead investor, took them about a week.
This was the week right before Christmas. It was
incredibly stressful, incredibly tumultuous.
We eventually came out of it better. We actually
got better terms on the deal that we came up with.
That investor has fallen to the wayside now and
it was a real learning moment for us in terms
of how to approach fundraising and also how to
be totally independent, and that's one of the
reasons why we've focused on profitability for so
long now. We've been profitable to spend the seven
years and one of the reasons is that we never
want to be put in the situation where we have
to go to someone for money to ensure the survival
of the business, and being profitable means that
we never have to do that. We can always do
it on our own terms and in our own time.
This episode is brought to you by
WorkOS. If you're building a SaaS app,
at some point your customers will start asking
for enterprise features like SAML authentication
and SCIM provisioning. That's where WorkOS
comes in, making a fast and painless to add
enterprise features to your app. Their APIs
are easy to understand so that you can ship
quickly and get back to building other features.
Today, hundreds of companies are already powered
by WorkOS, including ones you probably know
like Vercel, Webflow, and Loom. WorkOS also
recently acquired Warrant, the fine-grained
authorization service. Warrant's product is
based on a groundbreaking authorization system
called Zanzibar, which was originally designed
for Google to power Google Docs and YouTube. This
enables fast authorization checks at enormous
scale while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases. If
you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features
like single sign-on SCIM or user management, you
should consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in replacement
for Auth0 and supports up to one million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
workos.com to learn more. That's workos.com.
This episode is brought to you by Attio,
a radically new type of CRM. There's a world
where your CRM is powerful, easily configured,
and deeply intuitive. Attio makes that a reality.
Attio is built specifically for the next era of
companies. It syncs with your data sources,
easily configures to their unique structures,
and works for any go-to-market motion from
self-serve to sales-led. Attio automatically
enriches your contacts, syncs your email calendar,
gives you powerful reports, and lets you quickly
build Zapier-style automations. The next era
of companies deserves more than an inflexible
one-size-fits-all CRM, join modal, replicate 11
labs and more, and scale your startup to the next
level. Head to attio.com/lenny and you'll get 15%
off your first year. That's A-T-T-I-O.com/lenny.
Something that I've heard from one of your
investors actually will not be named is that
at your board meetings, you have one slide
on the financials of the business and then
the rest of the deck is product updates,
the roadmap. I think this is very rare,
especially for companies at your stage that become
really focused on financials in the business from
the CFO perspective and a lot of founders lose
sight of the product. Can you just talk about
this element of how you all think about the
product that's so central to the business?
I think one key thing is that we don't know it's
very rare. We approach a board meeting just like
we do anything, we craft the experience about how
we think it should be and how we think it's going
to be useful. So just like our board meetings
or our product meetings or the way that we do
launches, we have shaped that in the image that
we want it to be and in the way that we think it's
going to be most effective. We've always been
an incredibly product-led company. We always
think first and foremost about the product.
That was the whole genesis of Canva itself,
having a product that we thought people
would love to use and desperately needed
to get out into the world and that's the
lens that we approach everything through.
In terms of board meetings, I think it's
been very helpful that our financials and
our growth have been amazing for so many years
that we don't need to focus on it and we can
just have that one slide with the graph going up
and to the right. We've also attracted investors
who believe in us and who understand that us
driving product and getting as much product
value out to our customers is probably the most
important thing we can be doing. So that's why
the board meetings do focus on that because what
we are launching in the product, what's ahead is
really determining the success of the company.
Obviously, financials are important and you can
do a bunch of lever pulling and thinking about
margins and all that kind of stuff, but product
is at the end of the day the most important
thing to Canva and the thing that's going to
help us stand out and continue to have success.
I really like this point you made about how you
didn't know any better almost, and it reminds me
of something else I heard about Canva. It took you
guys a long time to hire outside execs. Almost
all your leaders are homegrown and it took you
a long time to even hire outside of Australia. Its
even higher in the US. Can you just talk about why
that's been so important and just the impact
that has come out of hiring people internally
and helping people be promoted internally?
One thing really focused on is team and culture.
I think you can probably bring in the world's best
person at X, Y, and Z, but if they're not fitting
into your team and understanding your culture
and have the same passion and vision that you do,
they're not going to succeed. So it's super
important that we have people along with us for
the ride and that might mean everyone at Canva is
awesome. They mightn't be the number one person in
the world for that particular thing, but they get
more done than the number one person could because
they've built that trust and that safety with
their team. They know how to communicate their
ideas, they know how to bring other people along
with them and lay out a vision in the way that we
understand it at Canva, and that is a critical
thing to building a great company, I think,
is having that alignment across everyone, across
your product teams, across your marketing teams,
across your customer happiness.
They all need to be aligned and we
all need to be rowing in the same direction.
We have brought in leaders, and some of them
have been incredibly successful. We have brought
in leaders, and they've exited the company after
a few months just because there wasn't that
fit and they didn't manage to figure out or
understand what Canva was and how to work within
this big ecosystem. Now we've got 4,500 employees
now and it's not just a matter of you coming
in and bringing all your ideas. You also need
to work together with all the other leaders that
we have and the team that's surrounding you.
As a lens into what is important. Canva, when you
say that they didn't understand what Canva is,
what's something that doesn't click for people
a lot of times that forces them to be exited
potentially? What is it that's so maybe unique or
important to the way you all think about stuff?
I have this theory that the type of product
you're building very much influences the way
that you think, and this stemmed out of a chat
I was having with one of the product leaders at
Spotify. And they said that at Spotify they do
an incredible amount of talking about problems.
They'll have a meeting, they'll talk about this
new product feature and they'll just hash it out
through conversation. And I imagined that that
was because Spotify is a very auditory product.
Everyone there thinks about music, sound,
podcasts, that is their mindset. At Canva,
we're all about visual communications. It's
pitch decks, it's social media posts, it's video,
it's t-shirts that you can make, and that's how
we think about things in a very visual manner.
So one of the things that's very particular
about Canva is really setting visions. And
I'm in visions, not just in the sense
of looking forward two, three years,
but also visions in the very visual sense. We need
to be able to see it. We need mock-ups. We need
prototypes. You need to get that idea out of your
head and present it to someone in a visual form
that helps you talk about and communicate about
it. That's one aspect of why some people I think
don't land on their feet at Canva because they
aren't necessarily visual thinkers and they
don't end up communicating what they want to do
in a visual way to the rest of people at Canva.
Another way is that the way that we've grown,
the way that we've built product has been quite
idiosyncratic over the years. And as I said,
we've learned so much just through doing and
established our own processes. And I think in
any system, if someone comes up from the outside
with preconceived notions or this idea that
they're an expert and tries to bring that in,
it's going to be rejected. So you really need
to work together and I think the advice that I
can give to people coming to Canva is just listen
for a couple of months, figure out what is really
working at Canva and why it works before you
try and change it. We're very open to change
and to new ideas, but just coming in wholesale
and totally changing the process, just because
that's what you've done somewhere else isn't
going to get you the most level of success.
That makes so much sense. We're talking about
cultural elements and so I have one more question
around culture. I saw a video interview you did
once about how you love this concept of giving
away your Legos, that's part of your culture
and the culture at Canva broadly potentially,
and this was originally popularized by Molly
Graham in this first round review article. That's
something you still believe in and if so, can you
just describe that concept briefly because a lot
of people haven't actually heard about this?
Yeah, Molly wrote a great article, which I
actually refer everyone who joins Canva to in
the cultural onboarding session, which I give
them. So I run everyone through the culture at
Canva and what they can expect over the next few
years as they work here, and one of those sections
is on giving away your Lego, and it's really
important to us because part of being in a startup
is scaling, when you're scaling from zero users
to a million to a hundred million, and when you're
scaling from three founders to 10 employees to 100
employees to 4,000 employees. You're scaling
everything from the product to the internal
processes you have, the finance team paying people
how you deal with user feedback. Everything's just
constantly growing, growing, growing. And I think
this is slightly different to a traditional job
where you get good at the thing that you
always do and you try and turn that into a
process that just continually works all the time.
As a startup, you just have to be changing and we
want people who are flexible, you can bring
new ideas, you can go to that next level. You
can think about not just a million people,
but 10 million people, 100 million people,
a billion people using the product, and
to constantly ratchet up that multiplier,
you need to change yourself, which means that you
probably need to give away some of the stuff that
you're doing now in order to get to that next
level. If you're the first email copywriter
at Canva, you can get away from writing all the
emails for the first year maybe, but when you're
writing emails for 100 million people in 190
different countries, in 100 different languages,
all at different stages of their journey through
using Canva from beginners to intermediates to
experts, that just massively multiplies the
complexity of the job that you have to do.
And if you're trying to write every single one
of those emails, you have no chance of scaling.
So you need to think about who you're going to
bring in to help you, what systems you're going
to introduce, what are the processes needed to get
100 different languages translated every time you
send out an email and that requires you to hand
off that stuff. You need to maybe stop writing
every single email, give that to someone else,
be comfortable with doing that because you often
build up a lot of self-identity and doing that
and you get a lot of joy out of it. That's why
you're a writer in the first place. But finding
joy in the other things of building a team,
passing on your experience, helping other people
do great writing or great product building or
great engineering is really what giving away
your Lego is about. And we still encourage
everyone to do that, to think about those moments
where they need to level up in their impact,
how they can bring their team along with
them, how they can pass on their experience
and help everyone really have a tremendous
impact with the skills that they have.
I think a lot of people and a lot of companies
struggle with this idea, and I'm curious if
there's something you've learned about how to
actually implement this. Is it just like, "Hey,
go read this article and then I might bring it up
sometimes when things are changing and there's a
reorg."? Or is there anything even deeper of just
this is a cultural element of we are constantly
giving up our Lego's giving things that we own?
Probably the deeper thing I think is giving people
opportunity so you can talk about growth
than just say, "Please grow." That's not
going to be terribly effective, but giving
them the opportunity and the support to do so
is super important. We have a system we call
coaching at Canva where you have a coach and
they're constantly working with you to look at
your skills, how you can improve each of those
individual skills, but also what it is that you're
actually doing and when it might be the time
to move on to the next level. Say you are just
doing a product role in this particular product
and now you need to be a coach of other product
managers and help build products. Understanding
those pivot points is really important and our
coaches help everyone at Canva. Everyone at
Canva has a coach that is constantly thinking
about this aspect of their personal growth.
And finding those opportunities where you can
push someone to do something that they haven't
done before or to expand upon an idea that they've
had and give them ownership of that idea is super
important. So when people do come to us with an
amazing product idea or a feature that they want
to build or an entire team that they think
should be spun up, we really listen to them,
and if it makes sense, we say, "Go and do that. Go
and build that part of the product, grab a couple
of people and start building video at Canva.
Do that thing that you're talking about." And
I think if you give them the opportunity and
a little push to go beyond what they think
they're comfortable with right now, that is
the best way to drive growth in your team.
Okay. There's two things I want to follow up
on there. One is this coaching concept. I've
never heard of this. So how does that
work? Do they have a manager and they
have coach, and who is this coach?
We don't really have managers. So your
coach is the person who thinks about you in
a specialty sense. So we have specialties,
engineering, product design, we got tens
of different specialties across Canva, and
your coach really helps.. Your coach is a similar
specialty leads, so if you're a product manager,
they're a product manager, so they know the skills
that you have to use. They know the trajectory
that you could possibly grow into. They know the
structures that are around Canva that you could
slot into when you want to go to the next level.
And your coach constantly checks in with you,
has sessions, might help you with the strategy
doc, might have a one-on-one with you. They
just constantly thinking about those ways
that you can grow and improve at Canva.
And then we have probably more of a, I would
say, collegiate managerial circle of colleagues
who help you who do 360 feedback, all that kind of
stuff. So that's the structure that we've arrived
on and it's worked pretty well for us and it was
driven actually by a formative coaching experience
that we had as founders quite a few years ago
from an external coach and we decided to bring
that into Canva as a whole philosophy.
And these coaches, are they professional
coaches or they're people in the company that are
like, "I will be a coach for this function."?
They're people in the company. So we've got
probably close to 800 or 1,000 coaches now
at Canva.
Wow.
We do have very specific coaches who are just
coaches and they can drop into any situation.
They're not product managers, they're not
designers, but they're relatively few. I think,
we've got probably five of those type of coaches
and they just work in very special situations,
but what we're focused on is enabling the
broader circle of coaches, so those 800
people to understand what it is to be a coach
and have the skills of coaching. So we focus
a lot on teaching them the skills of coaching,
how to build a growth mindset in their coaches,
all the skills that you need. So
yeah, it's a massive part of Canva.
And so there's a product management coach and
this person helps all the PMs become better at
the craft of product management.
Yeah.
Wow, so interesting. Okay, and then the
performance review piece, how does that work?
Yeah. So your coach feeds into that,
but we also do 360 feedback from all
the people that you work with and we do that
on regular cycles. As with everything at Canva,
the cadence of those cycles has changed over the
years, but now we do that every six months.
We talked about product for a little bit.
I want to spend a little time on product
management. I'm curious just how you think about
product management. There's this constant debate
across tech companies about the value of PMs.
Are we better with more PMs? Are there too many
PMs? What do PMs do for you? You're a chief
product officer. Where do you find product
managers bring the most value to Canva?
And then do you just have thought on the
future of the field of product management?
I don't know. It's one of those things that I
don't want to quantify. I don't want to put it in
a box and say this is product management. Because
I've worked at a few places now. I've actually
only had one real job, which was at Google where
I got to experience product managers the Google
way. And the way that they do product management
is totally different to the way that we do
it at Canva, and that's partially by design
because I didn't want to do product management
like they did at Google, and that's because of
the different cultures that they have. Google's a
fantastically engineering-driven culture and the
way that they think about product management
is mostly in the technical sense of like,
"Here's a piece of technology, what can that
technology do, how do we scale it?" At Canva,
we focus a lot on experience and as I said
before, it's a very visual experience, so we
require a different product management process,
but also a different product management mindset.
I think we probably did that more from the ground
up than a lot of other startups just because Mel
and Cliff were a lot less, I think, inculcated
into how product management has done other
places. I had a bit of experience from Google
but was still fairly independent in my thinking,
so we almost went back to first principles
on how product management should be done,
and to be honest, we didn't want to have the
term product manager for a long, long time.
It wasn't until about year '06 or '07 where we
actually had product managers, we decided to cave
just because it was easier to explain to people.
But it also took us four or five years before we
even had another product owner who wasn't us. Part
of that was us giving up our Lego, and I think we
took a little too long to give up our Lego on that
one, but the other part of it was us figuring out
exactly what we wanted and how we built product
and how to communicate that to someone else
and get them to do it in a similar way and
work with the teams in the way that we did.
For us, product managers are really connectives.
They connect the team, ideas, data, a whole bunch
of different things, and it's very messy. There's
no exact recipe for how to do it, but connecting
these disparate areas and moving the team and
the technology and our customers to a new place,
a new vision is essentially what product managers
do, and it's going to involve compromise,
it's going to involve changes in the feature
scope, it's going to involve timelines of like,
"Okay, we can't ship it in May, it's going
to have to be July. Let's figure out what we
can do with marketing to make that work." This
constant movement and connection and reorienting
around the constraints that have suddenly
arisen in the last week, and that's where we
see great product managers operating in Canva.
You mentioned Mel and Cliff. For folks that don't
know, they're the other two co-founders of Canva
and they were dating when they were starting
Canva, I think it was called Fusion Books back
in the day before Canva. Now, they're married.
What's it like working with a married couple as
the other two co-founders, and is there something
they did well that didn't make you feel like this
third wheel person that isn't married to them?
It is always tricky working with a couple because
they're on it 24/7. When you leave the office and
they head home, they're still talking about
product, business strategy, all the things. I
think they've done a really good job of evolving
those ideas overnight through the conversations
they have and over dinner and walking, but
then bringing that back the next day and being
transparent about that and that's super important.
If you are working in that kind of dynamic. There
are definitely moments where I have missed
out on a memo and stuff has rapidly proceeded,
and I think I've just gotten used to that and
gotten used to catching up really quickly,
having a word with them on the side to
clarify what the motivation is here and
just constantly maintaining that alignment.
And I think it happens in any partnership or team.
There's moments where there's small alignments,
there's more tectonic stuff that happens over
months or years, and you need to realign at
some stage. I think it happens with friendships,
it happens with my wife, it happens with our
product teams. There's always these moments
where you need to re-communicate things and relay
the land of it. And I think we've been great at
doing that as co-founders even for the small
things and also for the more tectonic things.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta.
When it comes to ensuring your company
has top-notch security practices, things get
complicated fast. Now, you can assess risk,
secure the trust of your customers, and
automate compliance for SOC 2, ISO 27001, HIPAA,
and more with a single platform, Vanta. Vanta's
market-leading trust management platform helps
you continuously monitor compliance alongside
reporting and tracking risk. Plus you can save
hours by completing security questionnaires with
Vanta AI. Join thousands of global companies
that use Vanta to automate evidence collection,
unify risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go to
vanta.com/lenny. That's V-A-N-T-A.com/lenny.
I'm going to go back to the beginning of Canva.
I know that it took you guys a year of building
before you launched it, so it took you a year
to build the MVP essentially. And I know you
have some strong opinions on how long to wait,
how MVPs are often way too early. Can you talk
about that just why you guys waited so long
before launching clearly worked out and so I'm
just curious your lessons from that experience.
Yeah, so when we launched or when we were building
the Lean Startup book came out, so that was all
anyone talked to us about investors, other people
building products, trying to give us advice.
They were like, "Just get something out the door,
as crappy as it is just to get in front of users."
I think, for us, the product is the experience and
giving people a great experience is an intrinsic
part of the product. It's also an intrinsic
part of how we've grown. People having a good
experience of being enthusiastic about it has been
how we've spread the word of Canva and organic
word-of-mouth growth was the biggest driver of
Canva's growth for many years and probably still
is, I think. People just telling someone else to
jump on this amazing product, I don't think we
would've had that if we just put our pretty crappy
product that people didn't have joy in using.
Sure, it might've got the job done, but if they
weren't excited about using it the next day,
then that wasn't a bar that we wanted to hit.
So we did hold off on launching the product
for a long time and investors did ask us many,
many times, "When are you launching? Can you
just get this thing out the door?" But we had
done enough research, we knew the problem space,
we knew what people wanted from the product. Part
of that was due to the work that Mel and Cliff did
on Fusion Books in a very constrained area. They
had looked at school yearbooks, they had built
an experience for that, and they had observed
what worked didn't work and how they might scale
that into a bigger product. It also worked for
me who'd worked in a lot of creative tools and
built a lot of creative tools over the previous
15 years. So I had a lot of understanding of
how people interacted with these systems and
the experience that we wanted to build.
So we did hold off and the product we
launched launched, we obviously weren't happy
with. You have to launch something that you're
not completely happy with, all the rough edges,
but you're releasing it knowing that the rough
edges are going to be outweighed by the joyful
experience. We still did a ton of user testing,
right? It's not like we just launched this thing
blind and said, "We hope people like it." We did
a ton of user testing. We did a ton of user
research into the features that people wanted,
and we built that up over time. And one
year to me actually seems like short time,
a lot of people think it's a long time, but one
year was just enough for us to scrape in with an
experience that people did truly love when we
launched, and particularly the market that we
went after when we launched really loved it.
I'm curious just what advice you share with
founders when they're asking you how joyous does
this first version have to be? How awesome does
my MVP need to be? One thread I picked up
as you were describing your experiences,
you all had deep experience in this space,
so you knew what you wanted to build. It
wasn't like this dark forest of exploration
is like we know what we want generally. Do
you have advice you share with founders of how
awesome their MVP should be and when it's worth
spending a year or two or three building it?
There's a couple of points in there. First is that
even today we build for ourselves, and I think
this is advice that probably a lot of product
people wouldn't give you is that you shouldn't
build for yourself, you should build for your
customer. But I think we're fortunate that we are
our customer and that the problems we experience
are the problems that hundreds of millions,
billions of people experience. I think that is
maybe a fortunate part of just the problem area
that we're interested in, but it has enabled us
to move really quickly on the product because we
can quickly know what's working in the product,
whether this feature is useful, whether it's
reached that bar of a great experience.
So that's one aspect of it and I think that is
also about being passionate, you entering an
area that you are extremely passionate about.
I often hear people are like, "I want to do a
tech startup. What is the best area I should
focus on to build a product in?" And to me,
that is totally the wrong way to go about building
a company that you're going to spend the next 10,
20 years in because if you're in an area that
you are particularly passionate about but you
see the opportunity to make a bit of money
or have some external measure of success,
that is a terrible way to go about being a
founder because you're going to hit these
rock bottom dark places and if the passion isn't
driving you through that, you're going to have an
incredibly hard time getting to the next step.
So that's probably the first area I talk about
in terms of knowing when a product is amazing.
The second one is that it really needs to spark,
joy, and delight in people and just pure
excitement. It can't just be like, "Oh,
yeah, this is a useful tool for me." It needs to
light up their eyes. They need to be like, "How
do I sign up for this thing tomorrow? How do I get
it? How do I pay for it?" And they need to want to
talk to other people about it because in the early
days of your startup, you don't have marketing
dollars, you don't have channels which you can go
to immediately get access to a million people. You
need to really foster the first people that are
going to use your product and they're going to be
the ones that are going to spread it and they're
going to set the foundations for your growth.
Interesting. So piece of advice number one is work
on something you really want yourself that you're
excited to work on. Two is get it to a place
where it lights up people's eyes. They're just
so excited with this thing. For that second bar,
what was it for Canva? Was it just that it was
impossible to do this design in a browser?
It was 2012, 2013 when we launched and visual
content was still in its infancy. Instagram
had only been out a couple of years. Pinterest
was on the rise. People were just getting used
to creating visuals and it was hived off to a
very select few because to create those visuals
you needed to afford some expensive software,
know how to use that expensive software, nowhere
to go to get fonts and photos and illustrations,
know how to put that together into something
that looked decent and then ship that off.
It was something that only 1% of the
world could do and democratizing design,
empowering the world to design is Canva's
entire mission, and we saw this sweet spot
at the time in social media. It wasn't what we
set out to go after. We set out to democratize
design to bring design to literally everyone in
the world and to everything that they're doing.
But through the user testing that we did,
through the levels of excitement that we
saw from different people, social media managers
really came to the fore at that time. So we knew
that they really fit what we could ship right
now. We didn't ship a presentation product or
a T-shirt builder in our very first version. We
shipped a thing that could make square landscape
and portrait graphics and blog post graphics, and
that got a particular segment of society excited.
We added on all the things afterwards because that
was part of vision and ultimately what we wanted
to build. But with a team of 10 people in the
space of a year, building something that really
got social media managers excited was what we
could pull off. And that's something we realized
in the last six months of that launch year. We
didn't quite know who our audience was going
to be. We knew it was a tool that anyone could
use, but in that last six months of user testing
and refining is when we really identified that
first target market and we just leant into it.
There's so many things you all nailed early
on. One of them is the focus persona/ICP,
which is you said social media managers. Just
to take the lesson from that, you basically saw
that segment getting the most excited about the
product and that told you, let's focus on this
group. Is that right?
Exactly.
And was it like an order magnitude more excited?
What do people look for there that tells them,
"This is the one."? What did you see
there other than just more excitement?
It was just incredibly emotive language, like
sheer joy. Particularly coming into the product,
we worked a lot on the onboarding process in
the last couple of months of launch and that was
really pivotal because the product features were
there. You could add text, you could add images,
you can change the color of things, you can
move stuff around the page. It was a simple
but powerful product, but there was this thing
holding people back from actually using it and
understanding what Canva could do for them. And
when user tested the onboarding of Canva a ton,
actually usertesting.com had just launched them,
which really unlocked us because we didn't have
to do these big formal labs or anything like
that. We could just go online and get results
in the space of half an hour. So that was
like a pivotal unlock for our product process
and that's something we still employ today.
And through that, we tailored the onboarding
process to get people excited and to understand
the deeper goal with Canva and the deeper impact
it could let them have. It wasn't just about
letting them put a pretty picture on the page,
it really unlocked their ideas and let them do
things they couldn't do before. And we shaped the
onboarding to do that and it resonated the most
with social media managers because they had this
massive content need that they couldn't really
service. And in the first minute of Canva with the
right onboarding, it just unlocked the whole realm
of productivity and impact that they didn't have
before and that's why they got super excited.
We talk a lot on this podcast about the power of
onboarding and the impact that can have on
retention and everything down funnel. Do you
remember what the unlock was in terms
of and getting more people activated?
Is there anything that's something
that other people can learn from?
For us, it was taking that first step,
particularly with Canva and any I think
creative tool. There's a real fear of the blank
page. So prior to any onboarding thought from us,
we had a blank page. We had a few coach
marks that said, "Here's where you do this,
here's where you do this." And then they'd be
left on this blank page and people would freak
out. So what we really focused on was just
taking that first step and then the next step
and then the next step. And before they knew
it, they built a design. And the way that we
did that was to encourage a really simple step.
So the first one was click on this search box
and search for a monkey. It literally said that.
Searching for a monkey is something you probably
don't do in most tools. So it was a little
surprising, which was a good inroad, but it
was still super easy. Anyone can type monkey. And
then you type that in, it comes up with this whole
sway the monkey images, which look hilarious,
and just dragging one of those out onto a page
is another simple step. And we just got people
to walk through that keeping their interest up,
keeping the bar of effort quite low, but within
three or four steps, they'd built up something
that they'd never been able to do before, and
it surprised them. The words that we literally
got out of years at testing were, I didn't know I
could be a designer. And that was what we managed
to do through several rounds of refinement
on the onboarding process. It is lowering the
barriers to entry and also increasing the amount
of delight, and I think those two things are what
you should be aiming for with your onboarding.
That's an incredible insight. Is there a video
of that original onboarding out there
or is the current one still similar?
The current one isn't similar. We have constantly
gone back to it because it performs really well.
We do actually apply the same approach of little
steps building up into bigger accomplishments,
and that's actually rolled out through our
last round of launches for the last couple
of years through something we call learn and
play. So with every launch that we do now,
we think about how to teach people about that
feature and how to get them really involved
in it. We have a whole series of learn and
plays where when we launch AI photo editing,
they can try it out right then and there. They've
got some great content that they can immediately
operate on, and it's a super simple step for them
to type in a prompt and see the result of that.
I think an interesting and really important
takeaway here is you built a very delightful,
incredible, innovative product, but it
still didn't work until you figured out
the onboarding and that you needed to figure out
the persona to focus on. All those things end up
being incredibly important, it's not just
build something amazing and delightful.
Definitely.
Staying within this realm
of growth, you've grown in large part thanks
to this incredibly SEO template strategy. You
mentioned in interview there's this guy, Andre
that came on early and helped you figure this
stuff out. Is that true? And if so, what was
the key insight that he had that led to such
a great success in terms of growth for you all?
Andre is an amazing guy. He's actually been in and
out of Canva three or four times now.
Keep pulling him back.
Yeah, keep pulling him back. We originally found
him, he came from a startup that was going under
here in Sydney. We had thought about SEO. We
knew it was this thing that you could use,
and I think in a couple of our pitch decks, we had
SEO as a whole growth channel that we were going
to execute upon in order for investors to make
a ton of money, but we pretty much knew nothing
about it. And it was sitting away in our backlog
of things to do in the first couple of years
of Canva. And we came across Andre and he just
really crystallized what SEO was and how it would
actually help us grow. So we brought him on, he
rolled out his strategy and it was fantastically
effective. It was also incredibly cheap, and
it was super easy for us to do ourselves.
He set up a whole team of people who
looked at people's motivations and the top
jobs to be done that Canva could service. He then
mapped that through the entire experience of going
into Google, typing a search query, getting that
search query, seeing that it was a great result,
firstly getting to the top result, but then also
the experience after they landed on Canva. So
if they searched for want to make a Halloween
poster, the top Google result would be Canva.
They'd click on it, they'd land on the Halloween
poster landing page. It would tell them how they
were going to do, it show you how the product
was going to do that, have a button there that
immediately took them into a Halloween poster
template, went through a fantastic onboarding
of customizing that poster really simply, and
then they would hit done, download the image,
and they had a fantastic experience and he thought
through that whole end-to-end flow from first
landing on Google and typing into the search box
through to that magic moment where they're like,
"Canva just helped me do something
amazing and I want to do it again."
Amazing. Okay. So a few things I'm hearing there.
One is figure out the jobs to be done of potential
users, figuring out where their search volume,
figure out ones you can actually solve for them,
like say a Halloween poster, and then
think about that experience end to end
from search to landing. And obviously, you
have to deliver on that promise. You have to
actually show them a really cool Halloween
poster that they can create, right?
Yeah. Again, it's like product led truly
means product led because you can't just
SEO the hell out of something that is a terrible
experience. So tying that experience at the end
of the SEO journey is just as important as the
technicalities of SEO itself, and Andre really
harnessed the whole spectrum of that to produce
the end experience, which ultimately ended up with
an active user having a delightful experience.
Is there anything else along those lines that was
really surprising to you or really, wow, that
worked a lot better than I thought because it's
probably one of the most well executed, most
successful SEO strategies in history. And I'm
so curious, just if there's anything else
there that's just like, "Oh, wow, that was
really effective and I didn't expect that."
There's a ton in the SEO realm that Andre drove
that can get quite technical. But I think
one of the other pivotal growth moments for
us was internationalization. I think as an
Australian company, we're fortunate in that
Australia isn't a great market to focus on.
We've got 25 million people here. It's okay,
but it's not sizeable. It's not going to make
you a huge success. Whereas probably a startup
that starts in the US will tend to focus on the
US because it's a huge monetizable market, and
you can entirely create a great company that just
services the US. But from Australia, we needed to
think about the world. And that meant that we
very quickly got into internationalization.
We started localizing and internationalizing our
products three years after launch, which is quite
early compared to a lot of other companies. And
we tackled it with real vigor. We had a goal of
being in five different languages within the first
year of localization, and we actually hit eight in
that first year. And then we set ourselves a goal
of being in 100 different languages the next year.
And the internationalization team smashed that
goal by the end of 2017. And it has drastically
changed Canva's growth trajectory because being in
other languages, offering a localized experience,
something that people in Brazil or Indonesia
or Spain or Poland can authentically feel
like they're using a product that's made for
them has totally changed who our market is,
how quickly we can grow. And the way the product's
used internationalizing into Brazilian Portuguese
meant that we had to focus a ton more on the
Android mobile experience, which was really
different for us because we focused a lot on the
desktop experience for the first four years.
People also in Brazil run entire businesses
from their mobile phone and the types of
content they're creating to interact with their
audience is totally different. So it's actually
shaped our product and changed our product
trajectory as a result of thinking about
internationalization. And it has just fueled
tremendous growth. Brazil, India, Indonesia,
they're all in our top five markets and
they grow way faster than the US does.
I know you went international in your four,
something like that, which is really early
for a company. It also makes sense for SEO plus
internationalization. Makes tons of sense.
Totally.
It's a lot more surface area.
Okay. I'm going to have two more questions. One is
around your freemium strategy. Another a thing you
all nailed. There's just this, you're both seeing
incredible growth and incredible monetization. I'm
curious what your philosophy is on what to include
in the free plan versus what people should pay for
because it's clearly worked out great.
Freemium for us wasn't so much a growth
strategy or a monetization strategy as much as it
spoke to our core mission of empowering the world
to design. We truly want to democratize design,
which means we want to get design into the hands
of as many people as we can because we think that
the world is a better place when more people can
create really rich visual content. So freemium
just made sense to us because we could get the
tool into billions of people's hands and they
wouldn't necessarily have to pay for it. And much
of the world can't pay for products because they
just don't have access to that level of income.
So providing that equality was really important to
us. But also you need to build a viable business
because you can't help the world design if you
can't afford to keep the lights on. So freemium
just really hit this sweet spot for us between
philosophy and business building, so it was always
part of our plan since day one. We initially had
element sales as our business models. So when
we first went to pitch Canva, it was all about
create a design. Anything you use in that design
will cost you a dollar. So if you dragged in a
monkey and you wanted to export that whole design,
you'd have to pay a dollar for the money.
Yeah, I've done that many times.
Yes. It was really exciting to investors at the
time. It was also really exciting to the content
creators who were giving us the monkeys to put
into our product. It was a totally new business
model. It unlocked, I think, an area that a lot
of people were unfamiliar with, which was stock
photography. Most people had not paid 100, $500
for photo, and that really held them back from
being visual content creators. So it was a really
unique innovation for us. And for the first two
years of Canva's life, that was how we derived our
revenue. It grew pretty well. It was still like,
I don't know, 30% month-on-month growth in terms
of revenue. But you can do that in the early
stages of a startup. It wasn't until we introduced
our first subscription product that we saw really
hockey stick growth in our revenue. And that was
always the plan to launch a subscription product.
But as with many things, it was a vision that
we didn't quite have meat around the bones.
So we knew we wanted to put in a subscription
what exactly that subscription would look like.
We didn't quite know. And through the first
couple of years of Canva, we started noticing
what people were asking for, what they would
be more likely to pay in a subscription for.
And that formed the first few features that
became what was then called Canva for Work,
which is now called Canva Pro. And we launched
our first subscription, I think about three
years after we launched the first product, and we
just rapidly saw the revenue from the subscription
start overtaking the $1 image payments.
So much so that three or four years later we made
image element payments part of the subscription.
And again, that was like a second hockey stick
in gross in terms of the revenue from the
subscription because all you can eat images inside
the Canva Pro subscription with just amazing value
add for people. And I don't even know if we get
any revenue from image element sales now. It's
all about just going into this subscription.
Amazing. Just hockey stick after
hockey sticks. Speaking of another
hockey stick, I want to talk about AI.
Oh, a whole hockey team of hockey sticks.
Just need to acquire hockey teams. I want
to talk about AI, something on the top of
everyone's minds these days. It's another
area you guys have nailed. You're doing
amazing work with AI. It's providing actual
value and business impact. I hear you have
an amazing internal AI ops team. Is there
anything that you've learned so far that
you can share about just how to integrate AI
successfully and effectively into a product?
As a technology company, you always just
need to be constantly evolving and using
the best technology. And when we started that
was mobile phones and cloud computing. They
were the innovations that came in that really
unlocked Canva. AI is the next decade I think
of innovation. It's the next pivotal piece of
technology that helps you build better products,
but it also can't just be the basis for your
product. You can't just be a product that's
purely built on AI on being a rapper around an
LLM or something like that. You still need to
think about what it is that people want to do and
how you build a product that actually meets that
need. It isn't just about slapping a chatbot
on something that already existed. It's about
deeply thinking about how AI can help them get
to that goal even faster. And we view AI as the
next way of democratizing design and empowering
the world to design, helping more people design,
helping more people design quicker, helping
more people design quicker with better quality.
And that's how we approach every aspect
of including AI in the Canva platform.
We've had a team of machine learning engineers
for probably seven years now. I think their
work has become a lot more visual now and more
customer facing way back when they were just
doing recommendation engines inside our emails
and our homepage and suggesting templates to
you. But now they get to work with some really
cool technology, which lets them produce images
for people and create designs and summarize
text and translate to a hundred different
languages like it's really stuff that you
can put directly in front of customers now,
and that's super exciting. And over the last
couple of years, we've built up more and more
visual AI experts inside Canva, and we approach
AI inside the product through three pillars.
First of these is that we need to build some of
our own AI tech, and we focus on building the AI
tech that we have the biggest advantage in that
we have the most data that we can put into it,
the most insights, the most criticality to
our product and our business. So we have teams
building our own AI models around design
and images and that stuff. Second pillar
is just finding the world's best AI people
to partner with. And there's a whole bunch
of stuff that you don't need to internalize in
your company. You don't need to create an LLM
because it's a commodity thing now. And there's
a bunch of providers who can do it way better
and have way more resources to do it with than
you do. So finding a great partner like OpenAI,
and we partnered with RunwayML to do video
generation, finding the world's best and
bringing them into your product with a
great integration, the second pillar.
And for us, the third pillar is our app ecosystem.
So we're fortunate now we've got 170 million
people using the product every single month. We
have quite an audience that people want access to.
And through our app developer ecosystem, they can
build apps which directly integrate with the Canva
product to give them access to those hundreds of
millions of people when people are quite eager
to do that. Now, we've seen huge uptake in that
from AI developers who have included stuff in
Canva from music generators to virtual avatars
that can present your presentation to you to a
whole slew of things. And those three pillars
have, I think, allowed us to create a really
coherent experience and one that still keeps
a focus on what people want to do, how to help
them reach their big goals in a way that doesn't
just push technology in the face in a way that
just is part of the experience and is a natural
way of getting them to where they want to go.
I was also looking at the GPT story of the fifth
most popular custom GPT where people can generate
logos using it. So maybe that's driving some
growth too. I know you wanted to share something
that you guys are launching or have launched by
the time this episode comes out. Is that true?
Yeah, so we've got a big event in Los Angeles
in a couple of months. It's our Canva create,
which is an evolution of the season openness
that we used to do. So season openers are no
longer just inside Canva now. We actually invite
our whole community in, and we're going to have
probably about 4,000 people in the theater in LA
and a couple of million online. And we're really
going to be pulling the covers off pretty much
the next decade of Canva. We've focused for the
first decade of Canva on unlocking individuals
and small businesses, giving them the tools that
they need to design and to express themselves
and create visual content. And as Canva has
grown and people have gotten used to creating
this stuff, they've invited their teams in,
they now collaborate with people on presentations,
on Canva videos, on swag T-shirts that they
need to make for their event next week.
And as more and more people are using Canva
together, it's picking up a lot of steam. We've
got 95% of the Fortune 500 using Canva. We've got
huge teams of thousands of people using Canva.
And this has really opened our eyes to not only
the enterprise opportunity, but also just the way
to redesign the way people work. And that is what
the event at the end of May is about. It's really
redesigning work for a whole number of different
verticals, from marketing to sales to HR to IT
to creatives that work inside large teams, large
organizations, large enterprises. We've redesigned
Canva for this collaborative enterprise age,
so we'll be pulling the covers off that alongside
work kits, which are a whole verticalized
experiences for people inside marketing and sales
and HR that want to use Canva, as well as a bunch
of improvements to our AI products and an actual
enterprise skew that we're launching as well.
So through this growth and through getting
to understand the needs of CIOs and heads of
security at enterprises, we've realized that there
pretty much needs to be a new enterprise product
of Canva that meets the needs of hugely scaled
teams, which has been quite different for us
because we have scaled from those individuals
just using the product all by themselves and
organically growing the teams. And now looking
at it from a top-down lens and building that
enterprise products is what we've been focused
on for the last couple of years. So we'll be
pulling the covers off that as well in LA.
I see another hockey stick approaching. I'm
excited of all these things you're launching. What
a business you've built. I feel like it's still
way too under the radar, even though it's this
juggernaut. Nice work, Cameron and team. Two more
questions I ask everyone, where can folks find you
online and how can listeners be useful to you?
They can find me online at themaninblue.com, which
is my blog that's been around for 24 years now.
What was the other question? How can you-
Yeah. How can listeners be useful to you?
I love their design stories, how design
has helped unlock something for them,
whether it's starting their first business or
helping a nonprofit that they volunteer at. I
just love bumping into someone in the street and
seeing the joy of design right up in their eyes.
So please do that whenever you see me.
Beautiful. Cam, you're awesome. Canva is
awesome. Go check out canva.com. Easy
to find. Thanks for being here.
Thanks, Lenny. See you soon.
All right. Bye, everyone. Thank you so
much for listening. If you found this valuable,
you can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcast,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.