Before you came on, I asked on Twitter,
what should I ask Seth Godin? The most
recurring theme actually had to
do with AI. How do you think all
these new AI companies build brands to
distinguish and differentiate themselves?
AI very soon is going to stop being a feature
the same way electricity is not a feature. What
AI companies and all companies need to do
is say, what's in this for the user? What
promise do I want to make a difficult promise,
a remarkable promise, and then how do I keep it?
You wrote a new book. You basically talk about how
a great strategy has tension at the center of it.
Tension is at the heart of every art form and
every innovation. What we do when we launch
a new product, we say, we have this thing that
can do X, and now the person is imagining what
their life might be like if that were true.
If they fall in love with that possibility,
now there's tension. Did you tell the
truth? Is it going to work for them?
There's the section that stuck out to
me, these four insights that basically
determine what your life is going to be like
outside of actually building the product.
For a product person, these are the critical
choices and you probably have glossed over them.
Today my guest is Seth Godin. Seth is an absolute
legend. He's published 21 books, including 18
international bestsellers. He's been blogging
every single day for almost 10,000 days in a
row now. His writing and his advice have inspired
me and so many people all over the world for the
past few decades. He shares wisdom and advice
around stuff that everyone can benefit from,
including how ideas spread, when to quit, how
to lead, how to stand out, and most of all how
to change everything. In addition to his writing
and speaking, Seth has founded several companies,
including Yoyodyne and Squidoo. He also started
the altMBA program, and as you'll hear in our
conversation, he actually started his career
as a product manager. In our conversation,
Seth shares advice on how to know if you have
good taste and how to build your taste, how to
build a brand in an increasingly crowded world
of AI startups and AI content, his thoughts on
the Jaguar rebrand and also the Tesla Cybertruck.
We also delve into his new book, This is Strategy,
including why every great strategy has tension
at its center, why you need to understand the
systems within which you operate in order to build
a great strategy and how choosing your customers,
your distribution strategy, and how you
validate your idea will inform the product
you build and the life that you live. We
also talk about how he used Claude as a
writing assistant in developing this new book.
This episode is short and packed with insights,
which I know is what you all love. If you
enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting
app or YouTube. It's the best way to avoid
missing future episodes and helps the podcast
tremendously. With that, I bring you Seth Godin.
Seth, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
What a treat, Lenny. Thank you for having
me. Lenny was my late mom's nickname,
so it's good to say that out loud.
That's so cool. I've never heard it used for
a woman, and every Lenny out there I've met is
wonderful, so I imagine she's wonderful. First,
I just want to say how honored I am to have you
on this podcast. When I actually started this
podcast, I was like, and I was listening to
you on Tim Ferriss at that point, and I was
like, man, what if one day I get Seth Godin
on my podcast? How cool would that be? I've read
so many of your books. I have a bunch of them in
the bookshelf back there. I reference your stuff
all the time, so thank you again for doing this.
Well, thank you. It's a treat to talk to you.
Today's episode is brought to you by DX. If you're
an engineering leader or on a platform team,
at some point your CEO will inevitably ask you for
productivity metrics, but measuring engineering
organizations is hard and we can all agree that
simple metrics like the number of PRs or commits
doesn't tell the full story. That's where DX comes
in. DX is an engineering intelligence solution
designed by leading researchers, including those
behind the DORA and space frameworks. It combines
quantitative data from developer tools with
qualitative feedback from developers to give
you a complete view of engineering productivity
and the factors affecting you. Learn why some of
the world's most iconic companies like Etsy,
Dropbox, Twilio, Vercel, and Webflow rely on
DX. Visit DX's website at getdx.com/Lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta. When
it comes to ensuring your company has top-notch
security practices, things get complicated fast.
Now you can assess risk, secure the trust of
your customers and automate compliance for SOC 2,
ISO-27001, HIPAA and more with a single platform,
Vanta. Vanta's market-leading trust management
platform helps you continuously monitor compliance
alongside reporting and tracking risk. Plus,
you can save hours by completing
security questionnaires with Vanta AI.
Join thousands of global companies that
use Vanta to automate evidence collection,
unify risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go to
Vanta.com/Lenny. That's Vanta.com/Lenny.
I want to start by asking a question that
one of your former colleagues suggested I
ask you. Wes Kao. I imagine you remember Wes?
Of course. Wes and I sat in a
room just the two of us for years.
So what she suggested I ask you, and this
question I love, is she... I asked her,
what did you learn most from Seth Godin
working with him? And she immediately said,
it's helping her build better
taste and increase her standards,
having really high standards. So I want to ask
you first of all, just how do you know if you
have good taste and high standards and then how
do you build good taste and higher standards?
Great question. Thank you, Wes. I define
good taste as knowing what other people
want just before they do. So if you're the only
person who wants peanut butter covered licorice,
you're entitled to eat peanut butter
covered licorice, but you don't have
good taste because everyone else
thinks that's weird. And people,
whether they're jazz musicians or fabric
designers are seen as having good taste when
they bring something to the world that the world
didn't necessarily expect but is glad to see.
What do you find helps? So Wes learned
from watching you that she realized,
okay, my standards are not nearly as high as
they could be. Other than working with you,
maybe that's the answer is work with people like
you that have really high standards. Just what do
you find is most helpful in helping people build
taste and also just increase their standards?
Standards, it's worth understanding what quality
is and the people who listen to this podcast know
better than most. Quality is not luxury. Quality
is not perfection. Quality means meeting spec,
and if you meet spec, you're done. If
you don't think the spec is good enough,
make a better spec. But if you meet spec, you're
done. And so what it means to have high standards
is that you relentlessly improve the spec in
service of the people you're working with and for.
And what it doesn't mean is that you take
something that meets spec and refuse to
ship it because you're a perfectionist.
That's hiding. And so what I learned at
Spinnaker where I had my first job, real job as
a product manager, was this idea that we weren't
there to make perfect for us. We were there to
delight the person who was buying the software.
And our standards were untouchable. We said,
"If that person, the one we're describing is
delighted with what we shipped, it's good. And
if they're not, it doesn't matter what kind of
excuses we have." This is the opposite of what
most people in this job do, which is they say,
how do I please my boss? And if you're just doing
your job, then don't expect to get rewarded for
more than just doing your job because we can
find lots of people who can just do your job.
That reminds me of one of your other really
powerful pieces of advice about how no matter
your job, this is a tangent, but it really
stuck with me once I read your advice here is
no matter what job you have, you couldn't love
it, enjoy it, be amazing at it, even if you're
just like a waitress or whatever. Can you just
talk through that? Because that's so powerful.
Well, I think I got it from the late Reverend
Martin Luther King Jr., and the idea is there's
no perfect job. A friend of mine, Tim, is
a famous jazz saxophonist and he's got to
schlep from city to city, and he's got to play
to half empty rooms and he is got to deal with
this and deal with this. So you're never going
to have unlimited artistic freedom. But what we
all have is the ability to understand where
the boundaries of our work lie and go there.
And if you're a barista and you've chosen
to be a barista, maybe because it's the
best thing you could get, well you're not
going to get the next hour over again. So
what would it be like to be the best barista
in the world for an hour? Would that be worth
it for you? Because I've had menial jobs
in food service and I got to tell you,
when the boss forces you to be mediocre and
bored, there's no amount of money they can pay
you to do that job. But if you're there and you
have a chance to add delight to someone's day,
you're doing that for you, not
because you're getting paid.
And you could totally tell these people in the
world when you go to a barista that just you can
tell, just loves their job. I know imagine
she knows this is not her career long-term,
but she just embraces it and just
has fun with it. There's so much
power to that. On a different note, you
mentioned that you were product manager,
which I did not know. That's amazing.
So most of the people listening to this
podcast are product managers. They're
either product managers, founders,
people that want to be founders, and then people
that work with product managers. So first of all,
I guess could you just share that part of your
life? Because I don't think people know that.
All right. So the origin story could take all
day, but I'm not going to tell the whole thing.
I'm going to tell the part that I thought was
normal that turned out to be the luckiest thing
in the world. The summers between the two years
of business school are very important to establish
your career arc. I got a job at Spinnaker
Software. Spinnaker invented educational computer
games. I was the 30th employee. And the summer was
spent doing assistant brand manager kind of stuff,
going to meetings with the ad agency, writing
copy. But at the end of the summer, they had
a lovely going away party for me, because I was
flying back to California. And then at the end,
the president of the company, the chairman
of the company and the head of marketing
bring me into this side when they say, "We
have a secret project, we want you to work
for us while you're at business school and
we're all going to pay you almost nothing."
"Okay, what's the secret project?" "We're going
to do computer adventure games with illustrations
and music based on science fiction novels, and
we've already acquired the work of Ray Bradbury
and Arthur C. Clarke." Now, I had read every
science fiction book in the Clearfield Public
Library from Asimov to Zelazny. This was a
dream come true, but they thought my job was
going to be make the packaging and run the ads.
And what I discovered, first of all is that I
couldn't really go back to business school. So
I showed up hardly at all at Stanford and just
took a lot of red eyes. But I discovered
that the engineers, the development team,
they had a lot of people vying for their time. And
if I didn't figure out how to get them to give me
way more than my fair share of development, I
wasn't going to have any products to make next
Christmas and then I was going to be out of a job.
And so I started a newsletter internally,
I was one of the first people in the world to have
desktop publishing because I was a beta tester for
the Mac, and in it I would mention anybody in the
engineering team who had worked on my project and
I would say something good about them. And then
I would print it out and put it in every single
person's inner office mailbox. And within three
months, four months, partly because the project
was really good, 40 engineers were working for me
and no one was reporting to me. And so I became
the de facto product manager and that is when I
learned marketing is the product. You don't make
a product and then hand it to some marketing yahoo
and say, go put a logo on this. That the product
we made, and five in a row went gold, saved
the company. Though product is why it worked.
And so I was supposed to know how to code
but I didn't, but I could be in the room. The
last month, RadioShack had bought how many
units? 3000 stores times five times five,
a lot of units. And if we had missed a date,
they were going to cancel the order and the
company would go bankrupt, and the software wasn't
even close to done. And we didn't have any source
control like we do now. There was no cloud,
so it was all in my head. So I did not leave
the office. I'm not exaggerating this, I did not
leave the office for the last 22 days, slept for
four hours a night upstairs, and if anyone had
a question, I could tell them who to talk to.
That was so thrilling. It was so thrilling to make
those decisions, to cajole this team, none of whom
were in it for the money, to make something
we were proud of. And then the stuff ships,
everyone else goes home to sleep for a month, but
I am the project manager and the marketing guy,
so I got to stay at work. And the next day the
phone rings and it's Herbie Hancock on the phone,
the great jazz musician, and Herbie says,
"The receptionist said you're the person
in charge of Fahrenheit 451." And I said,
"Herbie? I'm 24 years old, man. Herbie?"
And he went on and on about how he had stayed
up all night to play it and that he loved it.
I love how natural of a product manager you
were in these things you shared of just thinking
everyone deflecting credit and all these things.
It's sign of a great PM. Along these lines,
I wanted to ask actually, so you're a PM
early on. Now, you obviously spend a lot
of time marketing. I know you're saying there's
obviously a strong connection between the two,
but is there anything you find that
people building the product most often
miss or misunderstand that just annoys
you or do you think they need to hear?
Maybe I got seven, but I'll try
to do them off the top of my head.
The first one is this, empathy is not
about kindness and empathy is not an
option. This is something that you are making
for other people. So the whole idea of RTFM,
read the manual, I'm angry at you. If
you're saying that to your customers,
you made a mistake, they did not make a mistake.
The second one is that the thing about projects
is when you run out of time and you run out of
money, the project is over. Don't run out of time,
don't run out of money. Good intentions are no
reason for an extension. The professional doesn't
ask for an extension because the professional
understands that things you didn't expect
are going to happen. That's part of the deal.
And I guess the third one would be for software,
particularly software as a service, if you don't
build the network effect into what you are making,
you are almost certainly going to fail. You cannot
hope that Apple's going to pick you, promote you,
and magically have you be successful. The
question is, will this work better for my
users if they tell other people about it? And
if the answer is no, then why would they tell
other people about it? And if they don't tell
other people about it, no one's going to hear
about it. But if the answer is yes, then
your marketing problems pretty much solved.
I feel like each of these is its own book that
we could talk through. And I want to come back
to this last point and how it relates to the
purple cow. I want to spend a little time there,
but first I'm going to ask a marketing question.
So before you came on, I asked on Twitter,
what should I ask Seth Godin? He's coming on
my podcast. I got a flood of suggestions. The
most recurring theme actually had to do with
AI. Actually the co-founder of Intercom asked
this question and it echoes what many people
are wondering. So his question is how do you
think all these new AI companies build brands
to distinguish and differentiate themselves in
a world that's increasingly filled with
AI companies, AI products, AI content?
Well, the first question is what's a brand?
Because it's not a logo. A brand is a promise.
It's what do I expect from you. It's would I miss
you if you were gone. And Hyatt Hotels has a logo,
Nike has a brand. The way we know this is if
Nike opened a hotel, we'd know what it would be
like. But if Hyatt decided to make sneakers,
we have no clue. They might be comfortable,
but that's all we would know. And so if you want
to build a brand, you got to stand for something
and you got to say what you don't do. And the
second thing is AI very soon is going to stop
being a feature the same way electricity is
not a feature. That lots and lots of things
run on electricity, but they're not electricity
companies. They just happen to use electricity.
So what AI companies and all companies need to
do is say, what's in this for the user? What
promise do I want to make? A difficult promise,
a remarkable promise. And then how do I keep it?
So making absurd promises might work at the VC
level, but it doesn't work when you're talking to
consumers because you can only break that promise
one time. And so to wrap up the brand part,
airlines don't have brands and airlines don't
have loyalty. And the way we know this is that
the only reason people stick with an airline
is for the points, which is bribery. Loyalty is
would you pay extra to stick with this? And if you
wouldn't pay extra, then the brand has no value.
I love this phrase, make a promise
and keep it. And the AI element,
that raises the bar because many
more promises are being made,
fewer promises are probably being kept. So is
the advice there, continue making an ambitious
promise and then the key is actually deliver
on that and that's what builds you brand?
Yeah. I have a very emotional connection
to Claude.ai. I think they have a brand.
ChatGPT's reputation with me is not
good because it regularly over promises
and under delivers and it does it without kindness
or humility. Whereas Claude, I don't know how
they did it, at least in my experience, brings
kindness and humility. So when it doesn't know,
it's very clear and it's not lazy and it's not
angry at me. And so I happily pay extra for Claude
because it has a brand. Whereas ChatGPT for me is
just a tool that I use if I have no other options.
I love the Anthropic/Claude's billboards. "We're
the ones without the drama." The AI company
without the drama. I was going to save this to
the end, but let's actually talk about it. So you
mentioned somewhere that you actually use Claude
to help you write this book and refine the book,
which I think is going to increasingly
happen. Could you just share that process
of how you did that? What did you do that might
be helpful to people to help you write this book?
Well, to be clear about my brand promise, because
it's true, every word that has my name on it,
I wrote. Every blog post, every book. I
don't have a team. This is my whole staff
is me. What I did with Claude and which
I encourage people to do in the book is
I would upload a list of four things and
say, what did I miss? And it would suggest
three things to complete the list. And often
they would be things I hadn't thought of. And
then I could go write about that or I would
upload a couple chapters and I would say,
what are the claims I'm making here that
you don't think that I'm sustaining? And
it became this patient editor that is so hard to
find in the real world because editors aren't paid
enough and given enough time to do their job
right. And what I find is if I have a sentence
that doesn't sound enough like me, I can ask
Claude to help me figure out why that's true.
I love that tactic of using it
to figure out what you missed.
I feel like you agree with this. I find that
when I write, part of it is I'm putting an
idea out there. I want to see what I got wrong
and what I missed. And I like that you basically
skip that step and don't put it out and just
make the thing you put out actually better.
Well, the thing about blogging every day
is at first it felt like how am I going to
keep up? But once I could build a queue
because I didn't want my streak to end-
How long is the streak at this point, by the way?
Post number 10,000 comes out
at the beginning of 2025.
Oh my God. In a row.
In a row. Some days there were two.
But what I found as I got a little
bit of a queue is that I would feel
bad because I had something to say,
but I couldn't because there was already one
in the queue. So I shifted from I have to
write something to I get to write something.
And now because I've taken the pressure off,
I have time to rewrite it because I don't have a
shortage of ideas for tomorrow. I have extra ones.
This episode is brought to you by Paragon,
the developer platform for building native
customer-facing integrations with third-party
apps. Our native integrations on your product
roadmap, whether it's to ingest context from
your user's external data and documents,
or to sync data and automate tasks across
your users' other apps, integrations are
mission-critical for B2B software products
today. But building these integrations in-house
cost and average of three months of engineering
according to the 2024 State of Integration survey,
which results in difficult roadmap trade-offs.
This is why engineering teams at Copy.ai,
AI21 and over 100 other B2B SaaS companies use
Paragon so they can focus their efforts on core
product features, not integrations. The result,
they've shipped integrations seven times faster,
all while avoiding the never-ending maintenance
that comes with rolling your own integrations.
Visit useparagon.com/Lenny to see how Paragon can
help you accelerate your product's integration
roadmap today and get $1,000 in credit on their
pro and enterprise plans. That's useparagon.com.
So let's talk about your book. You wrote
a new book. It's called This is Strategy.
I've been reading it over the past week and
I've been so into it that I actually left it
at my mother-in-law's house. I don't have it
with me. So it's called, This is Strategy.
It's about how to build strategy and develop a
strategy. There's a lot to love about the book,
but the section in the middle that is what most
stuck out to me that I want to spend a little
time on. You have this four sequence of advice
that I love, so I'm just going to read it real
quick. Choose your customers, choose your
future. Choose your competition and choose
your future. Choose the source of validation and
you choose your future. Choose your distribution,
and you're also choosing your future. Can
you just talk through these four insights,
these four steps that basically
determine what your product and
life is going to be like outside of
actually building the products directly?
Yeah. And for a product person, these are the
critical choices and you probably have glossed
over them. You have probably assumed it's a given
and you've sacrificed your agency over the four
most important things you should be choosing.
So the first one is picking your customers. If
your motto is you can pick anyone and we're
anyone, if your hope is that you have to win
SEO to get anything, you're not going to succeed.
When you choose your smallest viable audience,
what language they speak, how much money they
have, what problem they're trying to solve,
what their technical facility is, whether they're
short-tempered, whether they're kind, whether
they're going to stick with you, you have chosen
everything that's going to go into the product
and what your future is going to be like. And so
the Humane Pin people, whatever it was called,
made a mistake when they picked their customers
because they showed up like they had a finished
Apple-quality product and they were trying to
appeal to the kind of people that would buy
on pre-order a finished Apple quality product.
When they shipped something that wasn't that,
and they knew it wasn't that, they're doomed.
Whereas if you say, here we are in Product Hunt,
we're only looking for 400 people. We're looking
for people who like the Raspberry Pi. Who wants to
wonk with this thing? Now you can dance and you
can have all these other things happen because
you picked a different customer. If you decide
to be a wedding photographer in the Hamptons,
well you better expect to have some very spoiled,
cranky brides and grooms, and grooms and grooms,
and brides and brides, that you have to deal with
because you picked your customers. Okay, so then
the second one which comes with that is who's your
competition? Because if you're competing against
Walmart, why are you surprised that they keep
lowering their prices? That's what Walmart does,
right? That way you decide which space that
you're going to operate in. You've built an
enormous set of boundaries around what you do.
The third one is validation. If you are trying
to please your boss, that's what you're going
to do. If on the other hand, you can have one
difficult conversation with your boss and say, can
we agree that I'm not trying to match your taste,
I'm trying to match the taste of these
400 people that we've agreed are our
customers? Every other meeting is going to
go way better from now on because you've
made it clear who you're trying to please.
And the last one, choose your distribution
matters a lot in the software business. For
example, a video game, which is where I started,
we were in Target and Lechmere and
mass merchants. Our competitors were
in Ziploc bags in computer stores. Well,
when something like Steam shows up, when
something like downloadable shareware shows up,
everything about your product changes. So again,
these four things are choices, and if you're
glossing over them it's because you're afraid.
And I think it's important to note, it's not
like you can just change these at will and
just like, okay, cool, we'll change your
distribution. These are intertwined. But
the important point here that I hear
is just make sure the product you're
building understands this is how you'll be
distributed. This is who you're selling to.
Yeah, I mean, so a friend just sent me a business
plan. They're making a food product and they're
saying, we're going to distribute on Shopify
and we're also going to sell to businesses,
airports, hotels, and people who
need to sell the food. I'm like,
there's only two of you. No, that's not
what your business... You got to pick,
today, before you even turn the page,
who are you for and who are you not for?
Along the lines of picking your
customer reminds me, a friend of
mine started a company selling a product to
real estate agents and she just warned me,
be careful who you're selling
to because you're going to be
spending a lot of time with these people.
Make sure you're ready to be doing that.
One of my very first books
was a advertising supported
directory paid for by law firms. This is not
something I want to recommend to anybody.
Another great nugget from the book that
really stood out to me is this idea of
tension. The importance of tension. You
basically talk about how a great strategy
has tension at the center of it. Why is
tension so important to a good strategy?
Okay, so let's agree that tension and stress
aren't the same thing. Stress is generally
not good. Stress is two things at the same time,
I want to leave, I need to stay. Right? I hate
my boss, but I need this job. That's stress.
Don't look for stress. Tension is at the heart
of every art form and every innovation.
Tension is it might not work. Tension
is da-da-da-na-na, and the other person says,
da-da. Because they need to finish the sentence.
So what we do when we launch a new product
is we say, we have this thing that can do X,
and now the person is imagining what their
life might be like if that were true. If
they fall in love with that possibility, now
there's tension. Did you tell the truth? Is
it going to work for them? And when I was
a kid, PF Flyers were the sneaker to get,
this was before Nike. And the promise of PF
Flyers was that they would finally make you
fast enough to run away from the bully. And I
remember 10 years old walking into that shoe
store and there was real tension in my head
because I needed to get away from that bully,
and I was keeping the PF Flyers people to
their promise, and they didn't tell the truth.
It comes back to your point about not delivering
on the promise that you make to build-
Yes.
... A great brand, right? Okay, I want to take
a little tangent into Purple Cow territory. I
have your book right here, by the way.
I have many of your books in the back,
but I don't want to make my library...
Oh, what is that? A milk carton?
This is the first 10,000
copies came in milk carton.
Oh man, I missed out on that. Was there any purple
milk inside? What color is a purple cow's milk?
We'll never know. We'll never know. I know you've
talked about this concept a gazillion times. I
feel like still people don't actually... Many
people haven't heard it. Many people don't truly
understand it, and it's the thing that I reference
most of your piece of advice. Could you spend a
little time just chatting about this topic of the
Purple Cow, the importance of being remarkable?
Okay, so let's start with Steve Blank. I'm
sure you've talked about his idea of customer
traction. The single best way to tell if a
startup's got any hope whatsoever is do the
people who engage with you stick around? Do
they come back for more? The second piece is,
do they tell their friends? And if they tell their
friends, what do they say? The word remarkable
means worth making a remark about. So I'm not
talking about coming up with some viral video
that's ridiculous in its gimmickry. I'm saying
if you make something where the person's life
gets better if they talk about you and you
know in advance what you want them to say,
then they are more likely to say it. So Marissa
Mayer probably created more stock market value
than any other product manager I can think of.
And the way she did it was there weren't very
many people at Google, but she was the one who
said, "No, you can't put another button on the
homepage. There are only going to be two buttons
on the homepage." And over and over and again.
At the time I was at Yahoo. Yahoo had the chance
to buy Google for $10 million while I was there.
That's a whole interesting story. But Yahoo had
183 links on the homepage and Google had two. And
the statement built into that is we are making
you a promise, and the promise is we are smart
enough to take you where you want to go without
you spending a lot of time browsing through 183
links. Tell us what you want and we'll take
you there. And so I was a tech-forward person,
and if a friend came to me lost on the internet,
confused about something, I'd just send them to
Google because I knew they wouldn't come back
to me for more help, because okay, fine, they're
gone. It's going to work. That's what to say about
Google at its launch is, hey, just type in what
you want and you'll find it. They built that into
the product. That makes it remarkable because I
wanted to tell other people about that because
it would raise my status as a tech innovator.
And the implication here, and you talked about
this, is that most likely the way you will win
is word of mouth. It's hard to win with paid
ads. It's hard to win with sales teams unless
you're building B2B software. What you need to
focus on is how to build something people tell
their friends about. And the core of that
is being remarkable. And I love just the
way you break it down. Being remarkable
is being something people remark about.
Yeah, and if you think it's just for small
companies, that's how Microsoft beat WordPerfect,
because Microsoft Word was the format you
needed your coworkers to work in if you
were using a modern computer, because
if they insisted on using WordPerfect,
then you were stuck with WordPerfect. Whereas
they had a migration path and once you migrated,
you didn't go back. So again, it's in my
interest to insist you use Word. So I did.
This point about Mercer Mayer of doing
this thing that was controversial,
it comes back to your point of creating
tension. It feels like it created tension
both with visitors and internally. There's also
these quotes that I have here that are along these
lines that you've said in the past, I don't
think they're in this book. If it scares you,
it might be a good thing to try. And safety is
risky. Is there anything you want to say there?
Well, so one of the things I talk about in the
book is that systems are everywhere we look
and they're largely invisible, taken for
granted. I spend time with high school seniors
talking about college. They don't see the college
industrial complex. They just think it's normal,
because that's what it is to grow up in
the suburbs. And what systems do to protect
themselves is they invent culture. Culture is
the way things are around here. And so if you
think something is scary, that's probably
because the system wants you to think that.
And so you shouldn't do something foolhardy. You
shouldn't be fearless. But what you should do is
think about why does it scare me to do this? What
system will be offended if I do that? Am I trying
to work with the system or am I leveraged
enough to help change the system? And so the
first people who put up downloadable software,
all the feedback was, you can't do that. It'll
be pirated. You'll never make a penny. Okay. That
might happen, and I can see why that feels scary,
but I could also see why the dominant system
of software distribution doesn't want me to
even experiment with this. But I only worked
on the software for five months, let's try it,
because if it doesn't work and it gets pirated,
I'll just have to make new software. It's okay.
It's interesting, the opposite of that
was also true with Salesforce. Their
whole pitch was no software. It's all in
the cloud. Once that became the system,
that became the tension and the risky move.
Yeah.
So you have this quote, actually. I want
to spend more time on the system concept
because it's so core to the book, and so core
to your advice for how to be better, you have
this actual quote. "What does it mean to be a
strategic thinker? It means to see the system."
What else can you share about it just for people
that are trying to become better strategically,
to understand what you mean when you talk
about the system, how to see the system?
We have to invent systems anytime we engage with
other human beings, because interoperability is
essential. There's a system for how we greet other
people in our culture. You shake hands, right hand
to right hand. And just show up sometime and
give the Vulcan salute instead and watch what
happens. It's very awkward because we just needed
to get this over with and now that's part of the
system. And so systems serve a valuable function
until they don't, because then the system starts
doing things to support itself, to reinforce
itself. So for example, there is a system that
says we should interview people for jobs. And
the most successful interviews are people where
they show that they are like us, they look
like us, they went to schools like us, they
have privilege and background like us. That is
toxic, because it diminishes not just diversity,
but our ability to put real talent on the team.
And if you don't see that system and name that
system, you're going to keep doing what you were
doing. And I was talking to someone yesterday who
said they had been working with a company and
the last four people that they had hired had
been captain of their Ivy League tennis team.
Well, clearly there's a pattern here and it's
being reinforced by people who don't want to get
in trouble, but the system's not helping them. And
so yes, we need the metric system and we need the
zip code system. Those keep working really well.
But if you are trying to show up in a place where
dominant players don't want you to succeed, you're
going to have to find something in the system
that gives you a chance to change the rules.
This metaphor that I love that's along these
lines of better waves make better surfers,
that a lot of your success is driven by choosing
the wave versus the skills that you
have. Can you just talk about that?
Yeah. So it's surprisingly profound. I don't
know where I came up with it, but when I see
people who are great at surfing, they're almost
always on good waves. And my son who surfs a lot,
I have noticed, passes up waves that other
people might take waiting for the right wave
because he knows he will be able to surf it
better. So when you think about which company
you're signing up to bring software from, which
people you're willing to put on the key roles,
are you willing to wait for the superstar who's
going to change things or are you in so much of
a hurry to make an imaginary deadline that you're
going to ship mediocre work? Because all mediocre
means is average. And so if you don't want to be
mediocre, you better do something different than
the other people are doing. Otherwise, you're
going to get what the other people are getting.
As you talk about this, I'm thinking about,
I don't know if you saw Jaguar's rebrand and
their whole launch. And it feels like
it's been rejected by the system. Any
thoughts on that? Maybe what they
got wrong or maybe it was genius?
Okay, so you've picked a topic that I really
like to talk about. Jaguar did not rebrand,
Jaguar re-logo-ed. And the logo might be a
sign that they're trying to rebrand and make
a different promise, and they're switching to all
electric, which I'm in favor of. But they made,
I think, a very significant error, which
is if you're going to start a car company,
a hundred million or a billion dollars are going
to get spent earning trust from people who never
heard of you. If you're starting with one of the
most iconic and beautiful and beloved car brands
that has the luxury of having almost no cars in
the world that could undermine what you want it to
stand for going forward, it's perfect. Own that,
that's brilliant. And to walk away from that so
that you could please some art director, I don't
understand why you think you're rebranding when
you just put a logo on that undermines many of the
awareness assets you already had going for you.
It feels like they got very, very controversial.
They went against the status quo more maybe
than they should. I don't know. What
would you have done if you were them?
You may recall when the International House of
Pancakes decided to falsely announce they were
changing their name to the International
House of Burgers and made a new logo,
because they wanted buzz. This is a Wendy's
Twitter tactic. Buzz does not sell hamburgers.
Oreo's got a lot of buzz when they did that tweet
about the Super Bowl blackout. There's no evidence
they sold even one more cookie. They're not in
the business of entertaining us. So Jaguar isn't
going to sell more cars because people like
you and I are talking about their re-logoing.
What's going to make them sell cars is customer
traction. What they need to do is find 50 people
who have authority and get them in a car that
changes them somehow, that transforms them.
And it's interesting if you think about two
things that Tesla did right at the beginning
with the model S. The first one is, according
to someone I know who worked there at the time,
the number one thing people would talk about
when they saw you in the parking lot of the
supermarket was the door handles, because the
door handles popped out. They popped out in
a way that's annoying and dangerous, but it
was noticeable. So there was a conversation.
And then what would happen is they'd say, what do
you think of it? And you'd say, get in the car and
you'd switch to ludicrous mode and you'd drive
at zero to 60 in 2.4 seconds and they'd start
screaming. This was fun for you and told a story
to the passenger. This is how customer traction
begins because I can't do that in a different
car, right? Compare this to the clown car,
the Cybertruck, which was intentionally divisive
and most people don't want to not only drive one
but have one on their block because divisiveness
is not selling. That what's selling is being of
utility, to help someone get what they want.
So here you have a category, the pickup truck,
the number one category for all cars in the United
States, just sitting there waiting to be taken.
You can cross the chasm if you're someone like
Tesla. And instead, they decide to pull a stunt,
and that's not okay. It's not good product
management. It's not good marketing.
Interesting. So you think Cybertruck
are not going to be a success?
Well, I think, compared to what, right?
So the Ford F-150 some years has made more
than a hundred percent of Ford's profit,
meaning without the Ford 150 pickup truck,
there is no Ford. That's how big a category that
is. You have a car with momentum and a public
company where you've earned the trust of a lot of
people. Now you have a category, pickup trucks,
that are purchased for a very specific
reason to show your neighbors you care about
utility. Even if you never use the bed, that's
the story of driving a pickup truck. So now,
if you bring people in that category who are
inherently skeptical of change and inherently
skeptical of design trickery, something that
is nothing but change and design trickery, no,
they're not going to adopt it. You could have
sold an enormous number of people who might've
bought a Ford 150 instead. That crossing of
the chasm is how you become really significant.
I feel like this alone could be its own
separate podcast conversation. I wish
we had more time. I'm going to ask one
last question, and this is a quote that
I found of yours that I also love that
is reminiscent of Elon Musk, actually,
as we were just talking about this. "The secret
to leadership is simple. Do what you believe.
Paint a picture of the future. Go there. People
will follow." Can you just talk about that?
I might be a little too glib because what I need
to highlight is the painting the picture of the
future needs to be based in empathy. You can't
paint a picture of where you want to go. You
have to paint a picture of where they want to
go, and it's this non-narcissism that is where
professionals do their work. That you are not
entitled to raise money, you're not entitled to
have market share, you're not entitled to
get a good price because you worked hard.
What we can do is be of service. We can
open the door to help people get to where
they always wanted to go. It's very difficult
to change what people want, but it's pretty
helpful to offer people a chance to get to where
they always wanted to go in the first place.
Seth, this was a dream come true. I
appreciate you coming on the podcast.
I appreciate you saying that. Where
can people check out your book? Where
should people go to learn more about what
you're up to? Anything you want to share.
So I'm not active on social media, but I do have
a blog at Seths.blog. If you go to Seths.blog/TIS,
you'll find everything you need to know
about the book and the strategy deck and
the collectible chocolate bar and whatever
other thing I've dreamed up in the meantime.
Chocolate. Seth, thank you so much for being here.
These were great questions, Lenny, I
could talk to you all day. Thank you,
I appreciate that. Same. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If you
found this valuable, you can subscribe
to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
LennysPodcast.com. See you in the next episode.