You're one of the first 10 employees, you're the
first product manager. It was when you joined,
the founders didn't really have an idea figured
out yet. When they landed on an idea, and then
ended up being wrong, ended up not working.
Six weeks after you joined, there was a pivot.
At the time, we didn't really have a solid product
yet. We would have 10 to 15 meetings every day
with potential customers. I was hired as the
first product manager. I sat in on those calls.
I still did not exactly understand what we
were going to build, which was confusing,
because I was a product manager, so
I was supposed to start building it,
and so, at some point, it
was like, "I have to ask,
what exactly are we doing here?" And that
ended up pivoting us around to cloud security.
So things started to click a little bit more,
you started seeing enthusiasm. Can you
talk about just what that phase was like?
We really felt the type of questions change,
right? Silly. The call sounded like, again,
"How are you pricing this, or when can we start
doing a POV?" I think naturally, as human beings,
you have a bias to look for affirmation,
versus a bias for what you don't want to hear.
You started as an engineer, you moved into
product, and now you're marketing,
which is not a traditional path.
I had a ton to learn about marketing,
with what I knew really well, with ...
Today, my guest is Raaz Herzberg. Raaz is chief
marketing officer and VP of product strategy at
Wiz. Before moving into marketing, Raaz was an
engineer, and then, for most of her career, was
a product manager. Prior to Wiz, Raaz led security
products in Microsoft, including Azure Sentinel,
and with Wiz, moved from VP of product to CMO.
If you haven't heard of Wiz, it's not only the
world's fastest growing security company, it's
also the fastest growing software company in
history, hitting 100 million ARR, just 18 months
after founding, and then, just under five years
after founding, was rumored to be exploring
an acquisition by Google for over $23 billion.
Even more wild, as you'll hear in our
conversation, the team initially went
in circles on what they wanted to build.
And it took them awhile to actually land on
the idea that is basically the most intense
product market fit of any B2B company ever.
In our conversation, Raaz shares what
signals told her and the team that the
original idea wasn't going to work, and
that what changed in their conversations,
when they finally found product market fit, why
she moved into marketing, and what she wished she
knew as a product leader from her new marketing
lens, also, her perspective on marketing,
and what marketing people often get wrong, and
why CMOs often fail. Also something she calls the
dummy explanation. Why you need to pay attention
to where the heat is within the organization.
She shares her most contrarian take on leadership,
and so much more. This was such a fun episode,
and there's so much to learn here for product
leaders, for marketing leaders, and for founders.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. It's the best
way to avoid missing feature episodes,
and helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you Raaz Herzberg.
Raaz, thank you so much for being
here. Welcome to the podcast.
Thank you for me.
So I want to start by giving a little context
on Wiz, for folks that aren't super familiar
with the company. You launched just under five
years ago, at this point. Within 18 months,
you all hit a hundred million ARR, which is the
fastest growth rate in history of any software
company. It's faster than the two other companies
I've had on the podcast, that also claim to be
the fastest growing software companies,
Deal and Ramp. You guys grew even faster.
I read that you are at over 500 million
ARR now. I know it's also not confirmed,
but a certain company that rhymes with Loogle,
offered to buy you guys for $23 billion,
and y'all turned that down, decided to
stay private. And also, something like
50% of Fortune 100 companies are customers of Wiz.
Is there anything I missed? Anything I got wrong?
Never heard of that Loogle
company, but other than that, yeah.
Okay. Okay, great. We're going to come back to
that. What's even crazier is in spite of that,
when you joined the company, you were
employee, something like, number seven?
Yeah, we kind of started, I feel like,
the founders, and the first six, seven
employees, we just started at once.
This episode is brought to you by WorkOS. If
you're building a SaaS app, at some point,
your customers will start asking
for enterprise features like SAML
authentication, and SCIM provisioning.
That's where WorkOS comes in, making
it fast and painless to add enterprise features
to your app. Their APIs are easy to understand,
so that you can ship quickly, and
get back to building other features.
Today, hundreds of companies are already powered
by WorkOS, including ones you probably know,
like Vercel, Webflow, and Loom. WorkOS also
recently acquired Warrant, the fine grain
authorization service. Warrant's product is
based on a groundbreaking authorization system
called Zanzibar, which was originally designed
for Google, to power Google Docs and YouTube.
This enables fast authorization checks
at enormous scale, while maintaining a
flexible model that can be adapted,
to even the most complex use cases.
If you're currently looking to build role-based
access control, or other enterprise features,
like single sign-on SCIM or user
management, you should consider WorkOS.
It's a drop-in replacement for Auth-Zero, and
supports up to one million monthly active users
for free. Check it out at workok.com
to learn more. That's workos.com.
This episode is brought to you by Rippling, a
single platform to build and scale your startup
on. Rippling handles all the "can't get it
wrong" admin work of payroll and benefits,
giving you back hours every week, but it does a
lot more than that. Rippling is a game-changer
for the entire company, with tools for HR,
IT and spend, all built from the ground up,
and designed to work together seamlessly.
Just hired someone? Rippling makes onboarding
easy, whether your new hire's sitting next to you,
or halfway across the world. In just a few clicks,
Rippling automatically generates an offer letter,
ships a laptop with the necessary apps and
permissions, and even delivers a corporate card.
An employee needs to update their benefits
contribution? When they do it in Rippling,
that change automatically syncs to payroll.
CTO forgot her laptop in an Uber?
Lock it remotely, with Rippling.
Many startups I've invested in, like Sprig, Elemy
and ClassDojo, use Rippling, because it's a force
multiplier for lean teams, helping them eliminate
major headaches, and operate their business more
efficiently. For a limited time, Rippling is
giving Lenny's listeners three months off.
To redeem, visit rippling.com/lenny.
That's rippling.com/lenny. Okay,
so for one of the first 10 employees,
you're the first product manager at Wiz.
Yeah. Yeah.
And what I read is that when you joined, the
founders didn't really have an idea figured out
yet, when they landed on an idea, and it ended
up being wrong, ended up not working. Six weeks
after you joined, there was a pivot.
So the fact that that was true,
and you went from this, "This isn't
working," to boom, $100 million dollars AR,
I want to spend some time here, because I
think there's a lot people can learn here.
So let me just ask, looking back at that point
when the idea wasn't working to realizing, "Hey,
maybe this is a better idea," what do you remember
are some signals that told you this isn't working,
and okay, maybe this is, because a lot of
founders are in that stage with their products?
When we started, it wasn't even Wiz.
The company was literally officially
founded as Beyond Networks, because
there was this idea of, "Hey, we want
to do something in the network security space."
Actually, myself and the founding team, and also,
the other five engineers that started with us, we
actually all came from a background of building
cloud security products before, but this time
it was like, "Okay, we actually don't want to do
cloud security, we want to do network security."
What happened was in those initial few weeks,
it also, we started was literally, exactly, Wiz
was founded together with COVID. It was that
March when the whole world shut down. Suddenly,
everything went terribly, terribly strange on
all of us. That's when Wiz started.
So it was like, our days looked like
talking to 10, 15 customers. Wiz is a B2B
product, the buyer is the CISO, the people,
the person that owns basically security for
the entire company. So we would have 10 to
15 meetings every day, with potential customers.
At the time, we didn't really have a solid product
yet, but we had an idea, and the deck explaining
our idea, and what we're going to build, and why.
We were all a very technical group of people, and
especially, our founding team, a staff, our CEO
at Wiz. Before Wiz, he led the entire division of
all of the Microsoft cloud security products. So
they're very, very impressive, very technical,
very well known and respected in the industry.
And so, we would join a call, and kind of
present and walk through our idea, and the
person on the other end would be like, "Oh, it
sounds interesting. Oh yes, sounds interesting,
we'd love to hear more. Yes, perfect. Sounds
interesting, we'd love to hear more." And
you finished calls with a good feeling, like the
person said, "Oh yes, interesting, interesting."
But like you said, I was hired as a first
product manager. I sat in on those calls,
sometimes officially participating, sometimes,
even, not officially participating, but listening
on all of the calls, and I finished a couple of
weeks of that, which is a lot of calls, I think,
two weeks or something. I still did not exactly
understand what we were going to build, which was
confusing, because I was a product manager, so I
was supposed to start building it, in some ways,
go to the dev team and start building it.
And that was a point where I felt like,
"I don't know what we are talking about exactly."
Now, I really thought, "I don't know what we're
talking about. I thought they all understood
what we're building, and I thought every
customer we had in the call, understood that
we were building." It's just that I did not
understand what we were building.
At some point, it was like, "Okay,
I have to ask. What exactly are we," like, In the
details, right? Not in describing a big problem,
in a high level, big potential approach to
solving it, but what exactly are we doing here?
And I think that that ended up opening a really
deep discussion of, "Okay, wait, maybe we are
telling a bit of a broad story, and maybe the
person on the other end is not going to tell you."
They're not incentivized to tell you, "You know
what? I don't know what you're talking about."
It's really, I guess they felt a bit like
me in some ways, and they were like, "Oh,
it's a really smart group of people. I'm sure
they're building something interesting." So yeah,
interesting. They're not incentivized to
really dig, deep dive into the problems, right?
So I think that opened up a discussion for us,
and we kind of understood that we were listening
in the wrong way, maybe, that we were looking for
positive reinforcements, but not really listening
intently to signs of deep enthusiasm, and that
ended up pivoting us around to cloud security.
There's so much to learn, just from the short
story, and I want to get into what you started
hearing that made it sound like, "Okay, wait,
maybe this is a better idea." But first of all,
just the fact that you're doing
10 to 15 calls a day, you said?
That was a bit of, in some weird way ...
Again, Wiz was founded in that terrible March,
where the world closed down. It seemed,
at the time, a really bad time to start a
company. Markets were frozen, and everything.
Even my mom, which knows nothing about what
exactly I do or why, I mean, I left Microsoft to
join Wiz, even my mom was calling me and telling
me, "This is not a good time to join a startup."
But it ended up being in some ways, like an
advantage, because everybody were home. Suddenly,
everybody were home, no meetings, no travel.
So suddenly, C-Sales, which are busy people,
and we started, originally based in Tel Aviv,
so we couldn't even fly, but suddenly,
it didn't matter. Because, I mean,
everybody's home. So yeah, we took
10-15 calls a day, back to back to back.
I think that alone is a really important
lesson of just, that's how you discover
something that isn't working/find the thing
that is working is, do many, many calls.
That is a lot of calls. I don't even know
how someone has time to do 10 to 15 calls
a day. But again, I think that's how you
do this. So I think that alone is a really
important lesson for folks to take away.
I love this point, that people are going
to try to be nice to you, especially
if they think you're really smart,
and especially if you're describing
things that might be helpful to them,
but what you're sharing is, you need
to not trust, that often is deceiving.
Talk about what it felt when it moved from
just, "Oh, this is cool, this is nice,
and maybe let's talk more," to, "Oh, maybe
this is actually something they'll buy."
We really felt the type of questions change.
Suddenly, the call didn't end, was like, "Oh,
this sounds super interesting. Sure, please
update me. I'd love to hear more." Certainly,
the call sounded like, "Wait, again, how are
you pricing this? How much will this cost?" Or,
"Wait? When can we start doing a POV? How
long is a POV?" Or somebody would finish
the call, and be like, "Okay, I know exactly
who I need to connect you to in my team."
Those are really strong indications that are
the type of indications we learned to look
for. Although there's something I think,
at the beginning of a company, it's very
scary. I think naturally, as human beings, you
want to get affirmation from the other side.
So you're actually, you have a
bias to look for affirmation,
versus a bias to look for what you don't want
to hear. That's just natural, being a person.
So I felt like, that is what we ended
up really being in tune with. "No,
I have to understand. They're intently
interested. They want to connect me to
somebody. They want to know how much this costs."
If somebody just tells you, like you said,
"Oh, super cool, yeah, I want to take
this as a good sign, but I shouldn't."
It's almost like you need to see them pushing
for the next step is what I'm hearing is,
"Let's do a POV, what's the next step to do
this? I want to connect you to this person, to
talk further about this," versus just, "Oh yeah,
this is awesome. Thank you." And then, okay, bye.
Yeah, exactly. And also, in B2B, that
is really the process you have to take,
after you have to get connected to the
actual team that will test the tools,
will deploy it. There needs to be
real passion about doing something,
and I guess that is the difference. It's real
passion about, "Hey, I want this right now."
The other point you made is that you were
the person, nobody was saying this thing
that was this elephant in the room,
almost of, "What are we even building?
I don't understand what's happening here."
I read somewhere that you were like, you told,
"I need to quit. I don't understand what this
is, and I'm not the right person for this role,"
and it turned out, nobody understood exactly
what was going on. Can you share that story?
It's funny, because it's a story that some of the
founders tell, and they tell differently. They
tell, "She came to us, and she was like, we have
to rethink," but that was not my perspective at
all, right? My perspective was genuinely, "Okay,
I have to confess, that was my perspective."
I was sure that I was the only one not
understanding. It's hard to get the courage, I
guess. Sometimes, it's hard to get the courage to
say, "Actually, I don't understand." But I think
by now, in my career, it's my favorite question.
I feel like I say, "I don't understand,"
a lot of times a day. I think, if you build
a company with the right type of culture,
in a sense, then it's not a shame to say, "I
don't understand, or please explain again."
It's having that culture in place that
enables it. And I also have to say,
when I think of the founding team, and the
founding team in Wiz, Wiz is a very flat
organization, in some ways. It's not about
seniority, it's really about driving impact,
and everybody can have a seat on
the table, and voices are heard.
And I think it also reflects really highly about
them, just giving me the seat at the table,
in a sense, to be even able
to say, "I don't understand."
Then, when I'm saying I don't understand,
not actually being open to, "Oh, maybe we
have to also think again." I think that tells
a lot about the culture, even, to this day.
But it's definitely, for me, it's a very learned
quality over my progression of my career, actually
allowing myself to be more vulnerable, more easier
in saying, "I don't understand, or I don't know."
I love this lesson so much. One, partly
because you said it's really scary to
be the person that's like,
"I don't understand," right?
That puts you, that's a very vulnerable thing
to say, because you're like, "What? She doesn't
get it. Maybe she is not as smart as we thought."
That can't be easy, to be the person doing that.
The other thing is this reminds me of Tomer
Cohen, LinkedIn CPO, has this really great phrase,
"We may be wrong, but we're not confused." I
feel like that's exactly what you're saying here.
Exactly, which is why I love this question
to this day. I love it. I do think that if
something is not easy to understand, then
maybe it needs a bit more chewing on it.
I love that. Okay, so things started to
click a little bit more. You started seeing
enthusiasm. Can you talk about
just what that phase was like,
and any lessons from just that turn
to, things are actually working?
I have to say, I think the feeling, after we
made that switch, what ended up happening is
that after that big conversation that we know,
I don't understand, we ended up having, and this
never happens, I don't think it's ever happened
since. It was almost a long, five-hour discussion,
with all of the founders, where we decided to
move away from that pivot to cloud security,
which is what we really, in some ways, know best.
That's our background, that's what we did before,
and we felt the problems there was so big
and so strong, and once we started having
the conversations with the new pivot to cloud
security, the room felt so different. I mean,
it was all over Zoom, but our
room, it felt very different.
Once we found the right path, it was so
easy to distinguish it from the wrong path,
in some ways, because we did start getting
those strong signals. And in some ways,
they pushed us forward.
A customer was like, "Okay,
I want to start a POV," and we're like, "Oh, okay.
Of course. Let's schedule for Thursday next week,
or something. We tried to even postpone
it a bit, because we had to run fast."
Another learning I have from that phase was,
I explicitly remember that first conversation,
where it was like, "Okay, let's do a POV." It
was a Fortune 10 company, a really big company,
and we had a beginning of a product. We wanted to
buy some time, until we actually started the POV.
Just because of that, we said, "Okay, also we
want to really understand exactly what they
will connect to us as part of the POV," because
everything was so initial. So we put this long
list of technical questions, "What are you using
for this? What are you doing here? What are you
[inaudible 00:19:47]?" On the one hand, because
we needed to know, to actually build a thing,
on the other end, just because we wanted
to buy time, and I was super scared.
I remember studying that e-mail, and being
like, "Ugh, they want a POV. And now, I'm
going to scare them away, with this
list of things they have to do, and
list of questions, like it's counterintuitive."
But actually, it came back filled a day later,
and I remember my lesson being, "You know what?
This is actually good. I want to make sure they're
committed, right? I don't want to push somebody
into a POV, if he is not committed to me at this
stage." I mean, it's not a well-built product.
It's going to be a journey we take together,
so they need to really want it. I need
that commitment from the other side.
I'm not trying to push something on someone,
especially not at this point, and my opinion,
not ever, not even today, not even when you
sell at large scales. I'm not trying to push
anybody to anything, I really want to make
sure they want it. I have to feel that want
back. So that was another learning for me.
It's like, first of all, when it works,
it works, and you do know when it works. And the
second is, "Don't be too afraid to get the pull
from the customer." It's okay. You need that pull
from the other end, as well. Don't push too hard.
I know people always talk about, "Look for pull,"
and I love that you're describing what pull looks
like. Somebody's next day, filling out a
really complicated annoying questionnaire,
because they just want this product they've
never heard of before you chatted with them.
Now, they're like, "Just give it to me now.
I'm going to do anything you need." Is there
anything else along these lines, before we move
into your current role and learnings there?
I also think that one of the things we did
very, almost uniquely, it was, was that,
because things started rolling so fast
for us, once we found the right path,
we ended up selling before we had a seller's team.
We ended up, almost in some ways, always being
behind, right? Okay, I'm closing contracts with
people, I haven't hired my first salespersons,
I don't know what we're doing here, I
don't know how to have the conversations.
But we ended up learning so much from that,
from us, ourselves, us being the founders,
myself, closing the deals, actually going
all the way to contracts and everything,
by ourselves. We learned a lot, we learned a lot.
And then, when we hired our first sales hire,
it was also like, "Look, we sold a couple million
of this, so you, for sure, as a salesperson,
you kind of give that confidence."
So I felt like there was multiple
places where that ended up happening, just by
accident, because of how fast things ended up
happening for us. Actually, it was a really good
learning experience to do it for the first time
yourselves. I think, sometimes, when you start
building a company, you have this wish that if
you can't do something, you're going to hire
the right person, and he will be able to do it.
Okay, I feel like my message is not clear
enough, and we just started this company,
it's okay, I'm going to hire my first product
marketer, and that's going to be it. Or I feel,
we can't close a deal, because I need to hire
my first salesperson, and that will be it.
I hardly find that, I don't think we've ever
had that work for us, honestly. It's like,
if you can't do it one time end to
end, and you're the core, core group,
the chances of just bringing somebody
from the outside to solve that problem,
it's wishful, in some ways,
but it never ends up that way.
I love this advice so much. There's kind of
two parallels here. If the founder can't do it,
who has the most context and passion and
motivation? It's unlikely an employee's
going to be able to do it. And it's similar to
the selling point, that if your early customers
aren't pulling from you, later customers
are not going to have a good time, right?
It's like, the most passion comes
early. How long did you all stay,
doing sales as a founding team? How many
millions ARR, roughly, do you remember?
Oh, a couple million. I don't remember the exact-
A couple million?
Yeah.
Awesome. That's incredible. Often, the heuristic
I hear is, one or two million ARR, and then you
start to hire salespeople. Okay, that
was an awesome lesson. I love that.
I want to talk about your current role.
So currently, you're CMO, and also,
VP of product strategy at Wiz. You started
as an engineer, you moved into product,
and now you're in marketing, which is not
a traditional path, especially for product
people. First of all, why did you decide
to move into marketing, from product?
Yeah, it's not a traditional path for anyone,
I think, also not one I would have necessarily
expected myself to be on. First of all,
it's not like I had this plan, right?
In general, I myself, people sometimes ask me
about career progression, and I never had a plan
for anything. That is just, the only thing
I did was follow good people around. That's
it. I never had a plan for anything I do.
So myself, coming to Wiz was following Assaf
and Ynon in the founding team. And two and a half
years into Wiz, at that time, Wiz was already,
it was a very clear product market fit.
Our revenues were already there. We had a
sales team that was fully functioning, but at
that point at Wiz, we felt marketing was still
something we didn't fully figure out. It wasn't
working super well for us. We were at this stage
where, yes, if there was a POV, a proof of value
happening, we would win it, versus competition.
But many times, we would come to a customer, and
they would be like, "Oh, I wish we heard of Wiz,
we just signed with a competitor," which it
breaks your heart, because I know they would
have chosen me, had they heard about me in
time. So you started feeling that challenge
around awareness and marketing. So two and a half
years into the company, basically Assaf, our CEO,
asked me if I was willing to take on marketing.
Originally, I thought it was, I remember,
he knocked on my, bothered me while I was
working on my computer, and we went into
this super cold room. It was like, when
you were a fast-growing startup, all of
the rooms are always full, you know what I mean?
We went into this server room, which is freezing
cold, and I was in the middle of something,
and he told me, "I think you should lead the
marketing org now." I told him, "Okay." I was
like, "Assaf, I'm cold, I'm going back to work. I
have a lot to do." It sounded that bizarre to me.
It's not only, do they not know marketing,
I spent my life in engineering, and in any
product, it's not the go to market side,
even. I was never part of the go to
market, or I have never heard of a lead
in my life. I did not know the word "pipeline."
All of those things were very remote to me, very.
It sounded like such a bizarre motion. But that
was on a Thursday, and then, I spent the weekend,
because he asked me to, and again, I just follow
good people, and do what they tell me to do.
So I spent the weekend listening to
a ton of podcasts, talking to CMOs,
just to even understand what do CMOs do,
what do marketing orgs do in B2B companies?
Then I ended up deciding to just give it a try,
and we did not know if it was going to work. I
also don't know if it's going to work forever,
but we ended up deciding to give it a try.
I think the thing that's convinced me to do it
was that, in some ways, I really felt like if,
in the early days of the company, finding product
market fit is a major block for the company.
And then, building a sales organization
becomes a major block for the company.
I felt like we were at the point, where you
have to figure it out to scale. At some point,
of every product, people start looking really
heavily at brand, whether we think that way,
or we don't. When I buy my iPhone, I
have no idea how it really is compared
to an Android phone. I did not look
at the specs. I truly have no idea.
So why do I buy an iPhone? I just know it's
the thing to buy. B2B products, even the
most complex products, people are still people.
They still buy it, because brand matters a lot.
That was part of what convinced me that this
is super important. So if I'm asked to attempt,
at least try, because I do
think it's really important.
I love this. I love the detail of the
cold room, by the way. Speaking of cold,
when we were chatting earlier, you had this really
beautiful metaphor of heat. And where heat is
within an organization and how it shifts,
as the company grows. Can you share that?
Yeah, it's exactly that. It's like that in the
early, early days when we just started with,
I remember, I felt like the heat was in
the product kitchen. Because it's like,
everybody's waiting to have something,
people want to start doing something, right?
Then they felt like, "Okay, you start
understanding it," and now, the heat moves
a bit to the engineering side like, "Okay, build
it. Somebody wants it, build it, make it work."
Then I felt, "Okay, so we close a couple of
deals now," right? We had our first couple of
clients. Now you bring in sales, and the heat
moves to sales, because they're like, "Okay,
we have this thing, now go sell it." And
then, the heat starts moving to marketing,
in my opinion, where it's like, "Okay, we have
a product market fit. Salespeople can sell it,
but they're saying, 'Give me more pipeline
like, 'Hey, nobody heard of Wiz. Give me more.'"
So the heat moves to marketing,
at that point. That's kind of,
I've always felt like, yeah, in some ways,
I also naturally, I guess, follow the heat.
And I think it's actually more so, that they put
the best people in the places that need the most
help. Clearly, that was you, when they did that.
This episode is brought to you by Cloudinary,
the foundational technology for all
images and video on the internet,
trusted by over two million developers,
and many of the world's leading brands.
Cloudinary is the API-first image and video
management platform built for product leaders,
who rely on visual storytelling to
express their unique product value,
who are building engaging web and app experiences,
and who understand that harnessing the power
of AI to automate is the only way forward.
Gil Grossman, engineering team lead at Fiverr,
says that "our users share billions of images,
video and audio files. Cloudinary's ability
to automate our post-production work at scale
amounts to a savings of up to 92,000 work days
per month." Think bold, build big ship fast.
Let Cloudinary handle your media needs. Start
your free plan today, at cloudinary.com/lenny.
I asked one of your board members, Shardul
Shah, what to ask you. He's a partner at Index
Ventures, and here's what he told me,
speaking of this move to marketing.
He said that when you were in your first
board meeting, the Wiz board meeting,
presenting marketing, and sharing your plan,
and you asked him, "Hey, can you introduce me
to all these marketing leaders, so I can learn
from them," he basically did the opposite.
He's like, "No, I'm going to introduce
all my marketing leaders to you,
because I think they need to learn from
you." Why do you think that's the case?
I think Shardul is very kind. I deeply
remember that meeting, because funny enough,
it was my first board meeting ever. That is
a funny thing by itself, because Wiz's board,
we have Shardul on our board, we have
Doug Leon, and we have Jeff from Insights.
It's almost like, it's very humbling to sit down
in front of those people, period. And since I
decided to take marketing, and I took to the CMO
role, this was also my first board meeting ever.
And also, it was the meeting where it's, in
some ways, I was not that. I was like, "Okay,
we took our product manager person,
she was never a CMO at any company,
and now she has a CMO here." So it was just very,
the whole setting was very stressful for me.
I just ended up, it was like, I think we just
had the meeting two months after I took over
marketing. So it was more of an update of, "Hey,
those are the changes I've made, and this is how
I'm thinking of approaching this, and this is
all the things I've done in the past two months."
It's funny, because I'm a very non-traditional
marketer, just because I really don't know
marketing. At this point, I kind of know already,
because I've been doing it for two years,
and I read a lot, but at that point, I generally
did not know. I could not even explain to you how
untraditional my approach was, in some ways.
I just really did what I thought. I mean,
I had a ton to learn about marketing, but
what I knew really well was the problem
we solved, and I really knew our audience.
I myself, I come from security, I come from
cloud security, I read all of the right Twitters,
and I follow all of the right people on Twitter,
and I read all of the right blogs.
I know it's funny, I know what matters,
I know it's interesting right now, generally
because, this is my space. I mean, I live in
that space, truly, as a customer. So I was just
thinking, "Okay, what are things I could do,
to start fixing the problem that mattered most?"
And that was, nobody heard of Wiz at that time.
Those were just, I was saying, "Okay, I think,
in order to do that, I'm willing to take chances,
I'll just focus on making a lot of noise." And
I think, even in that short time of two months,
we saw changes happening already, in some ways.
So I think, that what's Shardul meant by that, of
course, although I do think he's being very, very
kind, and I have learned a lot from many, many
marketing people, including my own team, by the
way, which is another interesting thing., right?
I took over a large team, of people who
are marketers, and I'm this person knows
nothing about marketing, but will now manage
this. So I learned a lot from many marketers,
including my own exceptional team.
But I think he meant, really looking
at it differently, just thinking, "Okay, what
is the end to the goal of having the right
people hear the right thing about my company,
ASAP," versus a ton of traditional aspects,
of building pipelines and different things they
really did not know how to do, at that time.
So following that thread, I'm curious,
what is it that you think CMOs mistake,
or often do wrong? Why do you think CMOs often
don't work out, and they brought in someone like
you, with this very fresh perspective?
Where do you think folks often go wrong?
First of all, I think CMO is a very, very
hard role. And also, I think it's a role
that is very hard to do without a lot of
trust, and without a deep connection to
the founding team. Everything you
do in marketing is very visible,
and you're kind of touching something that
matters so deeply to the founding team,
and you are the one representing it to the world.
So it's very hard to build that trust,
and it's very easy to break it, because
one bad ad, or something that one of
the founding team will say, "Oh, this is not
us, this is not what I mean, this is not the
right thing," it breaks the trust really easily.
And I think it's especially challenging. I mean,
I really don't know how somebody that does
not come from from a security background
could be successful deeply, in this type of
a role, for a company like Wiz, because it is
really about understanding your customers,
and it is really about understanding your
product. I think that's very, very hard to gain.
So I guess I would say, I think it's the deep
trust you need with the founding team, and the
really deep connection you need to the product,
and to the market. I think both of that,
when you come from the outside, in a way,
because you are not part of the founding team,
and also, you maybe come from outside the market,
sometimes, because it's a very technical
market or it's a very different domain,
then I think it's two really big challenges.
I'm not saying you can't come over them,
but I think, it's just a very, very hard job. On
top of that, it's a very diverse job. When I was
a product manager, I managed product managers.
I know exactly what they like, what they don't
like. That's my audience, I know who to hire. I
have the best network, I know every single PM and
security around me. It's so different.
When you are a marketing leader,
you manage performance marketing, which is a
numbers game. You manage designers and brand,
and then you manage events and field. There's
nothing in between those things that is deeply
correlated. Sp it's just a very, very
challenging and very interesting role.
This trust point is so interesting,
especially based on what you said earlier,
where what you want it to do is create noise,
take some risks. That's extra hard, if you're
not someone that the founding team trusts.
Can you share some of the things you did
that helped create noise, and get the Wiz name
out there, that might inspire folks of like,
"Oh, that was really cool, we
should do something like that?"
Yeah. Another insight I had about
marketing in the early days was how
different it is from product. As a product
manager, I was always, and still believe,
it's so important to think really hard
about everything you add. Less is more.
If you decide to build a feature in a product,
then A, you're taking engineering time,
which is the most valuable resource in every
company, in my opinion, and B, in some ways,
you can never take it back. It's complicated
your product. Even if one customer likes it
and uses it, at least at B2B, you're never
going to be able to suddenly take it away.
Every new feature you add to your product, you'll
have to think about, "Okay, how does it work with
that feature?" So it's like making a mistake,
adding something to the product that is not
the right thing, or that is not truly, truly
what your customer needed, even if it's what
they asked for. But if it's not what they truly
needed, it has a huge cost associated with it.
Marketing is quite the opposite, in my opinion.
There's no cost to anything, no maintenance to
anything, no technical depth, no anything. If
tomorrow I post a video on Wiz's LinkedIn page,
and I think that video is super funny, and
nobody likes that video, nothing happened.
Tomorrow, I'll post a different
video, no maintenance, bye-bye,
forgot it ever happened. In some ways, it
dawned on me how opposite those things were,
and I was like, "Okay, we have to just use
it to our advantage. Let's try everything,
let's try everything. I'm trying to make noise."
It was right before, when I took over, it was
before RSA. RSA is the Super Bowl of security
companies. So it's where every vendor's come to
showcase, and all of our buyers are there,
and you know how those conferences go. You
pay for having a space assigned to you, and it's
a very expensive space to assign to yourself.
And we had the exact same spot we
had the year before. I said, "Okay,
it's a booth at a conference. I'll just make
it the weirdest booth ever, because my goal is
just having people look and be like, 'Oh, what is
Wiz, right? Because they've never heard of me."
Instead of doing a classical cyber
booth, I decided to say, "Okay,
let's scrap our booth, and do a Wiz of Oz booth,"
which literally looked like a Wiz of Oz booth,
and we had actors, like Dorothy, and
all those things hanging around there.
It looked nothing like any booths in the show,
which is a cybersecurity show, things are red
and black, and people with hoodies. And we
decided to take a completely opposite approach.
In general, I also decided that we're
going to take a completely opposite
approach was brand. I wanted Wiz's brand
to, again, my first motive, stand out.
I wanted Wiz to have a very positive, optimistic
type of brand. So I went all in on, "Scrap
whatever we were doing before, which was dark,
and go pink, go bright blue, always go optimistic,
and focused on magic, not scaring people from
the facts, but magic." And that ended up,
and it was scary, don't get me wrong.
Half of me was like, I remember feeling
so scared walking to the show, to the floor
trade. Because I was like, "Is this going to
be the most terrible, bizarre? Are people going
to be like, 'What is she thinking?'" So I knew
it could either be a failure, or a hit.
And it ended up, the amount of people
that stopped by our booth was five times
the amount of people that stopped by the
year before. It's the exact same space, the exact
same investment, because you invest in the space.
But also, ever since we do themed booths,
every time, we change themes to keep it
fun. At this point, you won't see other cyber
companies even doing themes. We were just,
"Okay, we'll do whatever it takes to make
noise," and this is just one example.
That is an amazing story. You said that other
companies now try to do something similar,
right? Oh, man. So along these lines, when
we were chatting earlier, you shared that
you kind of have this mindset of being very
okay with failing, that's a core part of you.
And it feels like, that comes up again
and again in the stories you share,
where you just try stuff, and
you're okay if it doesn't work
out. Can you just talk about that
part, and why that's so important?
Almost every single thing I've done in
my career, in some ways, even before,
I never thought I was going to be successful
in it. I guess there's a lot of times,
it's a lot of talk about being more confident
than yourself. I don't know, at least for me,
I don't really know if that's a real option, okay?
I just know that I'm kind of okay with being
pretty sure I'm going to fail at something,
and still attempting it. That is the thing
that has grown in me where, when I took the
job, it was, I was sure, I was sure they got
confused, that they offered to take me with him.
I was certain that it's going to be like, "Okay,
they're going to figure out that I'm not the right
fit for that super smart and talented group of
people," who have all worked together before, by
the way, I was sure they're going to find me out.
And I was pretty sure I was going to fail,
but I will still take it. I thought I was
going to fill the product manager role,
too, although I did have the experience.
So that also makes it easier to move, in some
ways. If I think I'm going to fail with anything,
I'm like, "Okay, whatever, I'll
try," and I think over time, yeah,
it releases you a bit. Sure, I might fail.
By the way, I might still fail. It's also
fine. Even in my current role, probably not for
every scale, it'll make sense for me to do it,
but that's also fine. It's still just
giving yourself the opportunity to fail.
That is really empowering. Is there
anything that helps you build that skill,
that's not natural to a lot of people,
being okay with failure, and leaning
into things that they think they'll probably
fail at? Where did that come from, for you?
Yeah, depending on what you believe in,
everything comes from childhood. In some ways,
I do think it has to do with, I think the way
my mom raised me, my mom really believed that
if you're good at something, so that's not
where you should invest your energy. She
really believed in pushing us to the places
where we were less confident in, I guess.
I mean, I was a very shy kid. My natural
inclination, as a young kid, was to close the
door in my room, read a book. I had no interest
in meeting other kids or doing sports or nothing,
nothing, really super, super shy. And I think,
also slightly unsocial by nature, really.
But for my mom, she could have been like, "Oh,
so she's really good was books and math, so let's
focus. Perfect. Let her build up the skill, and be
really good with that." But no, she would make me
go swimming, and make me go meet other kids.
In some ways, I feel, she always used to
say that friction is good. If you brush your
teeth, and there's a bit of blood somewhere,
then you need to brush harder there. It's
that idea, that friction is kind of good.
If you're good at something already, then
you're good at something already. So it's
a bit more about learning how to learn,
how to push yourself in other areas.
I think she put hard work and courage,
in some ways, or friction, mostly,
above talent. Talent only gets you so far, but
that hard work in the friction gets you more.
That is an awesome story. It's interesting
that friction is good circles back to the
story you shared about creating hurdles for
potential prospects early on, and creating,
looking for enthusiasm, where they're filling
out these long surveys. How about that?
No, it's true. You're right. It
shows something. It shows if you do,
it's always easier to be in inertia, right?
That's why I also say, sometimes, it's like
breakup advice I give my girlfriends
over the years, where it's like, "Well,
if you decide to break up with somebody,
it's for sure the right decision, right?"
Because not breaking up with somebody
is much easier. It's so hard to break
up. So that makes it, by default, the
right decision. So it's like, yes,
where there's friction, it means
that you put something extra in.
I want to circle back to marketing/product
advice, going back full circle a little bit.
So folks that are in product, now that you're in
the marketing world, thinking about marketing,
what do you think you wish you knew as a
product leader, that you think a product
leader should be thinking more of, or maybe you
miss, that you now see as a marketing leader?
Having done products for many years, I really
did not understand the criticality of marketing,
and even of product marketing. I really did not
understand deeply enough that sometimes even gap,
between when you're in the product,
and you really live inside the product.
In the technical domain, you can sometimes not
understand how far you are from a common person
in your market, or a seller in your market. And
marketing, in a lot of ways, bridges that gap.
It's like a multiplier, but the further you
get away from the core engineer, than product,
then in order for the messages to move correctly,
they have to be crystal clear. That is something
I understood only when looking at it from the
other side. If you're on the product side,
you can often work with things that
are fluffy or blurry or gray, okay?
Somebody will ask you, "Can the product do this?"
You'll be like, "Yeah, not exactly, but it can do,
blah, blah, blah," kind of work around something,
right? It doesn't have to be crystal clear,
because you can kind of go around things, in a
way, that when you try to scale your message,
you can't. It gets lost in translation. You
have to be crystal clear, black and white.
You have to communicate very clearly,
especially as an organization scales,
you have to communicate very clearly.
Suddenly, you're looking at the product
org from the outside, in the company that scales
fast. And you said, "Whoa, product marketing,
in marketing, plays a really important role, in
being able to take that message and amplify it."
And if you are giving signals that are even a bit
gray, fuzzy, then it's not going to work, and you
can't expect them to do a good job with it, in
some ways. I really, by understanding the go
to market perspective, and the user perspective,
and the seller perspective, I suddenly understood
how things that can look simple on the inside of
that side, are very complex, when you cross over
to the go to market side. And I think learning
the difference is so, so important for product
people to understand, that they have to deliver
those crystal clear messages about the product.
Is there an example of that,
where you're like, "Oh, wow,
I thought this was good, but no, nobody
understands what we're talking about?"
There's so much. I think, for example, in our
domain, it's very, almost custom, to talk in a
lot of initials, and a lot of things in security
are, "Use initials for them." You say CSPM,
for Cloud Security Poster Management, and you
use a lot of those types of initials, and you
keep assuming that the world knows what you mean.
But then, when actually looked at things over,
from the marketing side, if you ask our product
people, engineers, "Where does our product fall
in terms of category," it would be CNAP,
Cloud Native Application Protection. But
if you go over and you look at Google, people
are not Googling that word. They're Googling,
"Cloud security solution," right?
So that's just a simple and silly example,
but it's that example, that when you live inside
something very technically inside your market,
inside domain, you're very remote, sometimes,
by accident from the buyer. So a lot of those
learnings clicked for me, only once they
saw everything from the marketing side.
You have this concept that you described
as a dummy explanation, when someone,
you just need it to feel really, really
simple. Can you add some color to that?
Yes. It's when I, now in marketing, and in
everything we write, and everything our team
produces in terms of anything, anything written
by Wiz, I keep going back to, I don't want us to
forget that we are inside our own bubble.
We go to work at Wiz every day. Wiz is a
cloud security company. We live inside our
own bubble, but reminding ourselves that
customers don't live in that bubble, they're
people in the world. Their life is not Wiz.
So every time you write something, I
wanted to not assume knowledge about Wiz,
or knowledge about the product, or deep knowledge
about the market. I'll give just a simple example.
Wiz itself is based on, part of the deep
innovation that Wiz brought to the market
that enabled the scale, was a very high correlated
signal that's based on a graph database. So inside
Wiz, we have the Wiz graph database, for security.
If you write something that says, the Wiz Graph
Database, I don't like it. Because why would a
common person know it is the Wiz Graph Database,
right? So it's making sure that every single
thing you say is understandable by anybody.
There's no reason to use complex terminology,
when you can keep things straight and simple.
Easier said than done, but such
a good reminder to always be,
is there a framework here? Are you just trying to
remember, people outside don't understand anything
we are talking about, and simplify it further?
How do you actually practice that? Because
I imagine everyone's, "Yeah, yeah, yeah,
I know. I know all this stuff," but they
don't actually do it. Is there any tips
there, for how to actually practice this?
I constantly remind myself about the
bubble. Every time somebody says, "Oh,
we haven't changed our color for
so long, or a website's headline,"
a lot of those things, for me, it's like,
you are the only one that is sick of it.
Your customers are just learning what you put
there 10 months ago. You are the only one looking
at this thing, day after day after day after day
after day. You're actually going to change it,
only they're just starting to grasp it,
and you're changing it under their feet.
It's living in that bubble, and constantly
reminding myself, it is a bubble. I'm in that Wiz
bubble, right, but my audience is not. So yeah,
it's a daily reminder. It's a hard daily reminder.
That is so funny. Okay, just
a few more questions. One is,
so there's four co-founders of Wiz. That right?
Yeah.
What your relationship with them,
how has that changed over the years,
and over time? I imagine it's very
difficult being, not a founder,
trying to have a lot of influence on
strategy and vision, and all these things.
Just, I guess, how has that relationship
changed over the years? Anything there that
might be helpful to folks, and any advice for
people in a similar boat, to work well with
founders who are also very product-oriented,
and very opinionated about everything?
Yeah, I think the Wiz founding team is a
truly incredible team. They also have a
very unique story. Wiz is actually their
second company together. So before Whiz,
they founded Adallom, which sold to Microsoft.
That's how they all ended up in Microsoft in
the first place. Even before that, they
all worked together in the Israeli army,
so they've known each other for, they've
been working together for 30 years, right?
Wow.
It's a long, long time. Well, not 30, I made them
older, like 20, 22, 22 years. It's a very, very,
very unique team, where there is complete trust
between the team members. Each has his own clear
domain, and that's why decisions are made super
fast, super fast, because, the complete trust,
and everybody has their clearly own domain.
I think the unique thing about Wiz,
and I truly think it defines their company's
culture to this day, is exactly that they did
not have to work hard, to be able to impact
strategy, and get a seat at the table.
I think that it's open, it's a very
open culture, and an open company,
that goes back to the beginning of
being able to say, "I don't understand."
They really believe in employees, and they
really believe in giving everybody a chance to
have impact. Regardless of title or experience
or anything, if you want to drive more impact,
you will get the chance. I think it's something
I really learned to adore in that team.
It's like, they will give their trust to
someone, and they will allow you to try.
And I think it also causes employees to have
a lot of loyalty, because you are given those
opportunities, and you are given that chance.
It builds a very, very healthy culture,
and I think, also, a culture that's very loyal.
Everybody feels part of what's being built here.
Incredible. And how many employees are
there? How large is Wiz at this point?
Just for folks to get a sense, if they
want to potentially join Wiz, some day?
Around 1,000 through 500, probably.
Okay, awesome. Amazing.
Okay, well, potentially final
question. I want to take us to Contrarian
Corner. I'm curious if there's something
you have a very contrarian opinion
about, something that you believe,
that a lot of other people don't believe?
We've already covered a number of things,
I think, like that, but is there
anything else that comes to mind?
It's so funny, because I don't think
we've covered anything contrarian.
Okay.
I think one thing is, maybe goes back to what
I was talking about before, but it was failing
in confidence. I think at least, being a woman
in tech, you get talked to a lot about imposter
syndrome, and building up her confidence.
I actually do think that my approach to it,
at least for me, has been just more effective.
I won't be able to build that confidence.
I do feel like an imposter, and I know
there's always those statistics about
many people feeling that way. So I think, maybe
just, "Let's embrace it. I feel like an imposter,
you feel like an imposter, everybody
feels like an imposter," It's kind of,
maybe embrace it, but don't let that
stop you from making a decision.
Maybe they will find out you're an imposter,
maybe let them find out. It's fine.
If you think about trying to go to an interview
for a company, and you start thinking, "Oh no, I
won't get accepted, they won't take me," perfect.
Let them not accept you. You think you're not good
enough? Perfect. That's on them, to not accept
you, right? Give yourself that opportunity.
And I think, for me, maybe less talking about
the imposter syndrome, more talking about just,
"Okay, but ignore it. You will never
know your limit if you don't try."
The best advice I've heard along these lines,
which is basically what you're saying, is that
when you take on a new role, you actually are an
imposter. You've never done this before,
and that's okay, and that's very normal.
Most people in a new role, when they're
promoted, given a big opportunity, yeah,
you are an imposter in many ways, but that's
okay. And that's exactly what you're saying.
I never heard it, but I love it.
Raaz, is there anything else you wanted to
share, anything else that we haven't touched on,
that you think might be helpful to folks, before
we get to our very exciting lightning round?
I deeply, deeply believe that we're
doing something super special in Wiz,
and I think the company is in such
an interesting place of hyperscaling,
but still keeping that authentic, and
I think, flat and enabling culture.
I think there's literally interesting
opportunities across every domain. So yeah,
just to say that we are always hiring for
great people, trying to make an impact.
Are there any roles or areas you're
specifically most focused on hiring now,
in case folks are listening, you're
like, "Oh, shit, I'm going to apply?"
Truly, the beauty of hypersaling is, we
are hiring across everything, but also,
if you feel super strongly about joining,
and you don't find the right role,
we'd still love to talk to you. There's many,
many things for passionate people to do here.
Awesome. We'll link to the Career page
in the show notes. And with that, Raaz,
we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
I'm ready, I hope.
First question, what are two
or three books that you find
yourself recommending most to other people?
So I focus like it was on the product
side of things. We mentioned the heat
in the kitchen. Actually, one of my
most favorite business books, and I've
read a lot of them, is probably Setting
the Table, by Danny Meyer, which is,
he owns Shake Shack, and a chain of
really great restaurants in New York.
And it's such an interesting business
perspective, from a different domain,
than obviously tech or SaaS. But there's so
many applicable lessons there, from the deep
connection to hosting, focusing and obsessing over
your customer. Shake Shack, unlike other chains,
where they optimize for you not to sit down, they
optimize for you to sit down there. It's a very,
very unique culture and unique vision, and
I've learned a lot. Some of the most memorable
lessons come from his management thoughts.
Imagine huge chains, but also very high-end
restaurants. I think it's a very, very
inspiring, inspiring book, and different,
just different from my domain, but
very applicable in my domain, as well.
And then, a second book I really like, I read
it early on in Wiz, and so did the entire
founding team, I think, the book by Netflix
co-founder Reed Hastings, No Rules Rules,
which also, I think, talks very clearly. Netflix
has a super unique culture and story, right?
Talk about pivots, they sold cassettes over mail,
and somehow pivoted to what it is today. That's
an insane story. Think about pivoting from a tech
company, to a company that has production to do,
and produces reality TV. Talk about the type
of culture you would need to truly pivot,
I think it's a super interesting read for anybody
thinking about putting strong culture in place.
I'm going to call an audible, and ask about
marketing, specifically. You said that early on,
you read some marketing books, and listened
to marketing podcasts. Is there anything else
that you recall was very helpful, in helping
you ramp up in this world, and do marketing?
Honestly, I think, at the end, for me, I
just ended up saying, "What are the companies
I feel do things really well? What are the
brands I love, and what do I love about them?"
And then, really obsessing about, what did
they do, what are their team doings? And then,
also, obsessing about the people behind
them. For example, I think Gong does an
amazing job in marketing, for a B2B product.
So it was like, "Okay, so what are all the
things Gong did?" Then I would look up every
single talk their CMO gave. So it's like,
I always backed up into it. I did not care if
it's a security company or not a security company.
I actually don't like the way most
security companies market things.
It's mostly by frightening and
fear, and I don't like it. For me,
it was just looking at brands I love,
and then backtracking from there.
I love that. We have the CPO of
Gong and co-founder coming on
the podcast very soon, so I'll ask him about this.
Oh, cool.
All right, next question. Do you have a favorite
recent movie or TV show you really enjoyed?
Honestly, I hardly, hardly watch anything. I
think The Wire is the best show ever created.
I will take that fight with anybody. But yeah,
I haven't really watched anything super recent.
The only problem with the Wire is it's so
long to watch. I've watched, I've seen it,
I love it, but it's a large commitment.
It's an hour times 22 episodes times,
I think, five seasons, but worth it.
Worth it.
Next question, do you have a favorite product
you've recently discovered, that you really love?
It's a funny question, in the world we live
in, where there's just so many similar things.
That's why. Which one should we pay
attention to? That's the question.
I'll answer a pretty random answer.
Yeah, okay.
Recently, I always go around with a notebook
and a pen, still that type of person. I mean,
I constantly walk around with
them, across office rooms, blah,
blah blah, and I always care deeply
about the notebook and the pen.
I'm a very picky person. I pick pens, I
pick notebooks, and I often lose my pens,
which is sad. I recently bought this cute
something, it's very geeky, like, a pen holder
for a notebook. I did not know they existed.
It's a very nice feature. It's small, magnetic,
and it claps into your notebook, and then you
can put the pen in it. Really nice feature.
How does one find this? Is there
a brand, or a name, or something?
I'll send you a link, but if you look,
"notebook pen holder," you'll find a ton.
Okay, cool. We'll link to in the show
notes, whatever one you recommend.
Just a couple more questions. Do
you have a favorite life motto
that you often come back to and
find helpful, in work or in life?
I think, keeping it simple. If you start
feeling like something is too complex,
or an answer is too complex, or something you're
building in the product is too complex probably,
or something in your life
feels too complex, probably,
it does mean something. But sometimes, you
just have to maybe take two steps back,
leave it there, until you come back to
it again, and you find a simple way out.
Whether it's a private feature or anything, I feel
like, if something starts getting too complex,
and you don't know how to design
it, or how to find end from start,
it does mean it's not the right solution.
It's too complex, it's not the right solution,
but sometimes, I take two steps back, and you
find it applicable to anything in life, almost.
Reminds me of the story when you were trying to
sell the initial version of Wiz/beyond whatever
it was called, early on, and it was just too
complicated. No one understood what the hell's
going on, and so I love how that circles back.
Final question. I know you can't talk too much
about this, but I'm also just curious what
you're able to share. As I said, allegedly,
a company whose name rhymes with Loogle,
wanted to buy you guys for many billions,
and you all decided to decline that, and
stay private. Anything you could share there,
about maybe why you decided to
do that, if that was true at all?
Yeah, I mean, I can't address
any specific offers. Obviously,
Wiz over the years has gotten many
acquisition offers. I can share,
that I think for us, us being the founding
team, the employees, the customers,
the board, staying on an independent path, we
all really believe that Wiz can become one of
the biggest security companies in the world.
When you look at Wiz today, and I mean,
we spoke about the unconventional growth,
when you think about it, in some ways,
Wiz addresses the biggest growing market
of security. Cloud security, cloud is the
fastest growing, cloud is such a fast-growing
market. Cloud grows 20, 30%, year over year.
We feel like everything is in the cloud,
but in reality, by estimation, only 20%,
15 to 20% of the infra today, is in cloud.
It's a really, really fast-growing state,
in a fast-growing market. And security by
nature is a bit of a market of leaders.
I mean, it's a bit like buying insurance for
something. You want to buy it from the best,
from the leader in this domain. And today, Wiz
really is that leader, because it's a new space.
Wiz is considered, I think, in many ways, and
that is also what makes marketing and brand,
not just marketing, but truly, brand so important.
Wiz is considered, I think, the cloud security
company, in a lot of ways. Still, of course, it's
our to lose. There's a ton of work ahead of us,
but that is a huge opportunity in front of
us, becoming the cloud security company. And
I think nobody thinks we are anywhere
near ready to give it up, in a way.
I totally understand that,
and again, Wiz is hiring,
in case you are inspired by what you're hearing.
Raaz, this was incredible. I'm so happy that
you did this. Thank you so much for being here.
Two final questions. Where can folks find
you online, if they want to reach out,
and maybe follow up on stuff? And
how can listeners be useful to you?
Find me on LinkedIn, and yeah, no apply. We'd love
great people who are learners, which I think is
what this podcast is all about. So definitely,
the right place to find the right people.
Awesome. Raaz, thank you so much.
Thank you so much for having me.
Bye, everyone. Thank you so much for listening.
If you found this valuable, you can subscribe to
the show on Apple Podcasts Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating, or
leaving a review, as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast.
You can find all past episodes,
or learn more about the show at
lennysodcasts.com. See you in the next episode.