thank you Jayy that's like the first time Bill Bill's kind of a a mentor of mine and it's so um humbling to be compared to him um I I'm here to talk
about your career I think your career is the most important product that any of you work on um but if you're like the
hundreds of executives and leaders that I've spent time with over the past 10 years uh you probably feel pretty alone
in trying to build your career and in some ways that was the inspiration for me putting together this skip earlier this year I left meta after a 25- year
operating career with this expectation that we shouldn't be alone when it comes to building careers we should look at Collective wisdom and in some ways
today's present ation is kind of the greatest hits of four or five things that I've learned over the last six months in particular in coaching and and and building communities for
leaders um before we get started I have to say that you know I spent a lot of time at home and maybe you do as well but because I don't have the same Pace schedules I did before my my two
wonderful dogs sit next to me and when they saw that I was putting together this presentation they really wanted to use their gen skills so saffron and
meifa are two dogs really helped me put together today's presentation and you you know if you like it you can kind of credit them um I'm going to start with a really simple question I want all of you
to think about the question of how many jobs you're going to have you know if you're like most people I talk to they haven't given it a lot of thought but they kind of think it's going to be like a half dozen or so now if you think
about it you're actually going to live a lot longer than perhaps you may realize you know I've always said that with the expectations around life expectancy
doubling every century and going up I always thought that someone of my age would live to 100 perhaps the Next Generation would live to 130 the
anthropic CEO published the statement that he thinks the number is 150 that's a long time then if you think about retirement retirement is actually a bit
of a Antiquated concept the idea that at 65 that we will stop working you know what are you going to do with all those extra years and if you think about
retirement it was based on the idea that we physically labor but all of you basically sit all day you know you don't
really need the actual physical rest bit and so what you will find is actually you'll want to retire differently perhaps pursue different Hobbies or
interests or even careers and most tech jobs and I suspect that if you ask your neighbor most tech jobs actually last fewer number of years than you may think
2 to three versus 5 to 10 so if you put the math together we're looking at easily dozens of jobs and when I say jobs I'm not necessarily saying
employers many of you transition from position to position within the same company but when you think about dozens of jobs perhaps multiple careers we need
a bit of a framework to think about these positions and so I thought about this framework kind of like a a building you know I think that there's this
Foundation phase that I think is at the beginning then there's these power years that you end up having where you have the greatest impact and then in the
penthouse is kind of that second career and if you think about the Investments you make in the foundation years it's to
find a superpower it's to diversify your strengths and experiences but in the power years you're actually leveraging
that superpower you're not broadening as much as leveraging that you care about the largest most impactful role you can get and if you think about compensation
as a leader for a moment think about the fact that this year you'll probably make the equivalent of two or three years early in your career so compensation is a hell of a lot more important important
in these years but when you get to the penthouse you might pursue Joy you might pursue a problem that you want to work on for a decade you might want a
different style of pace and so this formation is critical for you to think about how you achieve which job and then just as important you have to make sure
that each job sets up the next one that's actually why I call the property the skip so I want to talk about two
specific points on the foundation itself okay second big topic was a mistake that I think many of you are making today is
you're not thinking through the story that you're going to tell about the role you hold right now okay when I think about a story I'll be specific it's what
product are you building what challenges are you facing what opinions do you have have to overcome those challenges and then are
those opinions actually Landing are they succeeding and if they're failing what are you learning about them so this idea
of product challenge opinion outcome is your job story now what I find is each
story that you collect is like a tool that we add to our tool chest and now down the road someone will ask you I have a problem
I'm looking to hire someone I need someone who can solve said problem the most impressive thing you can do is say well I have a story to tell you I have
the ability to tell you that I have seen said problem I've held this opinion I had this constraint and it really worked out and I think that the more stories
you can collect the more jobs you can open up in your power years now this same tool is very powerful for career
Management in other ways so several of you in this audience right now are probably thinking now that we're in the afternoon session you're probably thinking boy I'm not sure I should stay
at my current gig there's all this great stuff happening out in the industry maybe I should take off I get these calls probably once a week if someone's like I'm stuck in my career I'm thinking
about leaving but I'm trying to decide should I stay or should I go many of you have asked that question yourself the technique I use is ask yourself what
story you will tell in 12 months in 12 months tell me if that story is different than today's story and shockingly a large number of people will
say actually I think the story is going to be roughly the same I've been in the role for a while we have a bunch of constraints some VP is going to make a decision on what to fund I'm not sure I'll have a much better story well
that's what we call career stagnation you should probably transition but some people will say actually I don't know how good the company's going to do but we're going to ship 11 products and during that time I'm going to learn a
hell of a lot I'm like well you're definitely not stagnating when your story improves you're helping Advance your career similarly when people come to me and say I have this IC role at this hot company and I have this
management role it may be something that's not so hot which do I take I always counsel them think about the story you'll tell in 18 months after you take the role okay
now the second thing I thought about is as I've talked to most of the executives and even the folks that are on stage today almost all of them will site there
is one bend the curve role I took there's a peak roll that happened to me that sort of changed the trajectory of
my career for me it was I had founded uh three times and when Google bought my last startup I joined the Google+ team and I was
associated with Hangouts and I was associated with photos and the way I thought about my career up until that point and afterwards was vastly different it was clearly the unlock for
my career so now the question is for each of you you need to find one of these Peak roles and so when you ask folks well how did you find it the
dissatisfying answer that most people will say is they'll say you know it's kind of mostly luck and I'm like well how helpful is that then they'll say well actually when I
looked into the data almost all of it luck is sort of always predicated on your professional brand you know this professional brand is something that
almost all of you know about but you all really struggle to invest in it some of it's like hard to invest in and some of
it's just like I don't even see my kids I'm so busy with my one-on ones or not making my workouts you want me to start a podcast who has time to go to a
conference actually don't worry about that last one but the the the point is that brand is what gets you luck but brand is this long-term amorphous thing
that's hard to control so instead I ask you to think about the reputation you're building today because the reputation you're building today is the brand you'll have tomorrow
so what that means is figure out what values you want to demonstrate I suggest that in today's market being Hands-On being gritty being opinionated but
loosely held being a team player not in for yourself these are all very clear values now the question is do the best people that you work with around
yourself know that about you do you have a relationship with them can you find 13 minute meeting once a week to go and
connect with those people make sure they know what you do make sure you know what you stand for make sure they know your story because they're going to have dozens of jobs they're going to go
places they will take your reputation with you that is how all of us delivered and built our personal
brand okay two big topics on leadership pitfalls that I want to hit on okay so this is one of those personal stories you know I think almost everyone at some
point during the year uses the word burnout and product management in their own mind you know for me I have a superpower which was I could bring a lot of force to work I was highly
opinionated and I was willing to prioritize work above everything else in my life I think a lot of people that are here probably feel that way too and what would happen to me is after about two or
three years I would get to a point where I'm like I I don't know if the company sees me for who I really am I'm doing great they say I'm doing well but I'm
not getting everything I want I'm not sure I'm getting the promotion that I deserve the compensation I need the scope that I desire I'm going to transition out you know next company
comes along and the same thing happens I push really really hard three years go by sort of have it a break three four five companies went by
so I finally sat down with my therapist and I said listen I have this pattern where I give so much to work and I never
feel that I get enough back and her question was who fault is that it's kind of a tough one I was like I'm paying you and now you're making me
feel bad and I realize that I'm over investing in a relationship and all of us know when we over invest in a relation ship and we will never get the
return we need and so the question is are you overinvestigation
[Music] resentment you start to enforce those
boundaries you hold back those 10 15% because you know that they'll never be able to return the the the the kids practice that you missed that workout
that you couldn't get to perhaps that company that you could advise to Branch out so I've always suggested that you should take pressure off of your
employer by enforcing boundaries despite what they ask ask because if you succeed they will give you more stuff and then
when you get that more stuff done your reward will be more stuff it keeps happening until you find the ability to put those boundaries and recognize that
it will only create resentment when you leave if you don't do it today this is an example of one of the talks that I've given around shadows and
superpowers the superow power here is your ability to create great force the shadow is the resentment that that's creates okay there are lots of examples
of this where when you become senior what you realize as a leader is you stop getting feedback nobody wants to give feedback to you because you're a leader
at that point yet what gets you to leadership isn't what takes you forward through leadership and so when you get no feedback but but you need to change
your strengths ever so slightly in order to succeed you're in quite the pickle now what I've asked these folks to do is I've asked them to look deeply at their
strength areas and seek the Shadows you know you might be a great Storyteller but you might struggle to get in the deta the detail you know you're a straight shooter you know I I got to
where I am because I'm very opinionate and I'm very direct I'm like great now you run a 400 person organization not everyone is at your level 300 of those
400 people have never really met you you're a straight shooter they call you an that is a shadow of your strength you need to recognize that what
gets you here isn't what takes you there you know the idea of a processed person not being opinionated and creative this process of seeking these Shadows under
your superpowers is highly effective because what you realize is that since you're never going to get feedback you need a place to seek feedback around so go out think about your superpowers
think about the opposite go ask people hey because I'm a graded process do you know where I stand the answer is probably no and then you think through wow I know I need to create a little
balce that adjustment expands your leadership okay so as we wrap up I want everyone to recognize that this career
that you have though it very lonely and it gets more lonely as become leader will not always be this way you are not alone with folks like Lenny with folks
like shus folks like the properties of the skip we're all trying to find ways to connect all of you together find ways not only to help each other but also
make sure that you're connecting with as many other product leaders as you can because we're the only ones in my opinion that can help help change our industry and catapult our careers
forward now to wrap up I want you to divide those dozens of jobs and recognize that you'll probably be in your hundreds when you're still working
I don't know if that's actually true but I wish I hope it will um into these foundational roles these high impact roles and these roles that have this
joyful giving associated with it make sure that you're thinking about the story St you're acquiring today make sure they're career additive make sure
they're filled with great opinion and grit that the reputation that you're making today is your brand tomorrow make sure you tell people about what you
stand for and make sure they carry that signal going forward that boundaries will only get enforced when you realize that your employers incapable of
returning essentially unconditional effort and so that's what creates the mentality to hold back and it gives you longer
tenures find your superpower it's essential to have those high impact years but Beware of the Shadows that sit underneath it and most importantly
continue to invest in each other help each other we're all in this together and we're going to have a great product career going forward thank you very much
it's been a pleasure [Applause]