I want to zoom back to the beginning
of Salesforce. One of the most
legendary launch events in startup
history. Just looking back at that,
any lessons from what you did right
to get people to pay attention?
I'm throwing everything against the
wall. I'm looking at what's going to
stick. I am looking to try to find the winning
tactic and turn it into a winning strategy.
Your stock is at an all-time high.
I'm curious just what you believe
is most contributed to you being able
to stay on top and continue to grow.
I actually never look at the
stock. I find the stock to be
very distracting. The stock isn't the
goal. That's not why we're doing this.
AI is the defining technology
of our lifetime and probably
any lifetime. When was the moment for
you where you started to realize this?
I keep having these existential freakout
moments about AI. This is really moving fast.
As a founder, you're just like, "Goddamn, I
just got used to AI, and everyone is wanting
to work on AI in my company. Now, we
got to freaking figure out agents?"
No, no, no, no, no. That's a
mistake. You want the mindset of,
"Oh, the next thing is coming. I
can't wait for the next thing."
Today, my guest is Marc Benioff. He's co-founder
and CEO of Salesforce, which is the second largest
B2B SaaS company in the world worth around
$350 billion at the time of this recording,
making $35 billion a year in revenue, and 25 years
later, is still growing like crazy and dominating
the market. In our conversation, we talk about
leadership, AI, domain names, beginner's mind,
marketing, product, sales, the hardest moment
in Marc's journey of building Salesforce. Also,
what exactly is an agent and so much more. If
you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting
app or YouTube. It's the best way to avoid
missing future episodes, and it helps the podcast
tremendously. With that, I bring you Marc Benioff.
This episode is brought to you by Cloudinary,
the foundational technology for all images and
video on the internet. Trusted by over 2 million
developers and many of the world's leading brands,
Cloudinary is the API-first image and video
management platform built for product leaders
who rely on visual storytelling to
express their unique product value,
who are building engaging web and app experiences,
and who understand that harnessing the power
of AI to automate is the only way forward.
Gil Grossman, Engineering Team Lead at Fiverr,
says that our users share billions of images,
video, and audio files. Cloudinary's ability
to automate our post-production work at scale
amounts to a savings of up to 92,000 work days
per month. Think bold, build big, ship fast.
Let Cloudinary handle your media needs. Start
your free plan today at cloudinary.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Enterpret,
interpret, unifies all your customer interactions
from Gong calls to Zendesk tickets to Twitter
threads to App Store reviews and makes it
available for analysis. It's trusted by leading
product orgs like Canva, Notion, Loom, Linear,
Monday.com, and Strava to bring the voice of the
customer into the product development process,
helping you build best-in-class products faster.
What makes Enterpret special is its ability to
build and update customer-specific AI models that
provide the most granular and accurate insights
into your business, connect customer insights
to revenue and operational data in your CRM or
data warehouse to map the business impact of
each customer need and prioritize confidently,
and empower your entire team to easily take
action on use cases like win-loss analysis,
critical bug detection, and identifying drivers of
churn with Enterpret's AI system wisdom. Looking
to automate your feedback loops and prioritize
your roadmap with confidence like Notion, Canva,
and Linear? Visit E-N-T-E-R-P-R-E-T.com/lenny to
connect with the team and to get two free months
when you sign up for an annual plan. This is a
limited-time offer. That's enterpret.com/lenny.
Marc, thank you so much for being
here. Welcome to the podcast.
Excited to finally get connected with you
and excited to do this podcast with you too.
I'm even more excited, and I actually want
to start with something that I think most
people don't know about you, but to me,
it's almost like a microcosm of how far
ahead you look and almost how...
basically, how visionary you are,
and that's that you've owned a number of epic
domain names. For example, bill.com, you.com-
You.
... code.com, appstore.com. First of
all, are there others I don't know about?
There's a lot.
Okay.
Salesforce.com.
That all came from... I'll tell you. It's a good
story actually because what happened was I was
working at Oracle for 10 years from 1986, and 1996
rolled around like it was a snap of the fingers.
All of a sudden, I realized, "Whoa, what has just
happened to the last decade?" The decade just flew
by. It was crazy. It was a big moment for me in my
career, and I had a... It was a huge acceleration.
I went from being a kid right out of college to
working for Larry Ellison. But after 10 years,
I was pretty trashed, and so I said to Larry,
"Hey, I need to go and take some time off."
So I went to Hawaii and rented a little house
on the beach. I had done some angel investing,
and it was a cool moment where some of my
companies started to go public, including
Siebel Systems and others, and Saba Software,
and people I had met at Oracle like Tom Siebel
and Bobby Yazdani. Then, I was just fascinated at
that point with the internet. I had been working
on it at Oracle for a couple years, so I started
buying a bunch of domain names of companies that
I thought companies. They weren't companies yet.
Now, they are companies. But ideas that I thought
the names would be great companies one day and
reflected where I thought things were going.
Yeah. It's a long time ago now. It's a really
long, long time ago. I think almost 30 years.
So one of the domain names
you owned was appstore.com,
which I know you gifted to Steve Jobs,
I read in your book. Is there a story
there that you could share because
that's an epic domain just to gift?
It's a great story, but it's really a story about
my relationship with Steve Jobs. When I was in
college in 1984, I had the opportunity to be an
intern at Apple. I wrote the first native assembly
language on the Macintosh. It's a crazy thing to
be able to say, but it's true that I was writing
these example programs for this Macintosh 68000
Development System on these Apple headquarter
buildings in Bandley, Bandley Road in Cupertino
and started to have a relationship with Steve
Jobs in that... Not that I was actually talking to
him. I was like this snot-nosed 19-year-old kid,
but he's running around the building. We
have this refrigerator over here with all
these fruit juices. There's a masseuse over here
doing shots and massages. There's a motorcycle
in the lobby. There's a pirate flag on the
roof, and there's Steve Jobs running around,
yelling at everybody, and it was freaking cool.
Okay. So you can just imagine like you're like,
"Whoa, this is like I'm in a movie." There's a
lot of other cool parts of a movie too that were
going on, and it started my relationship
with him, and then I actually got to know
him then as I eventually got to Oracle. Then,
eventually, I started Salesforce, and I had this
moment at Salesforce. It was, I think, 2000,
2001. I cannot remember exactly what it was,
and we were at the opening of one of his
movies for Pixar, and we're having dinner.
There's a lot of details around the dinner.
It'll be a hugely long story if I go forever.
He says to me, "Well, Marc, now, listen to me.
You're doing so great. You've got your company,
Salesforce. If you need any help, you make
sure you call me, okay?" I'm like, "Yes,
sir. I will do that." He took out his... He had
just introduced the iPod, and he's like, "I got
a thousand songs in my pocket here. Look at this,
and that, and all that." It's this cool device.
I'm like, "That's such a cool screen. Steve."
He goes, "Oh, thanks so much." I go, "Steve,
you could do movies on there too, not just... or
photos. You didn't have to do songs." "No, Marc. I
will never do a device like that. Absolutely not."
That's a little insight into his personality that
he would never ever exactly say, "Oh, yeah, I'm
going to do the movie device that have the photo,
the phone, the this." So, anyway.
Things were moving along at Salesforce,
and so I was like, "I'm stuck, and I need
to get through my block, writer's block,
entrepreneur's block. I'm going to reach out to
him." He's like, "Come down here right away."
So, literally, I got in my car, brought a few of
my team with me, and we go down, and he's like,
"Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah, you're blocked. There's
three things you need to do right now." I'm like,
"Okay. What are they?" He go, "Your company, it
better get 10 times larger than it is now in 24
months or it's over." "Oh, okay. Yes, sir. Yes,
sir." "Number two, you better sign a huge customer
for this Salesforce automation product like Avon.
They're a great salesforce." The CEO of Avon was
on his board at the time, so that was on his mind.
"And one last thing I'm going to tell you you must
do." I'm like, "Yes, sir. What is it?" "You better
go build an application economy." "An application
economy?" "Yes." "What does that mean?" "I don't
know, but you're going to go figure it out."
It was like meeting with your guru and getting a
Zencon or something where you're... Now, you have
a puzzle I have to solve. I literally went away,
and I had all the notes from the meeting. I went
through it over and over again. Then, finally, I'm
like, "I think he wants me to build an app store."
At that moment, I went to the domain registry,
and I bought appstore.com. Then, I started working
on it at Salesforce so that we would have the
ability with our platform to build apps, and then
sell them, and that you could do all these things.
So I did all that and launched AppExchange in 2005
or 2006. We didn't call it App Store because when
we tested the App Store name in focus groups,
customers are like, "This is not an app
store. This is an app exchange. We're all
going to exchange apps and capabilities with each
other." Anyway, it rolled out, iPhone rolled out,
and then he basically said to me one day, "Hey,
come down and see me." This is maybe a year
after iPhone. I'm like, "I'll be right down."
I get down there, and I have some team members
with me. They'd heard this story before, et
cetera, and then we're sitting there like
this in the Apple Auditorium. It's not like in
a hotel or anything. I remember it very clearly
like it was yesterday. He said, "I brought you
all down here today." It's very good theatrical
performance. I could never do what he does. It's
incredible. He's got the thing, and then he says,
"And I'm here to reveal to you the App Store."
All of our people go, "Huh." They're doing break
breath, and they're all like... go white because
they're like, "Oh, Marc has been talking about
App Store for years. How could Steve even..."
Then, at the end of it... It's all over. Everyone
leaves the auditorium. They're all going out to
play with the App Store and all these things.
I walked down. He's sitting down there by
himself working on something. He's in the
corner of the stage. I go, "Hey, Steve. Can I talk
to you for a second?" He goes, "Of course." Very
generous with me. Very kind with me. I go,
"Steve, I'm going to give you a gift." "Wow,
but Marc, what are you are going to give me?"
"Steve, I'm going to give you something you
don't have, but maybe you'll need, which is the
appstore.com URL, appstore.com, and the trademark
for App Store because after that meeting we had
six years ago, I ended up trademarking these
things and buying this URL." He's like, "Oh,
it's very nice, but you know this App Store
thing isn't going to be very big. Whatever,
but thank you very much." That was the story
of App Store. It's amazing. It was a very amazing
relationship that I had with him. Very grateful
to have that relationship and dramatically
influenced me in my career and my whole life.
There's one thread that I love about everything
you shared. Here is how generosity was at the
center of so much of this, him helping you, you
helping him, just wanting to help each other.
He is a very generous person, and I'll tell
you that he never turned down anything that I
asked him to do. I have so many stories, but one
story was I was thinking about buying this house,
and I wasn't sure should I buy this house, Should
I not buy this house, whatever, and so he went...
He said, "I'll go look at it for you." So he went,
he is looking at this house, and then he calls me,
and he goes, "Well, I don't know if you should
do this or that, but this might be good. Maybe
it is good. Maybe it is a good idea."
Then, I'm emailing with him after that,
and he's very sick, and it's all very sad. Then,
he sends me an email, and the last email he sent
to me was he said... I said, "Wow. Well, this has
worked out better than I thought." He goes, "Marc,
everything has worked out so much better than we
could have ever imagined." It was just a beautiful
thought and incredibly sad all at the same moment,
and that was my last correspondence with him.
I feel like we could do
Steve Jobs stories all day.
Yeah. Oh, no, I have hours.
Yes, you can.
I have a lot of Steve Jobs stories, but-
Oh, man.
Yeah. Anyway, those are a couple of them.
By the way, I also love that he had
B2B SaaS advice here like, "You need
a big customer. You need to hire
ACVs, build the marketplace."
Oh, he hated those. He hated SaaS, and he
hated that I was doing enterprise software.
Yeah, he did.
He's trying to talk me out of being an
enterprise software executive. He's like,
"Now, Marc, what are you going to do? You're going
to go home and tell your kids that you're working
on enterprise software? Who do you sell to, CIOs?
Have you had met them? How can you be doing this?
I can't imagine a more horrible career." I'm
like, "I love it, Steve." "No, Marc, you cannot
love this. This is not great." It was really a
funny thing. He really disliked that, but yet,
he was incredibly supportive of me. He would call
me all the time. It was really amazing, actually.
Yeah. It feels like a place he was
wrong in the end here, which is cool,
cool to know. I want to go
in a different direction.
He was rarely wrong, by the way, so.
He was rarely wrong with B2B SaaS. $350 billion
of value. Who would've known it existed? Speaking
of that, so I want to zoom back to the beginning
of Salesforce and when you launched Salesforce.
It's crazy to think back to that when basically,
you were trying to convince people the future of
software was not desktop software, it was
going to be in the cloud, it was SaaS. You
had all these end of software logos. You had
mascots walking around with this no software
thing. You hired fake protesters at... I think
it was Siebel's conference. It was very hard.
I think you read one of my books, Lenny.
I know the history of a lot of these things.
Oh, okay.
It's one of the most legendary
launch events in startup history,
so I've heard of it many times at this point.
It was a crazy moment. I mean, Siebel, who was
really the enterprise software company doing CRM,
was doing a user conference. I was looking for an
opportunity to launch our product, so we hired a
bunch of actors. They were doing this event in
San Francisco, and San Francisco is very woke,
so people expect a good protest. So we got some
picket signs at Home Depot and made some signs
that said, "The end of software is near," and all
kinds of other... "No software," and all these
things. We had a lot of funny things on signs.
We were running a protest outside of Siebel that
they were in the software business, but we were
like, "Oh, no, we've got to get out of software.
We've got to create the end of software."
So we have picketers outside of the streets.
Anyway, he comes out himself out of the building
and really gets super upset. Right then,
we hit a button, and we have other actors in a
van who come out, and they are staging themselves
as news crew. So they are like KNMS, K No More
Software, and we're like... They're interviewing
the protesters. So now he thinks that it's
a media thing. He calls the police. He got
very upset. He's a great guy. By the way, I love
Tom Siebel. I think he's also one of the great
entrepreneurs of our generation. He's
just fuming, and he doesn't know what's
going on. He doesn't exactly know it's us, and
we're just having the best time. That night,
we had our huge launch event at one of the top
theaters in San Francisco. We hired a great band,
and it was really... We just had so much fun.
It was just a really great time. That was all
happened. I remember very well. It was February
22nd of 2001 or 2000, 2000, February 22nd, 2000.
I love this. I haven't heard that interview,
the reporter part of that story before.
It was crazy.
I love it, and it sounds frivolous potentially,
but I think the genius of this
that I want to touch on is-
"Frivolous" is a good word.
It probably was frivolous.
So what I imagine is you're trying to get
people to even know Salesforce exists,
to differentiate, to get the name out, and I
feel like that's something a lot of founders
struggle with. They don't really know how to
get their name out, how to get people to pay
attention. Just looking back at that success, I
guess, just any lessons from what you did right
to get the word "Salesforce" out to get people
to pay attention at all to what you were doing?
Well, it's a noisy world, Lenny, and you can see
that. You can get on Twitter. It's like... I mean,
there's a lot of noise, and how do you break
through? We have that challenge today. We're
introducing a huge new product called Agentforce.
I've only been working on it for a couple
months now. I introduced it at our Dreamforce
Conference, and that was one way to break through,
which was I took our conference and said, "It's
just going to be about Agentforce." I'm trying to
think about, "What are all the things I need
to do to get my company 100% on Agentforce,
my customers, everyone?" because I know
I have a window of opportunity here.
We're first, we're ahead. We have hundreds
of customers on this now. We're on it,
which is amazing. We've moved our whole
help infrastructure to Agentforce. We're
seeing incredible results. We've cut our human
escalation from our support infrastructure down
by 50%. We're resolving 83% of all of our
inquiries robotically. It's incredible. So,
now, how do I get that message out? How do I do it
globally? How do I find my KNMS moment where I can
come up with something that's viral and exciting?
I'm trying lots of different things. I have
Matthew McConaughey and Woody Harrelson who are
two friends of mine helping me. So they said,
"We'll cut ads for you." They have
not been together in an ad ever,
and they haven't done anything together since
True Detective. They're friends of mine. Again,
very generous people to agree to do this. We've
shot three ads so far. I put them out on Twitter
to get feedback from folks. Is this a good idea?
I am running this help.salesforce.com to show
what we can do with it. Is that a good idea?
I'm training all my salespeople in how to sell
it. Is that a good idea? I'm running
aggressive marketing against Microsoft
because they have really a terrible product,
Copilot, that I have to position against and
market against. Is that a good idea? Should
I be marketing and positioning against them?
I'm trying lots of things, and what I'm
trying to do, Lenny, is what I recommend
to all entrepreneurs. The message is really in
the medium here, which is that I am looking to
try to find the winning tactic and turn it into
a winning strategy. I don't know actually which
one of those things is going to be the most
important thing in launching this product,
so I'm trying a lot of things with that old
expression. I'm throwing everything against the
wall. I'm looking at what's going to stick. Then,
once I find that thing, I will then grow that as
my strategy, and that is what I'm trying to do.
I'm even expanding my distribution organization.
I'm trying to hire an additional one to 2,000
account executives just to focus on Agentforce.
So I'm trying to do everything I can to get
that light switch to go on where I can show
customers this is an incredible opportunity
to lower your cost, to make things better,
and to show that for the first time, we can
have digital labor, that Salesforce isn't just
managing your data, but we're a digital
labor provider. So this is that moment.
There's so much there that I love, this idea of
trying a bunch of things, looking for the tactic
that becomes your strategy. It feels like also
there's this focus of just go all in and focus
on this one thing, and then try a bunch of
different ways for this one thing that you're
focused on to win. There's also an element
of... I just had Seth Godin on the podcast,
and one of his big lessons is be remarkable.
Create something people remark about. So this
celeb-oriented ad that you're working on,
I think, is a really good example of that.
Well, that is a key thought though that
he's saying, which is you got to find it,
but finding that is the hard part, so you got
to be like... One of my friends is Chris Rock,
the comedian. So what he'll do is he just doesn't
go out and do a Netflix special with all of his
jokes. He's out there testing his jokes in
clubs and doing all kinds of crazy things.
I won't go through all the crazy stuff he does
to test his jokes, but by the time it gets to
the big Netflix special, he knows what works and
what doesn't work. So that is something that we
all have to do as entrepreneurs. We need to
be testing lots of things. We need a lot of
experimentation, and we can't be too arrogant.
I think another thing that's extremely important
is... I have a pretty deep meditation
practice for three, four decades which
is we have to be cultivating our beginner's
mind. We have to use our mindfulness in a way
to clear everything out and then get back
to, "What is my beginner's mind?" In the
beginner's mind, I have every possibility, but in
the expert's mind, I have few, and in some cases,
maybe none. So I've been doing this a long time.
I've been writing software since I'm 15. I'm
now 60. That's 45 years. I don't want to have an
expert's mind. I want to have a beginner's mind,
and how do I have that beginner's mind? Because
those ideas will come at me if I can go,
"What could work?" rather than saying,
"Oh, I know what is going to work," or,
"This is the one thing that is going to
definitely work," or, "We have to do this."
As soon as you start using words like that, you
know that you're going to completely implode
and fail. You have to say, "Here, we have to do
all these things." Like in my company right now,
we just did this all-hands call. I was like,
"There's six things I really want to get done,"
but one thing is I didn't get everybody focused on
Agentforce and really watch the energy. Number two
is I need to find more fuel in the company to fuel
this idea because this is clearly a breakthrough
product, so how do I get everyone focused on it?
Number three, where I think it's really important,
we need more distribution capability. We don't
sell through franchises. We're not selling
through dealers, resellers. We sell direct,
so I know I need more account executives.
Number four is I need to be telling lots
of customer stories. So, number one,
customer zero, me, and number two is I
need to tell you all the stories. Like,
you can see the story of Disney. I'm doing a huge
amount of AI work for them and Agentforce work.
Let me tell you the story about Disney. I need to
tell you that story, and then we have this whole
ecosystem of people around the company called
Trailblazers, millions of them, who know our
platform. They all have to become agentblazers.
The last thing is I just shipped the product into
all 135,000 Salesforce customers. So it's their
nascent, and they need to flick it on. I need to
motivate them to turn it on. These are the six
things I'm thinking about all the time. So it's
not just one thing. I'm trying to figure out what
it is, and I need a beginner's mind to assess how
do I move forward, how do I evolve, how do I
inspire, how do I motivate, how do I energize.
This episode is brought to you by Coda. I use
Coda every day to coordinate my podcasting and
newsletter workflows from collecting questions for
guests to storing all my research to managing my
newsletter content calendar. Coda is my go-to
app and has been for years. Coda combines the
best of documents, spreadsheets, and apps to help
me get more done, and Coda can help your team to
stay aligned and ship faster by managing
your planning cycle in just one location,
set and measure OKRs with full visibility across
teams and stakeholders, map dependencies, create
progress visualizations, and identify risk areas.
You can also access hundreds of pressure test
templates for everything from roadmap strategy
to final decision-making frameworks. See for
yourself why companies like DoorDash, Figma,
and Qualtrics run on Coda. Take advantage of
this special limited time offer just for
startups. Head over to coda.io/lenny and
sign up to get six free months of the team
plan. That's coda.io/lenny to sign up and
get six months of the team plan. Coda.io/lenny.
I love this idea of beginner's mind. I imagine
it's very difficult to operationalize,
especially for a company at 25 years old
at this point. Obviously, you meditate. You put
a lot of effort and focus into building this.
It's hard to do that within a company.
Is there anything you do with meetings,
with leadership, with the way you operate that
spreads this way of thinking within the org?
Well, Salesforce is now the second largest
software company in the world, but also the second
largest software company in Japan, and that's a
country where I put a lot of time and energy into.
I love going there. I love going to Kyoto. When I
go to Kyoto, I like to go to some of these amazing
Zen temples. By the way, that's one of the things
that Steve Jobs love to do, and he used to go to
these great sushi restaurants. There's a great
one in Kyoto named Sushiiwa. If you go in there,
you'll see he's signed something for them. It
says, "All good things. Steve Jobs." I said,
"What did he do over here?" He would go to this
great sushi restaurant, and then he would go
to Ryōan-ji, the Rock Garden Temple.
Incredible metaphysical temple.
I've gone there. I've gone there for decades.
I've brought a lot of friends of mine there.
Yeah. You got to clear your mind and let it
come in. You got to receive it. You need to
listen. I remember I even brought Neil Young
there, the musician. He's one of my favorite
people in the world, and obviously, I love his
music. His soundtrack is the soundtrack of my
entire life. We were sitting there, and he was so
deep in meditation, and then he started walking
around. The temple was closing, and then he was
in the zone, and I didn't want to bother him,
but I'm like, "You know, I think we got to go."
Anyway, it turned out he had written a whole
album while we were there in his head,
and he was basically transcribing it all.
This incredible creative process. Look, we're
all writing an album in our head. What album
are you writing? What music are you writing?
How are you getting into that zone yourself?
You want to be a great entrepreneur. You want
to be a great CEO. You got to clear your mind,
and you got to be ready to write that music.
That music could be your business plan,
your product plan, your product launch plan
like we're talking about for my Agentforce
product. That's what we're all trying to do,
and I use a place like Kyoto as a place to
do that also because geography is important.
Where you are matters. I know you're in Marin,
so Marin County. Maybe you can go out to the
top of Mount Tam. Maybe you go to Spirit Rock
with Jack Kornfield and go clear your mind
there, but you got to find the place to
do that and create the location. It may not
be in the office. It may be somewhere else.
By the way, you have the most amazing friends
list. All these folks you mentioned, I've met.
Okay.
I don't know how long this
goes. [inaudible 00:29:49].
They are cool. I am lucky that I've
met a lot of cool people. Yeah. I
don't know how I got so lucky
to meet some of these people.
I want to zoom out a little bit and talk about...
Every month or so, I hear about a startup,
I do a bunch of angel investing, that's
trying to basically disrupt Salesforce,
come after Salesforce. They bash your... don't
kill me for saying this, your user experience.
They're like, "Oh, so complicated.
It's been around three to five years."
We are too complicated. I agree.
Okay. I'm curious just what you
believe is most contributed to
you being able to stay on top and
continue to grow. We're recording
this today, and your stock is at an
all-time high basically even now.
Wow, I didn't even know that.
Roughly.
I actually never look at the stock.
Okay.
I find the stock to be very distracting, and I
encourage my employees also don't look at the
stock because the stock is just a reflection.
Money isn't the goal, right? The stock isn't
the goal. It's coming at the end of the journey.
It's like that's not why we're doing this. The
journey is the reward. That's also something
Steve Jobs would say all the time. Another bow
to Steve Jobs here. I think that this is really
important, and I look at myself as a startup.
I am a startup CEO. I'm a startup
entrepreneur. I'm still at the
beginning of Salesforce. No matter what I'm
doing at Salesforce, whether I'm the CEO,
I'm sometimes the chair of the board. Like, last
week, we had a board meeting. Sometimes I'm a
product manager. This is a startup, and we're
a 25-year-old, 75,000-person, $38 billion, $300
something billion market cap startup, but we're a
startup nonetheless. We have some great products,
but we are just starting. As an example, Lenny,
we are just starting the digital labor industry,
and we have a product called Agentforce, and we
are just starting. We are just at the beginning.
I want to bounce around a little bit, but
let's talk about Agentforce. I know this is,
as you've said, the thing you're most focused on
right now. It's a big bet you all are taking. When
people hear this word "agent," I think a lot
of people are embarrassed to even ask like,
"What does that even look like? What is an agent
beyond what LLMs are today?" Is there an example
you could give of something you've seen that
maybe blew your mind of what an agent can do?
Yeah. I saw it in the movies. I saw it in Minority
Report, which was a movie that was co-written by
our futurist, Peter Schwartz. Tom Cruise runs
into the Gap store, and all of a sudden, it says,
"Hey. Hey, Tom. Have you thought about this new
shirt? Look at these jeans. You bought this last
time. Now, you could try this. You could try that.
What about this? What about that?" It knew his
history. It understood him. It knew what was going
on. This is 20 years ago. This whole store changes
digitally to reflect his interest, his ideas, and
it's starting to talk to him and work with him.
That is an agent. It isn't just the agent that we
saw in the Matrix, Mr. Smith, or whatever it is.
It's someone that's working with you,
someone. That's an interesting, for you,
slip. It's something that is working with you.
It could be your piece of software in your
phone. It could be a robot that's going to be in
your home. It could be your car that knows you,
understands your preferences, has an institutional
memory of you, and now is helping to advise you.
I'll give you an example that I'm going to... I go
into UCSF all the time. I'm actually just getting
through an Achilles rupture right now, so I've
had a lot of interactions, and the hospital...
or you're getting your healthcare, getting
your labs done, getting your physical done,
getting your scans done, whatever it is. There's
always these pre-operative and post-operative or
pre-procedure and post-procedure things, and
you're getting these phone calls. Every time
I get a phone call, I'm like, "Ugh, that
probably just cost them a hundred bucks,
and we probably could do that a lot
cheaper and a lot easier with an agent."
Then, when I talk to my doctors and nurses
at UCSF, they're all burnt out post-pandemic
because they're scheduling pajama time to go
through all their digital messages at night.
It's like a lot of this could be done a lot
easier with agents and AI, and we're going
to make their lives a lot better, a lot easier,
simpler. Some of those things that they're doing,
they don't need to talk to me about what my
cholesterol number is because I got my labs,
and the cholesterol number is this number or that
number. A lot of this can be done with technology,
and then save the parts that are important for
them like when I come to see them or I want to
have a real, deeper, more empathetic conversation
face-to-face with a deeply experienced doctor.
That's a whole another opportunity for me.
That is an agent or the agent is like... Here's
an example. I had a CT scan, and you have to drink
this contrast, and then all of a sudden, the...
drink it, but they give it to you through an IV,
and then they're taking better pictures. But then,
you have to drink water to flush the contrast
out of your body. Do you think anyone called me
and said, "Hey, did you drink the water?" No,
nobody calls me to drink the water. You have
to remember. You're on your own in healthcare in
the US. So the agent is going to call you and say,
"Hey, did you drink the water? Did you take your
meds? Do you need to have a repeat lab? Do you
need to go see your doctor again?" So the
agent is going to be there by your side.
So that's an healthcare example. There's a
lot of examples that we can probably have.
There's just a story in The New York Times
which isn't about agents specifically. It was
about comparing ChatGPT to a doctor
where they tested a doctor's ability
to diagnose versus a ChatGPT directly
or a doctor plus ChatGPT. By far,
the best was just ChatGPT, removing
the doctor from the equation.
Yeah. They wrote up a clinical study where they
actually did look at, in a semi-peer-reviewed way,
that ChatGPT, in many cases, was giving more
accurate diagnoses than a doctor because the
doctor had a more bias coming in working with
the patient. So that's super interesting and
I think something that we should probably
all look at that study and think about that.
Speaking of The New York Times, there's actually
this quote I found. You did this op-ed talking
about AI. So the quote is, "Throughout my
career in Silicon Valley, I've witnessed
numerous waves of innovation, but none compared
to the profound impact of AI. AI is the defining
technology of our lifetime and probably any
lifetime." When was the moment for you where
you started to realize this where it's like,
"Oh shit, this is not just another cool toy?"
Well, I keep having these existential freakout
moments about AI, and it's happened over a series
of decades. But for those of us who grew up with
these movies like WarGames and Minority Report or
Her or... across the board or read some of these
books. One of my favorite books on AI is Ghost
Fleet. You think about, "Where are we going with
AI? Where are we going with AI?" With Salesforce,
I think about our journey, and I've been waiting
for this to happen and trying to bring us along,
especially in the last decade with the
development of our Einstein platform, and
now the development of our Agentforce platform.
This week, at Salesforce, we'll probably do about
2 trillion AI transactions. With our total
now, Einstein and Agentforce platforms, we're
definitely the largest provider of enterprise AI
transactions in the world as far as I could tell,
and I keep thinking, "Wow, this is going to
get more and more intense." One step was we had
to automate all these customer touch points.
So like wearing my Disney fanboy shirt here,
we run the Disney Store and the Disney Guides,
and there's Disney Real Estate, and there's the
DisneyQuest call center, and there's... Every
aspect of Disney. When you're a customer,
you're interfacing with Salesforce.
So that's what we've loved doing,
automating all these customer touch points: sales,
service, marketing, analytics, Slack, integrating
it all with MuleSoft. That's what we do, and then
aggregating it all into a big database where we
call it data cloud, and then federating that
data cloud to other data sources. So that's the
two steps we've been doing, automate the customer
touch points, aggregate the data, and then step
three is the agentic platform on top of that.
When you think about what's happening now that
you can go to help.salesforce.com and have your
issues resolved with that on the agentic layer,
that's amazing. Then, the fourth layer that will
come will be the robotic drone layer where those
robots and drones will then feed off of the
platform and all of these capabilities. That
vision of the future is something that we've
all had in the industry for years. It's not
my magic vision. This is a vision that's
been around. It's been the fundamentals
of computer science that we would move from
having... We'd go from data to automation,
and that is what we're all driving, and we're
driving that industry. We're going lower cost,
easier to use, and more automated constantly.
That's powerful. This is really moving fast.
You mentioned Einstein briefly. I'll
also mention my dog is named Einstein,
and I got Einstein swag once with the
socks, and I love them, so. Also, that's also an
example of you bought einstein.com very early.
Yeah.
That was another domain name that you owned.
Well, I just thought Einstein would be a great
name to talk about artificial intelligence,
and it really has been. There. You can
see him behind me right on my shelf,
on my bookshelf. I keep him back there. You see
Einstein? I think they were [inaudible 00:39:50].
My view is blocked.
Oh, I'll go grab him.
Totally. Okay. Let's check it out.
There he is. Ugh.
Show and tell Segment in the podcast.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, cute.
Yeah.
That's a big old Einstein.
That's a key part of our vision for Salesforce,
our Einstein platform was everything we're doing.
We wouldn't get to Agentforce without
getting to good old Einstein here.
Very cute. As you talk about all this, I
imagine many people are thinking, "Oh shit,
we're not going to have as many people working.
What are we going to do with our jobs? AI as
agents." I know anything you say could be
taken way out of context and just like,
"Marc Benioff says everyone is not
working," but I guess just... I know
you've said you're not going to be hiring as
many engineers next year. I guess anything
there to help people understand how the
workforce will change in the future?
Well, I can tell you about my own company and what
I'm telling my own employees, which is that, yeah,
we're going to have to rebalance some of our
workforce because you can see it in the numbers
I just gave you which is we need less support
engineers because we have a robotic support
layer with Agentforce. So that is very real,
and we all need to adapt. At the same time, I'm
hiring a lot more account executives and folks to
grow the company. So I just encouraged everybody
on the all-hands call to think about that.
Then, I just gave you the idea of healthcare.
The interesting thing about healthcare though
is that a lot of the jobs that I think that are
going to get created just... we don't have people
for, and I think there's a lot of things that we
need help with in the world that we don't have
people for. So I think a lot of these jobs will
not necessarily get replaced, and I think that...
I have a home in a small town, and in this small
town... It's very much a blue-collar town. Folks
are still working in the restaurants, driving
trucks, working in the supermarket, and working
on their homes, building, construction, gardening.
Look, it's going to be a long time before, I
think, jobs in the small town where I have a
home will ever get impacted. But in the large
town where I have a home, San Francisco, well,
then I just gave you an example where I think
that jobs will get impacted. So it'll be a
tale of two cities, literally, and I think you
will see different impacts in different places.
So what I'm hearing there is
support people trending down,
account executive sales trending up?
Right now, that is Salesforce in a nutshell.
That touches on something I wanted to touch on
also which is that you're... A lot of founders
today are very product-minded,
very product-oriented founders,
and they want to build product-first companies,
grow product-led, all these things. Salesforce,
I think, very publicly, is very sales-led, very
marketing-led, not product-led. Obviously, product
is a core part of it, and it all works together,
and all these things. But I guess just any advice
for founders that are very product-oriented and
maybe are hesitant to lean into sales, into cust-
Yeah. I would say we're not sales-led. Well,
I think let's just use
Agentforce as an example, right?
Mm.
So we're running the year, we're running this
year. This is our fiscal year 25. Okay? It
ends in the end of January next year. Lenny,
this is the year of data cloud. This was not
supposed to be the year of Agentforce. So it's
the year of data cloud. I just gave you the
pitch. We've automated all the customer touch
points. Now, we're adding the data cloud to all
of our customer implementations. We have 135,000
customers. We've implemented data cloud into all
of them. They all need to turn it on. Our teams
need to show our customers how to build data cloud
and how it's going to help our customers have a
better data structure. I almost combined "beta"
and "data" together. So they need a better data
structure, data architectures, data cultures.
Then, we had our breakthrough, and I can tell
you the story where all of a sudden, I'm like,
"Wow, this agent technology is happening
much faster than I thought it was going to,
and we are going to market now." By the time
we get to Dreamforce, we are going to take this
incredible technology. We accelerated it radically
because we bought this company called Airkit,
which is one of our Ohana... It's a great story.
Great entrepreneur have this company,
fantastic company called RelateIQ that we
bought many years ago, about 10 years ago,
stayed with us for many years, like six or seven
years, wanted to leave, and we said, "Great." We
gave them the investment to leave, invested
in the company through Salesforce Ventures,
built this amazing platform, and then we
said, "Now, we want to buy it back." Then,
he came back about a year ago, and then
it just accelerated the agent vision,
and then we delivered Agentforce production code
at the end of October. So, all of a sudden, now,
we are releasing this product.
I think it's very important,
if you're an entrepreneur, to realize it's not
just about the product. It's not just about sales.
It's not just about marketing. It's not just about
accounting. It's not just about your investors.
It's not just about your employees. It's not just
about your stakeholders. It's about everything,
so you better be ready to be an orchestra
leader. You can't just be playing the clarinet.
I think that's what you're getting to, which
is that there's entrepreneurs who are like,
"I'm just going to play the clarinet." For those,
I don't think they're going to go as far as
they could go. You want to be playing the whole
symphony, and you want to get everyone running.
That symphony is sales, service, marketing,
product. Every part of your shareholders,
your stakeholders, your customers. You have
to be constantly playing the whole symphony,
and you have to have a big mind to think about,
"Whoa, I have a lot of stakeholders in my company,
not just one stakeholder." It's not just about
product and technology. If you're going to
narrowcast yourself, you're doing a disservice not
just to yourself, but to everybody else as well.
Speaking of big mind and beginner's mind, we have
a recurring segment on this podcast that I call
Fail Corner. Where it comes from is people come
on this podcast, they share all these stories of,
"Everything is going great. We're killing it.
I've had all these successes," and people get
discouraged because they hear just people only
succeeding when they often fail. So I try to ask
guests to share a story, and let me ask you
this. Is there a story you could share when
it was a big struggle for you when
you're struggling when something
went super wrong that you worked
through and learned something from?
Sure. Well, I'll just give this example.
About two years ago, we went through this
huge transformation in our company, and there
were a lot of crazy things that were happening,
but it was a little bit like we're all on this
Airplane, and everything is going really well.
Then, something seems to be going really
wrong, and we look up front, and the two
pilots seemed to be missing. Then, the one guy
with the parachute jumped out of the plane,
and then we're all like, "Whoa, what are we
going to do?" We had to do some really crazy
and somewhat destructive things at the moment to
basically get the regeneration of the company.
One of those things that we did two years ago was
we had to architect a layoff, and we had never
done a scaled layoff before. We had to lay off 10%
of the company to save the company, and I didn't
want to do it. I mean, it's the last thing I
want to do as an entrepreneur, which is to adjust
our headcount, but we were coming out of the
pandemic, and we had just hired too many people.
Now, it turned out that a lot of companies
in Silicon Valley all did that same maneuver
during the pandemic. Things were so robust
in the pandemic that we were overhiring. By
the time the pandemic was over, we had too many
people. I mean, what did I know? It was my first
pandemic. All of a sudden, my next pandemic, I'll
know that there's an economic cycle associated
with it and an inflation cycle too.
So I learned a lot in the pandemic,
and now, we're here. Now, all of a sudden, we're
architecting two years ago this layoff. Then,
when we did the layoff, then I'm trying to
overcommunicate. I'm having all employee
meetings. It's a complete dumpster fire. It's
a nightmare. I'm getting bashed in the press,
on Twitter. Everyone is shooting at me.
It's like, "Oh, boy." If I had a thick skin,
it got a lot thicker during that moment because
it's never going to go well no matter what,
and it didn't go well but we got through it to
the point where you're giving me these accolades,
wonderful, on this podcast about where we are
today financially and from a structural standpoint
or now from product innovation standpoint,
but that's not where we were two years ago.
It was clear we had to go through a financial
transformation, which included an adjustment
of our head count, and we had to go
through a technology, and a product,
and an innovation transformation. Those two things
were going to require us to do a number of things,
and they were going to be painful. So we all
had to go through some of that pain to get the
gain that we have now, and that was not easy.
I was in shock that I was going through this
two years ago because I had already been
running the company for 23 years. Things
were going pretty well. Yes, there were a lot of
failures during that period. I just didn't expect
another massive issue to hit me. But guess what?
There're constantly massive issues coming at you,
and there's more coming, and that's the nature.
My friend, Michael Bell, is probably the best
entrepreneur I know. He says, "There is no
linear success." So what that means is that
stock chart that you just referred to, there's no
up-and-to-the-right perfect chart where it's just
one line. I don't care who you are. Apple doesn't
have one. No one has one. Okay? There's going to
be changes. It could be economic changes. It could
be societal changes. It could be the pandemic.
There's no up-and-to-the-right. If you think
it's only going to be about up and to the right,
you're in the wrong business or you have the
wrong life. Right? Hey, the monastic life is
maybe more for you where you're just out living
in that more of that steady state. Right? But
if you want more variation where it's not steady
state, the entrepreneurial life is a rock-and-roll
roller coaster, and you get ready because
it's going to be pounding you all the time.
One of these people that you described that
jumped out of the airplane speaking on the roller
coaster ride is your co-CEO, Bret Taylor. What's
interesting to me is he's also all-in on agents,
and what it makes me think about is there's
this meme of what did Ilya see when he left
and tried to kick out Sam Altman. I'm
curious just like what did you guys see
about agents being the future that you're
both so committed to this? So interesting.
Well, I just think that this idea that
agents are one of the most important
things that we're all going to work on, and I
think everyone is going to go to agents. Look,
I just heard about Google today has Agentspace.
At first, I was like, "Well, I guess they like
the Agentforce name." I love Sundar. He's one
of my favorite people in the world. We heard
Microsoft now has agents. I read Oracle has agents
now. SAP has agents. Everybody's got agents,
and good. That's what we want.
We don't want to be the only one.
If you're the only one and no one else
is working on it, you've got a problem,
actually. So you don't want to be the only one.
You want to be in a market. You don't want to
be one company offering a solution and the only
one. You want to be in a competitive market where
people are competing with you, and you're selling
against somebody else, and you're getting better,
and you're moving forward. It's like the
automobile industry. One of my favorite people is
Akio Toyoda. Toyoda-san was now the Chairman of
Toyota, was the CEO of Toyota. His grandfather
started Toyota. He says, "Better, better, better.
Never best." It's the Japanese motto of Kaizen.
So we talked about Japanese Shoshin,
which means beginner's mind. Now,
we're learning another Japanese word here,
Kaizen. Kaizen is continuous improvement,
and you need to be doing continuous improvement.
With where we are right now with agents, every
software industry is going to move to agents. We
have to just like every software industry... Well,
at least in CRM or automating customer
touchpoints, data and managing data, and building
that data infrastructure, agents. It's all
related. We're all moving in the same direction.
I'm just thinking as a founder, you're just
like, "Goddamn, I just got used to AI, and
everyone is wanting to work on AI in my company.
Now, we got to freaking figure out agents?"
No, no, no, no, no. That's a mistake. That is the
mindset you want. You want that mindset. You want
the mindset of, "Oh, the next thing is coming.
I can't wait for the next thing." In some ways,
you have to be saying, "I can't wait for the next
failure. I can't wait for the next success. I
can't wait for the next innovation." Oh,
well, that's innovation overall, right?
See, we're in an industry where technology is
constantly getting lower cost, easier to use,
and more automated. So if you're doing for
two and a half decades, or four decades,
or four and a half decades now that I've been
doing it... When I started in this industry,
I started on a computer called the
TRS-80 Model I with 4K of RAM. I was
doing a podcast recently, and they're like,
"Well, who did you sell your first piece of
software to?" I said, "Well, I sold it to
CLOAD Magazine in Goleta, California and-
For $75.
For $75, and they said, "Thank you for..." and
then they said, "Oh, that's great, and did you
send them the disk?" I'm like, "No, no. There
was no disk. CLOAD standard for Cassette Load in
BASIC. That was the command in BASIC, C-L-O-A-D,
Cassette Load, CLOAD. That was the command. So
that was the name of their magazine, and then you
would get the cassette every month with five or
six things that they had bought from people
like me." I mean, they didn't know they were
buying it from a 15-year-old kid in high school
in Burlingame High School California. But I had
written the How to Juggle thing, and they bought
it for $75. They sent me the one-page agreement,
and I signed it. Then, I told my parents, and
they're like, "What? Huh? You're doing what? Oh,
okay. That's nice, honey. Great job."
So they didn't understand. Nobody knew.
It was crazy. It was like 1979 or 1978, so nobody
knew I was selling software. I was in high school.
It was just a moment in time, but I need to
have that mindset all the way along which is,
"What is the next great thing? What is the next
great success? What is the next great failure?"
You're growing. You're evolving. You're learning
from that. That's what you want. You want to
have that growth mindset. Right? You want to
embrace that. Does it make sense what I said?
Absolutely.
I jumped on that one little thought. "Oh,
gee, yeah. I've got this now under control,
but now I've got agents, so now,
what am I going to..." It's like,
"No, that's what you want." By the way, I want
what's after that too, and what's after that,
and what's after that. That's what's really
exciting about the future. It's coming.
Why?
I want to be... One of our customers said
this, and people think I said it. It wasn't
me. I want to get to the future first and welcome
our customers there. That's what I think is... By
the way, that's what I think Elon Musk does so
well. He is like... I don't know all the crazy
things he's doing to see the future. He's clearly
doing some unusual things, but then he's like,
"Yeah, we're going to have robots in the
future, and brain machine interfaces,
and driving electric cars. All of these things
are going to be happening in the future,
and I'm going to have 10 companies
that are going to do all of them." Wow.
He's not only thinking about
it, he's doing them each.
Amazing,
Amazing.
No one like this.
Yeah.
Never seen anything like it. I don't
understand how it is even possible.
Same. Marc, I know you have to run. This was
incredible. I think this is
a beautiful place to end it.
Oh, Lenny, you're so much fun. I've been looking
forward to being on your podcast
and talk about entrepreneurship,
and thanks for everything you're doing for
the industry and for entrepreneurs everywhere.
Same, Marc Benioff.
We're all so grateful to you.
Goodbye now, and welcome.
I feel the same. Thank you. Bye. Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to
the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.