The idea behind Replit is that making software
today is very difficult. We want to make it
easier. People view this as a developer
in their pocket essentially. We have 34
million users globally. There's people
everywhere learning to code on Replit,
building startups, building
personal software, personal tools.
For people building products,
say, product managers, founders,
what skills do you see will
matter more, matter less?
Typically, you're bottlenecked where your ideas
are not fitting in because they need to be
made and they need to be made quickly. Now, you
open up that bottleneck. So now actually making
things is a lot easier. Actually, you become
limited by how fast you can generate ideas.
I think people are unaware of
just how far things have gone.
I could imagine whatever five years from
now, someone running a billion-dollar
company with zero employees where it's
like the support is handled by AI,
the development is handled by AI, and you're
just building and creating this thing.
Man, the future is wild. Today, my guest is
Amjad Masad. Amjad is the co-founder of Replit,
an AI-powered software development and deployment
platform for building and shipping software. It's
one of the fastest-growing developer communities
and AI products in the world. There's a lot of
talk these days about how AI is changing, how
products will be built, how product teams are
going to operate, which functions will be more
and less valuable over time. But I feel like very
few people have actually seen what modern AI tools
can do and have fully grasped how much you can get
done with very little technical skill now and in
the future. And so I'm going to do an experiment
with this podcast where I'm going to do a series
of behind the product episodes where we go deep on
important products that product builders should be
aware of and should probably start playing with.
In our conversation, Amjad does a demo
of what you can do with Replit today,
which is going to blow your mind. And then we
spend most of the conversation talking about
the implications of this on the future of product
development, on the future of product management,
and on the future of startups and founders.
It's a very exciting time. It's also a very
scary and destabilizing time for a lot of
people, and my thinking is the more you are
aware of what's possible today and where things
are going, the better position you'll be in to
thrive in this very wild and crazy future that
is coming very fast. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's the
best way to avoid missing feature episodes, and
it helps the podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you Amjad Masad. Amjad, thank you so
much for being here. Welcome to the podcast.
It's my pleasure.
I thought it'd be great to start with just
having you explain what is Replit? What's
the vision? Where is this going?
What job does it do for people?
The idea behind Replit is that making software
today is very difficult and we want to make it
easier. One of the reasons for the difficulty is
that it is very fragmented, so you would need to
download what's called an IDE. It's basically a
code editor. You need to download the runtime,
basically Python or JavaScript, need to figure
out a package manager to configure your kind
of open source packages, and once you've done all
of that, you need to figure out how to deploy it,
how to share it. So it's a very hard process,
and that's one of the ways where people get
stuck and never learn how to code because it
just feels like this cumbersome IT process.
And so the vision for Replit has always been is
like, okay, making software is fun, is great,
more people should do it, but so for more
people to do it, it needs to be easier to do,
it needs to be in one place, and it needs to
be learnable. It's easier to learn. So that's
the product today. It is I think one of the more
easier IDEs/ environment/deployment environment
on the internet, and I think we make it really
easy for people to just jump in even without
prior experience of coding, especially now
with the new AI products that we built.
This episode is brought to you by WorkOS. If
you're building a SaaS app, at some point,
your customers will start asking for enterprise
features like SAML authentication and SCIM
provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in, making
it fast and painless to add enterprise features
to your app. Their APIs are easy to understand so
that you can ship quickly and get back to building
other features. Today, hundreds of companies
are already powered by WorkOS, including ones
you probably know like Vercel, Webflow, and Loom.
WorkOS also recently acquired Warrant, the Fine
Grained Authorization service. Warrant's product
is based on a groundbreaking authorization system
called Zanzibar, which was originally designed
for Google to power Google Docs and YouTube.
This enables fast authorization checks at enormous
scale while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases.
If you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features
like single sign-on, SCIM, or user management,
you should consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in
replacement for Auth0 and supports up to 1 million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
workos.com to learn more. That's workos.com.
This episode is brought to you by Persona, the
adaptable identity platform that helps businesses
fight fraud, meet compliance requirements,
and build trust. While you're listening to
this right now, how do you know that you're
really listening to me, Lenny? These days,
it's easier than ever for fraudsters to steal PII,
faces, and identities. That's where Persona comes
in. Persona helps leading companies like LinkedIn,
Etsy, and Twilio securely verify individuals and
businesses across the world. What sets Persona
apart is its configurability. Every company has
different needs depending on its industry, use
cases, risk tolerance, and user demographics.
That's why Persona offers flexible building blocks
that allow you to build tailored collection and
verification flows that maximize conversion while
minimizing risk. Plus Persona's orchestration
tools automate your identity process so that you
can fight rapidly shifting fraud and meet new
waves of regulation. Whether you're a startup
or an enterprise business, Persona has a plan
for you. Learn more at withpersona.com/lenny.
Again, that's withpersona.com/lenny. What's
the scale of Replit at this point? How large
has this gotten? How many people are using it?
We have 34 million users globally. We
have a large global presence. There's
people everywhere learning to code on Replit,
building startups, building personal software,
personal tools or internal tools
of the companies. More recently,
we've been expanding to companies. We released
our kind of B2B package in July, and that's been
growing really fast. It's been really fun
to see people bring Replit to work as well.
Damn, I knew it was popular. I didn't
realize it was that large actually.
As I was preparing for this podcast episode,
there's this tweet that went viral where this guy,
Jevin, who I actually know. I know
this guy from Canada, he's awesome,
tweeted about how his 11-year-old girl built
an app in Replit. She just had an idea and she
built it. And the best part of it is someone
in the... replied to him and they're like,
"You have to launch an app. You have to host
it somewhere. You have to build a database. You
have to deploy it. There's no way to do that." And
he's like, "No, that's exactly what Replit did."
Yeah, that's what we do. Everything that
commenter was talking about, and he's
right. The surprising thing about an 11-year-old
building an app is not so much even the coding,
it is like all the nonsense around it,
and so we just abstract all that away.
I love that and I struggled with that myself
when I was an engineer way back in the day.
Oh, you were an engineer. I didn't know that.
I was. I was an engineer for 10
years. I was an engineering manager,
and then I jumped ship into product.
Wow.
I'm happy I did but I do miss that. I was not
an amazing engineer. I was a good enough startup
engineer, so this is the kind of stuff that I
would've left to use. So we're going to jump
into a demo of what this actually looks like.
I thought maybe actually before we get into it,
there's other tools that people are aware
of that help you build stuff. And so to
put a finer point on what this does and
how it's different from other things,
you may have heard of, say, Cursor, it comes up
a lot these days, just talk about a little bit
about the competitive landscape of who else
is out there that helps you build product.
Again, we go back to this idea of end-to-end
platform for making software. So that's from
writing code all the way to deploying it,
and monetizing it and all of that. Now,
every step in the process of the software
development lifecycle, there are a lot of
different tools. So Cursor is a fork of VS Code
that's made that has really awesome AI tools,
but that's an editor. You still need runtime, you
still need a deployment environment. Actually,
quite a few users use Cursor in tandem
with Replit, because Replit just
simplifies the runtime and deployment environment.
And so you have products, AI products, different
places in the software development lifecycle, but
really what differentiates Replit is that we do
everything, but also that makes it harder to adopt
for certain people. If you're at a big company,
it's very easy to bring a new editor and start
coding with it. It's quite hard to bring something
that's quite opinionated about everything from
how the code runs to how the code deploys,
but that's the trade-off we're willing to make
is like yeah, we're not going to get into the
enterprise main software development pipeline,
but we want to empower everyone to be able to
build software, and that means product managers,
designers. We have operations people, sales ops,
HR ops. We have lawyers using Replit, and so it
is democratizing the act of software engineering.
Amazing, and that's why you're here. Let's do a
demo. While you're pulling it up, you're going to
share your screen and show us what this product
can do. And the reason I am excited about doing
a demo, and this is an experiment, kind of a
new type of podcast episode I'm doing where
we're diving into specific products and what they
can do, I feel like there's so much talk about AI
and what it's doing and people keep reading
about, oh, AI can do this and AI can do that,
and I feel like not many people actually see this
stuff in action, especially the most cutting edge
stuff. I think people are unaware of just how
far things have gone and how much is actually
possible, especially when someone that knows what
they're doing is using the product. So I'm excited
to show people what is actually possible and
especially because this is going to impact the
future of product management and product teams.
So I'll turn that over to you. Give us a demo.
Awesome. So this is Replit's homepage. You
can create what's called a Repl, which is
a project. We have all sorts of languages.
You can pick from really in the hundreds,
but most recently, and this is how Replit became
a thousand times easier, is you can just describe
what you want to make. So you go on this home
page, we have this text box, and you can write
something like make me a cool app or what have
you, but a more descriptive prompt is better.
And so I asked RPM at Replit, Aman Mathur who's
a fan of the show to tell me what PMs like to
build. And so he came up with a prompt. He kind
of really crafted a great prompt. So I'm going
to put it here. And basically, what we're asking
for is we want to build a web application. You
can say what stack you want to use or you can
leave it up to the AI to decide. Here we're
saying build it in Node.js for product managers
to track feature requests on a public dashboard.
So say I have a product, I'm growing, I have a
community, I want that community to engage with
building the product. I want them to submit
feature requests, vote on them. I want to be
able to manage that. So we're talking here about
the features of voting system, feature requests.
Read a few of them just for folks that
aren't watching on YouTube to give them,
send some of the stuff in this prompt.
So a feature requests submission, so allowing
the users to add features. A voting system,
so allowing users for these features, feature
requests and status tracking, being able to, it's
like a kind of advance style board with columns
like planned and progress, so that way the admin
can kind of share with the community what they're
building. And we want it to be user-friendly
design, so make it modern and all of that nice
kind of prompty things. And then admin controls
for product manager. So as a product manager, I
want to be able to really manage this community.
I love that it builds internal
tools too, not just the front end.
Yes. Exactly. Exactly. All right, so we're going
to start building. Since this is a pretty big,
big prompt, the initial coding might take a while.
There's different styles of using Replit agents.
I often go with minimalist prompts. That's also
how I code as well. I have a vague idea for what
I want to build and iterate from there. Other
people, product managers like to write PRDs and
more descriptive things, and you can do either of
those things. The AI now responded and then said,
I'll build all of that for you. I'm going to build
up the initial prototype and you can tell me how
it feels, and then we can make it better from
there. The AI is also suggesting, adding comment
threads, implementing email notifications, and
so I can select those and it's being creative,
it's telling me what else I could build,
but for now, I'm just going to go with a
prototype and then we can assess from there.
So as you see, as the prototype is starting,
you can see this progress pane where we
can watch the AI doing its thing here.
It's created a Postgres database. Obviously,
when we're building a full-stack application,
you need to be able to save things. This is one
of the cool things about Replit. We have all
these services, storage, database. So now it's
coding, it's building the database schema. Now,
it's building the home page, and it's actually
quite fun and edifying to watch it build this,
because you can really start to learn how to
structure web apps. And if it runs into a problem
and as things get complicated, it might run into a
problem and you want to be able to help debug and
things like that, it's good to be able to have an
idea of what's going on, but it's not necessary. I
think a lot of people just don't care about the
code and are still able to build things, but we
want to make the process transparent. We want
to show people exactly what the agent is doing.
You're basically sitting there
behind an engineer on a computer
and just watching them code is
what the experience feels like.
Yeah, and actually, the way we built it is it's
a multiplayer system. So Replit has real time,
what we call multiplier coding, and we reused
the multiplayer system to build the agent.
So the agent in the code is structured as
another user of the platform. So basically,
we're both coding together. So I can go
into the files here and that's the thing
that makes Replit really cool. I think
people are familiar with some of the more
chat interfaces like v0 and others where it's
purely chat, but this is a full IDE where you
can go and look at the files and edit them
yourself or ask the AI for an explanation.
What's the limitation of what this can do
today? What can't you do? Say you're like,
you have zero coding experience, what sorts of
products can you not yet build with something
like this that might be possible in the
future? How far does this take you now?
You can build MVPs. I think you can
also start to get some initial users.
I think when you start iterating on
the product like large iterations,
you might run into problems. For example,
it's not very good at database migrations,
and so we're trying to fix that. So when you're
iterating on the product, a lot of the times,
you're actually changing the structure of the
app and that requires database migrations. And
so now it might change the database in a way
that creates an error that's unrecoverable.
And at that point, you might get stuck,
especially if you don't know how to code.
Some people will figure it out by going to ChatGPT
and Claude and asking questions and I actually am
really inspired about how persistent some of
our users are, which is really amazing. But I
think you'll get an MVP pass, the MVP where it's
a product that's working and you need to change
and iterate on it. It's still a struggle now, but
I expect over the next few months, we'll continue.
It's if you think about it's like we're building
as you were building, so we're building out the
agent so that it can continue getting better as
our users are also building their applications.
Got it. So what I'm hearing is it's really good
at building the first version and helping you
get to something that you can even have people
use. It's not amazing yet evolving from there,
using AI to help you make the product
better and better and better and iterate.
Yes.
But you can get in there if you know how
to code and take it from there, right?
Yes or you can hire someone. We
have a feature on the site called
Bounties where you can hire human
coders to kind of help you finish.
That's going to be our job for
humans. That'll remain for a while.
You know what we want to do? We want
to get to a point where the agent can
go grab a human when it runs into a
problem. I think that would be sick.
Oh, my God. It's like everything's
reversed. I love it. Oh,
I think it might be done. Check that out.
Yeah. So now the agent is asking us, is the
application running and showing the homepage?
Like it's confirming.
Yeah, almost asking us to do a QA. I'll just say
yes. So it found an error. So there's an error
here and it's like there's a dumb warning,
"I'm going to fix it." So in the meantime,
as it's fixing it, so it can be proactive,
right? Because it looks at all the errors
and things like that, but in the meantime, we can
use it. I just created an account. It's coding.
[inaudible 00:20:12] It's cool.
Let's see how it restart. Okay, we'll wait for it.
How long would you say it would take an
engineer to build this? A typical engineer?
A few days, I would say to a week. I mean, if
you're really good, it might be hours but it
probably would take me a few days. I would say I'm
like decent engineer, it'll take you a few days.
And it took how much? 5 to 10 minutes.
Yeah, and it probably cost
us something in the sense.
Wow, in terms of compute.
In terms of compute, yeah. Probably, I would
estimate it like 15 cents or something like that.
Wow. Okay, so here it is.
Here it is. And the agent was
like, "Okay, this is looking good,
completed it if you want to deploy it." But
I'm like, "Okay, I'm going to test it first."
And so currently, it's living
just locally on your local host.
Yeah. It's not local host,
it's on a Replit but yes,
it's the equivalent of local
host. Because it's really easy,
I can even invite you to this session. You
can be here with me and so it's all online.
Got it.
So let's submit a feature. So make the product
prettier. That's what a typical user might say.
So we have this here, you can upvote it. I guess I
can't upvote it because I'm the user that created
it, but created another user. You can upvote it.
But now we need to be able to move things around
as the admin, so I don't know how to log into
the admin panel. So I'm going to ask the agent,
how do I log into the admin panel? So
it might've already built the feature,
and it's not exposed in the right way.
It'll be able to [inaudible 00:22:08]
What I love about just watching you interact with
this thing, and just real quick throughout, it
feels like an engineer that is behind the scenes
building this thing like on Slack and you're just
talking to them. They built this thing, they're
like, "Check this out, I'm done." And you're like,
"Oh, okay, about how do I log into this admin
panel?" And they're like, "Okay, here we go."
Yeah. So it says, "Would you like me to help you
register account?" So it's creating an account,
an admin account for me. So it's not only builds
things, it also maintains things. In this case,
it's actually doing SQL queries. It's not
writing code to create an admin account for us.
It's insane. I want to talk about the implications
of this on product development and
product management and founders, but
what we just witnessed is somebody, I know you
do have technical abilities, but someone that
didn't have to have any technical skill, build a
real product that people can use in five minutes
that looks good and works, and you could keep
making it better by talking to this agent.
I'll tell you from our experience what
we're seeing, there's so many products
that are empowering developers. It's a very easy
calculation to say We're going to make engineers
20% better and we're going to sell it to companies
and we're going to take 10% of that value,
right? That's why there's so many startups now
that are just trying to make engineers a little
better. Our calculation is like, well, what if you
made everyone developer? What does that look like?
And so when we released agent and really made
programming a lot easier, what we're seeing is
that people, exactly like you said, people view
this as a developer in their pocket essentially.
What we're hearing from customers is that I'm
doing things I would otherwise have to go hire
a developer, but also because the activation
energy is lower than going to hire developer,
whether Upwork or other places, I'm building a lot
more ideas that otherwise I wouldn't have built.
I think it was it called the javelin's paradox
or something like that, which is when the cost of
things go down, the total consumption of it goes
up, which I'm not sure why they call it a paradox,
but the cost of electricity goes down, maybe
you would expect that the total spend goes down,
but actually total spend goes up because people
consume more of it. And so I think that's going
to be the case of software. As the costs go
down, people will just make a lot more software
to improve their lives and to improve their
work and start more startups and all of that.
So to follow that thread, what are you seeing
inside of startups or even big companies in
terms of how folks are already using this
knowing this is the worst it will be and
it will only become smarter and better these
days? How are people actually using this that
are say product managers or just non-technical
people within startups or bigger companies?
On the SMB side of things, a lot of people are
building kind of back office tools. So we have
real estate agents that have a lot of data, have
a lot of things they want to manage in their
business that building a lot of these tools, that
they otherwise would have to buy, but typically
when you buy, it's actually not exactly what you
need. And that's kind of the problem with SaaS,
like one size fits all. And so a lot of people
are seeing it as sort of a SaaS replacement for
in-house tools and things like that. And then when
you go to the bigger companies, it's anywhere from
prototyping to actually production apps to tools
as well. So we've seen product managers build,
like I said, like a v1 of an app and actually
go out and test it with users. I can't name the
company, but there's a public company that
have used Replit to test a v1 of an app.
And obviously after that sort of works, they
take it to the engineers and they're like, "Okay,
we built this thing. We think it's a great thing.
We test it with some users. Let's go actually put
it on the roadmap and build it into the actual
product." So you are instead of unblocking
product managers from having to need engineers
for everything that they want to build so they
can really build the v0 or v1 of the product.
And that's super empowering for them. We saw it
also with marketing departments like SpotHero
has a head of marketing that actually can code
decently well but use Replit to build these apps,
and they built a competitive analysis application
that looks at a competitor's pricing and makes
sure that they're benchmarked correctly. And so
it's a full stack app use database and everything
and it runs on a continuous fashion. And we see
sales engineers use Replit to spin up prototypes
really quickly. So actually someone at X,
formerly Twitter is on the partner engineering
side of things, and he uses Replit agent
to spin up applications and prototypes for
customers to see how they can use the X API.
I love this. I love these examples. By the way,
the demo, is there anything else you want to
share about the demo before we close that out?
So it created an admin account.
We can ask it with the username,
password and kind of go into it and
manage it but basically that's it.
The app's complete in terms of what we ask
for. We can send it out. I can give you a
URL. Let's actually just deploy it really
quickly to show people how you can deploy.
Maybe the show notes, we'll link
to the app, you could check it out.
Sounds good.
Okay, cool. That's amazing. So
this is deploying it onto some
cloud provider. I don't know what you use, but...
We use Google Cloud. So we
abstract all of that away from you,
but we use Google Cloud behind the scenes.
Imagine a place where you can find all your
potential customers and get your message in
front of them in a cost-efficient way. If
you're a B2B business, that place exists,
and it's called LinkedIn. LinkedIn Ads allows you
to build the right relationships, drive results,
and reach your customers in a respectful
environment. Two of my portfolio companies,
Webflow and Census, are LinkedIn success stories.
Census had a 10x increase in pipeline with a
LinkedIn startup team. For Webflow, after
ramping up on LinkedIn in Q4, they had the
highest marketing source revenue quarter to date.
With LinkedIn Ads, you'll have direct access to
and can build relationships with decision makers
including 950 million members, 180 million senior
execs and over 10 million C-level executives.
You'll be able to drive results with targeting
and measurement tools built specifically for B2B.
In tech, LinkedIn generated 2 to 5x higher return
on ad spend than any other social media platforms.
Audiences on LinkedIn have two times the buying
power of the average web audience, and you'll
work with a partner who respects the B2B world you
operate in. Make B2B marketing everything it can
be and get $100 credit on your next campaign. Just
go to linkedin.com/podlenny to claim your credit.
That linkedin.com/podlenny. Terms and conditions
apply. Let's go down this thread actually while
this is happening, just like what allows for this
to be possible technology wise? What is the stack?
Whatever you can share that enables this to exist.
Yeah, for sure. First of all, it's all
the abstractions that we built. So the
way a Replit works is the very bottom layer. It's
our runtime. So this is the operating system,
this is the package manager, this is the
language runtimes. We built a system that
is able to install packages in any language,
including native packages. So the AI, anytime,
it needs a package. I can go here and show
one of those. By the way, the AI can take
screenshots as well so that it checks it works.
So here you can see it is taking screenshots to
make sure that the homepage is rendering. Here,
you can see it wanted a drag and drop library,
and so it installed that. And so it has access
to all the packages across all languages,
including Linux and all of that. And then the
layer on top of that is the editor and the
infrastructure that runs the editor, including
what I described as the multiplayer editor.
And then we expose all of that infrastructure to
the AI. And there's almost like a new discipline
called AI Computer interfaces. So sort of like HCI
is now a ACI and turns out LLMs need interfaces
that are actually quite different than humans.
They're trying to make them use human interfaces
like Anthropic's computer use, but those are
really expensive and you need to process all this
images and video. So instead, for the shell for
example, we give it sort of a text representation
of what the shell is doing at a certain increments
for package installation. We give it a certain
tool for editing. We give it an editor tool that
when it's writing the code, it's getting feedback
on whether there are errors or not, similar
to what a human sees, but it's actually old
text just to make it easier. So that's AI computer
interface, and obviously, all of that is sitting
on foundation models. So the improvement in
foundation models has allowed us to build this.
The most important model that we use is the Sonnet
model from Claude, from Anthropic, and it is the
best model at coding. So that's the model we
use for coding, but we use models from OpenAI as
well because a multi-agent system. And so we have
models that are critiquing. We have manager editor
model, and we have a critique model and different
models will have different powers. We also train
some of our models, like the embedding model
for search is something we trained internally.
So I actually wrote about it back in '22. I said
it's going to be society of models, like products
will be made of a lot of different models,
and it's quite a heavy engineering project.
To say the least. We were talking offline
and you said you've been working on this
since 2009 when you first built the
first idea of Replit. Is that right?
Yes.
Oh, my God.
Here's the deployed app. I can send
it to you and you can use it and you
can see my request even on the logged
out page so I can register, upload it,
and log in as admin and move things around. We
can see what's in progress, what's completed.
This looks like a product. I could
see designers spending days designing,
passing it to engineering, PMs, having feedback,
engineers taking a few days to build it.
Yes.
And here's just a prompt, here's what I want.
That's right. And we can iterate on it very
easily. We can also iterate on the UI. We can say,
I don't like this or that, and it'll do a good
job. So we can go here, we can start a new
session or a new session to create an entirely new
feature here, and it'll just do the right thing.
And it builds from that code base. It understands
here's what you've built.
I want to add this thing.
Yes.
Okay.
And that becomes your history, right? This was
the v1 and now I'm working on this new feature,
and it's almost like what engineers
do in Git commit messages. By the way,
it generates Git commit messages for
everything that it does so you can
roll back as well. And so we're trying to
make it so that yes, it's for everyone,
but we're trying not to abstract too much away.
We want to build tools for you to learn to use.
And so we want power users to be able
to understand the full power of Replit
and it is really deep product. I think you can
spend a couple of years to kind of master it.
I want to talk about implications, but
I want to come back to something you
mentioned that is incredible that people
may have missed. You basically built a
computer specifically designed for the AI
agent to use that is a different version
of a computer specifically optimized
for how AI wants to use a computer.
Yeah. So there's an entire discipline called
like HCI, right? It's like how do you do that-
Human-computer interaction.
Yeah. So now there are papers about AI computer
interfaces and interactions. And so large language
models are trained on large stacks of corpus
from the internet, but they're still kind of
alien creatures. So they're not like humans, so
they have different behaviors. It's unclear what's
the best way to give it an editor. So there's so
many experimentation about what's the best way to
give it a view on what's editing, how many files
can you show it before it starts to hallucinate.
And right now, it's more of an art than science,
but it's becoming more and more like a science.
This is insane. So it's a simple way to think
about it. There's this foundational model,
here's what I want you to build, and
here's a computer to use to build it.
Yes.
How am I [inaudible 00:37:07]
Here's a computer with a set of tools. Here's
a tool to install a package. Here's a tool to
edit the code. Here's the tool to run a SQL
query and also services. Here's a bunch of
services you can graph from. Here's a database
service, here's an object source service,
here's an auth service. So you can think
about it as a bunch of external services,
the computer with a bunch of tools, and they're
all interfacing with the foundation model.
It's funny listening to this how, it
starts to feel like the fact that we
might be living in a simulation is
not as far-fetched as it may feel.
Like this feels like the beginnings of
what a simulation computer would be.
Yes. You can go really Sci-Fi on this
and it's like where is it headed, right?
Yeah.
If we give it enough tools, let's say, I can
drop it in Slack and instead of interfacing
with it in this fashion, I want to interface with
it in a totally autonomous way. So we actually
have this feature coming up where instead of me
testing it, we give it another agent. So here,
instead of me interfacing with it and saying this
is running or not running, we can give it another
agent that is actually testing the application
and then let's say interface with it entirely
through Slack. And I'll say something like, give
me Taylor Swift tickets the moment they land.
And so it'll build an app that continuously
monitors the web for when Taylor Swift tickets
land and there's an agent that's using the app
to be able to get that. And you can imagine it
has some kind of wallet or credit card. And
then the moment it lands, it gets it. What
I'm trying to say is that software, like agents
being able to do software, is how AI gets more
general because software runs our lives, runs
the internet, runs our businesses. And so the
more competent AI becomes that software, the more
general they are in terms of what they can do.
Okay, this can go in so many directions. I'm
going to bring us back to the implications for
people building products, say, product managers,
founders, how does this change, that function,
that skill set? What skills do you see will
matter more matter less? Which functions are
maybe in some danger and they should start
thinking about a different career path?
One interesting persona that we're seeing is
the CEO, the CEO of startup. Andrew Wilkinson
from Tiny is a big user. And so these people
are typically creatives. They built a company,
they hired people. A lot of them can't code. A
lot of them are designers or product managers or
something else. And you can imagine a bottleneck,
you can imagine a bunch of ideas in their head,
and the ideas have to translate through them
talking. And then someone else listening to
them and assuming that someone else
actually understands what they say,
and then that's someone else going and trying
to build what they want to build. And also
assuming that person has time, because a lot of
times, your engineers are kind of stuck building
the current thing. They're not thinking about
the future thing. And so what gets me excited
is a lot of these CEOs are building the future
concept, the next product they're going to build,
the next, say, company they're going to build.
And so it unlocks the creativity and again,
sort of unblocks them from that. And look, it's a
v1 of the product but it can push things forward.
You can touch it, you can feel it, you can say,
okay, this really has lags and we should work on
it. You give it to your engineers and they can
improve on it from there. So that's one persona
but I'm really excited about it, the CEO/founder.
In companies, one of the things that I think is
sort of hard about tech companies is these
silos between designers, product managers,
and engineers. And everyone feels that pain
of, we have low bandwidth communication,
which is language and then text on Slack and
Zoom calls. And it leads to a lot of frustration,
because it's really easy to misinterpret people
and again, leads to siloing where people working
on something, and then you pass it on to the
next team and it's not really what they expect.
That happens a lot between designers and
engineers, but the common language that everyone
shares is code. Ultimately in software tech
companies, everything that we're talking about
need to eventually flush out in terms of code. And
so what if the language becomes actually working
prototypes and working applications? For example,
we have a Figma extension that translate Figma
mocks into React that runs on Replit. So instead
of giving the engineers just mocks or screenshots,
whatever, you just say, oh, here's a bunch
of React code, just make sure it runs on
our infrastructure but don't mess with it,
don't move the pixels around. And so I think
it just opens up silos of the companies, make
communication around product a lot more concrete,
because I can give you a working prototype and
that'll change how people work, if you can imagine
that everyone can make software. It's really kind
of a radical reimagining of not just what tech
companies are but really what most companies
are because everyone can be more general.
So say you're a PM listening to
this, an engineer or designer,
what skills do you think if you were one of these
folks? If you were in building Replit right now,
what kind of skills would you suggest folks
focus on more and would you think are just like,
okay, this can be less valuable in the
future, don't worry about these sorts
of things? And you can either pick one
of those three functions or all three.
I think a very important scale that's perhaps
harder to develop but it's worth working on is
being generative, being more generative, being
able to generate new ideas quickly, because you
can think about it as a factory line. So you have
ideas, you have the production of these ideas or
the initial production of these ideas, and then
you have other people that want to consume these
ideas or work with you on these ideas. And so
typically you're bottlenecked by the middle
part where your ideas are kind of like they're a
lot of them and they're not fitting in, because
they need to be made and they need to be made
quickly. And so now you open up that bottleneck.
So now actually making things is a lot easier.
Actually, you become limited by how fast you can
generate ideas, and I find that true of myself as
well. I consider myself quite generative, but now
I have this tool and I can build a lot more and
explore a lot more and I'm finding that, well,
actually, I'm running out of ideas sometimes.
So training that muscle I think is a good thing.
I think learning a little bit of coding and
not the traditional way of learning coding.
If you go to a coding bootcamp, they're going to
start with what is Git? Actually my co-founder,
Haya, was a designer. When we're
first building the Replit together,
she went to WebAssembly to do a coding course.
And the first day, they spent this whole time
on Git and she's like, "What is that? What does
it do?" I still don't know what it exactly does,
but it's like you're inverting the process, you're
giving the tool before the actual problem. And so
I think all of that stuff, you don't have to
worry about, so things that you don't have to
worry about. I think a lot of the, as a PM, as a
designer, as someone who's not in your code editor
every day, don't worry about all the tooling.
And if you learn a little bit of coding just
by talking to an AI, doing a little bit of
debugging, building something with Replit,
running into a problem and trying to fix it
just using AI, you'll learn a bit of coding.
And I have this that's been called not by me,
dubbed as Amjad's Law, which is the return on
investment for learn to code is doubling every
six months. And really just learning a little
bit of that skill, learning a bit of skill
about how to prompt AI, how to read code,
and be able to debug it. Every six months, that's
netting you more and more power because you're
going to be able to create a lot more. It's going
to be easier to create. You're going to be able
to create a lot more complete things. So that's
another skill that I think could be necessary.
This is super interesting. Okay, so this
last point, you made Amjad's Law. It's
interesting because when people, as someone's
listening to this, I could see them being like,
engineers are in trouble. Why do you need
engineers at this point? These agents are
building the code. Your point is specific
engineering skills are going to be incredibly
valuable and more and more. How often are they
doubling would you say? Every year you said?
No, every six months.
Every six months, these specific engineering
skills are becoming more valuable. And the
idea is you don't need to know everything.
You don't need to know the foundation,
to build the app as much. It's more
to unblock the agent and understand
the mental model of how this stuff is
built so that you can move forward fast.
That's right. That's right. Understanding
the basic components of it, I would say, yes.
Yeah, so it's like we need
new engineering schools to
teach you these very specific skills
versus spending years on algorithms.
And I think no one has done that yet, and I think
this is a big business probably ready to get
built. It's like AI native coding. It's totally
different than traditional coding. That's why on
Hacker News, there's so much skepticism about AI
native coding tools, because they're like yeah,
it's a glorified autocomplete. And I understand
if you're writing operating system, kernels,
it's not really doing that much for you, but
if you're building products, it's building
it for you at this point. And so if you're
starting a school to teach AI native coding,
you would skip so much of computer science and the
basic tools, and you would teach the basic idea of
how to structure an app, and then you would teach
prompting and then you would teach, I think a
little bit of debugging. I think debugging
is quite a good skill right now to learn.
Interestingly, if you want to be good at
debugging, there's a lot you need to understand,
which is basically what you're saying is that's
the subset of things to understand is things that
break. And to do that, you have to understand how
it all works. What are servers? What are APIs? All
these things. Okay, so we've been talking
about how this is very good right now,
building a prototype, building a v1, MVP, people
can use it, you can deploy it. You deploy this
app, people can start using it, and there's a
scale it can reach. Do you see a future where
you can build a Salesforce sized business
fully Replit or other tools that can scale
to hundreds of billions of dollars of value? Or is
there just going to always be some limit of like,
you need actual engineers and designers sitting
on this thing, building it, thinking it? Awesome.
If my law is directionally correct, even if
the months are not, I'm not exactly right that
the duration is correct, you're going to see a
compounding effect of the power. It's actually
quite hard to convince yourself. But if you really
convince yourself that we are on a massive scale
of improvement in AI, then the answer is yes. And
it's absurd to my engineering mind that I'm saying
it is, but know Ray Kurzweil, this futurist talks
about how exponentials are really hard for humans
to grasp. And so actually when we started building
the agent, I told the team, it's easy and we
fall in this trap before. It's easy to build and
optimize for today. In '22, we built Copilot-like
thing and autocomplete. We train our own models,
we optimize the hell out of them. But at some
point, that modality was kind of not the right
modality, which is the autocomplete modality.
And the right modality is actually this, I
think for now, as being able to chat inside
the programming environment and for the agent
to create things for you. But in order for
us to make that bat, a year ago the models were
actually not there. The models could not do this,
but we were like, okay, we're going to build for
the models that are landing in six months. And
truly six months later, the model started to land
that are capable of this, of the reasoning that
we needed and whatever. And so that was like saw
it if you want, which is, oh, wow, we switched to
it and the reasoning improved so much. And six
months later, you have a son of you too. And
so it's really almost like a six months cadence.
And so if we're really on this trajectory, then
I would say next year, you're able to just scale
and maybe you get thousands of users paying you.
The AI can do maintenance. We already showed
the AI doing SQL queries and doing migrations,
so I will be able to do maintenance, debugging,
things like that. I think where it gets really
tough is that when you're hitting scale and you
want to architect a system that is resilient,
and so that means you would start sharding
databases and you would start using different
queue systems and components and things like that.
And I think the AI needs to have access to the
entire suite of tools to be able to do this.
And I think that's going to be the next
bottleneck. And I think the AI needs to
be a lot more reliable at doing that. But
I could imagine whatever, five years from now,
someone running a billion dollar company with
zero employees where it's like the support is
handled by AI, the development is handled by AI,
and you're just building and creating this
thing that people are finding valuable and
are paying you for it. That being said, it's
worth thinking about the economics of it. If
the cost of software goes down a lot, then what is
the price that you can charge on software? So can
you actually build the next Salesforce if anyone
can generate Salesforce? And then the question is,
and this is why I emphasize being generative,
because I think then the thing that will make
you better is by being able to iterate and improve
the thing really quickly and generate new ideas.
And stay ahead of all the other people
building these tools so quickly. Oh,
my God. An interesting other kind of mental model
I'm seeing as you talk about this sort of thing is
not to offend religious folks, but there's
this concept of God of the gaps. I imagine
you've heard that where it's like God explains
all the things that we don't yet understand.
And over time that kind of space shrinks and
God's like all the things we don't get yet,
those gaps. That was God that proves there
needs to be a God. And it feels like right now,
humans are the gaps in these tools or these
agents you talk about that you can hire
within Replit are fixing these little gaps. And
over time, AI will fix these things themselves.
That's right.
And these gaps will shrink.
Unless we hit some fundamental limit and the
current regime of AI, which I'm not an expert
about how far transformers could scale, but I
feel like we found the thing that could scale
pretty far, but maybe there are limitations in
data or other things like that that we could be
surprised by. But if there isn't, then we are on a
massive trajectory of removing these gaps quickly.
Yeah, very true. We have no idea. We keep
thinking it's just going to keep going,
but maybe it'll stop at some point. I could keep
going and going, but I think we should also let
people go play with these things and process all
the things we've been talking about. Is there
anything else that you think might be helpful
for folks to think about or learn or study?
I'll give advice to founders or leaders at
companies. The way we work is going to change
rapidly, and it's important to be resilient to
that change. One thing that I think is really
difficult now is having roadmaps, especially if
you're doing anything in AI, but really anything
that AI could affect, you want to be able to
react to it really quickly. And so when the
Anthropic drop the computer use set of capability,
we slaughtered our roadmap because we don't really
have an explicit roadmap. We immediately jumped
on it and started building things and we launched
some things around it. We're going to be doing
more with it, but there's going to be capabilities
that are going to drop. And you want to really,
in some cases, if it really affects your business,
you want to be able to jump on it really,
really quickly. So being agile, not being
stuck with roadmaps, being able to just say, oh,
we're just going to switch priorities right away,
is going to be super important.
Not being, like I said, with silos
at Replit, there's so many people that are on
the scale of designer to engineer, designer,
product manager. Actually, I mentioned Amman
earlier. He started as a designer at Replit,
and now as a product manager. We have people
who start as designers, become engineers,
and we have people in the middle and we're
comfortable with that design engineers
that fit at different parts of the scale. And
the design engineers go to the design correct
meetings and some designers go to the engineering
meetings. You got to be fluid because again,
when designers can code and engineers can design,
I mean it really becomes, you can't have a lot of
structure around that. So you want to build a
culture and you want to build an environment
or milieu that is really, really flexible,
which is uncomfortable for a lot of people.
Man, the future is wild. Everyone's a hybrid
person now. Let me just actually double down
on what you just said, which I think is really
interesting. It's almost like if you're an
engineer, where your skill set will become
most valuable is unblocking these AI tools
and knowing debugging and figuring out how to
allow it to go further and further and further.
Within PM and design land, based on what you're
describing, where the skills will become more
valuable is generating ideas, almost like finding
opportunities, discovery, finding what problems
need to be solved, and then articulating that
as clearly as possible to the AI tooling.
That's right.
Super interesting.
Yeah, this is a very crisp sort of advice
that people can follow today, I think.
Oh man, what a world. Okay,
I'm jot. This is incredible.
My mind is racing. I've got to
go build some apps immediately.
Yes, you've back. Love that.
I will do that. So just to leave listeners with a
couple things. One is just, what should they know?
Where do they find you? How do they try Replit?
Anything else other than just go to replit.com?
Yeah, just go to replit.com. It's an open beta
right now. We're kind of quickly improving and
going to exit beta I think in a few weeks. But
if you're comfortable testing something that's
not perfect, go to replit.com. If you subscribe
to our core plan, you should be able to access
the agent and start using it. And we are, I
think the place where we're most active is
Twitter. So Twitter are like X, the handle
Replit, R-E-P-L-I-T or my handle @amasad.
Oh, yeah. One other thing I wanted to make
sure we had a chance to touch on is you're
working on something new, something
that's coming in the very new future,
maybe the day this episode drops. Talk about that.
All right. So depending on when the episode is
coming out, this could be the first time people
hear about it. But we have this product
called agent. It is sort of high agency,
does everything from setting up the project
and all of that. And so now, we are working
on assistant. Assistant is let's say the cousin
of agent. It is a little less powerful but a lot
more controllable. You can focus on features or
areas of the code that you want to change and
you still don't have to know how to code, but it
is a lot more manageable and it is a lot faster.
So you saw how it took some time to kind of create
the project and code some of the things. Assistant
is in the order of milliseconds and seconds to be
able to respond to you. And so again, as I talk
about the idea of tools, we want people to have as
much power and autonomy as possible. And so there
are certain instances where agent is the best.
It's going to do the debugging for you, it's going
to create the database for you. But if you want
more control, assistant is going to give you that.
Just so folks totally understand what
this is going to do for them. What's the
mental model for what this is? If it's
like a person, we're helping you out.
Agent is like having a developer work. You give
them the PRD, right? And they're going to go and
build the thing. Assistant is like you're sitting
next to them. So they built the thing and now you
walk over to their desk and you say, let me move
this button. Three pixels to the left. Let me
change this thing. So small increments of changes
that you want happen really quickly and you want
it reliably, that will give you that. So it's just
much faster iteration on UI and things like that.
Incredible. The future is wild. Final
question I always ask everybody,
how can listeners be useful to you?
Come work at Replit. We have a PM role.
I think up if you're product manager.
We're hiring engineers and product managers. So
come work at Replit or refer someone to Replit,
especially if you're like our
tools and you want them to get
better. The best way to do that is
to get us great people we can hire.
Well, you're about to get a flood of
product managers applying. Goodluck.
Amazing. I love that.
Amjad, thank you so much for
being here. This was incredible.
Thank you. Thank you for your podcast
and the community that you've built and
newsletter and everything.
It's been awesome to watch.
Thanks, man. Appreciate that. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to
the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.