So much of the way that we tackle problems
and build products is this builder mindset.
It's like I have a plan. I then manipulate
things to match my plan and make it happen.
And this is a way you can create tons of value.
Part of the problem though is it can't possibly
create more value than the effort that you
put into it. What I look for instead are
things that can be gardened, things that can
grow on their own and that you can direct or
maybe give a little bit of extra energy to
or curate over, and is a totally different
mindset for it. If you do this properly, it
looks like magic. I've been told that this
is completely against all the advice that
people get, including products nowadays,
but I think it's a very powerful approach
that works in a lot of different contexts.
Today, my guest is Alex Komoroske. Alex
is one of the most original, articulate,
and first principle thinkers on the future of
product and tech that I've ever come across.
This conversation will get your brain buzzing in
all kinds of ways. Alex spent 13 years at Google
where he worked on Search, DoubleClick. He led
Chrome's Open Web Platform team for eight years,
led augmented reality within Google Maps, and
developed a new toolkit to align company-wide
strategy from the bottom up. After a stint
at Stripe as head of corporate strategy,
he's currently founding a startup that
aims to reimagine the web for the AI era.
In our wide-ranging conversation, we cover how
LLMs and gen AI will impact how we build product
in the coming years, what skills will matter
most as AI becomes a bigger part of our lives,
what companies can learn from slime mold,
organizational kayfabe, the adjacent possible,
strategy salons, why you should be thinking
more like a gardener than a builder,
plus a bunch of productivity tips, life advice,
and so much more. This was such a fun episode,
and I'm sure this is going to get your
mind thinking in completely new ways.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. It's the best
way to avoid missing feature episodes
and it helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you Alex Komoroske.
Alex, thank you so much for being
here, and welcome to the podcast.
Thanks for having me.
I love the way your brain works.
My brain immediately starts buzzing
anytime I start reading some of
your stuff. And one of the more
interesting things that you write and do
and a really interesting habit you have
is you actually have this doc that you
keep called Bits and Bobs that I love,
and we're going to be touching on a lot of the
things that you share in this doc, Bits and Bobs,
and we'll link to it. First of all, can you just
explain this doc, Bits and Bobs, what's it about?
Yeah. I think it's like 600 pages now. It's this
one Google Doc. Every so often, almost every day,
someone will accidentally add a suggestion like
add a space or something because it takes so long
to load that while they're waiting, they'll tap
on the screen and then it'll turn into taps on
adding a comment or something. And I take a
lot of notes. And people, I tell people when
I'm in meetings with them of like, "If you
see me on my phone or typing, that means I
think you said something very interesting and I'm
writing it down. It's not that I'm just that I'm
disengaged. I try to collect all these ideas."
And then once a week, I go through, I take a few
hours and I just reflect to myself and try to find
patterns and unpack and find meaning and things.
And I write those down and I started sometime
in the past sharing those publicly, and it's
now become a thing I literally can't stop doing.
I just find someone who was like, "Oh, if you get
more exposure for this, if you broke these up into
tweets that you sent out once throughout the day,"
it's like, I did this for me. I'm happy to let
other people see and peek into my weird mental
process if they want, but this is 100% about
my own self-reflection. And it's not designed.
I don't want anyone to feel compelled to read it
or... In fact, it's designed a little bit to be,
I allow myself to be a little bit illegible. I
want people to have to work a little bit with
it. And it's not going to lay it out on a platter.
It's going to jump between different things. I'll
use terminology sometimes that is, what are you
talking about? And I do that specifically. I don't
want anyone to read and be like, "Oh, it sucks. It
wasn't worth my time." It's like, "Cool." It's a
600-page Google Doc of my just unspooled insights.
It's okay for you to not want to dive into that.
This episode is brought to you by Eppo. Eppo is a
next generation A/B testing and feature management
platform built by alums of Airbnb and Snowflake
for modern growth teams, companies like Twitch,
Meero, ClickUp and DraftKings rely on Eppo
to power their experiments. Experimentation
is increasingly essential for driving growth and
for understanding the performance of new features.
And Eppo helps you increase experimentation
velocity while unlocking rigorous deep analysis
in a way that no other commercial tool does.
When I was at Airbnb, one of the things that I
loved most was our experimentation platform where
I could set up experiments easily, troubleshoot
issues, and analyze performance all on my
own. Eppo does all that and more with advanced
statistical methods that can help you shape
weeks off experiment time, and accessible UI for
diving deeper into performance, and out-of-the-box
reporting that helps you avoid annoying prolonged
analytic cycles. Eppo also makes it easy for
you to share experiment insights with your team,
sparking new ideas for the A/B testing flywheel.
Eppo powers experimentation across every use case,
including product, growth, machine learning,
monetization, and email marketing. Check
out Eppo at geteppo.com/lenny and 10X your
experiment velocity. That's geteppo.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta. When
it comes to ensuring your company has top-notch
security practices, things get complicated fast.
Now, you can assess risk, secure the trust of
your customers, and automate compliance for SOC 2,
ISO 27001, HIPAA and more with a single platform,
Vanta. Vanta's market-leading trust management
platform helps you continuously monitor compliance
alongside reporting and tracking risk.
Plus, you can save hours by completing
security questionnaires with Vanta AI. Join
thousands of global companies that use Vanta
to automate evidence collection, unify
risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go
to vanta.com/lenny. That's vanta.com/lenny.
I started it many years ago in the same
conceptual thing, taking a bunch of notes.
I have a thing called The Compendium, which is
an open source tool. If you look at it currently,
it looks like I haven't touched it in
years, but that's actually incorrect.
I built this about five years ago. I use it
every day. And so I have, I think let's see,
I currently have 17,248 unpublished working notes.
And so what I do during the week is I'm taking
notes very quickly in meetings, and then every
day or two, I go through and I process them and
put them in as working notes in The Compendium,
and this is where I correct misspellings. I add
just a little bit more context so that it will
make sense to me if I were to read it in a year.
And also, I built a feature into it that uses
embeddings to find similar cards. I find similar
ideas from the past. And then what I do on Friday
afternoons is I sit down and I go through all the
notes I added that week and I just click and
check the ones that still resonate with me,
they still seem interesting in some way.
And then I have a little export thing.
I put it into a Google Doc, and while
the kids are napping on the weekends,
I just go through them and try to distill them
a little bit more in a more long-term format.
And then on Monday mornings, I publish
them. And again, it's a deep... For me,
it's like I can't imagine not doing this.
It is the place where I find most of my
most interesting insights is by reflecting on
interesting conversations from the week before.
As we get into the conversation, people
get to see how deeply you think about
stuff. Part of the reason you're able
to think so deeply about stuff is you
have this practice where you take time to
reflect and share and crystallize. There's
so much power in just forcing yourself to
write it out, I imagine versus, just not.
100%. I find that when you're busy, you're
constantly just go, go, go, go. There's no
time to do any deep thinking. Deep thinking takes
time and space, and you got to create that space.
The mundane, pointless bullshit will take every
square inch you give it. So you got to make that
space to sit back and reflect and luxuriate in
these ideas. And when you do, you're often like,
"Oh my God. Oh wow, that's one I'll keep."
And I told people, back at the very beginning of
my career, I used to work from home on Fridays.
And people gave me so much shit for this and
they'd say, "Oh, you're working from home on
Fridays." First of all, I will line up my output
any day of the week. I'm very proud of the impact
I've had. Second of all, Monday through Thursday,
I'm in meetings from 8:00 to 6:00 or whatever.
I'm just running between. I'm singing, pinging
people and scheduling things and flinging action
items. And the one day I don't take meetings is
on Friday, and that's the day I read documents
carefully that people had sent me or reflect.
And I think to myself, what is the thing that if
I had done it before the week started would've
saved me tons of time and effort that week?
So for example, maybe in 10 different one-on-ones
with people on the team, I had to explain to them
a strategic thing that we were doing or a change
that we were making. And the idea and the way I
framed it worked for everybody. Well, you know
what? That should probably be a document, right?
If the same idea worked for 10 different people
and now in the future there's probably 10 other
people that need to hear it, and now I'll write
that document in 30 minutes and now I have it as
a memorialized thing that other people can read on
their own time without having to involve me.
And you also find these interesting ideas
sometimes where you look at this problem that
you're banging your head against, you go,
"Oh wait, if I will like that, that would've a
wildly different dynamic." And you can only find
those when you take a step back. And I find that
people, I told someone, I mentored someone, I've
mentored hundreds of PMs over the years and I told
someone that at one point and they go, "Oh, I wish
I had the time." And it's like, you got to make
the time. All of us are busy and we will always be
busy. And so this to me is not something I do to
just for the enjoyment of all. I do deeply enjoy
it intrinsically. It's something I do because I
think it makes me more productive and effective.
I'm very tempted to go down a whole
direction of just how you structure
your time and your productivity
calendar and all this stuff,
but I'm not going to do that. That
could be another episode if I do.
I do for that for hours.
What I want to do instead is pick on some of
the Bits and Bobs that you've been focusing
on noodling on that I think are going to be
really helpful to listeners in how they think
about product and the future of AI and all
these things that I think are emerging. And
the first one is actually that I want to get your
thoughts on how AI and LLMs are likely to impact
product development. A lot of the listeners
of this podcast are PMs, engineers, founders,
people building software, and you're spending
a lot of time thinking about AI and product
development. A lot of your Bits and Bobs have
been just like, "Here's what's happening. Holy
shit. This is how things are going to be." So let
me just ask you this how do you anticipate LLMs
and gen AI are going to change how products
are built in the next three to five years?
I think they change a lot. I think LLMs
are truly a disruptive technology. In fact,
I would argue that what we're seeing in
the industry is us trying to use mature
playbooks from the end stage of the last tech
era in one that doesn't really fit yet. To me,
LLMs are magical duct tape. They're formed
principally by the distilled intuition of all of
society into a thing that operates between, a cost
structure between human and plain old computing.
So much of how the industry is built presupposes
the idea that software is expensive to write and
cheap to run, and LLMs undermine both of these.
So it makes it LLMs allow writing shitty software
to be significantly cheaper, not necessarily good
software, but good enough in certain contexts. And
also it means that there's certain software now
that isn't plain old computing that can be run
cheaply. It's relatively expensive marginal cost.
And so if you're going to do a consumer startup,
it can't be based on advertising. It's just too
expensive. Advertising cannot clear the inference
costs even with inference costs declining. So
I think the way to me, a disruptive technology
changes tons of stuff, all these assumptions you
didn't even realize you were making because you
didn't realize it could be any different.
Imagine if you were locked in a room for
your entire career, no windows, and you have all
these experiences. You're going all this know how.
You're getting this sense of how things work, what
will happen. And then imagine that room tilts on
its axis by five degrees. Everything looks roughly
the same, and yet now the dynamics of the force
of gravity is pulling in a different direction
than it was before. You didn't even think about
the force of gravity before because it was
so omnipresent. It never changed that it's
just a blank in your head. And now gravity has
changed effectively for your perspective and
all kinds of intuition is now wrong. I put this
thing on the table, it's going to stay there,
and then it slides off and falls into the
wall. All kinds of weird stuff will happen.
And I think LLMs to me feel like that. I can't
tell you the number of people who are... At
some point at a year or two, someone came to
me, they're like, "I just built a prototype,
product that would've taken me three months. And
I can believe it's going to start up." I was like,
"How differentiated do you think that is?"
Everybody can do that now. It changes the
basis of competition. I think today I see a
lot of folks using LLMs, and LLMs are like a
squishy computer. We're used to computers
doing exactly what we told them to do,
which is not necessarily what we meant. And only
some people have learned the skill of programming,
the arcane magical incantations to make
computers do exactly what you meant.
Now, LLMs can do all kinds of stuff. And
they don't do exactly what you told them,
but they do typically do roughly what you
meant. I see all these places where people
will build products and they'll say 80% of the
time, 90% percent of the time, it's great. 5% of
the time it punches the user in the face and
they're like, "Oh, we're going to reduce the
number of times it punches us in the face." It's
like even if you get it down to 99% of the time,
it's fine. If it punches in the face, that's
not a viable product. And so how do you design
your products assuming that this thing will be
squishy and not fully accurate and fully work?
People use these things a lot as oracles. "I'm
going to have it. I'm going to formulate the
answer and it's going to be a fully fledged
answer." And of course, strawberry has been
really stabbed at. Gotten a chance to play with
it. They are getting better at some of these kinds
of behaviors at great expense. But in a lot of
cases, I instead would rather say, "How can you
take LLMs for granted? How can you assume that you
now have this magical duct tape? Don't assume it's
going to solve all your problems. Don't assume
it's going to do autonomously be able to give high
quality results of every case. But what can you
now build now that you have magical duct tape?"
You're a product manager for most of your
career. Now, you're a founder. I'm curious
what your advice would be to product managers
and people building products in terms of what
skills they should lean into, what you think
is going to be matter most. There's hard
skills. There's soft skills. There's getting
more technical. There's getting more product
business-oriented. Just what do you think
people should work on more and becomes more
valuable and what do you think becomes less
valuable from a product builder perspective?
I think in this early stage, we're in the
community gardening phase, not the factory
farming phase of this technology. And so I think
what people need most is curiosity and play. You
should be playing with these things and trying
out different things and seeing what weird things
are possible now. One of my favorite things, to
be honest, right now, it's using AI is WebSim.
WebSim is so weird. What a weird idea, like why?
And then you play with it and you realize, "Oh,
this is a thing that could only exist in a world
where LLMs exist." And I think these kinds of odd,
interesting, weird, provocative, generative
things will be where a lot of the interesting
patterns are found because right now
we're so used to... If the playbook,
if the cost structures have changed,
the kinds of things are now possible,
the playbook is wrong and we should throw it
out or at least ignore it to some degree. So
it will feel like we are navigating through
a whole new industry that it has in the past.
Anytime that an industry gets really, really,
really, really, really good at like vertical SaaS,
we know how to execute the crap out of that. We
know exactly what to do. It doesn't require that
much. It requires consumption and execution
velocity and all this. But vertical SaaS,
I think, is not the right model of how you
would attack a problem that is an AI native
style problem. And I think that those are where
all the interesting things will be. And again,
I think a lot of the tactics that we're trying
out at the beginning, they won't work. It'll
turn out that they only work 95% of the time,
and 5% of the time they punch you in the face
or something. And that means that you have
to be more adaptable and you have to assume
that a scrappy thing will be more important.
One of the ways I put this is we've seen a
vast reduction in the cost of distribution of
information, and now we're seeing a reduction
in the cost of information production. And
most of it is slop. And so in this cacophony,
how do you stand out? You stand out by having good
taste. I think taste is the most important thing.
You have a perspective that is different from the
background noise, different from the average and
that people find compelling. How do you find your
own taste and how do you lean into that taste is,
I think, much more important than just generically
executing in the way that everybody else could do.
There's so many threads I want to follow
here, but maybe on just this last one,
when you say taste, what do you mean by that?
What should people think when they're like,
"Okay, I got to work in my taste"?
Taste, one way of looking at this is differentiate
from what the LLM would've written if given the
same prompt. How different, how distinctive is
what you have to say. And I think so much in large
industry, in large organizations is about fitting
into the role. How can you be a better and more
efficient cog in that particular kind of machine?
And I think in this new world, what you want to do
is how can I become the best version of myself?
How can I lean into the things that I have an
interesting perspective on that make me different?
Those are the kinds of things. And now of course,
if you lean into something and you're doing
something out there and nobody resonates with it,
then it doesn't count. Good taste is something
that is individual and also compelling to
others. And so find what things you say that
resonate with other people and lean into that.
I love that. Back to the WebSim example, we're
going to link to this, but definitely play
with WebSim. I was interviewing Dylan Field at
Figma Config and this was his... Asked him like,
"What's the number one thing you think
people are going to get more excited
about in the future that you're playing with
now?" Because he's really good at identifying
things that are going to be bigger in the
future, and that was his choice. And it's
very hard to understand exactly what it
is if you just go there. But basically
it's like you type a URL and it invents
what that website is using just AI LLMs.
That's insane, as in. And you can get it to
do, you realize as you play with it more,
you can get it to do all kinds of specific things
and you can steer it based on the way it uses the
context of the last few pages. It creates
a coherent world that's coherent with the
things that you have recently seen, because
you can steer it directly and you can watch
fascinating people. They'll cover all kinds
of wacky little techniques to get to generate,
like generate a game for your kid that's on a
specific type. You can do all kinds of stuff.
And I'm not saying necessarily WebSim to me is
a disruptive thing. Things that look alien and
weird and yet are compelling, those are what we
should be paying more attention to as opposed to
take an existing playbook
and slap something on it.
I love that. Another point that I saw you
make about AI and the way it's different
from other things we've done is most of
the tools that we adopt in the workplace
are collaborative where it helps your team
be better, helps you collaborate better,
and AI is the opposite. It makes you individually
better. Can you talk about that insight?
100%. I think this is one of the reasons
is that the question right now of, okay,
everyone's talking about AI and yet nobody's
doing... There's no interesting breakout
success obviously other than OpenAI and
Anthropic obviously. So is there any value
being created? I think it's entirely possible.
And Ethan Malik who's a good friend, who has
an amazing blog who's absolutely worth reading,
has pointed out, too, that this is a thing that
make individuals better in a way they might not
want to tell their manager about. I can now do my
job twice as fast. And if the organization sees
that, they might go, "Wait a second. We should
pay you half this much." They're like, "What if
we get rid of some extra people or something?"
And so if this stuff is magical duct tape,
it's very hard to make scaled, repeatable,
large scale things out of it. It's very easy
to do rig the shit out of anything. And so
you'll see it being used in the small in a
way that's almost entirely below the level
of awareness of the seeing at the organization.
The organization almost won't see it or sense it,
and yet it could be adding significant value
or just being used quite heavily. And I
think this is one of the things that makes it if
everything is happening in the long tail of usage,
then you could conclude, "Oh, it's not being used
for anything in the industry," but it's being
used all over the place. I talked to Claude 20
times a day. I just have long conversations with
it. I have tons of projects loaded up with
all kinds of contexts on different topics,
and I literally could not do the job I do now
without having a conversation partner like Claude.
Let me follow that thread real quick
because a lot of people are like,
"Okay," people keep telling me, "Play with
AI. Use ChatGPT." Sometimes it's hard to
see exactly what they can do with it. Can
you give one example of how you found it
really helpful or how you use Claude
or another tool in your day-to-day?
I use it to think through problems. And so like
when I'm trying to name a concept or get a handle
on a few different ways of looking at something,
just saying, "Here's what's in my brain about this
topic right now. Here's some relevant context."
I have a number of projects that just stuff as
much of the Bits and Bobs into the context as
I can, which is very helpful. And I just say,
"Just play with it. Just give me 10 examples of
that thing," or then, "Critique these ones," or,
"It feels like this one's the best one for me.
What works about this? Why is this one the best?"
Or, "I want to work at an angle now that has
something about know Helen Nissenbaum's concept
of contextual integrity. How would I layer that
in?" It's just think of it as having a extremely
well-read but slightly naive friend who is will
never make you feel dumb and is willing to engage
you in any particular topic you want to go down.
So when you talk to an expert like a lawyer or a
doctor or something, you know that that time
is extremely valuable. You have a very small
slice of time, and so there's tons of
questions you don't even bother to ask.
"That's a dumb question. I'm not going to spend
$1,000 to answer that question." Whereas if you
can have that conversation, now this is not
saying use it for legal advice, but it can
allow you to explore through a problem domain
and then later check it with experts and say,
"I believe this is a coherent outcome or a
thing that should happen." And they can go,
"Oh yeah, that works." So I use LLMs to help me.
It's like getting a, it's like an electric bike
for idea spaces. You can just cover so much
more ground so much more quickly in them.
I love that metaphor because it builds on
Steve Jobs's that computers are a bicycle
for the mind. And that's really a
beautiful way of thinking about it,
that LLMs are like the
electric bicycle for the mind.
I don't think if that's someone else's, the...
Oh, okay.
I don't know where it came from. Part
of my job is a collector of ideas,
and so I try to put myself in the most interesting
information streams with interesting people that
I've found to have taste, have a perspective
on something. Maybe I disagree with it,
but they definitely have a coherent idea.
And then I just allow myself to like, "Oh,
that's a really good idea and let me build
on that or let me..." I don't even know
where that particular one came, but I'm
95% sure that somebody else said that.
I want to get to this idea of gardening versus
building that is central to a lot of the way
you think about it. But before we get there, I
want to touch on another bit and bob that I love
that you come back to occasionally, which is this
idea of organizational kayfabe. Talk about what
this idea of kayfabe is on its own and then how
this applies to organizations in your experience.
One thing I should flag before I dive into any
this stuff, sometimes when people hear me talk
about how organizations work and systems, they
think I'm being cynical. And I want to be very
clear, I'm hyper-optimistic and I also believe
that one of the moral precepts is how do you
maximize the agency of real humans as ends
in and of themselves? And so sometimes when
I get excited about this, people go, "Wow,
that is so cynical." No, I'm just trying
to describe the system as it actually exists.
Once we know how it exists, we can figure out
how to make it do great things and how we as
members of this system can tweak and nudge it.
So I just want to flag that before I dive into
this. I have this slime mold deck which has
gotten a ton of traction over the years, and part
of the reason for that is because it feels like
people tell me it feels like they think they're
crazy and it feels like giving a big hug saying,
"You are not crazy. Here's why this thing shows
up." And once you acknowledge it, it feels like
a bummer to acknowledge it, but once you do, now
there's all kinds of options that pop up. "Oh,
given that this thing is way more expensive than
it looks, I can now do this instead. That one's 10
times cheaper. These two options, this one is way
cheaper, way more likely to succeed." So once you
see these forces, you see them more clearly.
So kayfabe is I think a lens that's useful
to understand how organizations actually work.
Kayfabe is a word that comes, I believe is a carny
word that is used and applied to professional
wrestling and it means a thing that everybody
knows is fake and yet everybody acts like is real.
And I think it's one of the defining forces within
an organization, any organization. So kayfabe in
the small is optimism, enthusiasm. When someone
says, "We're going to do this thing," you say,
"Yeah, we're going to do that," even if I think
this isn't going to work. If you say, "I don't
think this think is going to work," everyone loses
hope and it definitely doesn't work. So having a
little bit of this is extremely valuable. It's the
lubricant that allows organizations to believe
they can do something and to attempt to do it.
The problem that you get is as organizations
get larger, imagine you are five levels down or
something and you have this project you're working
on and you're trying to give a status update to be
rolled up to leadership. And it's currently a
yellow, and your manager asks it and you know
it's not going to be presented to leadership
and enrolled up until next week. "It's yellow,
but I've got my arms around the problem.
I know how to fix it. I'm going to go talk
to Sarah. I think we have a solution. By
the time this is reported up the chain,
it's going to be green." So if I make it yellow,
there's a non-trivial chance that someone's going
to swoop down and say, "Well, what's going on? We
have a review," and it will be way harder to fix,
so I'm just going to... A little white lie.
This is a totally reasonable thing to do. It's
a self-defensive thing to do. And it's probably
the right thing for the organization too. The
problem is this happens up multiple layers and
it compounds. So then your layer above you does
the same, and the same, and the same, and levels
up you can be many orders of magnitude off of the
ground truth. And so the kayfabe, the thing
that everyone pretends to believe is true,
is obviously incorrect. And the dangerous part
about this is it can lead you to make very bad
decisions. And if you as someone who sees this can
see that wait a second, the official strategy is
definitely not going to work, you're like, "I got
to tell somebody. We're doing work that's going
in a bad direction. It's not going to work." And
you go and say, "I think that it's actually not
going to work for these reasons."
And what someone will say to you,
this happens by the way, I'm not substituting any
particular organization, this happens literally
in all organizations to some degree, is the
senior person will say, "Alex, I agree with
you. It's not perfect, but if you hit the ground
truth button, if you share that and everybody,
the whole thing will shatter and we can't
do anything. And so help me fix it. Don't
say the ground truth. Just help nudge it and
fix it." That's a good point. Okay, so you
help working on it and then you realize a month
later, wait a second, it's getting worse. We're
doing things that's not good for the company.
It's not creating user value. It's not good for
the employees. They're burning out. It's just not
good for anybody and it's getting worse. And so if
you think you're going to go and hit the ground
truth button, before you do, you'll be flying
tackled to the ground by somebody and stabbed
in the dark because you will destroy everything.
And so it becomes correct to hold onto this
idea of if you acknowledge the kayfabe is false,
then you are in danger of getting knocked out of
the game. And so how do you do good things despite
the fact that you're pulled in two different
directions? And this increasingly in the limit,
it can be good to a point where the easiest way is
if I do, if I hold on this idea, we might create
significant value for the company. If I let go of
this idea, I die. So the easiest way to maintain
this split-brain thing is to just turn this part
off and just earnestly believe the kayfabe. This
has been organizations become zombies, and anyone
individually you talk to behind the scenes will
agree yes, it could not possibly work. That
turns out that these things work this way,
and yet the entire organization lumbers on.
And this is a death state for large organizations.
It happens all over the place in any number of
different conditions, and this is one of the
reasons it shows up. And I think acknowledging
that is an important way to help navigate and
still make good grounded things happen. How can
you allow disconfirming evidence to show up that
doesn't kill you, that helps make you stronger?
And if it all has to come in one massive moment
that could ruin everything, then you aren't
going to hear it. And then it will build up
and build up and build up and build up into
a super critical state that could shatter.
I was just listening to a couple podcasts, and a
thread that came up in a number of them is some
of the most successful leaders, their instruction
to their reports is, "As soon as there's bad news,
I need to know as soon as possible. Do
not shield me. I just want to know all
the bad news as soon as possible." Feels like
that's one solution to what you're describing.
Disconfirming evidence hurts, and so you won't
realize it because it hurts at any given moment.
It's like, "Ugh, it's a distraction. We're
just trying to get this thing done." And so
it comes from a good place to not get it, but if
you're busy, that's one of the reason you need
to take a step back. We take a step back,
you're a little bit calmer. You can absorb
this as confirming evidence. It doesn't feel
like an existential threat. It's really easy
to get surrounded. If you are very powerful,
you will find all the confirming evidence
you need. And if it doesn't exist, it will
be created for you without your knowledge.
And so this is one of the reasons that large
companies are radically different than smaller
companies. And one of the traps that you can get
into of not realizing this dynamic is happening,
and you can make very bad decisions if you
don't understand that it's inherently what's
happening because they're all, "Oh, we'll have
some bad actors." No, no, no. If people don't
play this game, this game is emergent. It shows
up even though everybody hates it. And if you
don't play the game, you are knocked out of the
game. The underlying dynamic that must be true
in any organization on a fundamental basis is you
can't make your boss look dumb because if you do,
they're the person who decides, "Oh, this person's
not performing," or whatever. And that one little
asymmetry, that one little fact, in most cases
it does not matter. That one little asymmetry is
what leads to the systemic compounding thing where
you get these really weird dysfunctional emergent
things that everybody hates, nobody wants, and
yet nobody is in the position to change per se.
I love your caveat at the beginning
that continues to resonate in my head
as you say this. You're not cynical
about, "This sucks." It's more,
"Here's what I'm observing. We need to
think about ways to get around this."
Yeah. Because I think so much pain and misery
is caused by us being not acknowledging these
fundamental, inescapable things. It's almost
impossible. Entropy is one of those things.
Entropy emerges because there's more ways to
go away from a point than towards a point. It
fundamentally must be true in really any universe
you can possibly imagine. And so if you're going
to fight entropy, you're going to lose at a
certain point. It's like if you are aware of these
things, you can find subsets of ideas that do work
despite these challenges. And that's some of the
stuff, the tactics I advise are often things that
look playful. They look unserious. They look like,
"Oh, you're saying you don't know the answer?"
No, I'm admitting I don't know the answer.
And I'm saying it doesn't matter if I don't
know the answer because this thing, this
very small seed I am planting is so cheap that
yes, I can't tell you for sure this will work,
but I could tell you there is a chance that it'll
work. And the downside of this is basically the
opportunity cost of planting the seed in this one
moment, and the person who's planting it enjoys
planting it so that an opportunity cost really
isn't that much because they get energy from
doing it. So who cares? Plant a bunch of these
suckers. If one of these grows into an oak tree,
that's great. Don't try to analyze beforehand
which seed is going to turn into an oak tree.
If it's super simple to plant the seeds, then
plant the seeds. And if it starts growing, then
keep watering it. That's it. That's the thing.
And people sometimes will see this as like,
I've been called in my list before because they
said, "Well, you're saying that you don't know
the answer to the thing." It's like no, I'm saying
I don't have to know the answer to the thing. If
on a systemic basis I let these ideas and then
you respond to the ones that are working that
are viable, it doesn't really matter if you didn't
know ahead of time which ones were going to work.
It's a great segue to talking about this core
idea that again informs a lot of the way you
think, which is this idea of building
versus gardening, the magic of acorns.
Talk about this general idea and
then I want to follow some threads.
So much of the way that we tackle problems and
build products is this builder mindset. It's like,
"I have a plan, I then manipulate things to match
my plan and make it happen." And this is a way
you can create tons of value. Part of the problem
though is it can't possibly create more value than
the effort that you put into it. And so what I
look for instead are things that can be gardened,
things that can grow on their own and that you
can direct or maybe give a little bit of extra
energy to or curate over, and is a totally
different mindset for it. So it's like a
lead by gardening vibe. I don't try to pick
the things in the system. I try to work with
what I've actually got and I try to lean in
on the ones that turn, I think are going in
the direction that I believe is valuable based
on constantly seeking disconfirming evidence.
And if you do this properly, it looks like magic.
It looks like a thing. It looks like getting lucky
because what you're doing is you're farming for
miracles. And so on a systemic basis, I can't tell
you which of these things will work, but I can
tell you there's a very high likelihood that one
of these will work in a way that is interesting
and transformative. And so if you're looking and
finding these seeds that have the compounding
potential of if they work, they would start
working at an accelerating rate, then you don't
have to know ahead of time. To me this is, I've
been told that this is completely against all the
advice that people get building products nowadays,
but I think it's a very powerful approach
that works in a lot of different contexts.
Is there an example that you can give from either
from something you worked on or something someone
worked on that came or true miss? Because
I think people hearing this might be like,
"But I got to ship stuff. I got to
hit some goals. I don't have time
to sit around and garden and plant
seeds. I got to actually build."
If there's an ecosystem approach, if
there's something that if it works,
it'll be self-accelerating. So okay, what
you're going to do this thing, we aren't
entirely sure what's going to work, but if a
developer writes a thing and somebody uses it,
it'll attract more developers, more users,
and then this would grow on its own. Then
and it's cheap to do the little example of the
thing. It's cheap to build a little open source,
tinker the little thing and just put it there. And
if nobody uses it, it's fine. It was fun to build.
It took you three hours. It's fine. If someone
does use it, then you just invest in incremental
bit of unit each time that you find a signal that
somebody is finding it useful and then you stop
if you ever cease getting that information.
So I would use this. Anything that is shaped
like an ecosystem that has some kind of network
effect, and many things have network effects,
have some kind of compounding loop. Compounding
loops are not rare. They are, "Look." It's
like truffle hunting. You have to know what you're
looking for and find the dynamics of a thing that
if it worked would work at an accelerating rate.
Lots and lots and lots of things intrinsically
have this shape. Anything with a network effect,
anything where the power goes up with a number
of users, but it shows up in all kinds of
problems that we don't normally apply it to.
Along the same lines, you also advise people to
think more emergence-oriented versus top-down,
kind of what you were just saying. But I
think that's another really interesting
way of thinking about the same idea,
create opportunities for emergence,
bottom-up versus top-down
control. You just chat about that.
100%. I think the emergence is one of the most
powerful forces if you know how to marshal
it and you know how to work with it. And the
only thing that's hard about it in my opinion
is you're going to look like you aren't very
serious. You're going to look like a weirdo.
You're going to look like a cook. And one of
the downsides, if you're working on something
and you're doing the normal top-down approach
where you make the plan, you execute the plan,
even if the plan turns out to not be useful, you
produce a thing and nothing interesting happens,
no one can say you didn't work hard.
But if you try doing this designing for
emergence and something amazing happens,
even once it happens, people go, "Ah,
it's luck. Where was the miraculous moment,
the heroic moment where you made that happen?
So therefore you had nothing to do with it."
And this was the biggest unlock in my career
actually was when I stopped my guts. I was
promoted to director at Google. I was like,
"Cool, I never want to be promoted inside of a
large organization ever again." And the freedom
to now do the highest impact work, even if
I can't make it legible to the organization,
was so powerful and I was able to 10X my impact
for the organization because I didn't have to
worry about making it measurable specifically in
a way that would show individual work effort. And
I think that's the hardest part. And you have
to have, typically what I would advise for PMs,
my approach at Google was 70% of my effort
and my team's effort should go on things that
everybody acknowledges are important and useful
and create value. Maybe it's boring, linear value,
but some kind of value. You're trying to minimize
the chance that any other person in a company
will say, "What does that team do anyway?"
This, if someone says this about your team,
your team is on the verge of death. And so you're
trying to minimize the chance that anybody wants
to say that or thinks that it's appropriate to
say that by clearly and unambiguously adding
value. You're not saying this is the best team
in the entire world, but clearly they're doing
something useful. They're executing well. They're
working hard. And of course that team should
exist. Think about it, of course they should.
But now once you do this, you have 30% of your
extra time that you can plant all these seeds.
You can find interesting little things where
maybe a junior PM on the team has an idea you
think it's kind of silly, but they're really into
it. And the there is this thing, it could work
out great actually. If you tweak it like this,
there is a potential. I could see how that could
work. If that PM is going to work on that anyway,
they want to do it anyway. Instead of saying,
"No, no, no, we don't have time for that. Be
a little bit more productive over here," say,
"Go for it. Here's my concerns. I imagine this
part might not work, but this part is really
cool right here." And then if it doesn't work,
then they've stretched their agency. They've
executed. They've exercised their agency. They've
learned. They've gotten stronger. They've grown.
It has the upside if it turns out to actually
work. And worst case scenario, the opportunity
cost to doing the thing that helped them grow
and they learn and they liked. So I don't know.
Don't try to force it. Don't try to stop it.
That's a really good example of actually
how to go about doing that on your team.
The way I've always thought about this is
the visual I share with people is like,
you want to create cover fire for your
team where your team's just hitting goals,
moving metrics, and then while with
that cover fire, you're building the
doomsday bomb inside, protected where
no one's going to come and stop you.
Yeah, because one of the hardest parts about an
acorn when you plant it is making sure a squirrel
doesn't dig that fucker up. There's so many things
that can destroy it, and just keeping it, allowing
it some space and allowing it some time is the
most important thing. And it's challenging to do,
but that's why it's important as a leader to
have enough credibility in the organization
that people can see that you are doing useful
work to give you the space, to give your team
the space to do this truly great work. If
you want to get your team to do good work,
there's a million different paths to do that.
If you want to get your team to do great work,
there's no shortcut other than to have
an extremely high-trust environment where
people lean into their superpowers in
a way that adds up to something greater
than some of its parts. That takes time. It
takes effort. It's very difficult to make
legible up to the rest of the organization,
but that is where great things come from.
It reminds me of something Ed Catmull shared in
Creativity, Inc., this idea of the ugly baby,
that every new idea is an ugly baby and nobody
wants this ugly baby. Everyone's just like,
"Get this out of here," because
every new idea is bad initially.
Yeah, it sucks. They're just like this ugly thing
that barely works or... But this is why what I try
to do is I try to see the greatness, the seeds of
greatness in everything. Everyone and everything
around me, I look for, I try to find and see, man,
what is the most compelling part of this? And let
me lean into that. And so one of the things I try
to do when I meet with people, when I mentor them,
I try with it within the first session or two,
whenever I can get a hypothesis, I say, "I think
your superpower is..." And I describe to them what
I think I can see them being truly exceptional at.
And sometimes I get it wrong,
especially if I try to do it earlier,
but when people feel very seen and they feel
acknowledged for that, they now are willing,
they're going to stretch farther and they're going
to respond to nudging feedback even better because
they know that you're not trying to tell them be
different. You're trying to tell them be more,
and you now the nudges will feel less like a stop
energy and more like someone who gets me and can
help me grow even more. And you can get some
amazing things out of people when you just treat
them with the respect. I assume that everyone
I talk to, everyone I talk to is interesting,
has seeds of greatness in them, even if they
don't recognize necessarily where they are.
Someone described to me actually this morning
in one of my little dirt clubs I run about they
help facilitate about treat everybody like
the Buddha. I think is I'm messing this up,
but this notion of imagine everyone you talk
to is the Buddha, in a Buddhist mindset,
and how do you see and find those seeds
of greatness and treat everyone with
respect intrinsically as an end of themselves.
This is one of those things that you do to be a
compassionate human. It's also, I believe,
a way to maximize the amount of value,
direct and indirect value, that's created.
So it's one of those win-win-win-win-wins
where just it's the right thing to do
as a person and a member of society,
and it's also the thing that can create a lot of
business value and create real value in the world.
This episode is brought to you by Coda. I use
Coda every day to coordinate my podcasting and
newsletter workflows. From collecting questions
for guests, to storing all my research,
to managing my newsletter content calendar,
Coda is my go-to app and has been for years.
Coda combines the best of documents, spreadsheets,
and apps to help me get more done, and Coda can
help your team to stay aligned and ship faster by
managing your planning cycle in just one location,
set and measure OKR's with full visibility
across teams and stakeholders, map dependencies,
create progress visualizations, and identify
risk areas. You can also access hundreds of
pressure-tested templates for everything from
roadmap strategy to final decision-making
frameworks. See for yourself why companies like
DoorDash, Figma, and Qualtrics run on Coda. Take
advantage of this special limited-time offer
just for startups. Head over to coda.io/lenny
and sign up to get six free months of the team
plan. That's coda.io/lenny to sign up and get
six months of the team plan, coda.io/lenny.
Coming back to a phrase that you used earlier,
slime molds, I want to spend a little
time here. So interestingly enough,
the first time I heard about you and what got me
interested in your stuff is I did a newsletter
post with the company Perplexity about how they
build product. And as they were describing how
they organized their team, the co-founders
described they organized like slime mold,
and he linked to your deck about slime molds
and I was like, "What the heck is this?" Can
you just briefly describe what you mean when
you talk about slime molds and how slime molds
are related to the way companies are organized
and how they should think of the organization?
Yeah. The main thesis of the slime mold deck is
that the core dynamic that makes organizations
hard to navigate as they get larger, even if you
assume everyone is actively good at what they do,
actively collaborative and actively hardworking,
is this emergent force or coordination of finding
the subset of projects to work on when everyone's
super busy that everyone agrees and commits to
and actually works on together. And finding
this coordination cost grows with the square
of the number of people who are working on
that thing. And so what companies typically
try to do is fight this or ignore that it exists.
If you're going to fight it, the one way to look
at this is think of a company like a vehicle.
When the company is very small, you can drive it,
you can steer it like a sports car. As a founder,
you are allowed to steer. Everyone acknowledges
you are allowed to steer. They're never, "Why is
he steering it that way?" So you, a founder, can
help navigate an organization around an obstacle
the organization cannot see or comprehend itself.
The problem is as you steer, as you grow into the
size, your organization goes from a sports car
and you grow into the size of a big rig, if you
drive a big rig like a sports car, you're going
to be a danger to yourself and others on the road
and you're going to grind the engine. And so you
got to drive the car that you actually have.
So what I see a lot of things happen in large
organizations, that people are just trying
to ignore this fact. And when you drive,
by the way, a car, your vehicle, like a big
rig, when it is a big rig, people go, "Oh,
it means to go slow." No, no, no. It means pivot
less. It means have a little bit more... Be more
intentional about the times that you adjust the
steering, invest more in program management,
invest more in processes, give a little bit
more slack in the planning process to absorb
any kind of surprising things that you can still
all reach the product launch at the same time.
The other option you can do is you can split your
thing up into a series a swarm of sports cars,
individual sports cars. And the downside of
this, you'll get the autonomy and strengths of
the bottom-up, the downside is other people will
externally will look at it and go, "Well, that
team and that team clearly didn't talk." You'll
say, "Yep, yep." You have to decide how bad that
is for you. Apple has chosen the former. It's very
important to them to have the illusion of perfect
coherence in their products. It worked very well
for them. They executed marvelously. And if you
also picked the exact opposite thing, everyone
else is like, "Yeah. There are like 15 different
ways of doing everything. They clearly don't talk
to each other." But it allows the overall swarm
of the AWS product suite to be very powerful
and anti-fragile or whatever you want to say.
And so slime molds, I think, is acknowledging
that organizations are, especially ones that
focus on autonomy and agency of their individual
employees, which is a lot of tech companies,
they are more like slime molds than we realize.
And if you fight that fact, you're going to have
a bad time. And if you embrace it, then you can
start realizing slime molds are actually kind of
amazing. They can find solutions to problems
you didn't even know you were searching for.
Alex, you have the best metaphors.
I don't know how you do this,
but they're so evocative and correct.
I can tell you that the
process I do if you're into it.
Please. That would be incredible.
I think by talking, I'm an external processor, I
literally can't think if I'm not talking. And so
I make sure I have as many interesting meetings as
I can, and that's where I discover what I think,
by talking to people. And the test is if I say a
frame, something that the person goes, "Ooh," or
like, "Ooh," they go, "Aha," that's a win.
That's a mark that's a good one. You're just
randomly casting about. I find one. And then if
a different person also has a similar response,
if a person in sales and a person in engineering
both find the same idea interesting, that's a
very good sign that lots of people will find it
interesting, how diverse in terms of background
skill sets, perspectives are the people
who resonate with the thing you're saying.
The intuition of this is if you find in a social
network, you want to see what's going to go viral,
if something is shared and it's shared within,
so the people who are at the beginning are all
highly densely interconnected in the social graph,
then the implied ceiling is relatively small. You
only know it works with that audience. But if it's
people that are very different subclass and very
little overlap, they both find it interesting,
that implies a much larger max audience. So
you're looking for ideas that resonate with the
diversity of people. And then once you find them,
each time you get something like that, you
invest a little more time in it and you think
a little bit more about framing it the next time.
I haven't done this during this chat, but in most
conversations, you'll see me as I'm talking
writing down stuff like, "Ooh, that was the
best formulation of that one so far." And so you
keep on coming back to it. You keep on tightening
it and seeing how, watching how it's responding
and referring with different people through like,
"Where do you get these from?" It's like I got
thousands and thousands and thousands of little
examples or metaphors or whatever that's sick.
One of the benefits of metaphorical thinking is
you connect nine of the 10 dots and you invite the
listener to engage with the argument to connect
that last dot. This allows you by the way to say
very controversial things, because if you say
connect all the 10 dots and it's like, "Oh, that's
the official strategy," then you are instantly
a dangerous thing. Whereas if you leave one dot
unconnected, people can go connect the dot and go,
"Oh my god, I think that applies to us." You're
like, "Oh my god, what?" "Yes, that's why I picked
that." But to counteract this because now it's
less obvious to people that's correct, you have
to make the metaphor evocative and interesting.
One of the reasons that slime mold deck got so
much traction is partially because slime is
gross, it's bad, and yet it's talking about
why slime is good. And so that has this instantly
subversive thing. I only know this after the fact
of trying to figure out why did that deck get so
much attention of all the things I've written.
It also is all emojis basically, which is
not how you often read a deck. It's very
beautifully made. I love that you've been
talking about the way you think and come
up with ideas is by talking to people and having
conversations. We also talked about how you write
in this Bits and Bobs approach. I asked someone
that you worked with at Stripe what to ask you,
and she said to ask you about strategy
salons, which feels like a good avenue
for this sort of thing. Can you talk about
what these are and how you set these up?
So these I also call now nerd clubs, and these
are my secret weapon. And I have a blog post.
I started writing right before my second kid was
born, and then he was born three weeks early and
I just lost the plot and now it's like a 40-page
draft of a thing that I'll probably never finish.
But I've used this tactic. I discovered it
many years ago as they strengthen some of the
techniques I'd used in open source community
organizing. And the situation was I was just
joining a new team at Google. I've been there
for many years, and there was at the time 12
different groups working in different aspects of
this overall problem domain. And in classic Google
fashion, they added up to significantly less
than the sum of their parts, as in not like,
"Oh, we'll see which one works," but, "These
two things directly undermine each other. If
you execute both of these strategies, neither can
work." And I knew that if you try to do pairwise
executive reviews on this very complex, ambiguous,
open-ended problem, you would get really expensive
pageantry that would obscure more than clarified.
So what I did was I created a secret group that
I called Navel Gazers was the original one,
and I wanted people when they hear about it,
I want people to go, "That will be a club for
nerds." They're like, "Yeah, do you want in?" And
so this means that only people who intrinsically
want to be in it for its own sake come in. So
you get only a positive "yes, and" kind of
energy. So then within these groups, you say,
you set the norms very explicitly and say, "This
is a collaborative debate environment. This is
only 'yes, and'." If somebody says a thing in this
group that is optional and secret and completely
off the side of anything that matters, if they say
something that you think is an actively dumb idea,
you are free to not engage. Just leave it. That's
fine. Because nothing's going to happen. We're
deciding anything interesting or important here.
And if you want to engage and you don't like it,
a productive way of doing that is saying,
"Oh, that's so interesting. I would never
would've thought to apply that lens. I typically
would apply this lens to that kind of problem. I
wonder if that applies here." And by saying, "I
wonder," you make it about you, not them. And so
that person can choose if that's an interesting
thing to build on or not. This sounds by the
way very non-rigorous feel like, "Ah, how can you
possibly get rigorous thinking in the 'yes, and'?"
It turns out there's limited amounts of time and
so people will choose to build on the things they
find most interesting. This is interesting things
are surprising and potentially valuable. And so
if lots of different people in the group are
building on the same idea, that's a good sign
there is something very interesting going on.
The third thing you do is you dribble in new
perspectives. Every one to three a week,
if you put in lots of new perspectives,
once the norms can all scramble, if you have one
in five people who all have a very particular kind
of personality can mess up the norms, and so
you're trying to minimize the chance you add
a jerk. It takes one person to poop a party and
go, "What are we even doing here?" You want to
minimize the chance that happens. But second
or thirdly and more importantly, you want to
have as people with as different perspective as
possible added into the group. And so this is what
Ken Stanley might call, for example, novelty
search. You're novelty-searching through the
different perspectives in the overall thing.
When you do this properly, you get something
magical. You get a group that people
find intrinsically valuable for its own
sake and just enjoy participating in and find
meaning in, that also stochastically spins off
changing insights for the surrounding context
because you're searching through these ideas
in a low stakes environment where the ideas
that lots people build on, they go, "Oh,
you should write that down." And this is like an
idea lab, what everyone will call an idea lab. And
this creates amazingly interesting insights. You
just can't force it to do anything. It has to be a
bottom-up and emergent, which means if you try to
steer it towards an outcome, it won't go. But if
you do these, they are amazing places to riff and
to share ideas and half-formed ideas. And this is
anywhere I go, I terraform the culture around me
and create these, because I need it as a place to
experiment and try out different half-formed ideas
and build on them and be inspired by other people.
And that is one of my secrets, strategy secrets
that I've been doing now for probably 10 years
ago is when the first one started. And there's
now I can count eight or nine of I've started
over the years. Some of them emerged. So many
of them are still at Google. And I think it's
like they're just wondrous environments
that I think create a lot of value.
And I love it's a perfect example of
your approach of emergent properties,
letting things emerge versus a top-down, "Here's
what we're doing and here's what we're talking
about here." If someone wanted to set this
up within their company or within friends,
any advice? What are some constraints
and ways of setting it up for success?
Communities are all about momentum.
You want to have a space too small,
a time too short. If you have a big cabinet space
of a lot of people in it and no one's talking,
people go, "I guess this is the place where
we don't talk," for whatever reason. So what
you're doing is you want the smallest seed of
people that you know are going to be actively
engaged. So maybe there's four of you that
already talk over lunch and you talk about
whatever topic and it's always really interesting
and generative. Cool, get that group together and
do a thing. And then incrementally add people
who you think are going to like that already as
it currently exists. And then you need to feed
it so you want to make sure that it never dies.
And a community with no people talking is
definitely dead. A community with one person
talking is already dead. You don't realize
it yet. And so you're trying to maximize the
chance that there's an interesting conversation
even when you as the facilitator are not there.
This takes some active policing by the... Like a
garden has a gardener, there's somebody pruning
back and saying, "Hey Jeff, just so you know,
I think that came out a little bit strong to
Sarah's idea and maybe next time add 'I wonder'
to the front of that statement," or whatever.
The other thing that you do is when people
reach out to you and ping you, they go, "Hey,
let's think about this thing," and you go, "That's
a really interesting idea. You should share that
in the group." And then they do. And then you
engage in the group and say, "That was really
interesting," little emoji response. And people
who didn't watch the interaction assume that Sarah
just decided proactively to stick her neck out and
share that and that it worked. And so this becomes
a self-sustaining norm in the community. And it's
not a secret. It's not if someone asks, "Yeah,
I told Sarah to share that," but people watching
don't realize that. And so it becomes a place that
people do take risks and feel comfortable sharing.
The other thing you do is once a week or so, you
want to make sure that you never propose something
in the group that people go, "Eh." You always want
to do a thing people go, "Yeah." So what you do
is you see that if you're talking to other people,
you say, "I wonder if we should have a live
conversation every so often, right?" The chats
were so fun, but it goes, "Would you come if I did
one?" "Oh yeah, I would." "Okay, great." So now
I say, "Hey, a few of us are talking. We're
just going to do an experiment. We're going
to have an hour-long conversation over lunch on
Wednesday. Anyone in the group is free to come."
And then what you do is you make sure it always
has quorum because if it doesn't have quorum,
then the thing, it looks like the community's
dead. And then what you do is you send FOMO
stuff afterwards. So you say, "Here's my notes
from the thing," or, "Thanks Sarah, Jeff," blah,
blah, blah, blah, "or an amazing conversation.
I thought the insight about," blah blah blah,
"was so ridiculously amazing." So you want people
who were in the group who didn't come to feel
like they missed out and to come to the next one.
And so you're constantly creating these kinds of
vibes to how to do it. You can't do it if you
don't have somebody with a lot of energy. I'm
typically the seed crystal for a lot of the groups
I'm in to start them off because I have a lot of
energy, and I like, anything that people have to
say that I think is open-minded or interesting,
I like building on and "yes, and"-ing and that
kind of gives the foundation that it can grow.
But look for the people who already roughly
want it. Don't try to convince somebody who
doesn't want it to want it. They will
not. They will ruin the whole thing.
I just love this playbook for starting to build
a little bit of community within a company.
Have you written about this by the way? And if
not, you should write a whole post about this.
I have. It's a long essay and it's just not,
you can see it in Bits and Bobs. If you gave the
Bits and Bobs to Claude and said, "Please write a
thing about nerd clubs and essay and the style,"
it would do it because there's a lot of the
pieces are in there, it's just not factored out.
I see you writing something
down right now, which tells
me you just articulated something
in a new way that you want to say.
Yeah, that's right. That's right.
You mentioned this idea of constraints of
time, and it reminds me of something that
you shared in one of your Bits and Bobs
around productivity. You say that if you
have two hours to do a five-minute task, the
effort to do that is impossible and instead
you should flip that. Can you talk about this
insight and how to be a little more productive?
Yeah, I think a lot of the trick to productivity
is to play yourself like a fiddle and figure out
how you work and what gives you energy and set
up your day to structure it that way. So I find
every time you start a task, there's an activation
energy, especially a task you don't really want
to do. And then when you complete it, there's a
boop. There's a little burst of energy. So if you
do this properly, you can get small things that
are extremely easy to knock out in 10 seconds of
effort, and then you do one that takes 30 seconds
of effort, and then you do one that takes a longer
bit of effort. But if you give it too much space,
it's harder to do. So you almost want to find,
"Okay, listen, I got 10 minutes. I got to
do this thing where I figure out how to add,
do this thing in gusto that I've been putting
off. Ten minutes should be enough time to do
it and structure it. So okay, right now is
the only time I have to do this, to do it."
And another trick is I use one of
my original media messages actually,
one of the original public ones is about
always rules are better than sometimes rules
for self-control. And so if you're going to diet,
"I'm going to skip lunch every day." Like holy,
you haven't full thought on that at some point
like a day with a big executive review, "I really
need to make sure I'm well-fed before I go into
this review," or something. And now you've broken
the streak and now it's over. Whereas if you say a
thing you know can do, "I will not have a dessert
unless it would be socially awkward for me to not
eat it. For example, in a small environment where
somebody made homemade dessert and all of us are
eating it, I'm going to..." So very clear black
and white rule that you can hold on forever.
So for example, since the pandemic started,
I've done a Peloton workout every
single day since the pandemic started.
Wow.
And now once I do start going back into the
office, if I had to commute into the office,
I would sometimes do a meditation to check the
box for that. But if I'm not commuting and I'm
not deathly sick, I've done a full workout since
then. And the idea each day of is today the day
of all the hundreds of days in this streak
that is the worst or the hardest for me to
do this thing? Is this the day? No, of course
it's not. I will do it. And so that keeps you
in this streak that makes it harder and harder to
get out of it. And in some ways, of course you can
torture yourself in an unproductive way like at a
certain point maybe you should stop that streak,
but I think those kinds of structuring help
you get the things done you want to get done.
It's like the Seinfeld trick of productivity where
you just keep track of how many days in
where you've done something essentially.
Yeah, exactly. And I think people don't
give those kinds of tactics enough credit
because there's lots of little social tricks to
yourself and others. This is when you have other
people who are depending on you for something
and will know that you didn't do the thing,
that were so much better. So just little tricks
like this help you be wildly more productive.
Actually, I want to go back a little bit. I'm
curious what you wrote down when we were chatting
earlier that you thought was a good articulation
if you're able to share, if it's interesting,
I wrote down, and the reason I wrote it
down is I've never... And by the way,
I collect everything even once I think
are maybe onto something. So I wrote down,
"A community with zero people speaking
is dead and a community with one person
speaking doesn't yet realize
it's dead," is what I wrote down.
So fun. I love this practice that you have.
By the way, the reason I can do it, I can
type insanely quickly. And in undergrad,
I wrote my thesis on the emergent power dynamics
in Wikipedia's user community and I did 150
hours of interviews with different editors in
Wikipedia, and I transcribed them myself. And
so I got really, really, really good at I can
just pipe an idea straight into my fingertips
and still listen to other stuff. So that's
another superpower is I've just constantly,
I'm able to capture it very, very quickly. I've
written notes that are at least good enough for
me to clean up within the next day or
two into something that's more stable.
Is there a way you built this
other than... Was it just you
did it and you had to do it and you
just figured out how to move fast?
I just realized later that I could
type really good, really fast. I
could just pipe it straight through to my
fingers and it worked. And, I don't know,
I don't know if I hadn't written my thesis,
would I have discovered that? I don't know.
I feel like everything you do is on super speed,
the way you think, the write and
get stuff done. There's a lot.
I just realized when-
... a lot of compute.
... when you're feeling productive, you're
unstoppable. And so just how can you be in
your flow state as much as possible? And there's
things that absolutely completely grind me to a
halt, and I just make sure I invest my time in
situations that don't have that characteristic.
So when I work on something that I believe
could work and have a big impact, I can't
stop. Sometimes I'll wake up at 4:00 in the
morning as I'm typically an early riser and I'm
just like, "I'll write this thing." The meeting
starts at 7:00 and I just think there's an idea
that's really cool here and I let myself lean
into those kinds of when I have the moment.
I also find that often if I have an idea
and I just have itching to write it down,
if I can write down 30 minutes and get a very
rough of it in one place, now it's easier to clean
it up later. But that first act of creation, I do
it whenever the muse hits because it's 10 million
times if it's like, "Oh, write that idea down
later," you keep on delaying it, delaying it,
now it's a month later. "What was the idea?
How did that work again?" It's gone. And so
I just try to capture the interesting insights.
It's like a butterfly collector. The butterflies
are going by, I try to collect them and put
them in my collection as quickly as possible.
Or garden as one might describe it.
Yeah.
This touches on a quote I wanted to talk
to you about. I think you described it as
your life philosophy. "Do things that give you
energy that you are proud of." Talk about that.
So to me, it's the combination of when you're
doing something you believe in and that gives
you energy, you are 10 times more productive. And
you also, the effort that you are doing is its
own reward. And so you are indefatigable on that
topic and you go for much longer. So finding the
substance of things that align with you that
give you energy, then just it's like infinite
energy. It's like they give an opportunity cost
because it energizes you more than the opportunity
cost of the time to go spend to other things.
And two, there are ways to give yourself energy,
like for example, playing a video game, or
there's any kind of mind-altering substance
that might give you that like, "This gives
me energy." Those are not things that I'm
not saying do those. I'm saying what are
the things that you'll look back and say,
"I'm glad I did that. I'm proud that I did that."
And if you take the perspective of a 10 years on
looking back on each decision and thing that
you're doing, and imagine seeing this decision
played in front of 1,000 people whose opinion you
care about, your family, your friends, your role
models, would you be proud is a good sign of life
that you're taking a broad enough perspective.
When you're busy and in the moment, it's so easy
to say, "I just got to do this one thing that's
probably not great to get this thing done. And
once I do it, it's going to suck. But once I do
it, it'll be fine." And then you find yourself
doing it again and again and again and again and
before you know it, you've lost who you want
to be and you're now a husk of yourself. And
so I think those two pieces lean into where you
find energy, where you specifically find energy,
your superpower, the thing that you intrinsically
enjoy doing, and just make sure it's something
that you are actively proud of and that helped
make sure you don't take a bunch of shortcuts.
Along those same lines, I think a lot of
people have heard a version of this quote,
which is, "New things that give you energy."
So one, I love the additional piece of it is,
"and that you're proud of." Two, you have another
quote that I love that makes you think deeply
about stuff, which is, "The secrets of life is
things you've heard a million times already,
you just weren't ready to hear
them." Talk about that insight.
So this I call the Hallmark card fallacy,
which is you discover at great effort some
deep insight that resonates with you and makes
you see the world differently, and you want to
share it. Insights are naturally viral. You
want to share them and you go tell someone,
it's like, "Guys, guys, the point of life is the
friends we made along the way." And people go,
"That's from a Hallmark card, man." And to
you, it is you now possess the knowledge,
the emotional intelligence to understand why that
phrase has been shared so many times. Before,
you heard it when you weren't ready and now
it becomes a trite, "Duh, everyone says that.
That can't possibly be a meaningful statement."
The reason people keep on saying it is because
it's meaningful. And so I think that having
that space of recognizing it, that when you
have these epiphanies that come from different
leaps in vertical development or the ability to,
when you stare into the abyss and make it through
the other side, you realize and learn a bunch of
amazing things that you want to pass on others,
and it's just really hard to get them to find it.
I find that that's one of the reasons I try to
write things that are or share ideas that are like
little seeds that you can shoot into someone's
brain even if the soil's not ready for it, it's
rocky or craggy, at some point in the future, if
something goes through there and opens up a crack,
that's sitting there to grow into an idea. One
of the things that makes me the happiest is when
someone I've mentored years and the years in the
past, they go search me out years later and say,
"Alex, I just want to let you know, you
probably don't even remember talking to me,
but that Tuesday at the building, the no-name
cafe or whatever, on Google campus, you said
something I was frustrated to hear in the moment I
didn't understand it. And I just want to tell you,
thank you because I finally understand what you
were trying to tell me. And I realized that that
influenced me in the decisions." That to me
is one of those meaningful things I can hear.
And so I just find that you can't force it
before people are ready to hear certain topics.
Man, that must feel so good to hear those sorts
of closing the loop on something long ago. The
point you make about cliches that you've heard
a million times actually finally feeling right
and profound, I had this very experience. I did
a psychedelic trip with some friends a while ago,
and at the end of it I was just like, "Man,
love is all you need. Love is all you need."
I felt that so deeply through the experience and
I was telling people, they're like, "Shut up."
You telling, oh, do you just do
psychedelics? Yeah, it's funny.
Yeah.
I have a lot of folks in my broader space who
obviously have used it. So I never personally
have myself, but I find there's various ways.
The transcendent mindset is this feeling of
being part of something much, much, much larger
than yourself and losing your ego in this thing.
There's different ways of doing it. Some people
will find it in hiking and being out in the
wilderness alone. Some people find it being at a
concert and thousands of people perfectly in sync
to this thing. Some people find it in religious
experience. Some people find it using psychedelics
and others to help get there. But a lot of it,
it's that same just being willing to be in awe.
There's so many times that people feel the feeling
of awe or wonder or curiosity is treated as a not
very serious or childlike thing. And I just
don't get that because that is how you are
open to disconfirming evidence. It's how you
see beyond the current limits of what you...
Your ego gets hurt when you get disconfirming
evidence. You don't want to hear it. And so
you'll construct the world around yourself
to not get that disconfirming evidence. But
disconfirming evidence is what makes systems
strong. It's what makes you strong. And so
how do you put yourself in the situation to
get that information and really receive it?
And part of it is just coming in terms
of the fact of early in my career,
someone called me kooky a bit. Oh, man. I must
be embarrassed. I'm like, "Okay, fine. Yeah,
I'm kooky, whatever." I'm totally at peace with
the idea that some people track me as kooky and
not particularly serious. I think people who watch
the work that I do and the indirect impact it has
realize that I'm doing something that is working
even if they don't fully understand how it works.
To start to close our conversation, I want
to throw out one more seed that might land
with someone in the right time. You have
this concept of the adjacent possible,
which I think is a really powerful concept.
And it's basically argues that a lot of people
jump to big bold ideas, and instead the better
approach is think about what's a constraint you
have and lean into the constraints and
use that as a guide. Can you just talk
about this and how this might inform how
people think about product and strategy?
Sure, yeah. The frame is the adjacent possible,
which is I believe comes from design thinking.
I've found it from designers in my life
who are the ones who would just speak to
it. And the adjacent possible is a set of actions
that you do, that you can do. They are right in
front of you that if you do them, they would
work, almost certainly work. And in the tech
industry in particular, we default assume that
the adjacent possible is like this and then flying
leap to something. And in reality, the adjacent
possible is quite small. It's within arm's reach.
And people will say, "Oh, you're being nihilist.
You're limiting your potential. You're saying
don't do big things." But when you recognize
that your adjacent possible is relatively small,
you realize that you actually have full agency to
pick within the subset that is within your reach,
and your actions matter because you take
an action and now the world reconfigures
and now you get a next set of actions and it's
based partially on the action you just took.
And so if you slice this thing up and you have
a coherent worldview and you have a principled
approach, you can arc to wildly different
outcomes than look like they were possible
while at each point, each individual action
is safe and reasonable. And so you can combine
both of these things. I think so many times
we try to jump and we jump to the end state
of the thing. And actually you don't need to
make that decision. If you can slice up your
decisions into smaller and smaller decisions, I'm
like, "This next step definitely makes sense."
It will almost certainly pay for itself or the
very least won't be too expensive. And then it
might allow these other things to happen and you
take it. And if those other things don't happen,
okay, don't take another step on that
path. That's fine. Go in other directions
for a while. If it does, then take another
step and another and another and another.
And this allows you to get rid of a lot of the
risk and still be exposed to all the upside.
And so the risk comes from trying to jump
too far ahead in an unknown environment.
Is the general advice if someone's working
on trying to figure out the roadmap,
trying to think about what products to
build is the advice, don't be scared
to go a little incremental versus what
people are always pushed, to do bigger.
You need both. So if you only do incremental, you
will follow the shortest, the steepest gradient
in front of you. So UXR says a user wants to do
this and you'll do exactly that and you'll end
up random walking through the thing. So you need
coherence about where you're going and the way you
get that is by creating a North Star for yourself.
It should be in three to five years in the future,
it should be very low resolution. It should
describe a thing that every single person who
reads it who has any kind of knowledge that might
be useful or relevant agrees that it is plausible.
If this happens, I would not say, "Well, a
miracle happened." It'd say, "I could see how
that could work." And lawyers say, "I could see
how that could work." And someone who's worked
on this 30 years ago at a similar product that
Microsoft says, "I can see how that could work."
And that if you got to the end point, everyone
would high five because if it's going to be a
thing, they're like, "I guess that could work." At
the end we'd be like, "Oh yeah, neat." That's not
worth it. You want another story would be like,
"Yeah, great. Wow, we kick off. We changed the way
this entire industry works," or whatever. And now
this is your North Star. North Star should update,
but it's because it's far off in the distance.
It will update. It will slide up across the sky
a little bit. It won't be jerking around. You'll
be arcing slightly differently. And then what you
do is you look in your adjacent possible and
you look for the thing that has the steepest
gradient that pulls you towards your North Star.
So you just want to go in that direction and you
want to go in this direction. This one is
second most in demand from what you think,
but it's pulling you the direction that you
believe will pull you there. Go in that one.
And then they keep on repeating. That's it. But
you need both. Because if you only do incremental,
then you'll end up random walking into a
corner. And if you only do the long-term,
you end up dreaming big and designing castles in
the sky that are impossible to actually manifest.
To give you a metaphor from an experience I
had, I did this silent meditation retreat once,
and a big part of Buddhism is to not cling
to a specific outcome and not have a plan
in mind and be sad if it doesn't work out.
And so I asked them just how do you achieve
success and want to be successful while not
doing that? And their metaphor is point your
card in a specific direction that you want to
go. Just point your card in that direction,
essentially in your example of North Star,
and just start walking. Don't figure out
this is exactly the path I'm going to
take to get to this end destination.
Yeah. And you'll know after the fact, you'll say,
"Oh, I curved a little bit or I had this little
jog than there." And you'll say, "Ah, it would've
been more efficient." But we're so focused on
efficiency of not wasting effort that we ended
up doing nothing at all or doing very dangerous
things that don't work. So I'm much sure that I
have a path that's slightly inefficient because
we're navigating unknowns and we couldn't know
no point. I think I've seen the number of times I
find where people say, "I need to know for this
strategy," that someone was trying to get me
to look at and then say, "is this number in five
years, is it going to be 93 or 95?" And it's like,
I don't know. And it doesn't matter either
if it's going to be that order of magnitude.
It doesn't matter, and we don't have to do that
analysis if we believe that the order of magnitude
is of that thing. It'd actually be we had spent
all the time to get the illusion of precision,
which at great expense, and then it's the
people say, "Oh, I'm data-driven. I want to
really run the analysis to ground." There's
tons of stuff you can't know ahead of time.
So if you're getting a false precision at the
beginner, that's a comfort blanket. That's just
helping you feel like there isn't uncertainty.
There's uncertainty everywhere all the time. And
trying to ignore it by trying to pin it down
with fake numbers that you just made up for
yourself at great expense is a really bad idea.
And that's why if the ideas are strong enough,
things that have a compounding return don't give
you, "Oh, we'll either get 93 or 95." It's like,
"We'll either get zero or we'll get 1,000." Great.
It doesn't really matter if it's 1,000 or 1,001,
who cares? It orders a magnitude larger
than the alternative, and so it is better.
That's really freeing. I noticed
again, you were writing something.
I'm again curious which you wrote
down that you thought was insightful.
I actually this time I was not writing did
something down. I was checking a thing I
thought you might say that was going to reference
was Tim Urban's, "Happiness is the reality minus
expectations." I always get that backwards,
but have you heard this frame, that happiness-
Let's get into it. Yeah, we're not
going to get this. This is great.
"Happiness is reality minus expectations," and
this is Tim Urban. It was from Wait But Why. And I
think it's a very simple distillation of it, of if
you set your expectations super high and it comes
in and it's amazing, but it's below it, then it's
a net negative. So the easiest thing, reality is
hard to change. It's not impossible. It's hard to
change. Your expectations are super easy. So just
change your expectations. Hold it lightly and
don't say, "Oh my gosh, this is going to be my
kid's birthday. She's going to remember it. It's
going to be the best birthday that she ever had
and we're all it's going to be perfect." Because
then when it doesn't go perfect and it starts
raining that day, you're like, "Gosh." You get
all worked up. Just say, "No, I want spend this
day in a way that I can look back on and remember
fondly." And that will include, yeah, it changed.
One other piece of advice someone gave me that
I really like is try to feel the emotion about
the story that'll make you feel in 10
years. So if it's funny in 10 years,
try to see the humor in it now. And this one in
particular was a friend, their newborn would,
every time you changed her diaper, would
poop. That was only... And when they did it,
it would often be projectile. And so it was like
a trap. You change the diaper. And it was like,
what are you going to do in that situation? And
then they're just like, "It's going to be a funny
story in a few years, so let's see the humor in it
now." Even though, God, I really wish this year-
That's funny.
... you're not spraying poop on her. And I
think that that kind of perspective is really,
people sometimes hear this as, "Oh,
you're saying don't dream big. Don't
set high expectations. Don't expect more and
be okay with mediocrity." That is not what
I'm saying. I'm saying hold those expectations
lightly. Allow them to change. Be willing to
be convinced by different things, and
seek something great. Seek something
that you can be truly proud of and that feel
very authentic to yourself if you achieved.
Alex, I feel like I could talk to
you for hours. I can't believe it's
already been almost an hour and a
half. So just to wrap things up,
is there anything else that you thought would
be fun to share or maybe a piece of wisdom you
want to leave listeners with before we
get to a very exciting lightning round?
I think we covered it. I think we
covered a lot of that. And again,
we could go on for hours and hours and hours
and hours. I could just do a random... I can
feature The Compendium where I can pull
up a random idea, and let's not do that.
Okay, amazing. Well, Alex, with that,
we've reached the very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
I am ready.
First question, what are two or three books
you've recommended most to other people?
Origin of Wealth by Eric Beinhocker, which
is great. It's about a complexity economics,
why the traditional economic model doesn't work,
and also why it takes an evolutionary lens on what
kinds of business plans work and how companies
execute them. That I found my entree into a lot
of the systems thinking and I thought it was
just absolutely brilliant. And the other one
is The Elements of Thinking in Systems, which is
short, easy to read, very approachable. In fact,
if anything, people think of it as not serious
enough because it's too easy to read. It's one
of those books that when you read at the beginning
you'll say, "This sounds right." And then later,
years later, if you read it again you'll go, "Oh
my God, that was so... I wasn't ready for that
yet, but that is totally the way." So she's one
of the people who talks about dancing the systems.
Let go and dance with the system is one of her
lines, and I think it's just a phenomenal book.
Next question. Do you have a favorite
recent movie or TV show you really enjoyed?
For me, I was thinking about this, it's The
Green Knight, which I watched I think a few
years old. It's about the Arthurian legend. It's
a challenging movie. In fact, when I watched it,
I was like, "I dislike this. I do not find this
interesting." And then I couldn't stop thinking
about it and it helped me. I think this is one
of the reasons I like to write in parable is a
parable is open-ended. It encourages and requires
the listener to engage into the idea and play with
it and see how it affects them and how they
affect it. And so for me, The Green Knight,
again, I'm not excited to watch it again, but I
found it to be the most impactful movie I've seen
in the last couple of years in terms of amount
of thinking that it caused me to do afterwards.
Wow, that says a lot. Next question,
do you have a favorite product you've
recently discovered that you really like?
To me, I think the answer for me is WebSim. It's
the one that I like playing around
with a lot. And I've said it before,
I use Claude 20 times a day. I find that
it's almost impossible for me to imagine
doing work. I mean of course now I've got to
use Strawberry and see how that feels, but yeah.
One use case of WebSim that I found really fun
that I used with Dylan is if you do Gmail, if you
give it gmail.com/someone's name, it just comes
up with what their email looks like. And could do
it for famous people, like for Patrick Allison or
whoever, and it's like, "Wow, that's really good."
The elements are really good. One of the
things we played around with is having a
thing that generates fake data of arbitrary
schemas, and I just write a short backstory
of a person and then have it generate
data that fits in this fictional user
person's world. And it's just amazing the
kinds of stuff, the coherence it has with,
it's weird and it's very specific to
that story, but elements are just so,
they're like these little holograms of all
this information of humanity is interesting
informational package, this little thing. And all
kinds, it's like a mirror that different things
reflect back out of it at you. And it's shocking
sometimes to see humanity reflected back at you.
It's like a zip file of all human knowledge.
Yeah, yeah.
Amazing. And it's because it's trained
on all the things we've written, right?
Yep.
All right, two more questions. You have a favorite
life motto that you often come back
to find useful in work or in life?
I guess I've said too, this
is cheating, but I said too,
the do things that give you energy that
you're proud of, and the happiness is reality
minus expectations I think are really
simple clarifying words to look like.
All right. Final question. You can
go in one of two directions. One is
what's something that you are going
to add to this week's Bits and Bobs
that you're thinking about right now
that we haven't talked about? Or just
go to your Compendium and pick a random
thing and see what comes up and share.
Okay, so this is the... I'll just read this off.
Great.
This is written a year ago.
"We've forgotten a world without
aggregators. Non-aggregator ecosystems
make it so participants don't have to fear
empowering their overlord, where that you have
to worry about each bit of action you're doing,
the aggregator is getting it more and more
powerful. MySpace was the Wild West. Facebook made
it so you can't change the CSS, which was better
for users, containing some freedom. Aggregators
make sense in the late stage of an era. At the
beginning, they curtail too much exploration."
That's just my random reflections. I don't
even remember what conversation that came from
originally, but of the power of... I am just
so obsessed with the idea that we are in the
late stage of this current technical paradigm
that we're in and so many things we feel like
we figured them all out and nothing can be any
different, and I don't love this outcome that
we're in, the idea of you're... Just one quick
framing. To me, if you ask somebody on the street
to tell you what the canonical piece of software
is, the answer they'll give you is something like
Instagram, which is to say an app, which I think
is a shame because an app is monolithic. It's one
size fits all. It's not decomposable. It doesn't
meaningfully interact with anything else in the
broader ecosystem. And it's also only allowed
to exist if some of the largest companies in the
world say it may exist, which is insane to me.
To me, software is alchemy. It's the ability to
extend human agency beyond ourselves to create
something that can then combine with what others
have created in unexpected and unforeseen ways
to create this commentary of possibility of human
agency. And somehow in the past decade, we've
become convinced that all of this potential should
be squeezed into about a dozen little boxes on
your phone. And now with the power of AI, everyone
just is default assuming that what's going to
happen is we're all going to be locked inside of a
box with a super God AI Clippy. And the only thing
that people disagree about is which Clippy is it
going to be? Whose Clippy is it going to be?
That to me is bonkers. I don't want that world
at all. I want a world where we use this magical
duct tape to escape the box, to allow software and
humans using it to lean into their agency. And I
think aggregators are amazing in an environment
where you have a safe environment to have all
kinds of interesting stuff that can't be fully
open-ended because the aggregator can't allow
it to escape the possibility of that ecosystem.
And so for me, one of the reasons I'm excited
about LLMs being a disruptive technology is
I think that it allows us to get out of this
monolithic sense of whatever. We're all just
beholden to a decreasing number, very powerful
organizations, and lean into everybody being
able to be creative and collaborative and
exercise their agency in a pro-social way.
Wow. Well, you blew our mind as a final
element of this conversation. Alex,
thank you so much for being here.
Two final questions. Where can folks
find you online? Where do they find stuff
you're working on if they want to read more
and follow the stuff you're thinking about?
And then how can listeners be useful to you?
Komoroske.com is where. My husband gives me so
much shit for it because it looks like it was
designed in the early 2000s, which it was. I link
to all the different posts there. If you click,
there's a Google group, but now where you can
subscribe to my updates whenever I post in the
Bits and Bobs or any medium article, that's a
good way of taking touch as I publish stuff.
And then the way that Google can be useful to
me is I have office hours on my site that are
open to anybody to join in. I am continually,
they're booked off in a few weeks in advance,
but if you find something that resonated with you
or that didn't, or you think is interesting or,
"Oh, here's a parallel. I don't know if you've
thought of it before," just reach out to me. And
I love, love, love talking to people, interesting
people especially who have life experiences and
backgrounds that are different from mine. At
one point, a magician showed up in my office
hours and described and said, "Hey, this tactic
you're talking about in your Bits and Bobs,
that's actually cold reading. That's what psychics
use." And I would find all these crazy connections
they'd never occurred to me before. And so people
just reaching out and sharing ideas and I love.
Alex, you're awesome. This conversation
was exactly what I was hoping it'd be.
My brain is buzzing as I expected.
Thank you so much for being here.
I'm excited for folks to listen
to this and to learn from you.
Thank you so much for having me.
Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.