We're going to be talking
about how to grow your power.
The reason why you should pay attention to this
is because it leads to a lot of good things,
salary, getting promoted, being happy
in your career, being less stressed.
You're not describing how the world
should work. This is just how it is.
Not only is, but how it was and how it will be.
The Seven Rules of Power, get out of your own way,
break the rules, show up in a powerful fashion,
create a powerful brand, network relentlessly,
use your power, and understand that once
you've acquired power, what you did to get
there will be forgiven, forgotten, or both.
This is not about personality. These
are skills they can be mastered.
People might be hearing this and they're
like, "I don't want to be this person."
Well, you already have done a fabulous job
of illustrating principle one. That is one
way to get in our own way. If I think
power is dirty, the first thing that's
going to happen is I'm not going to do what
I need to do to be successful in my career.
The opening quote to your book that I have here,
if you want power to be used for good,
more good people need to have power.
That's exactly right.
Today, my guest is Jeffrey Pfeffer. Jeffrey is a
Professor of Organizational Behavior at Stanford's
graduate School of Business, and teaches one of
the two most popular and oversubscribed courses in
all of the MBA program, called the Paths to Power.
The other class, by the way, is Touchy-Feely,
which we dove into last month. In his class and
in his recent book, the Seven Rules of Power,
Jeffrey teaches the things that you can do in
your life and in your work to build your power,
and through that get things done and advance in
your career. As one student described the class,
it's the cod liver oil of the Graduate School
of Business. You know it's good for you,
but you feel a little nervous about it.
In our conversation, we dig into each of
the seven powers, why it's important to build
these skills even if you feel uncomfortable.
We talk through a bunch of examples of the power
in action and the impact it has had on people's
lives, why it isn't as cringey or scary as you
may think. I was actually nervous to have this
conversation and I ended up being a huge fan of
Jeffrey and the work that he does. We end the
conversation with what you can start doing today
to start building your own power. This podcast
is basically for anyone that wants to advance
in their career, whether you're an IC or a CEO,
and I'm really excited to bring it to you. If
you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting app or
YouTube. It's the best way to avoid missing future
episodes, and it helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you Jeffrey Pfeffer.
Jeffrey, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you, Lenny. I am honored
that you invited me on.
I'm even more honored that you decided
to come on. We're going to be talking
about something that makes a lot of people
uncomfortable. I think it's going to make
me uncomfortable. We're going to be talking
about how to grow your power in life and in
business. Let me just start by asking why
does this stuff make people uncomfortable,
and why is it still important for
people to learn how to do this well?
Well, it's important because a guy named Gerald
Ferris developed a scale of political skill.
And he and a bunch of his colleagues over
the years did a lot of empirical research
that demonstrates that political skill is
associated with a lot of positive outcomes,
salary, getting promoted, being happy
in your career, being happy in your job,
being less stressed. So the reason why you
should pay attention to this is because it
leads to a lot of good things. The reason why
it makes people uncomfortable. You said it made
you uncomfortable. Maybe I should ask you the
question, why does it make you uncomfortable?
There's a lot of things here that
are probably not how people want to
live their life necessarily,
or want other people to act.
Yeah, so I think it makes people uncomfortable
because the realities of what it takes to get
power bear almost no resemblance to what you're
taught in Sunday school or the mosque or wherever,
how your parents raised you. They bear almost no
resemblance to how we think the world ought to be.
They bear a little resemblance to our aspirations.
And I think we look around the world and we see
people who have acquired enormous amounts of
power and have used it for bad. But I tell people,
I see people with hammers hitting other people
on the head. That does not mean that a hammer
is not a useful tool. You can take a screwdriver
and stab it into somebody's belly. I have a very
dear friend who we'll probably talk about later
in the podcast. Laura Esserman is a breast cancer
surgeon, and I tell people, Laura has a knife.
She uses it to cure cancer. Muggers have knives.
They use it to rob people. So I think we've
confused the tool for how it has been used.
You also have this quote that the people who need
to understand power and build their power skills
are people who come from
backgrounds or characteristics
who would normally put them at a disadvantage.
I think that's exactly right. I will go this
Sunday to Nashville Tennessee to talk to a
bunch of people of color in the NFL who are
trying to rise up the ranks. Stanford runs
a program because the NFL is serious, I think,
about trying to make more opportunity for people,
underrepresented minorities. But these
are folks who will not succeed unless
they learn power skills, because the world
is stacked against them in lots of ways.
This episode is brought to you by Uizard,
empowering product leaders to ideate and
iterate faster than ever before with the power
of AI. As a product manager, I often spend
hours taking screenshots and then annotating
them with feedback for my team. With Uizard,
I can simply upload my screenshot and Uizard's AI
will turn them into a fully editable UI design,
that I can then take, make tweaks to, and then
share with my teams in minutes. And when I want
to get really creative and explore totally
new ways to improve our product experience,
I can use Uizard's AI to generate new design
concepts from simple text prompts, and turn
them into interactive prototypes effortlessly.
There's a reason that over 2.6 million people
have trusted Uizard to accelerate every phase
of their product life cycle and speed up time
to market. Developers can even export UI
components to React and CSS to speed up
their development. Uizard's drag and drop editor
is super easy to use and you can collaborate in
real time with your entire team. Even your CEO and
customer service teams can contribute. Unlock all
of Uizard's game-changing AI powered features
and more with 25% off Uizard's Pro annual plan.
Visit uizard.io/Lenny and use code Lenny
to check out today. That's uizard.io/Lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Webflow. We're
all friends here, so let's be real for a second.
We all know that your website shouldn't be a
static asset. It should be a dynamic part of
your strategy that drives conversions. That's
Business 101. But here's a number for you. 54%
of leaders say web updates take too long.
That's over half of you listening right
now. That's where Webflow comes in. Their visual
first platform allows you to build, launch, and
optimize web pages fast. That means you can set
ambitious business goals and your site can rise
to the challenge. Learn how teams like Dropbox,
IDEO and Orange Theory trust Webflow to achieve
their most ambitious goals today at Webflow.com.
Another element of your course that you try to
make clear in your syllabus is to teach
people not to be as judgmental. You also
have this whole huge bold phrase, "This class
is not for everyone." Can you just talk a bit
about maybe why it's not for everyone and
then why being less judgmental is important?
The class is extremely popular. I have a
long waiting list. It's kind of mythical.
And because of the principle of social
influence, we are influenced by what other
people do. We're influenced in our choices of
restaurants, we're influenced in our choices
of music. I'm not sure I like Taylor Swift, but
I certainly want to go see Taylor Swift because
everybody else is. And many people sign up
for the class. And one year in particular,
there were some people who sat in about the third
row up, directly in front of me, and they looked
every day like they were having some terrible
thing put up some horrible orifice or something.
They looked literally in pain, and so I decided,
and of course they learned nothing. If you come to
the class and you're in that much psychological
discomfort, you're not going to learn anything.
And so what I try to do is tell people that in
order to benefit from this class, you have to
be open to learning the material. And if you're
not, and by the way, this would be true for any
class. If you go to physics and you say, I don't
like physics, I hate physics, I don't believe in
physics, I don't believe in the theory of physics,
whatever, you're not going to learn anything. And
so I'm trying to get the class, given those huge
waiting lists, I'm trying to get the class to have
people in it who are in fact going to benefit from
it rather than sit there and look like they're
in pain. And the judgmental thing, if Matthew 7,
"Judge not that ye be not judged." The Koran says,
"Only Allah can judge people." The American poet,
Walt Whitman said, "Be curious, not judgmental."
Mother Teresa said, "If you judge people, you
have no time to love them." Judgment, if I
need to build a positive relationship with Lenny
because you are on my critical path in my job,
and jobs necessarily entail a reasonable amount
of interdependence, I get things done through
and with other people. If I decide that Lenny is
whatever set of bad adjectives you want to use,
dumb, incompetent, immoral, whatever, my ability
to build a positive relationship with you,
and you remain on my critical path, becomes
almost zero unless you're a better actor or
I'm a better actor than I think most people are.
So therefore, you should suspend judgment in the
sense that if somebody is on your critical path,
the only judgment you should make is they're
on my critical path. If I want to get something
done, I need their collaboration and cooperation,
and the fact that I may not like them is in fact
irrelevant. And as I have taught senior executives
over the years, it is absolutely clear to me that
one of the skills that they have mastered is they
have a skill that you cannot tell what they think
of you. And that's important because I need your
collaboration, I need your cooperation. And if I
leak out in ways that say I don't respect you or I
don't like you, I don't admire you, whatever,
my odds of getting you to work productively
with me goes essentially to zero. So that's
a judgmental story. Does that make sense?
Absolutely. And I have a quote from your syllabus
along these lines, "Not everyone we encounter in
Paths to Power is someone you're going to want
to emulate. This is a class about how to get
things done, how to build and wield influence,
and there are multiple ways to accomplish these
objectives." So I've had two friends actually go
through the course. One I asked about the course
of the impact it had on her. She's actually
a founder now. And she told me that your
class was her single most favorite class at all of
Stanford Business School, because it was realistic
and applicable to life as a founder. Because it
didn't sugarcoat business, didn't sugarcoat life.
It told her how the world really works and it is
helping her succeed with her startup right now.
Thank you. There's no higher praise
than that. I actually don't read,
I shouldn't probably say this on
the public, but I don't actually
read my course evaluations because the impact
I want to have is not to have people like me,
but to have that kind of impact. To make people
more successful, more effective in their lives.
That is a good segue to one of your rules of
power. So let's just talk about your Seven Rules
of Power. I actually have your book right here
and if folks want to learn more, here it is, Seven
Rules of Power. This is your fourth book about
power, and this is your best book about power,
because it basically summarizes everything you've
learned in a really cohesive way. So let me first
share the Seven Rules of Power and then I'm going
to dive into a few of them. Does that sound good?
That sounds perfect.
Okay, so the seven rules, one,
get out of your own way. Two,
break the rules. Three, appear powerful. Four,
build a powerful brand. Network relentlessly.
Use your power, and success excuses almost...
Everything, correct.
Okay, success excuses everything almost. Got
it. Okay. So let me start with power four,
which is around personal brand. And
the reason I want to start here is I
have a friend that's actually in your class
right now, Ralph, and I saw that he started
a podcast. And he told me that he did it
because it was part of the homework that
you give students. You call it Doing Power.
Is that the name of the homework assignments?
Yeah, I have. So we give them a bunch
of assignments throughout the class,
which are self-reflective assignments, but
their big thing for the class is they have
to do power. They have to do something during
the quarter to take the principles of the class,
and what they're learning, and put them into
practice. And that is because everything I do,
I do for a reason. That is because if you
don't use what you learn, the learning will
disappear. So if you go to a French class and
you learn French, and you never speak French,
in about a relatively short period of time
you'll forget everything you learn. And so I
want the learning to stick with them, so
I try to get them to do something with it.
While we're on this tangent, I
wanted to talk about this whole,
you have a book, the Doing Knowing Gap.
Knowing-Doing Gap.
The Knowing-Doing Gap. So let's just spend
a little time there. I think that's really
important. What are some examples of
things that have come out of people
doing these homework assignments, things
that maybe led to something interesting?
Let me take my most extreme example. My
most extreme example is probably Derek Kan,
K-A-N. And Derek Kan was a little bit older when
he went through the MBA program. And in 2012,
his Doing Power project was to
get appointed to be Mitt Romney's,
it was Mitt Romney was running for president,
to be head of economic policy for the Romney
campaign. Believe it or not, he was
offered the job. Believe it or not,
he turned it down for reasons which we could go
into if you want, but aren't that interesting.
He wound up relatively soon thereafter as
number three in the transportation department,
working for Elaine Chao. And I have a
picture of him when he comes to the class,
I introduce him. I tell students, I give them a
trigger warning and I introduce him. He wound up,
at the end of the Trump administration,
as the deputy director of the Office of
Management and Budget. And since typical of the
Trump administration, by that time there was no
director. He essentially ran the $6 trillion US
budget. This is six years out of business school.
I was thinking whether he got that
during his class. Amazing. Okay,
so this is a success story of Doing Power. Let's
talk about this first power of building brand,
and I think this is where people start to feel
uncomfortable. They're going to be like, oh no,
I don't want to be doing this.
This doesn't feel good to me.
Why?
So let's talk about it.
Okay.
Let's see. So talk about this
power of building a personal brand.
There are by definition fewer positions at the top
than at the bottom. The world, we might not like
this, and I know people, the late Tony Hsieh,
the Zappos tried to do holacracy or whatever,
but the world is essentially hierarchical. The
animal kingdom is hierarchical. It is better to
be at the top than at the bottom for a number of
reasons. Okay. If that is true, if there are fewer
positions at the top and then at the bottom, then
your job to advance your career is to figure out
how to get promoted. There are many ways to get
promoted, but I will guarantee you one thing,
no one is going to promote Lenny if they don't
know who the hell you are. So it is not sufficient
for them to know who you are. They have to know
that you're smart and personable and have whatever
skills you've got, but they have to know you.
If they don't know you, you cannot choose what
is not in your head. You know that better than
I do. So therefore you have to do something to
differentiate yourself. You have to build a brand.
So when I think of Lenny in your podcast, I think
of something. Not just 25 billion podcasts. When
I think of somebody in McKinsey or Bay or BCG,
one of the consulting firms, a gazillion people
start off as front-line consultants. What are you
going to do so that somebody knows who you
are? What are you going to do that creates
value for the firm and for you? So my friend Keith
Ferazzi, when he started at Deloitte Consulting,
did not do the spreadsheet stuff that he was,
by the way, not very good at and didn't like.
He started the Lincoln Quality Award. He
decided to try to take Deloitte's brand
recognition from about one or 2% to 30%.
He was appointed, though he left before
he actually took the job, to the position of
partner and the first chief marketing officer
at Deloitte. I have another friend, Tristan
Walker, who wanted to get hired at Foursquare.
He sent emails to the founder. The founder
ignored him. So Tristan Walker did something
I think very bold. Tristan Walker began signing
up partnerships. So one day the founder says,
holy God, he signed up Starbucks. Maybe I
ought to hire this guy. So you have to do
something that causes people to know who you
are, and that is what building a brand is about.
It sounds very benign put that way. When
people hear, I need to build a personal brand,
it sounds like I need to post on LinkedIn, I
need to post on Twitter, start a newsletter,
start a podcast, which I know is kind
of a part of it. But what are some
examples you've seen of ways to build
a personal brand that are effective?
So I have a friend who I bring to the class,
a lovely tall Asian woman named Laura Chau,
who made partner at a venture capital firm after
four years, which is fast. Laura works for Canaan
Partners, C-A-N-A-A-N. Laura said, I do not
work for Andreessen Horowitz, I do not work for
Sequoia, I don't work for Greylock, I don't work
for any of these very visible large VC firms. So
if I am going to get deals in the consumer space,
that's her domain of expertise is consumer and
consumer tech, somebody is going to have to know
who Laura Chau is. Because again, you're not going
to get the deal if nobody knows who you are.
And so she basically did everything you talked
about. She did writing. She started a podcast
in which she invited influential people on.
She contributed to a book. She helped people out.
She did networking dinners. She did everything she
could so that people would recognize and know
Laura Chau. And one of the things she did was
she's tall. In general, Asian women are not tall.
She decided to play up the fact that she was,
in the words of some people, the tallest
Asian woman they'd ever seen. She wears
heels. In her heels she's six feet one inches
tall. She also, when she comes to my class,
many people come to my class with hoodies, God
knows what. She has style and it's a unique style.
So she thinks about very strategically, how am
I going to dress? How am I going to look? How
am I going to show up? How am I going to do what I
need to do so that people know who I am? Obviously
there's substance. If you have visibility without
substance, people will know you're useless. But if
you have substance without visibility, no
one will know the substance that you got.
You also talk about how you can reframe
this idea of not being self-promotional,
but it's amplifying the impact
of the team that I work with,
or it's me scaling myself by sharing
things I know and pointing people to it.
Absolutely, absolutely.
Awesome. Okay, let's move on to a different
power. Let's talk about power one, which is
getting out of your own way. Talk about what
that means and how someone can work on that.
Well, you already have done a fabulous job of
illustrating principle one by talking about how
this is the topic that makes people uncomfortable.
And when something makes people uncomfortable, in
general, they're going to shy away from it. So if
I think power is dirty, if I think power is evil,
if I think power is something I want nothing to
do with, the first thing that's going to happen
is I'm not going to do what I need to do to be
successful in my career. So that is one way in
which we get in our own way. Another way in which
we get in our own way, many people suffer from
what is called in the psychology literature,
imposter syndrome. They believe that they were
the admissions mistake at Stanford. They were the
hiring mistake in whatever company they're working
for. That somehow they got to this job, but they
don't really deserve to be there because they're
surrounded by people who are smarter and better
than them, and therefore they will do things.
I can't even believe that this goes on. So I
will have students, not many, but a few. Now
raise their hand, I'll call them, and the first
things out of their mouth will be, I don't know
if this comment is going to be useful. This is
called pre-emptory apology. If the comment is
not going to be useful, don't say it. That's
number one, but number two, don't apologize.
Pardon me for interrupting. Pardon me for taking
up your time. Stop all this apologizing. If you
got the job you're in, you probably are not only
qualified, you're probably overqualified. So don't
use descriptors of yourself that disempower you.
Don't think of yourself as not deserving of the
job that you hold, because that attitude will
leak out and other people will say, if Lenny
doesn't think he deserved the job, then maybe
I shouldn't think he deserves the job either.
So basically the first power is you're shooting
yourself in the foot by worrying too much about
whether people like you. This friend of mine who's
now the founder that I read some quotes from,
she said her number one takeaway from your
class is if you want to be liked, get a dog.
That's correct. That is a quote
from my dear friend Gary Loveman,
who for many years ran Harrah's, which
then became Caesars, the casino company.
You also talk about this. Yeah, there's this
quote I have. "Acknowledge that others are
often no better than you, because that makes you
feel better about the story." So for people that
actually want to be liked, I like being liked.
I don't know if it's a flaw in my upbringing. Is
the lesson you're capped on your power if
you worry about if you want to be liked?
At the end of the day, you don't want to be
intentionally disliked. You don't want to
violate my dear friend Bob Sutton's book
The No Asshole Rule and gratuitously be
an asshole. But you are hired to get a job
done. It's interesting. I unfortunately am
now too old. In the words of my chiropractor,
I'm suffering from too many birthdays. So I
have a lot of doctors who are doing a great
job. Trust me, when I choose a doctor, I have a,
unfortunately he retired, a neurosurgeon who
did two surgeries on my spine. He's considered
to be one of the top 20 in the country.
If you go on Yelp, you read about his
personality and his office furniture. As I said
to somebody, he's doing microsurgery on my spine,
I can wind up permanently paralyzed. I
really don't care about his personality.
I don't care about his office furniture.
That's an extreme example, but it makes
the point. When you are put in a role, you
are put in a role because presumably you
are supposed to perform in that role. If you
get appointed to be a head coach, if we make
you a quarterback on an NFL team, or we make you
center on a National Basketball Association team,
you did not get that job because people thought
you had a cute personality. You got that job
because you have the skills to make your
organization successful. And if you do
not use those skills because you're worried about
what everybody else is thinking, you are not only
harming yourself, but you're harming them because
you are not doing what you were hired to do.
So a simple way of thinking about this, which
makes me feel better about. As we talk through
this, I'm becoming less uncomfortable with
these, which is a good sign. It's don't
actively try to be disliked. Don't prioritize
being liked, prioritize competence and respect.
Correct, absolutely.
And doing the thing that needs to be done.
Absolutely.
Okay, great. Let's talk about rule number two,
which is break the rules. So basically again,
these powers are ways to grow power, and
you're saying that if you break the rules,
you get more power. Talk about why
that's the case, what that looks like.
Well, for many reasons, number one, when you break
the rules, you stand out. You become memorable
when you do something that's unexpected. And
being memorable is of course important, as we've
already discussed. That's number one. Number
two, the rules were made mostly by the people
who are favored by the rules in place. So if we
were talking about business strategy, we would
talk about a word that is probably now overused.
We would talk about being a disruptor. That you
would disrupt an industry. And how do you disrupt
an industry? By doing something that is different
from the other industry incumbents. In Southwest
Airlines, you don't do hub and spoke. At Amazon,
you provide an incredible level of customer
service. Whole Foods, you don't optimize on the
cost of the stuff in your store, but you optimize
on fitting local taste, whatever. You would be a
disruptor, you would do things that are different.
The same principle holds for you, that if you are
going to be successful, you have to do what
number one, plays to your strengths, to use
the title of a Gallup book. Number two, you have
to do things again that cause you to stand out,
and you have to do things that basically
will make you more successful. One of the
conventional wisdoms that people I think adhere to
way too much, is don't ask. Don't ask, don't ask
for help. You need to show self-sufficiency.
So my colleague, Frances Flynn, Frank Flynn,
wrote an article with Vanessa Lake entitled, If
You Need Help, Just Ask. And it turns out people
overestimate how many people they're going to have
to ask to get help, and it turns out that asking
for help makes people uncomfortable.
I was married, if you read the acknowledgments
in Seven Rules of Power. For more than 35
years I was married to Kathleen Francis Fowler,
who I could send you a picture. She looked
literally like a supermodel and I never have
been any particularly better looking than I am
now. So somebody said to me, how'd you get her
to go out with you? And the answer of course is,
I asked. I asked, I asked, I asked. No one, well,
maybe not no one. But few people are going
to go out with you if you don't ask them out.
Few people are going to marry you if you don't
ask them to marry. Few people are going to do
anything if you don't ask. And what is the worst
that could happen? If you ask and they say, no,
you are no worse off than had you not asked in the
first place. If you don't ask, you're not going to
get it. If you ask and they say, no, you're
not going to get it. Get over your ego, ask.
Is there another example that comes to mind
of someone breaking the rules say in business,
that ended up being really successful as a result,
or just someone that is really
good at this in business?
I can give you many examples. One
of my favorite examples would be
Jason Calacanis. I don't know if you know Jason.
Oh yeah, I know you did a case
study on him. I know him well. Yeah.
So I think Jason, I think consistently
breaks all kinds of rules. First of all,
when he comes to my class, nobody likes him,
but that's okay. Almost nobody likes him. But...
That's power number one. He's not worried about.
Yeah, that's number one. But also I think
there's a conventional wisdom in the venture
capital industry which he defies almost
completely. He makes a lot of little bets,
not a few big bets. He runs a very lean operation.
He doesn't have a lot of partners. He doesn't
have actually any partners, so he can't be
fired by his partners. He began his career
in journalism, which is interesting. Being a
journalist is a wonderful job because you get
to ask people all kinds of questions. And if
you ask smart people questions, and you have
some reasonable level of intelligence
yourself, at the end of that process,
you're going to wind up incredibly
smart and incredibly insightful. And
he wound up incredibly smart and insightful
around aspects of the internet industry.
And he definitely has a lot of power. I think
I am going to link to the case study in our
show notes where you basically walk through how
he went from nothing to a very powerful person.
And by the way, a very rich person as well.
Let's talk about another power, power five,
networking relentlessly. What does that
look like and how do you get better at this?
Well, I think there's research that shows
that many people find networking dirty,
and that's because I think they think about it
in the wrong way. My friend John Levy, who has
written a fabulous book, You're Invited. Which
is a book about how to put on events that people
want to come to. Is a fabulous human being. Will
tell you that the first principle of networking is
in fact generosity. It's generosity. What can
I do for you? How can I be helpful? Who can I
introduce you to? Either a company or a product or
a person who can be helpful to you in your career.
But in order to be able to introduce you
to someone who's going to be useful to you,
I have to know people. If I don't know anybody,
I can't introduce you to anybody. And the more
people I know, the more likely it will be that if
you say, I need to know somebody in X, I will know
that person. So the broader your social network,
the more people and the more things you will know.
If knowledge is power, networking is a fabulous
way to get knowledge about people and about ideas.
It's funny to hear this where it's
like, yes, obviously this is right,
but connecting it to if you want to
become more powerful, more successful,
you need to do this. I think that is a
powerful point that we're all making here,
is just like this actually is necessary
if you want to acquire more power.
Of course. I have a funny story about networking.
So we have a thing in Stanford called View From
The Top, in which these fancy people come in
and give a talk. And one of the people came
in and give a talk and made my class instantly
popular, because he's an extraordinarily wealthy
person. His name is Omid Kordestani, and so I
reached out to him and I said, "Omid, let's have
breakfast." So I can understand because during
the thing, when somebody asked them what class
was the most important in his success, he said
mine. So I said, "Tell me your story." He said,
"Well, I graduated from Stanford. I'm Persian in
background, immigrant background. An engineer,
HP, all the things that would make you
kind of a nerd or something." He said,
"I went to work for a couple of startups
that didn't do well. Then I found myself
in the mid-nineties at Netscape." The browser
company, big deal. Anyway, Marc Andreessen.
Oh yeah.
Okay. "So I found myself in Netscape in marketing
and business development. I was not making any
progress. One day I decided to take your class to
an extreme. I decided to stop doing my job." So
I said, "When people gave you projects to do or
assignments or tasks and you didn't do them?" He
said, "It turns out that I spent my time, not
obviously at the bar, but in networking first
with people inside of Netscape. And it turns out
if you're well-connected to the senior leaders,
they don't really care if you do your job or
not. That's number one. Number two," he said,
"oftentimes I can find other people to do the work
I was doing. So instead of basically spending time
doing my job, I networked first within Netscape."
But Netscape was not that big of a company. So
after a while he decided to go through, which
is by the way, his job anyway, in marketing and
business, he decided to basically drive through
the Silicon Valley talking to people. And this
is the rest of the browsers are just beginning.
Nobody knows what a browser is, nobody knows what
the internet is going to become. So he's having
all these fabulous conversations. All right,
so he now knows basically everybody. It's 1998
and a little tiny company decides 10 engineers,
typical Silicon Valley company. 10 engineers,
all engineers. I have a friend who went to
work for a company, run a company that
had 26 people. He didn't have one sales
and marketing person. Anyway, the company
now has 10 engineers. They decide they need
to hire their first business person. Being
an analytically oriented company, they say,
we're going to do this very analytically. We are
basically going to ask everybody we can think of,
and a few people we can't. Give us a list
of the best technically oriented business
people that you know. And there is of course
one name that appears on every list. It is
Omid Kordestani who becomes employee number 11 at
Google and makes two and a half billion dollars.
Great success from networking. Well done. When
people hear about networking, it just feels like
you said, very cringe. I don't want to go to these
networking events and try to pretend to talk and
care about people. Do you have any advice for
just how to make networking feel less cringy?
One of the exercises I give my students
is I say, write a list of 10 people who,
if you knew them and if they knew you, would be
important for whatever you're trying to accomplish
in your career. So maybe you're trying to get into
biotech, you need to know 10 executives in biotech
or whatever. Make a list of 10 people. Then for
each person figure out how you are going to meet
them. By the way, not necessarily in a network
event. Maybe you want to do what John Levy does,
which is hold dinners. In which by
the way, the guests do the cooking,
which is a very interesting idea. That
of course taps into the IKEA effect. You
always like something better if you participate in
creating it. Maybe you want to hold dinners, maybe
you want to try to reach out to them at lunch.
Maybe you want to reach out to them and say,
here's an article I think you'd be interested in.
Here is somebody who I think you'd benefit from
meeting. So recently, I'm not a particularly good
networker, though I'm better I guess than some
people. I recently met Esther Wojcicki, I'm sure I
killed her name. She's considered the grandmother
of Silicon Valley. She's Susan Wojcicki's
mother. And she is interested in depression,
particularly depression among teenagers.
And I said, you should know Leanne Williams,
who's in the Psychiatry and Behavioral Science
Department, who has done probably 300 articles
on depression and has invented something which
is called Precision Psychiatry. So I connected
them to each other. Just send an email. I think
you ought to know each other. They got together.
I get credit for knowing people and connecting
them, but I also benefit them. Leanne needs to
raise money. Esther's got money. Esther needs to
understand the cutting edge research in depression
and biomarkers of depression, which is what
Leanne's specialty is, so they benefit. So this
is not some icky thing. This is connecting
people who benefit from being connected.
That touches on something
you teach in the book is,
in your networking you want to become a
broker, you want to be central. That's
kind of what you want to work on. Can
you talk a bit about what that means?
Well, that means you want to connect people.
So many people with benefits, and many groups
with benefits for being connected, and they're
not connected. What does a venture capitalist
do? Connects people with ideas to people with
money, and takes a fee for doing it. What does
an investment banker do? Connects people
trying to sell businesses or raise capital
with people trying to buy businesses or who
have capital. What's a real estate agent do?
Connects buyers and sellers of houses. There
are all kinds of examples where the person's
entire job is connecting people. But even for
the people whose job it isn't, you benefit from
knowing people. The more people you know, the more
things you know. As I sometimes say in my class,
if leadership management, call it what you will,
is getting things done through other people, it
seems like common sense that the more other people
you know, the more you'll be able to get done.
As someone that has become central to a lot of
things in the product world, and has built a large
network as a result of this podcast newsletter,
I can tell you a thousand percent. This creates
a lot of opportunity and power, you could
say in quotes. So I've seen it happen.
Of course.
This episode is brought to you by Heap,
the product analytics solution that shows
you everything users do on your digital
product, website, mobile product or other
digital services. We all know a great digital
experience when we see it. It's intuitive,
it anticipates your needs, and it makes it easy
for you to do your job. If you're trying to build
that kind of experience for your users, you need
up to date, reliable information about what your
users do in your product and why they do it. Want
to know how your users behave across platforms,
what keeps them coming back, what they're
doing that you're not even aware of? Well,
I have some great news for you. Heap captures
all of this user activity for you automatically,
and then gives you definitive answers to all
your questions about user behavior in seconds,
not weeks. With Heap, it's easy to prioritize
the product investments that improve conversion,
engagement and retention. Visit
heap.io/Lenny to get started with a
demo. That's H-E-A-P dot I-O slash Lenny.
Another lesson I guess you teach is to
pursue weak ties. Talk a bit about what
that means. What do you mean by that?
Well, the people to whom you are strongly tied,
your family, your spouse, significant other,
your friends, the people who work with you at
work will probably, because they are close to you,
know the same things and the same people that
you do. So to the extent that you build ties
with people who are more different from you in
every dimension, you are more likely to learn
non-redundant information, and come in contact
with people that you don't already know. This
again seems common sense. There's a lot
of research behind it. Mark Granovetter,
a sociologist who still teaches at Stanford,
wrote a book entitled The Strength of Weak Ties.
And basically, no, actually, pardon me. He wrote
an article called The Strength of Weak Ties. His
book was called Getting a Job. And he did a
study, I guess it was at that time in Boston.
He did a study of job seekers in Massachusetts,
and he looked at people who got jobs through
applying to ads, through more formal means. And
then he looked at people who got jobs through
referrals from their network. And it turns out, of
course, the jobs that you get through your network
referrals are much better jobs. And oftentimes
the best jobs that people got were referred to
them by people that were not particularly
close to them. Because they had a view,
that's the word I was looking for, a view
into the ecosystem of the Boston labor market,
that the other people didn't have because they
weren't in the same place as the other people.
I love that lesson. Let's
talk about another power,
which is using your power. So when people
think of using your power builds more power,
that's not intuitive. You talk about
how it creates this self-perpetuating
growth of power the more you practice
power. Can you talk a bit about that?
Sure. So when you are given, it's
interesting, my friend Deborah Gruenfeld,
who wrote a book called Acting with Power,
talks a lot about people's ambivalence
to power. So sometimes people are put in
a job. Herminia Ibarra who teaches now at
London Business School, at one point taught
in Seattle, at one point taught at Harvard,
has an article in the Harvard Business
Review in which she talks about a woman
in a drug company who gets a promotion, and says
to her colleagues, to whom she's now overseeing,
that she's not sure why she got the job. She's not
sure she deserves the job. Needless to say, she
didn't do very well in this job because she got
in her own way. But part of this is you are put
in a position of power. You're put in a position
of authority in order to make things happen. So
to the extent you mobilize your resources and
get things to happen, you'll get more resources.
People want to be associated with success.
To the extent that you become successful,
more people will want to work with you. To
the extent that you get more stuff done,
you'll get more promotions, more opportunities.
Nobody's going to give you a job to do if the last
five jobs like that they gave you, you couldn't
get done. So the more you are able to do, which
oftentimes of course requires power and influence,
the more you're able to do, the more you'll be
asked to do. But better yet, the more resources
you'll be given to help you get things done.
And I think there's interestingly
you teach that just showing that
you have power creates more power.
People see that you have this power
and they start to follow your lead
more, right? That's a part of this.
Yep. I just saw over the weekend the movie, the
latest movie in the franchise of the Planet of
the Apes. When Jim Collins left Stanford, he
gave me a book called Chimpanzee Politics,
which is of course not based on the Planet
of the Apes, but it's based upon the study
of chimpanzees. We are the same. People are
attracted to power, you know that. By the way,
that will account for a lot of what is going
to happen in the presidential election.
Let's save that for the end, because I think
that's an interesting piece of your book,
of the connection to Trump. So let's save
that for a bit. I think that'll be really
interesting. Kind of along the same lines of the
area we're just talking about. And another rule
of power is to show up in a powerful fashion. So
look powerful, talk about what that looks like.
So my colleague at Berkeley, Dana Carney,
C-A-R-N-E-Y, is writing a book called Tell,
which is about the importance of body language
and how to master body language. There is some
evidence that suggests we respond mostly to
how people look, secondarily to how they sound,
and by far the least important to the content
of what they say. You can see this by turning
on your TV and turning off the sound. Watch the
presidential debates with the sound off. They'll
be much better. I have another colleague
in marketing by the name of Baba Shiv,
who talks about people's freaky mind, or the
idea that we are in fact descended from primates,
and that we are controlled in lots of ways by
our emotions. And so we respond affectively to
other people. We respond to how they look. There's
evidence in economics that suggests tall people
earn more salaries, control, earn more money,
controlling for lots of things, attractive people.
As long as you're not too attractive, you earn
more money. Optimal level of attractiveness
because people respond subconsciously
to how people look, how they sound,
how they show up, how they present themselves. In
my class, I take the example of Tony Hayward of
BP, the Macondo oil spill, and Lloyd Blankfein
who was accused of shorting the securities
that he was selling, which by the way, Goldman
did. And before I let them hear Tony or Lloyd,
we show about 60 seconds. And Lloyd's case 34
seconds with no sound. And even if you did not
know who these people were and I asked you
to make a bet, who's going to keep their
job and who's going to lose it? You would
know just from their physical appearance.
I love that.
And by the way, what Dana Carney will tell
you, and what common sense will tell you,
is that these are skills that can be mastered.
Robert de Niro was not born Robert de Niro,
in the sense of acting skills are learned. How
you show up, how you command the room. There's
a guy named Regis McKenna who is older than
God, who's famous for running a very, very,
very fancy public relations firm in the Silicon
Valley. And his biggest contribution to life,
as well as by the way to his personal wealth,
is that he made Steve Jobs Steve Jobs. When
Steve Jobs began, Steve Jobs couldn't convince
you to buy water if you were dying of thirst.
He could not give a presentation to save
his life. And Regis McKenna and his team
took Steve Jobs under their wing and created
Steve Jobs, a man who could sell anything to
anybody. These are skills. This is not about
personality. This is not about undergoing some
kind of cosmetic surgery or whatever. These
are skills, everything we've talked about,
networking, showing up, all these things.
These are skills that can be learned.
I have a list of some of the stuff you actually
recommend for looking and appearing powerful. So
I'll read a few and I'm curious what else comes to
mind. So do not read from notes. Make eye contact.
Keep it brief. You say that anger can be a signal
of power because it's outside the norm. It's kind
of breaking the rules. Don't apologize.
It's kind of the opposite. More gestures,
which is interesting. Open body posture.
Louder voice. Okay, I'm going to speak
louder now. I like this. Okay, what else
comes to mind as ways to appear powerful?
Invading people's personal space. So gentle
touching, standing close to someone. We're
not talking about sexual touching, we're talking
touch on the arm or the shoulder, shaking people's
hands. That's a way of I think being more
powerful. But you've covered the main ones.
Eye contact. One of the problems with Tony Hayward
of BP is that he's been given a statement to read.
You cannot read something in front of you and make
eye contact at the same time. So he looks like
he's scripted. He looks like he's insincere. Jack
Valenti, who I had the privilege of knowing, who
for 38 years was the head of the Motion Picture
Association of America, and typically rated one
of the number one or number two most effective
lobbyists in Washington DC, said to my class
when he came to my class, which he did, "I never
appeared before Congress with notes. I wanted them
to believe, which was by the way, true, that
I was in complete control and complete mastery
of the material, and that I did not need notes
or a bunch of assistants around me to help me.
That I, as the head of the MPAA, understood
the motion picture industry." And then he
would give you a little aside about how it was
the one industry that consistently had a budget
surplus in trade. He would talk about how many
jobs he created and he had all this stuff at
his fingertips. But basically his command of the
material made him more powerful. It's interesting,
Jack Valenti was five foot two inches
tall and he came, talked to my class,
and the next class I said to people, "What are
your reactions? What are your thoughts?" And
a woman raised her hand and said, "He feels
taller than he is." And I thought that was an
assessment that was both true and insightful.
When the five-foot-two Jack Valenti appeared,
because of his presence, because of his body
language, because of his Texas drawl, because
of how he moved on the stage, he felt bigger.
You would not say he did not feel five-foot-two.
Let me read a couple more because this
is a good example of stuff he did. Other
ways to appear more powerful is more
speaking time, longer gazing time,
more disinhibited laughs. Is that just you
laughing and feeling like you're just...
Well, humor. Humor. The famous author, Salman
Rushdie said, and I quote Salman Rushdie,
it's a fabulous quote. "If you can get
people to laugh, you can tell them anything."
Yeah, stand-up comedy is a great example
that. So again, I think here people might
be hearing this and they're like, I don't
want to be this person. I don't want to
be talking all the time. I don't want to be
pretending like open posture. Is the advice
here just you don't need to do all these
things. Just know this makes people more
powerful. Don't necessarily judge people, do some
of these things maybe because it'll add to your
power? How do you think about just people
that are turned off by this sort of thing?
That's a wonderful question. So I say to my
class, on the very first day of class, that we
will go through four stages. We'll go through the
stage of denial. It doesn't work in my culture,
it doesn't work in my organization, doesn't
work for me, it doesn't work in my religion,
whatever. Then we'll go through anger. When they
get angry at me, how can you teach us this stuff?
Then they'll go into sadness. I actually believe
this and I'm depressed. And if we're successful,
they will go through acceptance. And the process
I have, again, I do not have the most popular
class at Stanford Business School because I am
good-looking, because I'm the smartest person
at Stanford or anything else. I am strategic
about thinking about if I have someone who's
going to come into this class, I have to get
them from denial to acceptance in 10 weeks.
And how are we going to do that? The easiest
way to do that, if I said, Lenny, I want you
to become a better tennis player, or a better
roller blader, or a better ice skater, whatever,
a better piano player in 10 weeks, what would we
do? If we have practice and coaching. And that's
what I do in the class, practice and coaching.
I have executive coaches who work with the class
and I give them assignments that ask them to
practice what they're learning. And therefore,
by the end of the class, most people have made
this transition because it is true. If you've
never... I had a dinner the other night, this
Israeli woman who's like, I've done amazing
stuff. Amazing. Which is fabulous. And she said
at the dinner, she said, "I would've never done
this before taking your class." And the way
you get them to do this is I don't say, Lenny,
you're going to swim the English Channel tomorrow.
If I want you to swim the English Channel,
we're going to start by swimming in pools and
make every day a little bit more challenging.
That's what we do. I don't start by saying, you're
going to network like Keith Ferrazzi or John Levy,
or you're not going to be as bold as Jason
Calacanis, who trust me is extraordinarily
bold. You're not going to necessarily do what I
did. You're going to begin where you can begin,
and push yourself out of your comfort zone.
Because, and again, this is common sense.
There's also a ton of research behind it. If you
always stay in your comfort zone, you'll never
do anything different or better than what you're
currently doing. This is true. If I said to you,
I want you to, at the end of 10 weeks, lift
a hundred pounds, I can't do that by on the
last day saying lift a hundred pounds. We
have to work up to it. And that is, it's the
same principle here. So don't do something that
looks so off the wall or so out of character for
you that you can't conceive doing it. Push
yourself a little, push yourself a little.
There's an interesting connection here too. What
some say is kind of the opposite of your class at
Stanford, which is Touchy-Feely. We had Carole
Robin on the podcast and she has a framework,
the 15% rule where you push yourself 15% beyond
your comfort zone. Where it's just a little bit,
but it's not too far, and it feels
like you try to do a similar thing.
Yeah, absolutely. So you begin by
doing what you don't think you can do.
Let's spend a little more time here around
the homework assignments, and this kind of
Knowing-Doing Gap that you talked about. So you
shared a couple of homework assignments you give
already, find 10 people, think of 10 people you
want to meet that'll help you with your career
and then try to meet them. And then there's
this, I guess my friend started a podcast,
I don't know which homework it was. What
other homework assignments do you give?
So we begin, there's a literature on goal setting
that says if you set goals, you're more likely to
achieve them. This is, again, not some huge
insight, but there's an enormous scientific
literature about this. And so I begin the very
first homework assignment is, which is by the way,
on the very first day of class, why are you here?
Why are you here? It is now the end of this class.
What would success look like to you? What would
you like to accomplish in our 10 weeks together?
Second assignment, I give them a reading from the
Power book, which is the book before Seven Rules,
which talks about the seven attributes of power.
Go out and get people to rate you on these or rate
yourself. Set for yourself a development plan,
energy, focus, being willing to tolerate conflict,
all these qualities. What are you strong on? What
are you weak on? What do you want to build during
our time together, and how are you going to do it?
So we begin with goal setting. One of the
assignments I give them, which is the class
that Jason comes to, what resources can you
create? You're at Stanford Business School, elite,
fancy Stanford. What can you do in your 10 weeks
here? I have people who created awards. A woman
who created an award gave it to Karlie Kloss,
the model. Got in trouble with the school.
It turns out it's easier to ask forgiveness
than permission. So what can you do to create
resources that will give you some leverage?
That would be a third assignment. The networking
is a fourth assignment. The acting with power.
I show them the videos and I tell them in advance
of the class, and I tell them they need to become
Tony Hayward. They need to do a better job, which
is, by the way, a low bar, representing BP. And
give me a 60 to 90 second video and then share
it with colleagues and get feedback on it. And
then we're going to call on people in the class.
In other words, for every idea, I try to think
of something. And this is all, by the way, this
is all front-loaded. And by the end of the class
we're not doing this so much. But I try to give
them an exercise that causes them to actually
take that idea and implement it. Find people, oh,
for branding. Write a personal brand statement,
get some feedback on it, then write it again.
How do you want to be known? Which is by the way,
useful to you because you're a second-year
MBA, you're going to go in the job market.
What do you want people to think about you? How
do you want people to respond to you? How do you
want to be known? So I basically take for every
topic and have them do it. And then the coach,
their person, their coach, who is responsible for
23 of these people, give them feedback on this.
I could see how this makes a
big impact on someone's life.
Yeah. And so at the end, I had a student a couple
years ago said to me, "It is not that I got more
feedback and more useful feedback from your
class than I did in any other class. I got
more useful feedback in your class than I
did on every other class I took combined."
I can see why. Let's talk about the last
power. So we've talked through six already.
We have only one more to go, which is maybe
the one that probably upsets people most,
which is that once you have power, people will
forget what you did to get there. Talk about
what that looks like and is that a power or is it
more just like this is what you should know about.
And I put in rule seven for the following
reason. In spite of everything that you and
I have been talking about, many people in a
stage of, I don't know, denial or something,
say, I'm worried that if I do this, at the end...
People believe that the world is homeostatic. It
is not. That it's going to adjust, but whatever.
At the end I will be brought low. They have
the myth of Icarus in their head. You fly too
close to the sun, your wings are going to melt,
you're going to be brought down. And so I try to
convince them, partly through a lecture and partly
through rule seven. And some of the principles
that I talk about in rule seven. That, in fact,
life is not homeostatic at all. That life
is actually self-fulfilling. If I believe
you're powerful, you will become more powerful.
If I believe you have no power, you will wind up
with almost no power, and that therefore it
is all forgotten and forgiven. And I begin,
I believe I begin. But if not, I could begin
with the story of the South Carolina Senator
who says nasty things about Trump, and then
Lindsey Graham, and becomes Trump's biggest
acolyte. And the New York Times, of course, is
fascinated by this. How can you say all these
horrible things about Trump and now be his,
basically have your lips affixed to some part of
his anatomy? And Lindsey's answer is, I want to be
relevant. He's the President of the United States.
This goes back to the judgment. I like him, this,
that, the other thing. He's the president. If I
want to get legislation passed, he, by the
way, has taken over the Republican Party.
If I want to get stuff done, I need to have him on
my side. And like many narcissists and egomaniacs,
it is not a good way to get them on your
side by saying nasty things about them.
So this is the pragmatics. People forget
that Bill Gates stole the code on which
Microsoft has built. People forget that Jeffrey
Epstein, after being convicted of sex offenses,
was still having dinners with members of the
royal family and members of the New York media
elite. People forget that Martha Stewart, who
served time in jail, has a brand that's never
been more valuable. People forget all this stuff.
I still remember sitting in the office of someone
whose name I won't use, but I'll use enough that
if somebody wanted to search it out, you could. So
I am sitting in this guy's office and he's, by the
way, a Jewish man. He's got pictures of him with
the Pope, he's got pictures of him with Ronald
Reagan. He's got pictures with him, with all these
people. What is his secret? He, by the way, took
a company into bankruptcy. People lost literally
billions of dollars. He was fined. He lost money,
but he walked away with about $700 million. It
turns out, $700 million makes you a big deal.
Lives at the biggest house in Los Angeles or one
of the biggest houses in Los Angeles. I can't keep
up with the construction of the big houses. People
want to be close to money, power, and success, and
they will overlook your flaws to be close to you.
And again, you talk about this in the book.
You're not describing how the world should
work. This is just how it is, and this is how you
can be successful in the world that we live in.
And by the way, this is how the world not
only is, but how it was and how it will be.
Because these ideas are not something
that I sat down one day and made up or
something. These ideas, everything that
I talk about, including this last one,
has social science and logic behind it. So you
can explain not only what is, but why it is.
So, let's talk about Trump for a bit. At the
beginning of your book, you say that basically
you were going to write a book about why Trump is
so successful and what he's done so well. And your
realization is no one's going to pay attention
if here's how to be like Trump. And essentially,
if you think about all these rules, it's
clear he is very good at all of these things.
That's correct. By the way,
not because he read the book,
but because he does it through
trial and error or something.
So when people hear that, they're like,
I don't want to be Trump. I don't like
how Trump is. I don't want to be seen that
way. Do you have any thoughts on just how
to make people feel comfortable following
some of these powers and building power,
knowing that, oh wow, maybe he's
the epitome of some of this stuff?
I will tell you a story. In 1993, a woman
named Laura Esserman, who's a doctor,
took my class. She claims publicly that this is
the only class at Stanford for which she did all
the reading. By the way, while she was getting
her MBA at Stanford, she was having her first
child and practicing medicine full time. Laura
Esserman said to me one day, "You have a case.
You have cases on all these people doing evil
things. Why don't you ever write a case about
somebody doing good things?" And of course,
I wrote a case about her. So she comes to the
class. Case was published in probably 2003, 2004.
She comes to the class and the students are,
what is the right word? Hard on her? That would
be a modest thing. The students eviscerate her
because she is incredibly smart, incredibly
well-intentioned, but she will not network. She
says, "I don't have time for schmoozing." She will
not do almost any of the stuff that we talk about
today. So she and her husband, Michael Endicott,
two of my closest friends in the world, and I go
out to lunch afterwards. And smoke is coming out
of her ears and she is pissed off. And this is
a very accomplished woman and a very smart woman.
And she's pissed. I said to her, "Laura, you have
boundless energy and boundless intelligence.
You're a force of nature. Let me discuss
something from the past subject of physics.
You are creating friction. With enough force
you can overcome the friction. If you reduce
the friction, just think how much more you
could accomplish." And she looked at
me and changed. And I will tell you,
and I've said this publicly, because I get to
introduce her for all the awards she's won,
and she's now won a ton of them. Including Time
Magazine 2016 list of a hundred most influential
people in the world. And I say to people, and I
say it with pride, that of all the things I've
done in my life, the thing I'm most proud of
and most proud of is creating Laura Esserman.
That is an awesome story and a really good way
of thinking about this from a different angle.
Yeah, no, and I said to Laura, I said, "You want
to make profound changes in the drug development
process. You want to make profound changes in
whether or not we learn from the treatments
that are being given to people. You want
to make profound changes in the connection
between research and teaching, research and
practice. You want to do all these things.
If you are going to accomplish any of these
things, you need to cross the bridge." And
she hasn't crossed the bridge completely and she
and I joke about it. But she crossed the bridge
a lot and she has accomplished incredible
things. She's won every cancer award that
can be given. And by the way, she's won all
these awards for the American Cancer Society,
who she fought with. She's won these awards from
the Susan Cohen Foundation, who she fought with.
This is an incredible example of the
opening quote to your book that I
have here. "If you want power to be used for
good, more good people need to have power."
That's exactly right.
And I like the, it's like a quote
attributed to me, is how you...
Yeah. Well, I don't remember saying it, but
somebody said, I said it. I'll take credit
for it. I said to Laura, "You want to change
medicine? Medicine is not going to change without
the application of power and influence." If change
was going to happen, it would've happened already.
You have to take on entrenched interests. She
has a whole thing, which we need not go into
because it's pretty technical, on screening.
She said, everybody's getting a mammogram every
year beyond a certain age, which is stupid for a
variety of reasons. You can read, she was on the
PBS NewsHour about this. This is what got her in
trouble with the radiologists. The radiologists,
of course, are selling screening. She said,
there's some people that need to be screened
every month, and there's some people that
need to be screened never because of their
genetics. She wants custom tailored screening or
precision screening. Anyway, she fights everybody.
Richard Blum, Dianne Feinstein's husband,
both Dianne and Richard Blum are now deceased,
was at a thing where she launched the Athena
Project. The Athena Project, she's now, with her
collaborators, collecting data on the diagnosis
and treatment and outcome for 150,000 patients in
the University of California Healthcare System.
So I'm supposed to give some opening talk to
provide entertainment. And Dick Blum is there.
Dick Blum, of course is wealthy. He's Dianne
Feinstein's husband. I said to him, "Dick, how
did Laura get you here?" And I still remember,
I think this is a quote in one of the books I
wrote. He said to me, he said, "Look." He said,
"I've learned that at the end of the day when
Laura asks you to do something, you may say no,
but at the end of the day, you're going to
do it anyway. Save yourself the aggravation."
Oh man, I feel like you're just endlessly full of
good stories that we could just keep going on and
on. Let me try to summarize the rules of power
real quick and see if anything else emerges. And
then have just a couple more questions. So the
Seven Rules of Power, get out of your own way,
break the rules, show up in a powerful fashion,
create a powerful brand, network relentlessly,
use your power, and understand that once
you've acquired power, that what you did
to get there will be forgiven, forgotten, or
both. Let me ask you a question, maybe half in
jest. You teach people how to acquire power. Why
aren't you the most powerful man in the world?
Ah, that's a very good question. To which I
have a very good answer. I have a colleague
who's unfortunately now deceased, by the
name of James G. March, who was a very,
very distinguished scholar. And James March said
to me many, many years ago, something which is
completely true. You can have power or you can
have autonomy, but you cannot have both. And I
have chosen to live a life of freedom, autonomy.
I could tell you stories that would bring tears to
your eyes. I'll tell you one. We had a dean of the
Business School whose wife was dying of cancer,
and she was projected to die in the fall.
So the Business School goes to him and says,
we'll give you the fall off to be with your
wife. She lives until June. It's now winter.
You have responsibilities as the Dean of the
Business School. You have to meet with alumni.
You have to go around and raise money. You have
to show up at events, university events. I do
not necessarily think that is how he wanted
to spend the winter and spring quarters,
but that's what you have to do. When I wanted
Jack Valenti to come to my class, I did not call
Jack Valenti. I called Judy Dickey. Judy Dickey
was his assistant. Judy Dickey controlled his
schedule. I meet Jack on such and such a day. He
can't make it on that day. Fine. I can adjust the
schedule. Can he make it on this day?
When I wanted my friend Gary Loveman,
who ran Harrah's and Caesars and then was the
number two executive at Aetna, I want him to
come to my class. I called Reggie Kirk. I didn't
call Gary Loveman. And that's all you need to
know. I do not have an assistant who controls
my schedule. I control my schedule. You will
not find my Outlook calendar on any website, on
any computer. I want autonomy. If I said to you,
"Lenny, I will give you $1 billion, or for
that matter, $10 billion if you can buy-"
Yes.
Wait, if you can have last week again. You can't.
You can't. Time goes in only one direction. I want
control of my time. It is much more important
to me, being a Dean or an Associate Dean, a job
that I was asked to do. I took one academic
administrative job. I'm actually memorialized,
believe it or not, in the Stanford Record, as
having led, and this is according to my expenses,
the Nobel Prize winner who was Dean
at the time, that I led the biggest
and most successful transformation in
the history of higher education. I did
it. I did it once. I didn't like it. Life
is too short. I want to do what I like.
That's a really profound point that I think
people don't think about, is there's always
this drive to acquire power. And your
point is that there's a big downside,
which is a lack of autonomy. Yeah. You think
about the, as I was trying to get Satya Nadella
on the podcast, and I talked to his comms
people, and they're like, every hour for
the next three months is booked already. We
know what he's doing. He's extremely booked.
And you think about the president, obviously
at Elon. I totally get what you're saying.
It is true, and I don't want to do that. And
by the way, power also comes with enormous
visibility. Donald Trump has done, for 40
years, what he's now being accused of doing,
the tax stuff, all this stuff. He's been a grifter
all his life. But when you become President,
people are going to look at things that in the
past they would not have looked at. You become
president of a university, you're going to have
scrutiny as the President of Harvard Law and the
President of Stanford Law, when they both had
to resign, in one case because of plagiarism,
in another case because of research misconduct.
Power comes. You're going to be put under a
microscope. People are going to look at what
car you drive. They're going to look at who
you go out with. They're going to look at how
you spend your time. They're going to look at
how you associate with, you'll have no privacy.
You'll have very little control over your life.
Everybody will feel completely free to dissect you
in public, in private, whatever. And you'll face
the trust dilemma. When you are rich and powerful
the question will be, are people praising you,
are people associating with you because of
you or because of the position you hold?
Yeah. Do you spend any time, just
to follow this thread in your class,
convincing people stop being
so obsessed with power,
stop being so obsessed with becoming the top
of everything? Is that a part of the class?
No.
Or is it just...
No. I teach them, they see we have a class
on the price of power. I bring out Rudy
Crew. Rudy Crew was the New York School's
Chancellor under Rudy Giuliani. By the way,
he tells many interesting stories about Rudy
Giuliani, who did not just become the joke that he
is overnight. He's worked hard to become that. But
in any event, he tells. And one year, one year,
because his daughter at that time was living in
the Bay Area, when I asked him about the effect
of the positions he held, Head of Miami Dade
County Schools, Head of New York City schools.
Had Hillary ever won, he would've been
Secretary of Education. Literally. There's
Lauren in the room. And he said to the
class, Jeffrey asked me the question,
"Why don't we let Lauren answer it?" By the time
she was finished, there was not a dry eye in the
room. What is it like to be the child? What is it
like to be the significant other of these people?
And you know the answer to that
because you can see the suicides,
the divorce rates. There is a price that not
only you pay, but a price that your family pays.
I think that's a really good balance to the entire
conversation. Maybe just as a last question,
what if we give the audience a homework assignment
to work on these power rules? What's something
that you'd recommend someone try to do? I know
it's probably dependent on what they're good at,
not good at. What's something that they could
do to start moving towards one of these rules?
So what I would say, and it comes from
something that you talked about in our
conversation at several times,
which is this is uncomfortable.
Okay. So if I want you to do something
uncomfortable, I could say, "Lenny,
go do this uncomfortable thing on your own." Or I
can say, "Lenny, I want you to do this with help,
with social support." And so the first thing
I would say to someone is, if you think this
is uncomfortable, or if you think you're not
skilled at this, get coaching. Get a coach.
I send out regularly the list of the coaches
who work with my online and on-campus classes.
Happy to do it. And they're happy to have the
business. Get a coach. Get a personal board
of directors like they talk about in the Wall
Street Journal. In other words, get people who
will give you advice, give you social support,
and hold you accountable. That's the very first
thing I would tell people to do. It's hard to do
anything on your own. If I said to you, "Lenny,
I want you to start an extraordinarily
successful podcast and I want you to do
it without any help." You would not be where you
are today. So that simple principle, get help.
It feels like a part of rule number one. Get
out of your own way. Ask for help. Jeffrey,
I was nervous for this podcast because I thought
this was going to be super uncomfortable stuff.
It turns out all of this makes so much sense,
and there's a really nice way of framing all
of these rules, and there's so much reason
to actually invest in these skills. So I
really appreciate you putting in the time
being here, sharing all these stories and
insights. Is there anything else you want to
share as a kind of a final note or something
to leave listeners with before we wrap
up? We did it. We covered everything?
No, I'm happy. I'm happy
you're a very good interviewer,
which is why your podcast is so successful.
I appreciate that.
I'm happy to spend the time with you, and I
hope whoever listens to this will, I hope,
first of all, there'll be a lot of listeners,
but I also hope that they will find it useful.
I know they will. Two final questions. Where can
folks find you online if they, or find your book,
I guess, if they want to learn more? And
then how can listeners be useful to you?
So you can find my book anywhere where books
are sold. Don't look at a physical bookstore
because nobody carries it, including actually
Stanford bookstore, where they run out of it
if people... And you can find it on Amazon.
Seven Rules of Power. So that's how you can
find the book. By the way, at the end of the
book I talk about, I have a personal website,
jeffreypfeffer.com. If you go to that website,
you can find my course outline. So you can take
the course on your own if you want, or get
somebody or take it in a group of people.
You can find research, you can find articles, you
can find columns. You can follow me on LinkedIn
or I don't do Twitter anymore, but you can follow
me on LinkedIn. So there are a lot of resources
available for this. A company was once thinking
of hiring me to give a talk in their organization,
and the woman who wound up hiring me said, "When
I was discussing you and arguing that we should
hire you for this presentation, one of the people
in the committee said, is he a good presenter?"
And her answer, I love this. I remember this.
Her answer was, "He's a fabulous educator."
My job is to educate. That is why I have done
what I have done for now more than 50 years.
Holy moly. I didn't even realize that.
For more than 50 years, I have been in the
business of education. Not just about power,
but about many other things as well. But I'm in
the education business, so I'm happy to provide
people with the resources, with the readings.
The Seven Rules of Power is well footnoted.
It talks at the end about we could reach out
for the coaches. You can go to the website
and get the book. But I think consistent
with what you and I have talked about,
if all you do is read, you're not going
to make very much progress. You have to
do it. You cannot learn tennis by reading
about tennis, or by watching a movie about
Serena or Venus Williams. You have to
actually get out on the court and do it.
Which is a good plug for your other book,
the Knowing-Doing Gap, which actually
helps you with the skill, which you can
also find all your finer retailers. Jeffrey
Pfeffer, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you for having me on your show.
Bye everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review, as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
LennysPodcast.com. See you in the next episode.