Warren Buffett famously said, in business.
I look for economic castles protected by
unbreachable moats.
Power requires a benefit
and a barrier, so he's taking care of
the benefit part by saying a castle,
you have to have a pretty good understanding
of why it's a castle and not a shack.
So in a lot of decks it's like,
"Oh, we have the most amazing
team. We move the fastest." You mention
how rarely is that actually a power?
You're on a treadmill and if you stop
running on that treadmill, you get creamed,
but it's not power. The things that drive
operational excellence can be mimicked.
Let's actually talk about
achieving these powers.
There's a thing called power progression.
There are times when certain types of power
are available. The path to power is
where the rubber meets the road.
Today my guest is Hamilton Helmer. Hamilton
is a legend in the world of strategy. He's the
author of 7 Powers, which outlines a framework for
identifying and developing sustainable competitive
advantage. It is widely considered to be the best
book on strategy and people like Patrick Carlson,
Peter Thiel, Reed Hastings, Daniel Eck,
and so many more leaders credit the book
and Hamilton's teachings for helping them build
durable lasting companies. In our conversation,
Hamilton shares what sources of power startups
can start developing early, which types of
power companies often think they have but they
don't, how power relates to strategy and moats,
when to start thinking about power as a startup
and also what individual product managers and
non-leaders can do about these insights about
power. Also, how Hamilton sees AI impacting
various entry and the sources of power. He
also gives a preview of his new book that
he's working on currently and so much more.
With that, I bring you Hamilton Helmer after
a short word from our sponsors. And if you enjoy
this podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow
it in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube.
It's the best way to avoid missing future episodes
and it helps the podcast tremendously. This
episode is brought to you by WorkOS. If you're
building a SaaS app, at some point your customers
will start asking for enterprise features like
SAML authentication and SCIM provisioning. That's
where WorkOS comes in, making it fast and painless
to add enterprise features to your app. Their
APIs are easy to understand so that you can ship
quickly and get back to building other features.
Today, hundreds of companies are already powered
by WorkOS, including ones you probably know
like Vercel, Webflow and Loom. WorkOS also
recently acquired Warrant, the fine-grained
authorization service. Warrant's product is
based on a groundbreaking authorization system
called Zanzibar, which was originally designed
for Google to power Google Docs and YouTube.
This enables fast authorization checks at enormous
scale while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases. If
you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features
like single sign-on, SCIM or user management,
you should consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in
replacement for Auth0 and supports up to 1 million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
WorkOS.com to learn more. That's WorkOS.com.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta. When
it comes to ensuring your company has top-notch
security practices, things get complicated fast.
Now you can assess risk, secure the trust of
your customers and automate compliance for SOC 2,
ISO 27001, HIPAA and more with a single
platform Vanta. Vanta's market-leading trust
management platform helps you continuously monitor
compliance alongside reporting and tracking risks.
Plus you can save hours by completing security
questionnaires with Vanta AI. Join thousands of
global companies that use Vanta to automate
evidence collection, unify risk management,
and streamline security reviews. Get $1,000
off Vanta when you go to vanta.com/Lenny.
That's Vanta.com/Lenny. Hamilton Helmer, thank you
so much for being here. Welcome to the podcast.
Hi Lenny, a pleasure to be here.
It's even more my pleasure. I want
to start by talking about when power becomes
important. When do you recommend founders start
thinking about power in terms of pre-product
market fit, post-product market fit? Is it
worth spending time thinking about power early?
Obviously it's good to think about a little bit,
but how much and how seriously should
founders be thinking about it before
they found something that people actually want?
One of the things that has really surprised me in
the last five years has been that my understanding
of the answer to that question has changed. And
before I thought it was you do product market
fit and then you do strategy, and if you try and
put strategy before product market fit, it is not
much you can do with it. That's wrong. Actually,
I mentioned before one of the great pleasures for
me in my work is being able to talk to company
founders and one of the things that has surprised
me is that conversations with them, even at an
early stage about strategic matters have a
richness and relevance to me that was unexpected.
And founders are practical people. I mean
it's very hard to do what they're doing and
they have to be extremely focused and choose
what's worthwhile spending time on. And so in
observing their reactions and that dialogue, I
could see that there was something going on that
was meaningful to them. And this second book we're
working on, we'll tease out why that's so more,
but the answer to your question is when should
you thinking about this? The answer is always.
And that's an odd answer. And so even before you
have product-market fit, it's worth thinking about
strategy. Now it's not strategy in the sense
of this fully articulated strategic planning,
we're going to do this, these are going to be the
competitors, this is how we're going to answer
them. This is how we'll price. Not like that at
all. At the earlier stage, you can imagine wildly
more degrees of freedom and the questions are of
the business propositions that you're thinking of
in trying to get to product-market fit, what are
the underlying characteristics that might tilt
them towards the availability of power or not?
And those actually are meaningful conversations
and certainly by no means certain. You're tilting
probabilities, you're not creating a determinative
things. And then later on, once you've already
have product-market fit, then you have to
understand your source of power to understand what
competitive position is because then you have to
establish that. And then later on in a more
stable phase when you're in a stability phase
of business, you have to know what your source
of power is if you have one, because you have to
know how to defend it. And then also it is also
the foundational knowledge that you need for if
there's another step. Because another thing that's
quite surprising about iconic businesses is they
often have a second act or a third act or fourth
act. I mean think of AWS or Intel going into CPUs
or Apple going into iPhones, all not the origin of
business. And that's actually common, not unusual,
and that's starting the process all over again.
Awesome. You mentioned this word strategy. I want
to set a little foundation here. How does strategy
relate to power when people are thinking about
these two concepts? And then do you have just a
nice definition of what strategy is? Everyone's
always just like, "What the heck do you mean
when you're talking about the strategy?"
As I said, I'm a concept person and so when you
develop concepts, you have to be very highly
constrained by their usefulness. I'm a great fan
of the great mathematician, John von Neumann,
and he had a view which really irritated a lot
of mathematicians, which is that if mathematics
wasn't guided by what was useful, it would
become, I think the word he used was aesthetic
to aesthetic. And so any concept developments
like that, it needs to be guided by usefulness.
And so in dealing with strategy, the question
is what domain of things do you want to include
in that conversation? Because the term is
ubiquitous in business. I mean do a Google search
sometime. I've done one recently on Google Scholar
for the word strategy and you'll get a million,
I'm not exaggerating, a million hits. And so
strategy for some people might mean everything
that gets to the pile, it gets to the top of a
pile in terms of what you have to do that year.
Everything is... And that's a perfectly legitimate
definition, but what I have found is that there is
a very important narrowing that makes it much more
useful. So that's coming back to what I was saying
[inaudible 00:10:17] makes it much more useful
to the business. So my view is that you want to
focus, it's very useful for a business to focus on
the fundamental determinants of business value and
that's an arbitrary choice. It could be something
else, but I can tell you from decades of business
experience that that narrowing is very useful. And
then so once you make that... Once you reach that
understanding, it tells you some important things.
So if you understand what drives business value,
I mean if you do the math of it right, it's NPV
of cash flow, right? Expected cash flow. And what
that tells you is that strategy is a long time
concept. You're looking far out in the future.
So think of Pearl Harbor, Pearl Harbor for the
Japanese was this enormous tactical success. They
just destroyed the US ability, naval ability in
the Pacific Ocean and the worst possible strategic
move because it completely solved Franklin
Delano Roosevelt's problem of how he could
get the US citizens on board to attacking Hitler.
The strategy of it was US's industrial might would
eventually win the war and population. And the
difference there is time constant, tactical short,
strategy long. And so if you focus on value that
narrows what you think about and allows you to get
rather concise and offer up advice to founders
about what they need to pay attention to.
So then how specifically is power informing
strategies? Like the way you think about it,
focus on your power and that
will inform your strategy?
Earlier I talked about these economic structures
that provide durability of return in terms of
refuge from withering arbitrage of everybody
who wants to eat your lunch. And so that's what
power is. So you have to understand what is an
economics? You're asking me questions that get
pretty deep into theory or I hope you don't, this
is too conceptual. But you have to say, you have
to understand how competition takes place and say
what is it that creates some kind of refuge? And
what it is is there's something in what you do
that gives you either a cost or price advantage
over others. So let's say you're lower cost and
that's the benefit. And the barrier side is that
there's something that is durable about that that
makes it over time that you can't, the competitors
can't take away from you. So benefit and a
barrier, we call it the to be or not to be test.
And if you have that, you can think of that
immediately translating into a value because
that will give you good margins out into the
foreseeable future, which is what you're after.
I don't know if that's... We're getting into the
weeds here, but that's what it's about. And so
power is those structures. Let me give you a quick
example. So one I use in the book. So Netflix with
scale economies, they have more subscribers. The
cost of their content is a very large fixed cost,
about 50% of their cost structure every
year. They can take that fixed cost and
spread it over more subscribers so their cost
per subscriber is less versus somebody with
fewer subscribers. So if they face the same
prices for subscriptions as their competitors,
they will be more profitable. And that's
a scale economy and that's an example of a
type of power and a common one I'd say.
But these things are hard to achieve,
right? Because there's the holy grail.
So let's actually talk about achieving
these powers. Essentially the argument here is
your power informs everything you do because
this is the thing that'll allow you to
stay durable and competitive and last.
There's seven powers. We're not going to talk
about all of them. If you want to go understand
each of them, go read the book.
Yeah. Let's not. That conversation
always goes too long.
Yeah, exactly. So what I'm wondering is, okay,
so say you're looking at this list of seven powers
and you're a specific type of startup, do you have
a heuristic that tells you here's most likely the
power and set of subsets that will most likely be
an option for you? Like B2B SaaS companies,
is there a smaller subset? Probably one of
these has to be one of your options versus B2C.
That's a great question Lenny, because I think the
path to power is where the rubber meets the road
and it's very complicated and nuanced. But I'll
give you a few thoughts along it and frankly our
next book, the Second Invention, that's what it's
about. It's about power, the entire book.
[Inaudible 00:15:56] I'll try to read it.
So in a book there's a thing called power
progression, which says there are... It tells
over the cycle of a business, there are times
when certain types of power are available and
the converse of that is times when they're not
available. And so there's some that only are
really available in when you reach a stability
phase of a business pretty far out there.
And so if you're starting a company, take those
off the table. So those two are branding and
process power. So often I find that there's a
confusion about this because brand recognition
for a startup may be incredibly important, but you
can get brand recognition by buying an ad in the
Super Bowl. That's not power, that you paid for
it. So take branding and process power and process
power is really operational excellence on steroids
and usually is imitable, so it's usually not.
So take those off the table and then a resource
type of power, which is you have something that
is of value that if you transferred it to
somebody else it would be of value to them,
but you own the rights. So the barrier is law
for example, or lack of knowledge from others.
And there are classes of businesses that are
like that. So prescription pharmaceuticals,
if you are the first person to come up with
Viagra, that's worth a lot of money. If you
took that license and gave it to somebody else,
it'd be worth a lot of money to them. But that's
a different class and it's usually not the
types of things that I'm dealing with and
it's obvious to everybody. So the key challenge
there is can you invent a pharmaceutical that's
effective for a large market. So you can take
those three off the table and that then leaves
counter positioning, scale economies,
switching costs and network economies.
And the important thing to keep in mind there is
that they're sequenced. So almost every startup
that you want to deal with starts with counter
positioning because remember what product market
fit is primarily is a substitution. You are coming
up with a way to satisfy a more or less existing
need in a novel way that creates more value.
Now sometimes you tap into entirely new needs,
but it's not so often. I mean Amazon
was up against brick and mortar stores,
Google was up against Yahoo and so on,
and so you're usually substituting and
that substitution, so your competition
at that point is functional competition.
And if you don't have counter positioning at that
point you're pretty high risk from an incumbent
who already has the capabilities necessary to do
that. They just have to extend their product or
do this or that, but counter positioning is the
refuge from that. And then you go into the other
three types of power scale economies, switching
costs and network economies, and those depend on
your scale relative to competitors. This is pretty
cursory, but that's what I'd say. I'll focus on
those four and I would recommend that you
think pretty hard about whether you think
you have counter positioning to start.
Awesome. I actually want to double down on
that thread, but just to summarize, I have the
list here. Basically you're saying if you're
an early stage startup, the four to really
that are actually potential powers for you
at least early on, counter positioning, which
your point is you could just start with that.
That's essentially positioning and business model
design, which happens at the beginning and then
you can start to think about network economy,
scale economy, switching costs as powers.
Right. And you've done the right thing by
not having me go through and define each of
those. But your listeners will need to go
back to my book and see what those things
are to get... We're going through the
shorthand as we should, but all of what
we've said won't be completely obvious to them.
Yeah, I think a simple Google search I find just
gives you a very simple definition of these.
Yeah, that's right. There's some people who have
done some really good summaries of this.
Or ChatGPT, even better in a lot of cases.
ChatGPT if they get it right
sometimes I find they hallucinate.
Hallucinate an eighth power. You mentioned how
some companies think they have a certain power
or it's common to think you have a certain power.
If you look at every startup deck, there's always
like, "Here's our moat, here's the way we're
going to have barriers to entry." I'm guessing
in almost every case they're delusional about the
power that they actually have and the power they
think they'll have. Do you also find that to be
true that often founders are wrong about how much
barrier they've actually created and is there a
power you often find most wrong and mistaken?
Yeah, so I agree with your observation, but
I don't want to be unkind. So I mean there
are two things to keep in mind here in terms of
making people feel better about that incorrect
slide in the deck. One is that founders have to
be optimistic. I think it's an important quality
that they maybe understate the risk a little bit,
but they're so committed to I'm going to do this
thing that they go through that and that may give
them an advantage over a large corporation trying
to do the same thing. The other is that despite
the name 7 Powers, which makes it sound like,
oh, you can sort this out. Actually understanding
whether or not there is a type of power in place
is hard. I mean I did it with my colleagues
here at Strategy Capital and we're looking
at a well-known company, it might take us weeks
to answer that question for a single company.
And it comes down to the hard part is industry
economics is what really are the economic
relationships and it's very hard. So with those
caveats that... Give them some courtesy, I'll say
some of the obvious ones are I mentioned before,
people sometimes think they have branding power,
but another one that I think I've heard you
mention is people often think that they get
scale economies through data. And I'd say that
that's possible, but it's rare. And the reason
it's rare is not because there aren't scale
economies in data, but rather that the range of
scale that the existing competitors have are often
large enough to be able to put them in shouting
distance of each so that the differences
in their cost per unit is not that great.
The curve flattens in other words, which is
typical of any, because the most common scale
economy is you've got a big fixed cost and you
prorate that. And as you get more and more scale,
the percentage cost advantage of a fixed cost
advantage like that goes down and that often.
So that's a pretty frequent one that we see.
We laugh whenever we hear somebody say they
have a flywheel, which gives you the idea of
network economies. There are often flywheels,
the ones that really are material, are
rare. The key thing here is materiality,
not whether the flywheel exists, but whether the
effect is strong enough to really tilt returns.
I was actually going to ask about that one
because in software and social consumer products,
network effects is always the pitch. Once we
get big enough, we create this huge barrier.
You mentioned just now you often find that's
not actually true. It's rarely something
that'll become a barrier. Is there anything
else you find with network? And I know your
power is called network economies, not network
effect. I guess just to be clear, are these the
same thing in your mind with different words?
Yeah, kind of. I mean I have called it a type of
power. So for me it's only those things
which clear the significance barrier,
hurdle rather that they're a large material. And
so there are lots of things that I would say have
network effects but not network economies.
Oh, interesting. Wait, can you speak to that?
So there is a difference between
these terms, network economies?
Yeah. So for me the difference is materiality is
that whether the value benefit is large enough
to engender a price delta significant
enough to give you materially different
margins into the future.
Basically, does that network
effect have an actual impact on your
business and your ability to price?
Yeah, it's not an impact, it's a material
impact. So it could have... If it's a penny
to your bottom line, that's one thing if
it's a billion dollars or something else.
Wow, that's actually really interesting. Is
there an example of a company that comes to mind,
they had network effects but not
network economies as a power?
I think you could turn almost anywhere and
get some modest network effects and any
platform business would probably likely have some
modest network effects. You asked me earlier and
you sent me about Uber and Lyft, I'd
say that they probably have network
effects involved but not network economies.
Wow, that's interesting. And the reason you're
saying they don't have network economies
is because they're still so competitive
they still have to spend so much money to
stay ahead and so the network is not-
Yeah. Right. The advantage that they
get, it's not material. Right.
Wow, that's so interesting. Along those lines,
it's so interesting to see Uber and Lyft these
days. In theory they both had some sort of strong
network effect. I was just looking, so Lyft is
5% the market cap of Uber. Is there a lesson from
just what it is that allowed Uber to just win and
kind of run away with the market essentially?
I'm not entirely sure, I'll take a guess, but take
it as a unformed guess. I haven't really studied
it carefully. I think that over time there,
if I had to guess, I'd say they're probably modest
scale economies in the business. And over time
Uber has just very successfully played a war of
attrition. And that's both been in how they run
their... They made one initial misstep, which is
they misdefined their business. They said it was
international transportation and it's not. That
business is extremely geographically specific.
If you have a great position in the Bay Area,
it doesn't help you in London. And so their
forays into China and everything really didn't
make, but they pulled back on that, focused
down on understanding their source of power, which
was a geographically specific scale economy. And
then they've done interesting things like Uber
Eats where they've tried to utilize the platform
that they have to get other opportunities for the
one side of their platform, the drivers. And so
if I had to guess, I'd say it was a well-played
war of attrition with modest scale economies.
And is that attrition coming from a
source of power or is that just like
a broader, more strict?
Yeah, it only works because
there are modest scale economies. If there
weren't any then if they did all this stuff,
they'd still have a global and see.
Got it. Let me go in a slightly different
direction. We've talked about power, we've
talked about strategy. There's also, there's
this word moat that comes up a lot. Everyone's
always trying to build a moat. In your mind,
is a moat equivalent to a power? Is there a
difference when people talk about these two?
Power requires a benefit and a barrier, you have
to have something that you do that gives you a
better outcome than your competitors, lower cost
or higher price, and then something that makes it
impossible for somebody else to mimic that. So
moat is the second. So it's not synonymous with
power because you can have a moat around a very
undesirable piece of property and wouldn't get
you far. But I think it is pretty synonymous with
barrier. I think Warren Buffett, Charlie Munger,
I admire enormously. I think I get credit for
popularizing those concepts and I think the way
they think about it is good. I'd say that 7 Powers
is probably more systematic and comprehensive in
saying that. I don't think. This is wonderful.
I don't know if you've read any of the Microsoft
antitrust literature that came out of their-
No.
...lawsuit, but there was a communication
between Bill Gates and Warren Buffett where
Warren Buffett was saying why he couldn't invest
in Microsoft. He just didn't understand it. And
so that meant the idea of network economies and
what the moat was there he didn't understand.
But I think the concept of a moat is a good
one. The idea that you have something that
gives you a refuge from competing forces.
In terms of Warren Buffett, I found the quote
about moats. Warren Buffett famously said,
"In business, I look for economic castles
protected by unreachable moats."
Right. And so he's taking care of the
benefit part by saying a castle.
Right. He's got it covered.
But one of the tricks to understanding power is
you have to have a pretty good understanding of
why it's a castle and not a shack. So I'll
give you a Netflix example. So a company I
admire a lot, and I think if some of the things
that they had to do to develop their business
were so important for their business that
don't guarantee a castle. So for example,
UI development, it's been an enormous amount of
resources on trying to get just the very best UI,
I mean a zillion AB tests, all kinds of things.
Their recommendation engine, everybody's knows
the story about how that went, their interface
with the content world and all this. So those
things are important. They're things they
have to spend a lot of time and resources on,
but they can largely be mimicked.
So when Netflix in an earlier phase was
fighting Blockbuster, when Blockbuster finally
threw in the towel, said, "Well, we done. Well,
better do a mail or a DVD business." If you
look at the Blockbuster site, their UI site,
you couldn't tell it different from Netflix. They
just copied it. And so all that thoughtfulness
about which things you put first and how you
structure it and all that to make this suitable
was mimicable. So that's an understanding of
looking at the properties you have and trying
to figure out if they're a castle or a shack.
I love that. This episode is brought to you by
Paragon, the embedded integration platform for
B2B SaaS product development teams. Are your
users constantly requesting new integrations with
other SaaS platforms that they use? Unfortunately,
native product integrations take months of
engineering to build and the maintenance
never ends. Paragon enables your engineering
team to ship integrations seven times faster
than building in-house by removing the
complexities around authentication, messy
third-party APIs and debugging integration errors.
Engineering teams at companies like CopyAI, Cinch,
TLDB and over 100 other SaaS companies are
using Paragon so they can focus their efforts
on core product features, not integrations.
The results, their shipping integrations on
demand, which has led to higher product usage,
better retention and more customer upsells. Visit
useparagon.com/Lenny to see how Paragon can help
you go to market faster with integrations today.
That's use paragon.com/Lenny. So let's take this
concept of 7 Powers. A lot of people listening
to this are just like individual contributor
product managers on teams building new products
or iterating on products they already have. What
do you suggest they do with this knowledge of
there exists these ways to build benefits and
barriers? I'm working on say a new product. What
do you recommend they do? What's something they
could do this week, next month to infuse these
lessons into the products they're building?
I'd say they're a few and it's a little
bit different. I'm not a great fan of the
strategically driven organization because that
idea, because it fuzzes over how this knowledge
is useful at different stages in the business. And
so for somebody in that position, say a product
manager in an existing successful business. So it
is important in terms of just understanding their
business to know what their source of power is
because they... And that can inform them about
what it is that they're working for. And also
they may see things since they're down in the
weeds, they may see things that are important
to that that they need to bring to other people's
attention. Because they're the ones that really
have the knowledge of what the heck's going
on. There's another aspect I mentioned before,
this idea of transforming, of starting up entirely
new things. And usually... I wouldn't say,
usually I say it's not uncommon for ideas
about that to bubble up from down below.
And so that's another source. So let's separate a
business into three phases, origination, takeoff,
and stability. So the answers I've given are more
in the stability phase. In the takeoff phase,
let's say you've launched a product,
you've gotten customer traction,
now you're in a phase where there's just very
rapid growth, probably other entrants like you,
what are you facing? What you're facing is
remember that underneath all of this is a
change in technology. That's what made the product
market fit possible in the first place. But that
doesn't just stop. That if you're in a technology
wave, often there are all kinds of offshoots both
for you and the compliments to your business
and everything else going on at the same time.
And to win at that stability phase, which is
really a market share win, you have to be aware of
those and understand, okay, we have to incorporate
this new feature. Or maybe now things have gotten
to the point where this new market segment is, our
product is attractive before it wasn't. This is
meat and potato stuff for somebody at that level
and it may well be the decisive element in terms
of whether you win that market share battle with
the other contenders. And so you have a very, very
important role at that point. And so I'd say the
first thing to do with your question is to make
sure you think about the different phases of this
and then ask what those responsibilities are.
What about for people that are just trying to get
better at being strategic, thinking strategically
something every product leader is always
encouraged to do, become a better strategic
thinker, build as muscle of strategy, what
do you often advise to people just get better
at the stuff? Obviously read your book.
Read the book, and then have conversations
with your colleagues about the topic because
as you internalize what that means and how,
have conversations with them about do we really
have this kind of power? What's going on here?
What's important? What isn't. Those conversations
tend to allow you to get a better grip on things.
I mean in the case of Netflix, Reed actually had
me come in and train the top a hundred people in
Netflix and strategy. We actually ran classes in
the company, but that's unusual I'd say. And I
didn't have the book yet. And so I think the book
gets people pretty far down that path already.
And you don't do that anymore, I imagine if
someone wanted to do that today, not an option.
I sadly don't have the time. I mean I do often
do fireside chats at company meetings and that
kind of thing, but not a full-blown course and I'm
not teaching at Stanford anymore either. And so I
don't. I enjoyed that immensely wonderful people
to work with. But sadly I don't have the time.
You're about to get a lot of requests
for fireside chats. I hope you're ready.
You mentioned AI at some point in our
chat. I'm curious how you think AI is
going to change your 7 Powers framework. Do you
think defensibility goes down in general? Will
certain forms of power become more important or
harder to achieve? How do you think about AI?
Yeah, it's a great question. I mean we're all in
this phase of wondering exactly how generative AI
is going to play out. My own view, currently I
don't see any change in seven powers from it in
terms of an eighth power or something. But the
issues that it brings up, like scale economies,
I mean think of scale economies. If you have
a fixed cost of trying to develop a model of
a billion dollars or something or network effects,
will AI models develop so that they learn in a way
that for one user's interaction helps another
user's interaction? That would be a powerful
network economy. Or if it learns, if you think
of if it learns about you and becomes a better
psychiatrist or something, then that's a switching
cost. So all these things are relevant to which
business models will work and I find that useful.
But I think in general, the way I think about it
is it's a standard form of potentially very
powerful technology that is being introduced
into the business world and just asking how
that plays out. I currently tend to think
of that there's three types of plays. There's
the company that's the technology play itself.
So if you think of microprocessors, it would be
Intel. There's the companies that wouldn't exist
without the technology. So for semiconductors
it would be Microsoft. And then there are the
companies that utilize the technology, but it had
existed before and after. So for semiconductors
it would be automobiles. They used a ton of
chips, but there were still cars before, after.
And so I'm of the view, I'm very much uncertain at
this point that generative AI, its biggest impact
will be that tertiary class. It will be used in a
lot of things that existed before and exist after,
but are made better by it like semiconductors and
automobiles. And so it reminds me, if you think
of really big technology shifts like this, it
reminds me of electricity. When electricity came,
you could completely reconfigure a factory floor.
You no longer had to have... You could have the
power source essentially at the operating unit
of an operator. But that took a lot of redesign,
incorporation, investment, learning, complements,
all kinds of stuff. I tend to think this will be
more like that. There will be some pure cases.
People will want to have them write their term
paper with ChatGPT or something. But if you
think of businesses, it's hard for me to think
of a single functional area in a business that
with redesign couldn't benefit. So accounting,
HR, R&D all have uses of this but requires
incorporation, which is always troublesome.
And so that's my view. But there certainly will
be businesses that couldn't exist without it.
And there's some that are coming up and some of
those are in fact the businesses that empower the
tertiary need, they're the ones that bring
in. But if you go back, this will date me,
but if you go back into business history, back
in, I guess it was the 90s, there was this thing
called business process re-engineering, the idea
that you could take a computer sensibility into
business processes, redesign them and get these
monstrous cost savings. And it was a gigantic
consulting opportunity for people. Whole companies
got developed based on that and it feels more like
that to me, but it's very interesting. I could
be wrong, but it feels different than crypto.
It feels like there's more of a real ultimate use
case. I mean, if it really is true what they say
that a 50% improvement in programming efficacy
is not uncommon, just that proposition alone
is worth an awful lot of money if you think
how many programmers are in the world.
No question. You mentioned eighth power. I just
want to check, is there an emerging eighth power
you wish you maybe would've included or
maybe added in the future that's like,
"Oh, maybe this is on the edge," or it's
like, "Nope, we got these seven?"
It's a great question. I'm always looking
for it because if you find it it probably
means it's so obscure there, it'll also be a
great investment opportunity. We're looking all
the time, but so far, no. So far I'm pretty
satisfied that seven is an exhaustive set,
but never say never. That's an empirical
seven, not a theoretical seven.
If we start seeing you making incredible
returns, you've clearly found an eighth power
[inaudible 00:45:41]-
That's right.
I want to close one thread on a power that
you mentioned that is often a pitfall,
which is around process power and basically
execution. A lot of people think so in a lot of
decks it's like, oh, we have the most amazing
team, we move the fastest, we're earliest.
You mentioned how rarely is that actually a
power actually being able to execute and create
a process that is an actual barrier? Can you
just talk a bit more about that to help people
understand okay, it's probably not our power?
One of the great thinkers in strategy was this
Harvard professor Michael Porter, and he in
probably 40 years ago, made the very controversial
statement that operational excellence is
not strategy. He got a lot of people of the
Harvard Business School faculty really mad at him
because that's what their careers were about and
it sounded like he was dissing them. But the point
he was making was when you get to this end state,
if you already have power that things that drive
operational excellence can be mimicked because you
can hire a consulting firm who has best practices,
knowledges that come in and get you up to snuff.
You can hire people from your competitors who
know how to do it better. And that's true,
but it's also true in this takeoff phase
in a business that we talked about before,
when you're trying to attain competitive
position, operational excellence is everything.
And so if you think of strategy, not statically
endpoints like Professor Porter was, but if you
look at dynamically how you get there, operational
excellence is essential for a strategy. So think
of those things I mentioned before about Netflix,
about their UI and recommendation engine and so
on, or international rollout, all those things.
They were in a battle to get more subscribers than
other people and those were critical for that.
But in themselves, they're critical in attaining
competitive position, but in themselves,
they're not sources of power typically,
unless there's some very tight considerations
here or very demanding considerations for the...
Unless if they have to be material, but they also
have to be opaque or some way people can't easily
imitate them. Either they don't understand what's
going on or they might be opaque. So for example,
think of TSMC. So when they put up the
latest fab and get that operational,
are there a lot of steps in doing that?
They know how to do with their staff is trained to
do it, but it's not documented necessarily and you
can't imitate it. Then maybe they have it. I don't
know if they have process power or not, but it
takes that level of complexity. In my book, I use
the example of Toyota and a car manufacturing is
complex enough that you can have this opacity in
terms of material steps, but it's not common. So
if you're in a stability phase of business, you're
stuck with this funny thing, which is most of your
day is on those issues and it should be because if
you don't do it, a competitor can and they can end
up better than you. And so you're on a treadmill
and that's the way business is. That's fine.
And if you stop running that treadmill, you get
creamed. So you got to do it, it's most of your
day, but it's not power. And there are those rare
cases where it's so material and so inimitable
that it can be power, but they're rare.
I like the heuristic that if you haven't
written it down or you can't describe it,
that might be a sign that maybe
process power is a power of yours.
Yeah. And there isn't a consulting firm that
offers to bring you up to speed on that.
They'll make you more like Amazon as a service.
Kind of along these same lines, you talk about
how the only things that create value in a company
are power, market size and operational excellence.
And I think hearing that will blow a lot of
people's minds because they think there's so
many things that contribute to the value of a
company and you whittle it down to these three
things. What can you say about that insight?
So I'd say they're right and I'm right. They're
right because there are this incredible...
I mean business is really hard and there are
just a multitude of things you have to pay
attention for. I'm right because all those
things fall into those three categories. So
it's an exhaustive set and it simply comes
out of the math. So we're both right I'd say.
Final question, the intent of a lot of your work
is to empower founders. I'm curious if you've
noticed any broad economic trends or shifts
that you think will make life easier or
harder for founders in the coming years?
Personally, I am very, very concerned about the
debt trajectory of the United States and of many
countries around the world, but I'll pick on
the United States, but it's a trend going on
everywhere. We're on a trajectory for this
extremely high indebtedness. And so if you
think about the last 30 years, right? There's
been a crisis about once every 10 years. So
there's the dot-com bust, there's the financial
crisis, there was COVID. Nothing makes me think
that the frequency will be a lot less. I don't
know what, who knows? These are all uncertain
events. But imagine if we got to one of those and
we had no dry powder and dry powder for us is the
ability to heavily deficit spend take on debt.
And fortunately our government did that in both
the financial crisis and in COVID. And because
that people had jobs. My own view about the
financial crisis is that if we hadn't done that,
plus having Ben Bernanke as the head of the Fed,
we would've gone into another great depression.
It was that ugly. So this current debt trajectory,
you don't know how long it will take exactly
when, but eventually that will mean we will
not have dry powder. People will not respect the
credit worthiness of this country. So that worries
me a lot. And it utterly will affect the idea of
company founding because if you get into a crisis
like that, the capital markets lock up and it
gets very difficult to do anything. And to really
stretch my credibility here, I'll opine on just
how hard a problem this is to solve. The reason
this is so difficult for this country to solve
and other countries is that it is right at the
crux of the delicate dance between capitalism
and democracy. So if you think about the problem,
of course that's driving all this is entitlements.
There's discretionary spending, certain recovery
programs and stuff, but those can go away. The
underlying trend that people just can't get
their arms around is entitlements. And anybody
who looks at the numbers can see that. Every
economist knows that. But that's not an easy fix.
And the reason it's not an easy fix is there are
two opposing views of what's going on, and
there's no way to resolve those two views.
One is that capitalism is rapacious and results in
more and more inequality and the government has to
do something about it. And the other is that
the government is on a path that is creeping
socialism that will undermine our freedom and
economic sufficiency. And the poster child for
the rapacious capitalism. One is, I don't know if
you've seen the recent analysis of inequality in
the United States just came out, much more robust
analysis. And it said that basically inequality
in the last 60 years of the United States is
unchanged, but that's post-transfer, post-tax
inequality, which basically says the amount of
taxing and transferring going on was about right.
So it says that the amount we're spending is about
right from that perspective, that it compensates
for the other inequities and we should be
spending that much so we should tax more.
And the poster child for the other point of view
of the dangers of government is the steadily
increasing without interruption percentage of the
economy that is government. And to levels that 75
years ago, people would've thought absolutely
impossible. So there are these two views about
what's going on. One is that we're compensating
for the normal inequities of capitalism,
and the other is that we're headed down a path to
socialism and ruin. And that leads to a deadlock,
which is you don't tax anymore and you don't cut
spending and that leaves deficits. So anyway, a
long, long rant, sorry but that trend is extremely
politically difficult to deal with and extremely
threatening and that concerns me immensely.
Not to leave listeners with a very sad state
of affairs.
Yeah, sorry.
No, no. I think this is important. I think
it's important people think about this and
know these things. Is there anything that gives
you hope? Is there anything that gets you excited
about either for founders or anyone in general,
just to leave folks with maybe on a happy?
Yeah, I mean, I am an optimist really in a way,
and I do. There's a famous Austrian and eventually
American economist named Joseph Schumpeter who
wrote this wonderful book Theory of Economic
Development way back when over a hundred years
ago, where he took the unusual view of saying
that the vitality of an economy depended on
entrepreneurs. And I ascribe to that. I think
that creativity and action are the ways society
and people advance. And I think the US's and
a free society has huge advantages in that. And
I think that I feel very lucky to be in a place
I'm in Silicon Valley, but to be in a place in a
country where that is vital and active and I think
that's ground zero for me. And so I think you see
that alive and well, I think. And there are people
that are very Enthusiastic about that as I am.
Beautiful way to close out our chat. Is there
anything else you want to share before we get
to our very exciting lightning round? Is there
anything you want to leave listeners
with or any last tidbit of advice?
I alluded to it before, but just that remember,
action is the first principle of business. You
do stuff and my book is very oriented towards
that. The idea was not to tell you what to do,
but to give you guideposts while you're on that
journey. People that are enthused about it,
I encourage you to do stuff. That's where it all
starts and I can think about it and maybe help
a little bit, but it's mostly doing stuff.
I love that point so much. It was something I
was going to touch on but I didn't get to is just
there's so many people that just sit around and
theorize about a strategy of their business,
especially in their early stage. Here's our
grand master plan, here's an amazing strategy or
just read about startup ideas and don't actually
try it. I love this final note of just try
it. Just do it. Don't just sit there and-
Yeah, yeah, just do it. And life
is full of surprises. You'll end
up in a place you didn't expect.
Amazing. Speaking of ending up in a
place you didn't expect, it's time for our very
exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
Oh, sure. I'll do my best here.
I'm not very good on lightning.
First question, what are two or three books
that you've recommended most to other people?
One book that is extremely wonky, and I can only
take it in very small doses, but is magnificent,
is one called The Road to Reality by Roger
Penrose, who's this brilliant mathematician.
And it will be very daunting for anybody unless
you're a deep math person, but his brilliance in
erudition just shines through in this thing.
And it's an amazing book. I would say there's
another book, boy, I wish I could remember
the name. Maybe you can get the name of the
author called Gene by this geneticist. And I
think he's a Harvard Medical School professor
that's about the history of genetics and he
is an absolutely luminous writer. I mean,
it puts me to shame. I'm embarrassed when I read
it because I think how pedestrian my writing is
and incredibly knowledgeable about the history
of genetics and I think that's such an important
topic. So those are two that I would recommend
highly, fairly wonky, but I like them both.
I love them. The author, I just looked
him up. Siddhartha Mukherjee.
Yes. Just amazing. You read it and you go,
"How did he think of that phrasing?" I mean,
it's just, he's amazing.
Do you have a favorite recent
movie or TV show you really enjoyed?
I'm a huge movie fan and have been all my life,
and I'm particularly keen on animated films. But
the movie that I've recently seen that I liked
particularly it was American Fiction. I thought
that was... It didn't make any of the easy choices
in a movie and as a result was just incredibly
interesting and thoughtful I thought.
Do you have a favorite product you recently
discovered that you really love?
In my office, just this last week, we actually
put a Persian rug in our entry room, and this
is what's called a Farahan Sarouk rug and
it's 150 years old. And it had an effect
in me that I didn't expect, which is it is
a work of great beauty. And it was before,
it was all hand-done before machines. You get
all this wonderful variation of the actual
icons in the rug and the different dye colors.
And I find that every morning when I walk in,
I go, "That's really beautiful," and it's
uplifting and it shows you the importance of,
or the value of the quality of art. I mean, just
blows my mind actually. So that's probably not
the usual product discussion that you get.
No, I love that answer. Recently we've had
some really unique choices. One is a very nice
Mercedes and a Rivian and a minivan recently.
We've got a lot of very nice things.
Oh, that's great. I'm a car guy too,
so I didn't answer on the car question.
Oh man, I love that. We have Rory Sutherland
coming on the podcast soon. He is one of
the leaders of Ogilvy and he has a whole
thing about how buying a home is the best value
of art to buy art if you live in a home that
makes you feel inspired and is beautiful.
Yeah, I'm a big believer in that. I mean,
I think that your place and how you connect to
it has an important grounding effect. And then
before I talked earlier about creativity and
I think surrounding yourself in an environment
that stimulates that is really important.
And so I couldn't agree with him more.
Two more questions. Do you have a favorite
life motto that you often think about,
come back to share with friends or family?
One is what Clint Eastwood's advice to actors,
which is don't just do something, stand there. And
so there are a lot of things that are long-termish
with low signal to noise. And you can often
just do a lot of stuff that you think makes
a difference, but it really doesn't. And so that's
one. The other one which is somewhat more profound
I think was one that I had a famous Sri Lankan
journalist was a mentor of mine and very dear
friend, and he had a favorite expression that I
adhere to all the time, which is everything is
always about something else.
Wow. Deep.
And that's so true if you're dealing with
this power stuff when if you really dig down,
everything is always about something else.
Speaking of power, final question. People that
have a lot of power are leaders
in the world. I'm curious,
do you have a favorite historical leader?
So yeah. I have some that I admire a great deal.
I'm a tremendous fan of Winston Churchill's. Most
really great people are quirky and he qualified.
There are things you could say about him that you
might not have liked that so much, but he was a
genius and had great fortitude, human sense. He
understood things long before other people. I've
give him high marks. Some of the great artists I
admire enormously. I'm reading a book right now on
the last 20 years of Michelangelo, which wonderful
book actually, and which is a very interesting
period because in his first 70 years he finished
up all that, he wasn't going to do sculpture
anymore. He just finished The Last Judgment,
which was the wall of the Sistine Chapel.
And I think the last major fresco he did.
And a lot of his friends at that time,
he was exiled from Florence and living in
Rome and he had this Roman community and a
lot of his close friends that had recently
died or had difficulties. So he's at this
inflection point in his life at 70, which in
those days was very old, and yet he went on to
do some of the most remarkable architecture in the
history of the world. And so you've got to admire
that. I mean, just doing that, which is that
rare second act. But I think for world leaders,
Winston Churchill is very high. I'm a fan of Teddy
Roosevelt, I must say too, in this country.
I love that. Hamilton, you are wonderful.
I feel like we have helped a lot of people
up-level their ability to think about strategy
and moats and power. Thank you so much for
being here. Two final questions. Where can folks
find more online if they want to dig in further,
and how can listeners be useful to you?