Today I am excited to bring
you a very special episode,
which was recorded live at Figma Config
with Figma CEO and co-founder, Dylan Field,
in front of a live audience at the Moscone
Center in San Francisco. This is the first
ever live recording of this podcast and it
was so much fun. If you watch this on YouTube,
you can see the epic stage that they built
specifically for us to recreate my podcast
studio. I could not be more thankful to
the Config team for making this happen.
In my conversation with Dylan, we dig into
how he builds and refines his product taste
and intuition, how intuition is a hypothesis
generator, the future of product management.
How Dylan attempts to operationalize keeping
Figma simple and to continue simplifying the
experience. A bunch of stories from the early
days of Figma that I've never heard before. Also,
he shares his favorite AI tool called websim,
which is wild. And if you wait till the very end,
you can see a very young child actor Dylan Field
in a clip that I found online that was hilarious.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. It's the best
way to avoid missing future episodes and
it helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you Dylan Field.
Dylan, thank you so much for joining
me and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you, Lenny.
Hi all.
Is this your first live podcast?
This is my first ever live podcast.
Also, a big thank you to the Config
team who set up this crazy studio. I had
no idea this was going to happen. I feel
like I'm in my studio here with a thousand
people watching us. It's very impressive.
I very much dig the background and also
the mics that may or may not be wired.
That's right. Don't say that. Don't tell people.
Oh, sorry.
There's no wires coming out of them.
There's no one behind the curtain either. Okay,
so Dylan, I want to start by just checking in on
how you're doing. So Config is about to wrap up.
We've been at it for two days now. I know how much
lift goes into doing these sorts of things. I
imagine you've been thinking about this for a
long time now. I'm just curious how you're doing,
any surprises, any highlights, any low lights?
The highlight is the community and just
the incredible, incredible people here at
Config. Y'all are awesome. I don't know
why I keep talking in the mic like this.
It's instinctual. But seriously, it's just
the most amazing community to be part of
and I feel so lucky. And then in terms
of how I'm doing at this exact moment,
exhausted, but riding on caffeine and
whatever this really cool probiotic drink is.
Any surprises from the past couple of
days? Anything that's like, "Oh wow,
that went a lot better than
I thought, maybe less well."
Demo, definitely things I would've improved. But
also Emil and Mihika were phenomenal, and it was
just so awesome to see them do their demos and
present materials. I was just really pleased
with the conversation, I think, that's getting
started at Config around AI. I was looking online
on social media and I think people are already
zeroing in the right conversation, which is, okay,
in a world of more software being created by AI,
what does that mean and the impact on craft and
the impact on quality and the need to have more
unique design and how design is a differentiator.
And I think some people are saying, "I agree with
that." Some people are saying, "That I disagree
with that", and that's exactly the bounds of
what the conversation I imagined would emerge
from yesterday. It was funny, the make design
feature, I think that I said on the keynote,
I was like, "This is going to give you the most
obvious thing in the most obvious form possible."
And then people online are like, "It's just
going to give you some obvious thing." I agree.
This episode is brought to you by WorkOS. If
you're building a SaaS app, at some point your
customers will start asking for enterprise
features like SAML authentication and skim
provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in, making
it fast and painless to add enterprise features to
your app. Their APIs are easy to understand
so that you can ship quickly and get back
to building other features. Today, hundreds
of companies are already powered by WorkOS,
including ones you probably know like Versal,
Webflow and Loom. WorkOS also recently acquired
Warrant, the fine-grained authorization service.
Warrant's product is based on a groundbreaking
authorization system called Zanzibar, which
was originally designed for Google to power
Google Docs and YouTube. This enables fast
authorization checks at enormous scale
while maintaining a flexible model that can be
adapted to even the most complex use cases. If
you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features
like single sign-on, skim or user management, you
should consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in replacement
for Auth0 and supports up to one million
monthly active users for free. Check it out
at workos.com to learn more. That's workos.com.
This episode is brought to you by Anvil. Their
Document SDK helps product teams build and launch
software for documents fast. Companies like Carta
and Vouch Insurance use Anvil to accelerate the
development of their document workflows. Getting
to market fast is a top priority for product teams
and the last thing that you or your developers
want is to build document workflows from scratch.
It's time-consuming, expensive and distracts
from core work. You could stitch together
multiple tools and manage those integrations
or you can use an all-in-one Document SDK.
Most product managers will tell you paperwork
sucks. Anvil's Document SDK helps teams get to
market fast, incorporate your brand style and
give you back time to focus on your company's core
differentiated features. For your users, paperwork
often starts with an AI powered Webform styled
and embedded in your application. From there,
you can route data to your backend systems
and to the correct fields in your PDFs via
API. Complete the process with a white labeled
e-signature. The best part about Anvil is the
level of customization their SDK provides.
Non-technical folks love Anvil's Drag and
Drop builder and developers love their flexible
APIs and easy to understand documentation. Build
documents software fast with Anvil. That's
useanvil.com/lenny to learn more or start a
free trial. That's use-A-N-V-I-L.com/lenny.
Let's keep talking about design. You once
said that the definition of design is art
applied to problem solving. Can you just
add a bit more to that? What do you mean
by that? Because that's an amazing line.
Well, I don't think it's my original
line. I think someone else said it,
but there's a lot of definitions of design out
there too. There's also 'design is dialogue'
or 'design is problem solving'. You just go
straight there. I could go with 10 more. But
I like art applied to problem solving because
I think that design is often... There is some
component of creativity to it and unique
expression that you're trying to provide
and create and put out into the world. But you are
also trying to do it and match it to a user need,
a problem that needs to be solved.
And I think that it's not pure art,
but if you lose the art and you're just
solving the problem, it's totally utilitarian
and it lacks soul. And so the combination of
those two things is to me really beautiful.
I'm going to pivot to a very hard hitting
question. I hope your PR people don't kill
me for asking this. Many people asked me
to ask you this question. Very important.
Please explain a Figma tradition
called raccoon feet and muffin hands.
I should probably just leave this interview
now. So this is a conversation, I'm not sure
exactly where it started, but it started in early
Figma. And basically we had these lunch tables at
Figma where we would just all gather and have
very long, interesting meandering conversations
before we got back to work. And one of the
questions that, was a 'would you rather',
was would you rather have raccoons for feet or
muffins for hands? And I think this is a deeply
philosophical question. I have pondered it since
I've heard it. I still don't have one answer.
If you've got an answer, I'm curious what it is.
I've got follow up questions. Can
you control where the raccoon take
you or are they just deciding
on their own what's happening?
I think that raccoons probably wouldn't
even agree with each other where to go.
Okay, that's complicated.
If you had raccoons for feet right now, do you
think that it would interfere with this podcast?
But muffin hands would also interfere with my
newsletter and I feel like I'd be out of work.
I don't know if you can type.
I'd need a special keyboard.
This is very difficult.
You haven't even thought
about the upsides of this yet.
What are the upsides?
We can get there, it's all-
Maybe I could eat some of the muffins.
It's the case for optimism.
Cupcakes?
If you have muffins for hands,
maybe if you're hungry...
Do they regenerate as you you eat them?
That's a good question. There's no answers
here, just questions. Do your nails grow?
Yes.
Oh, okay. Interesting. It's
deeper than you might think.
I'm going to play a short clip
with Rick Rubin and then I have
a question about it. So we'll see if that plays.
But exactly what he does and how is difficult
to describe. Do you play instruments?
Barely.
Do you know how to work a soundboard?
No. I have no technical ability
and I know nothing about music.
Then you must know something.
Well, I know what I like and what I don't like.
And I'm decisive about what
I like and what I don't like.
So what are you being paid for?
The confidence that I have in my taste and my
ability to express what I feel
has proven helpful for artists.
So I'm not going to say this is you. You
need to grow the beard. But I think this
is a little bit you because what
I've heard from a number of your
colleagues is that one of your superpowers
is intuition and product taste. And someone
said that you have the sixth sense for what's
going to work, when you're designing Figma
and you're making decisions in the product.
So I'm curious how you've built and refined
your intuition and product taste when
it comes to Figma and then even broadly.
That's a lot kinder than I thought you were
going to be. I thought you're going to be like,
"You don't know how to code and
you don't know how to design."
No.
But no, here's my framework for it. I
think intuition is like a hypothesis
generator and you're constantly generating
these hypotheses and others are generating
hypotheses as well. And you then take these
hypotheses and you put them forward and you
debate them and you try to find data to
support them or negate them. And then
you winnow it down into what is our working
hypothesis? And from that you move forward.
I heard that you read every tweet that
mentions Figma and share them with folks.
There's a Slack channel where you paste them.
I imagine that is a part of this where you're
just constantly watching what people are saying
about Figma, what people are complaining about.
I definitely look everywhere trying to
constantly ingest information about Figma,
and it's not just Twitter/X, whatever that's
called now, but anywhere on the internet,
support channels, et cetera. And I'm always
trying to understand. I also ask a lot of
questions and I try to get to root problems
and understand where people are coming from
and what are they actually trying to solve.
Sometimes people are saying, "Hey, I need X",
but they really want Y or Z. And trying to do that
myself and engage and dive deeper there, but also
to encourage our team to do that, I think leads
to really good outcomes in terms of what we ship.
Is there something you've changed your mind
about, building on that, either based on customer
feedback or some employee just making a case and
like, "Okay, you're right." Is there something
that comes to mind of something you've changed
your mind about recently? Somebody said Flides.
For when we started out Flides. I have not.
It's Figma Slides. Well, it's not recent,
but one good example of me changing my mind is
that you all have Pages in Figma, you're welcome.
But I think I have deep skepticism of Pages still.
I'm not sure they're... If you could freeze time
and I could just go in with my team, work on Figma
for a very long time, I'm not sure we'd come to
the same implementation of Pages that we are at
today. I just don't think it's the most elegant
solution in the context of the entire system of
product design that you could create. The world
told me and our team that that did not matter
and they needed Pages. And don't worry, we're not
shipping Pages. But I am still very skeptical of
them and I think that in general, probably my team
would tell you that I don't always change my mind,
but I also build trust with people in deep ways.
And I think across our organization, if things
are not going to be fatal, then if I hear from
someone, "Hey, I really think we should do X",
then I'll say, "Okay, just go with it. And here's
my feedback, here's what I'm skeptical of, let's
see what happens." And then sometimes they come
back to me and they're like, "See I was right."
But usually they're pretty polite about it.
Just to build on that, something a lot
of people try to work on is being good
at influencing leadership execs, CEOs. What
do you find works to change your mind? What
do people come to you with that helps
you like, "Okay, you're actually right?"
I think the more concrete an artifact
is or the more you can debate something,
the better. I ask for examples a lot, I try to ask
follow up questions about things and make sure I
fully understand it. And I think where I get stuck
sometimes is if I ask follow up questions and we
don't have answers yet, and then my response might
be, "Let's go find the answer to these questions
and then let's go back to this conversation", if I
think it's something that's really important. And
I think for some people they might go, "Okay, this
is actually really obvious. I can't believe you're
so dense and you don't get it yet." And sometimes
they're right and they come back and they're like,
"Okay, here's the data now, can we move on?"
And we do, we move on and they're right. And
I just think that it's important though to just
really understand something from first principles
for a lot of decisions. And maybe it's just a
perfectionist quality repeated over time, I think
it leads to good outcomes as long as you make
sure it's not bottle-necking the organization.
So following up on that, let's talk about
product management. So last year you had
Brian Chesky here, I think maybe on this
stage, maybe a bigger stage. And he said that
they got rid of product management at Airbnb and
everyone cheered and all the PMs were very sad.
And he didn't actually mean they
got rid of product management,
they changed the function and evolved
it. I'm curious just to get your take.
It's funny. This year we have you here
Lenny, so that's your answer. No...
I had him on the-
Before and after, all. Surprise.
We're still here. We're still here. I want to
get your take on product management. You all
have amazing product managers at Figma. I've
had three of them on the podcast already. I'm
curious just what value you find the
best product managers bring to Figma?
It was really funny last year after that
interview, so Yuhki, our chief product officer,
had invited me to a dinner for our PM team. And
it took a while to get out of Config at the end
of the day, and I eventually made the dinner but I
was 40 minutes late. And I walk in and Mihika who
was on stage yesterday, presenting Figma Slides,
Flides, she was standing up and doing a mock Brian
Chesky impersonation. And she's standing up in
front of the entire product team and she goes,
"And then Brian Chesky's like, 'There don't need
to be any PMs.' And Dylan's like... Ooh." And
I'm like, "Hi, Mihika." And I'd never seen her
so red. And then I gave a quick, "Hey PM team,
I believe in you. Thank you for your hard work."
Seriously, I think that if you zoom out, it's
always tricky whenever you're asked to formally
define, what is the separation between a product
manager, a designer, and an engineer? It's always
hard to actually create those clear lines. And
I think in many organizations they're blurry.
But at the end of the day, a PM and designer,
they need to have some technical expertise or at
least understand how some systems work to probably
create the best things they can possibly make. A
designer, engineer, they should probably have some
sense of the business objectives. They should
have some sense of what users want. An engineer
and a product manager, they should have taste and
craft and some sense of the option space, and some
desire to care about the visual implementation.
And I think you can include research in there too,
if you want to make it four legs of the stool
rather than the trio. And you can talk about
all three probably should have exposure to users
and be talking in dialogue with users. So I think
that if you think about that group holistically,
each is important. If you think about a team,
there's all these qualities that you have to
have to make a great product. And that said,
I think for product managers and the product
function... I think sometimes when you see people
that fall down in that function is because
they treat it too much like process. Which
is very important too, don't me wrong. Good
process can help support good outcomes. But
I think that you can't lose sight of the problems
that you're solving. You have to go talk to users
and you have to actually have a strategy. And
if you're really good, you should have a point
of view. And some point of views are going to
lead to good outcomes and some point of views
aren't. And there's some tense sense of taste.
And you also have to bring everyone together
and make sure that they get to the objective,
that it's celebrated, and that at the end of
the project or when you complete a milestone,
everyone's stoked. Otherwise, it's not going to
be a team that gels, you're not going to get to
the next outcome. Even if you get to an outcome
and it's a milestone, but if everyone's unhappy,
you failed. And so somehow good product people are
able to do all this and they're able to create
great frameworks that bring everyone along with
them. And so everyone's able to have a shared head
space around what it is they're trying to get to.
Someone once said that if PMs disappeared or if a
PM goes on vacation, everything's okay for a week
or two or three and then things start to crumble a
little bit because they glue everything together.
Do you find that sort of thing? Let me actually
ask a different question along those lines,
are you bearish or bullish on the future of
product management? Do you think PMs will continue
the way they are? Do you think PMs will dwindle
any sense of the future of product management?
I think probably everyone's learning to do a
bit more of everyone else's job in this current
moment. That said, I definitely think there's
still immense value in product, immense value
in design, immense value in engineering. And
so I think those roles will continue to exist.
So maybe I just want to come back to the question
of just, with the best PMs that you work with,
do you find, what value do they most bring?
I guess is there anything that's like,
"Here's what would be gone
if we didn't have these PMs"?
The best PMs, I think again, create those
frameworks that bring everyone else along
and those frameworks also have a point of
view and a strategy associated with them.
So you're able to take the strategy, take the
point of view, wrap it all up in a framework,
and then make it so that everyone knows what
the destination is and how to get there.
So along these lines, something I've heard you're
really big on is simplification. Somebody told
me that when you're in a designer view and
things just feel too complex to you, quote,
"You furrow your brow and insist there must be
something simpler." Why is simplification so
top of mind for you, why is it so important
for you and just why is it so hard to do?
Oh, gosh. Well, I think probably anyone here
who's worked on product knows how hard it is. I
think the more that you add, the harder it is to
create something that's coherent. One essay that
Evan, my co-founder, introduced me to early
on in famous history, I think from Stevie's
[inaudible 00:23:06] grants or something like
that, contains the term irreducible complexity.
And it's basically this idea that one plus one
does not equal three, it sometimes equals one
and a half. And the more that you add and the
more that you continue to put in something,
the more complex it gets and the worse it gets.
And I think this is definitely true for tools.
So in the context of Figma, we can make
it more powerful, but to do that in a way
that's not making it more complex at the same
time is extremely hard. And we have to always
be paying attention to how complex or how simple
things are because if we don't, it just becomes a
monstrosity really fast. And there's parts of our
product that, I don't want to dive into that part
of the conversation, the self-critique,
but definitely as I'm in conversation
with a bunch of our product leaders at
Figma, there's parts where it's like, "Okay,
this thing is too complex as a system and we made
all the right local decisions and yet together
they're too complex and they're not working
anymore. And let's go revisit the system now."
This episode is brought to you by UserTesting.
Transform how you build products and experiences
with UserTesting. Get fast feedback throughout
the development process so that you can build
the right thing the first time. Make better
decisions that lead to better business
outcomes. Companies are being asked to do more
with less. They need to move quickly to build
experiences that meet changing customer
expectations and do so faster than ever,
all while minimizing risk and costly rework.
With UserTesting, you have a trusted partner
in experience research. They empower user
research product and design teams to make
higher confidence decisions with human insights.
Learn more today at usertesting.com/lenny.
I know you just redesigned Figma. I imagine part
of that came from things are just getting too
complicated, not as simple as we want. Is there
anything that's been bugging you in the old Figma
but like, "Oh, this is way too complicated,
I really want to simplify this thing"?
Yes.
What's that?
We'll move on, but many things.
Sounds good. And in terms of how to keep things
simple, so I had Dharmesh Shah on the podcast,
he's the co-founder of HubSpot,
and the way he described it is
that you're always fighting the second
loft through more dynamics of entropy,
just the product getting more complicated.
And he sees himself as part of the solution,
of top down, you have to be on top of that.
Is that the way you see it? That's your role,
to keep things simple. Do you think people
further down the ladder can do that?
Absolutely, everyone's responsible for
simplicity. And I think another quote
that is not mine but is a really a good one
is "Keep the simple things simple. Make the
complex things possible." And I think that's
a really important principle to hold as you're
designing tools. And I'd say that it's really easy
to make the simple things complex, unfortunately.
I want to pivot to talking about early days
Figma. So I don't know how many people know this,
but it took three and a half years to launch
Figma from when you were beginning to work on it.
Way too long, don't do that.
This is my question. So it took three and
a half years to launch and then five years
to get your first customer. Dylan, what
the hell were you doing all that time?
I don't think it took five
years for a first... Well okay-
Paying.
First paying customer, sure. Okay, fine.
Slightly less but approximately five years,
it gets to be round up. I think that if I had been
probably better at hiring and recruiting... I see
Nadia in the audience, making eye contact with her
the entire time, for some reason. She's our chief
people officer. If she had been at Figma from
day one, we would've hired probably faster and
we would've gotten to market faster. But I think
that it was a hard product to build and to get
everything to come together with. I also see Sho.
And I think for... Sho's joined us as a director
of engineering. He's a VP of product now. Again,
people can wear many hats. And he was someone that
joined Figma and said, "Hey, y'all need to ship
this thing, you're really close." And he really
helped catalyze us to ship in that moment. And
I think, in week one, he gave a presentation. It
was like, "Here's what we got to do, here's
the gap. Everyone agrees on it. Let's go."
You already said that you wish you
shipped earlier. Is there any advice
there for just people building something today of-
Get it out as fast as you possibly can.
Everything they tell you about making sure
that you get a product out really quickly
is totally true. The faster you get it out,
the more feedback you get. That is a positive
thing. And now I index on that when we try to
build. And FigJam's a great example of that, we
shipped it incredibly fast and it helped us get
to market and get feedback faster. Figma Slides,
great example of that too. Dev Mode, for what
it's worth, it took us longer. We just had to keep
iterating and building it and building it again.
Certain directions we tried didn't work out
and we really had to get to a place where we
were able to really believe that we were adding
value and really understood the developer's user,
and it just didn't happen for a long time. So
it's interesting because I think people look
at Dev Mode and sometimes they go, "Oh, this is
quite simple", to the point about simplicity.
Figma, is this simpler than FigJam? And the
reality was it took at least three times as long.
So your advice is ship quickly.
There's also this push the-
I'd hold the bar, for sure.
That's the question I have, is there's also a
lot of talk of just the bar has risen. You need,
especially B2B software, craft is really
important. Linear talks a lot about this,
just the bar is very high for people to
switch from something out there. Is there
anything... I don't think you'll have, "Here's
the answer. When you're ready to ship...", but
just any advice of just like, "Here's good
enough" versus "No, you should probably wait."
Well, another thing that Evan taught me
was that for a new launch, you got quality,
features, deadline, choose two. And I think
that the beautiful thing about software is
you can keep iterating on it. So it's not
like a physical product where you have to
always have quality in there, otherwise
it's never going to have quality. You
can ship it with features and deadline and
then improve it iteratively over time. I'm
not saying you should always do that.
Sometimes you need to at least have a
minimum bar of quality for the things you have
and you're going to ship less features maybe.
So you choose quality and deadline and sometimes
you say, "Actually here's the minimum feature
set and we're going to have this quality bar and
you're willing to push it out." But I think you
have to know when you're introducing a new
thing, what it's going to take and then to
make that minimally awesome product. But also I
think that when you're iteratively improving it,
you shouldn't just be focused on the features,
you have to focus on the quality too.
I like this term you use, 'minimally awesome
product'. Love it. So the way you got your
early users for Figma is quite fascinating.
I don't know how many people know this story,
but you basically wrote a script to scrape Twitter
and create a graph of the most
influential designers on Twitter,
and then you made it your mission to convince
them to use Figma and make them evangelists.
Is there anything more to the story there?
And then I have a question along those lines.
You can't do this anymore, first of all, because
the Twitter API doesn't exist anymore. Rest in
peace, Twitter API. But look, I was an intern at
LinkedIn and when I was there I saw some really
cool work people had done with Gephi, which was
a network visualization tool. And based on that
I thought it'd be interesting to try to, like
you said, look at who the design network was,
who the central nodes were, which you can just run
[inaudible 00:31:31] on and see. And you could do
that for other communities too, which I have done
in the past just because I'm curious about social
network dynamics and social network analysis.
And you could just do those things back in 2012,
2013 when Figma started. So I constructed this
list of, "Here are the most central designers
in the graph", but also then I looked at their
work. And the ones that I was really inspired by
as a total fanboy, and someone who wanted
to learn as much as I could about design,
was inspired by these folks, the ones I was
inspired by I reached out to and said, "Hey,
can I buy you a coffee?" And most of them are
really kind. The design community is amazing.
And they said yes and then from there was able
to learn from them, show them Figma, get their
feedback. And I think it started honestly
more as me fanboy and me getting feedback.
One example is Tim Van Damme. I saw him on
Dribble. Max [inaudible 00:32:35], I'm like,
"Oh, my God, this guy is just genius. These
icons are incredible." I think the first
time I met Tim was at Dropbox and think
I had this total fanboy moment. I'm like,
"I've been tracing your icons." He's like, "Hi."
And I had been working on vector networks
with a team, and my test cases were a lot
of his icons. Because they were just beautiful
and I liked looking at them and studying them.
And to now have Tim on the team and have him
doing the icons for UI 3 is such an honor,
and privileged to work with someone of that craft.
So reaching out to your hero sometimes works.
It's interesting because when people hear that
story, when I've heard that story many times,
it was always like, "Here's a growth hack.
Find the most influential people in your field,
go try to convince them to use your product." And
the way you're describing it is you were using it
more as feedback. "I just want to show you the
product, get your feedback, make this better",
and then it ended up working. They're like,
"Oh, I love Figma, I'm going to use it."
Well, I think it especially works for designers
that way, because designers are really good at
giving feedback. It turns out that not everyone is
good at giving feedback, but designers are awesome
at that. So we're really lucky. And literally
early on in Figma's existence, folks... I think
Payam [inaudible 00:34:00] is here somewhere. I'm
not sure if he's in this room, but I was hoping
to see him before the end of Config. Payam wrote
a very long doc for us about all the things that
he wanted to see in Figma after we did a user
research study with him. With a bottle of wine
because our text editing didn't work very well
then. So I ran him through the user study, I knew
we'd need a bottle of wine to finish and it took
hours. The type of sentence in Figma was so slow.
That reminds me of a story I've heard where...
One of your first customers was Coda, sponsor I
think of Config. It used to be called Krypton.
And there's a story where you installed Figma,
you helped them get set up, you drove
home and then they called you like,
"Hey, Figma is not working anymore." And you
drove back yourself to help fix them and it
ended up their wifi was down or there
was a wifi issue. Is that the story?
I don't remember what the solution was, but-
That's what I heard.
... we were halfway home and somehow I saw... I'm
sure I was not looking at my email while driving,
definitely is not something anyone here
should do. But somehow found out that
they had an issue and we turned the car
around. Shishir is amazing by the way,
and has been a mentor for a long time to me and
many people on our team. And he, I think, at the
time did not know he was the first customer.
And later on he came over to Figma's office
and I introduced him without really thinking
about that. And I was like, "This is Shishir,
he's team was really the first user of Figma
as a team." And he goes, "Wait a second, I am?"
I want to talk about something totally different.
Something I've noticed you are good at is you
spot trends ahead of other people. So obviously
WebGL you were on early and that's what allowed
Figma to exist, to link it in the browser.
I saw you tweeting about CryptoPunks way
before they were worth millions of dollars.
You're just like, "Look, CryptoPunks. Look,
I got a few, they're really cool. They're
super cool, little pipe." I'm curious if
there's anything these days you're really excited
about that might become bigger in the future?
Well, we talked about websim. We were just talking
about them backstage and I think
before this conversation too.
Talk about websim.
And that's an example of something
where it's so interesting because
there's a generative UI component and yet
it's not what we're going for, for Figma,
it's totally different. So we actually
invested in websim with Figma Ventures.
Maybe explain what websim is for folks.
Websim is a hallucinated internet basically.
If you go to websim.ai, you can use different
models like Claude or GPT-4o, and you can do that
either through their defaults or you can use open
router to get a bigger context window. And the
more that you use it, the more you construct
this context window of this almost universe that
you're building up in websim. And as you do it,
it's almost like you're world building. And I just
have gone deep and geeked out on this when I've
had time, and they've evolved the platform a lot.
So we were back there and they were showing
me some new functionality that's really
cool too. But I think it's so interesting
to see it as this almost lean forward
entertainment tool using the internet.
So I thought you would answer this and so
we're going to have a picture come up here,
that I tried websim and played around with it.
And hopefully a photo comes up somewhere. So all
I typed here was gmail.com/dylanfield. So this
is in an invented Gmail. Just came up with this
using AI of what your inbox should look like and
it looks pretty accurate. There's Adobe stuff-
DOJ, not FTC.
... financial. This is not actual information.
Nobody buy stock based on this. So it's pretty-
No comment on 75% year over year.
So the way it work-
I hadn't ever tried Gmail before.
Did you try you? What was your inbox?
I didn't do me. I don't think it would
have anything. It'd be like, if it does-
Who are you?
So the way it works is just you
type a URL or a prompt in the URL
field and it'll just invent what that
website looks like. It's hilarious.
It's awesome.
It's awesome. So I think they're going
to get a lot of traffic right now.
One time someone posted in our random channel on
Slack, they said, "I had a dream last night." It's
always a good start for the random channel. "I had
a dream last night that I was working on FigJam,
but it wasn't FigJam, it was Frog Jam.
And websim was like figma.com/frogjam
and it came up with a whole marketing
website complete with toad puns for Frog
Jam. The sticky notes were lily pads and
you were supposed to... It had this whole
metaphor of hopping from lily pad
to lily pad to generate new ideas.
This is genius. Interestingly, before Figma,
your only other job was an intern at three
different companies and now you're leading
this juggernaut of a business, a thousand
plus people. I imagine there's a lot you've had
to learn over this time. So I'm not going to
ask you what you've learned because I think
it's probably a lot. I'm curious just what
has most helped you scale and learn? Is it
exec coaches, is it co friends? Is it hiring
execs? What's most helped you scale with the
business and become the leader you are today?
I think all the above. And also just having
a mindset of, you have to constantly adapt
and grow and change and adapt. But I would say
that mentors can come from anywhere. It can come
from the community, all of you. Mentorship can
come from the people you hire. It can come from
folks that you actively seek out as investors or
explicit mentorship and mentors. It can come from
people that call themselves coaches. And what's
interesting too is it can come from people you
mentor as well. There have been plenty of
people where they ask me a question at some
point and I give them an answer and they think
it's insightful for whatever reason. And then
years later where we're talking again and I ask
them a question and they're like, "Well, years
ago you told me..." And they repeat back what
I told them like, "That's a really good point."
Or they've grown and they've changed and they've
learned and they tell me something completely
different. They give me a new framework. And
so I think that when you're... A lot of times
when I talk with new founders, they teach me
things that are totally things that I've just
never thought about. Or interns at Figma have
been mentors to me, in many ways. So you really
have to have a ready mindset and just always
be ready to absorb new information, I think.
When you were just tinkering around with
Figma 12 years ago, I think at this point,
did you ever imagine you'd be running a
thousand person company and audience just
spell bound by what you're building? There's
people lining up to take photos with your
logo in the lobby. That doesn't happen. That's
very rare. Just to give you a chance to reflect
on just how it feels to have built that over time,
how does that feel? I'm sitting here right now.
I feel very, very lucky, but also very humbled
by just the community that is around Figma. I
mentioned in the keynote, but just the people
that are in the Figma community are the people
that are shaping the world's technology. And
the chance to serve them and to make software
for them and hopefully improve their life in
some little way is such a privilege. It's a
responsibility and one I don't take lightly,
but also I try not to carry that as a weight,
but rather as pump me up and get
me excited to go build for them.
When we were talking about this idea earlier...
The first thing you said is it's a responsibility,
which I didn't expect. Is there
anything more there just like,
"Wow, I really have to help make..."?
Well, again, going back to the simplification
point, it's very important that we continue to
make Figma more and more simple. We make Figma
as powerful as we can for the people that are
in our community. That we figure out what
people's needs truly are and that we advance
the state of the craft, make it so that we do
that in a responsible way. And that we champion
design and champion quality. So we're trying
to do all those things. We sometimes mess up,
but people have been very patient with us and
we're very thankful for that. And thankful for the
support of just everyone here and in our community
that are giving us a chance to make this impact.
Is there anything else you want to...
Oh, there's some applause. Love that.
Thank you.
Applause break. Is there anything else
you want to share? Anything else you
want to leave listeners with before we
get to a very quick lightning round?
Well, no, one thing I'll share is I think we're
so early on this journey of computing in general.
And in our lifetimes, we're going to have
the chance to just build such incredible
technology and incredible products. And I'm really
excited to see what everyone in this room builds,
but also everyone on the internet that
[inaudible 00:43:48] maybe also builds
and send me cool stuff. If you build something
cool, message me somewhere and share it with me.
What's the best way to message you?
Email's good. You can probably
figure out my email if you-
Just use websim.
... [inaudible 00:44:03] for five seconds or use
websim. Twitter/X is good. Those are
two places at least you can find me.
Dylan, with that, we've reached our
very exciting lightning round. We
only have a couple of minutes left. It's
a very short one. Do you have a favorite
product that you've recently discovered
that you really love other than websim?
Well, I'll say that, and it's
not like a favorite product,
but I will say that if you get...
Hesitate if I should say this or not.
We'll cut it out in post, don't worry about it.
I'll say this, it's so fascinating to look
at all the different LMs out there right now
and what each one is uniquely good at. And
it's really fun if you can hack them the
right way and get them in the right mood,
what they'll do. That's what I'll say.
Whoa, what does that mean?
It's my diplomatic answer.
Interesting. Do you have a favorite
life motto that you come back to,
repeat to yourself, share with friends
or family, that you find really useful?
I don't know if I've got a life motto, but
one piece of advice I've always appreciated is
when people give you advice,
they're not giving you advice,
they're giving themselves advice in your
shoes. I think that's an interesting one.
So if I gave you advice here, I'm
giving myself advice in your shoes.
Final question. Not many people know this, but you
were a child actor when you were five years old.
Do you think you made the right career move?
Do you feel like you sometimes regret acting?
Yes, definitely. That's my mom. My mom's in
the audience and she says yes. No. We've been
talking about product. If you're an actor, you're
a product in some way. And that's not to disparage
actors, actors are awesome. Acting is awesome. I
loved it. But my differentiators when I was five,
five and a half I think, was that I could read
and I could sit still and I was decently cute.
And I hit puberty and those things
were no longer differentiators. And
then it was like, let's do some computer science.
So to close, we're going to play a...
Oh, applause. We're going to play a clip,
something I found on YouTube to
close and enjoy. 30 seconds clip.
Where will you find a world of
ideas for your child? Only at
eToys. From Barbie to Brio to SwimWays.
eToys, where great ideas come to you.
That was a good find. Thank you.
Dylan, thank you so much for doing this.
Thank you. Can I make one
comment about that commercial?
Okay, one comment.
One comment before we end. That
commercial made that company go
bankrupt. Thank you all for joining.
Thank you for having me, Lenny.
Good luck. Thanks Dylan. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If you
found this valuable, you can subscribe
to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.