It's so incredibly necessary in improving
decision quality to take what's implicit
and make it explicit. It's not that intuition
is crap, your intuition is sometimes right.
If you don't make it explicit, then you
don't get to find out when it's wrong.
When you look at companies that have
read your book, what do you find are
the brainwashing tactics that really stick?
People generally think the purpose of a meeting
is for three things, discover, discuss, decide.
The only thing that's ever supposed to happen in
a meeting is the discussion part.
Something that comes up in product a
lot is this idea of pre-mortems.
So a pre-mortem, it's great only if
you set up kill criteria. Commit to actions that
you're going to take if you see those signals.
You have a very interesting framework for
how to think about decision quality when
the outcome is very long-term.
There is no such thing as a long
feedback loop. And the way you choose
to shorten the feedback loop is to say,
what are the things that are correlated with
the outcome that I eventually desire?
Today, my guest is Annie Duke. Annie is the
author of the bestselling book Thinking in Bets,
and also her more recent book Quit: The
Power of Knowing When to Walk Away. She's
also a special partner at First Round Capital,
which we spent some time on and is incredibly
fascinating. Prior to this part of her career,
she was a professional poker player. She's won
over $4 million in tournaments, including winning
a World Series of Poker Bracelet, and she's the
only woman who's won the World Series of Poker
Tournament of Champions and the National Poker
Heads-Up Championship. Currently, she spends her
time helping companies make better decisions. In
our conversation, we cover the many lessons that
she's learned from her friend Daniel Kahneman,
who recently passed away. What simple change she's
found has the most impact in a company's ability
to make better decisions, how to make better quick
decisions when the feedback loop is very long,
and also why she doesn't actually believe in
long feedback loops, how she changed the way
that the partners at First Round Capital make
decisions, which is incredibly interesting.
Plus, why when you're thinking about quitting,
that probably means you've already waited too
long and you should have quit a while ago.
I learned a ton from this conversation and
this is definitely going to change the way
I think about a lot of things. With that,
I bring you Annie Duke after a short word from
our sponsors. And if you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in
your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's
the best way to avoid missing future episodes
and it helps the podcast tremendously. This
episode is brought to you by Vanta. When it
comes to ensuring your company has top-notch
security practices, things get complicated fast.
Now you can assess risk, secure the trust of your
customers, and automate compliance for SOC 2,
ISO 27001, HIPAA and more with a single platform,
Vanta. Vanta's market-leading trust management
platform helps you continuously monitor compliance
alongside reporting and tracking risk.
Plus, you can save hours by completing
security questionnaires with Vanta AI. Join
thousands of global companies that use Vanta
to automate evidence collection, unify
risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go
to vanta.com/lenny. That's vanta.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by UserTesting.
Get fast feedback from real people throughout
the development process so that you can build
the right thing the first time. Companies are
being asked to do more with less. They need to
move more quickly while building experiences
that meet changing customer expectations, all
while minimizing risk and costly rework. With
UserTesting, you have a trusted partner who
provides user research teams with the skills,
tools, and data to be able to articulate
the value of user research to the business
so that you can make an impact and build the best
experiences with confidence. Get started today at
usertesting.com/lenny. Annie, thank you so much
for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you so much for having me.
It's my pleasure. I was telling a bunch of
people that you were coming on this podcast and
every single one of them was so excited that we
were doing this, so I'm quite excited that this is
happening. I want to start with a question about
Daniel Kahneman. I know you two were very close.
You did a podcast together. I know you grew to be
good friends over the past few years. Sadly, he
passed away about a week ago at this point.
Yeah.
I'm curious, what are
some lasting lessons that you took away from your
time with him? Maybe one or two things that stick
with you and you think will stick with you?
It's hard for me to describe properly how humble
this man was, and it seems so impossible because
his influence was so huge and his intellect was
so huge and his insight was so change-making in
the areas that he worked. But he was so humble,
he really wanted to hear what you thought. He
said, "I don't know a lot", he would change his
mind. It's funny, I got asked in a class that
I was teaching about thinking fast and slow
and someone was talking about how there's a lot of
studies in there that didn't end up replicating.
And what I've seen from a lot of other people in
the field who really where their work is defined
by some line of work that didn't replicate,
where they're really arguing against the fact
that it doesn't replicate. Just trying to justify
or say, "But no", or this and that. This real lack
of open-mindedness to the idea that you know what?
Maybe it turns out not to be true and that should
be okay. But the thing about Danny was when you
talked about it, he was the first one to tell you,
"I wish priming wasn't in the book. It doesn't
replicate." He was just so open-minded to the
idea that he knows what he knows now, but
he knows that he doesn't know everything.
Another thing that people don't know about him
outside of academics I think are that he was one
of the pioneers in something called an adversarial
collaboration. So one of his favorite things, and
he in some ways invented it, was find someone who
really disagrees with you and then write a paper
with them and try to figure out with them what's
the study that would resolve the issue. So an
example of that was Danny did work on happiness as
it relates to wealth. Kahneman and a collaborator,
Angus Deaton, they published a result that
got a lot of press about the relationship
between money and happiness, and the idea was
money doesn't buy happiness beyond $75,000.
So that got published in 2010. I'm sure if
you ran that exact same study, it would be
more than $75,000 now because it would adjust
for inflation. But it was like the idea being
once your basic needs are met and you're not that
worried about paying rent and so on and so forth,
it's not going to have that big of an effect.
But then a decade later, Matthew Killingsworth
said, "That's not true that actually money
and happiness are correlated through all the
income levels. The more money you have, the more
happy you tend to be." Okay, so this is a classic
example where people will tear each other down
sometimes and that guy's wrong and whatever. And
instead, it was Kahneman's like, "All right, let's
do it together." And they joined forces along
with Barb Mellers to basically try to resolve that
issue. He was just always seeking out, it was just
like everything was like, why am I wrong? And he
was eager and he was excited and he wanted to...
I remember having a lunch with him where
I realized after the lunch that the whole
lunch was him asking me questions about my
work. Why is he asking me questions about
my work? Right? He's Danny Kahneman. But he was
just so curious about other people and he just
made time for everybody. He just loved the people
around him so much. And I think that in the end,
it's hard to believe, but I just think that that
dwarfs his body of work, which is spectacular.
But he as a human being was just so spectacular.
And I do think you hear all the time about people
who are so incredibly brilliant. It's the
brilliant but asshole thing, and it was
just so the opposite with him. He was so kind.
That's amazing. And it feels like there's probably
a strong correlation between people that are
curious, always looking for how they're wrong, and
finding time to spend it with people to debate and
discuss and ask. Feels like there's going to be a
strong correlation with that and finding really
interesting insights uncovering new things.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. [inaudible 00:09:12].
Well, thank you. Thank you for sharing all
that. I wish I had known him. Let's talk about
decision-making. So there's two areas I want to
spend time on. As one would not be surprised,
decision-making and quitting. And I know that
you've been on a lot of podcasts. I imagine many
listeners have read your book or have heard a lot
about the stuff that you teach. I'm going to
try to come at this from a bunch of different
directions and do it a little differently. First
of all, I know you're a parent. As last I heard,
you have four kids. I just had a
kid, he's almost 10 months now.
Oh, congratulations.
Thank you. I'm curious, what your frameworks
you find most helpful in parenting and in raising
your kids that have stuck with you there?
Well, let me just first off say I get a lot of
people who are pregnant who come and ask me for my
advice about parenting. And I'll tell you the two
pieces of advice I give people. The first is this,
there's all sorts of parenting books, there's
all sorts of styles. A book needs to sell,
so they need to sell you something new
or different or whatever, okay. But the
only thing that matters really is that your
kids know you love them, really know deep
in their bones, know you love them.
And we can argue breastfeeding versus
not breastfeeding or co-sleeping versus not
co-sleeping or attachment parenting or sleep
training, we can talk about all that stuff, right?
Do you homeschool? Do you send them to private
school? Do you send them [inaudible 00:10:49]?
We can have lots of [inaudible 00:10:51], but it
all dwarfs in comparison to your children know
that you would lay down in the street in the
front of a bus if it meant that they would
be alive and happy. That's the number one
thing I say. Number two is at some point, you
will drop your baby on its head. So I bet this
has happened to you already.
Well, yeah. Sort of. Okay.
Sort of, right.
Keep coming.
So here's the thing about babies, is babies
can't move. And so you get very used to
as a mom or a dad or you're sitting on the couch
and you're folding laundry and your baby is right
here next to you and your baby can't move. And
then one day without warning, your baby can roll
over. And you think it's fine because you put a
pillow there or something, but you turn your back
for a second because you're like whatever and
then your baby falls on its head. It happened
with every single one of my children. And they
don't fall that far and whatever, but they're
totally fine and you're not a bad parent. And
it's just this, there are things you don't know
and stuff's going to happen and it's not going to
be perfect. And every little thing isn't going to
have some lasting impression on your child because
at some point, you will drop your baby on its head
and you will not mean to, you didn't intend to.
But in my case, it was always like, oh my gosh,
my baby can roll over. I did not think that was
going to happen today. And gosh, by the time I
got to the fourth one, it's like I'm chasing after
one baby to try to get the diaper on and this and
that, so then the other baby hits its head. So I
think there's just a lesson in that which is like
it's a small thing, don't sweat it and don't get
mad at yourself because you made a mistake. It's
like the mistake would be, oh, I realize my baby
could roll over now. So now you should make sure
that you're taking extra precautions about your
baby rolling over off the couch. But it's really
just a funny way for me to say your baby's going
to hit its head or walk into a coffee table or get
cut or whatever. It's like they're very resilient
and you didn't do anything wrong as a parent,
so don't beat yourself up about that. And then
I do actually have one other thing I say.
Yeah, go for it.
Be having four, you have very little,
you have no influence whatsoever basically on what
your child's personality is. What you can do as a
parent is make sure they say please and thank you.
So what I find with parents of one is particularly
if that one is very well-behaved, they think
they're a great parent and they may be. That
would be resulting. They may be, but once you have
four, what you realize is like, oh, my parenting
really didn't have anything to do with it. But
my children do say please and thank you.
This is really valuable, good advice. I need to
hear this. My wife is going to need to hear this,
too. She's always worried about the
soft spot on our kid's head and getting
hit into some things.
No, it'll be fine.
Okay, great.
It's actually it's part of why it's there. Really,
your baby will be fine. I mean, that's the thing.
We used to cart babies around in the wilderness,
we were living in case. We're fine, we're built
for it. We're built for a much rougher world
than the world that babies actually grow up in
now. I will say my oldest child when she was
in high school, just for whatever reason, she
had no interest whatsoever in alcohol or drugs
or anything like that. And I remember just feeling
so smug about how well I had raised this child and
how great she was, and oh, these other parents
who clearly weren't doing a good job. I mean,
I didn't really but because it's hard
not to. And then my next child went
through high school and I was like, [inaudible
00:15:02]. That's just a temperament thing.
It's a good example of resulting in action.
It is a good example of resulting, but all my
kids have turned out fine and they're all very
different, but yeah. But as far as decision-making
is concerned, which is a totally different
thing, I'll actually quote Danny Kahneman
on this one. Nothing is as important as
it seems when you're thinking about it,
that's a really important one. One of the things
that I used to try to do with my kids all the
time was mental time travel, which is actually a
very good decision tool. So they would be really
upset about something and it could be something
that happened at school or it could be like they
were grounded for something or whatever.
And the thing is when you're in the moment,
it just feels like so big. And the thing that
I used to say and they say all the time now is
this is going to be so great for you when
you're 40 at Thanksgiving. You're going to
be able to tell these stories to your children
and it's going to be the best, like you should
be thanking me so that you can talk about your
crazy mother at the Thanksgiving table. And it
allowed them to get some time and space from it to
realize this is going to be funny at some point.
At some point, it's going to be a hilarious story
that you tell people. No matter how horrible it
seems now, it's going to be a hilarious story
at some point when you're older. And it sounds
like a fun thing I was doing with them, but it's
actually a really good decision-making tool for
us in general, right? Look, there are absolutely
things that 20 years from now are going to matter,
for sure. But most things, no. If you think
about most things that ever happen to you,
like you're 21 and your girlfriend breaks up
with you or whatever and you just think it's
the end of the world and you're never going to
recover and all these things, but if you could
get yourself like, well, how do I really think
I'm going to think about this in 10 years? Am
I still going to be heartbroken in 10 years?
Probably not. And I think that we need to get
that perspective of time so that we can get out
of the moment because in the moment it just feels
so important and the feelings are so big. And
it's like the focusing effect on this second
and the feelings you're feeling right now are
so huge that we forget the scope of time. And
I think that that's absolutely one of the best
things you can do with your kids, and you can
do it in small ways too, right? You can choose to
play this video game or you can choose to study
for your task. A week from now when you get
that test back, how do you think you're going
to feel about those two choices? Right?
So that was a tool that I used a ton and
it's just generally an amazing decision-making
tool, just generally for people. It's one that
I happen to use with my kids all the time. And
then I would say that the other one was using
the word nevertheless, which is this is a great
leadership skill, the word nevertheless. So let's
say my child got caught doing something wrong. I
don't know, I found a bag of red solo cups in my
backyard that they forgot to throw out after a
weekend that I was away. That's hypothetical. So
I'm grounding them and it's a lot of argument
back, right? So they think this is a debate
and they're giving me all of their input and
their opinions on why it's unfair and all the
other kids do it and the other parents don't get
mad and whatever, whatever the argument is. You
have to have the balance between them feeling
heard, which I think is incredibly important
that your children feel heard, and following
through on what you know or believe is right.
So it's I hear you. Nevertheless, you're grounded
for two weeks. I hear what you're saying and I
understand. Nevertheless, this is what's going to
happen. And obviously, the words that you can use
for that might be different. You have so much more
authority obviously over your children than you do
in other places. But in the workplace, this is
very good because employees gripe all the time
at decisions that you make in leadership because
they think they're right and they want their way.
And to have the ability to say, I heard you and
your input, trust me, was incorporated into the
decision, nevertheless, this is the path we're
going to take. Right or wrong, that's what we're
going to do. So I think there's a lot of things
that basically you can say. These are good things
to do with kids, but they're actually just
generally really good decision strategies.
I'm taking notes on all these things.
These are going to be extremely useful.
Nevertheless is a really
good one with children.
It connects to something Dr. Becky teaches, if
you know her, of telling someone, "I believe you."
When your kid says something and they're upset
about something, start with I believe you.
Nevertheless.
And here's nevertheless,
exactly. Fair enough. I think we're going
to start having to pivot this podcast to a
parenting podcast because there's so much stuff
here, but I'm going to try to resist. So we've
been talking about decision-making and frameworks
and things like that. Something I wanted to ask
you is how much better can someone get at making
better decisions? So for example, say someone
listens to all of your podcasts, reads your book,
studies it intensely. What's the delta you find in
somebody being able to make a better decision? And
where [inaudible 00:20:35] comes from is Daniel
Kahneman of all people. People ask him, "Do you
just live such a optimal life now that you know
all of these biases we have and all these mental
errors we make?" And he's like, "No, I can't..."
I think he said famously, "I don't, actually. I
can't use these in practice. This is just stuff
that I have learned, but it doesn't actually
impact my day to day." So I'm curious just how
much better can someone get? What kind of delta
have you found in terms of making decisions?
Okay, so it depends on whether you actually do
the things. I mean, I think that that's what the
issue is. I think Kahneman did some work way
back that started him on this journey. That
was basically work on hiring and it was taking
it from completely unstructured Lenny, saying,
"I just know a great product manager
when I see one", whatever that means,
to me going to Lenny and saying, "Okay,
I understand that you think that you see
a great product manager you know one when you
see one", but can you explain to me what that
means? In the abstract, what are the things
that you're looking for in someone that you
want to fill that role? And we can then excavate
that, right? And make what is implicit because
you're applying some implicit model to how you're
thinking about the person that you're interviewing
and how they map onto the role that they're
going to be, but let's make that explicit.
So we can make that explicit, we can turn it into
a decision rubric, we can create a structured
interview process out of that. And then what he
found was after you've gone through that process,
if you then use your intuition after having
done that, not before, that then you actually
can really drastically improve your hit rate
on hiring. And in that case, it was from about
a 50% hit rate to 65. So that's pretty huge,
so that's a really big difference. The problem
is nobody does it. So I can tell you that most of
the conversations that I had with Danny that were
about my work in particular were just him saying,
"How do you get anybody to do it?" Now that's not
to say that I would be better at that than him,
it's that he didn't do my job, right? So he was an
academic doing research and so on and so forth,
I'm living in companies embedding for years.
I've been with one client for five years, one
client for four years, one client for four
years also, almost four years, three and a half
years. And then I just took on a new client who
I've been with for six months, and that's my
whole client roster because I stay with them
so long. So if you do it, the answer is quite
a bit. Like at least in terms of Danny's work
in relation to something pretty noisy like hiring,
you went from 50% hit rate to 65% hit rate,
which is huge. It's enormous. The problem is that
the way that you can make decisions in order to
be better at them is not supernatural
to the way that humans make decisions.
I think we think a lot more highly of our
intuition than we really ought to. We think
very highly of our ability to notice things in
the moment and act rationally toward them in a
way that really we ought not to. We tend to think
that we have insight that other people don't have
when actually the other people probably have more
insight into our situation than we do. So I think
the answer is a lot with a big if, with an if you
can get people to do it. And I think that's where
the issue comes in. Now, the good news is that you
can then reverse that and say if I'm willing to do
it, think about what an edge I'm going to have
over people who aren't willing to do it, right?
So we can think there's people who don't know
about it, there's people who do know about it
but don't do it, and then there's people who
do know about it, but do do it. And it's that
last group that's so tiny. So the answer
is I think a lot, but nobody does it.
So maybe following that thread, when you look at
companies that you've worked with or companies
that have read your book and really dove
in and started to implement some of your
piece of advice to make better decisions, if you
could look back at the ones that had an impact,
what do you find are the mental models or
frameworks or tactics that really stick that most
often have an impact and the biggest impact?
I think the one that's easiest to implement
is this. And it's so easy, and I just wish more
people would do it. The best way to get somebody's
opinion is independently of other people's
opinions, independently asynchronously. So the
way that I put is I want people to stop talking to
each other so much. When we think about what did
people generally think the purpose of a meeting
is, they think it's for three things. Discovery,
which is I want to discover what your opinions
are, what your judgments are of something, right?
So I want to find out what you think about
something. So for example, if we're in product
development and we're trying to figure out a
timeline, we're trying to develop a product
roadmap and we're trying to figure out how long
it's going to take to release certain features
or something like that, we all come into a
room and we start yelling it out together.
It's so bad for decision-making, I can't
even tell you. There's cross influence,
the loudest person in the room tends to then
have an outsized influence on the decision,
the most confident person in the room tends
to have an outsized influence on the decision.
And that's great if the most confident person is
also right, but the problem is that's not always
so. And so that's the discovery piece, right?
And we tend to do that in a group. And then
there's discussion, which is I've now discovered
the way that Lenny is modeling this problem or
what his judgments are about certain things or
his forecasts are, his estimates are. And now,
we're going to discuss those ideas and we're going
to discuss your ideas in comparison to my ideas,
and that's going to happen in the group
setting. And then there's also now,
we're going to decide in the group setting. So
we're going to make some set of decisions about
say what the roadmap is going to look like.
Here's the thing that I think is the easiest to
change, is to realize the only thing that's ever
supposed to happen in a meeting is the discussion
part. So we should absolutely be coming together
as human beings to discuss everybody's judgments
and opinions and the way they're modeling the
problem and their forecasts. In particular,
it's really good to come in and discuss the places
where people are different. So you've been in
many meetings, I'm sure about 80% of the time is
double clicking. Oh, I agree. And I want to now
we've literally just used different words to say
the exact same thing because I'm in agreement.
If we can focus the discussion on places that
people disagree, we're much better off. But so
now we can take this, discover, discuss, decide.
So I'm saying discuss is only supposed to happen
in the meeting, that's the only thing that's
supposed to happen in the meeting. So what's
happening with the other stuff, the discover and
the decide? Well, and this is the thing that I
think I actually have been able to get people to
do is discover what people think before you get in
a room independently of each other. So how would
you do that? Well, let's imagine that you're going
to have a meeting about the product roadmap.
So you would say to yourself in this meeting,
what are the opinions that I need to get from
the people in the room? It could be a brainstorm.
What are all the different features that we could
develop? So it could be a brainstorm. Fine. Write
to them independently and say, "Hey, free for off.
Just come up with all the different features that
you think would be reasonable for us to consider
developing and then give me a forced rank from
best to worst of your own ideas with some three to
five sentence rationale as to why you have these
things in this order." And so I could do that,
but maybe we already have a list. I can send
that out for a forced rank to everybody. Okay,
so here's the final list of things we're really
considering. Prioritize those for me, just force
rank them. And then again, give me a rationale.
Give me a little bit of free writing as to why
you think this should be, that you have these
things in this order. Maybe we've decided now on
what our top five priorities are. Great. I could,
before the meeting, send the top five priorities
out. "Hey, we've decided on this stuff." For each
thing, I'd like to understand what you think a
reasonable timeline is, how many sprints it's
going to take, so on, so forth, right? So we can
ask for that type of information so that we can
start making estimates because that's going to
affect budget and what we're going back to the
board with and so on so forth. But regardless,
just figure out what is the thing that we're
going to be discussing in this meeting? And I'm
going to send it out to everybody independently
and I'm going to say, "Don't reply all,
just send it back to me independently."
If it's a repeated decision, you can actually
create a rubric that lives on Airtable or Coda
or Google Sheets or whatever, I don't really care.
And people can input their decisions there where
they can't see anybody else's decision. So with
Google, you can use Google Forms in order to do
it, and then it dumps into a spreadsheet that
only you can see. That's a great way to do it.
So anyway, so you do that and now you can now
see everybody's opinions that you then now send
out to the group and say, "Everybody, look this
over before we come in and discuss." So notice
you're still working as a group, but you're
working as a group where you're not in the same
room together and talking at the same time. And
there's a word for that, which is nominal group.
So it's a group that at that moment is working
independently and asynchronously of each other.
So if you can get people to do that, and I do
have companies where I don't consult with them,
but I've just come in and talked to them briefly
or whatever that do actually implement that
piece of it. That is a huge piece of it, that's
ginormous. And then you do the same thing for
deciding. So the decision should not be made in
a room, it's made either. I love the one decision
maker model, but not everybody's down with that.
But you can have a vote forum where people go vote
in private about the way they're leaning.
You can do a variety of things with that,
but just don't do it. Don't do it in the meeting.
And then just the last thing that I'll add,
which is a muscle that you really have to
exercise, is I think it's really important
to understand that the word alignment in terms
of we're all aligned as a group, right? The
word alignment is stupid and it shouldn't be
used. And I know I'm saying that very harshly,
but it's true. It's dumb because it doesn't exist.
You have 10 people in a room and they're all
really different people with different opinions,
and they're never going to come out of the room
agreeing with each other. And it's really bad
if the expectation is that they're supposed to,
and it's really bad for a few reasons. One is
it isn't reality, and that I don't like coming
out of things without reality actually kicking.
So it's not reality. People don't actually agree,
they're not actually aligned on the decision.
That's just the thing that makes you feel better,
right? So I think that that's problem number
one. But problem number two is that if the goal
is alignment, if the goal is agreement, then the
meeting becomes coercive and you never want that.
So the way that I'm supposed to talk about my
ideas is to convey why I believe what I do,
not to convince anybody that I'm right because
if I'm working to convince people that I'm right,
it becomes coercive and that's horrible. So you
have to get comfortable with walking out of the
room. This is the nevertheless. Walking out of
the room understanding that once you have that
discussion, it's not that Lenny, your opinion
might change. It could, right? I could say my
thing and it could be just so damn brilliant
that you change your mind somewhat, right?
So you come maybe you're like, "Oh, I'm thinking
about this differently and actually", but maybe
you don't and you still believe a thing that's
very different than me. And leadership has to say,
"That's fine. I've heard both of you and I know
that this isn't going Annie's way. Nevertheless,
trying to think about what all of our goals
are, this is what the decision is going to
be and it's totally fine that you ended up not
agreeing with each other because it's reality.
And what it allows me to do is get a better
sense of what the space of decisions is."
So those things I have been able to get people
to do and they're actually quite impactful.
Imagine a place where you can find all your
potential customers and get your message in
front of them in a cost-efficient way. If you're
a B2B business, that place exists, and it's called
LinkedIn. LinkedIn Ads allows you to build the
right relationships, drive results, and reach
your customers in a respectful environment. Two
of my portfolio companies, Webflow and Census,
are LinkedIn success stories. Census had a
10X increase in pipeline with the LinkedIn
startup team. For Webflow, after ramping up on
LinkedIn in Q4, they had the highest marketing
source revenue quarter to date. With LinkedIn
Ads, you'll have direct access to and can build
relationships with decision-makers, including 950
million members, 180 million senior execs and over
10 million C-level executives. You'll be able to
drive results with targeting and measurement tools
built specifically for B2B. In tech, LinkedIn
generated two to five X higher return on ad
spend than any other social media platforms.
Audiences on LinkedIn have two times the buying
power of the average web audience, and you'll
work with a partner who respects the B2B world you
operate in. Make B2B marketing everything it can
be and get $100 credit on your next campaign. Just
go to linkedin.com/podlenny to claim your credit.
That's linkedin.com/podlenny. Terms and conditions
apply. There's an implication here you touched on
a bit that there's a DRI essentially, there's one
decision maker. Sometimes people start to feel
like, "Oh, my voice isn't heard. I don't have a
lot of say, I can't be part of this decision."
And you talked a bunch about just how to make
people feel included, you get feedback along the
way. But any advice there if you try to move to
this model of making people feel like, "Okay,
I actually have impact on where this goes"?
Yeah. So here's the really wonderful thing about
moving from a coercive model to really, I guess
you could say a model of curiosity, right? You
want to be curious, not coercive, which means that
the way that people in the meeting are talking
about what their opinions are is in the mode
of conveying information, not trying to convince
anybody. So once we move away from that coercive
model, and when I say coercive, I'm not saying
anybody is purposely trying to set up a culture
of coercion. Sometimes that's true, but for the
most part, everybody's trying to do a good job and
nobody's trying to set up a culture of coercion.
But as soon as you say, "Are we all in agreement?
Are we all in alignment?" And as soon as you're
allowing people, and I'm sure you've been in these
meetings, right? If you allow people to interrupt,
if you allow people to say this, "I think you're
wrong", "I disagree", "Here's why", those
are all very coercive things to have happen.
Interrupting someone is silencing them. Saying,
"You're wrong", well now, you become tribal and
people aren't going to be open-minded and
they're going to stake their ground and
it's all really bad. So let's move away from
that. Number one, that's already going to help.
But when we think about the way that
meetings normally happen, again,
there's all this crosstalk and some people aren't
speaking and some people are and so on, so forth.
And then of course, not everybody feels equally
heard. But when you work as a nominal group,
let's talk about something as simple as we're
going to make a forecast of how long it's going
to take to launch this product feature. Okay.
So I'm going to send out to everybody, what's
your point estimate? What's your lower bound?
What's your upper bound in terms of timeline?
And you could do it in some way, like how
many sprints do you think is going to take
whatever language you want to use? Now, everybody
independently now gives their forecast with a
rationale for why they believe that. And then you
come into the room and you run a discussion where
everybody's getting to say what their estimate was
and why they believe that, and people are getting
to ask questions. "I have a question" always is a
clarification, it's just I don't understand. And
as the leadership, the way that you would do
it is, let me give you an example from a real
one because that'll be easy. I did one of these
discussions for a question about remote work,
like what did the company want in terms of
remote versus hybrid and that kind of thing. And
so there was a lot of disagreement about whether
whatever the policy was, it should be consistent
across functions. Lots of disagreement.
So let's take somebody who was on the, no,
it shouldn't be consistent across functions. So
they now say why they believe it shouldn't be
consistent across functions and they say things
like, "Well, different functions have different
requirements, right?" So there's some functions
that have to be in the office, like if you're IT
as an example, but there's other functions which
are more collaborative and creative and whatnot
where it makes sense for people to be in the
office, whereas engineers doesn't really matter,
right? So there's different needs of different
functions in terms of how much they need to be in
the same space. So I'm not agreeing or disagreeing
with this, I'm just saying what somebody said.
So now as a facilitator, I never say, "Oh, I
agree." What I say is I just want to make sure I
understood what you said and I reflect it back.
So I say, "So what I heard you say is that not
all functions are created equal in terms of how
well they work remotely or how well they work in
person or what the flexibility might be. So what
you're saying is there're functions that have to
be in person. Period. And then other functions
where that collaborative element being in the
same office would be more important versus some
functions where being remote is totally fine.
Is that what you meant?" And then they have the
ability to say, "Yes, that is what I meant" or,
"Actually, I meant something slightly different.
Let me say what that is", and then I reflect that
back. Okay, so literally you're just going
around, you're calling on people to do that,
and then you're reflecting back what they say
without offering your own opinion. I don't know,
Lenny. Tell me how someone doesn't
feel heard in that situation.
Yeah. Absolutely. I would feel so good
if somebody just clarified and made it
clear they know exactly what I'm saying, even if
the decision doesn't end up the way I want.
Right, so that's the thing. And then what actually
ends up happening is that the people in the room
feel more, the psychological term would be
endowed, more endowed to the decision. In
other words, they feel like they have ownership
over the decision. And whatever the decision is,
they generally will see their selves
reflected in it because they were heard.
And they also will generally understand that
nobody, no one really ends up with exactly
every single thing that they wanted to
see in the decision because they also
get to see the true spread of opinions on the
team. And what you see in that situation is
that there's lots and lots and lots and lots
of disagreement, which you don't see if you
talk in a group. It narrows the space, right?
So for example, particularly if you're senior,
if you say, "I think this is going to take three
months to launch" and I was thinking four weeks,
you're never going to hear four weeks from me,
ever. But if we get those opinions independently,
you will actually hear that I think it's going
to take four weeks. You may tend to be more
right there being more senior, but I may have
something interesting to say. You should hear
what I have to say. And this also allows me to
learn from you, too. But because I haven't heard
your opinion first, then I'm not going to conform
my opinion to yours. So it actually spreads the
surface area of disagreement that you see on
the team, which then makes people feel much
better about the decision not being exactly
what they want because they recognize like,
"Oh, this is actually a hard problem.
People really disagree on this stuff."
Amazing. I think this is going to be really
helpful to a lot of people. Just to close the
thread on this little summary maybe is core advice
here is brainstorm separately. So I guess first,
there's discover, discuss, decide. To
discover ideas completely independently,
basically brainstorms. You're a big advocate of
brainstorming independently, sitting on your own,
thinking through ideas. And then bringing people
together to discuss all the things they've come up
with and especially where they disagree. And then
ideally having one person that makes a decision
once she or he has taken all the input.
Yeah, you can have one person. I mean,
I work with people where it's like a partnership
and there's six people who are going to vote,
but they still do it independently. They go to a
forum. So I don't know what your vote is. And all
six people don't have to agree. I mean, I just
think it's really important that once you get
above an end of one, you shouldn't necessarily
expect the people to agree, which I think is
just really important. And this is good for more
than just brainstorming. It's for forecasting,
any kind of project planning, budgeting. Yeah,
I mean, we do this, for example, at First Round,
we have a structured forum for evaluating a
company in terms of whether you should invest in
it because there are facts and then there are the
way that you model those facts in. So it's a lot,
what are the investor's opinion of the founder
and the product and that kind of thing.
And we just have structure around
how we're eliciting those opinions,
which is really helpful. The other thing that I'll
just add to what you said is that you can actually
be in the same room together and still discover
information independently. So this will happen on
the fly all the time where people are talking
and they start talking. Something comes up,
like someone suggests some new feature or
something like that, and then people start saying,
"Yeah, but that's going to take..." And you go,
"Stop. Okay, everybody take out a piece of paper."
So you can still get that same independence
on the fly as well as doing it in advance.
But yes, that was a very nice summary.
If this is just the one thing people take
away from this conversation already, I think that
could have a big impact. Speaking of First Round,
one, we actually just had Todd Jackson
on the podcast talking about-
Love Todd.
... love Todd, talking about product
market fit. That episode will have come out before
this episode. Also, so I asked Brett Berson,
your colleague at First Round, what to ask you.
Oh, okay.
Yeah, yeah. By the way, your title of
First Round is amazing, special partner.
I've never seen that before.
I am. It's a title just for me.
Oh, my God.
I adore Brett Berson.
Me, too.
So I'm interested, I'm
interested in what he said you should ask me.
Nothing too spicy, it's along the lines of what
you talked about. So you said that you have
a very interesting framework for how to think
about decision quality in the short term when
the outcome is very long term. For example,
investing. Also, many decisions we make in
business, things you need to decide now that
you only find out years from now. Can you talk
about your advice there and your insights here?
Oh my gosh, I'm so happy that that's
the question that he asked.
Yep, I see.
Okay, so can I give a tiny
bit of background to this?
Absolutely.
So prior to talking to First Round, I have another
client too who, they're amazing, Renegade Partners
at Roseanne Wincek and Renata Quintini. They're
incredible. Before finally hooking up with them,
and they work at different stages, First Round
is C, obviously. Renegade is more like A B,
tiny bit of dabble in C. But before running into
them, I talked to quite a few venture firms who
are interested in talking to me post-Thinking
in Bets having come out, so this would be 2018.
And there was a theme, there was a theme across
them all. The first one was, well, the kind of
decision-making you're talking about we don't need
to do because we just know a good founder when we
see one. So that is a sentence that came out of
many people's mouths. And as I just said to you,
okay, I have no doubt, but don't you want
[inaudible 00:46:52] make that explicit?
There's all sorts of great things that come
from making it explicit, not just in terms of
the increase in decision quality in the moment,
but it actually allows you to close feedback
loops much better. So that was one thing that
I found quite surprising. But the one that I
really found very interesting was being told,
"Well, what you're talking about doesn't apply
because our feedback loops are a decade." And
in poker, you got an answer right away. You won
or lost the hand right away. So the way that
you're thinking about decision-making doesn't
really apply, until I met First Round and then
Renegade where they actually heard what I had to
say because I gave the same answer to everybody.
So we'll just put aside that wouldn't you want to
make that explicit. The first thing that I would
say is, oh, poker is much noisier than you think
because when I win a hand, I have no idea why.
So I do actually have to wait a long time because
I have to play many, many, many hands before I
actually know, do I actually have an edge? Because
I actually don't know very much. On one hand, for
one thing, I almost never see my opponent's card,
so I'm left in a dust of uncertainty. But
separately from that, the main thing that I
said was, how could you possibly think that the
feedback loop is 10 years? And this is what I
think really caught First Round's eye because
when I was talking to Josh Kopelman about it,
he said, "Well, what do you mean? We don't
get an exit for 10 years." And I said, "Oh,
I'm sorry, do you invest? And then you go
to sleep like Rip Van Winkle? And then you
wake up 10 years later and you go, 'Hey, how'd
that go?' Or are there all sorts of things that
happen in between?" The simplest thing, the
simplest thing is does it fund at Series A?
And the little pushback that I would get there is,
but we're not investing for Series A. And I say,
"Well, I know that", but have you ever had a
company that exited for more than a billion
dollars that did not fund at Series A? And the
answer is no. And I'm like, okay. So it sounds
like that's necessary. Might not be sufficient,
but it's necessary. And it's certainly a signal
that is actually more highly correlated with
exiting out well than the investment at C. And
then, oh, right, you have series B. And that's
separate from all the other things that you can
look at, like what you talked to Todd Jackson
about. Is it achieving product market fit? We
know that eventually for it to be successful,
it's going to have to achieve product market fit,
right? So you can look at what's happening
with that, just general things about traction,
what's happening with net new ARR,
ability to retain top talent churn.
I mean, there's so many different things that you
can look at, all of which are things that you know
must happen in order for the big thing to happen.
Okay, so what that means is that this is the big,
I'm going to make a bold statement here. There
is no such thing as a long feedback loop. You
can make a decision about how long the feedback
loop is. That is your choice to live in a long
feedback loop, and you can choose to shorten the
feedback loop. And the way you choose to shorten
the feedback loop is to say, what are the things
that are necessary but not sufficient? That's
one thing, for getting a good exit, or what
are the things that are correlated with the
outcome that I eventually desire? And what that
means is that when you're at the decision point,
right? Like in First Round's case,
I'm going to invest in a company.
What you have to understand is that you are
making a prediction about how the world is going
to unfold, how the future is going to unfold.
And those things that you're predicting. You
can track, and you can track them back to the
decision and you can do it pretty darn fast,
mind you. I mean, think about being in 2021.
There were companies that were raising in A
six months after seed. Today, it's a little more
16 months-ish. But even so, let's just say that
that was the only thing that you decided to do.
I'm going to forecast the probability that this
company's going to fund at Series A. And then
obviously, those companies start to fund or
not fund at Series A and you're finding that
out in 16 months. Here's my question for you,
Lenny. Is 16 months shorter than 10 years?
So it's probably why he said to ask me that
question because I just really do. I mean, I have
a very strong opinion about this. The feedback
loop is as long as you choose it to be. And if I
take that back to some of the things that I heard
early on when I was talking to people, what I
would say is that I think that there is a certain
amount of psychological safety in allowing the
feedback loop to stay long because really of two
main factors. One is that, look, if I was early
into Uber and now I'm a celebrity investor or
something, I don't really want to know if I'm good
or not. Do I? Right? I don't really want the world
to know that. I mean, if I'm good, that's great.
But it feels like they already believe that I'm
good because I happen to be early into Uber.
So since people already think I'm good,
I'm just losing to that decision, psychologically
speaking. Not investment quality speaking,
but psychologically speaking. Okay, so here's
the problem though. Why was I early into Uber?
Did I have an insight into a real pain point in
a developing market, blah, blah, blah? Or did
my buddy start Uber and I was like, "Sure, I'll
give you some money?" Right? I mean, obviously,
I'm talking about the extremes here, but we don't
actually know what the decision quality was,
right? All we know is that you had a good result
and given that you had a good result and people
think very highly of you, what are you going to
gain? Right? So it's so nice to just let that
feedback loop sit there and allow people to
have the opinion of you. That is really nice,
feels good, right? And not actually find
out the answer because why would I want to?
Unless you're really super focused on decision
quality, then you would want to do that. So that's
part of the psychological safety. And what that
goes to is, the real core of it is that it's very,
very difficult for human beings to
deal with feeling wrong in the moment,
even if it helps them in the long run. It's
just hard. And the tighter the feedback loop,
the more that you risk finding out you are
wrong in the short run. Now that helps you
to learn and improve your decision-making if
you're focused on it and you're good at it,
right? That's going to help you. And then
in the long run, you're actually going to
do better. But human beings are notoriously
good at trading off the long run just to feel
good in the short run. That's why we're all
eating chocolate and cupcakes and stuff that
we know is bad for us because it feels good.
And so much of our decision-making is trying
to advance this positive self-narrative and
the idea that yeah, we're going to have a
more positive narrative ourselves in five years
if we do some stuff. Most of us are like, "No,
I don't really want to make that trade. I'd
rather just feel good now", and I can use the
fact that we are living in power law, under the
influence of power law. I can use that to just
confirm a lot of things that I wish to believe
that are true of me. And if you take that away
from me and you take the uncertainty away from
me, it's going to be really hard. And I will tell
you that's what I love about both Renegade
and First Round is that they're just like,
I want to know. It would be such a horror for me
to think that I was making good decisions when I
actually wasn't. And that's what really matters
to me and I think that it's just so special.
Hearing all this makes me want to be an LP in
First Round. Not that they would let me in there,
but just knowing that you're in there futzing
with everything and the way they're thinking is
really inspiring. I'm curious if you
could share an example of anything that
they tweaked as a result of this analysis
that you did and how they evaluate.
Well, first of all, let me just say they didn't
really record a lot about their decisions when I
first came in. They voted and they had a record
of the vote so they knew who said yes and who
said no, but they didn't have a lot of other
information. So the first thing that happened
was just that. Okay, what do we really think
is the way that you would model whether you
should invest or not invest in? Very broadly, you
would say you're reading the market, the team,
the founder, the product broadly. We're going to
make sure that those opinions aren't just like
it's good or it's bad, but it's on a scale of
one to seven so that we can actually get some
precision and some spread among the partners in
terms of, say, strength of market. We're going to
make sure that we have shared definitions of those
things, which you'd be surprised people don't.
So when I am thinking about market and market
quality, I might be thinking about something
very different than you. So we want to make
sure that we have a shared definition of that,
and that's reflected in something that we would
call mediating judgments, which are judgments
that you make related to market prior to actually
judging what you think of the market in general.
So you could think of something like competitive
landscape, so you would judge that. So that turns
into what these mediating judgments are,
which is basically an implied definition.
So you create that, and then you also think about
what are the forecasts that are important. One
thing that you already know is you're going to
forecast the probability the company funds at
Series A. So that was a huge change, just a very
different way of making decisions. What we've
been able to do with that now because I've been
there for five years is we now can actually look,
say the partnership as a whole, and look
at these ratings that they're making of
the component pieces of parts of how they're
modeling, like what makes a good investment,
these forecasts that they're making.
And we actually know how these companies
have now unfolded. So in the simplest sense, we
know whether hundreds of companies have funded at
Series A or not. And now, we can actually look
and say, how good are the partners at actually
forecasting this thing? Right? Are they random?
Are they better than random? And we actually know
that and we can feed that back to them so that
they can understand their own accuracy around
these pieces of the decision because the fact
is that whatever a seed investor says to you,
whether that company is going to fund at
Series A is part of their decision. It's
included in the decision. So they're making
that forecast whether they make the forecast
explicitly or not. So what we're saying over at
First Round is let's make it explicit because
you're doing it implicitly anyway, and then we
can actually start to look at your accuracy.
We can now feed that back to you and let you
know how accurate you are, which will then
help you to become more accurate, right? We can
also look, because we know in any given vintage
what are the best companies or what are the worst
companies. Remember, we're having people do these
ratings on a scale of one to seven of say the
quality of the market, and we can look across
the partnership and say, "Look, Lenny, when you
think the market is great, how does that map onto
how well the company is doing in the future?
When you say the market is terrible, how well
does that map onto how that company is doing, how
that company ends up doing in the future?" And I
can come to you and I can say, "Oh, Lenny, by the
way, your judgments about market are amazing."
You know a good market when you see one and it's
really mapping on in a great way onto how that
company unfolds, but you're not so great with
founder, or maybe you're great across the board,
or maybe you're not. So we can now start to
give people, we can give the partners insight
into their own decision-making, not only to
allow them to improve the decision-making,
but also to allow them to understand not to over
index on certain things that maybe aren't as
predictive as an example for them. We also can
change the rubric based on the evidence now.
So the first version of the rubric is always
taking the intuitions of the partners and making
those explicit, but then we can start to loop
those back together and understand, well, maybe
this thing that the partners thought was important
actually isn't predictive across any partner. For
example, we can start to develop the rubric based
on the data. These were all things that weren't
possible because prior to that, if I had come in
and said, "Well, let's look at decision quality",
how would I do that? I mean, I have no idea why
people were... I just know whether they said
yes or no. And so it's very difficult to them to
start to do some really serious refining of the
decisions if I don't have that information.
I desperately want to know which partner it
makes the best decisions. I know
you're not going to share them.
No, I'm not going to. The partnership as a whole
is excellent as we know. And this is what I will
tell you is that all partners have strengths and
all partners have weaknesses, and they're not
perfectly overlapping, which is wonderful, right?
I mean, that's one of the things. It's like what's
really wonderful, and I think it shows the power
of why would you have more than one person having
input into a decision, is some people are very
strong on rating a particular aspect of market, or
some people are very strong on rating a particular
aspect of the founder. There's overlap and then
there's things where Todd is uniquely great at
something, or Josh is uniquely great at something,
or Bill is uniquely great at something. So that's
a wonderful thing about it is that everybody has
strengths and everybody has weaknesses and they're
not perfectly overlapping. So this is where you
can see getting that spread of opinions and really
understanding, breaking that decision down into
its component parts really shows you the value
of diverse opinions as input into a decision.
I could talk about this thread forever. Maybe let
me just ask one more question just because I'm
super curious. Is there anything surprising that
stands out, that came out of this analysis so far?
Just like, oh wow, maybe market isn't as important
as we thought or this person is amazing at-
Yes. So I think just generally speaking, when
you're creating the initial decision rubric,
there are things that people are really pounding
the table about that they think is especially
important in making a decision. And one of the
things that we found is that sometimes their
intuition was absolutely right. The thing that
they were pounding the table about is incredibly
predictive, not just for them but other partners.
But sometimes it's not at all predictive,
and these are equal table-pounding situations.
So let's say you're pounding the table about
something, sometimes the thing you're pounding
at the table about is predictive for you and
for all the other partners that it's actually
quite predictive about how the company does.
But sometimes when you're really
pounding the table about something,
it's not just that it's not predictive for the
other partners, it's not predictive for you.
And I think that what's really important to
understand about this, and this is why it's so
incredibly necessary in improving decision quality
to take what's implicit and make it explicit,
is that our intuition is sometimes right and
sometimes wrong. It's not that intuition is crap
and your intuition is just completely wrong, I
mean obviously, that can't be true. We would die,
right? So your intuition is sometimes
right, but it's also sometimes wrong.
And if you don't make it explicit, then
you don't get to find out when it's wrong.
You don't get to find out when it's off base,
and that's a disaster. So that's the thing that
I think is really interesting is that you have
equal vehement and confidence that this particular
factor is really important. And sometimes it is
and sometimes it isn't. And it's so surprising
because we're talking about people who are true
experts who are great, and I think that we all
just have intuition about intuition, right?
You just intuit that if they're so amazing,
clearly their intuition about what's important
would have to be good, but not necessarily.
That's the thing, not necessarily. Yeah, I think
that was probably the most exciting thing.
Keeping it mysterious, but I
still appreciate you sharing.
Well, I have to keep it mysterious.
Yes, I understand.
I can't give away the trade secrets.
I wanted to touch on a different framework that
I've heard a lot of companies actually using, and
something that comes up in product a lot is this
idea of pre-mortems, which is essentially think
ahead of time what might go wrong. Can you talk
about this? Because I think that it's something
that's easy to implement, really powerful,
and a lot of people are actually doing this.
Yes, okay. So a pre-mortem is great, but only
if you attach a pre-commitment with it. So I
just want to be super clear about that. What
you find with pre-mortems, this actually work.
I actually did this work with Maurice Schweitzer
and Linnea Gandhi, who are both at Penn.
Then when you have people do pre-mortems,
it generally doesn't actually change their
plan very much or it changed their behavior.
So I think that we have the feeling that if you
do a pre-mortem and you think what are the ways
that things might go wrong, that that's going to
change your plan, but probably not unless you're
specifically using it for that purpose and you
say, "Okay, we're going to do this, but let's
think about how we might change our plan in light
of this information." But I think what's actually
more important than that is what a pre-mortem
allows you to do is to set up kill criteria.
So kill criteria are just a set of signals that
you might see that would tell you that it's time
to pivot or stop because once we actually
launch something, we're very, very slow
to decide to quit. I'm sure that everybody has
felt that way before. Things go on way too long,
even like they're over budget and you've blown
the timeline. And when you finally shut it down,
you realize you should have done it a lot earlier.
And this is true across the board because of a
variety of biases. The most well-known, and
probably the biggest influence is something
called sunk cost, which is that feeling, but
then I'll have wasted all the time and effort
that I've put into this already. So it's taking
into account what you've put in in the past and
deciding whether to continue on in the future.
So what we want to do is actually just get
better at that thing. So understanding that
when you've gotten to the pre-mortem process,
you probably are going to launch it,
like it's probably going to be the case.
Use the pre-mortem to set up kill criteria. So
I'll give you an example from a sales team that
I worked with. Basically, I sent them out
a prompt, all the IC is a prompt that was,
imagine that you got a lead through an RFP or
RFI and you worked on it for six months. And now,
it's six months later and the deal is dead.
Looking back, you realized they were early
signals that that was going to be the case, what
were they. So this is a pre-mortem. What are the
things that you saw that would tell you that
this was going to go south? And they came up
with all sorts of ideas. Notice this doesn't mean
they're not going to start off pursuing the lead,
right? But they saw, they came up with all sorts
of signals. So I'll just give you three of them.
The RFP RFI was clearly written with a competitor
in mind, so they felt that was a very bad signal
that was probably going to go badly. Another one
was the customer didn't want to demo, they only
wanted to talk about price. Obviously, that's
quite bad. And another one was after the first
few meetings, they couldn't get a decision maker
in the room, right? So it was a much longer list
than this, but those are three. So for each of
those, that now becomes a kill criteria if I see
this thing and now you attach an action with it.
So in the case of price, they actually just said,
"We should kill it." If they literally don't
want to demo and they're only asking about price,
they're just trying to beat up somebody else
on price like we're a box-checking exercise.
So there, they just said, "We're going to kill
it. We're not going to pursue the deal anymore."
So this is great because salespeople will pursue
deals forever and leadership is like, "Well,
why did you stop pursuing that deal?" And they
get in trouble for it. So this is going to help
with that problem, right? In the case of the
RFP RFI was written with a competitor in mind,
they have an action associated with that as well,
which is ask them directly if they're working with
a competitor and how far down the road they are,
depending on the answer you would kill or pursue.
In the case of we couldn't get a decision
maker in the room, offer up executive
alignment at the next meeting. And if they
say sure, great. And if they say no, kill.
So that's actually what I feel is the
best use of a pre-mortem is to say,
I'm going to try to figure out what those signals
are along the way that things are going badly. And
now instead of just hoping that when I see
those signals, I actually act rationally,
which is a hope that it will not come true. That's
why there's many people who climb Everest in the
middle of a blizzard, even though they shouldn't
be doing that. Use the pre-mortem to now create
structure around those signals that you've
spotted and commit to actions that you're
going to take if you see those signals. And I
think that's the best use of a pre-mortem.
That's really helpful. And it's interesting how
many of your examples come back to just of a
framework that you often talk about, which is
make it explicit what is implicit. There's another
example that the First Round example is a great
example of that where it's just, here's all our
assumptions, they just make them actually explicit
and just shows how much [inaudible 01:10:32].
Right, then you can examine them. You can
examine them, people can discuss them,
you can figure out if they're wrong or right or
whatever. It's like, I want to be very clear,
I'm not anti your gut or your intuition. I
think it's probably sometimes pretty good. I
just want you to make it explicit, that's all.
Okay. So we didn't have time to get into quitting,
which is your more recent book. Maybe we'll
do a follow-up episode specifically thinking
about quitting, but let me just ask-
It's my fault because my answers are long.
It's my fault.
I apologize to everybody.
No apology is necessary. We'll have plenty of
time in the future, hopefully. Well, let me just
ask one question. I found this one quote from you
where you said you should assume that if you're
thinking about quitting, it's already probably
past the time that you should have quit. Do you
still believe that? Is that generally a good rule
of thumb? And just any takeaway, tip, lesson on
quitting as our one question on quitting?
So the data is pretty strong that by the time
you quit, it's probably long after the [inaudible
01:11:37]. And it's really just because, look,
when we start things, we're starting
things under difficult circumstances,
which come from the uncertainty of the decision
to start something. So when we start something,
luck is going to have an influence on the outcome,
which obviously, we have no control over because
luck isn't in our control. And then there's also
hidden information. So what happens is that after
the fact, we know that we're going to learn new
information and it can make it very hard to start
things because we want to be more sure than we
actually need to be. It's why Bezos has the 70%
role to try to roll people back and be willing to
accept that uncertainty in the starting decision.
Now the good news is that when you learn that new
stuff and the new stuff that you learn is, "Ooh,
if I had known this, I wouldn't have started
it", you have the option to quit generally.
So that's the good news. The bad news is
that the same difficulties that apply to
the decision to start apply to the decision
to stop. In other words, we're making that
decision under uncertainty as well. So we're
not going to know for sure whether it would've
turned out well or poorly unless we continue
to do the thing that we already started. And
we don't like to walk away from things unless
we know for sure. So as Richard Thaler put it,
most people won't quit until it actually isn't
a decision. In other words, the whole thing is
blown up, the startup has no money, or you're up
on Everest and the blizzard is literally upon you
and you're stuck in it. Or I think as he said,
until you've fallen in the crevasse already, then
you'll make the decision to quit because then you
know how it was really bad. So people generally,
for example, don't quit their jobs until they
feel they have no other choice or relationships
or projects or products that they're developing,
it all applies because we want to know for sure.
And then on top of that is the fact that there
is this issue of sunk cost, which is when we walk
away, we feel like we'll have wasted everything
that we've already put into what we're doing. But
of course, waste is a prospective problem, not
a retrospective one, even if we treat it like a
retrospective one because it's the prospective
one. Well, if you wouldn't start this today,
then that means that everything that you're
putting into this going forward is the actual
waste, right? But we do that all the time. We go
forward with things that we ought not to be going
forward with because we're trying to protect the
resources that we've already sunk into it in the
past. Then there's other issues that have to do
with, for example, endowment, the ownership over
the things that we've built. This is particularly
bad in product because we're building things.
And once we build things, we own them. And once
we own them, we don't want to give them up and
we actually value them more highly than identical
things that we don't own. And then there's issues
of internal and external validity, which is
really just a fancy way to say your identity.
How do other people view you? How do you view
yourself? Do you feel like you failed? And what
that means is that by the time, there's so many
biases against stopping that by the time you're
actually even thinking about quitting, it's
probably already past the time that you ought
to have quit. But we'll still continue on
until we know for sure we didn't have any
choice because here's the thing. When you walk
away from something and someone's like, "Hey,
why'd you stop that?" And you're like, "Oh, I had
no choice" and you tell them everything that went
wrong and, nobody's going to question you.
They're going to be like, "Oh, well,
it sounds like you put in your best effort." But
if you walk away early, people are like, "What?"
So just quickly, I'll tell you I think just one
of the best stories of this that I've got in my
pocket here. Let me pull it out before the end.
So Stewart Butterfield creating a product called
Glitch, and Glitch is a massive multiplayer online
world-building cooperative game. Releases it, this
is in the aughts, and it's like a huge hit with
the critics. It's Monty Python meets Dr. Seuss,
it's an incredible whatever. They're getting
tons and tons of great word of mouth and PR not
doing any paid marketing. They have incredible
investors in Andreessen Horowitz and Accel,
they have $6 million in the bank and they
5,000 have diehard users, meaning users who
use the game who play over 20 hours a week.
The issue is that customer acquisition was a
beast that for every one person who was playing
over 20 hours a week, there were between 95 and
99 people who came for five minutes and left. So
obviously, this is a customer acquisition problem,
which everybody knows. So they make an agreement
in 2012 that they're going to do paid marketing,
which they do for six weeks. And during that
six weeks, their acquisition of new users,
it's growing like six to 7% week over week, which
is amazing. And at the end of that six weeks,
this is November of 2012, at the end
of that six weeks, that Monday morning,
Stewart Butterfield writes a note to his investors
and co-founders and says, "I woke up this morning
with the dead certainty that Glitch was over."
Now notice nobody would do this in this case,
right? But this is what happened is that the
issue is that you really have to see is this
worthwhile or not? Would I start this today?
That's a forecast of the future, right? And
what he did was some back-of-the-envelope math,
and he said, "Look, if we continue to acquire
customers at the weight that we've been acquiring
them at the cost that we've been acquiring them,
it's going to be 31 weeks until we break even."
But that's an absurd assumption because customer
acquisition costs, it's going to go up. Cap has
to rise because we're going to saturate the core
gaming market, so it's got to rise. So what he
realized at that point was that this was not
a venture scale business, and he was in this
for a venture scale business. So even though
nobody else saw that he was supposed to shut it
down, he saw he was supposed to shut it down.
And not only that, he saw that he was supposed
to shut it down for his employees who were
working for equity, and he had now realized
that the equity wasn't worth their time and
that it wasn't fair to them to keep going
with it. So he shuts it down. Obviously,
that feels... Who does that? Right? And he will
actually tell you that he knows he should have
shut it down before the marketing push, but he
needed the marketing push to prove it to himself
that he was seeing the future clearly. Now, the
code to this story just quickly is two days later,
he's like, "Well, I'm a startup guy. I want to
start something", and he's got this internal
communication tool that his team is using in
order to develop this product that everybody
loves. And he says, "Actually, they really like
that. Maybe that should be the next product."
So he goes and talks to the investors, they roll
their money over into that. And that thing, which
had no name at the time, now gets a name which
is searchable log of all company knowledge, which
is Slack. And so I think this is the important
thing to realize is that we get so focused on,
"But what about everything that I've put into
it?" When what we forget is that when you're doing
something, there's not just the cost of doing
something that's not worthwhile that's direct,
but there's also the cost of not being able to
devote your attention to other opportunities
that might be available to you. And as smart as
Stewart Butterfield is, he couldn't see Slack
until he quit Glitch. And that is a true cost that
he would've born of continuing with Glitch. If he
had continued with Glitch, Slack would not
be something that we're all using today.
That is an incredibly beautiful way to end
our conversation. I feel like I have at least
a billion more questions to ask you and on the
other hand, I feel like we've also helped a lot
of people make much better decisions through this
chat so I'm really thankful that you made time
for this. Two last questions. Where can folks
find you online if they want to learn about the
stuff you're up to in case they want to work with
you? And how can listeners be useful to you?
You can find me at annieduke.com if you're
interested in working with me. I have a Substack,
Thinking in Bets. Please go check that out.
I teach a class on maven.com twice a year
on effective decision-making. So if you're
interested in that, you can go to Maven and
check it out. My next cohort at the moment is
in September, although I might do one in May.
I'm not sure. But in terms of people can help me,
I co-founded an organization called The Alliance
for Decision Education. We're trying to bring the
kinds of knowledge that we have about improving
human decision-making in adults to K through 12
education to make the world a better place. So
I would love it if people could go look at that.
If you're interested in it, get the word out.
Amazing. So we'll link to all those
things in the show notes. Annie,
again, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you. Thank you so much, this was so fun.
Same. Bye, everyone. Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable,
you can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show
at lennyspodcast.com. See
you in the next episode.