... Duolingo is a $14 billion company,
it's hitting all-time highs too, it just
keeps going up, but I think it doubled in
value in the past six months. Streaks is the
most impactful feature. We have, right now,
over 9 million users with a year plus streak.
If you look at the numbers, I think it's been
our biggest growth lever. What Duolingo really
focuses on is, how do we help users build habits
around language learning? Getting user come back
the next day is the biggest problem to solve.
Let's get into the motherload of
learnings from the journey of streaks,
talk about the key lessons, insights,
and also wrong turns along the way.
I'd say test everything, we've run in the last
four years over 600 experiments on the streaks,
so every other day. We've actually set
up really good infrastructure for copy
testing. We used to say continue,
our standard CTA is continue,
and we changed that to commit to
my goal, and it was a massive win.
There's so much human psychology
that you all learn through all
these experiments of just how to motivate
people, what motivates, what demotivates.
Say that you played a mobile game, or that you've
done it for 3,000 days in a row, I don't know,
maybe that hits a little bit different than
you've learned Spanish for 3,000 days in a row.
Today, my guest is Jackson Shuttleworth.
Jackson is a group product manager at Duolingo,
leading the retention team. This is a different
kind of episode that I'm experimenting with,
where we spent the entire conversation focused
on the journey and lessons of a single feature,
in this case, Duolingo streaks. Duolingo is a $14
billion business, just over the past six months,
they doubled in value, they're hitting
all time highs in usage and market cap,
they're also one of the very few successful and
also the single biggest consumer app business
in the world. And as you'll hear from Jackson,
the streaks feature is the single most impactful
feature that most contributed to this growth and
success. In other words, you could argue this
one feature created billions of dollars of value,
which to me means it is worth studying in depth.
In our conversation, Jackson shares the history
of the streaks feature, all of the biggest wins
and wrong turns they've taken along the way, what
he and his team have learned about what works and
doesn't work with a streaks mechanic, and also
how they set up their teams to operate in a way
that allows them to run over 600 experiments
on this product and continue to find big wins.
I hope to do more episodes like this on features
and products that you'd love to hear more about,
so leave a comment either on YouTube or on
Substack, and tell me which product or feature
you'd love to see me cover. And if you enjoy this
podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow it
in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube, it's
the best way to avoid missing future episodes,
and it helps the podcast tremendously. With
that, I bring you Jackson Shuttleworth.
Jackson, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Yeah, thank you. Long time
listener, first time caller.
I appreciate it. So, this is going to be a really
interesting conversation, I've never done an
episode like this before, where we basically
spent an hour, an hour and a half going into
one feature of one product, but this is a very
special feature, it's a very special product.
Have you ever spent an hour, an hour and a half
just talking about this one feature with anyone?
Well, internally, so when we onboard new
folks to the team, we'll do, I actually
just did this with somebody that joined the team
recently, where we spent, yeah, I was like, hey,
let's spend an hour just talking about the streak.
We got through an hour and I got through about
30% of what I wanted to share, there's just so
much, we'll talk about this, but there's so much
that we've learned over the years, but never
anything externally like this. I think we've
shared bits and pieces of learnings, but this
will be the motherload of learnings hopefully-
Here we go.
... of how Duolingo built the streak.
We should title this the Motherload of Learnings
of Duolingo Streaks. This episode is brought
to you by Pendo, the only all-in-one product
experience platform for any type of application.
Tired of bouncing around multiple tools to
uncover what's really happening inside your
product? With all the tools you need in one
simple-to-use platform, Pendo makes it easy
to answer critical questions about how users are
engaging with your product, and then turn those
insights into action. Also, you can get your users
to do what you actually want them to do. First,
Pendo is built around product analytics, seeing
what your users are actually doing in your apps
so that you can optimize their experience. Next,
Pendo lets you deploy in-app guides that lead
users through the actions that matter most.
Then, Pendo integrates user feedback so that
you can capture and analyze what people actually
want. And the new thing in Pendo, session replays,
a very cool way to visualize user sessions.
I'm not surprised at all that over 10,000
companies use it today. Visit pendo.io/Lenny to
create your free Pendo account today and start
building better experiences across every corner
of your product. P.S. Do you want to take your
product-led know-how a step further? Check out
Pendo's lineup of free certification courses,
led by talk product experts, and designed
to help you grow in advance in your career.
Learn more and experience the power of the
Pendo platform today at pendo.io/Lenny.
Pendo.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta.
When it comes to ensuring your company
has top-notch security practices, things get
complicated fast. Now, you can assess risk,
secure the trust of your customers, and
automate compliance for SOC 2, ISO 27001,
HIPAA, and more, with a single platform, Vanta.
Vanta's market-leading trust management platform
helps you continuously monitor compliance,
alongside reporting and tracking risk. Plus,
you can save hours by security questionnaires
with Vanta AI. Join thousands of global companies
that use Vanta to automate evidence collection,
unify risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go to
vanta.com/Lenny. That's V-A-N-T-A.com/Lenny.
Okay, so for people that don't know anything about
what Duolingo streaks are, can you just first give
a brief explanation of what is Duolingo
streaks? What is this feature all about?
Well, presumably people know, Duolingo is a
language learning app, the Duolingo streak
tracks, currently anyway, how many days in a row
you've done a lesson. So, you come to Duolingo,
you do a lesson, your first lesson you'll
start a streak, and then every consecutive day
that you come use the app, you'll extend your
streak. And I should actually put an asterisk
around how many days in a row because we also
have built flexibility into the feature. So,
we have these things called streak freezes,
it's like insurance for your streaks. So, it's
a pretty simple feature, in theory, but over time
we've layered on challenges, and goal setting,
and rewards, and social features... A lot of
our notifications are tied to the streak. So,
pretty simple feature to understand, but it's been
a really rich feature for us to build on top of.
Some people might be hearing this and be like,
Duolingo streaks, what's the big deal? There's
other people that are like, holy, I want to
learn everything I can possibly learn about
Duolingo streaks, so many companies are trying to
copy what you've learned from this. Give people a
sense of the impact that this one feature
has had on Duolingo's success and growth.
And this is not just the subjective retention
PM talking, I think this is our biggest feature,
with the exception of the lessons. And I think
it's actually [inaudible 00:07:24] start that.
Streaks are a great engagement hack. I'm of the
opinion that any team, any app out there can
introduce a streak, and if you figure it out, it
probably works to retain users, but at the core,
you have to have an app that people want to use,
and people really like using Duolingo. It's fun,
it's delightful, you learn something. And so,
it allows us to layer an engagement mechanic on
top of that the streak is really powerful.
So, it ships a disgusting amount of DAUs,
again, it is one of our golden geese. And again,
what's cool is that, you look at notifications,
notifications for Duolingo is massive. Us sending
better, whether it's copy or timing, so many of
our notifications work because they reference
the streak, because users care about the streak.
And so, not only is it itself, us iterating on
the streak a huge driver of DAUs, but it's also
something that enables other really high valuable
features. I was looking up some stats before I
came on, and it's pretty crazy. So, we have right
now over 9 million users with a year plus streak.
Wow.
So, 9 million of our users have used
Duolingo every year, almost every day,
for well over a year. Which is pretty... I don't
know, I like to imagine things in terms of like,
okay, well, if you put all these
people in a city, or in a place,
where would it be? I'm like, ah, it's
like a very large city, 9 million people.
For a year, have a year long streak.
For a year.
That's incredible. I was just looking at the stock
of Duolingo, so Duolingo is a $14 billion company
at the time we're recording this. It's hitting
all-time highs too, it just keeps going up. I
think it doubled in value in the past six months,
something like that. And what I'm hearing from you
is streaks is, other than just the core learning
feature, which is just the product of Duolingo,
this is the most feature in terms of
growth, and in that retention specifically.
If you look at the numbers, I think pretty
objectively has been our biggest growth lever
for driving DAUs, and also say a lot of it's
just related to how we think about growth at
Duolingo. And a lot of what we try to do is
organic growth. We think about growth just as
much as bringing new users onto the platform
is not losing them. If you're just bringing
people onto the platform, then they churn,
that's not going to be sustainable. And so,
as much as we can do to keep our users
coming back and actually retaining as users,
it's going to give us a much easier
base to continue growing DAUs off of.
Perfect. Okay. Talk about how this feature
originally came to be. What was the original
version of it? What was the original
insight that led to [inaudible 00:10:05]-
Yeah, so the oldest streaks or as old as
Duolingo itself. When we launched Duolingo,
we launched with a streak... And I say we, I was
just graduating undergrad when Duolingo launched.
So, this is well before my time. But we launched
with a streak feature. Initially how the feature
worked was you'd come to Duolingo and you'd set
a goal for yourself, and it was an XP based goal.
So, Duolingo, a little bit of nomenclature,
we have an experience point based system that
drives a lot of our features in the app.
And the way you'd set it is you'd say,
based on what your language learning goal was,
maybe you have a 10 experience point goal versus
a 50 experience point goal. And so, extending your
streak would be, hey, can you hit 50 experience
points? If that's what you set your goal to be.
And this worked well, I think this also speaks to
how Duolingo initially grew. Luis launched it with
a TEDTalk, we probably had a more tech-forward
user base initially, and so this whole idea of an
experience points based streak system made sense.
But what that also meant is that you could have
a user come and use the app, do multiple lessons
a day, and maybe they just set too hard of a goal
for themselves, and then lose their streak. Which,
you don't need to be an expert in streaks to
understand that's probably not good. The nice
thing with how we initially set it up though is
it really did connect with what your goal was. So,
if you were serious, let's track how good
you are at being a serious language learner.
But I'd say one of the most impactful experiments
we ran was about, this was actually as I was
joining, or just after I joined we had run this
experiment, was to move it from a XP based streak
to just do one lesson a day, and you'd extend your
streak. And the risk that you can sort of imagine
is, well, then users kind of care less about
it because it's not connected with their goal.
And we saw none of that. This was a huge driver of
DAUs, just making it easier to extend your streak,
but I think really importantly it's still
meaningful. The unit of use, and as you're
thinking about building a streak, I think it's
really important to think about what the unit of
use of your app is. The unit of use for Duolingo
is doing a lesson. And so, if what we care about
is users coming back every day and doing a lesson,
because it shows that they're actually engaging
with the app, then it doesn't hurt us to make our
streak focus on just do one unit versus multiple.
And so, that was probably the big [inaudible
00:12:25] change experiment that we ran at
the time was moving from an XP-based streak
to a one lesson streak. It's also simple,
and I think that's one of the things to think
about with streaks. It's always easy as a PM to
have a million goals or objectives for what you
want your feature to be and potentially build a
more complex feature, and a one lesson streak,
it's just easy for more users to understand.
Yeah, that's exactly what I was going to say. And
just for folks that aren't super familiar with XP,
it's basically experience points
and you get them from doing things,
it's like a [inaudible 00:12:53]-
Yeah, you do stuff on Duolingo, and then
based on what you did and how well you did it,
we give you experience points, this actually
drives a number of our features in our apps. So,
leaderboards is the big one, we have a leaderboard
system, where you try over the course of the week,
you battle with 29 other people, and you
want to win, that's all driven by XP. So,
we do have other features in the app
that really benefit from this XP system-
Cool.
... the streak is just no longer one of them.
Awesome. Okay, so I want to talk about the
journey from that point to what it is today,
but a quick tangent, I saw Luis tweet just this
week, someone asked him, "How do you decide
whether to optimize for learning or engagement?"
And he's like, "No question, everything we do is
focused on engagement because you won't learn
anything if you're not coming back to the app."
As an engagement PM, that was the coolest
thing he could have ever said. It's, well,
again, very much as subjectively I guess as an
engagement PM, that's how I've... I am sure the
learning folks at Duolingo will cringe when they
hear it, I see myself as a learning PM as much
as an engagement PM, because the easiest way not
to learn on Duolingo is not to come back the next
day. And so, if we don't make the app retentive,
you will have no opportunity to engage with our
learning features. Now, I do think that there is
a long tail of learning, where, if you start to
dumb down, and honestly this is something we
wrestle with the streak as well, you start to
dumb down the experience, and your users aren't
actually learning, they're not going to care.
Streaks work best when they're sitting on top
of an app that users care about. But yeah,
if you don't come learn on Duolingo.... If you
don't come back to Duolingo, then you're not
learning. We track a lot of this with, the work
that we do, we make sure that as we're making
changes to the streak, we're not hurting the
learning experience and we don't have a ton of
interaction with it. So, we're constantly thinking
about this, but thank you Luis for saying that.
It makes sense to me. Okay, so lets get
into the motherload of learnings from
the journey of streaks. So, the first
version went from XP to one lesson,
talk about the key lessons, insights, and also
wrong turns along the way to what we see today.
Duolingo has very much, has a strong test
it philosophy, we're willing to test a lot
of different... Honestly, we'd much rather
test it than debate it for days and days. So,
we actually followed up this experiment with, and
this is a little bit later, with hey, what if we
make it even easier to extend your streak? And so,
we actually tested, hey, if you do one exercise,
just one exercise in a lesson will extend
your streak. A lot of the insight was good,
you look at the funnel, hey, there's a lot of
users who are starting but not finishing lessons,
they're not extending your streak, the loss
aversion doesn't kick in, they don't come
back... So, this followed that train of thought.
What we realized when we ran this experiment is
DAUs moved not one bit. And what we were doing
by... And if we go back to unit of measure,
we had dumbed down the unit of... Nobody
thinks about, oh, I just want to come do one
question on Duolingo, nobody thinks about that.
So, we had a less clear unit of measure that
we were basing our streak around, and the users
that we were capturing with our streak, you come,
you do one or two questions on Duolingo, then you
leave, were the least engaged users imaginable.
And so, I think that's something also to think
about as you're building your streak, is like
what is the user that you're solving for? So, not
only what is the habit that you're building for,
but what is the level of commitment, and that
was an example where we over indexed on a type
of user who we honestly just weren't going to
keep, that was a very easy shutdown decision.
That's an awesome story, just to comment in that
real quick. Just you went, let's just go to the
extreme and make it just like streaks, yeah, get
everyone going streaks forever, and then... I love
that it turned out and it's not bringing users
that you want, and it's dumbing down experience.
It makes me think of Farmville, where you have to
go and harvest your crops every, whatever, hour,
that lasts for a bit and then eventually people
are like, what the hell am I doing with my life?
Yeah, exactly. We test every, I was looking at the
numbers as well, we've run in the last four years,
over 600 experiments on the streaks.
So, every other day effectively-
600, wow.
... we're running an experiment. And they range
from big, like this, changing how the mechanic
works, to let's swap a string with another string
and see if that copy is better for users. So,
we're constantly testing on everything. I do think
that, I'd be more careful running that experiment
now, at some point your streak gets big enough
that, again, I got 9 million users on the streak,
I got to be really careful... Those are our best
retaining users, you got to be careful. But in the
early days of the streak, I'd say test everything.
See what... Don't get super caught up in it has
to be like this, just test a bunch of stuff and
see what speaks most to users. Because I think,
again, you will constantly be surprised by the
insights that you get from whether you... We
shut down about half of our experiments,
so half of our experiments lose,
we still learned a ton by virtue of
running them. So, super, super valuable.
That's actually a good success rate, a lot
of companies have only 20% of experiments
be positive. What's your policy on if it's
neutral, do you ship it, or do you kill it?
It really depends. If we're adding something and
it's neutral, we tend to shut it down because it's
just more cognitive load, it's something that
we're going to have to start building around,
a new UI element that we have to figure out
how it fits into our system. I'd say when we
do ship a neutral experiment is, something
that we have real conviction around, okay,
yeah, maybe this was neutral but it's going to
give us a new platform to then build on top of,
so that experience might be neutral,
but now we can build these DAU positive
experiments. My general take
there is though, in that case,
build that in as part of your V1 so that
you make sure that at least your hypothesis
around this roadmap has play should probably
be the case, but in general, shutting down a
neutral experiment so you don't introduce more
complexity to the app is the way we tend to go.
Makes sense. All right, what else? What
else have you learned along the journey?
Well, maybe I can talk about a few different ways
that we structure, a few different themes that
I think we lean on. So, the first is focusing
on the zero to seven day user experience. And
I would say this is, if you look at whatever our
breakdown of experiments are, we run definitely
more than average number of experiments on getting
users to go from a zero to seven day streak. And a
lot of this is because we've looked at the data
for our retention curves, and what we found is
that once you get to seven days, loss aversion
kicks in, and you retain. So, going from a one
to a two-day streak, huge jump in retention,
two to three day streak, slightly less but
still huge and it's up until day seven. Once you
hit day seven, it flans out. And it's not to say
that if you have a 30-day streak, you're way more
attentive than day seven, but not in the order of
magnitude that it is from day one through seven.
So, we do a ton of work to get users to that
point where loss aversion kicks in, and then
they don't want to lead the app. One of the
fun ones that we did, and it's honestly as much
about process as it is about the feature itself,
was we have a feature called streak goal,
and it is... Again, so much of this stuff
seems so obvious in retrospect, but it was really
novel at the time. We had this idea of like, hey,
maybe we'll just goal users to hitting a certain
streak length. As you can imagine, this is pretty
powerful user psychology, and we started with the
simplest version of this. And this is how Duolingo
does a lot of our testing. Rather than design the
big complex feature for V1, just do the simplest
encapsulation of what that feature can be, see if
it has legs, and then just add to it iteratively
over time, this is partially how we get to 600+
experiments on streaks, they're not all big ones.
But we started... And it was funny, we actually
took a learning from our monetization win teams.
One of the strings that they had, the pieces
of copy that they had, worked really, really
well was, I think it was your 5.6 x more likely to
finish the course if you subscribe to Plus. Now,
it's Super, our subscription. It was a really good
hook that if you really cared, you'd sign up. And
so, we had a similar thought, where it's like, oh,
let's just tell you how much more likely you are
to finish the course if you get a 30-day streak.
And so, we started with that, and I think it was
like you're seven times more likely to finish the
course if you have a 30-day streak, and just that
message when you started your streak, I telling
you that, was awesome. Huge win. Indicating an
outcome... And Duolingo doesn't have, we have
a gem economy but we don't actually have,
it's all you learning. But being able to actually
talk about it in terms of the outcomes that a user
would think about, in this case, trying to finish
the course, was a huge win. So, this is where
we started and we're like, ah, goal setting,
all right, we should go much harder on this.
Found a-
Yeah, we found our thing, and now let's just beat
the heck out of it. So, we followed that up with
another experiment, where we tested different
lengths. So, we test 14 days and 50 days,
and we found that they were all good, but they
appealed to different users. And so, we started
to realize, all right, well, we probably need
to be more thoughtful about who we give these
different options to. And so, then we followed
that experiment up with, all right, let's start
with 30 days, and then we're going to let you
opt out, we'll say, no, I don't think I can hit
it. And our thinking was, and then if you say no,
we'll hit you with an easier goal. Because we just
wanted to get you to commit to a goal. And this
was a fascinating one because it was a good win
to give users that easier goal, to try to capture
them before they said no, but it was almost
just as big a win to add that opt out button.
So, we tested separately, and I'm a huge fan of
testing way too many arms for an experiment,
just to be able to isolate your hypotheses,
but we captured just what happens if we add an
opt-out button, and adding an opt-out button...
And you would think, as a PM, oh, now users might
not engage with my feature, that's a bad thing,
but it was a huge win to let them do that. And
the learning here was that this intentionality
of saying, no, I want it... Previously it was
just a continue button, but now it's like,
no, I want to hit 30 days, and having that be
an intentional decision for them, yes or no,
even though again, this had no impact, or no
impact past this screen. Everything that I'm
talking about now was just that screen that
day, and then was all thrown out. So, that
optionality was a huge insight, and so because
of that, we built a goal setting feature where
you could choose between different goals, giving
users that optionality was likewise a huge win.
I'll say one final learning on this, again, you
talk about friction, and good and bad friction,
we thought once we built a goal picker screen,
where you could pick between different streak
lengths, we were like, oh, well, let's recommend
that users do a harder goal, thinking that okay,
well, a harder goal is going to be better
retention, and we'll the preselect harder
goal for them. And based on all the learnings
that I just shared with you, you probably imagine
lost pretty significantly, we realized that
yes, we could speed users through the screen
more by virtue of picking a goal for them, but
that act of selecting, I think it's 30 days,
I think it's 14 days, was where we were getting
so much of the engagement from this feature.
There's so much human psychology
that you all learn through all
these experiments of just how to
motivate people, what motivates,
what demotivates, it feels like you guys should
write a book on human psychology and motivation.
I feel very much like a amateur armchair
psychologist with everything that, at least
as far as people who want to learn languages on
their phone go, I really understand those folks.
Right. So, one theme I'm hearing here so far
is you guys are basically just mining for gold,
just looking for a vein in some mine, and once
you hit it you're like, ooh, this worked, you just
go crazy on just testing all kinds of things to
see how far you can take that one little thread.
Yeah, and I think, I shared how this idea came
partially from a monetization win that they had,
I think there's a lot of, because Duolingo
runs... I don't know what percentile we're in,
but it's got to be a very high percentile
of per capita experiments run for a company,
based on company size. We're just constantly
learning so many things and there's a really great
cross-sharing of monetization say, hey, this thing
worked for us, is that something you can use? So,
I'd say it's rare that we go into something
where it's just like, let's just try something.
Typically, we have some insight because of all of
these experiments that we've run, that hey, if we
do this, I don't know, it's one here, or it's
worked here, it's driven this user engagement,
if we massage that and try in this scenario,
or a different screen, we come in at least
with a strong hypothesis of this will work.
A lot of times we do look, and we're like,
a lot of the apps that we look at actually
are games themselves, so it's like, all right,
you're playing Royal Match, or there's the new
Pokemon trading card game that I'm spending
way too much time on, you look at
these games and see what they're doing,
and it's really good fodder for what
we can do. But a lot of times you're
at least going in with a strong hypothesis
based on what you've seen work elsewhere.
Got it. So, just to double down on that
point, it's not just random experiments,
it's here's a hypothesis we're fairly confident,
or has a chance to be true, let's try it.
It's not just let's just try everything?
Yeah. And I think that how strongly
you feel about the hypothesis directly
ties to how hard that experiment is. With
copy, for instance, we've actually set up
really good infrastructure for copy testing.
I'm of the opinion that companies should run,
as long as you have the user base to do
it, copy test constantly. The amount of
copy tests that we've had that have won, and I
don't know, you just try things and you figure
out what wins is definitely legion, and [inaudible
00:27:15] massive wins from little copy changes.
Is there an example of that, of just the impact?
Going back to that goal screen, we used to
say Continue, our standard CTA is Continue,
and we changed that to Commit To My Goal, and
it was a massive win. And again, it was like,
okay, users tapping on that, what are we
asking them to do? Commit to the goal,
what is that going to lead them to do? Commit,
not churn. Just that little copy change, that
one time, right there, led to huge wins. And copy
changes are so cheap, it's just you translate,
for us, we have a lot of users all over
the world, and a lot of UI languages,
but just come up with a bunch of ideas,
translate some strings... This is one where
the feedback that you'll typically get from
Luis. So, all of our changes at Duolingo go
through product review that are reviewed by
Luis, so Luis reviews every single change
that we propose, every experiment that we run.
Typically with copy, he's just like, I don't know,
test it, there's nothing better than be told
by Luis, I don't think this is going to win,
but sure, if you want to. And a lot of times, to
his credit, he's right, and a lot of times our
intuition was right, but it's just so cheap
to do it. I think when the lift is smaller,
it's great to have a hypothesis, but
you don't need to beat it up too much.
So, on this thread, I didn't realize Louis
reviews everything you're planning to change,
and this may be the answer to the question I was
going to ask, which is, one of the criticisms of
running a product and company this way, of
just experimenting constantly with all these
micro improvements and changes, is it can
lead to something, like a monstrosity of a
product and experience that isn't consistent
and cohesive, and just that often happens.
Is the solution to that having the founder
basically review all the changes? Is there
anything else y'all do to avoid it becoming
Farmville or whatever, is a good example of that?
Yeah, our product review structure where we've
got our head of product design, one of the lead,
the product management leaders, and then
Luis, NPR. And because they see everything,
and they have a really high product bar, and
so that helps. I think over time we just,
as PMs, have to look at, okay, where is our
feature headed? And so, we do this with the
streak at least on a quarterly basis, to look
at, okay, well, what have we learned, how has
our streak developed, and how do we imagine
this going in near future? It's easy to do,
and in some sort of awful local maxima,
if you're not constantly looking at your
roadmap and you don't have a clear strategy. For
me it's like, if you have a clear strategy where
your feature is going, hopefully all of those A/B
tests are not just done to get some cheap gain,
they're done with a long-term goal in mind.
I do think though, and we do this every now
and then with the streak, eventually you just
hit a local maxima, and you say, you talked
about launching neutral experiments, this is a
great example, where it's like all right, cool,
now we need to throw a bunch of this stuff out,
based on all the learnings, can we reset this
real estate, can we reset this UI, reset this
feature, in such a way that is just as good as
what we have now but is way more plain or simple,
that we can, again, start to layer on? Those are
really hard experiments to get to win obviously,
because they are so optimized, but they're really
important to do, otherwise, yeah, you just
end up with a kitchen sink of a feature.
One other tidbit I just want to mention,
an advantage you all have that other companies
don't have is people want to learn a language,
and so getting pushed to come back to an
app for something that they want to do,
it's not an advantage a lot of products
have. So, anything you want to add there,
of just like this is why Duolingo might be a
little different from what you're working on.
That is definitely a benefit, if I had an app...
And that this is actually why I think a lot of
mobile games do streaks differently, because to
say that you played a mobile game, and as somebody
who plays a lot of mobile games, that you've
done it for 3000 days in a row, I don't know,
maybe that hits a little bit different than you've
learned Spanish for 3000 days in a row. I think
the comparison set is much larger though, than
a lot of companies give themselves credit for,
and I think that there's... There's a lot of
ways that companies think about their... There
are very few companies I imagine out there in
the world saying, oh, we don't do some degree of
good for our users... Even if it's like a game,
it's like, I don't know, you're giving somebody
a moment away from the craziness of their lives.
And so, I do think though that is contingent on
companies who are going to figure out if a streak
works for them, to figure out how can you frame
the streak in such a way that a user does feel
good about it. And it's easier for a Duolingo,
but I think there's creative ways to phrase
this for users. The other thing maybe just on
that that I'll say is, the streak works really
well for Duolingo because with language learning
it's really hard to see day-to-day progress in
becoming more fluent. And fluency is not even
the right word, it's like becoming better
at Spanish or whatever, it is a years long
process for someone to get better at a language.
Duolingo makes it easier, but you still got to put
in thousands of hours if you're going to reach C1
or C2 fluency, and that is really hard to track on
a day-to-day, and so the streak works really well
for us because we might not be able to tell you,
hey, you now know 0.01% more Spanish, but we
can show you, hey, you've gotten your streak
a little bit higher. And so, I think this works
particularly well when you're an app that is
doing something that's going to be sensed or
felt over a longer term to help contextualize
that progress in a way that makes more sense,
or at least feels more tangible to a user.
Great, that was a great context. Empowering
to a lot of companies that aren't necessarily
doing language learning. Okay. So, it
took us on a long tangent away from
lessons and experiments you ran along the
journey of iterating on the streak. So,
a few things you've shared so far is
just, it started with this XP idea,
and then went to a lesson, then you iterated
on ways to make it simpler, maybe harder,
you added streak goals, where you commit to
I'm going to hit a certain goal of streak.
What else? What else have you found that
has worked, didn't work, lessons learned?
Again, sticking with this one to seven
day streak, the idea of a streak,
particularly probably to this audience,
is obvious. Like, oh, it's a streak,
it just counts how many days. We've realized over
time that a lot of users do not understand how a
streak works, and it can be as small as, well,
I don't understand how streak freezes work,
or I don't... Like my mom the other day
was talking to you about it, she's like,
"Oh, I didn't use Duolingo and I come back and
my streak's still there." So, there's certain
elements of the feature that we can do better
at explaining, but even what a streak is, it's
tracking how many days that I've used the app,
yeah, the more that we can make the feature easily
comprehensible to users, the more retentive it is.
And we've run a number of experiments to do this.
You asked about early easy copy changes that we
made. Actually, this is my first win experiment
when I joined Duolingo was, when you start
a streak, we have little copy at the bottom
of the screen that just, I don't know, it's like
flavor copy, we use it to celebrate you, or give
you context, and I ran some tests that just tried
to in eight words explained what a streak was,
that was it. And it was a massive win because
it really dumbed down here is exactly how the
streak worked, and it really helped users just
understand what they needed to do. And I think
this is something that's like, you constantly got
to remind yourself, particularly if you work in
tech and you're building cool tech features, but
your user base is not a bunch of tech workers,
to think about, all right, who is my audience?
And for us it's not just tech workers, it's not
people in America, it's people all over the world
of all ages of all cultures, and so making sure
that your feature is even something as simple
as the streak is understandable is critical.
What was the actual copy, do you remember?
It was... I think it's still on
the app, it's like, "Start a day
to extend your streak, but miss a day
and it resets," something like that.
That makes sense to me. Very clear.
Yeah.
In eight words, I love that. Okay. And then,
when you say massive win by the way, just to
give people a reference point, what does that
look like? What is a massive win in this scale?
Well, and it's funny, and this was four years ago,
but I think it was in the order of magnitude of
over 10,000 DAUs for us, and actually, maybe
a small bit of context. So, Duolingo really
cares about the metric CURR current user
retention rate, and actually our first ever
Duolingo post with Lenny was the newsletter
that our former head of product wrote, Jorge.
Still the single most popular newsletter post
of all time in my newsletter, across 300 plus-
I would highly recommend that if you were
interested in this, give it a read. To summarize,
basically, what we found is that, if we
wanted to drive DAUs, and Duolingo cares,
our growth North Star is DAUs, the metric that
is most effective, where a percentage change
in that metric is most effective at driving
DAUs is current user retention rate. And this
is just users who are not new or resurrected,
getting them to come back tomorrow. And so,
most of the work that our teams do, our
retention-based teams do is focused on CURR.
And so, the retention team that I lead focused on
CURR, it just so happens the streak is the best
feature at driving CURR. And so, this experiment
was the biggest CURR win that we had had, and it
was like a top three CURR win, anyway for us.
Just this little copy. And that's why I say,
test copy 1000 different ways, sometimes
it's not the big beautiful feature that's
going to drive the huge gains, sometimes
it's just something simple as a few words.
I love this. Okay, so you said 10,000
DAUs, I think that references you guys
measure incremental impact and
absolute numbers of new daily
users you're going to drive attributed to
that experiment, is what it sounds like.
Yeah, and we do both. We'll also look at,
a lot of times I'll look at, for retention,
day one versus day seven versus day 14, a lot
of what I'm looking for is for us to have a
better day 14 impact than better day one impact
because it means that users are retaining better
over time. This is particularly for users
that would see a feature multiple times. I
just like absolute DAU numbers because as long as
you're controlling for different biases, like a
recency bias or a novelty bias, it's a really
easy way to just have an absolute comparison.
You start to look at percentage changes and
then it's influenced by who your treatment,
how many users saw the experiment, but at least
an absolute number is easier, in my mind, to
start comparing.. Again, there are pitfalls with
it, but we find that that's a pretty useful way.
That lesson comes up a lot on this
podcast, and that approach to experiment.
[inaudible 00:38:25].
So, yeah, you're in good company. Quick tangent,
if there's not an answer to this, no problem,
coming back to the idea of just experimenting
like crazy and not creating a product that nobody
wants to use anymore, is there an example of an
experiment that was positive that you all decided,
no, we don't actually think this is what we
want in the product, they ended up not shipping?
Retention doesn't only work on the streak,
although you would think... Most of our work
is the streak. We've touched a lot of different
surfaces over the years and there was one
experiment that we launched that, we talked about
XP earlier, in the lesson, the only UI elements
are a progress bar at the top, and then how many
hearts you have. So, we keep it really simple,
and this very much speaks to the design philosophy
of Duolingo, which is simpler UI is better, and we
decided, hey, let's add XP in there. And so let's
show your XP ticking up as you're going through a
lesson, that's going to make the user feel good,
it's going to show you what you've earned, you're
going to be less likely to quit, all of these good
reasons to do it. And then you finish the lesson
and then we'll show you've collected all this XP.
And it won, the hypothesis was a good one. But we
realized, and I remember having this conversation
with Luis, is like, cool, this is our most
important screen in the app, it is our lesson,
it is where users learn, and the focus here is
on learning. And now you've added this other thing
up there that could be distracting for users. And
I think the question, we talked about roadmaps and
strategy here, the question that he had for me,
and I didn't have a good answer for at the time,
was like, so what else are you going to do with
this? What's your iteration ideas? Where's
this going to go? Is this going to make the
lesson experience more gamified? And what we
realized is that, honestly, it was just an
easy engagement win idea, but we had touched
our most sacred space in the app to do that.
And so, that was a case where it's like, yeah, it
was a nice win, but we'd added that UI element,
and at least at the time it was less clear what
we would do with it and we realized that long
term it was just going to get in the way, and
we'd rather, for simplicity's sake, pause that,
shut it down, and keep the lesson to be a little
bit of learning sanctuary it was. Now, it's funny,
nowadays I think we actually have enough XP
based mechanics and fun things that we can do,
that I think actually a lot of the beliefs
about the in-lesson experience have changed,
such as something like that could work, but at
the time didn't feel good to keep that around.
That is an awesome example. Hopefully we have
time to talk about how the team operates,
where my mind goes is like, oh, but you have all
these PMs and teams that want to show impact,
and the performance reviews, and all that
stuff, and you're not shipping something,
they're like, oh look, we did a win.
So, I want to chat about that later,
but let's keep going on things you've learned
and things that didn't work along the journey.
The other thing that I'll call out with the
streak, it's like we have the... The image
of the streak is this flame. And we have the
streak flame, and it's very much core to our
iconography. It's important to acknowledge that
that's a metaphor for a retention mechanic. The
idea of keeping a flame lit. And again, I think
we've established the flame is for a lot of users
as sort of their understanding of a streak,
which is great, but there's a lot of people in
different cultural context and different stages
of life, where the idea of keeping a flame lit
to show your commitment to something makes less
sense. We did some UXR in India many years ago,
and this was something that just did not resonate
at all there, which was a really interesting
learning. And that's something it's like,
again, depending upon what your user base is,
the more global UXR you can do to understand
how users are actually understanding and
experience your feature, the better, because
you just, again, encounter insights like this.
And so, even our screen design, we used to have
a flame, it was mostly this flame that would
light up every day. But again, it was like
an indication of a metaphor for a mechanic,
and when we redesigned it, we did
this, Kurt, one of our animators,
did this awesome odometer animation where it's
like your number would tick every day... It
looked good, but from a product perspective, what
was cool is we actually focused the design on the
screen to show your number going up, and then it
would say seven day streak, eight day streak. And
I think that as you're thinking about designing
around a streak, don't get too caught up into
what is this the beautiful story that you're
trying to tell, at the expense of it being a
really comprehensible feature. And so,
as you're thinking about product design,
making that product design a clear distillation
of this is what we're actually tracking,
form should follow a function here, was a learning
for us. And you'll see that now in a lot of places
where we're showing streak, we're really leading
with the number, not necessarily the flame.
That's a theme that I'm hearing again and
again is clarity, don't obsess with making
it too clever, and don't ever think
it, just clarity has a big impact.
Clarity also doesn't have to come at the expense
of delight. And this is something where you hit a
milestone and Duo gets, it becomes, we call him a
Phoenix Duo, and he becomes awesome, and lights on
fire, and I think there are things that you can
do to still make the experience really exciting
and delightful and celebratory, and I would not
lose that, but just don't do it at the expense...
And I think it's also about figuring out, you
can get away with doing more of this for users
who are deeper into their streak experience than
users who are starting, where it's like your
goal for the one-day streak user is just to make
sure, do they understand how this feature works?
Even something... Again, just another random
experiment. At the bottom of the streak screen
we have a calendar, and over the years it
just looks more and more calendar-like,
and that is simply because we find that
the more we make it look like a calendar,
days on top, little circles, the check...
The more we make it look like calendar,
the more that people realize, hey,
this is a daily mechanic. And so,
think about the screen holistically, but every
single thing that you're doing on the screen,
how can you use it to communicate what is
the point of this feature? How does it work?
This episode is brought to you by Coda. I use
Coda every day to coordinate my podcasting and
newsletter workflows. From collecting
questions for guests to storing all my
research to managing my newsletter content
calendar, Coda is my go-to app and has been
for years. Coda combines the best of documents,
spreadsheets, and apps to help me get more done,
and Coda can help your team to stay aligned and
ship faster by managing your planning cycle in
just one location, set and measure OKRs with
full visibility across teams and stakeholders,
map dependencies, create progress
visualizations, and identify risk areas.
You can also access hundreds of pressure-tested
templates for everything from roadmap strategy
to final decision-making frameworks. See for
yourself why companies like DoorDash, Figma,
and Qualtrics run on Coda. Take advantage of this
special limited-time offer just for startups,
head over to coda.io/Lenny and sign
up to get six free months of the team
plan. That's coda.io/Lenny to sign up and get
six months of the team plan. Coda.io/Lenny.
I imagine one of the biggest wins was just
giving people flexibility along the journey,
like streak freezes and all these things,
is that a big vein of opportunity discovery?
It is. Actually, I'm going to show you one of
the most thoughtful gifts that anybody has ever
given to me, this is our Duolingo Serenity, or
Streak Serenity Prayer, my co-lead, Antonia-
It's like knitted, right?
... [inaudible 00:46:05]
this for me. It's amazing.
Wow.
And so it says, "Luis, grant me the
serenity to accept the flexibility I need,
the courage to reach perfection when I can,
and the wisdom to celebrate regardless."
Aw.
And that actually is kind of
our strategy with the streaks.
I love the show and tell
by the way, that was great.
Yeah. Well, I guess for podcast listeners,
we'll have to get an image somewhere. This
idea of flexibility versus perfection, and then
regardless, celebration, is core to how we think
about the streak. Because I think for the streak
for us, it's very much a bend not break. If you're
going to miss a day, I'd rather you come back,
having missed that day, to an intact streak, but
if you don't have to miss a day, I'd much rather
you don't, I'd much rather you come back and use
the app every day. So, that thing on flexibility
though, that's almost certainly been the biggest,
from a mechanic perspective, the biggest DAU
driver. One of the earliest experiments we ran
was going from you used to only be able to have
one streak freeze and then we let you have either
two or three. So, we tested two different
arms. It was, again, another huge DAU win.
This actually is funny, it was something that...
And this is, again, a callback to that growth
model post from Jorge. It actually was really bad
for CURR because we were basically saying, hey,
you can take a day off, and that's
okay, but it was really good for,
this is going to be like Alphabet Soup, [inaudible
00:47:31], a weekly active user return rate. So,
basically, users who had taken a day off, we were
getting them to come back more at higher rates,
and so it made up for our losses in CURR.
But effectively, what this meant is that,
why two streak freezes work better than one was,
I don't know, sometimes people just need a little
bit more flexibility than one day. But again,
the really interesting insight of this experiment
was that three streak freezes was actually no
better than two streak freezes. And there were
two competing things here, and I think this is
important if you're going to build a streak to
figure out what your flexibility mechanic is.
We were getting more users to return after
longer times away to an intact streak. But if
you start taking three days off from any habit,
it's just going to be less likely that
you return even four days later. And so,
we had these competing things where more users
might be returning to a streak, but a lot of users
were also just not coming back, we were training
them to take more time off. So, that flexibility,
what's the right amount of... We've again, this is
another area we've run hundreds of experiments on,
what is the right amount of flexibility?
And we are constantly surprised here. I
still don't have the answer for at every point
in your streak journey how much flexibility you
need. One thing that I can say with certainty
though is, give more flexibility when a user is
starting their streak. Again, one of our biggest
streak freeze experiment wins... I feel like I'm
constantly saying this, one of our biggest
wins, but they all were really, really big.
One of our biggest streak freeze wins was when
you start a new streak, we give you two streak
freezes. And again, it's so funny to think back,
it's like how are we not doing this to begin with?
But at the time, the streak freeze was an overly
gamified mechanic, you had to buy them with gems,
that's our in-app currency, because we wanted
the whole idea of this to feel like it was really
something you earned, that there was a little bit
of pain to getting that streak freeze. And so,
we tested though, what if we just give
users when they start off their streak
two streak freezes, and holy smokes to that win.
And it's sort of obvious now, in retrospect, but
if you have a one or a two or a three-day streak,
it's really easy just to let it die and restart,
again, you need to get to seven days, what we've
seen in the data, for it to really lock in. And
so, giving users more flexibility so that it's
harder to lose their streak initially, and then
conversely, and this is what we keep learning,
eventually, once people get on long streaks,
you don't want to give them as much flexibility.
Because there's a lot of times where, yeah, users
don't... And I'm like this, I've got a 400-day
streak. Note that that is a lot less time than
I've been at Duolingo, I have lost and restarted
streaks a lot of times at my time at Duolingo.
But you start getting on long streaks, and you
really care about this feature, you really care
about your streak. And most people, as long as
you're not backpacking through, I don't know,
the back country of Utah, you'll be in a place
where you can get service. And so, figuring out
who is the user that actually could use Duolingo,
and not conditioning them to start taking days off
that they didn't otherwise need to do is important
to figure out where that line is for your feature.
This is fascinating. You can also buy a streak,
right? With money. That's a feature, right?
Yeah. And it's funny, this is also
something that we [inaudible 00:50:54]-
You can buy a freeze, sorry, not a streak.
Yeah. So, you can buy a streak freeze,
and the way it works is you can buy gems,
and then you can use those gems to buy a
streak... And this is something we wrestle
with. We're actively working on an experiment,
right now that's having a small hit to revenue,
but it's a really nice win for retention,
and I think it's actually worth thinking
about from day one, as you're building a streak,
do you see this more as a monetization feature,
or do you see this more as a retention feature?
What's the role of monetization in this? What's
the role of retention? And I think for us it
started out much more organically, and so we
have a lot of monetization hooks, that again, is
the retention PM, I would love to get rid of. But
again, it's sort of part of how the streak works
right now. And so, we always have this tension of,
hey, if we start to make it harder to buy
streak freezes, then fewer people buy them,
buy gems to buy them, and so there's this
more convoluted series of impacts that happen.
Yeah, no, I love that people
wanting to buy streak freeze is
like the ultimate sign of how much streaks matter.
Yeah, streak freeze is the other big
one that we've recently demonetized,
or introduced a free option for, is getting
back a lost streak. So, used to lose a streak,
we had a feature, in the day, back in the day,
called Streak Repair, we'd give you your streak
back, you had to pay gems. But what we found that
worked way better was a feature called Earn Back,
and this is basically where you would have to
do a certain number of lessons, as long as you
came back within a window soon after losing your
streak, do a few lessons and we just give you your
streak back. And that was such a retention winner.
And again, what we thought about was it feels like
you've earned it so much more when you've done...
You deserve to have your streak back, we haven't
cheapen the streak because you've done something.
And in this sense, this idea of cheapening the
streak is something, like from a philosophical...
Philosophy of the streak. From a philosophical
level, we wrestle with all the time, of,
cool, we're giving out more streak freezes,
at what point do we cross the line and users
start to realize their streak means nothing? Now,
everything that we've seen, users are
totally cool with using streak freezes
and still thinking about their streak is this
meaningful thing, but my co-lead, Antonia,
who made that awesome cross-stitch for me, she is
the keeper for us of the sanctity of the streak.
And a lot of times as we... And I think this is
really important to have, as you're thinking about
building your streak. You can almost always
get engagement wins, up to a certain point,
by just cheapening the streak, making it easier to
extend, letting users have more flexibility, but
you kind of got to hold the line at some point.
And it's not clear where that line is.
And once you... You talk about
one-way doors or two-way doors,
there's a point where you go too far and it's a
one-way door, and all of a sudden those users,
those 9 million users on one-year streaks don't
care about their streak anymore. And that is,
I don't know, again, retention PM perspective,
that'd be an extinction level event for us. I
don't want all of these users to stop
caring about their streak. And so,
to have somebody who is invested in the sanctity
of this streak, and for us it's Antonia and Luis,
he's very good about this, is really important,
just so you make sure you don't go too far.
That's an awesome insight. So, to protect...
And push notifications I think are another
example of this in general for companies, how
much is too much? Because everyone is just like,
let's just send another push, it's fine, just one
more. And so, your solution to that is a person is
like the keeper, and almost the gatekeeper,
plus the founder, of how far is too far.
It's good if you can have that.
I think push notifications are
also easier because there's a lot of
things you can do around, all right,
we'll send a budget cap for how many
notifications we'll send, you can-
It's like [inaudible 00:54:38] policy.
Yeah, policies. But I think with a lot
of things, at least for the streak,
it's harder to create policies for in the same
way, a lot of it has to be done based on feel,
and so you just got to use
your best judgment at times.
Sweet. Okay. Any other, maybe
one or two more lessons from
this journey of what streaks has become today.
You mentioned notifications, and I've
mentioned this a few times. One... It's funny,
you tend to think of, exactly as you say, you
can just always send another notification,
it's going to be some win, and at some point it'll
be a bad experience, but it's tough to see that.
There's actually a notification that we... So, we
send two notifications related to your core streak
each day, the first is a practice reminder, we
send it, this is actually an interesting insight,
23 and a half hours after you practice
the day before. Whoa, that is a lot.
23 and a half. Okay,
So, basically, if you practice at noon today,
we'll send it to you at 11:30
AM tomorrow, and we have done-
And it's, because it's like assuming they
are free in that time the day before,
maybe they'll be free at the same time?
And we actually moved, we used to let users set
this practice reminder time, and our thinking was,
cool, you're going to say 7:00 PM, that's when
I really want to extend my streak each day,
and then you know what? I say this to somebody
with two kids, life gets in the way, life always
gets in the way, and when you think you're going
to practice will change, your life will change,
whatever. And what we realize is the best
indicator of when you should practice was
when did you practice the day before. We could
almost certainly get more detailed, we have tried
a bunch of ways to have much more complex logic,
and what always wins is 23 and a half hours.
That's so interesting. Revealed
behavior versus stated.
Yeah, exactly. So, again, we send this
practice reminder 23 and a half hours later,
the other thing that we'll do though is we'll
send a, what we call a streak saver, and this
is at 10:00 at night, if you have not extended
your streak, we'll send you a message saying, hey,
it's your last chance, this is it, if you don't
extend your streak. And you would think that,
that's kind of spammy, that's kind of annoying,
to get a notification from an app at 10:00 PM,
but what we found is because people care about
their streak, their streak is this good thing
that they attach positive emotions,
that they don't really want to lose,
that notification reminding them, hey, come back
and... People see this by and large as a positive
notification and not a negative notification.
Obviously, it serves our purpose as well of
getting users to come back and not lose their
streaks, but again, I think if you can think
about your notification strategy related
to what is the feature that it's tied to,
how do users perceive that? You can
almost certainly, not get away with more,
but you can be thoughtful about notification load,
and when to send notifications, and again, for us,
this late night message, that's also highly
impactful, super good, is actually something
that could be perceived as spammy, but a
lot of our users really do... Somebody who,
it's often late at night, and I work here, and
I'm like, oh, forgot to do my... I was think about
Duolingo all day, here it is, 11:15, and I still
haven't done it, that message is really powerful.
Yeah. It has saved me many times,
I totally know that message,
and I love that it's a late night message
from an app, very rarely do you actually,
are happy about that, and I love that
this actually is a good example where-
It's really funny, all of the stories that
you hear about people extending their streak,
if you look around a Duolingo party, where it's
like 11:30, 11:45, all the Duolingo employees,
they're are doing their lesson at the last
minute. You always see these pictures of
people in the club doing, or at a concert doing
Duolingo, and yeah, because it's like otherwise
you're going to use a streak freezer,
or God forbid you will lose your streak.
That's so funny. Okay, anything else? And if
there's more than one more, definitely share,
but any other really interesting
lessons or wrong turns or insights?
I talked about streak freezes, and we've done
a lot with streak freeze, but I think if you're
going to make flexibility a thing, it's probably
also useful thinking about how do you celebrate
perfection. And so, we have a feature that we
have, it is the simplest thing in the world, it's
called Perfect Streak. And it's just, if you don't
use the streak freeze for a few days, we make your
streak look gold, and we make your little progress
bar on the calendar just look a little bit nicer.
There's no reward for doing it, you don't get
anything other than this nice little indication,
and it is awesome. It is a simple feature, it
is ultra not complex, and it is really powerful,
not only for getting users to, as a bit of a
reward, they'd be hey, get to seven days without
using a streak freeze and your streak becomes
perfect, but it's also a really nice indication
of users who aren't using streak freezes.
Here is the thing that if you don't use a
streak freeze, which, again candidly, I would
love for you never to use a streak freeze,
if you don't use a streak freeze, your streak
will stay perfect. It's funny, we actually just,
we're constantly responding to bug reports about
the streak. It is... I swear to God, we have the
best infrastructure around this feature because
it is so important. We had an employee who lost
her, I think a four-month perfect streak, and it
was a big deal for her because she did her lesson,
and she was crossing international dateline, there
was a bunch of stuff going on that was like, it
was just kind of weird in our backend. But people
start to care about perfection as much as they
do their streak, and for that person it was a big
deal when they lost their perfect streak. And so,
this is just an example of, look, if you're
going to go after flexibility, which is good,
finding a way to pull users back into perfection
is a really important counterweight to have.
What I'm imagining is you guys need a Amazon style
chatbot that just gives you the streak
back, it's just like, okay, here you go.
We have very much... So, we have,
if people lose their streak,
there's ways to get in contact with us,
but we've actually thought about that,
where it's like, okay, we should
just build a self-service feature,
and if we think that your excuse is good enough,
whatever, we'll just [inaudible 01:00:34].
Yeah, yeah. [inaudible 01:00:35].
Because again, I'd much rather you
be on a streak than have lost it,
particularly [inaudible 01:00:41].
Right. But it also can feel that easy. I love
this, I also love this point about just the
power of the animation and user experience
having impact, that's really interesting.
Is that something you find often, just
celebrating and making it feel really
amazing without copy or any feature
is just like, holy, you're awesome?
This is another thing where it's like when users
care about the feature, using not only animation,
haptics, sound effects, using... And it's funny,
we don't have sound effects on the streak,
this is probably something we'll look
at in the not too distant in future,
but haptics are something we
have done a lot of testing on-
Like the phone vibrating in various ways.
Yeah, exactly, your phone, there being a really
cool haptic pattern as you extend your streak,
all of this stuff wins. And it's cool because I
think it wins... There's a few reasons. One is
it just makes you feel good, you get some cool
moment in your streak, and we celebrate you,
and we celebrate you in this visual way, and
your phone's buzzing, it just feels awesome.
The other thing it does is it causes you to pause
on that screen, and I think there's this desire,
as you think through a lot of, as PMs think
through, oh, how can I get users through this
funnel as painlessly as possible? I talked
about [inaudible 01:01:52]. There's a lot
of times where I don't, I want you to stop.
I want you to stop and land on the screen.
You got to be careful not to do this for too many
screens, but the one big ones, sometimes I just
want you to pause there and enjoy the moment.
If I can get you to enjoy the moment more,
you're going to care more about your streak, and
you're going to be coming back tomorrow. And so,
animations that are cool, and that cause you
to really soak it in, haptics that feel good,
all of that comes together to make you really
focus on that moment, all of that just gets
users more connected to their streak. So,
animation in the right times works well
and it's something we've had win quite a lot.
Who designs the haptic stuff?
Is there a haptic designer?
For the longest time it would be a product
designer, or actually, it initially started as the
engineer would be like, all right, would cobble
together haptics, based on what they felt good,
then it became a product design role, where they
would use their best judgment. We actually just
recently required an animation studio, Hobbs in
Detroit, and now they are the sort of keepers
of, they do a lot of motion design work, haptics
very close to that, and so they do a lot of that.
I do remember trying to hire for a while a haptics
contractor, like haptics design, and it was the
saddest hiring I've ever done, because it was
just, I don't know, it was such a specific...
I don't know. I just went through a lot
of people who, it's just a really tricky
space of kind of sound effects, kind
of motion design, sort of technical...
Yeah, such a unique role.
Very unique specific skill set.
Right. And there's very few apps
that really need this this deeply,
so you're almost creating this person.
Yeah.
That is fascinating. That's like a
whole podcast on its own. By the way,
I was going to say as you're talking about this,
I love that it's a win to celebrate people that
don't lose their streak, you introduce this
way to make it flexible, and that's a big win,
and then you go the opposite direction of, if you
don't use this feature, you also feel even better.
Well, and it's funny, you talked about the
danger of feature bloat, or we sort of talked
about the danger of feature bloat, this is
actually something I'm constantly thinking
about with this. We have the streak, but
then we also have the perfect streak,
and we count how many weeks you've
had a perfect streak. Well, all of
a sudden we have two streak numbers that
are competing with each other. It's funny,
we actually don't introduce the concept of a
perfect streak until after you've hit seven days,
and some of this is just because the cognitive
load of additional streak features. A lot of
our cooler streak features, you got to get
on a long enough streak. And not to say we
haven't tested it because we have, because we test
everything, introducing these features earlier,
but what we've found is that pretty universally
they lose when we introduce too many things,
too many concepts to users too early in the
experience, it's just hard for them to manage.
Okay, sweet. I know that we can go down this track
for hours and hours, there's endless learnings
about all the things you all have done along the
journey. I want to shift to talking about how your
team operates. So, there's a lot of threads you
touched on of just how a team can do this so well,
shift 600 experiments, as you said, continue
to find opportunity. What are some maybe
lessons or advice you'd have for folks that are
like, oh wow, I want to work more like this,
from your team's experience, how does your
team to operate that folks can learn from?
Yeah, maybe just a little bit of context.
Duolingo cares a lot about... So,
most of our teams are metric-based teams.
So, we do the most work with streak,
but the metric, what we really care about
at the end of the day is CURR, and DAUs,
because we see that DAUs hit CURR. And so,
when you can be really laser focused on,
my goal each quarter is to make this metric
go up, I think it's much easier to make sure
that you're working on the highest ROI thing.
I think when you think more about like, oh,
I want to make this feature better, I think
it's easier to get lost in what better means,
and how you think about better. And so, I do
think that having a really strong degree of focus
as a team on what is the metric that I'm caring
about, and how is that directing my efforts is-
Versus feature-oriented. So, basically
your teams are structured around
a metric/a goal/outcome versus we
own this feature, or this product.
So, retention owns streak, I guess, but that's
only because we've seen streak drive CURR better
than any feature. But we are not, we have this
IAP hook with our streak freeze purchases,
there are other teams that work on, that can and
have worked on the streak, because it's not ours
to say, no, no, no, we do all the iterations
here, we just know that it drives our metric
better. In the same way that leaderboards, we have
a team that focuses on how much time you spent,
we want users to spend more time on Duolingo so
they're learning more. Leaderboards is the best
vector for doing it, so that team does a lot of
leaderboards work, but every now and then I have
an idea that I think will be highly retentive,
and I will go in, and I'll pitch to them,
and then we'll do some change to the
leaderboard to make it more retentive.
But I do think having that clear metric of
we're trying to drive CURR not we're trying
to just make this feature better, helps at least
make sure, give the team clear marching orders,
and that focus I think is really
good for prioritizing backlog.
Cool. This is a really important point,
this is the same way Airbnb worked,
when I worked there for a long time, is
it's, here's a goal that we want your
team to be responsible for, you can work on any
product you need to hit this goal, as you said,
often various products are most connected to
what you're doing, but what you're describing is,
even though a team's kind of... I imagine you
own it from a [inaudible 01:07:29] perspective,
and you're like are the shepherd of this part of
the feature because it hits your goal, helps your
goal most. But any other team can come in and be
like, hey Jackson, we need to work on some streak
stuff to help with learning, you're like, go for
it. Just a tangent there. Do they work really
closely with your team if they want to do some
work in the code? How does that work logistically?
Yeah. If you are, again, this is where I say
there's soft ownership, we're not against teams
doing things to the streak, but if we're going
to do something given we probably have multiple
quarters worth of a roadmap around the streak... I
say probably, we do. Multiple quarters of roadmap
for what we can do to the streak, if other
teams want to come and mess with it, okay,
we got to just figure out how is that going to
work with what our plans for the streak were,
how do we make sure a lot of times
when teams are coming in thinking, hey,
let's do this to the streak, they're in context
that we might have, and so there's as much of a
much simpler version of what we're doing now, a
bit of a knowledge sharing, of saying, all right,
well, this is what we think about the streak,
this is what we've seen work, hasn't worked,
how does that influence some of the
hypothesis that you have. And so,
I think getting that really... Making
sure the juice is worth the squeeze.
Good old-fashioned product
management work right there.
Yeah.
Cool. What else is interesting about how you
all operate and how you all work
to achieve this sort of success?
Again, my team lead runs, Antonia runs the
most... A really process, if you're going to
run this experiments, you have to be really
process-oriented and really thoughtful about
which experiments am I going to run when,
how is that going to set up the next one,
there's heavy Jira automation, I think sometimes
the Atlassian suite makes my eyes bleed,
but there's a lot of times where that degree
of process helps the team unblock engineers
and make them move really fast. And so,
making sure that you have really good
process around how are you going to run so
many experiments, it's worth investing in.
Can you follow that thread actually?
Just when you say that, what does that
look like? What are some elements of that
process to make this work efficiently?
All the way down to, really detailed roadmaps
around, all right, we're running this experiment
is based on the results of this experiment, or
might hook into an element of this feature, how do
we make sure that we're lining up implementation
on this so that as soon as this thing runs and
we're ready to go, we can start rolling out the
next one. I hate features just sitting around and
us not, again, continuing that thread. So, it's
not just thinking about what's our engineering
bandwidth, but also what's the design bandwidth
to make sure that we have the next iteration of
this feature ready to go. We're planning months
out, as we think about these feature iterations,
even small ones, feature iterations, because
when you lose cycles, not pushing on a feature,
it's just sort of lost opportunity. And so,
everything from being thoughtful about engineering
roadmaps to design roadmaps to product roadmaps,
all of that needs to come together in a system.
So, essentially, mapping
dependencies across function,
and you're saying in Jira you can do this.
You can do a lot of it in Jira, there is a
non-zero amount of Google Docs that we have,
that sometimes does things a
little bit... I don't know,
sometimes it just looks a little bit
nicer, it's a little more flexible.
Yeah. [inaudible 01:10:38].
But Jira is our, it is where
the motherload of process is.
Great. Okay. What else?
Another thing that I'll just say is, we really
resist the urge to do the big V1. And I think
this is, I shared the streak goal example,
where, a lot of times when we're exploring
something we will say, okay, well, that's cool,
how do we strip away a bunch of stuff and figure
out what our core hypothesis is? And then, just
ship that thing first as a V1. Because it's easy,
and I've found this time and time
again, it's easy to add things,
features that make them win, I've worked in
retention engagement long enough, I can add,
I know enough things to pull, and bells to
add, and whistles to make something win,
but there's a lot of times where it's like
cool, t [inaudible 01:11:27] because all the
whistles you added, not because of what your
core hypothesis was, and a lot of times if you
can just really simplify what the feature is, it's
also much easier to ship, it's easier to design.
You're not designing for a whole system, you're
designing for something much simpler. And so,
getting everybody to think that way, allows us
to end up shipping faster, shipping simpler,
designing faster, getting faster approval, getting
insight, and then doing what I talked about with
streak goal, being able to run iteration after
iteration after iteration, add these things
iteratively. And then not only by doing this are
you able to move faster, but you get confidence
at each step of the way, that, hey, my series of
hypotheses is actually born out. Or if it's not,
cool, then we're going to drop that part of the
feature, and then just ship what actually matters.
If I can try to summarize the broad lesson so
far that I'm hearing, and maybe you would've
shared this, but I'm just thinking, if I
were to try to design a company to operate,
that we all operate, you essentially map
all the levers that drive the business. So,
you have this mapping of all the metrics
that drive up to growth and daily active
users. CURR ended up being the biggest
specific metric to drive growth long term,
so there's imagining a tree of all
the opportunities you could work on,
you found this is what is most connected to our
growth. You basically just start mining, I don't
know if mining is the right metaphor, but just
looking for things that move that specific metric.
You just look and poke and explore, and then once
you find one, you just go real deep on trying a
lot of different... You come up with a hypothesis,
and a strategy of here's how we think we can do
this, and how we can move this, and then you just
try a bunch of stuff. There's also this element
of the Arrested Development quote, "There's
always money in the banana stand," comes to mind,
where it's just keep working on, see there's more,
there's going to be more opportunity at this.
When I joined Duolingo, the PM that I took over
for, Anton, who used to lead the retention team,
I remember saying, "Dude, the streak, it
just counts up, you guys have been testing
on it for years, how much more work can we
do on the streak?" And he was like, Jackson,
you child... He didn't say exactly this, but
this is how I felt it. Like, Jackson, you child,
we're not even 30% of the way optimized. And four
years later, I say that with such conviction,
we are so far away from... We've made a ton
of strides, but we are still so far away,
and every quarter where we ship a ton of wins and
improvements to the streak, it just continues to
prove to me that there is so much more to be done.
So, I think your framing of it is... And I would
say there's a lot of thought that goes into,
again, I talk about the strength of the hypothesis
that you have to have as you start to build
out larger feature strategy, I do think it's
really important to not just do a bunch of random
stuff but do it with intent, with a goal in mind,
otherwise, you do end up in these local maximas.
But yeah, there's still a bunch of stuff that we
haven't tried that I think we have high confidence
in working out and so we'll keep doing that.
Are there any other, say, lasting lessons
from this journey that if someone were to
try to operate this way, build streaks into
their product, anything you'd recommend?
Yeah, I really do think it starts with...
Streaks are an engagement hack. You can
make your app more retentive, I'm almost
positive, almost every app out there can
make it more retentive. It is loss aversion,
that is, again, armchair psychologist Jackson,
it's just a thing that works on humans. But
if your app is not something that users want
to use every day, or whatever cadence
you want your app to be, to work on,
it's going to be, you're only going to get
so much from that streak, and honestly,
it's probably going to distract you from what
really should matter, which is making your app
something that people want to use every day.
And so, if you start focusing on the streak but
you haven't made that an enjoyable experience,
you're just going to waste a lot of time,
honestly. And so, I think making sure that you
have your core loop of your app figured out,
that it is giving value to users, it is something
that they want to come back to every day,
that really sets the stage for something to
layer a streak on. So, resist the temptation,
if you don't think you've reached that point,
to go too hard down the path of streak.
That's a really good point. Just like
a streak is not going to solve your
problems if people don't actually care
about the core value you're providing.
No, and honestly, it'll probably cause more
problems if what you end up focusing on is
how do I make the streak highly engaging, but
your app is... You're wasting time that could
otherwise be better spent on solving more
critical problems. So, that's one learning,
the other thing that I'll say is, we met with
one of our board members, Bing, Bing Gordon,
a few weeks, or a few months ago rather, and he
had this comment where he was just like, "The
reason why users care about your streak so much
is because you care about your streaks much." You
being Duolingo. The reason why users care about
our streak so much is because Duolingo cares about
the streaks so much. And we're like, what do you
mean? Well, he's like, well, after every session
you see a big streak screen, and it's animated
cooler than almost any other screen in the app,
and then sometimes you see some other screens,
and there's all these other... You don't let a
user forget it, you talk about them in messages.
And so, I think it's worth thinking about, look,
if you're going to build a streak, and then you're
going to [inaudible 01:17:06] it off into the
corner of your app, where users aren't going to
see it, they're probably not going to care about
it as much, which might be fine, because there
might be other levers that you think are more
important to pull on, but there's a reason why we
focus as much on the streak as we do, and that's
because we want it to be top of mind for users.
And that's not by accident then that users start
to care about it. And so, I think just as you're
thinking about building the streak, making sure
that you're giving it the visibility it deserves,
if you want it to have the kind of impact that
Duolingo has, it's sort of an important hierarchy
principle to think about as you design things.
That's such a good point. You look for cues to
the app of tell me what I should pay attention to,
what's important? If you're just like
fire, explosions, you made a streak,
oh, maybe I should pay attention to this
feature. And then the push notifications
obviously encourage you there too.
Anything else along those lines?
Maybe final thing is, look, we ran so many
tests on our Duolingo streak to figure out
what worked. We have a philosophy at Duolingo,
of test it first. We are a lot of times willing
to test things. I really think that if you're
going to try to introduce a streak, or you want
to improve on the streak you have, don't get
too caught up in the philosophy of everything,
make sure your hypotheses feel like they're good,
but my recommendation is just try things. And
this is, again, you said it earlier, it's like
this is as much human psychology as anything,
and as soon as that becomes the case, you kind
of just got to understand what users respond to.
And the easiest way to do that is to stop spending
time batting around ideas in a conference room and
just try some stuff. So, huge recommendation to if
you're going to invest in a streak, try and figure
out what works through testing with users rather
than trying to get it perfect on the first try.
Say someone's listening and they're like,
should we do streak, is this worth doing?
What's your take on just the chances that a streak
feature would be helpful to another consumer?
I am well known for saying in the
company that I think every team,
every app could benefit from a streak. Now,
how you implement it is very different,
and I think you got to, what is your user's
use case? If they're going to come use,
I don't know, tax software... Okay,
you know what? Now that I say this,
tax software would be a hard one, but maybe it's
all about you need users to come back every day,
during the tax season, or how many times...
I don't know. Now, that I say this out loud-
Times you upload your [inaudible 01:19:37] forms.
Yeah, that is a hard use case. But the vast
majority of companies I think have a good idea
of like, all right, here is my ideal use case,
I want users to come here three times a month,
that would be ideal. Or four times a month.
You can build a streak to work. Peloton has
weekly streaks because the idea of doing a
Peloton workout every single day was hard
for this user during COVID. It was just like
every now and then you get on the Peloton,
that was great, but the idea of a weekly streak
was something that I could keep up. And so,
I think figure out what your usage pattern is,
as a user, and then build your streak around it.
But as long as you're not a really, again, the tax
example is probably a good counterfactual, but as
long as you have some degree of frequency in your
use, I think almost anything can have a streak.
So, Duolingo, it's, again, a $14 billion
company, this feature, possibly the most
contributing factor, other than the core
product, to that level of success in market cap,
and it's hard to imagine another just feature of
a product that has had this much impact on growth
and revenue and building this sort of business.
So, I love that we spent this much time on it,
the motherload, the motherload of advice and
insights. So, thank you again for putting-
Of course. Very fun.
With that, we've reached our very
exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
I'm ready.
First question, what are two or three books
you've recommended most to other people?
All right, I'll start with A Guide to Midwest
Conversation. So, I'm based in Kansas City,
I'm a proud Midwesterner, and us Midwesterners
talk in a certain way. I think you hear about
Minnesota nice, but we tend not to say what we
mean, and it is a very funny primer into what
Midwesterners actually mean when they say what
they say. So, highly recommend reading that.
I like that you give that to people, just like,
here's what I might be telling
you, which you may not read.
My wife is German, and I gave it to
her so she could better understand.
I see German being the opposite of that, okay.
Very different. Another book, this is a good one,
Fate is the Hunter. This is a really cool book,
it's a memoir of one of the early commercial
airline pilots, and it is wild to hear the
stories about what flying was back in the
day. I'm a former management consultant,
I flew every week for almost six years,
and I never once had to worry about,
am I going to make it to the other end of this
flight alive? That was not the case back then,
and so some of the stories about what it used to
be like to be a pilot on some of these planes,
before modern aviation technology, is fascinating,
and makes you really appreciate what we have.
It feels good to read a book like that,
being a software PM or engineer or
whatever, how different that life is.
Hardware is hard.
Hardware. Oh man, it's not haptic design. Okay.
Next, unless there's any other books you're
going to share? No, okay, great. What's a favorite
recent movie or TV show you've really enjoyed?
So, I have two kids, I watch a lot of Bluey,
it's really good, I swear, it brings me no
shortage of joy. But adult show or show not
meant for four-year-olds that I have watched,
I just finished the latest season of Emily in
Paris, man, wonderful. I realize it's not the
highest brow of television, but just
beautiful people in beautiful cities,
solving problems that are not earth-shattering,
sometimes it is nice to just tune out. Also,
I'm learning French on Duolingo, slight plug
for the app, I can understand a lot of the
French that is being spoken, and there is no
better joy than having invested as much time
as I have in French, and actually being
able to use it. So, huge fan of Emily.
That is so funny, what a fun Venn diagram of
interests. My mother-in loves Emily in Paris,
I saw someone tweeting about what Visa
is she on? How is she still in Paris?
Yeah. You best just not ask questions,
there's a lot of questions for this
show that are better left unasked.
[inaudible 01:23:40] Okay. Do you have a favorite
product you recently discovered that
you really like? Other than Duolingo.
Last week I went to Home Depot, and I
bought a new ladder, and ladder innovations,
you don't think of often, but you can make
one of the legs go a little bit further than
the other leg. And as somebody like myself who
has a house that is built on a slight slope,
every time I go up on my ladder, I take
my life in my hands, but with this ladder,
I'm always even. I cleaned my gutters twice
last week just because of how awesome this
ladder has... How much this ladder has
changed my life. So, ladder innovation,
I don't think it gets talked enough about and so
I'm happy to give it the spotlight it deserves.
I appreciate you doing that, and it's
the first ladder recommendation we've
had on the podcast. Two more questions.
Do you have a favorite life motto that
you really find useful in work
or in life they share with folks?
This probably will not be much of a surprise based
on how I've talked about our willingness to test
things, but you miss 100% of the shots that you
don't take. I'm a big fan of just trying things,
even if your possibility of success is not
100, because you learn a lot along the way.
Final question, do you have
any fun traditions at Duolingo,
amongst either the PM team or the company in
general that might be delightful to share?
We have way too many traditions to count. I will
share the weird tradition that we do at every
retention standup, and this started during the
pandemic, we obviously used to stand up in person,
and then when we went remote, we did this thing
where whoever's the last person to go would count
down 3, 2, 1, and then we'd all try to clap at the
same time, which was kind of fun and dorky, but we
fell in love with it, and four years later we're
still doing it. Recently we've added, we all say
yee-haw in unison afterwards, I can't tell you
why. But trying to synchronize a clap via Zoom,
and then all shouting yee-haw... I did this in
a phone booth the other day and after I came
out someone told me, "You know that those
aren't as soundproof as you think," but
when you get a good opportunity to give
a yee-haw, you can't pass up on it, so.
I love these little things, they sound so minor,
but they're such important elements
of team culture and tradition,
and so important for PMs to find ways to
just have fun and do something ridiculous.
I will say, it took a while to get
people behind shouting yee-haw,
but now that we have people doing it, you can't
take it away [inaudible 01:26:08], we all love it.
Oh man, I called our all hands for a while,
y'all hands, feel free to steal that.
You get it, you get it Lenny. Yeah.
I get it. Jackson, this is incredible, I feel like
people are going to listen to this with notebooks,
and just like, okay, here's a bunch of ideas
we should try with whatever we're working on,
whether it's streaks or not. Thank you so much for
being here. Two final questions, where can folks
find you online if they want to reach out, learn
more, learn more about Duolingo? I know you're
hiring product managers, so share more there,
and finally, how can listeners be useful to you?
Yes, you can find me on LinkedIn, that is
where most of my online social media is, so
Jackson Shuttleworth, and then how
people can be useful to me, yes,
as you said, we are hiring. We're actually
hiring for my team. Are you interested in
thinking about streaks as much as we do? We
might be the right home for you, so please,
you can apply on our website. We're also hiring
from a number of other product management roles,
and they're all as thrilling as this work is.
And then, I'm always interested about how other
companies have implemented streaks and what
they've learned, and so what I'd say is if
you're a company who's implemented a streak
maybe in a different way than Duolingo has,
or you found a whole ton of success and
another vector, another element of the feature
that we didn't talk about today, I would love
to know more. I used to catalog basically every
streak I found out there, and as it's become more
of a popular feature, it's just been hard to keep
up on. So, if you have interesting streak insights
to send my way, I would love to hear them.
I love that, a collection of all the best ways
of doing streaks. Jackson, just I want to say
congrats to your team and you for having so
much impact. This is like the dream of a lot
of PMs and teams, is to see this much impact and
continue to ship wins, and so congrats, nice work.
Thank you very much.
Thanks for [inaudible 01:27:59]. And with
that, Jackson, thanks so much for being here.
Yeah, thank you Lenny, this was a lot of fun.
Same. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening,
if you found this valuable, you can subscribe
to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also, please
consider giving us a rating or leaving a review,
as that really helps other listeners
find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
Lenny'sPodcasts.com. See you in the next episode.