You've worked at two businesses that have
done incredibly well combining product in ops.
Uber always has this mentality and Opendoor
does two of the product operations, twin
turbine jet plane where you can fly the plane
on one engine for a little bit if you need to,
but it's operating most efficiently and
effectively if both are working together.
What has having been in ops done to
make you a better product leader?
Gave a really deep understanding of
how the business actually works. It's
a pretty good foundation for
them going on to say, okay,
what do we actually want to build
in a more scalable technology way.
Something else I've heard that you're very
good at is staying very calm under pressure.
I've slept on the floor in
China before launching uberPOOL,
and when you reflect the stress onto your teams,
everybody tenses out. It counterintuitively
doesn't produce better outcomes.
Today my guest is Brian Tolkin. Brian is currently
head of product and design at Opendoor. Before
that, he spent nearly five years at Uber where he
joined as employee 100. Before Uber had UberX or
uberPOOL or any shared rides, he actually started
on the ops team at Uber, moved into product,
ended up leading product and launch of uberPOOL,
and then taking it global. He also started the
product operations function at Uber. Before
that function was really even a thing,
which I didn't know until the chat that we had.
In our conversation, Brian shares a ton of lessons
about building products with a heavy operational
component. Also, how to run great product reviews,
how he implements the jobs to be done,
framework and Opendoor's successfully.
The story behind Zillow trying to compete with
Opendoor failing and then partnering instead. Plus
a ton of great stories from the early days of Uber
and Opendoor, and so much more. If you enjoy this
podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow it
in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's
the best way to avoid missing feature episodes
and it helps the podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you Brian Tolkin. Brian, thank you so
much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you, appreciate it. Thanks for having me.
First of all, just a huge thank you
to Kayvon Beykpour for connecting us,
introducing us. He said all kinds
of amazingly nice things about you.
He also gave me some very hard questions
to ask you. I hope you've come prepared.
Terrific. Put me in my hot seat.
Okay, I want to spend a bunch of time talking
about product and ops. You started your career
in operations. At Uber you actually started on the
ops team and you moved into product. You've also
worked at both Uber and at Opendoor, which have
both huge operational components. I think it's
really rare that people, one, see a company
scale to the heights of Uber and Opendoor
with such a heavy operational component that
are still tech companies and also it's really
where someone starts an ops and then moves
into product and ends up where you are,
where your chief product officer, really
successful company. So I have a bunch of
questions here. Maybe the first is just what
has having been in ops done to make you a
better product leader? How does that change
the way that you operate as a product leader?
Starting on the operations side gave a really
deep understanding of how the business actually
works. You are truly operating it day in
and day out and the success of the city is
in large part driven by the inputs that you
are putting into it every single day on the
ground and whether or not there was rain that
weekend, which was a nice driver of metrics,
but talking to customers every single day like
one-on-one onboarding drivers responding to
support tickets, there's no centralized support
team, there was no closer to the customer,
right? And so I think that foundation actually for
really understanding what moves the business and
being super close to the customer actually is a
pretty good foundation for them going on to say,
okay, what do we actually want to build
in a more scalable technology way?
This episode is brought to you by Pendo, the
only all-in-one product experience platform
for any type of application. Tired of bouncing
around multiple tools to uncover what's really
happening inside your product? With all the
tools you need in one simple to use platform,
Pendo makes it easy to answer critical
questions about how users are engaging
with your product and then turn those insights
into action. Also, you can get your users to do
what you actually want them to do. First, Pendo
is built around product analytics, seeing what
your users are actually doing in your apps so
that you can optimize their experience. Next,
Pendo lets you deploy in-app guides that lead
users through the actions that matter most.
Then Pendo integrates user feedback so that you
can capture and analyze what people actually want.
And the new thing in Pendo, session replays. A
very cool way to visualize user sessions. I'm
not surprised at all that over 10,000 companies
use it today. Visit pendo.io/lenny to create your
free Pendo account today and start building better
experiences across every corner of your product.
PS, you want to take your product led knowhow a
step further? Check out Pendo's lineup of free
certification courses led by talk product experts
and designed to help you grow and advance in your
career. Learn more and experience the power
of the Pendo platform today at pendo.io/lenny.
Pendo.
This episode is brought to you by Explo, a game
changer for customer facing analytics and data
reporting. Are your users craving more dashboards,
reports and analytics within your product? Are
you tired of trying to build it yourself? As a
product leader, you probably have these requests
in your roadmap, but the struggle to prioritize
them is real. Building analytics from scratch
can be time-consuming, expensive, and a really
challenging process. Enter Explo. Explo is a fully
white labeled embedded analytics solution designed
entirely with your user in mind. Getting started
is easy. Explo connects to any relational database
or warehouse and with its low-code functionality,
you can build and style dashboards in. Once
you're ready, simply embed the dashboard
or report into your application with a tiny code
snippet. The best part, your end users can use
Explo's AI features for their own report and
dashboard generation eliminating customer data
requests for your support team. Build and embed a
fully white labeled analytics experience in days.
Try it for free at explo.co/lenny. That's
E-X-P-L-O/lenny. I've seen that a lot of
companies, and this was definitely true to
Airbnb, where the product team looks down a
little bit on the ops team where they're like,
"oh, we're doing things that are going to scale
to millions of users. We're doing these things
that are going to apply to everyone." There's
this ops team over there doing a few things
that are going to not scale. They keep asking
us for things to build for their one-off ideas.
What do you think that product teams often maybe
miss or don't understand about the ops teams that
would help them see them in a different light?
Yeah, it's a great question and I think Uber
always had this mentality and OpenDoor does too
of like a twin turbine jet plane where you can
fly the plane on one engine for a little bit if
you need to, but it's operating most efficiently
and effectively if both are working together,
and I think that's really true, right? The
reality is operations teams, local teams,
can iterate faster, can scale talking to
customers really much more efficiently,
have great qualitative insights, and so if it's
seen more as a harmony instead of a competition,
I think that's really, really
helpful where it's like, okay,
how do we get the insights that are happening
day in and day out in the field, on the ground,
whatever that may be, and help us build
better products because of that, right?
Like a PM sitting in San Francisco can't be in
Opendoor's case 50 markets, walking houses every
single day in Uber's case, whatever, a thousand
cities understanding the nuances of safety in
South America and it's just not possible, but what
you can do is foster a really good relationship
and a really good feedback loop of how people
who do deeply understand those things can help
give insights. Now is actually the birth of
product operations was that insight as well.
Can you say more on that?
Yeah, sure. So, sorry, I should probably
define what product operations was. At
Uber it was basically this notion that we had
centralized, this was later in my career at Uber,
but we had a centralized product team
building stuff mostly in San Francisco,
not strictly through the Ross, but
at this point around the world,
but mostly in San Francisco and then we had
a very globally distributed operations team,
and there was a bidirectional feedback loop that
wasn't super strong and that feedback loop was
basically when the EPD teams in San Francisco
built new features, how do we effectively put it
in global markets and then how do we effectively
get input from global markets to better build
features. And so one solution to that problem,
our solution at the time was to start up a new
function called product operations who had
accountability and reported into operations
but physically sat with and operated much like
a member of the product team to help solve that.
Is that maybe the first time there's a... Did
you invent product operations as a function?
I don't think so because at the time, I believe
Google had a function, I can't remember what
Google called it was something slightly different,
but I met with a few folks who had been in similar
type roles at Google and a couple other
places, so I don't take credit for certainly
for inventing IT and other people have actually
dabbled in this model at Uber before me there
was just a formalization of it and our actual
building out of the organization, et cetera.
Did none of that. Sounds like you basically helped
make it a thing. I know you're being very modest,
I think. Coming back to your point about
decentralized operations teams, something I've
read is that search pricing came out of one GM and
a market just testing, emailing all the drivers,
hey, we're going to give you extra if you
drive on Saturday night. Is that true?
That would've been probably a little bit before
my time, but that being said, one thing that
is true is that surge pricing for actually
quite sometimes all of 2012, certainly 2013
probably, I don't know when we necessarily
switched, was very much a human in the loop
system or a very manual system where GMs
in every city would control basically the
parameters in which surge would operate and so
much of the time that would need, for example,
Monday through Friday, there would be no search,
it couldn't flip on, and then Friday nights and
Saturday nights it would flip on from whatever
you set, 7:00 PM to 3:00 AM and the cap was X,
whatever the cap was. And then within those
parameters the algorithm would optimize for what
the price was. But yeah, GMs controlled whether it
was on or off and what geographies were surging.
Wow, I didn't know that. Was that out of we
believe we are better than the algorithms or
we just don't have time to make them amazing
yet, so we're just going to help them along?
Yeah, I think it was probably a function of
a bunch of stuff, one of which is like, hey,
this is a fairly new concept and it's powerful
and dangerous and so let's make sure we understand
what's happening. The second is this belief that
local city teams know their cities best and so
you might know that an event is happening,
a baseball game gets out and it's like, oh,
I know that this baseball game's going to get out
at 10:00 PM so I'm going to set surge at 9:45 and
the algorithm may not be able to pick that up.
And then the third is the technical constraint
of nowadays clearly it's all automated, but
it's really hard to build a fully dynamic,
always on geospatially aware pricing
system and not just a little bit of time.
That makes sense. I feel like you're full
of wild stories from your time at Uber.
Is there one that comes to mind of just, I
think you helped scale in China, uberPOOL?
Yeah.
Maybe that's the one. I don't know. Can
you share wild story from early Uber days?
Yeah, so in the early days of Uber, one fun story
is obviously UberX is a random mainstream product
but has a funny, silly name, UberX. This product
in the early days was going to be all hybrid
and had a bunch of different potential
names. I was not personally driving this,
this was someone else on the operations
team, but they built the model for
what this product could be and there's no name for
it yet, so it was going to be a placeholder. So
what do you put in some placeholder? X. So UberX
and then the company was moving quickly enough,
the product got the green light, it
launched, and here we are, I don't know,
12 years later, 11 years later, whatever
it is and UberX is the name that stuck.
That is hilarious. I love it. So it was a
placeholder. It's like many products start
that way where they're like, this is just
the temporary name, and they're like, okay,
I guess everyone just knows it this
way now we're going to stick with it.
Exactly. It's too expensive to
change and rebrand at this point.
That's an awesome story.
One that is good about scaling Uber uberPOOL in
China is we were launching Uber pool in China and
this was going to be, China at the time was pretty
big for Uber, but uberPOOL was not there yet,
and so we were going to launch. And myself
and a few other folks were in Chengdu China,
which is the first Chinese market that we were
launching uberPOOL in and we were going to be on
the ground took to launch. We wanted to go live
at, I believe it was 6:00 AM for rush hour on,
I don't remember the day, but whatever, Monday
morning, and so we're there over the weekend
getting ready to set up and at the same time
we were doing some data center testing. And so
we flipped on all the testing infrastructure and
thought it was going to work and nothing works,
and the matching algorithm just isn't working
and we're like, oh my god, now it's whatever,
5:00 PM the day before we're supposed to go live,
6:00 PM, 7:00 PM okay, let's get on the phone
with the US, try and figure out what's going on.
I remember I slept about 30 minutes that night
between 2:00 and 3:00 AM being like, okay, well,
we have to go live at 6:00 AM I think there was
some press around it. We were planning on
going live and I think we got everything
finally working at probably about five 30 or six
in the morning and launched just in the nick of
time. And I'll never forget, we launched, it
was great, we monitored, everything was good,
and then we walked out for breakfast at 7:30
in the morning. Everyone sleep depressed,
no one slept all night and we got these
pancakes street food things and I have to
imagine they were not that good, but in my mind
it was the best meal I've ever had in my life.
It's like a meal after a marathon or a big hike.
Exactly. Yeah, exactly.
Everything's so delicious. This comes up a lot
of just these moments that are so incredibly
stressful and hard and leap deprived end up
being the best memories and the best stories
to tell and things you look back at fondly.
It's so weird how human nature is like that.
Yeah, I mean another one more recent for
Opendoor was when COVID hit, physically
we buy and sell homes, and so we were physically
going into people's homes and suddenly March 2020
going into people's homes was not something
people were comfortable with. And you look at
the real estate data coming out of China at the
time and it looked like coming to a standstill,
and so we actually turned off the core business
and we stopped buying homes for a few months. hey,
we can't go in and we don't know if anyone's going
to be buying any homes, and so what do we do? And
we took those few months and then came out
the other side and had virtualized the whole
process. Then it was pretty stressful, right,
because looking at a business that relies on
going into people's homes and suddenly you can't
do that anymore, what do you do? So, again, a fond
memory to look back on a very stressful time in
the moment where it feels very, very difficult.
Just since you mentioned Opendoor, I think
many people have heard of Opendoor. Maybe just
give a quick explanation of what Opendoor
does for people that aren't exactly sure.
So we're a digital platform to buy and
sell real estate. The core product today
is a seller focused product where people can go
online, enter some information about their home,
and we'll make an all cash offer to be
able to sell simplicity and certainty.
So the product really works for people
who want something that is certain and
simple and easy. I don't know if you've ever
sold a home, but it can be a very, very, very
successful difficult process with showings and
open houses and how to price it and will it
sell and all of that stuff. And so we offer
basically a way to skip the whole process.
So you basically sell your house to Opendoor
and it's just like, cool, done, move on.
You picked your closing date, you move out
when you want. Yeah, there's no hassle.
Sounds amazing. I want that. Coming back to ops
and product, just to close this thread again,
you've worked at two businesses that have done
incredibly well combining product and ops. Are
there any just broad lessons you've taken away
from how to make these two teams and functions
work well together and to build a business
that's very ops heavy but also offer driven?
The first one we touched on, which is a,
there's just got to be mutual respect. Both
functions have their time and their place and
their skillsets, and you just don't build big
businesses of this type without respecting the
fact that that both need to exist. The second,
particularly on the product and engineering
side, is really understanding where and how
the technology leverage comes from the business
and then being really focused on making sure
generally, especially in the earlier days, you are
more limited on the technical resourcing side than
you might be on the operational resourcing side.
And so how do you be really focused on where to
invest your time, effort, and energy technically,
which is why most of the engineering effort for
Uber was on the dispatching system and the pricing
system. That's just where the leverage was at the
time, given the scarcity of resources.
And so I think the second one is being
really intentional about where those techs are
and then being really forthcoming and saying,
hey, that means all these other places where
yes, it can make things easier, more efficient,
et cetera, et cetera. We are okay not investing
in right now, and that needs to be an explicit
decision and very transparent. But then the last
bit I would say is a deep understanding that the
real world has entropy and it's hard and it's
messy for us at Opendoor, we go into homes,
someone may not be home, scheduling may be off,
at Uber the driver may cancel the radio GPS.
All these things happen, right? Computers are
deterministic, but humans aren't, right? And so
building products that have a little bit
more flex or a little bit more fail safes
in case those things happen becomes
a little bit more of a paramount.
One other thing, the last thing I would say is I
think that the companies evolve as well. So what
I talked about at the beginning of Uber being
very focused from an engineering and product
side on the dispatching system and the pricing
system, obviously over time not to evolve now
it centralized all of these functions as the
company got bigger and more mature and scale
and optimization started to be more important
and expansion and that Petri dish of trying
new stuff and the tools got better and the
tech got easier and there was more internal
infrastructure. And so over time things can start
one way and shift over time as the business needs.
Let's actually spend more time there.
You keep saying things that make me
want to dig deeper. So at Airbnb we went
through the same thing where there was
all these local ops teams driving supply,
finding homes, bringing out the platform,
and then there's this tipping point where
the product in organic growth or word of
mouth ended up driving more and then orders of
magnitude more. So there was no need for these
folks to spend time doing these things. Can you
just maybe share an example, either we Opendoor,
when you talk about there's a time and
a place and a skillset for ops, how that
evolved? What was the team doing initially and
then what did they end up doing as things grew?
Yeah, I mean, maybe a very easy good example
to pick just one part of the Uber process in
the early days is at small scale, actually back
when it was Uber black drivers, every driver
was individually onboarded in a 90 minute to a
two-hour in-person in the office onboarding with
deep setting of expectations. The next version of
that... So that's obviously very ops driven. The
next version of that is a small classroom type
setting of three or five or six drivers at a
given time. Also, very ops driven. And then as we
got into more mass market products like Uber Taxi
or UberX, it was like, okay, maybe 20 or 30 at a
time. So now it's a little bit bigger classroom
setting. And we said, okay, let's make a video.
Instead of giving verbally the same presentation,
let's just make an onboarding video and that
was the next set of scale, but now suddenly we
have a different problem, which is okay, you
have to validate all of these credentials.
So most driver's license who they are, all
that stuff at one person, easy at three to
four at a time, easy, 10 at a time, a little
more challenging but fine. At 20 at a time,
okay, you're starting to run up onto it now
you fast-forward six months and you're doing
a thousand a week or whatever, suddenly
your system breaks and it's like, okay,
we have reached the point where operational system
improvements is no longer viable. So, you say,
okay, we have gone from the iteration stage to
the scale stage and technology is uniquely good
at scaling. So now we say, okay, instead of having
a bunch of folks around the world taking pictures
of driver's licenses and validating and doing all
that stuff, how do we integrate with some type of
OCR technology or auto recognition of driver's
licenses that feeds to a system that knows
what a driver's license is or can do automatic
validation and suddenly you've done two things.
One, you've scaled your system, and two, you've
just created a ton of time for what at the time
was probably dozens if not hundreds of people
running these onboarding sessions all over the
country, the world at the time to do other stuff.
And so now you can level that up and say, okay,
do we do more analytics? Do we do more
figure out the next process that needs
optimization or whatever the case may be
in that virtuous cycle just continues.
The way I like to think about this
is do things that don't scale and
then scale the things that you're doing.
That's the phrase I always come back to.
Exactly.
This reminds me of a hot take that
previous podcast guest shared in a
newsletter post Casey Winters. He talked about
that operations is usually, and it's a hot take,
that operations is a sign of inefficiency and
over time your job is to squeeze that away and
make it product software as much as possible.
Doesn't mean you always get there. Thoughts?
Yeah, I actually don't. Fundamentally,
it depends on what the operations is,
but I don't fundamentally disagree, but I
think that the right lens to think about it
is... And then those folks can move on to
the next challenge. And so there's always
another hill to climb. And so I think that
was one of the things at Uber and Opendoor
where there's this culture of on the ground
experimentation that's really helpful where
we were just talking about driver onboarding
may now be solved with technology so you have
a few extra hours a day. How do we get better
at optimizing the UberX system? How do you
start tinkering with food delivery? How do you
start thinking about higher capacity vehicles?
How do you think about better feedback loop
for those manual surge pricing toggles that
we talked about? So I generally agree it just
generally free across and solve more problems.
It feels like a big part of this is making
sure the operations teams understand there's
more opportunity, even if this ends up being
automated, your job is not going to go away.
We're going to find something new to try and
experiment and do things that don't skip.
Yep.
Awesome. Okay. Going a
completely different direction.
Great.
I hear you're very good at product reviews.
Okay.
A few people told me this. I'm curious
how you set up a product review and
any things you've learned, any tips for
how to run an effective product review?
That's very whoever mentioned that. But yes,
big fan of doing them actually in particular
to maybe bridge the conversations in companies
that have ops driven cadences or start out very
ops driven because the cadences can sometimes
be different. And so the operational cadences
that you might have something like a WVRA weekly
business review may not be conducive to always
picking your head up and saying like, Hey, where's
the product going on a slightly longer timeframe.
And so I think product reviews in general for
all companies are probably really helpful,
but actually in particular for some of the
product and operations led companies. In
terms of things I've learned, I think being really
intentional about what the goals are, I think it's
okay to say that there are two goals, a goal
of accountability and inform to an audience.
But also most importantly, I think this is the
primary goal is to help make the product better,
to help the teams think through a
problem and to have that, again,
back to our earliest conversation, be a very
intellectual conversation about the work and
how to make the product better and not
super scary. Product reviews hopefully
are not feeling like firing squads. That's a
scary environment to be in and not necessarily
one that's conducive to how do we make
the product better. Obviously sometimes
the conversations have to get a little intense,
but in general that's what we're shooting for
is something that helps the team go back and
think through how to make the product better.
So the two goals you try to communicate for
your product reviews, accountability slash
informing people what's happening, but
also just like we are here to make the
product better and setting that context. Yep.
Is there anything you'd do specifically to make
it not feel like a firing squad? Like you're
coming in here to be attacked and criticized?
Do you set context at the beginning of the
meeting? Is this just a part of the culture?
Yeah, I think definitely part of the culture,
but also I am a firm believer in general that the
people closest to the problems also have the best
context to solve that problem. And so as a more
senior voice in the room, often the
job is probing, asking questions,
throwing out ideas in a way that says like, hey,
this is an idea. This is not a mandate, this is a
thought. And if there's context missing that would
inform the product direction, then providing that
context in not a question asking sense, but hey,
this is context that you might not be aware of.
And so I think it's all in how you show up as
a leader and what that looks like in terms of
probing and pushing the team on dimensions
that they may not be thinking about. And
then understanding that the team is bringing
a perspective that you don't have, which is
they think about this problem 40, 50, 60 hours a
week, and you might think about this problem three
hours a week. So you bring them a breath, the
team brings a depth in haven't been there yet.
I don't know if you heard Dharmesh Shah's episode
or his thing on flash tags. Have you seen this?
I have not, no.
Okay. He has a whole system. So you talked
about how as a leader you want people to not
take everything you tell them as feedback as
I need to do this. So he has a whole set of
hashtags that communicate how important this is
to him from hashtag FYI to suggestion, to a plea.
Yes.
A plea to you.
This was actually explained to me. I don't think
I've seen the original source, so I'll go back
and watch it, but this was explained to me as
I'm actually a big fan. I think that's great.
Yeah, just get everyone on the same
page. Okay. Maybe one last question
here. Who do you try to invite to
product reviews? Do you have any
frameworks and ways of thinking of
who to invite, who not to invite?
Yeah, good question. We, I would say have
oscillated over time, but in general,
big subscribers of the best conversations
happen when they're relatively small,
so try and keep it under 10. Could be wide
distribution of the document. The artifacts
created are actually really powerful and they're
powerful for the whole team to understand. And
secret power is they're very powerful for
new people who are onboarding to be like,
here are the last 20 product reviews, you'll
get a pretty good idea of what's going on. But
generally the conversation itself try and be
relatively tight. We try to keep it under 10.
And these artifacts, you mean the recordings
of the meeting that people can watch or?
Yeah. Or just the document depends
on what the company culture is,
whether you want to record it or
just have the document either way.
And then is there some specific cadence you
operate on? Is it like a weekly product review
that people can sign up for? Does every team,
how do you like to set this up the cadence?
Yeah, obviously it scales are with the
size of the company. For us right now,
what's working well is signup cadence.
We have two slots a week that anyone can
sign up for as their product area needs
it. And then if there's something that
we would love to see that we haven't seen in
a bit, we do a little bit of all in telling
to make sure that the work is generally
cycling through on a quarterly basis.
This episode is brought to you by Attio. A
radically new type of CRM. There's a world
where your CRM is powerful, easily configured,
and deeply intuitive. Attio makes that a reality.
Attio is built specifically for the next era
of companies. It syncs with your data sources,
easily configures to their unique structures and
works for any go-to-market motion from self-serve
to sales led. Attio automatically enriches
your contacts, syncs your email and calendar,
gives you powerful reports and lets you quickly
build Zapier style automations. The next era of
companies deserves more than an inflexible one
size fits all CRM. Join modal, replicate 11 labs,
and more, and scale your startup to the next
level. Head to attio.com/lenny and you'll get 15%
off your first year. That's A-T-T-I-O.com/lenny.
Adjacent topic. I hear you're a big fan of drops
to be done, which is okay, so it's a fun recurring
topic on this podcast. We've had many people that
love it, many people that hate it. I love seeing
both sides of it. I love that you find it helpful
and you implement it at Opendoor. I'd love to
hear just how you actually apply it at Opendoor,
what you've learned about how to
apply jobs to be done effectively.
Yeah. I think like all frameworks, the right
answer is to pick your set of frameworks,
have more tools in your toolbox, and then
actually understand when and how to apply them. So
we try to avoid being a hammer and everything's
a nail. We try to for course the framework if
it's not working. But I think what I really like
about it is it forces you to put yourself in the
customer's shoes. I think in a slightly deeper way
and be a little bit more empathetic when I think
about building at Opendoor versus say building
at Uber or when you are building at Airbnb is
we are not... Most people at Opendoor, we don't
have homes to sell every week or every month,
nor do we buy homes every week or
every month. On average in the US
is something people do once every seven years.
I'm sure the average at Opendoor is something
similar, and so it's a little bit harder to be
a customer. I took Uber every day. You probably
use Airbnb a number of times a year. And so
in some sense for some of those companies,
you can bill for yourself, you would intuit
the job to be done because you're just doing
it for yourself. We don't necessarily have that
context. And so a framework that forces us to be
really thoughtful and intentional about how a
customer might perceive our product is really
helpful. The other thing that I like about it
is the canonical version of it encourages you
to think about the context in which the user's
operating or the other things outside of your
product that they might be going through.
And in our case, the home buying or selling
journey often is a certainly multi-week, if not
multi-month or multi quarter journey with a lot
of complexity and a lot of conversations outside
of our product. You may be talking to an agent,
you may be talking to a friend, you may be driving
around the city trying to find a house, and the
framework is very flexible and encouraging of
saying what is actually the job to be done of this
user when they're thinking about our product and
what is the context in which they're operating.
I'd love to go one level deeper to talk about
how you actually implement it. Do you have
templates of, you have a startup project as
a blank, I blank, blank, blank? How do you...
I would say we're medium rigorous on template
standardization or adherence. So we do have a
template, the standard product review
template talks about jobs to be done
and has a section for what is the problem
statement and what are the jobs to be done.
And this is a doc that when
you're coming to a product review,
the person running it and coming
is filling out this document?
Correct, pre-filling it up, sorry, pre-filling it
out. And again, I think we are not sticklers about
always using that template, but I think the beauty
of a template is yes, it sets expectations of what
you expect, but it's also just easier often for
people to be able to work off something. And so
yeah, it's part of our product review template
and then part of our planning process as well.
Because we've used it for a while. I think
there's been an internalization of the culture
where people will also just start commenting
about it or writing about it and saying, hey,
what is the job to be done here? Or what is
the user trying to do? Which is maybe another
colloquial phrase in it. And so, yeah, I think
there's a cultural seeping that has happened.
From memory, just what is in this template. So
what's the phrasing that you try
to use for setting up a problem?
Yeah, yeah. I mean, the specific framing,
I would have to go remind myself on the template
itself, but generally it looks like context,
problem, potential solution, risks,
risks/premortal and measurement of success.
And then we also try to bucket our product reviews
by stage. So you could be in the ideation stage,
which might look very different than at the very
end of the process. Like, Hey, we're getting
ready to ship speak now forever hold your piece.
Those two artifacts will also be very different.
Okay. So it's not as a blank the
standard jobs to be done language,
it's not exactly how you implement it's
more just make sure we're thinking of it
what is the problem for the customer?
What is the context of their problem?
Correct. Yeah. Yeah, we're
not math living our template.
Okay, awesome. Any other tips or lessons about
just working well with this concept of jobs to be
done? Maybe when you come into Opendoor and like,
hey everyone, we're going to be thinking this way.
Is there anything there that would be useful to
people if they're trying to operate this way?
Recognizing that correctly implementing a
framework, any framework, but if you don't in
particular, we can talk about takes a little bit
of time and getting used to and understanding. And
so I don't think you can just like, okay, we're
going to make the template and then that makes the
content better. That just takes people's content
and they wedge it into the template. It's actually
the cultural internalization of like, hey, this
might be phrased as the job to be done, but is
this actually the job to be done? Let's talk about
why the customer might be in that situation or
not be in that situation. Or I think the job
to be done might actually be something else.
Or you might say, hey, the job to be done is
maybe an early day version would be the job to
be done is to get an offer from Opendoor. And it's
like, well kind of, but the broader job to be done
might be price discovery for the customer. And so
you can have a rich conversation where it's like,
well, one might be a little bit influenced
by our business goals. I don't think you
just run around and people are like, yeah,
I'm going to sell my house, but my goal is
to get an offer from Opendoor. And so that's
like, okay, the template might be the same,
but it's actually the content that takes
a little bit of cultural instantiation.
Got it. And it sounds like people talk
from what is the job to be done that feels
like a core part of the way you think
about it. What is the job to be done?
Just that language alone feels really powerful.
Is there a resource or a book that you point
people to help your team learn about the jobs to
be done work? Is there one thing you find useful?
Not about jobs to be done. I do a lot
more pointing people towards internal
examples of where I saw other PMs maybe do
as well or blogs and stuff. But your blog
is a column when we pass around, not about
jobs to done, but just about many topics.
I'm flattered. Thank you.
Yes.
I really appreciate that. I was
also thinking as you were talking,
you're friends with Kayvon and jobs to be done
on Twitter was quite the journey for them,
traumatic for a lot of people. I think
it went very far to the extreme of the-
Yeah. I think they're more dogmatic about it.
Very dramatic. And so I guess it's a
lesson here, maybe don't take it that far.
Yeah. And I think it probably, and I don't
know if Kayvon would agree with this,
I imagine he would, the generalized
version of you pick the right framework
for the right job and if you say there's
one framework to rule them all and this
is the only framework that works and then of
course every problem into it, then we chop.
The way I think about jobs to be done is
exactly the way you're describing it where
it's just think from the lens of the job to be
done for our customers. So for my newsletter,
what is the job to be done of my newsletter
to help you become better at your job as a
product person building product. And
that actually ends up being really
helpful. And it feels like that's the
way you guys think about it at opening.
Yeah, absolutely. And you're
crushing it by the way.
Thank you. So are you. You talked about, I'm
going to go into another question to deflect
your compliment. You mentioned that Uber, there's
a million transactions happening every second,
it's massive scale. Opendoor is completely
different. You have very few very large
transactions. Yeah. I'm curious how you do
experiments, if you do experiments, do you do
A/B tests? What have you learned about just how to
think through low sample sizes plus A/B testing?
Yeah, very hot topic of conversation. We do A/B
test. It is obviously the gold standard. And so
we do as much as we can. Of A/B testing there are
parts of our funnel and flow that have more volume
than others. So top of quality testing easier than
down funnels, A/B testing purely product or tech
features easier than A/B testing processes,
operational processes. But you're totally
right. We are not doing hundreds of millions of
transactions a year. And so experimentation can
be more challenging. And so I think one way to
think about it is A, acknowledge the problem,
which just to say don't, and we've made this
mistake many, many times, but don't just force
yourself into A/B testing without running
the power analysis and say like, hey, are we
going to get results? What is the size that will
detect and what is the runtime of that experiment?
And be honest, is that acceptable? A second
lesson here, is there certain experiments
that are important enough and it's hard to
triangulate signal in any other way that you may
say a six-month runtime is an acceptable outcome
and we are going to start it in June and we will
be smarter for it for 2025 planning and we're
going to set it and forget it and we're grateful
we did, and that's okay. But the only mistake here
is thinking you'll get an answer in a month when
you won't, and then pretending you do and then
waking up a month later and being like, "Well,
it was insignificant and this and that." We could
have known that. And then the third thing is,
and experimentation is all about increasing your
conviction in the problem or the solution. So the
generalized version of the statement is, if
there are parts of your funnel or flow that
are low end and you can't run a canonical A/B
test, how might you otherwise increase your
conviction in the solution that you're building?
And there turns out there are a decent number
of other ways to do that. The first best, most
obvious is talk to more customers. But there are
other statistical techniques that again, aren't as
rigorous or good, but may be possible. You may be
able to use observational data, you review with
diff and diff, you may be able to look at sister
cities or twin cities. You may be able to segment
by geo, you may be able to reduce your power and
say, hey, we're going to run at 80% confidence for
all of our experiments instead of this traditional
95% because that's a worthy trade-off. And if
we're wrong one more time out of 10, that's okay.
You can do a long-term holdout to match
your intuition. And so there's a lot of
other techniques to hone your intuition. There's
a lot of other techniques to build conviction and
confidence. And so we try to be very creative
on doing that. And then the last bit I would
say is if you're not going to get significance, if
there's no other techniques at your disposal, then
sometimes you just got to trust your intuition
and ship it. And if that's what you believe,
then that's what you believed and you shouldn't
spend time trying to get false precision.
I want to spend more time on that last point,
but real quick, the power analysis you
talked about, there's people, don't know,
there's calculators out there that you could just
plug in, here's how much traffic I'm getting,
here's how much of an impact difference I want
to see, here's how long it'll take to find out.
Yep, exactly. Totally. And some of the calculators
are great where you can also plug in the traffic
and your acceptable runtime and it will tell
you the minimum detectable impact and then you
can gut check your own intuition.
So you can play around with that.
Awesome. We'll try to link to one of those in
the show notes. So, on the intuition piece,
is there anything more there? Just like how
you think about when you run the product team,
just how you recommend people leverage intuition
versus not. Because some companies are like,
we're just going to trust the data. I don't
really trust your opinion. You don't know
this customer exactly. You talked about
Opendoor, I'm not buying houses myself,
so I don't know how much I can trust my
intuition. Just what's your general advice
to your product team of how to think about their
intuition and when to rely on it versus not?
So, at Opendoor, for example, I'd say on the
relative spectrum, we're quite data-driven. And
then it's when we come into this challenge where
we say, okay, that is another technique or tool
in the toolbox. I think the generalized
version of that is customers, products,
people can surprise you. And so this happens all
the time for people who build products. I'm sure
you've got great stories from Airbnb where you
saw something, put it out there just was very-
All the time.
All the time. And so I think there's definitely
a humility to say if you can, if it's relatively
easy to test your assumptions or test your
hypotheses. That is always better to gut check
yourself. And that takes a little bit of humility
to say that, but we've all been wrong plenty of
times. But if that's just not on the table, I
think the reality is you can't pretend it is. And
sometimes you got to use taste and judgment and
then you say, okay, what is my conviction level
and do I have just medium, low or high conviction?
And if I have anything low or medium conviction
and it's a decision of consequence, I should talk
to more customers, check it with another person
and see if their intuition matches. Something that
gets me personally to the high bucket category.
And then I think the last part, which is some
part of experimentation is if you just ship
something because it's your intuition or
it's where you want to see the product go,
do you have a reasonable feedback loop to
understand whether or not you are correct?
So that could be customer support or ticket
volume or feature adoption, whatever the case is,
it may not be an output metric in the traditional
A/B test, but some more rigorous system that
says, hey, I had this hypothesis, we just
shipped it for x, y, z constraint reason for red.
I think that's awesome advice. I agree with
everything you're saying. You mentioned this
word humility, and it is a good segue
to something I want to talk about,
which is Zillow. One of the most interesting
things that's happened in your space is Zillow
basically decided, hey, we're just going to
do what Opendoor is doing, they launched it,
you're basically frenemies for a while, and
then they're like, no, it's not working. Now
you partner and now you work with Zillow on
this stuff. So are you able to share what went
down there with the story of what happened,
how it went, and where things are at now?
Yeah, I mean we do partner with Zillow.
Zillow's been a fantastic partner for us
and we've really enjoyed a working relationship
with them. I think when you think about it,
they have tremendous amount of reach and audience
and all these online platforms have tremendous
reach and audience. And we happen to have a fairly
unique selling solution. And so there's a nice,
not to use a business school word, but
there's a nice synergy so to speak,
between a high intended audience who's
doing a lot of browsing and searching and
discovery and starting their process on one
of these online platforms and what we offer,
which is transaction services that allow
people to actually move particularly on
the seller side. And so there's just a pretty
nice symbiotic relationship there with the
Zillow's and the regimens of the world. And so
both of those have been great partners for us.
What do you think Zillow maybe
underestimated or didn't get
about the space that made it harder than they
anticipated? That seems obvious. Of course,
let's go down funnel, let's just
do it all. And they're like, "Oh,
shit, not working." What do you think they
didn't get or what do you think they missed?
I guess continuing on the humility point, I
won't necessarily pretend to be in their shoes,
but I will say the business is challenging
and it's complex from a number of different
dimensions. It's not a traditional software
only product, but you have to be really good
at pricing. You have to be really good at product,
you have to be really good at the operations. You
have to be really disciplined at risk. You have
to be really good in the capital markets. And so
you have to put all of these functions together
to build a vertically integrated product. And
that's the reality. And so that is something
that's been in Opendoor's DNA from day one
because we started with a vertically integrated
product. And so we can't deliver unless we have
all of those things. Right? And so I think that's
something that continues to help us to this day,
is that vertical integration requires
all of those pieces coming together.
That makes a lot of sense, and I think it's a
good reminder of there are adjacent markets and
businesses that always feel like, "Oh, we could
expand to that someday." Such a big opportunity,
this business could be so much bigger. And then
you realize your business is completely not set
up to operate this way. Zillow is very software
driven, just I am not going to simplify what
they do, but it's a website, very software.
And obviously as we talked about Opendoor,
a huge operational component. And then as you
said, the pricing piece and the debt stuff.
Yeah. Yeah, totally. Yeah.
Yeah. So I think it's a really good reminder
that just when you're taking on something
completely different, it may not fit into the
way your company operates and partnering makes
sense. Anything else there that's interesting
to share around the Zillow thing? I guess one
is maybe it was just like, I imagine it was
very stressful. Zillow's getting into it. "Oh,
shit what are we going to do? They got
all the traffic." Yeah, anything there?
Yeah. I mean, it's certainly stressful. I think
in general we try to live by whether Zillow or
anybody else being competition aware, but not
necessarily competition focused. And the reality
is vast, vast in our space. A vast majority of
people still move the traditional way. And so
this isn't something where it's like the size of
the prize isn't particularly large enough short
or anything like that. The reality is it's the
largest asset classroom in the United States,
and if we just stay super focused on, hey, who
are the customers that we serve really well that
we talk to every day, there's a little
bit of confidence that comes from being
able to stay focused on that regardless of
the competitive environment, again, because
it's not like the market is fully saturated.
This is the same thing back in the Uber days
as well. It's like transportation is
almost infinitely large. And so, yes,
it feels like there's heated competition between
Uber and Lester or whatever back in the day,
but the reality is there's plenty of
trips that happens and people need to
get around sitting in plenty of different
ways. That's neither Uber and more Lyft.
And staying focused on how you can develop for
your customer, I think is the best way to focus.
There's a podcast that will come
out before this episode with Jeff
Weinstein from Stripe who's building Stripe
Atlas. They had a similar experience with
AngelList launched a direct competitor
to Atlas, and then they realized Atlas
is so much better. Forget it. We're
just going to send everyone to Atlas.
Really?
Yes. And I think it's the same exact lesson that
if you just stay focused on jobs to be done,
let's say, of what is the job to be
done and do the best possible job,
and knowing that the market is much bigger, that
you're not really competing with someone else,
another company, it's the default behavior
in your case. It's like people are just
buying their house the old-fashioned
way. That's the actual competition.
Exactly. Yep.
Yeah. Okay. So, along these lines, something
else I've heard that you're very good at is
staying very calm under pressure and
staying very levelheaded when things
are really crazy. This is something
that a lot of people are not good at,
especially leaders. They stress
everyone out things. You go crazy,
they don't create a good vibe. And then two,
something people want to get better. Leaders and
non-leader are like any lessons, anything you've
learned about just how to develop this skill?
I think part of this may have been sharpened
in the early days of Uber. Everything felt
like a fire drill all the time. So the only way
to operate, but I think you almost hit the nail
on the head in the question, which is a little
bit of an intellectual answer of when you reflect
the stress onto your teams, everybody tenses up
and tightens up. And so it counterintuitively
doesn't produce better outcomes. And so I
think the other reality to remind ourselves,
and these are a bunch of mantras that
just are helpful in these moments,
is you're never as good as you think you are.
You're never as bad as you think you are. And
so that more even keeled demeanor, I think allows
you to have a clearer head when you're operating
under the pressure and to think more clearly.
I think one of the maybe least helpful answers,
but unfortunately, the reality is you got to be
in some stressful situations to also have the
perspective that cycles past the things past. And
that remaining calm is what matters. And so maybe
the advice there is reflecting on one of these
situations happen, exposing yourself to them,
not running from them and then learning from them
so that the next time it comes around you can say,
Hey, I've been here before. I've slept on the
floor in China before launching uberPOOL and
thinking we're going to miss a launch deadline.
And what were the tools in my toolbox and my
toolkit that showed me that in terms of getting
it done or not, and what were the lessons?
I love that. So part of it is just go through this
experience many times and you'll start to realize,
okay, it's not actually going to be as
bad as people may think. You mentioned
this toolkit instead of tools. Is
there anything else there that you
come back to that ends up being helpful?
You mentioned this mantra of it's never
as bad as people think it is, it is
never great as people think it is.
Yeah, I mean, I think exposing yourself to
other people's stories or however you may learn
is really, really helpful. So again, whether it's
your podcast or books or biographies or one of the
podcasts that I love is Founders Podcast, which
talks about historical famous entrepreneurs. And
obviously these are elevating very famous people
already, but there's a lot to learn from a lot of
these stories as well and understanding
that the journey in pack is nonlinear,
it never is for anybody. And so I think being able
to expose yourself to other stories that even may
if you don't have those personal experiences
and then understanding how others navigate.
Got it. So just hearing of other people's crazy
experiences and building on this muscle of like,
okay, they've gone through
crazy stuff, things work out.
Yeah, totally.
We'll make it through. Okay. I have
this note here that I think either
someone mentioned about you or you may
have mentioned that product is finding
the kernel of truth in a sea of ambiguity
and signals. Does that mean anything to you?
Yeah, absolutely. I mean, I think in most
organizations and to do the job effectively,
you're going to get signals from everywhere and
good ideas come from everywhere. It may be your CS
team or CX team. It may be a customer directly. It
may be a conversation you had. It may be a YouTube
video you watched that sparked an idea. It may be
feedback from an executive, it may be whatever.
You went out and did a field visit. You are
going to get a lot of inputs around what people
think about your product, what people think you
should do next. And I think that the core job is
to understand what really matters, right? What is
noise? What is a good idea, what is a suggestion
and what is back to the jobs to be done for what
is really going to move the customer forward?
And unfortunately that means saying no to maybe
what sounds like some good ideas along the way,
but if you can really figure out this is
really what matters, that's the core part
of the job. It dovetails even back to our earlier
conversation. In the early days of building tech
and ops companies is where's the tech leverage?
Same question, where's the kernel of what really
matters that tech can uniquely solve? And
let's go do that and be comfortable with
other fires maybe burning. That's what really,
really, really matters. It's a hard discipline.
I love that. If there's not an
example, that's totally fine,
but when you talk about this finding this
kernel where tech could be highly leveraged,
is there any example that comes to
mind of that working out really well?
I mean, I think back in the Uber
days, I think it was like, hey,
we're not going to build sophisticated tooling
infrastructure. We're not going to build a
centralized growth team. We're not going to build
any of that. Because if you think about the early
Uber network from the simplest form, you've got a
rider and a driver and you need to connect them,
price the transaction and issue some receipts
probably and collect payment. So it's like, okay,
do we do that really well? And until we do that
really well, all the other stuff is noise. It's
immaterial how efficiently we answer support
tickets. That's not critical. And so now it's
super critical, but in the early days it's not
that critical. And even the customer acquisition
costs may not be super critical, in this case it's
growing rapidly on the things. And so pouring fuel
on the fire may not be super efficient there.
So I think that's a very good generalized
example. One other tip that maybe is helpful
that I frankly constantly work on and try to
get better at is all these ideas and feedback
that comes from everywhere, make sure it's
written down for a number of reasons. One, you
can then go reference it, but two, part of the
job is making sure the people who present those
ideas are heard and respected and know that it's
at least somewhere where it was considered.
And then you can look at it all and say,
okay, but what actually really, really, really,
really matters here? And yeah, that's another tip.
When you say written down, is there tools
you find really helpful here? Is it just
put it in a big doc that we're keeping? Is there
anything you find to actually operationalize that?
I've seen different companies do it differently,
but wherever you tend to try and keep a backlog,
whether that's a Google sheet or your
actual backlog in Jira, whatever you use,
but at least it feels like, okay, the
context was captured, and the idea is there.
Awesome. Okay. I'm going to take us to a recurring
segment on this podcast called Failure Corner.
Okay.
Is there a story you can share of a time
you failed in your career had a big failure,
and how that experience made you better?
We can talk about the very early days
of uberPOOL, and the first launch,
if you will in San Francisco. So, carpooling
product, multiple riders in a Mercedes car. And
we had this idea that it would be effective for
commuters, this was very, very early days. And so
part of the launch was, okay, we're going to beta
it with just some popular commuting corridors with
specific companies or maybe the marina to Google
or whatever and try and match people according to
what their companies and that's how we'll drive
liquidity. And we very quickly realized that back
to what the kernel of truth is here is liquidity
is the only thing that matters. And there just
wasn't enough. There was never going to be enough
to do this company based thing. That wasn't the
strategy that was going towards from us. And so
the reason I don't know if it's a full failure is
maybe this is true all failures, you learn from
it, you pivot and you go on to the next thing.
And obviously we did that and then spent a lot
of our time and effort trying to say, okay,
what are the bounds of liquidity and driving
liquidity that we can do to understand what
the most important or what the limits of the
product are. So as an example, we launched and
maybe people in San Francisco. Remember this $5
anywhere in San Francisco, we work for promotion,
which is obviously a great deal, obviously costs
a lot of money, but the whole idea here is like,
oh, okay, if liquidity is what really matters, if
we were to juice that and really drive liquidity,
how high can our metrics get? And then we can
go chase more sustainable ways to do that. But
it was a interesting fail case from launching and
learning to say, hey, this initial strategy just
isn't going to work, we got to go. And any part
of it was a hedging strategy where with a small
audience and there'll be a beta population,
it's like, well, this one you just got to go.
I think a lesson there is also don't overthink
it, don't try to get too cute. Just like
we're trying to make a perfect
beta test versus realizing, okay,
we just need a lot more people in it.
Also, your $5 promotion made me think of
the early promotions of the ice cream and
the bunnies delivery and all that stuff.
Yeah. That was by the way, a example of fully
distributed, the benefit of having those early
Petri dishes. Someone a local marketing manager
like, Hey, this would be fun. Yeah, that would be
really fun. The platform can support it. And those
promotions were fantastic. And it started out,
I can't remember if the first one was ice cream
or puppies, I think it was ice cream. But yeah,
branched into all sorts of stuff. Boats,
ice cream, puppies, kittens, I think,
and all credit goes to local ideas of inspiration
just being focused on trying to grow within.
I love that we've circled back to the beginning
of our conversation, product and ops working
together, the benefits of both. Before we
get to a very exciting lightning round,
is there anything else that you wanted to
share? Any last nuggets of wisdom that you
think might be useful to people when they're
trying to build product companies teams?
This was great. We covered quite
a bit of ground. I think the only,
I don't know if this is a generalized wisdom,
but something I've been thinking about as my
career has progressed a little bit, especially
building out proper organizations, especially
as more tools come online, it's very clear that
there's different types of PMs and we spent a
lot of time talking about once we can operate
in the physical and the digital or the product
and operations worlds. But even within that,
there's more technical PMs who grew up in minute
engineering discipline. There are people who came
from ops and there are people who came from design
and grew up in a more user experience background.
And one thing that I've been moved on as is build
out the team is thinking similar to a product
roadmap is it's not really about is this person
good or bad or whatever, it's is this person's
skillset and context to the problem that is really
needed. And so back to that conversation on, hey,
where do we get tech leverage? It's like, Hey,
is this person who has this unique skillset
as a PM for this problem type? I don't know
if that's helpful, but it's something I've
been spending a lot of time thinking about,
especially this view job posting niche view
product manager. Or it's actually like, well, how
can we be a little bit more thoughtful about what
the actual skillset needs off this type of team?
Awesome. It's like a person product fit.
There you go.
And I think it's because a lot of companies
hire generalists and they're just like,
we'll hire someone smart, ambitious, and
with experience and general experience and
then we'll put them on different things. So
I think these are two different philosophies
and it probably makes a lot of sense
for an Opendoor with very unique type
of business, with very specific skills that
are necessary to be really good there. Okay,
amazing. Brian, with this, we've reached our
very exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
Let's do it. Can't wait.
Let's do it. First question,
what are two or three books
that you've recommended most to other people?
Shoe dog, Black Swan, Design of Everyday
Things, and for a fun one, Shawn Theron.
Amazing. Four books for the
price of two to three. I love it.
Apologies. I'll stick to the rules.
No, no, there's no rules. There are no rules.
There you go.
Next question, do you have a favorite recent
movie or TV show that you've really enjoyed?
I like the sports docu ones
on Netflix, so Full Swing,
Drive to Survive, Break Points,
tennis, golf, F1, all of them.
And wasn't there that Nike
documentary recently with Ben Affleck?
There is, which I have not seen. So
if it's good, I don't know if that's
a recommendation or just an acknowledgement.
It's worth watching. If you like Shoe
Dog, I feel like you'd enjoy it. It
was entertaining Michael Jordan,
things like that. Next question,
do you have a favorite product that you have
recently discovered that you really love?
So we just got a puppy and we are about to have
our first child. And so all of my purchases
recently are puppies and children focused. My
buddy gifted us the Phi collar for our dog,
and so we've been really enjoying that.
Another one as I'm getting busier for
news and stuff is Particle, which is a
great news aggravation tool, AI news tool.
Cavan's wife's business. I am a huge fan, actually
I think it just came out of beta and now it's
like a full app that anyone can download. I just
actually installed it yesterday again and I love
it. I get these pushes every few... I don't know,
it's like a couple of times a day of just like,
here's what's happening. Also, congratulations
I should have said on your pending child.
Thank you.
Lucky for you. I have a newsletter post
with all the products you should buy,
it's called New Parent Gift
Guide for Product Managers.
Love it. I will definitely
probably buy all of them.
If you don't already have them
all. And now everyone's probably
sending you their spreadsheets of
all their favorite stuff there.
Exactly.
Okay, next question. Do you have
a favorite life motto that you
often come back to share with
people either in work or life?
Well, mostly just stay curious.
Stay curious. I love it. Two more questions. Who
has most influenced you in
the course of your career?
One of the people who inspired me very early on
in my product journey. I've been fortunate to
have a number of very good mentors and obviously
we talked about earlier while I was founders of
books or me a lot from other people's journey.
But one person who was personally important to
me early in my product journey and very supportive
of this guy named Jeff Holden, who was the chief
product officer at Uber back in the day, and
is like a young PM transferring into product
really took me under his wing. And I
think I'm forever grateful for that,
for Jeff, for helping grow my career,
but also try to pay it forward a little
bit in terms of people who are going in the
career. That was really meaningful for me.
Last question. I hear that your interview at
Uber was pretty wild. Can you tell that story?
Yeah, I can. So, long story short, I
was starting a company my senior spring
before graduation and we had to go our separate
ways. So I hadn't done traditional recruiting
ever. And my buddy called me up and was like,
"Hey, we're looking for smart, hardworking people
at this Uber thing. Are you interested?" And quick
side note, I had actually done some very early
diligence work on these taxi apps back in 2011,
looking at the time was Uber Cab and Cabilis and
Taxi Manage can probably names nothing these
days. And so I knew what Uber was and so I said,
"Yeah, sure, I would love to." And so I
had the first round of interview went well,
and they said, great. And at that stage is
come on onsite, the full enchilada one works,
and this was post-graduation and was helping out
some companies but didn't have a full-time job.
So I said, hey, I'm pretty flexible. How about
next Tuesday? I said, great. So we scheduled it
and then on Friday or Saturday or over the
weekend I looked, I'm like, oh, Tuesday's,
July 4th. I scheduled my interview for July
4th. And so I called my buddy and I'm like,
hey, I am so sorry. I don't want to make people
in on July 4th. Should I cancel? Should I reach
out? Everyone's accepted. Whatever you do, do
not cancel your interview. Like, okay, I'll be
there on July 4th. And so I went in to the office
on July 4th and there was a very small handful of
people there. It was actually launching that day,
was launching Uber's second ever product type,
which was Uber SUV. And I had this, I think it was
probably five hour gauntlet interview on July 4th
from noon to five and missed my July 4th barbecue.
And it was quite the experience, but I think maybe
set the stage for some of the early days chaos.
I'm very glad I didn't cancel the interview.
And was Travis involved in
that interview or is it just-
Travis was involved in the interview. She
was one of the... I think there were four
or five people, and the two who were generally
guiding my interview process and Travis and one
other person starting that day. And part of the
gauntlet interview was a simulation of the job,
if you will. And so some of that was building
some novels on the computers and some of it
was writing potential emails to drivers and if
she had the driver come in and you did chat,
so I was in this room by myself typing away on
the first part, which was building the model.
And I hear him knock on the door and Travis
comes in and he just sits down and says, "Hi,
I'm Travis." I don't know who you are, but
I'm Brian, and we have a 45-minute chat,
or maybe it's been about half hour, 45
minutes. And clearly I'm not producing the
work that I'm supposed to of the interview.
I'm supposed to be building this model. I'm
supposed to email it back to the person who
sent it to me. Clearly I've done nothing
chatting with the CEO. And I hear a knock on the
door and the door opens and the person sees that
I'm talking to Travis, "Oh, continue,
continue" and it was very good. Also,
pretty intense conversation with Travis that
definitely set the expectations working there.
And clearly worked out. And
Travis was happy. Is what-
I hope so.
... I imagine.
Yes.
Amazing. Brian, thank you so much for being
here. We went through everything that I was
hoping to get through. Two final questions. Where
can folks find you online, and is there anything
you want them to check out that you might be
up to? And how can listeners be useful to you?
Super kind. They can find me online on
Twitter, LinkedIn, both just Brian Tolkin,
my name. In terms of being useful, if
you have a home to sell, feel free to
go on to Opendoor. More importantly,
if you have feedback on the product,
but would love to hear it. Otherwise, any feedback
on what people liked or would love to learn more
about from what we chatted about would be
super great. So I'd love to hear from you.
Brian, thank you so much for being here.
Lenny, I really appreciate it.
This was great. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to the show
on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.