wow I didn't I didn't realize there was actually a campfire here this is very cozy hello everyone so I'm going to gaze into the haze here and ask for some
audience participation because the title of my uh talk is How to Win Friends and Influence decisions so first how many of you have had to influence decision in
the last week or tried to influence a decision so back in my previous Life as a design leader I really thought that that my job was to influence you know
design is about storytelling it's about trying to have everyone else see what the future is and Influence People towards it then I thought you know one day if I become a founder and I've got
my own company I could just tell people what to do then it turns out I did that and in fact I actually have to influence more than ever so all of you who think your
job you're going to get out of the job of influencing unfortunately I'm here to tell you that is not the case but since I have you all here and you are an amazing group of very
talented senior experienced product leaders I'm going to ask for your help you see I have a prior prioritization
question and I've got three options for what our incredible team here should do behind door number one we've got an
INF for rewrite which the engineers have been clamoring for door number two all the designers are saying our onboarding experience really sucks and so we got to
we got to redo it and behind door number three our CEO has been talking to all of their other founder friends and gen AI is the thing we got to add a new
feature so friends how many of you think we should do the reite show up hands I can tell which of you have
an engineering background from from this okay redesign the onboarding experience all right all right how about that
differentiated gen feature we've been inspired by Claire's talk from before how many of you know that I'm about to lead with a fourth slide that
tells you guys this is really not the question so yes um you know what it is pretty hard to prioritize something like this I
feel like I'm constantly every single week in discussions that sound similar to to that and the reality of course is it's hard because there's so many
variables and all sorts of questions and things that come into every single prioritization decision so we're going to put that aside for now what I want to
talk about in this talk is actually what is a good process that we can take that gets us from look I have a strong opinion because I'm sure many of you
here probably did have an inkling and in all of your influence and prioritization decisions you probably do have a strong opinion how do we get from that to that
opinion actually shapes us towards a better outcome so this going to be a simple foolproof five-step process
ready so Step One is very simple let us draw a circle
so do it with me now let draw draw a circle what do I mean by that well I love this story and this quote this bet un quote because I think
it really encapsulates this picture which is when it's just me at home with my brother it's me against my brother but when my cousins come over it's me
and my brother against the cousins and then if the other neighborhood kids come on over and they're going to challenge us to something it's me my brother and
my cousins against that group what I love about this is it illustrates we get to choose where we draw the circle do we draw the circle
around ourselves is it I need to convince you that my idea here here is the right one or are we going to draw the circle more
broadly now no matter who it is that you are disagreeing with and you're on totally separate pages with and you're trying to convince your company there is a circle around you which is hey we all
work at this company and because we work at this company we all care about the company winning in fact if the company wins we hate our goals we make a lot of
money Rising tide lifts all boat and so there's always a way to draw a circle where now it is you and the person in the circle against whatever it
is that is the problem or the goal and so the lines that you can use here is just always always always start with that always start with look what we
really want is to make sure that we make a great product that our customers love so now let's talk about the various ideas or it is just really important
that we can achieve our Revenue targets because otherwise we're not going to get that roundout of funding or whatever terrible thing is going to happen so let's Orient around how we're going to
best do that and I think it's so important it's not just these lines it's the mentality that we have if you go into a meeting thinking I need to convince this person I'm right you've
just drawn the circle around yourself but if you go in and you say okay we're both in the circle together a lot of this becomes so much more natural and easy
and the energy I promise you is going to be different step number two so we drawn in the circle step number two assume that
everyone is seeing the truth what do I mean by that so this is a story that I think about and I kid you not I think about this probably three
times a week which is the parable of the Five Blind Men and the elephant and so the story goes there are five Blind Men and they saunter into the woods and they
encounter an elephant for the first time and so each of them is like this is our opportunity we can really get to know this elephant so the first man says he goes up and touches the elephant he say I
know what an elephant is the elephant is rough and hard like a like a tree tree trunk and then the second blind man goes
up and he touches elephant he's like you are totally wrong totally wrong the elephant feels like leather and third blind man goes and
like you guys are both ridiculous the elephant is like a rope I actually forgot what the fourth and fifth Blind Men said but I think you get the gist of the
story now all of us who are blessed with eyesight we can see you know what they're all right they are all seeing some version of the
elephant because the ear is like leather and the legs are like a tree trunk and the tail is like a rope but it's also the case that none of them are
completely right they all see truth but they don't see the whole truth and whenever we disagree this is usually what is happening we're all seeing some
version of the truth but it's not put together in a way that lets us cohesively understand it and of course this is pretty obvious
because a lot of times look we do have different experiences we have different roles if you ask a designer to evaluate a piece of work they go straight to well what is the customer going to think is
it easy to understand does it feel aesthetically pleasing if you talk to a salesperson about the work they're going to go straight into like what does this mean for our Revenue targets everyone's
got a different perspective and it is often the product leader job to hold these different perspectives and to be able to see the truth that is
encapsulated in each of these different disciplines and of course it's not just again between product managers or product leaders you also see this right some team is trying to optimize for
growth and retention and some other team is trying to optimize for revenue and they're going to be at odds because sometimes the best thing for growth is not the best thing for Revenue but
instead of being like I got to convince them I got to convince them that they're wrong just acknowledge and put on the table the fact that we do see we all see
truth but we see a a version of it and it is our job to acknowledge that and to do our best to put these versions of the
truth together towards the greater good and I love just being able to acknowledge that in the in the beginning of what is likely going to be us discussing a different perspective right
look it really does seem like we see things differently and but we all have something valuable so let's just put that on a table or you can also sometimes you know call it out in advance hey so you are a
designer so you more easily can spot usability issues while I can more easily spot the places in which you know usability or pricing are going to come
into conflict but just acknowledge what everyone brings to the table and that helps them feel heard and helps them see okay now we're now we can now that we've realized that we all do see something
valuable we can more see everyone else's perspective so so far we've drawn the circle we have acknowledged that everyone sees some truth this is where
the fun part begins step three is let us be like detectives and uncover where each of us sees the
truth and I'm going to move straight to the lines that you can use because I think that these are two very very powerful questions so now that you and I are both
Al that we want us to provide a great customer experience while hitting our Revenue targets what would we have to both what would have to be true for us
to believe that we should do feature a or what would have to be true for us to generally agree that feature B matters
more another way of asking the question is if I am advocating for a and you know it and you are advocating for B is to ask a question of hey well if you're
advocating for B what would convince you that a is actually better for the goal that we both aligned on in the beginning so let's go back to those
questions we had at the beginning infer rewrite why might infer rewrite be actually the most important project for us to
tackle well if our performance is really degraded let's say we have a lot of customers and our performance has been degrading and we're very concerned that
if the performance doesn't get better our customers are going to churn that would be bad both you and I don't want churn and customers that would be a
disaster or let's say we're about to add we assume that we're going to do a big marketing push we're going to add a bunch of new customers and the product is so buggy that we're worried that we're not going to make a good impression and they're not going to
stick around that would be bad or maybe the reason is just simply it's so difficult to add new changes to our code base that all of our Engineers
are really upset and morale is horrible and they're all going to rage quit on us now again these are extreme examples but I think that actually talking about
the extremes is one tactic that brings everyone else along because we can always agree on the extremes and if we can agree on the extremes what we do is we start putting the prioritization
question as something on the table where we're on the same side and we're just trying to figure out what's the best balance right so okay let's agree on extremes that would both be bad if these
things happen we should do the info reite but what about redesigning onboarding well onboarding really matters if we're going to add a lot of new users is that true are we going to add a lot of new
users and it would matter if we were going to add a lot of new users and we somehow knew that our product is actually very good the product has product Market fit but somehow these new
users are not understanding how to get value out of the product that is where onboarding would really matter right and again reasonable people will likely you know I'm seeing many of you nod like yes
this is what we can agree on and finally what about a gen AI feature well if this new technology makes it 2x 3x 5x better for us to
deliver our value prop that would be awesome we should do that or if we don't do it and we're worried that all our customers are going to go to competitor because they're they're doing it and we
should probably prevent that as well so in this case again reasonable people will agree and this brings us very well to
the next point which is once you have these scenarios it's time to turn the problem into a data question so now that we've established
like in these extremes yes we can all agree we should do that the question becomes well are we in this scenario and the specific questions that I find
so powerful are just simply asking well how can we know it's really true that the degraded performance is going to cause a lot of our customers to turn or
what evidence do we have that this new janaa idea is going to be really well received in the market or
how can we quickly get signal on whether it is the case that most of our Engineers are so fed up with the terrible quality of our code base that
they're about to rage quit and once you start asking these questions I'm sure you know your your brain is already firing all of these different solutions oh let's go do a survey or let's go talk
to our customers oh let's go and and check that dashboard let's talk to the data scientist and and do an ad hoc analysis but once we all start asking these questions like what evidence do we
have we can quickly figure out how to get the answer and when I mean data I mean it very broadly right data is just any information that gives us a little bit more context as to the questions
that we have so could be quantitative could be talking to customer success or interviewing sales or just getting on a call with 10 customers or doing a
internal survey but all of that is going to help us with some of those scenarios that we were looking at before
so back to our examples we said look in for reite if the performance is degrading and are our customers are going to churn well how was our performance has it been getting worse
have we seen that correlate with churn and the customer base or have we pulled 20 customers and said hey how do you feel about the performance or how have
you felt about the bugginess of our of our experience as of late right lots and lots of ideas for how we could get a little bit more evidence again we should
also by the way if you're a startup maybe the fact that you don't have that many existing users means it doesn't matter that much if they churn because you're putting a lot more eggs into acquiring the next set of users but all
of these you know understanding where you're turn understanding how many users you have like what how many users do you expect to add how unhappy are Engineers this all give us evidence or data that
helps us become more clear about whether we are in scenario one or two or three similarly with onboarding good questions to ask are like well are we really adding a lot of
new users in the next quarter in the next six months and what is the current retention and maybe what are what's good retention look like for our our app in
the marketplace something we can ask our Venture capist what is the usage of these core features and is it true that if we manually walk users through the product and they get it
then they use it a ton versus when they don't you know through through the actual product experience um they don't right that makes a real case that onboarding is a great
lever and finally with adding differentiated AI you know have we done any quick experiments have we prototyped things have we used chat GPT to answer a bunch of these questions and see if it
actually dramatically helps us with the value prop of what we're trying to do have we gone and talked to Smart customer custers hey we got five ideas do any of these seem like they would
help you do your work or or uh achieve your goals more efficiently and also of course there's customer or there's market research just looking around asking around figuring out what else our
competitors doing and are we going to get left behind so lots of really great ways to get more insight get more data but I can see some of you thinking okay I got to
move really quickly who has time for all that and I agree with you because I work in data and I can tell you that data will never actually give you certainty as
much as we like to as much as uncertainty is uncomfortable we won't ever get the certainty the best that we can get is just a little more evidence a little
more insight at the end of the day most of the decisions including the biggest and most important decisions we're going to have to make on a leap of faith somebody has to make that decision and
so if you've gotten all the that you can get or maybe you can't get that much and you just have to move on the question you should ask yourself is okay maybe you and I still disagree right we got all the data we looked at
the evidence we're on the same page you know we drawn the circle but we still don't disagree what should we do and this is where it's time to move
the conversation up a level and make it a people question who is now the best person to make the call usually I find it is far easier for people to agree on
who's the best person to make the call than it is on what the specific decision might be now again if you're in a large orc there already may be naturally a chain of escalation and you can follow
that but you don't always have to follow it you know you can also say look you and I since we're now in the same Circle we we know that this person is really
deeply invested in the end goal and for this particular decision they have the best combination of context and skill both are important if you're going to
make a decision on what's the right new technical infrastructure do not ask me I don't have the experience to make that I could have all the context but I'll still probably make a bad decision
whereas um if even if somebody has the skill but they just don't they don't know they don't have the data they don't have the history the context they still may not be the best person to make thisis so you need both best combination
of context and skill now as a product leader what is so powerful about this is that you can actually Point towards and nominate the
person to make the call it doesn't have to be the same person that makes every decision in fact that would be suboptimal because no single person is the best at having the right context and
skill to make every decision so in certain cases this is where you can nominate hey this decision is a lot more about how we can improve um the the
technical infrastructure so for the product I nominate the enge leader or this this this particular initiative is much more about how we can improve the customer experience and I'm going to
nominate that in this case we should just listen to the design leader on on this you do not have to be the person who makes all the decisions or knows
what the answer is you have to just make sure the best decisions get made and one of your biggest lovers is getting better at identifying who is the best at making
which decision finally of course you want that person person to be clear D and calm they don't have a bone to pick they're not out for Revenge they're not so
stressed out about whatever it is going on that is the person who is ideally the candidate for making the call so here are some lines you
can use I know that founder mode is all the rage now so you just pull it out there guys we need a found remote this so I recommend I make the call it's also okay
to nominate yourself but make it so that everyone feels like they can share in the fact that we're all doing this again to drive the best
outcomes for our team so let's say you do all this okay you do all this you got the data you nominate a person and you still feel like ah we made the wrong
call what do you do are we are we done by the way all everything I've said so far it does not guarantee that you're going to get what you want all the
time but the game is not over because I'm a big believer that time eventually reveals more and more truth so what can happen is we did
everything but you're you're sure you're certain that this was the wrong call write that down write down document you know if you have a documentation culture it will be written
down but document hey three people didn't think we should do this and four people did and we nominated X person to make decision or you know our our VP as and and we made decision X but remember
who made what call and that way after one month or three months or six months
or a year go back and look at what happened did the decision bear fruit if yes there's a lot to learn from
that did the decision not bear fluit also a ton to learn from that but I think this is so important for us to have a practice of in fact what I like
to do is put a calendar invite for myself at these time frames so after we make a major call one month later I'll say go back and think about that decision we made three months later six
months right you will learn different things at different time frames because the story is evolving as we live life and so when you go back and you
watch your replays and you go back and evaluate what was the outcome of these decisions there's many many layers of what it is that you learn now the most obvious the ones that we end up talking
the most about as product people are well what did we learn about our customers and their needs and secondly what did we learn about our product and the levers you know is pricing a lever
is onboarding a lever is putting more power user features a lever for monetization or what whatever it is that we're trying to
drive but I want us to go further as well because Beyond those layers there's also the layer of hey are we actually measuring things in the right way are we
sure that we know what success looks like because metric goals can change and it's my experience having worked and and looked at you know the history of many
things that sometimes you think that what you have is a growth problem and it turns out over time it's a retention problem you you know what you learn is that retention matters more and once you
realize retention matters more over time you might refine that further retention of this particular customer segment matters more because they are the ones that actually lead the most to our
ability to monetize and and have like great uh monetization retention so how what we learn about the way that we measure success is a third layer right
um beyond that we can also learn how do we make decisions I love the previous talk because it was about that it was it was the learning is not necessarily
about what is the decision but how do we come together and do better product reviews how do we improve the decision-making process should we spend more time doing getting evidence or are
we are we repeating the same conversations over and over and we actually need to move a little faster right so there's a meta layer about how we make decisions and then finally and I think this is the most underrated what
did we learn about the quality of each person's individual ual judgment because at the end of the day thinking about influence is thinking about the people problem and the people
Dynamics so if your executive is making 10 decisions in a row about some Dimension it turns out over time he's wrong I hope the
conclusion that the entire company can come to is this person is not to be trusted on whatever it is that that they're making so this and you're not going to know this until you keep the score and
you continually go back and reflect and this is very important for the self as well right we like to go in we're product people we pride ourselves on having great judgment about what it
is with product and there are going to be areas where you have biases I have biases I guarantee it and we're not going to learn about that until we do
this over and over again so to recap we're going to start by drawing our Circle
we assume that we're all seeing parts of the truth like the Blind Men and the Elephant we're going to try and be like
detectives and together figure out where the truth applies in these extreme examples then we're going to see what evidence do we have right turn it into a
data question and if we don't have time to gather our data eventually turn it into a people question and finally we're going to continue to watch our replays
I want to end on a Zen Buddhist concept so this is a character called moo and literally it means nothingness
but in the Buddhist tradition it's meant to refer to this idea that sometimes the true answer the best
answer is much greater and vaster than the question that was originally posed it is often the case that the
question we're asking is too narrow of a question in this case we started out with prioritizing the info rewrite or
the onboarding or adding a differentiated AI feature but if you if you look into the future 3 months 6 months a year later
there actually many many possibilities for what a great outcome could look like perhaps we realize we need better instrumentation and measurement perhaps
we realize we should do all these it's more a matter of sequencing than if we should do these things perhaps we discover that actually wow once we dug into retention we realize we have a
retention problem and there's in fact 20 other ideas we have for how to improve retention maybe we came up with a better process for how we work together
a story that I think about a lot is that back in Facebook's history history things were going well they're growing growing growing viral social network until one day growth stopped and what Mark did was task a
small group of people to go and solve the growth problem get us back on track so that we can grow again and the team came up with a lot of ideas hypotheses tested and so
forth I don't remember what was the idea or the lever or the thing that they did that started growth again but I can tell
you the process that they uncovered the culture of growth the way that they became more data informed the framework
that they develop that turned out to blossom into a an incredible cultural set of practices that every single team at Facebook adopted and is still a core
part of what makes Facebook Facebook today that is the true gift that is the thing the gift that keeps on giving so in conclusion you know what
problems are going to come and go there's going to be a decision to make today tomorrow next year there's going to be tens of thousands of decisions that you're going to make and that your and your team are be together going to
make but relationships but the learnings the people the wisdom these things are forever these things are rare figuring out how to do that well and enjoy the
process with the people that you work with that is the truest gift I can think of nothing better than waking up every morning and just excited to come into work and solve problems with people we
like instead of feeling like it's a fight every day I think that is what we should be trying to optimize for thank you everyone
[Applause]