I'm curious what it is that PMs
do that annoy engineers most.
Hoarding credit. PMs, they tend to be
the front-facing person for initiative.
Engineers sometimes think that they don't
get the credit for their work because the PM
takes all the glory and all the credit for the
project that they really worked very hard on.
I find the best PMs are the
ones that talk the least and
encourage other people to do the presenting-
The next thing that engineers really
get annoyed about with PMs, when they
just don't understand the details and act like
they don't matter, it just shows a real lack of
empathy for the work that engineers are doing
and I think it really can be very off-putting.
Is there any insight you can
give about what people may
be missed about the motivation of
engineers, what gets them excited?
A lot of people assume that engineers
just write code and don't underestimate
the ability for your engineers to want
to understand the business problem,
want to understand the customer problem. I think
the product managers that have done the best,
they're not threatened by
other people having ideas.
Today, my guest is Camille Fournier. Camille is
one of the most respected technology executives
in tech and the author of the Manager's Path,
which many considered the definitive guide for
navigating your career and moving into management.
Over the course of her career, she was CTO of Rent
The Runway, VP of technology at Goldman Sachs,
global head of engineering and architecture at JP
Morgan Chase and head of platform engineering at
Two Sigma. She's also releasing a new book later
this year called Platform Engineering, A Guide
for Technical Product and People Leaders, which
you can actually pre-order today and we get into
this topic in the latter half of the conversation.
We also dig into what PMs do that most annoys
engineers and how to stop doing these things.
Why major rewrites are often a trap. Why you
may want to be doing fewer one-on-ones. What
most surprises people when they become a manager
and some really useful heuristics for how long
you should stay in IC before you make the
leap into management and tons more. This
episode covers a lot of ground and we'll help
you think about management. platform teams,
team culture and the PM and end relationship
in a whole new way. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in
your favorite podcasting app or YouTube.
It's the best way to avoid missing future episodes
and helps the podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you Camille Fournier. Camille, thank you
so much for being here, welcome to the podcast.
Thank you so much for having me.
It's my pleasure. I want to start by
asking you a question that is on the
minds of a lot of product managers is
how to be less annoying as a product
manager. I know you worked with a lot of
engineers over time. I'm curious what it
is that PMs do that annoy engineers
most and how can PMs stop doing that?
I would say there are a few things that PMs
do that annoy engineers and to be clear,
I am sure that engineers annoy PMs, just
as much. So I've realized this is a two-way
street. So I think there's some things that
are really easy to fix and some things that
are maybe a little bit harder. So the easy things
to fix are hoarding credit. Sometimes I think PMs
because they tend to be the front-facing person
for initiatives, they're talking to customers,
they're talking to the executive team, whatever.
Engineers sometimes think that they don't get the
credit for their work because the PM takes all
the glory and all the credit for the project
that they really worked very hard on, right?
So making every effort to be credit sharing and
inclusive of the engineering team and giving them
the opportunity to speak about their contributions
when it makes sense. I think those are all things
that PMs can do to avoid that kind of ... What I
consider a pretty easy annoyance, just like don't
pour it all the credit. This is not just you,
right? There's a lot of work has to go into that.
I think that sort of dovetails into the next thing
that engineers really get annoyed about with
PMs when they just don't understand the details
and act like they don't matter and I think this
is just a little bit of a cultural difference.
I mean, even managers, just normal managers,
people like me who are looking across really
broad areas or you have to be kind of big picture
focused, and you forget that engineering done
successfully really is all about the details
and you don't necessarily have to understand
all of those details, but when you act like they
don't matter and you don't care about them and
it's just like, I don't care, just like tell me
when you can get this done or why is it going
to take so long? My god, this just seems like
such a little thing. It just shows a real lack
of empathy for the work that engineers are doing
and I think it really can be very off-putting.
Even though I will totally agree that
sometimes you're going to get details
that don't really matter and you just have to
be a little bit patient in those circumstances.
Today's episode is brought to you by DX. If you're
an engineering leader or on a platform team,
at some point your CEO will inevitably ask you for
productivity metrics, but measuring engineering
organizations is hard and we can all agree that
simple metrics like the number of PRs or commits
doesn't tell the full story. That's where DX comes
in. DX is an engineering intelligence solution
designed by leading researchers, including
those behind the DORA and SPACE frameworks.
It combines quantitative data from developer
tools with qualitative feedback from developers
to give you a complete view of engineering
productivity and the factors affecting it.
Learn why some of the world's most
iconic companies like Etsy, Dropbox,
Twilio, Vercel and Webflow rely on DX. Visit
DX's website at getdx.com/lenny. Let me tell
you about CommandBar. If you're like me and most
users I've built product for, you probably find
those little in-product pop-ups really annoying.
Want to take a tour? Check out this new feature,
and these pop-ups are becoming less and less
effective since most users don't read what they
say. They just want to close them as soon as
possible, but every product builder knows that
users need help to learn the ins and outs of your
product. We use so many products every day and we
can't possibly know the ins and outs of everyone.
CommandBar is an AI-powered toolkit for product,
growth, marketing and customer teams to
help users get the most out of your product,
without annoying them. They use AI to get closer
to user intent, so they have search and chat
products that let users describe what they're
trying to do in their own words and then see
personalized results like customer walkthroughs
or actions, and they do pop-ups too, but their
nudges are based on in-product behaviors like
confusion or intent classification, which makes
them much less annoying and much more impactful.
This works for web apps, mobile apps and websites.
And they work with industry-leading companies like
Gusto, Freshworks, HashiCorp and LaunchDarkly.
Over 15 million end-users have interacted with
CommandBar. To try out CommandBar, you can sign
up at commandbar.com/lenny and you can unlock
an extra 1000 AI responses per month for any
plan. That's commandbar.com/lenny. By the way,
CommandBar just changed their name to Command AI.
The third is playing telephone. Anybody
in a manager role can fall victim to this,
but I think PMs especially can be very annoying.
So if you are being asked questions that you
cannot answer because you just don't know or
because that's something that involves a level
of technical detail that only the engineers have
that you just don't have, and you put yourself
in this in-between position where people ask you
questions, you turn around, you ask the engineers
questions, you take whatever they say, especially
when you don't really understand it, which happens
sometimes, right? Go back to the original asker
and sort of get in this middle-person scenario.
I think that is very annoying and frankly,
it's a waste of time for everyone. This is
something that managers of all stripes do, but
PMs definitely do it and that drives engineers,
particularly senior engineers on projects, it's
crazy. And then, the last one that I wanted to
put on this list is just when sometimes it feels
like product managers want to hoard all the ideas
for themselves, right? They want to be the ones
that come up with every single sort of product
idea and every single detail. What I see happen
in those cases is that I see engineers start
to over-engineer things, because engineers are
like, well, I need to take control of something.
I want to have some creative outlet, so I'm going
to use my engineering skills as my creative outlet
and I'm going to spend a lot of time obsessing
over the right framework or the right this,
that or the other. That may actually not matter
that much with products delivery, but when you
take the people that are part of the project team
out of the creative loop entirely, they're going
to find that creative outlet somewhere else
and it's actually kind of bad for the product.
That's really interesting, the last one. So you're
saying if you keep engineers from having a voice
in what you're building and prioritizing,
that's what encourages engineers to rethink,
let's just rebuild this thing, let's use a
new framework, let's rewrite this system.
Yeah, I mean that's my ... that happens
without you doing that, sometimes.
Yeah.
I do think ... I think when I see it worst and
I can basically always predict what I'm going
to see, a lot of that kind of engineers
building stuff, finding creative outlets
and kind of building stuff, maybe they shouldn't
be. I'm going to find that in places where they
are so quashed their creativity for the actual
business or product that they're building and
their voice in that is so ignored that they
don't have any outlets in that space and so,
they are going to use the space that they
have an outlet in, the place where they
have some control and that's usually the
technology choices and the details there.
That's fascinating. I want to actually
dig further into that around rewrites.
You have a really interesting take
on that, but before we get there,
let me spend a little time on some of these.
These are awesome. So on this theme of not
involving engineers in ideation and coming
up with what you're actually building,
what have you seen just very tactically, is
there anything you've seen that PM do super well?
I think the product managers that have done the
best, they're not threatened by other people
having ideas. They're not threatened by the
engineering team being full of smart people
because they realize that yeah, some of the
engineers may have good ideas, but they still
don't really know how to do the product job. Just
my experience is there are plenty of engineers who
actually think they can be product managers and
they don't really understand all of the elements
of the product job that they would need to be
successful. And when product managers take the
time to build those relationships, well, make sure
that people do feel like they can both share their
ideas, but also that they start to appreciate
what the job of this product person actually is.
And what they're really bringing to the
table in terms of really how do we measure
this input? How do we really understand the
customers, how do we really think through
the details of what's going to make this
successful from a business or a customer
perspective? I do think that that creates just
a much better interaction pattern and then,
engineers can feel good about sharing ideas and
understanding that many of them won't go anywhere,
but there's somebody that's actually going to
listen and take the time to care about them.
Coming back to some of the things that you said
annoy engineers of PMs, this idea of playing
the middle person, sounds like the solution
clearly is there. Just connect the engineer
to the other engineer or your engineer to the
PM that's trying to figure this out, right?
That one is not always easy because again,
you have this tension of a lot of the job,
of any management role is being in meetings
and filtering stuff so that people who are in
focus ... individual contributor mode can focus
and get things done and not spend half of their
weekend in meetings. You've just got to be very
careful about knowing when you're crossing that
line and when you're crossing it too often. And
if you're having to often say, "Let me get back to
you, let me get back to you, I don't know, let me
get back to you." Maybe the person you're talking
to is asking the wrong level of questions of you.
Maybe you need to connect them to the engineers
directly, but just being aware that that
shouldn't be a default behavior. That
will happen occasionally, but it shouldn't
be a thing that happens a lot because if
it's happening a lot, then you're likely
missing something, you're likely losing
something in that telephone game translation
and that's going to cause problems over time.
Awesome. So basically, if you're just
finding your middle person too much,
then it may be time to connect people
directly. And I know the reason PMs
often are afraid of this is the engineer may
agree to something that they think is a bad
idea for their team or may not understand all the
ramifications on the product or just obviously,
just spend their time in meetings
and not be building anything.
Yeah, yeah, and sometimes you mean
you do it in a group meeting. I feel
like Slack and other chat type things
actually make it a lot easier to see,
have the right people in a group in a
thing, but again, that's distracting.
So there's not an easy solution to that one,
just I think it's important to be aware of it.
Yeah, that's a really good point. And
then, in terms of hoarding credit,
is there any tactical thing you've
seen PMs do really well here is it,
just every time they're announcing the product,
"Hey, these engineers were involved or-"
It's more than just saying thank you to all
these people, but it's actually sometimes
stepping back and letting other people speak,
especially if it's something that's a really,
really big technical lift. I don't think there's a
super easy fix to that. I think it is just really
being mindful that that can be very much a sore
point for engineers when they just feel like,
"This is my work, I'm not getting any credit for
it, and this person is hogging all the glory."
I love that. Yeah, I find the best PMs are the
ones that talk the least and encourage other
people to do the presenting and announcing.
And so, I think that's a really good reminder
is let your engineers do that. Okay, amazing.
So we talked a little bit about this idea of
rewriting and how engineers sometimes just want
to rewrite the system and I think a lot of PMs
do too. A lot of times you're building your
features on a thing that someone that doesn't
even work at the company and were built five,
10 years ago, and there's always this sense of,
"Okay, maybe we should just rewrite this
thing everything will move so much faster."
Do you have a really interesting take that
I think a lot of PMs will love to hear,
which is that rewrites are often a big trap
and often don't end up being what you think
they might be? Can you just talk about
your experience and perspective on this?
Yeah, so I mean I have personally overseen a
number of, if not quite rewrites, re-architectures
and major system evolutions. So I absolutely do
think they are sometimes a thing that needs to
happen, but I also, have seen so many instances
of cases where the engineers have convinced
themselves that the only solution to the woes that
they're experiencing with the system, it's hard to
support, it's hard to change. Nobody wants to work
on it, because it's this old crappy technology,
is that they just have to go over to the
side, build the new thing that will replace
this old system and that is going to
sort of free them from their misery.
And I think projects where you acknowledge that
you do need to do an uplift, but you make a very
thoughtful staged plan as to how you're going
to do that, and you really think through, okay,
we don't need to touch all of this stuff,
but we're going to take the recommendation
system, it really needs to be uplifted and
that's a well-contained, you know, API and so
we can start to fix that without having to change
the whole whatever web framework, right? So I do
think there are ways to do these evolutions, but
people really underestimate. They underestimate
the time to migrate stuff from the old system
to the new system, is a huge, huge problem.
Particularly when you're talking about systems
where you have sort of external people using the
system in some way, whether it's web UIs or APIs.
You think, "Oh, we kind of know what's going on,
so it's not going to be that big a deal."
Engineers notoriously, notoriously, notoriously,
massively underestimate the migration time
for old system to new system and that causes
a lot of problems. By the way, you still have to
support the old system while you're working on
the new system. So I doubt many of the PMs in the
audience are ever happy when they hear, we need
to go away for six months, a year, two years to
build this new thing and we just can't really
add any features to the system in the interim.
That's infuriating, I'm sure, and frankly that's
a problem and I don't know that that should be
an acceptable answer in many cases. There may
occasionally again be a case where that is what
has to happen, but I think most of the time you
can't really afford to just say we're going to go
away and we're not going to touch the system for a
long time and we're going to build something new
over here. So many things about why that doesn't
make any sense. So this is a little bit of field
of the blog post that you're referring to. So,
if you've got a system that doesn't really need
feature enhancement or development because it's
just sort of fine and the users are using it.
And it's just annoying to the engineers,
why in the world would you invest so much
money in writing a new version of it? There's
a little bit of a cognitive dissonance that
sometimes happens if you need to do new stuff
and the old system literally is not ... it's not
possible to do the new stuff that you need to do,
you need to figure out a path to get to
a sustainable system or you can continue
to add and evolve. You should be investing
and so there does need to be an investment,
but you have to ask yourself, if I could go away
and not touch this and not do anything to it for a
long period of time without it really harming my
business, is it worthwhile to change it at all?
Does it matter, and there's some questions there.
I also think that when people try to do rewrites,
particularly again if it's something that
you're really trying to just move to a new
language for example or sort of modernize in
a certain way, [inaudible 00:18:45] a lot of
times people really underestimate what the old
system does and how well they know what the old
system does. There's so much logic buried in
legacy systems, it tends to be undocumented,
it tends to be weird. You haven't
thought through all the business rules,
you haven't thought through the data formatting
and I think again, it's much, much harder to
replicate all the important things from the old
system to the new system than people expect.
So there's more than that, but I do think
sometimes you need to evolve systems and my
advice would be when you're struggling making an
evolution plan, take pieces potentially of the old
system, uplift them, make them more scalable, make
them easier to work with, clean up the tech debt,
but trying to say we're going to just go away.
We're going to rewrite, we're going to build
something brand new and it's going to solve
all our problems, it just very rarely works.
I think a lot of PMs will be like, "Yes, thank
you so much for saying this, because I think
that's also always a big struggle between the
ENG team and the PM team." So just to summarize
what I think a lot of people miss or what you're
saying a lot of people miss when they're thinking
about let's rewrite this thing, is the migration
to the new system, migrating customers, users,
data to the new thing is going to take a lot
longer than you expect. You underestimate
knowing what it actually does and you're going
to miss features and you can introduce new bugs.
This actually is very similar to what I've
seen with redesigning a whole product flow.
There's always this sense of let's just
rethink this onboarding flow from scratch
or let's rebuild this part of the product and
always it ends up being a negative experiment
result. It always ends up being less good and
then, you have to spend all this time clawing
back to get to where you were and also, you
forget the stuff that would ... the features
that you had and you're like, "Oh, shit, I
forgot about that feature, I forgot about that
feature." So it's interesting, there's a very
similar situation in the product side. Okay,
amazing. I'm going to go to a slightly different
topic, which is around engineering leadership.
So I know you've written a lot about
engineering leadership, you spent a lot
of times with engineering leaders, so I have a
few questions here. One is that I know that one
of the things that haunts engineering leaders
most is finding the balance between staying
technical and their technical expertise, and
their leadership expertise and basically finding
the right altitude of how high ... where to be
in the org and also how in the details to be,
and also staying technical enough to be relevant.
What have you learned in your own experience
of finding that balance and how do you advise
engineering leaders as they struggle with this?
Yeah, so one piece of advice I give everybody is
don't stop being a hands-on technical until you
feel like it's in your bones. You feel like
you've got mastery that you could ... if you
know a second language fluently or
if you played an instrument really,
really seriously for a long time or maybe a
sport really, really seriously for a long time,
you'll be familiar with the ... I haven't done
that in a long time, but if I was to pick it up,
it would be rusty, but I would get there pretty
quickly, right? Maybe physically, I wouldn't be
as strong as I was or whatever, but I would
get there. You can do that with writing code.
You can do that with technical skills if you
do it for long enough, I think you can develop
sort of a baseline mastery, where you're
not going to be as fast and a lot of the
challenges of being technical is actually in
all the tooling and all the tooling evolution,
but you're not going to be necessarily
as fast as people who have been doing it,
but you won't be completely clueless and I
think that all the things you learn getting
to that really comfortable mastery of some part
of hands-on tech will stay with you and will help
you just maintain a level of confidence in your
own technical know-how and maintain a level of
empathy for what it means to be a good engineer.
And I think just make you a lot less anxious about
being hands-off, even though I think everybody
who makes that transition for a year or two,
especially if you're really have to be hands-off
or you just don't have time to write code at all,
you are going to be anxious for a while
no matter what. The things to then think
about from that point is, being technical is
also just about knowing what's going on and
paying attention and being able to ask ... what
people care about with technical leaders in my
experience is they want people who actually seem
like they sort of understand what you're doing
and can ask good questions and help guide you
to better decisions without actually being the
one who's like, "Oh no, you need to use
this library instead of that library."
It's actually sort of annoying when somebody
that's very senior and hands-off tries to tell
you, don't use this library, use that
library because I don't know about you,
but I don't really believe people who have been
hands-off for that long when they try to tell me
what to do and the thing that I'm kind of the
expert in right now, but I do appreciate it
when I'm given more guidance around, well, have
you considered this? Tell me about how you're
planning to handle that situation. What are the
major technical challenges with implementing this
and that can actually spend the time to listen
and ask thoughtful questions on the back of that.
The last thing I would say is surround
yourself with smart technical people,
also as much as you can, and be willing to
listen to them, talk about tech and ask them
questions about things. I feel like that's part
of the reason that I am able to stay technically
savvy and credible amongst people who work for
me is not that I'm writing code because I'm not.
But I am listening to a lot of very smart people
talk about technology a lot, down to the level
of I'm trying to debug this database issue, what
the heck is going on? And just constantly being
interested in those stories and learning from
them and learning what really smart engineers
are thinking about and worrying about.
The more you can build that network of
people that are still hands-on and stay in
touch with that, I do think that helps a lot.
So on my last point, how are
you actually doing that? Is it
watching ... going to conferences
with friends, something else?
Yeah, yeah. I mean, I guess for me it started
with going to conferences, meeting people. Now,
I'm in a lot of different chat groups where
people are just sort of regularly communicating,
staying in touch with ... staying in touch with
former colleagues. I will admit I'm kind of a
social person and I have a big network,
so this may be easier said than done,
but I do think being in the right group chats ...
I also think, I'm sure reading various tech news
and tech sort of commentary and discussion
boards, I mean it's definitely a mixed bag
of that stuff I think that like ... but there are
smart people. You find the smart people in there,
you sort of follow what they're saying. I think
that's another good way to keep that perspective.
Is it a sign, I wonder if you're
not interested in that anymore that
maybe you should move into something
else. I don't know. If you're like,
don't really pay attention
to engineering technicalness.
It's hard for me to say because I'm such a
nerd. I really love tech. I'm in this industry,
because I'm just actually genuinely
very interested in certain corners,
not every corner of technology but certain
corners of technology. I want to know what
the latest stuff that's happening in databases and
infrastructure and I find it all very interesting.
I find the problems interesting. So I think that
makes me very successful because I just have that
natural curiosity and passion and interest in it.
But I don't know that that's a total prerequisite.
Yeah, but you've been talking about ... it reminds
me a little bit of this guy, LevelsIO on Twitter.
Have you heard of this guy? He was just on
Lex Friedman. Have you listened to that yet?
I think maybe I saw a clip of
it, but I haven't listened to it.
So I think one of the most successful indie
engineers where he just works on his own thing
all by himself, never raises money, just
launch his products that make money. And
a funny thing about him is he works ... all
stuff is in PHP and jQuery. He's just like,
this works. I've always had this to do, learn
Node.js, learn Python. And I'm like, I'm too busy
to build ... while I'm building to learn these
new things and he's been incredibly successful.
So it touches on sometimes maybe you don't need
to just keep rewriting to the newest frameworks.
Yeah, no, I mean look, I actually ... I feel like
I know a lot of smart engineers who are in that
category. They're like, we built amazing things
in PHP and relatively simple SQL and so much
of tech is over-engineering things and I don't
totally disagree. I think the challenge is though,
of course, what works as a one person show,
doesn't always work in a scaled organization
for better or for worse, we're in different like,
you've got to match what makes one person really
productive. Will it make 100 people, 1000 people,
even 10 people really productive? That's always a
little hard to tell and that's why I do think you
should be not ... I think it's always a good idea
to be keeping up with what's happening and what's
changing in whatever kind of side of tech you're
in, but not obsessively chasing every fad.
I think being aware of, but not necessarily
chasing them, but particularly, if you're working
in groups, teams, larger companies, even midsize
companies, there is some amount of, you're
balancing the tech that makes one person go fast
with the tech that makes 10 or 100 people go fast
and those are not always exactly the same thing.
Just to kind follow this thread a little bit
and to kind of nerd snipe you a little bit,
is there a platform or language or framework
these days that you're either very excited
about that you think is helping
people move faster and do better
work or the opposite just like this is ...
everyone is excited but this is not good.
I will say this, one example I actually
put in my own notes for this conversation
was GraphQL. I would not tell a team to use
or not use GraphQL at this point because it's
a bit out of my expertise zone and my level
of management. It's not really my job anyway,
but it is one of the things that is both popular
and thought relatively poorly of by most of the
senior people that I know. And so, I guess
I would say that's one where I would say if
you're seriously thinking about it and you're
not Facebook, you may really want to make sure
you know what problem you're trying to solve
because the impression that I have from sort
of listening to people talk about it is
that GraphQL is kind of trying to promise
front-end engineers that they don't really
have to collaborate with backend engineers.
And they can just sort of build whatever
and it'll all be fine, and it just doesn't
ever seem to work out that well for anybody who
actually does it in practice. Again, obviously,
it can work out that well because Facebook
has made a great go of it. I'm sure there are
other companies that are, but that's one where
it's not that new but it remains one of these
things where it seems like an interesting
fad that maybe is burning a lot of people.
That's awesome. I appreciate you sharing that. I
don't know if this is exactly an example of this,
but on that podcast levels, I forget
his actual name, Peter I think,
shared that whenever there's a framework
that has a VC funded startup behind it,
that's not a good sign because their
job now is to convince engineers to
use it and then pay for it and that's not
necessarily going to be the best product.
That's true. Although I will say that some
of the most time-wasting frameworks have
also just come out of big companies, or
the context of the big company that may
have made that framework super useful within
that context doesn't translate to startup
or small company or even big company that
doesn't have the rest of the context set,
but I don't think ... He's not wrong. I also just
think big companies share the blame on that one.
I guess we should all just come back
to PHP and jQuery and be simple.
Maybe.
Okay, so to close out this
thread on engineering leaders,
finding the right balance, just to summarize
your advice here. One is get to mastery before
and is your advice here, get to this
point before you move into engineering.
Engineering management. I will say part of this is
also in particular, if you happen to be a woman or
otherwise, underrepresented person in tech because
people will tend to underestimate your technical
abilities just unfortunately as a get-go.
I also think it's particularly important to
kind of develop that internal confidence in your
abilities before you make this sort of scary leap,
which is scary for everyone of have a ... if you
have that mastery before you make the leap, I wish
more people would do this because honestly, I do
think there are a lot of people who never really
gained the mastery. They go into management, they
lose it and some of them are still perfectly good
managers and look, there are good managers
who were never technical to begin with.
I don't want to say that that's impossible. I
just think that if you care about being technical,
if you are technical now and you want to maintain
that tech-savvy, don't just become a manager the
first time somebody offers it to you. Make sure
you've really spent your good time writing code.
Is there a number of years
heuristic you think about
or some way to tell you that
maybe you've hit that point?
I think this has been since disproven,
but it was that 10,000 hours idea of
mastery at some point. For me, it was like
an undergraduate degree, a graduate degree,
and four or five years of full-time work. So
maybe I might be slow. I didn't start coding
a lot in middle school like people might do
now, but I felt like ... I took several years
of hands-on work in a very intense undergraduate
and graduate programs for me. So I do think it's
probably somewhere in the 10-year range
of really having spent a lot of your time
over those years writing code and really
understanding how to be a technical expert.
Got it. So essentially if you're thinking
about moving into management as an engineer,
you may want to wait until you've done it
for 10 years in some form, which I think
is a lot longer than a lot of people
would've thought. And I imagine many
people are not doing that. And then, in your
experience not doing it as well, it could be-
If you were programming a lot in high school and
you got an undergraduate degree,
so let's say you've got six years-
I see.
You may only need four or five years of work, 40
hour a week writing code experience. I'm sure it
depends on the company, but I do think when you
see people that are 23, they are just out very
recently out of school, it's a different thing
if you're a founder and that's a whole different
life, but if you're at a big company and somebody
is like you have great communication skills, why
don't you start to become a manager? Often they're
actually pushing you to become a project manager,
which is actually also the worst sort of path
to real leadership in my opinion. If you don't
feel like you're done ... Also, if you just don't
feel like you're done, if you're still having fun
writing code, don't rush becoming a manager,
writing code is awesome. Have fun, enjoy it.
I know exactly what you mean. So I used to
be an engineer, actually I was an engineer
for 10 years. I definitely don't have mastery at
this point. I moved into product from that and I
definitely so missed actually just sitting
there and writing code and building stuff,
that was very hard to give up.
I imagine you still missed that.
I think I might've forgotten about it
at this point, but there is nothing
as satisfying because you get the fast
feedback loop. It's just wonderful. Yeah.
This episode is brought to you by Coda. I use
Coda every day to coordinate my podcasting and
newsletter workflows from collecting questions for
guests to storing all my research to managing my
newsletter content calendar, Coda is my go-to
app and has been for years. Coda combines the
best of documents, spreadsheets and apps to help
me get more done and Coda can help your team to
stay aligned and ship faster by managing
your planning cycle in just one location.
Set and measure OKRs with full visibility across
teams and stakeholders, map dependencies, create
progress visualizations, and identify risk areas.
You can also access hundreds of pressure tested
templates for everything from roadmap strategy,
to final decision-making frameworks. See for
yourself why companies like DoorDash, Figma and
Qualtrics run on Coda. Take advantage of this
special limited-time offer just for startups. Head
over to coda.io/lenny and sign up to get six free
months of the team plan. That's coda.io/lenny
to sign up and get six months of the team plan,
coda.io/lenny. On the topic of moving into
management, you wrote maybe the definitive
book on engineering manager career path, and
so when someone moves from IC to management,
what do you find is the most surprising
thing to them? What do they most often not
understand or are surprised by like, "Oh man, I
did not see this as part of my job or my life."
Yeah, I mean I think there's a few things. I do
think ... assuming that they're actually trying
to do it well, I do think there are a lot of
people who move into management and then just
don't really understand the job at all and aren't
even self-aware enough to know that they don't
understand it, but for those who are trying to
do it, trying to do it well. I think a few things
that tend to surprise them are the fact that you
really don't own your time as a manager. Your team
and your management and the company owns your
time. More and more the more senior you become
as a manager. I think individual contributors
often think that if they become a manager,
they will still have some of the freedom that
they have as a senior individual contributor.
But then they'll also be able to tell people
what to do and they'll have all this authority.
And the reality is, management is much more ...
I'm not a huge fan of servant leadership exactly,
but management really is a service job. You are
serving the team, you are serving the company.
Your job is to help make things better and that
usually doesn't mean that you're making all the
decisions. It usually doesn't mean that you
snap your fingers and people jump. Because if
you try that, especially in tech, right? People
are just going to revolt. They're not going to
listen to you. It's just too hard to have
... that's not the culture that we live in.
And I don't think that's a good culture. I
don't think that command and control, I tell
you what to do and you do it. It just doesn't
create creativity, right? It's the same thing
as like PMs, trying to have all the ideas, right?
No, you've got all these brilliant people working
for you on a team, your job as a manager is not
to tell them what to do in every single case.
Occasionally, yes, a lot more. If you're trying
to convince them of what you think should happen.
In some ways, you're sort of nudging, you're
encouraging, you're directing, you're setting
guardrails for processes or behaviors or whatever,
but it's not this glorious fearless leader.
I make all these decisions and everyone looks
up to me and it's awesome kind of job. It's
much more grueling, much more ... you are really
just sort of reacting to things in the moment.
And it can be very ... it's a hard job. I do
think particularly management when done well,
when you're really trying to do it in a thoughtful
kind, but also, productive way is a very hard job.
I wonder if engineering is where most ... where
the highest percentage of people that move into
management move back to IC. I've seen that a bunch
and I wonder if engineers are the most common.
I don't know, but-
After realizing what you just said
is true, like, "Oh, what I done-"
So do you not think product managers also
do this? Because I think product managers
also actually suffer from exactly this kind of-
They do.
Maybe sometimes-
Yeah.
But interestingly, I was an engineering manager
earlier in my career. I really did not like it.
I was very unhappy in that role. As a PM manager
though, I was very happy, it was a lot easier.
Yeah, because PMs are way easier to manage. PMs
are awesome to manage. PMs want to ... they're
just so helpful. They want to do this ...
they're good communicators. I love managing PMs.
I have to say, I have to say, just my experience,
engineers are such a pain. They're
all primadonnas. I am an engineer,
but PMs are more fun to manage my experience.
So actually, you have a point. You have a point.
But I wonder. Yeah, because I haven't seen a lot
of PM managers move back to IC product management.
I find that once you can build product through
teams and not sit there all day in Excel and
check in on deadlines and things, it's hard
to give that part up. You kind of enjoy being
higher up in that chain. Yeah. Kind of along
these lines, something that you have a really
interesting perspective on is one-on-ones. Most
people are like have one-on-ones with everyone,
have them regularly, they're really important. You
actually have this contrarian take that maybe you
should have less one-on-ones, especially as
an engineering manager, you talk about that.
Yeah, so to be clear, you should have one-on-ones
with your direct reports and your manager and
you should hold those sacred ... I tend to do my
weekly or maybe every other week. So this is not
about that set of one-on-ones. So the one-on-ones
of the people that you are directly managing and
with your own manager. But I think there is
this ... I don't know if it's the remote work,
sort of explosion that's happened or it's big
companies or what, but what I've seen and I've
heard a lot of friends at many companies complain
about is this idea that everybody is doing
one-on-ones with everyone else. So the manager is
doing one-on-ones with their team. They're also
doing one-on-ones with all of their peers.
They're doing one-on-ones with all of their
stakeholders. They're doing one-on-ones with
product and design. And I think that it's just
not a scalable approach, right? Linearly scale
with the number of relationships you have. And so,
as your company grows, as the number of things
your team supports grow, as the team grows,
you just can't scale that way. You cannot expect
to maintain a one-on-one approach to kind of
organizational relationship building and awareness
passed a fairly small team/company. I also think
that people think that one-on-ones will solve
all of their problems. And I think the reality
is you have this one-on-ones with people that
don't really want to have a one-on-one with you.
If they're not in the mind to invest in your
relationship, if they don't really care about
what you're doing, they actually may not like
it that you're asking them for a one-on-one,
let me show up like, because it's like, okay,
well I should do this to be a good corporate
citizen or whatever. But they're just like,
why are we doing this? What is the point of
this? I also think that one-on-ones,
particularly when you use them first
of stakeholder management. So when you're
meeting with people that's not your team,
but other stakeholders that you may need to deal
with, if you have a lot of stakeholders ... so
I've been in a lot of positions where I have
a lot of internal stakeholders because I build
internal platforms is a big part of what
my job has been in the last many years.
Having all these meetings as one-on-ones with
those stakeholders can actually be kind of a
weakness because when your stakeholders just
tell you in a one-on-one that they're happy or
unhappy with things, your unhappy stakeholders
aren't hearing that. So you may have one really
unhappy stakeholder and five really happy ones
and all you're saying to your unhappy one is,
"Well, everybody else is happy and they're
not seeing it for themselves." And they're
just having to say, "Trust me, because
I've had these other one-on-ones with
all these people and they're saying it's
fine." And it just kind of sounds whiny.
And so, when you're dealing with a lot of
stakeholders and trying to just rely on one-on-one
management of that is actually not very productive
in a lot of ways. So in general, I guess I just
think people should respect their own time more.
As much as I just said management, you're kind of
at everyone's mercy and that is true, but also
respect your time. Don't just load yourself up
with meetings because you're a manager and that's
your job. Do you really have something to talk to
a person about? Do you really need to ... when
you have a one-on-one meeting with someone,
you are asking for their time. You shouldn't
just be doing that kind of haphazardly for fun.
This is a little bit of my personality. I'm
not a great company networker. Some people are
really good at just like, let's go to get coffee,
let's go to lunch and let's hang out and build a
relationship. And honestly, those people are
really successful in many ways that I am not.
I do sort of envy that skill. I'm really good if
I work with you. If I work with you on something,
generally speaking, people really come to respect
me because I'm very engaged and I'm a really good
collaborator in various ways, but I'm really bad
at just getting to know you random one-on-one,
where we don't have a purpose to the meeting.
And that's not to say those are always bad, but
I do think that a lot of people with ... that's
your comfort zone, if that getting to know you,
random, relationship building one-on-one is your
comfort zone, I should probably do more of them.
You should probably do fewer of them because
you should always be pushing yourself to get
out of your comfort zone and are you really
getting something out of that or are you just
being able to tick a checkbox that says, I had
eight meetings today, therefore I was productive.
Yeah, that super resonates. Kind
of pulling on this thread of how
you operate and how you work something
that I've heard you're really known for,
is creating a work culture where
people work really hard but also,
have a really good work-life balance. And when we
were chatting, you, you actually told me you're
not a great believer in working too hard. Can
you just talk about this philosophy on building
a great culture where people don't work too hard
but also, get stuff done and don't burn out?
I think we all understand that if we could just
figure out and focus on really the most important
things, we would just ... everything would
be better. And it's hard to figure out what
the most important things are, but overwork
kind of lets you just sidestep doing the hard
work of figuring out what's important in
the first place. I listened to one of your
podcasts where you talked to someone who said,
if you've never fired someone and regretted it,
you don't know where the line is, of who you
should and shouldn't buy. And I will admit I
have mixed feelings about that, although I get
what you're saying. If you don't regularly reset
your expectations of what you should and shouldn't
let slide, do you have any idea where the line
of what is actually important to work on is?
I just think ... and the thing about that is
it's not like firing people where you do it once
or twice and you regret it and you learn pretty
quickly, unfortunately. I think you actually have
to kind of regularly test the circumstances and
challenge with, am I really getting the most out
of myself? Am I really producing the best value
or am I just making ... swaging my internal
guilt about I need to work 60-hour weeks,
I need to sleep in the office, I need to whatever,
to show that I'm a hard worker and I care. And so,
I guess I do really think that people should
challenge themselves to be focused and get
the important stuff done and always be
asking themselves what is important to do?
And what's important to do does change over time.
But if you're not regularly doing an audit of your
time and trying to knock things off that list
that don't matter, you're probably wasting a lot
of time on things that don't matter and okay, you
don't want to work less. You love working a lot,
that's fine, but you could probably just be
getting a lot more valuable stuff done if you
would do these audits regularly, right? I also
think people don't delegate enough. So, if you
don't delegate, then you get overwhelmed because
your team doesn't know how to do anything, because
you haven't bothered to spend the time delegating,
which actually takes more time initially, usually,
you have to teach people whatever it is
that you're trying to get them to do.
Not always, sometimes they'll surprise
you and they're better at it than you are,
but maybe not. And so, you have to teach them,
but then you finally ... you freed yourself up
to scale. So I guess I'm just a real believer
that working hard and a focused way for over
fewer hours I think is a more productive way to
approach work. And I think I have lived my career
that way. I've been successful in it and I have
encouraged it and people who have worked for me,
and I think I've seen a lot of success
through it, but it's not a thoughtless
exercise. It's an active process of
constant reflection to get to that focus.
For someone that is listening to this and is like,
I want to start doing this, is there anything ...
any specific practice you've found useful or
any specific tactic to actually do this well?
I think there's different approaches you
could take, right? One approach you could
take is just like every Friday I'm going to
stop working at 4 PM or something, let's say,
and I am not, or I'm not going to let myself
work this weekend. Forcing yourself to log off,
forcing yourself to have boundaries and saying
... and then doing out of what did I get done,
I think can help. That's scary. And people don't
like doing that, but I do think that that's one
of the best ways to do it is really just saying,
I'm going to log off. I'm going to log off every
day this week at 6 PM. I'm going to ... because
your brain is probably going to keep thinking.
You might still be a little stressed out, you're
still thinking about work, you're still worrying
about it, but there is a difference between
thinking about it and doing it, and particularly
for those of you who are earlier in your careers,
this was actually, I think one of the reasons that
I did get to mastery was because I was extremely
good at being focused when I was at work, when I
was a hands-on programmer and really writing code
for many of the hours of the day. And that meant
I was not ... this was pre heavy social media.
I was much less distracted, which I don't know
if I would be able to do it in the modern era
as easily, but having that real heavy focus
time because I was like, "I don't want to work on
the weekend. I don't want to stay here until 9 PM
every night. I just want to get this done." And
it meant that I didn't do quite as many copies.
I didn't go to lunch and chat with people all
every day, but I was very, very productive and
I learned to get a lot done in a short period of
time. And I do think learning those skills earlier
in your career and then continuing to apply them
throughout your career is another piece of advice.
In terms of staying and getting
focused, is there anything that
helps you focus? Is it like headphones,
a drink? What gets you in the zone?
I mean, yeah, I have a lot of rituals.
I have my caffeination rituals.
Say more.
Well, I mean I can't drink coffee anymore because
my stomach got messed up at some point, but I
drink tea in the morning. I drink caffeinated
water also. I have a Diet Coke at lunch,
so I have these rituals of my caffeine hits that
help me. I have to be in a quiet place. I do find
non-music that is ... I really like Four Tet, for
example, as music to focus or the new Andre 3000
Flute album is extremely good for focusing,
where it's not quite predictable, no lyrics
and not quite predictable. For me, that helps me
focus a lot. I can't be listening to any words
and focus. My brain just cannot ignore words. So
those are some of the things I use to help folks.
That is awesome. I have a similar caffeine
strategy. I'm drinking tea always during these
podcasts and this little thing I got here and
then, my wife doesn't want me to drink Diet Coke
because she thinks the sugar and it is not good,
but I still drink it sometimes and it works great.
I switched to green tea. That's my approach.
Start with black tea and then switch to green tea.
That's smart.
Man, there's so many things you shared
that I wanted to dig into. Let me share
a couple of things. Your point about delegating I
thought was really important, and there's another
benefit to learning to delegate, which is team
members feel empowered. You give them a chance to
take on responsibility and they feel like I have
an opportunity to show I can do this other thing.
Yeah, and you're never going
to scale if you don't delegate.
Yeah, and it's hard to start learning to
do that, but once you get good at it, it
becomes so great. I love just delegate everything
every time, and people enjoy it. They're like,
"Amazing. You're giving me opportunity." The thing
you said about how ... if you're not sometimes
regretting something you cut or potentially
firing someone you don't regret, Elon actually,
Elon Musk has a great approach to this. I don't
know if you've heard his philosophy on optimizing.
He has this whole five-step process of
figuring out how to optimize something,
and one of them is try to cut things like, do we
need this thing or not? And if you don't recognize
that 10% of stuff you cut, it was a mistake,
you're probably not cutting enough stuff.
You'll have to figure out your own metrics.
But I definitely think testing the limits,
it's scary though. I'm going to be
honest. Doing that is always scary.
It brings up like, I forgot to finish
the assignment nightmares of school,
especially for the overachievers that often end
up in these kinds of companies and jobs. Again,
you got to do things that scare
you or you're never going to grow.
Okay, I'm going to go in a whole different
direction. You've got a book coming out
about platform engineering and platform
teams. This is something that I get a lot
of questions about. A lot of people are
thinking about moving to a platform team
or struggling working on a platform team or
struggling working with a platform team. So I
have a bunch of questions along these lines.
The first is I asked a bunch of people that
worked with you what to ask you and someone
that worked with you shared this quote about
his frustration working with platform teams
that he's often complaining to you about and
he works on customer-facing products. And so,
he said platform teams that are often slow.
They're often pushing us to compromise on
features to adopt their systems. They often
get infinite funding even though they don't
have to show any ROI. And so, maybe from the
perspective of working with a platform team,
say you're building something customer-facing,
any tips for effectively working with a platform
team and building a great relationship there.
I'm very sympathetic to anybody who feels that way
because part of the reason that I wrote this book,
I co-wrote it with a friend, Ian Nolan, is that so
many platform teams are guilty of all the things
that he's complaining about, that my friend
was complaining about, that they don't listen,
they're not delivering effectively, they're not
explaining their value to the company. And it is
infuriating when you're dealing with that. And
honestly, I'm very sympathetic. The thing that
I would say though is the more you can, first
of all, spend the time understanding that the
platform team's problems a little bit and trying
to collaborate and work with them and be clear
about what it is you actually need and how you're
willing to work with them, I think the better.
I think if you get mad and you just try to avoid
them or undermine them or whatever, that may
work in the long run, but it's just going to make
everything worse in the short run. So I do think
that if you've got a platform team that you're
frustrated with, some tips, I would put are like,
"Look, find the parts of that team that are good
because I'm sure there are some," right? Maybe the
databases team is awesome. And really make sure
you are maintaining a good relationship with that
part of the team and you can point to how you
are collaborating extremely well with that part
of the team. Help give them product feedback.
This is annoying but sometimes needs to happen
because a lot of companies, I actually
think product ... you need to have a
product mindset and frankly, you need to have
product managers to build good platforms,
internal platforms. A lot of companies just
don't do this. They don't believe that they
should waste head count on product managers for
internal teams. So you end up with this platform
team that has a lot of smart engineers, but they
don't really know what to build. So they're just
sort of building whatever they think is right. And
so sometimes your job is to product manage them,
is to tell them, these are the problems
that we have and this is what we need.
And the clearer you can be about that,
particularly when they don't have a product team,
oftentimes, you can kind of lead them from
the side in that way. And so I think that's
another approach that I would take when
you're in that situation. Find the parts
of the team that are working and working well
with your team and make sure you develop those
relationships and try to just get over the anger
and frustration and just be clear about what
it is that you need and help them understand
what they should really be doing and building.
That is really interesting advice. So especially,
you're saying if they don't have a PM helping,
make sure they're guiding things well, is you
can help them ... basically help them think
through stuff that will benefit them and also,
help the stuff that you're trying to get done.
Yeah.
That's awesome advice. Okay, so what
about from the leadership perspective,
trying to build an effective platform
team, do you have any advice on how
to structure these teams and incentivize
these teams to help them be successful?
First of all, I'm a very strong believer that
platform engineering has to involve software
engineering. If you don't have any software
engineers on your platform team and you only
have more operations systems engineers, DevOps,
SRE, which I realize there are some SREs that are
software engineers, but they tend to not want
to write big software. I think you're kind of
missing the picture. Platform engineering is
not just maintaining cloud infrastructure and
doing small scripts or blueprints or enablement
projects for other teams, because that doesn't
really create a cohesive and coherent platform.
It doesn't create products and frankly you need
to be ... platforms are products, ultimately.
You should be thinking about how do I create
coherent offerings that make this company more
productive? So you need software engineers. Yes,
you need sort of operations systems,
SRE specialists as well. And of course,
you need product people. I had product teams on
... product managers for all of my platform teams.
I've really developed out that practice in
the companies that I've worked for doing this
because I just believe that you're not going to
get great results if you just believe that to
engineers and engineering management. They
will do their best and you do occasionally
find engineers that have really great product
instincts in this space, but the actual details.
And focus of the product work is just you can't
write a bunch of code and/or manage a big software
engineering team and be a product manager at the
same time. That's actually just asking, I think,
too much of people to do that really well, at
least for very long. So I think when it comes to
structuring a team, recognize this is not just
like SRE V2. This is more than that. You want
software engineers, you want systems engineers,
you want product people. And then, one of the
reasons you want product folks is because
you want to be thinking about impact-based,
outcome-based approaches, not just like, "Well,
we built this thing that seemed cool, we adopted
this technology from this company because that's
what everybody on the internet is talking about."
Whether it's VC funded or big company. We actually
thought about what are the problems the engineers
at my company are facing? How can we improve their
productivity or deliver leverage to this business
through whatever it is we're building, right? Are
we reducing the cycle time for engineering tasks?
Are we solving problems that are preventing
products from launching and scaling? Are we making
really meaningful cost reductions or efficiencies
and, in our products or in our platforms? These
are some examples of measurable contributions,
but I think one of the challenges is that people
create these platform teams and think that they
can be sort of divorced from having an impact
focus because it's like, "Well, you just got to
run the infrastructure and make sure it works."
And it's like, "No, you actually do still
have to do ... if you do that OKR stuff or
goal setting," or whatever, you've got to take
a lot of the best practices of product. It's a
little different in the internal world, but it's
still very important if you want to do platforms.
On the line of having PMs within
the platform teams. Some of the
best PMs I've ever worked with where PMs
on platform teams, and that just tells me,
it's not like where you put PMs that are just
meant like that's ... where you could have some
of the highest leverage because platform teams
enable the rest of the company to move faster.
Yeah.
And one difference there, I'm curious if
you agree, is your ratio of PM to engineer
can be a lot higher. You can have a lot
more engineers per PM on platform teams.
Yeah. Yeah, I think that's right because
I think so much of the work in a platform
team is not exactly product work. A lot of it is
like scaling or really deep kind of technical,
like I got to figure out how to actually do
this technical thing or I've got to do this
performance efficiency and you don't always
need a product spec for that, right? It is
often just a very engineering heavy task. So yes,
I think the ratios do tend to be a bit different.
We dove over right into this topic. Maybe it
might be helpful to help people understand what
is a platform team, just what are examples of
teams that would be considered platform teams.
I mean, I guess the high level definition
that I have of platform engineering is if
you are developing and operating platforms
that ... where they're trying to manage
overall system complexity and deliver
leverage to your business. So a lot
of the teams that people think about nowadays
and when they're talking about platform teams,
they're talking a lot about teams that may have
formerly been called dev tools. For example,
so your CI/CD tooling for the company, a lot of
the cloud infrastructure provisioning and tooling.
If you're at a company with certain technical
problems, you may very well be building semi
bespoke storage systems. For example, maybe part
of your platform teams. I actually think that
there are ... And then, actually web frameworks
... Web mobile framework and support for that.
That set of engineering can also be part of a
platform offering. I actually kind of believe that
there's also sort of what you might call
integration platforms or platforms that are in
between that infrastructurey developer tooly stuff
and products. So billing platforms for example,
if you have a single billing platform for all
of the different products in your company,
that shares a lot of overlaps in the
challenges of those more dev tools,
infrastructurey platform teams because you're
probably supporting lots of different product
lines that are using this system that needs to
be able to scale with certain efficiencies. You
need to still do the product discovery.
You probably have a little bit more of
a business product focus than the pure internal
tools teams, but that gets to the blended area.
For founders that are earlier stage or companies
that are smaller hearing this and they're like,
"Oh, shit do I need a platform team?"
So yeah, you're shaking your head,
if people aren't watching on YouTube. What's
a sign that's time maybe to start creating
a platform team and setting aside
resources for something like that?
So first of all, I think it gets to be like, you
have 50 plus engineers. I don't think this is
the kind of thing that you start when you are 10
engineers, right? But when you are ... so there's
a lot of ad hoc coordination that's probably
happening amongst your engineering groups right
now, where maybe you just have one ... you have
your GitHub and somebody is making sure that all
of that stuff is sort of working. You have a few
cloud databases and you got a couple of people
on each team and they kind of share notes to
figure out what's going on or whatever. Okay,
it's all good, but at some point, you hit either
a lot of inefficiency where you're seeing the
same people across a bunch of different teams.
Each team has the same kind of people having to
solve the same kinds of problems. It just seems
like why do I have three people in every team,
dealing with this instead of centralizing it
and making it a little more efficient. It also
could be that you hit some core scaling issue that
starts to really need a dedicated team to solve.
Again, that could be developer productivity.
Every development team is trying to do it their
own way and everybody is just super slow because
you just can't get code released and it all has
to be coordinated across every different team and
it's just like, what is going on? We need to fix
that or you actually have a technical challenging
area that needs a focused team to fix the scaling.
Those are some of the signs that you may
want to start thinking about a platform team,
but it's really like ... generally speaking, I
would not jump into it early. This is something
for companies that have matured where it's worth
investing and making people internally more
productive and centralizing certain functions
just from a cost and efficiency basis at minimum.
Say you're on a platform team, say you're
an engineer or even a PM, any advice for
how to be successful and thrive within that
environment and be a great platform team.
If you want to do platforms. If you're an
engineer, certainly if you're an engineer
or an engineering manager, you've got to remember
that half of the work is actually the operational
quality, operational excellence of these
things. Platform engineering is not just
writing code and then throwing it over the walls
to someone. Being interested and passionate about
the operational challenges and scaling bits
of systems I do think is fairly important,
if you want to be a great platform engineer
from a software engineer perspective,
if you're more like a product manager, "Look,
you've got to really care about ..." I think
you got to be really both interested in
working with really smart engineers who are
going to know way more than you do about things.
And almost being a really good, not necessarily
zero to one but past one person because actually
a lot of the best platform type offerings in
companies start in individual application teams.
An application team has a problem and they solve
it for themselves and it turns out that that's
actually a really good idea for how to solve that
problem. So a good platform team is often
looking around for those and then sort of
taking them and then assimilating them and making
them available to more and more people. And so,
I think if you want to be in that kind of zero
to one building the brand new stuff all the time,
you may not be as happy in a platform team.
But if you're really interested a little bit
more of taking things over, stabilizing,
scaling them, making them efficient,
making them evolve as a company evolves, I
think you'll be happier in that circumstance.
Awesome. Is there anything else along
these lines before we wrap up and yet
a very exciting lightning round that
you think might be helpful for folks
working with platform teams or working on
a platform team, building platform teams?
I think there are two things that we haven't
touched on or maybe three that are really hard
about platform teams and that I think don't
get much press, which is running platform
projects is a little bit different than running
agile projects. You can take a lot of the best
practices you may have learned from agile type
product delivery, but you are running longer,
running larger scale, more complex builds because
a lot of the stuff that you build at the platform
level just takes longer. It's a little bit
more complicated. So you've got to be willing
to get into that kind of stuff, especially
if you're in a management job in that space.
You are going to deal with a lot of migrations as
well. So it is very annoying. Migrations happen,
even if you don't force them on people,
your a cloud provider is going to say, oh,
you've got to migrate from EKS view 19 to 121
or whatever, and that may require changes in
code and then that's a real pain in the butt for
all of the application teams. So people who are
interested in how to smooth over the customer
and company impact of this underlying change,
I think we'll be very happy in platform teams. If
you're not interested in that, you may not enjoy
the work as much. There's just a lot of detail
oriented work and platforms. And then of course,
the final part is the stakeholders are a
nightmare. My friend who wrote the question about
how his product or his platform partners drive
him crazy. I have no doubt he drives them crazies.
Because you've got all of these stakeholders,
your peers and tech, maybe product managers,
maybe executives that are like, what is this
team? Are they really worth the money? Why are
we spending so much on it? I don't understand
what they're doing. I could do it better in
some cases. So there's actually a big part of the
job, particularly as either product managers or
engineering leadership is stakeholder management
and really learning how to do that well.
And that is not always, that's probably I
think universally agreed to be the least
fun part of the job. I don't think anybody
loves it, but it is certainly a skill set.
I'm glad that I have. And so, I think if you
are thinking about building one of these teams.
And you're like, I can just do the fun
tech stuff or the cool product stuff,
I'm really passionate about engineering
productivity or I'm really passionate
about state scale storage systems and I
don't want to think about any of the other
stuff. You may not actually be happy in
the long run in leadership positions.
It may be fine as an individual contributor,
but for leaders in particular, there's a lot
more to it than the fun tech problems, the
fun operations problems, even the product.
You said there's a few things we haven't
touched on. Is there anything else?
That's the fastest and anybody who's
interested, my book will be coming
out in the next couple of months from
O'Reilly and covers all of this depth.
Yeah, is there a date specifically
people should watch out for?
I think it's actually pre-order on Amazon now.
It's called Platform Engineering, and then,
there's ... I think it's like a guide
for technical product and people leaders,
something like that. But I think the
release ... I don't know exactly when
the Kindle release will be, but we're still in
copy edits, but it should be done pretty soon.
Okay, amazing. So you can pre-order it now.
Rolling to it obviously in the show notes and
description, it's called Platform Engineering.
Before we get to a very exciting lightning round,
I want to take us to a recurring segment
on this podcast that I call AI Corner. AI
is very top of mind for a lot of people and
I'm always curious how people are finding it
valuable in their work or in their life. So
the question is there anything you've found
AI to be helpful with ... in your AI work?
Any way you use it in an interesting way?
I find it helpful, for example, if I've written
a sentence and I'm like, I like this sentence,
but I feel like, I don't like the phrasing or
the format that I've used, it needs to be edited,
but I can't quite figure out how. I will
often put it into ChatGPT and be like,
"Can you reframe this? Can you rephrase
this for me?" It doesn't always work well,
but sometimes it does. It's like, "Oh yeah, if
I just switched this around or changed this word
choice, it's a much easier to read sentence." I
do think it's ... I think it's just before that
and small. I think it's large, lots of texts
I haven't had as much luck with. I'm a little
bit of an AI novice still, I would say.
What I will say is that AI is really bad,
if you try to ask it for quotes or at least
ChatGPT is. I haven't used a lot of the other
ones that much. I actually saw there was some
Twitter or some social media thing that's like,
did Francis Ford Coppola get fake reviews
from ChatGPT of the new, what is it, Agopolus.
Yeah.
Agopolus maybe.
And I was like, I actually had that scenario
where I was like, I need a quote ... I was
looking for quotes for the book and I was
like, maybe ChatGPT knows, but I was like,
"Can you give me any good quotes on ..." I forget
what it was. Let's just say it was on managing
complexity or something like that, and it gave
me these really interesting quotes. I was like,
that's great, but I better double check that.
And they were not real. They were never real,
not a single quote. And I'd be like, that's
not actually a real quote. Yes, you're right.
That's not, so here's a different one.
I was like, that's still not a real quote,
so don't ask it for quotes because ... or if
you do, make sure it's a real quote and not just
an interestingly phrased ... I mean good
summarization in some ways of the text,
it was sort of quoting from,
just not an actual quote.
That's a good reminder of just generally don't
assume what it's telling is true. Generally,
it's not giving you real things. It's
making things up and usually they're right,
but often they might not be right. That's a
really good reminder. On that first tactic,
is there a prompt that you find helpful
for how to actually feed it in there?
Is it just here's a line, help me
come up with a better version of it?
No, I have not figured out the prompt engineering
thing at all. I tried to get it to summarize a
paper for me the other day, and it literally
gave me the summary of a different paper,
and then I asked friends and they were like,
"Well, here's a summary." I was like, "Actually,
that seems like a good summary." And they're like,
"Well, first I told the AI that it was an expert
in the field and that it needed to read carefully
and that it was really smart," and I'm just like,
how do I have to manage the machine?
I already have to manage all of these
humans? Why are you making me
manage machines now too, please?
I thought this was going to solve all of our
problems. Yeah, that role. There's an acronym
for how to approach engineering, and there's
always like give it the role. Here's the role
you're going to play for me. You are an amazing
writer and here's what I want from you. Yeah.
I'm also very bad at it. By the way, Claude I
here is really good at writing. That's one of
its superpowers, so if you want to try writing,
that's worth trying. Claude by Anthropic. On the
second point you made of fake quote. So,
yeah, Francis Ford Coppola is coming out
with this movie with ... As you mentioned, this
trailer is just full of all these quotes that
people supposedly said about all his other movies
that Godfather and stuff. And they're all like,
these are terrible ... They're all
terribly mean quotes about his movies.
It turns out, yeah, they're all not
real quotes, and they actually took
down the trailer, I just read because he's
just making up quotes by famous critics.
Well, so maybe-
Maybe it was ChatGPT.
You can get fooled. I don't know if it was ChatGPT
or a cheeky intern or something, but we can get-
Or very intentional marketing stint.
Or that.
Yeah. Anyway, with that Camille, we have reached
our very exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
Yes.
Amazing. Okay. First question,
what are two or three books that you've
recommended most to other people?
So the first one is, What Got You Here Won't
Get You There. I love it. I think anybody who
is trying to challenge themselves and grow, should
read it, it's fantastic. The second one is called
When Things Fall Apart by Pema Chodron. That
is when you are ... For me anyway, when I am
struggling with whatever circumstances around me,
I find it a very soothing or reminder that life
is hard and the best way to ... you just sort of
have to breathe with it and be with it and let it
remind you of how life is hard for everyone and
sort of make you a kinder person in the process.
Is there a favorite recent movie
or TV show you've really enjoyed?
I loved Alien Romulus. It was great. If
you like a scary alien movie, fantastic.
I hate scary movies, so that's
a new Alien movie. Okay.
Yeah.
Anyone know there was a new Alien movie.
I loved it.
Awesome. Is there a favorite product you've
recently discovered that you really love,
whether it's an app or even physical product?
So I don't know about recent, I'm a big
Whoop fan. I got it during the pandemic
and it is one of my ... I'm just a
weird fan girl for it. I don't know.
I just really ... I enjoy it. I use it
every day. Maybe it's totally inaccurate,
but it seems accurate enough and I just
find it a very interesting and cool product.
I know Whoop product, people listen
to this podcast, so I think they'll
be happy to hear that. Two more questions.
Do you have a favorite life motto that you
often come back to, share with friends or
family, find useful and work around life?
If you don't challenge yourself, if you don't
take risks, you'll never grow. That's a big
one. I think you've got to ... challenging
yourself, taking risks is how you grow. I
think the other one for me is stay curious. The
more you can remember that there's more that you
don't know than that you do know, and staying
open-minded and being willing to be wrong,
I think the happier you'll be and the
better you'll be as a leader for sure.
Final question, on the topic of working out,
you're blocking it with your head generally
during the podcast, when we moved ... Behind
you is a very significant looking barbell
set or dumbbell set, I don't know which one
is which. Talk about your workout regimen or
anything along the lines of how you work out.
I have been lifting rates probably for longer than
some of your podcast listeners have been alive,
which says more about my age than anything else.
So I used be ... I now have two kids, so I lift
weights as sort of maintenance, but I used to be
a very ... I could deadlift than twice my body
weight and I was just a very, very strong person.
Now of course, everybody is into weightlifting,
which makes the gym really annoying. So partly
why I have a set in here, a small set with a
baby sized bar is ... so when I can't make it to
the gym, I can at least lift a little bit at home.
What's your favorite workout, lifting wise?
I love really basic deadlift, squat,
overhead press, that kind of
very simple, the classic lifts.
Amazing. Camille, this is awesome.
As everything, I was hoping it'd be,
we covered so much stuff. Two final questions.
Where can folks find you online if they want to
reach out, follow up on stuff and check out your
books and how can listeners be useful to you?
Yes, so with the weird state of social media now,
that's actually a harder question to answer than
it normally is. I am on LinkedIn, so you can
always follow me on LinkedIn and I'll probably
... I haven't traditionally put that much there,
but I'm expecting I'll probably start putting
more there in the coming months. I also still use
Medium when I write. I actually like Medium, so
medium.com, scamille is my username. Those are two
good ways. I have a Twitter/X account that it is
currently locked, and I may or may not unlock
it at some point, but social media, as I said,
has gotten weird. So I think probably LinkedIn
is the easiest way for this kind of stuff.
And I read somewhere that scamille is rooted in
your love of ska music back when
you were younger. Is that right?
It's true, yes. It was from high
school. I was a big ska fan.
It's funny how our usernames just stick from,
we were really young and that's the way
we're represented online now forever.
Yeah.
That's absurd. And then, you
didn't answer my final question,
which is how can listeners be useful to you?
I have a new book coming out. I have another
book that I've already written. Obviously,
I love it when people buy my books so I love when
people share my books with other people. My first
book is translated into a bunch of languages,
which is super exciting, and I hope that if you
read it and enjoy it and learn something from it,
you will let me know. Tag me on some social media.
I think that's just awesome and stay tuned. Look,
if you are looking for people potentially to come
talk to your company about platform engineering, I
could be interested in that, but I always love to
meet interesting people. If you're in New York,
reach out, who knows. This has been an amazing,
amazing time getting to chat with you, Lenny.
Thank you so much for inviting me on the show.
I feel the same way. Thank you for
agreeing to come on the show, Camille,
you're awesome. Thank you so much for being here.
Take care.
Bye everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.