Today, I am super excited to bring you a
very special episode with Shreyas Doshi,
recorded live at the Lenny and Friends Summit
in front of 1,000 people in San Francisco. This
is Shreyas' second time on the podcast.
His first visit is the third most popular
episode of all time of this podcast, and
I love that Shreyas was game to try this.
In our conversation, Shreyas shares three
questions plus a bonus question that he
wished he'd asked himself sooner in his career.
We talk about why product leaders are so busy,
why the job is so frustrating, why
it is so central to build good taste,
and also why you're probably not listening as
well as you should be. This was so much fun,
a huge thank you to Shreyas for doing this.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. It's the best
way to avoid missing future episodes, and
helps the podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you Shreyas Doshi. Shreyas, thank you so
much for being here, and welcome to the podcast.
Thanks, Lenny, for having me. This is amazing.
I was going to ask, we recorded our
first episode, I think two years ago,
and I was in a tiny room in my
house. I don't know where you were,
but it was very not like this.
Thoughts on the setup of this episode?
So first, the Lenny Empire keeps growing,
which is amazing to see. And second,
as I was coming up here, somebody told
me this used to be a car dealership,
and I actually realized I purchased my car here.
What?
So crazy, only in SF.
What kind of car was this? Say more.
It was a Honda CR-V.
Okay, wow. I am told this venue was also
used for... Jimi Hendrix performed here,
and Aretha Franklin performed here. So it's
like Jimi Hendrix, Aretha Franklin, Shreyas.
There we go, that's going
up on my Twitter bio soon.
Okay, so usually, when we talk, you're full
of ideas and you're full of answers. When we
were preparing for this, you told me, "I have
questions, I have questions I want to ask."
You know, reflecting on my career
as a PM leader over the years,
there are some questions I
wish I had asked myself sooner,
but I did not, and I had the great luck of
having a life, a PM life full of suffering,
and I have zero complaints about it. But as I
look back, I feel like there are some questions
that even if I asked myself some questions, those
questions, I wasn't honest to myself about the
answers. So that's what I thought I'd do, is share
the questions that I wish I'd asked myself sooner.
Awesome.
Yeah.
Love that, okay. This episode is brought to
you by WorkOS. If you're building a SaaS app,
at some point your customers will
start asking for enterprise features,
like SAML authentication and SCIM provisioning.
That's where WorkOS comes in, making it fast and
painless to add enterprise features to your app.
Their APIs are easy to understand so that you can
ship quickly and get back to building other
features. Today, hundreds of companies are
already powered by WorkOS, including ones you
probably know like, Vercel, Webflow, and Loom.
WorkOS also recently acquired Warrant, the Fine
Grained Authorization service. Warrant's product
is based on a groundbreaking authorization system
called Zanzibar, which was originally designed for
Google to power Google Docs and YouTube. This
enables fast authorization checks at enormous
scale, while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases. If
you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features,
like single sign-on, SCIM, or user management,
you should consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in
replacement for Auth0 and supports up to 1 million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
workos.com to learn more. That's workos.com.
This episode is brought to you by Paragon,
the developer platform for building native,
customer-facing integrations with third-party
apps. Are native integrations on your
product roadmap? Whether it's to ingest
context from your user's external data and
documents, or to sync data and automate tasks
across your users' other apps, integrations are
mission-critical for B2B software products today.
But building these integrations in-house cost
an average of three months of engineering,
according to the 2024 State of Integration survey,
which results in difficult roadmap trade-offs.
This is why engineering teams at Coffee AI, AI21,
and over 100 other B2B SaaS companies use Paragon,
so they can focus their efforts on core
product features, not integrations. The result,
they've shipped integrations seven times faster,
all while avoiding the never-ending maintenance
that comes with rolling your own integrations.
Visit useparagon.com/lenny to see how Paragon
can help you accelerate your product's integration
roadmap today and get $1,000 in credit on their
Pro and Enterprise plans. That's useparagon.com.
What's the first question?
Right, so let's see, the first question is why am
I so busy? Why am I so busy? And the background
is that I have spent most of my career just being
completely stressed out, just absolutely stressed
out every day. And there were many reasons for
it, but one of the core reasons was I was always
super busy, and there was always work I felt like
I couldn't do that I wanted to do, and so I would
go home at the end of the day, and even if I
had worked hard, I'd just feel dissatisfied.
And so that was a constant fixture of my life as
a PM, PM leader, and it's only... So I did product
work for about 20 years before I started this new
chapter of my career. And I think I only fixed it
in the last three or four years of my career as
a PM leader. But that means that there were about
16 or 17 years where I was just incredibly
busy, and because I was incredibly busy,
I was extremely stressed, and even though I was
doing a good job, I was not feeling very good
inside. And then, that showed up in my body,
like all sorts of pains and aches I realized
were actually not physical pains and aches.
They were pains and aches from the stress.
It's like health issues that you had?
Yeah, yeah, minor stuff. I mean,
relatively minor stuff, but playing tennis,
and you pull your back muscle, and now you are
horizontal for three days, doesn't feel good.
Who here is very, very busy, and is
just way too busy? Raise your hand.
That's it?
Yeah, I know.
Whoa.
Everyone's like [inaudible 00:07:39]
everybody. Yeah, people were like,
"Yeah, yeah. I don't have to raise my
hand, I'm busy." Yeah. Okay, keep going.
Yeah, and so here's the thing, when we talk
about being busy, and managing your time,
energy, all of that, I mean, this is a group of
senior product people, so you all know that. Take
tips and techniques, like maintain a to-do list.
I found the LNO framework very useful for me,
which I've shared before. I used to like
working out of a calendar, those types of
things. And I think you're all familiar with those
things, but what I wanted to call out is that,
at some point in our product career, we reach
something, we reach an immovable force that
will just overwhelm us, no matter what we do.
And that force is a scope. Okay, so as we grow
in our product career, our scope grows, and
we kind of like that, which is all great,
but at some point, if you haven't already gotten
there, many of you have, but for those of you who
haven't, you will get there, where your scope will
be so large, that no matter what you do in terms
of efficiency, whatever framework you use for
prioritization, whatever framework or tool you
use to manage your to-do list, whatever
tools and techniques you use, whatever
prioritization you do, your scope is so large
that you are still going to be incredibly busy.
And so that's what I faced, like I
was saying for the first about 16,
17 years of working on products, and only in the
last 3 or 4 years was I able to kind of find some
answers on how to deal with that scope. And so
perhaps we can talk about that, what do you think?
Yeah, so you're basically saying
there's all these productivity tricks,
ways to do more faster. And no matter
how many of these tools you've got,
you are just going to take on more and
more work, and they'll peter out? I'll
say many of my most popular newsletters posts
are, "Here's productivity tricks and tips."
And so people are always looking for these.
And I'm curious to hear where you go with this,
of just like that is not the answer
long term, there's a different approach?
Yes, and so the challenge is the following. How
many of you are going through some kind of annual
planning right now or you're planning on going
through annual planning? Please. Everybody loves
annual planning, great. So let's take annual
planning. If you are a high-level manager,
leader within a company, what does your month
look like? Or in some cases, unfortunately, what
do your two or three months look like when you
are going through annual planning? It's all these
kind of spreadsheets to fill out, and meetings
to have, and dependencies, and priorities, and
stakeholders to meet, and so on. And so I noticed,
for instance, that at some point, that was making
me really busy, and then that was making me
feel guilty now, because I had my team to
look after and to support, and then I had product
decisions to make and various other things, and
I've gone on some planning retreat or whatever.
And there you go, you last four, five, six, weeks,
does that sound familiar to folks? Yeah? Okay,
so I noticed that I needed to change that at
some point, and actually found a solution, again,
late in my career, but I found a solution, because
I asked myself this question, which is, "Why am
I so busy? I'm doing all the efficiency things,
I'm managing my to-do list like a champ. I have my
calendar set up just right. I have my routine set
up just right. I'm working out so that I'm engaged
at work, I'm productive, I'm doing all of that.
Why am I so busy? Oh, it's planning season, and
that is supposed to take up four to six weeks."
And this was at Stripe when I encountered this.
So that is supposed to take up four to six weeks.
Well, I realized that you don't have to do that.
And so at some point in my time at Stripe, what
I realized is the following, we go through a whole
all sorts of just rituals around planning for four
to six weeks. Then, we emerge and we share our
plan with our executives. You know the questions
they're going to ask, like, "If money were no
concern, what would you do? What is your ambitious
plan? So if we gave you five more engineers, what
would you do? What other things would you include
in the roadmap?" Right? The standard stuff.
And so you emerge, you do your presentation,
and then you publish the plan, and then you start
the new year with a lot of enthusiasm and a lot
of excitement. And January goes fine, until you
get three customer escalations for features that
were not in your plan. And so now, you try to
figure out how you're going to revise resources.
You go talk to some dependency team that's going
to sort of support these new features from these
customer escalations. And you go through that
process, and you revise your plan again. And then,
usually by the time it's last week of February,
everybody's forgotten the actual plan. And now,
we are executing off of some other list somewhere.
And by the way, when you mention this at times,
politely of course, you might mention like,
"You know, I'm noticing we are not actually
really using the plan that we spent four
to six weeks minimum doing." And then,
some smart person in the room chimes in with,
"Plans are useless, but planning is everything."
I don't know, Eisenhower, somebody else, I
don't know who said this, "Plans are useless,
but planning is everything." Nobody knows
what it means. Nobody knows what that means,
but everybody appreciates, "Ah, plans are useless,
but planning is everything." Right? So I went
through a few years of this. And then I go, "You
know what? I'm going to bend some rules here."
And so what I realized, Lenny, is you don't
have to go through these four to six weeks,
and it was an accident. Basically, what happened
is around that time, the product I was working on,
Stripe Connect, it's like a major product for
Stripe, major, major business for Stripe. And
I had put together a product strategy, like
a real product strategy for this product.
And so this must have been earlier in the year.
And so now, planning season came along. And the
interesting I found is that because I had a real
product strategy, not one of those fake ones,
a real product strategy that I had gotten
alignment on with everybody, my planning
for this major product for Stripe took me like
three days. Right, so while a lot of my peers,
unfortunately, for their own products, were
in this four-to-six week cycle of planning,
and meeting, and blah, blah, blah, I just put
it all together in three days, and whatever
artifacts were needed, I put them together.
I did not fill out some templates. That's
where it's about bending the rules, because
if a template doesn't make sense, why should
I fill it out? There's no need to fill it out.
And so that's when I realized that actually,
if you have a real product strategy, a
real one that everybody is aligned with,
that you have got pre-alignment on, then a lot of
this nonsense we tend to do with annual planning
actually goes away. Now, you still have to do
some resource allocation and all of that, but
even there, you don't need that false precision.
How many of you have gotten into arguments about,
"So should it be eight engineers for this team in
2025, or nine engineers for this team in 2025?"
Like, who cares? We all know that even those
numbers that we set up, we don't actually follow
through on them, as 2025 happens. So that's
just an example of where we spend a lot of
time on things that we think are strategic,
that we think are important, but actually,
we ought to spend that time on other much higher
leverage things. Right, now it does require some
upfront work, in this case upfront work on a
clear product strategy that everybody understands,
that everybody's aligned on. But frankly, if
you have that, planning should be a breeze.
So what would be your kind of tactical tip
for folks that want to do this better? I know
there's probably a billion examples of these
sorts of things you shared, so planning is an
example. Folks that want to be less busy, maybe
on that one is it give yourself very little time,
and focus on strategy, and let that be the plan,
basically, versus every single person and their
roadmap for the next six months. What's the piece
of advice you'd share there? And then, I want to
move on to the next question, because I want to
make sure we get through all these questions.
Yes, there's definitely a specific tip, which
is if you do have a strategy that will make a
lot of your prioritization problems go away,
it will make a lot of planning problems go
away. And even if you do have some escalation
from sales, which you will, or from support,
or somewhere else, you now have at least a more
rigorous framework to figure out what to do with
that escalation. So there's definitely that.
But I think other thing I want to share is that,
and this was my other realization as I
asked the question, "Why am I so busy?"
is I realized that I am so busy because I'm
not making good product decisions. Okay, now,
you have to understand, by this time I'm like
15 years into building products and whatever,
11 years into being a product manager. And
so I think I'm pretty good. That's my kind
of self-image. But then, again,
if I'm being honest to myself,
I'm not making as good product decisions as
I can. So can I share an example of that?
Please.
So what I noticed is that you have a meeting
about some product feature that somehow is
requested or is really important, whatever the
case might be. And so you have a meeting with
some stakeholders and your engineering
team, designers, et cetera. And then,
you're trying to decide, "Should we build this or
not?" And somebody says, "You know what? Why are
we doing a meeting for this?" I read somewhere
or I heard Bezos say that two-way doors, it's a
two-way door. You quickly make a decision. Like,
just quickly make a decision and move on. This
is a two-way door. And so you say, "Yeah, that's
right." And any time we hear something like that,
two-way door, you're like, "Oh, that person's
really smart, so I want to be like them."
So I noticed that myself and my team, we were
making these kinds of decisions without very
clearly thinking through customer motivation,
very clearly thinking through differentiation,
very clearly thinking through a distribution
approach for whatever this feature is. And
while it sounds like, "Oh, of course you should
be doing this," I guarantee you this is not how
most product teams work. They're talking
about, "Well, is Bob the engineer going
to be free? And when are they free? And if they
are free, then let's build the feature." That's
kind of how a lot of product decisions happen.
The challenge here with this kind of approach,
and again, this is what happens in practice,
I'm not talking about whatever theory you read,
this is what happens in practice. So when you
follow this approach and you assume that, "Oh,
this is a two-way door, we can kill the feature,"
in reality, it doesn't work out that way,
because here's what happens in reality.
So in reality, you commit to the feature,
and it's going to take five, six weeks to do
it, and then a couple more weeks to make sure,
to ramp it up, et cetera, right? And so now the
feature is out, and now you have your Q1 QBR,
right? Say two months from now you have your Q1
QBR, and you're going to present your business
review, whatever. You're going to present
what you did, "What did you do last quarter?
How are your ships performing from last quarter?"
And so now, it's time to talk about this feature
at the QBR, because you have to share that/
Now as you start talking about this feature,
the CEO will ask, "So yeah, we launched
the feature. I'm very glad we launched
this feature. How is it doing?" And you want
to be able to say, you are the PM leader,
you want to be able to say something smart, and
something that makes you look competent. But the
challenge is the feature hasn't had much adoption.
So I'm not going to ask anybody to raise hands,
but I think most PMs are familiar with this
conundrum. And of course, we are verbally very
agile as product leaders. So what we say is we
don't have data, so we use favorable anecdotes.
And so we say, "Yeah, we launched the feature,
and you know what? This customer from this company
really loves the feature." And we put in an
anecdote, it's like, "Life-changing feature."
It doesn't matter that they're the only person
using it. That doesn't matter. "Life-changing
feature," right? We use data when it favors us,
we use anecdotes when it favors us. So anyway,
so we present that. Now. we do have
the sales counterpart in the room too,
our sales counterpart, and they say, "You know
what, though? We are still not winning many deals
because of this feature." And so of course the CEO
asks, "So what's up? Why aren't we winning deals,
even though we have the feature?"
So the people on the customer side
usually we respond, "Well, I'm glad we have
the feature, but it's not full featured yet.
We need all these other bells and whistles to
meet the table stakes." So now, what happens?
Somebody uttered the word, "Meet the table
stakes." Now, it's over for you, because now,
the only response you can give is, "Oh, yeah,
that's already part of the plan." And now,
you put your engineering leader on the spot and
you say, "Alice, isn't it? Haven't we allocated
engineers to it already?" And so now, Alice has to
come up with some response, which is like, "Yeah,
yeah, yeah, Carol and David are going to work
on it. It's slotted for one of these sprints."
And so now, you exit the QBR, you high-five
each other. Well, "Good job, team, great job,"
et cetera, et cetera. But now, you have signed up
for even more work for a feature you should not
have built in the first place. That's why we're
busy. And through a product leader's life, what
happens is we just accumulate all of this debt,
feature after feature. So I guess what I'm saying,
Lenny, is one of my other tactical tips would be
sometimes it is useful to pause for two minutes,
or two days, or two weeks before making that
decision, right? Because frankly, most doors
that look like two-way doors are actually one-way
doors. They are two-way doors at Bezos' level,
but as a PM leader, for you, they are a
one-way door, and that's making you busy.
Wow. I feel like you're a stand-up
comedian/product manager. That was incredible.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta.
When it comes to ensuring your company
has top-notch security practices, things get
complicated fast. Now, you can assess risk,
secure the trust of your customers, and
automate compliance for SOC 2, ISO 27001,
HIPAA, and more with a single platform, Vanta.
Vanta's market-leading trust management platform
helps you continuously monitor compliance,
alongside reporting and tracking risk. Plus,
you can save hours by completing
security questionnaires with Vanta AI.
Join thousands of global companies that
use Vanta to automate evidence collection,
unify risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go to
vanta.com/lenny. That's vanta.com/lenny.
I know it's Spotify, I heard one of their
core values is, "Talk is cheap," but it's
the virtue version of that. It's like,
they actually prefer to talk more, and I think
that's exactly what you're saying. Basically,
spend more time on these things that seemingly
seem just small little ideas and experiments.
Yep, thinking is cheap, so you
should do more thinking, not less.
Amazing. Shreyas, what's your second question?
Yes. So my second question, I
have to get the words right,
do I actually have good taste? Do I actually
have good taste is my second question.
And for me, I asked this question after, again,
all of these things... By the way, everything I
say, I have been that guy, I've made that mistake.
So that's why I just have to admit to myself that,
yes, I have made these mistakes. And one of the
mistakes I made, this was when I was at Google,
and I was relatively new to product,
about less than five years. And at Google,
there's some parts of Google where you would
be told as an early career PM that like,
"We don't do strategy here. Strategy is for
MBAs, okay? We are all about execution, okay?"
So I'm in this environment, I'm naïve, and I
look around me and I'm like, "Google is the
most successful company on the planet," at the
time, and they are saying this, and I'm hearing
this consistently, so it must be right. It must be
right. And so I start saying it. I start saying,
"Oh, yeah, execution is everything, and we don't
do strategy around here." And I even remember
there were not that many PMs, but there was a
PM at Google who was kind of like the same level
as me, but he just had much more wisdom than me.
And he was trying to nudge me into... Like, I was
managing a product. And he's like, "Shreyas, what
is your strategy here?" And I was like, I told
him the same thing. Like, "Oh, no, no, what are
you talking strategy? We don't need strategy. We
just need to get shit done." That was the thing.
And so I kept repeating that mantra until I got
to Twitter. So this is Twitter right after their
IPO. And I saw Twitter had an incredible asset,
which is the product and the network effects. It
had other incredible assets, including the brand.
It had other assets that were great, including
the talent. And yet, this company was struggling,
the product was struggling. And even if
it wasn't struggling, it was making a lot
of money. But the point is it was not meeting
its potential. So that's when I realized, and
it wasn't like some sudden realization, it took
me six to nine months of being at Twitter. This
is circa 2014. That's when I realized that, "Oh,
my gosh, Twitter's biggest problem is a product
strategy problem. The reason they're struggling
is they don't have a real product strategy."
Now, of course, attempts were made to create a
product strategy, but it wasn't a real compelling,
cohesive product strategy. So that's
when I realized the folly of like, "Oh,
wait a minute..." I was at Google six
years. I spent most of those six years
saying like, "Ah, strategy's useless. There's
no point to strategy. Execution is where it's
at. "I'm like, "No, actually, I was wrong." And
that got further solidified as I went to Stripe,
and I was kind of now growing earlier stage
products and trying to make them highly,
highly successful. I saw an even greater value
and importance of having a clear strategy.
And so that made me realize, basically...
You know, we talk about taste, we all talk
about taste, and it's about the beautiful pixels,
and the perfect product, and the whatever else,
the Steve Jobs-esque passion, and all of that,
whatever it is. And yes, taste is about that,
but I think there is something that we
as product leaders, and certainly I did,
needed to recognize about taste as just a factor
in pretty much everything we do, which is like,
do we have good taste around the beliefs we choose
to create within ourselves as product leaders? And
then, those beliefs end up dictating everything we
do, including how we manage, how we lead, how we
make decisions. And so it's that taste I'm talking
about when I say, "Do I really have good taste?"
And when I asked myself this question, and again,
I really had to dig deep. It wasn't easy, but at
some point I realized that no, actually, I don't
have good taste. I don't have good taste in how I
choose to evaluate things that come my way. Again,
not in terms of the product, because by that time
I had skills to say, "Well, this should not be a
two-step flow. This should be a three-step flow,"
whatever the case may be. But I still did not have
good taste in terms of how I choose what are the
things I choose to believe, how do I learn, who
do I learn from, what content I learned from,
what content I resonate with? And then, I went on
this journey to try to develop that better taste.
What I'm hearing is people focus maybe too
much on the output, like the experience,
these experience design taste versus what they
choose to take in as informing their taste,
and what they see as an example of great
and correct. Is that what you're saying?
Yeah. And look, taste is about the ability to
identify what is really good, without needing
to see its results, because, look, it requires
zero taste right now for anybody to say, "Oh,
that CEO of NVIDIA is a genius, right? Jensen
is a genius." If you are saying that in 2024,
it actually requires zero taste, because
you can just look up NVIDIA stock price.
It requires zero skill. But to be able to say
that in 2010, you have to realize Jensen Huang
didn't change much between 2010 and 2024. So
Lenny, even in sports, there's this saying,
"Game recognize game," and that's about taste.
But what we need to understand is it's game
recognize game before the game is called, right?
Like, game recognize game in the practice session.
Because it takes no genius right now to say,
"Well, Patrick Mahomes is great quarterback," or,
"Virat Kohli is a great cricketer," or
whatever else. It requires no genius to do
that. It requires zero taste. So I also believe
some of us, especially as we get more senior,
and we get more successful, and we just get
a lot more scope, and responsibility, and a
lot of accolades, we become these tough graders.
Like, "I don't like anything," right? Like, "Ah,
this is crap, this is crap, this is crap." Again,
that requires zero taste. Anybody can say that.
Anybody can just say, "Everything is horrible."
So I do think there is something about being able
to understand that, and I think I'll share some
examples. This two-way door thing, so let me just
share a few observations, if I might. So the first
one is we get overly excited about cool metaphors,
okay? Like, one-way door, two-way doors.
There's some guy, I don't know who it is,
I just read somewhere, there's some guy who
had written a blog post about this idea,
but he called it reversible and irreversible
decisions, and it was the same idea. And I think
somebody was lamenting that that did not catch on,
reversible and irreversible decisions. But what
caught on is two-way door and one-way door. What's
the difference? The only difference is you got
attracted to the catchy metaphor, and the other
one is the authority bias, because Bezos said it.
Take another example, we get very
impressed with alliterations. I'm serious,
we get very impressed with alliterations. Okay,
so how many of us love fail fast? Fail fast,
okay, nobody's going to raise hands now. Okay,
fine. Maybe you truly don't love fail fast. How
about fast follow? How many of you love fast
follow? Let's consider that, like fail fast,
"We're going to fail fast." What if that thing
were called fail quickly? It's the same meaning.
Do you think you would be as attracted to
that idea if it were called fail quickly?
No.
Probably not, so what changed? The only thing that
changed is one is an alliteration. So I see this
in everything. Like, let's see, the other one is
we also get very impressed with complicated charts
and math we don't understand. And some of you
product leaders who are at the top of the game,
you actually use this as a strategy. So as I
realized that here's the outcome of that, asking
myself that question, was that what I realized
is everybody says, "Oh, I'm a first principle
thinker. I am a rigorous thinker," whatever.
But I realized that if I really want to be that,
I have to shed a lot of these just
patterns that were just built in me,
and I kind of have to evaluate the idea
separate from all of its social proof,
and authority proof, and whatever else. And
that ended up being a meaningful change in my
growth as a product leader, because the moment
I started shedding these kinds of social proofs,
and authority proofs, and all of that,
it just made me a much... We all again
think we are critical thinkers, but we are not,
right? So it made me a more critical thinker.
I want to move on to the next question,
just so we can get through some of these
questions. Before I do, can you just
show people your notes real quick,
just like show it from a distance? This
is how Shreyas plans for something like
this. There's color coding, I wish I
understood what was going on there.
People ask me, "What's your favorite
note-taking app?" It's a common question
I get, and I say this, right? It's a
$5... Like I guess the pen costs $3,
and I think the Office Depot clipboard costs-
Wait, doesn't that pen... Does it
have the different color clicky thing?
Yes, yes, yeah. A [inaudible 00:38:04].
Yeah, exactly. This is great.
That's going to be another podcast episode. Okay,
so we want to try to do two more questions. We
have six minutes left. The last one's a bonus,
so maybe we touch on it briefly.
Shreyas, what's your third question?
So my third question is why does my job feel so
frustrating? Why does my job feel so frustrating?
And it goes back to the point that, look,
I loved, loved my PM leadership job. I just
absolutely loved it. And I think looking back,
I would not have exchanged it for anything else,
any other experience. That said, there were daily
frustrations. There were daily frustrations in
that job, and a lot of it has to do with the fact
that the PM leader's job is extremely lonely. The
PM's job, the PM's on your team, their job is
also lonely. But a PM leader's job is further
lonelier. So there's that. There's also what I
learned at the time when I started asking this
question is that our jobs get frustrating when we
behave, most of the time, in misalignment with our
superpowers and who we truly are at our core.
Okay, so for me, as I was evaluating that
question, it's like, "Why am I getting frustrated
every day? I love the job, I love the macro,
but I do not like the micro. And so why is that?"
And that's when I actually... There's a simple
framework that I've shared, which is you can be
doing your work at three levels. Product work
happens at three levels. There's the impact level,
there's the execution level, and there's the
optics level. My epiphany as I was exploring this
question was I have a preferred level at which I
like to operate, but if most of the day, and most
of the week, and most of the month, I am forcing
myself to operate in not my happy place, in my
non-default level, that makes me very frustrated.
So many product leaders, their happy place is the
execution level. In my case, my happy place is the
impact level. So that is fine. Your happy place
can be whatever level, it doesn't matter. But the
point is, as you go higher up in the corporate
ladder, no matter what kind of company it is,
you are now going to have to spend a lot of
time on optics, at the optics level. And I have
willpower, I have the skills to do it, I have all
of that. So it's not about willpower or skills,
but willpower is finite. So as I spent day in and
day out, just mostly doing optics work, I realized
I was not happy and I was getting frustrated. And
so that's when I realized the solution, which is
I have to abandon the traditional path, that like,
"Oh, after this level, I'm supposed to do this,
and then I'm supposed to do this, and then this
is what society expects. This is what my mom
expects. What will people say on LinkedIn
when they see my LinkedIn profile?" Like,
"Oh, he has this progression, this, and
then what stopped? Why did it stop?"
So when I realized this, I said, when a team
grew to a certain size, so when I was at
Stripe and I realized this, when the team I was
managing, it had a fan out of about 50 people,
so this includes engineers and everything,
I said, "This is enough." Because for me,
any time a team goes to like 50s, and 100s, and
beyond, it is a law of corporations that you're
going to have to spend a lot of time at the optics
level. So instead of just pushing, pushing through
against who I truly am, what did I do? I just
went back to more of an earlier stage product,
and then I was fine with like, "You
know what? I'm not going to just
play the corporate game," as an example.
So I guess my suggestion would be identify
your superpowers, and like Shakespeare said,
"To thine own self be true." Just be honest to
yourself. Operate your career and make your career
decisions not out of expectation, not out of envy,
like the LinkedIn envy of like, "Oh,
this person is at a different level.
We both went to the same grad school, so
I got..." No, identify your superpowers,
because if you identify your superpowers and work
in accordance with them, you will do the best work
of your life. You will love it, and you will be
great at it, and you won't have that frustration.
I wish we had an hour for every
single one of these questions,
I feel like there's so much more to get
into. We have 40 seconds. Do you want to
touch on your last question or do you want
to leave that for a follow-up discussion?
Let's touch on it, let's touch on it.
Okay, we got to go though in 30 seconds.
All right. My last question is am I really
listening? Okay, and this is perhaps the hardest
one for me, because I thought, of course I'm a
good listener because I listen, then I recap, and
I make eye contact, and I tell them, "This is what
I heard," And all of that nonsense. I realized
there is an entirely other level to listening,
which once you understand that there's an entirely
other level to listening, that is what enables
you to be a world-class leader. And so that is
what I guess my last takeaway is, is ask yourself,
"Am I really listening?" If you want resources,
there are very few people who actually talk about
what that real listening means. I would refer you
to what Rick Rubin says about listening, I
would refer you to what [inaudible 00:44:30]
said about listening, and what Drucker
said about listening as some pointers.
Amazing. Shreyas, you said you were
going to hang out for the next hour
somewhere. You want to share that
real quick, and then we'll get off?
Yes, I will maybe try to hang
out in the back part of the room.
Be quiet back there, too.
Yes.
Shreyas, thank you so much for being here.
Great, thank you. Oh, should we take a picture?
Oh, yeah. We're going to take a quick selfie.
We're going to take a picture.
There we go. They're going
to turn lights on, I think.
Oh.
Okay.
All right, folks.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to the show on
Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite podcast
app. Also, please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review, as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.