When you're looking for a job, you need
a spear and not a net. What happens when
we're building a product? Same thing, right?
We want this product to be for everyone,
but we've learned with product market fit that
doesn't work. We need a narrow, clear focus.
How did you realize this is a
really powerful method versus
the way people normally look for jobs?
While it's hard to figure out your candidate
market fit, it's also a relief to know it's
not about you. So what I ask people to do is
I ask them to think about what they want and
what they don't want. Now, you might
not think that that's a radical step,
Lenny, but most people don't do that. When
they get laid off, they spray and pray.
This is very much like a product
person thinks about new product.
There's no I in team. Well,
there is an I in village,
and the I in village is that when
you start to interview and negotiate,
you've got to be in charge. I want
you to play to win, not not to lose.
Is there anything else that you think might
be helpful to people looking for jobs?
If someone did this, it would blow my
mind. I would hire them on the spot.
Today my guest is Phyl Terry. Phyl is the author
of Never Search Alone, which I've seen so many
people reference as the most impactful thing
they read for helping them find a job. Once
you listen to this episode, you'll see why.
Prior to this book, Phyl was on the founding
team of the first company that
Amazon acquired back in the '90s,
and then was CEO of the pioneering product and
customer experience consulting firm Creative
Good for over 15 years, where Phyl and the team
had companies like Apple, Facebook, Microsoft,
and hundreds of other companies as customers.
Phyl also co-authored Customers Included,
has written articles for the Harvard Business
Review, and has delivered more than 500 keynotes
to companies like Apple and Microsoft. This
episode is for anyone struggling to find a job
or unhappy in the job that they're in. I promise
you, the time you put into listening to this
episode will help you find a job that you love.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. It's the best
way to avoid missing feature episodes and
helps the podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you Phyl Terry. Phyl, thank you so much
for being here, and welcome to the podcast.
Oh, what a pleasure. I'm
such a fan of yours, Lenny.
I'm thrilled to be here.
Thank you.
I'm a huge fan of yours, and I think by the end
of this I'll be an even bigger fan of yours.
What I'm hoping that we can do in our chat
today is to help people who are struggling
to find a job and especially struggling to
find a job they love, actually find that job
with actual tips that they can use today
in this week. How does that feel to you?
That's great. We have some practical
time-tested stuff that I've developed
over the last 25 years with leaders in
Silicon Valley, especially in the product
community. We've really brought a product
lens to reinventing the job search, Lenny.
This is a perfect Venn diagram of topics then.
Yes.
There's a lot of ways I can approach
this. I want to start with a question
about something that you run, something that
you created, something that has had a lot of
impact on a lot of people: Job Search
Councils. What is a Job Search Council?
It's a support group of six to eight job seekers,
so product people, but it is not just for product
people, but the product community really owns
this, it comes out of the product community.
And what they do is they commit to being
with each other, to supporting each other,
go through the process of looking for a job and
I lay out a methodology, how to figure out your
candidate market fit, one of the big concepts
in the book. As well as how to play to win,
not not to lose. You know what I mean? People are
scared in the job search. Here's the thing, Lenny,
that people really have a hard time believing,
everyone, I mean everyone, and I work with some
of the most senior people in Silicon Valley,
I'm talking about CEOs of public companies,
I'm talking about chief product officers,
VPs of product at great brands, everyone,
no matter who they are, Lenny, feels insecure
and anxious in the job search. And if you do
it alone, it magnifies that.
So with Job Search Councils,
there's this great hack, I didn't invent this,
it's baked into human psychology, if you put
anxious people together and ask them to be open
and vulnerable and to ask for help, and we'll come
back to asking for help, it actually flips the
anxiety and the fear into hope, into motivation,
into accountability and confidence. It's like,
"What [inaudible 00:04:20]?" It's fantastic.
My mother taught me this, we can talk about
her at some point, but it's really powerful.
That's amazing. Your whole book
is called Never Search Alone,
so the whole premise of how you recommend
people look for jobs is to look for jobs
with other people. You mentioned maybe it's
your mom, maybe it's something else, how did
you realize this is a really powerful method
versus the way people normally look for jobs?
Yeah. I set up my first council more than four
years ago. I set up the first CEO council for
internet CEOs in the mid '90s, and then I've run
product and CEO council since. But it goes all the
way back to my mom. 1960, Lenny, 1960, what is
that? 64 years ago? In the San Fernando Valley,
my mom was a newly-minted elementary school
teacher, and she put together a council of
teachers. That group met for 50 years, 5-0, until
the year she died. They worked together to ask for
help and support each other in their careers.
And Lenny, people say to me, "Does this Never
Search Alone method work in a tough job market?"
And I'll tell you, it comes out of tough job
markets. Absolutely, yes. Starting with my mom.
So in 1974, my dad... in 1976 he left and it was
just me and my mom and my sister. He had insisted
that she stop teaching, so she lost her tenure and
everything. Her candidate market fit was terrible,
but she had her council. It was the mid '70s,
and Lenny, you probably can't imagine how
hard it was for a single middle-aged woman
with kids looking for a job in Los Angeles
in the mid '70s. It was terrible. But she had
her support group and they held her hand. The job
she could get, guess what? She had to be an entry
level teacher again after having been a senior
teacher coaching and advising. It was really
tough. So that had a big impact on me.
And then when the dotcom bubble burst,
I was running Creative Good, and suddenly there
was a depression. And suddenly I'm helping
hundreds of people try to figure out their job
search. So it's been going for a number of years,
but it goes back to my mom. I dedicate the
book to her and the community we've built.
That's beautiful.
Let me tell you about a
product called Sidebar. The most successful
people that I know surround themselves with
incredible peers. When you have a trusted group of
peers, you can discuss challenges you're having,
get career advice, and just gut-check how
you're thinking about your work, your career,
and your life. This gives you more than a
leg up, it gives you a leap forward. Having
a group of trusted and amazing peers was key to
my career growth, and this is the Sidebar ethos.
But it's hard to build this trusted group of
peers on your own. Sidebar is a platform for
senior tech professionals, director to C-level, to
advance in their career. Members are matched into
peer groups to lean on for unbiased opinions,
diverse perspectives, and raw feedback. Guided
by world-class programming and facilitation all
running on Sidebar's technology, Sidebar enables
you to get focused, tactical feedback at every
step of your career journey. If you're listening
to this podcast, you're already committed to
growth. Sidebar is the missing piece to catalyze
your career. 93% of members say Sidebar helped
them achieve a significant positive change in
their career. Check them out at sidebar.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Sprig. What if
product teams knew exactly what to build to
reach their goals? From increasing conversion
to boosting engagement, these challenges
require a deep understanding of your users,
something that you can't get from
product analytics alone. Meet Sprig,
a product experience platform that generates
AI-powered opportunities to continuously improve
your product at scale. First, Sprig captures your
product experience in real time through heat maps,
replays, surveys, and feedback studies. Then
Sprig's industry-leading AI instantly analyzes
all of your product experience data to generate
real- time insights. Sprig AI goes even further
with actionable product recommendations to drive
revenue, retention, and user satisfaction. Join
product teams at Figma and at Notion by uncovering
AI-powered product opportunities at scale. Visit
sprig.com/lenny to book a demo and get a
$75 gift card. That's S-P-R-I-G.com/lenny.
There's a lot of elements that you mentioned that
we're going to dig into, so job candidate fit,
playing to win. You touched a little bit this
idea of settling, figuring out what to settle
for. Your mom took a job that's below what
she was doing before, so I want to chat about
all these things. A little bit more on these
councils. What's the scale of these? So I think
it's going to blow people's mind just how many
of these are happening and [inaudible 00:09:16]-
We have launched more than 2,000 of these
Lenny, 2,000, and they're completely free,
completely 100% free. It's volunteer-driven. We
have hundreds of pages of tools. We've done a
Slack community. We have a free matching
program. You can sign up and we'll match
you and put you in a council. Then we'll give
you training, live training. There's so many
volunteers. We have 20,000 hours of volunteer
work that's already been put into this, Lenny.
You said that it's free. I know
these things aren't free to run.
Yeah.
I saw somewhere that you mentioned that
basically all your book sales and also
just your own money you spend on running these
councils. Talk about that for a little bit.
Yeah, actually two times the book
sales are going into running this.
So we have 20,000 hours of volunteer time, but
you also have to pay for technology and you have
to pay for certain kinds of support. Later we
will talk about this, and we're always looking
for more volunteers. I have a process for people
to apply if they're interested in being a part
of the team. But yeah, I have dedicated this
to my mom, and I'm giving everything to it.
What's the general structure? If someone's
trying to think about how these things work,
if they want to join these as we
go through it, how do they work?
Okay, so you apply at phyl.org,
P-H-Y-L, Phyl with a Y. Again,
it's free. We match you behind the scenes.
Now, when you apply, we ask, "First of all,
are you in a job and looking or are you out of
work?" Because we separate those two because
they have different cadences. If you're in a job
and looking, we call you a slow seeker because
you have a full-time job and you can't work
as quickly. If you're out of work and looking,
we call you a fast seeker and we put you in
different groups. Fast seeker or slow seeker.
We also ask though, are you willing to be a
moderator? Every council needs a moderator,
and every moderator is a job seeker who volunteers
to do that. If you volunteer to moderate,
first of all, you get matched faster, and
secondly, you get more training and support.
It's a little bit more work for a lot more
benefit. We've gotten 2,000 moderators, Lenny,
it's amazing. And we feel like we're just
beginning. So you apply, you get matched,
and then you go through an orientation program
that we run live where we tell you how this works
and what to expect in your first meeting. And then
there's a whole set of agendas and materials and
everything in the book as well as everyone gets a
free workbook, a 100-page workbook after they join
the community with all of the templates and guides
and questions. And then the moderator pulls you
together, you work on Zoom or whatever technology,
it's remote typically. And you do a first meeting,
we call it meeting zero, where you're open and
vulnerable. People share stories about their
lives and who they are, builds trust and get
a sense of who people are. And then you move
into the process. You meet twice a week typically
if you're in a fast seeker council and every two
weeks if you're in a slow seeker. So that's the
start of the answer. Does that help you think?
Yeah, really helpful. And then you basically are
on this council until you find a job, I imagine.
Yeah.
Awesome.
Is there anything you can share around the
impact you've seen? The reason I reached out
to you to come on this podcast is I just started
seeing people mentioning that they found a job
and maybe the thing that helped them most was
your book and being on one of these councils.
I imagine there's a lot of stories you hear
and a lot of numbers you could see of just
people succeeding going through, so what can
you share about just the impact you've seen?
Well, I posted on LinkedIn today that I
was going to be on your podcast and I asked
people if they wanted to share stories
with me, and over email and LinkedIn,
I've been flooded with stories from people who are
in the process or people who did it. If you like,
I can pull up and share a few of
those if that would be helpful.
Yeah, if there's a few you have
there, that'd be really sweet.
Okay, so Justin Meats is a chief product officer
who's gone through the process and he posted on
LinkedIn today. He said, "As a product leader,
I love how it has you apply the product process
to your career." This comes out of the product
world, it's a product lens on the job search,
and it's for everyone, but it really makes
sense for product people. And he says,
"Not only does your JSC help bounce ideas and help
your job search, they also help you keep going and
accountable when you're low on emotional energy."
I talk about this in the book, Lenny, I say,
"Look, most people think, 'What's the most
important thing to manage during your job
search?'" They think, well, maybe it's their
resume or LinkedIn profile or their ability to
network or candidate market fit, a concept
I introduced I think is really important.
All those things are really important, but
the most important thing to manage is your
emotional balance. I talk about your emotional
balance sheet. And for many job seekers, they
have more liabilities than assets on their old
balance sheets. They have more fear and anxiety,
they feel demoralized, they have a hard time
going. That's why these things are so important.
He also says, "Hey, it's a journey, and the
more you embrace it, the more you learn about
yourself." And he says... and this is important
Lenny. I don't have a magic wand that especially
in a down market today that magically gets a
job. It's hard. The job search, it can be hard
and humiliating at times. I know. This is why I
want to create this community, why we're doing
this. We want to give you a place where you
can really get the support when it's hard and
humiliating. But the process will ultimately
set you up for success if you follow it.
This one woman who just started, she's a senior
product leader in a major financial institution,
and she said she couldn't believe the level
of support and openness and vulnerability. We
really emphasize people being open and vulnerable,
and I've learned a lot about how to create that
environment. It ties back to asking for help,
which I know we'll talk about more at some
point. But when you create that, it's amazing
what people can do together, Lenny. Amazing.
Just to reinforce this point, people listening
may be like, "I'm just going to keep looking
for a job. I'll use all this advice. I don't
need a group." What's your best pitch, again,
to help people see the value of doing this in a
group and joining a council or starting a council?
I acknowledge that that's a reaction that
some people have. That's totally valid.
This is unusual, what we're doing here. This is
not how people look for a job. We're trying to
disrupt the job search process. Lenny, this is
my quick story. We had a great interview with
a couple. Two of them were product leaders. They
had met at Amazon and then had gone to have great
careers. They both got laid off. The woman joined
a Job Search Council right away. She loved it,
she raved about it. Her husband, who was also
an engineer, was a little more introverted.
He's like, "Ah, this isn't for me." She said,
"No, listen, you won't... " And finally he
read the book. Because the book, it works for
the product mind and for the engineering mind,
it makes sense. He said, "I'll join a council,
but I'm not going to be field connected to people.
But I'll do this because you asked me to."
He sat in the interview, we have it up on the
side, he was like, "Oh my God, I couldn't
believe it. The level of trust we created
right off the bat I've never experienced in
my life. It's really truly accountability,
the motivation, the ability to hang in
there." And so I say to people, " Look,
try it." We have all these videos on our
website with all these people talking.
Go look at it. If you want to read the book
first and see if you think this makes sense.
But try it. You will be shocked in a positive
way. You'll discover how delightful it is.
We live in a world where there's increasing
loneliness, Lenny. There's so much research
about this, the Surgeon General's book, everybody
talking about... And it's more detrimental to our
health than smoking cigarettes. Bowling Alone
famously came out 25 years ago. We live in a
world where people have not experienced community
in a powerful way. I don't mean message boards,
I mean real community. And I think you have a
sense of this because you do real community.
And that's what we're talking about here. It's
real community but with some practical tools
and techniques, which we'll talk about. What
do you think? Is that a good response to the-
I'm sold. I don't need a job, but
I want to join one. You also just
had a really beautiful way of describing
these programs as a safety net for people.
Yeah.
Does that ring a bell?
If we go up to the 30,000-foot level, what
are we doing here? What's our mission?
We're building a private safety net for all
those who've been laid off or let go. Look,
we're not going to do what the government does
with unemployment insurance, we're never going
to be able to do something like that. But the
government's never going to be able to innovate
around how to actually look for a job. That's
where we come in. We are trying to build this.
We talked about this earlier, Lenny, creative
destruction is this economic concept that sits
at the heart of capitalism. Creative destruction
basically says, "Under capitalism, it's dynamic.
New products and services displace or disrupt old
products and services, companies and methods."
It's why our economy has grown sixfold over the
last a hundred years. It's remarkable. It's why
we have this amazing multi-trillion dollar
economy. But it comes with some negative
unintended consequences, which is that people
both in jobs and out of jobs, they're anxious and
fearful. There's no program that addresses that.
That's what we're going after here. We're trying
to be the solve for the unintended consequences
of the thing that is so positive in many ways
and that we as product people love because
we get to build new products and displace
old products. I'll just say one more thing.
The reason you know this creative destruction
works so well is if you compare our economy
to the late Soviet Union's economy. They
were a planned economy with no creative
destruction. So there was no innovation,
and eventually it just failed. It
just collapsed. It's remarkable,
this is a huge country with a massive military
and nuclear weapons, but they couldn't make
their economy work. Why? Because they didn't have
this element. So it's something to celebrate,
but as we celebrate it, we need to have
something that addresses the negative unintended
consequences. All of us who benefited from this,
I think it's our duty to do something about it.
That is beautiful. You're very good at this.
Let's shift to talking about tactics. Let's talk
about some of the things that you've shared. So
you've mentioned things like candidate market fit,
playing to win. Go wherever you want to
go. Let's pick a few and then dive in.
Candidate market fit is probably the most
important job search tactic in the book,
aside from the Job Search Council, and it may be
the thing I'm known for. When I die, they coin
candidate market fit. So here's the thing, and
this is why this is so important in a down market,
when you're looking for a job, you're
in a marketplace with supply and demand
characteristics. So if there's a lot of supply,
which there is right now in the tech world because
there's been a lot of layoffs, the overall
economy, there's been net job additions,
Lenny, but those have been primarily in
healthcare and government. There've been
net job losses in tech. We could talk about why
that is, but that's the world that we're in.
So let's say you're a director of product.
Two years ago when the economy was great in
tech and the job market was great in tech,
you could probably get a VP of product role.
What about today? Well, today your candidate
market fit's been pushed down because there's
a bunch of VPs of products who are going to
take a director role. Guess what? That means
you might not be able to get the director role
you might need to get a senior manager role or
whatever. Now, the important thing about
this is it's not a personal segment about
you. It's the marketplace. And that's what so
many people today in their notes to me said,
that it was such a relief for them. While it's
hard to figure out your candidate market fit, it's
also a relief to know it's not about you.
So what I ask people to do is the first radical
step I ask them to take is to think about what
they want and what they don't want. Now, you might
not think that that's a radical step, Lenny, but
most people don't do that. When they get laid off,
they spray and pray. That's the typical, "Let
me just... " Wait a minute, just take a moment.
They're like, "Oh, don't slow me down." I'm like,
"I'm going to slow you down to go fast." In fact,
what our data shows is that the average job search
in the Job Search Council from beginning to end is
three months. If you look at the national data for
job search, it's three to six months. So we are
at the very low end of the national average.
So this is not a slow down, take two years,
whatever. No, no. Most people need to put food
on the plate, so it's a slow down at first. And
we as product people should understand this.
You want to think about your strategy. You want
to understand the marketplace, your customer, the
product market fit. You're not going to just go...
You're going to iterate. First step, what do you
want and what don't you want? That's the Mnookin
two-pager named after Allison Mnookin, who was
a member of one of our product councils. So we
run product councils and general management
CEO councils for people in jobs. That's a
paid program that companies pay for. It's out
of that program helping those people that I
developed this methodology that we're now as
a community giving to the world. So Allison,
she was the GM at Intuit, and then she spun out
a division and ran it as CEO, and she's now a
professor at the Harvard Business School. And
about 15 years ago, she was in transition and we
talked and she created and we created this thing
we called now the Mnookin two-pager. I told her,
"Allison, I'm going to make your name
famous." That's my job. I love her.
Great name.
She's wonderful. And it's just a simple thing,
what do you, what don't you like and you create
it and then you share it in your council. And
here's something cool, Lenny. Let's say you and
I are in a Job Search Council. You share yours,
I share your mine. Now you see a few things about
what you don't like. I'm like, "Hot damn, I also
don't like those. I forgot, I got to add that."
Or you say a thing about what you like, you're
like, "Oh, wow, no, that's really important to me,
and I left that out." So that's part of the shared
learning environment. I'm asking you to do these,
but with others who you're walking it through.
Now, once you have done that Mnookin two-pager,
and it's a draft, you don't have to get it fine,
and not everyone knows exactly what they want,
by the way, this is important, especially younger
people. But sometimes mid-career people too,
they're like, "Oh, I'm not... " So I'm not
asking you to make a final decision, no,
no. We're going to iterate. Okay, we're
product people, we're going to iterate.
So we're going to take this Mnookin two-pager,
this draft that shared with our council,
and we're going to go out and do a listening tour.
Because guess what? In the job search, we're the
product. We're our skills and experience. That's
the product that we're bringing to market. So we
have to go see what the market wants. Now we have
a sense of what we want, but what does the market
want and what does some of our trusted friends,
what do they think about what I want and what
I'm a fit for? And what do they think I'm a fit
for now given the market conditions that we have?
I will tell you, people are terrified to do the
listening tour. They're like, "I don't know,
what am I going to hear from people?" Because
I asked them to ask a golden question,
if you were in my shoes, how would you approach
this? I call that the golden question. It's
such a creative question. It really opens
the conversation. But they think, "Oh no,
people are going to tell me all this stuff." No,
mostly people tell you this. Once in a while you
get a helpful piece of critique, "Oh, you make
everything a priority, in which case nothing is,
and you could work on that." Super helpful
to know. We all have stuff to work on.
But I will tell you, once people do the
listening tour, they're blown away. I mean,
the people who are in jobs, they love, they love
helping others if it's done well. Because guess
what? They're also anxious themselves, and
they want to give back. They want to feel
like they're supporting people. You actually
end up, and we're going to talk about this,
but when you ask someone for help while
you've done your homework, you're thoughtful,
they want to help you even more. They become
invested in you. So the secret about the
listening tour is that not only are you getting
market research customer feedback on your fit,
you're also creating a whole group of listening
posts, people who are invested in your success.
Just to clarify on that specific point of this
listening tour, you write this Mnookin two pager,
which basically describes what you want, what you
don't want, goals you have, what you hate. And
the listening tour is find colleagues, friends,
people that are other, say, product managers and
get their feedback on what you want, what you
don't want, what you hate, what your goals are.
And what they're seeing in the market,
what they think you're a fit for.
I see. Got it. So it's like, "Oh, this is
unrealistic. You're not going to get this."
That's right.
Looking for that [inaudible 00:27:02]-
And we see both things, Lenny. So
some people underestimate their fit,
others overestimate it or don't recognize that
changed market condition. The other thing I'll
say is that in the book I have three different
kinds of structured listening tour conversations.
One I call reverse exit interviews. This is people
you used to work with before, go ask them, "Hey,
what did I do well, what do you think my
strengths are? What do you think I'm a fit
for? Here's what I'm thinking. Do you think I
accurately am projecting myself?" The second
is your broader network, and that's where I ask
you to do the golden question, "If you were in
my shoes... " And then third is recruiters.
Now, this is an important hack. Recruiters
don't like being barraged with, "Get me a
job." They do like someone saying, "Hey,
what do you think I'm a fit for?" asking their
advice. And this is especially true if you pre-
And this is especially true if you've pre-built a
relationship with a recruiter. So anyone listening
to your podcast right now, if you're in a job, I
have a really important message for you. When that
recruiter calls, pick up the phone even if you
don't want the job, help them, network with them,
introduce them to other people, and build that
relationship, because whether you lose a job
or whether you decide to start looking when
you're in work, you want that relationship.
Now, Lenny, there's a problem many people haven't
done that. Okay? So part of what we're doing with
the Never Search Alone community is we're
building a recruiter network. We're finding
recruiters who are willing to, in a protected
way, do a couple of conversations a month,
helping people think about their candidate
market fit. And if anyone listening to the
show is a recruiter, please come join us and
volunteer. We need more recruiters. I know
many of you want to give back and you don't know
how. You tell me this. Here's a way to give it.
Mm-hmm. Love that. Okay, and so the intent of this
is that you're trying to figure out, one, what
does the market want, and how do I be honest about
what it wants because what you want may not exist
right now, and then, two, help you refine your
pitch and how you're approaching and who you're
talking to. Is there anything else that comes out
of doing this exercise? Because I think people
might be hearing this, like, "Ah, so much work.
I have enough work to do, all these interviews.
Got to reach out to people. I got kids and
a family. I have to write this two-pager
now and listening tour." What other benefits
do you get out of this, doing this exercise?
You build those relationships. You turn people on
as listening posts, so you light up your network
in a way that you... If you just send an email
saying, "I want a job," or if you just go, "Hey,
do you have a job for me," people don't know
what to say. But if you say, "Hey, if you're in
my shoes, how would you approach this, and what do
you think if you were me I should be looking for,
and what are you seeing in the market," they love
that, and now they're really thinking about it.
And if they see a job that might
be a fit, they tell you about it.
They tell you about it. Yeah, and that gets
to candidate... Because at the end of this,
we're going to create a very simple,
narrow, focus candidate market fit
statement at the end of listening tour.
So once you've now done this listening tour,
now you need to create a focus candidate
market fit, and this is tough. Look, again,
this is why you need a job search council.
You need them to be there with you during
the listening tour. Not every listening tour
conversation will be a home-run. Once in a while
it'll be a dud. I talk about this in the book,
like, "Warning there are some curves ahead."
You could have a conversation... A number of
women that I have worked with over the years
who've gone and done conversations and they've
gotten frankly sexist feedback... It was not
helpful. "You're too poised," or "You're not
poised enough." It's just this strange set of
stuff. So you need your council to help you parse
out and interpret what people are telling you.
And at the end of this listening tour, and it
never really ends, but once you've done 10 or
15 and you're ready to say, "Okay, I'm going to
take a stab at my candidate market fit," now you
need your job search council because you're
going to want... Every bone in your body is
going to want that to be expansive, to want it to
be broad. Remember, we're product people, at least
those of us in Lenny's podcast community; what
happens when we're building a product? Same thing,
right? We want this product to be for everyone,
but we've learned with product market fit,
that doesn't work. We need a narrow, clear
focus. Same thing with candidate market fit.
So I say to people, and we have this whole
grid that we give them, "I'm looking for a
director of product role in a healthcare, series
B startup in San Francisco," like "Bing, bing,
bing," and people say, "Oh, if it's so narrow,
I'm going to lose..." And here's the thing, when
you're looking for a job, you need a spear and
not a net. With a net, everything slips through.
Now, part two to this, people are expansive,
but not reductive. What are you talking about,
Phyl? Here's what I mean. If you give them
a specific... If I say to you, "Lenny,
I'm looking for a director of product role at
a healthcare startup that's a series B in San
Francisco," well, if you see another FinTech
startup that's in a heavily regulated industry
looking for a director of product that's a series
B, you're going to be like, "You know what? Phyl
is looking for that, but I bet Phyl could do
that." You can be expansive. But if I told you,
"Hey, Lenny, I'll take any product job I
can," you are never going to think of me.
You're never going to remember me. You're not
going to be reductive from a broad statement,
but you will be expansive from a narrow.
And I'll tell you, Lenny, this is so
hard for people, and this is why, again,
you need that council and you need that
broader community. And every two weeks we do
a LinkedIn Live where we address... We go over
these questions again and again because
it goes... If I were in the job search,
I'd feel the same way, even with all the
darn research I've done. It's really hard.
If you've been using this metaphor, approaching
this like a product person, and this is very much
like a product person thinks about new products
is there should be a very narrow audience to start
with kind of a wedge or an ICP. When someone's
building this, what is a sign they've narrowed it
enough? Are there a certain number of attributes?
What tells you that, "Cool, this is small now"?
So it's typically three to four attributes, and
we give people a whole grid in a set of examples.
So we had a woman who was a designer. She was a
product designer. And what her product market fit
was, she was looking for companies that either did
not have a design team or needed to reboot one. So
she wasn't talking about stage of business, or
even industry, but that really plants an image
in your mind. If you hear about a company that
doesn't have design or looking to reboot design,
you're going to think of her immediately
because after you've done your listening
tour and you've created your candidate market
fit and your council signs off on it, Lenny,
this is important, then you go back out to your
listening tour and you tell all those people,
"Thank you for your help. Here's the candidate
market fit I've come up with." And you also post
it on LinkedIn. You tell the whole world, right?
Now, will that candidate market fit change over
time? Yeah, we're iterative, right? So if you
go and go... And the market is changing. What
was true three months ago may not be true now.
Two weeks ago the stock market was convinced
we're going into a recession, and everything
crashed. Two weeks later we're like, "Oh, no,
we're not going into a recession," and
that affects the psychology of hiring
managers and companies. Not just psychology, their
willingness to open up, recs and everything else.
So things are changing, so you need to be
flexible and adaptive to that, which is also
why you need the council and why you need to have
a good network around you that you've asked for
help from and they're invested in you and can be
there for you as you try to keep navigating this.
Just to follow us through it a little
bit more, when someone is... Someone's
thinking right now, "Okay, what are
my attributes," what's on that grid,
roughly? There's stage of
company, I imagine there's-
Stage of company, industry, level of role
and function, of course, and culture.
Is there a set of options
you have of type of culture?
Basically everyone wants a good culture, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, exactly. So culture.
Sometimes it can be very specific, like, I
need a company that has a particular kind of
policy for kids, or whatever, remote or hybrid or
whatever, that kind of element. But I tell people,
make it simple. This should not be paragraphs
and paragraphs. It should be a one-sentence
statement. You can do a longer thing
that you can then share with people
when you're getting into the conversation, but
you want something simple that people go, "Oh,
Lenny looking for a chief
product officer role. Oh."
Yeah. It's exactly like you
want your product to feel too.
Exactly.
I need a SOC 2 compliance,
so I'm going to think of-
That's [inaudible 00:36:17].
Yeah, exactly. Okay, so I'm thinking
through this list here. So level and
role I imagine people get a pretty good
sense of where they want to be. Stage,
any advice for someone to decide
what stage is right for them?
If I were coaching someone which, as
you know, I do, we would talk a lot
about this. But when I'm in the book and in the
community, I say, "To figure out stage again,
I want you to rely on your job search council
and your network and your own experience," and
it becomes pretty... People usually have a pretty
good sense, like, "Who was I talking to recently?
I need a big..." Whereas many people are like,
"I don't want that. I want a startup." Okay.
And what I will tell you is that one thing
to keep in mind right now is that there are
more jobs in the startup world than there are in
the established companies in the tech world for
product people. That's where new job creation has
been happening. It's slower than it was before,
but the big companies, they've just been
shedding people. They've just been throwing them
off. Whereas the smaller companies, there's more
opportunity there. Now that doesn't mean that...
If you can't stand working at a startup, I'm
not telling you you should go there necessarily.
But I will say this, and again, if you need
to put food on the table... We were talking
to someone recently; they had moved to a
new city and then were laid off the next
day. They moved for the company, and then they
were laid off the next day, and they're like,
"Okay, I need to get a job." I said, "Okay,
yeah, sure. Just know that if you're going to
get any job just to have while you still look
for the job you really want, just know that
that's hard. That's a hard pen. I understand
it and I support it, it makes sense, and it's
hard." It's harder than you realize, and you
absolutely have to keep your job search council,
because otherwise you're going to get lost.
Can I share one story about candidate market fit-
Please.
... that might be helpful to people? I was
coaching... He was an EVP at a traditional
media company, but on the digital side,
running their streaming business, but it was
very much an old economy, old media company. This
was not a player in the streaming space. And they
smartly recognized that if they stayed there, they
were going to end up in a pretty bad cul-de-sac.
And by the way, that company's had layoffs, and
they would've... So they decided they wanted to
go work for a company like Netflix or Apple TV.
And they're someone who ran hundreds of people,
corner office, limo, first-class, you know
what I mean, in the airplane? What was their
candidate market fit? They went out and did this,
their candidate market fit, if they were going to
join a top streamer was as an individual
contributor, Lenny. Because those guys,
they didn't respect much of what they brought
from traditional media. And if he had done this
search alone, he would not have done that. But
to his credit, he decided to take that, and it
transformed his career. He's not someone who had
a lot of management experience, but also tied now
with one of the top streamers. He's just done
incredibly well. But that is really hard to do.
So in this example, when you talk about
candidate market fit, a big part of it
is what the market wants from you. It's not
like he's like, "I'm going to go IC." He just
realized as he was going through the process,
"This is where I'm actually going to succeed."
He talked to people, and I helped him network with
people in Silicon Valley. They were just honest
with him. And that's what Justin was talking
about, this can be hard and humiliating at times
to figure out... We had another person who was a
chief product officer in a startup, and she was
great. She helped me with the book, she was an
early reader, she's a member of your community,
Lenny. And she realized that she wasn't getting
the right product trend. She was the only product
person, and she didn't really know what she was
doing. Well, what was her candidate market fit?
It was an IC. It was an IC role, an individual
contributor role in a larger tech company. And
to her credit, she realized that was the right
path for her learning, and she did this before
the shoot really hit the fan. I'm in the
tech world, fortunately. Just not swear.
I talk about this in the book. Sometimes you
need a two-step strategy. Let's say you want to
be a VP of product at a top streaming company or
whatever it is, but you not a fit for that today.
So the question is how do you step there? I tell
a story in the book about a guy who'd been a VP of
product. He wanted a COO role. He was not a fit.
He was not a fit, Lenny. And it was very clear.
The market was telling him, he did the listening
tour, but he came back to me and said, "I don't
care. I want a COO role." So he interviewed with
50 companies. 50. Can you imagine? It took them a
year and a half. The 50th company hired him.
10 days later, they were a public company,
massive fraud, and they went bankrupt. I said,
"Okay. The market is clear. The only COO role
you're a fit for is a company that's about to
go bankrupt." And he's like, "Okay," and he
went back to the VP of product role. I said,
"If you want to become a COO from that role,
where you are today, one of the great paths
is to do it from that job inside a company."
Okay? And that's what he ended up doing. It was a
two-step strategy. He couldn't go straight there.
I'm not talking about people's innate worth,
Lenny. I believe every human is worthwhile person,
and I deeply believe in belonging and giving
people support and spreading love and creating
community. But I also believe in being practical
and realistic. I didn't create this situation. I'm
just trying to report to you what the situation
is and how you can manage it so that you don't get
stuck. How many people have you seen, Lenny,
who get stuck? They get stuck in a bad job,
they're not learning, and then they can't go
from there? They get into their 40s and 50s,
and it is tough. A number of people in the job
search community who are in their 50s, 60s,
whatever, they're dealing with ageism, they're
dealing with... They're not close enough to the
technology frontier. You got to get closer to the
technology frontier, even if that means you're
going to go from the EVP to an IC role. That's
how creative destruction works. The closer you
are to the technology frontier, the more new
jobs and opportunities there are. The further
you are from the technology frontier, the worse
you're going to be over the long run. You might
be able to get a better-sounding job in the short
term, but you're going to find yourself stuck.
I love your Venn diagram of just
warmth and support and belonging,
and also just straight
real-talk. Here's the reality.
Yeah.
What a combo.
Oh, thank you.
This is such powerful advice, and I
think people might be feeling like,
"Yeah, I get it, but man, I don't want
to be a IC again. I've been a director,
I've been a VP. That sounds really not great."
Is there anything else you can share to help
people get past that, of like, "Okay, maybe I
really should be looking for an IC role again?"
Again, if you're in a job search council, and
also you're in our Slack community, what you're
going to find is that you're not alone. That's
a big thing. It's not you. There's not something
wrong with you. This is the market that we're in.
And by the way, the more relationships you build,
the better you do your listening tour... One of
the tactics, Lenny, I tell people is you've got to
send out an update note every month to all of your
network that you've talked to. And it might be,
"I don't have a job yet," or "I don't even
have any news, but I just want to let you
know I'm still going and I appreciate everything
you've done for me and I'm still looking for X."
That could be it. And Justin, in his note, I
referenced him earlier as chief product officer,
his note on LinkedIn today said, "Phyl told me to
keep people updated, and I didn't do it enough."
Don't make that mistake. You got to do that.
Lenny, I met with a group of about 50 job
seekers recently who've been in the Never
Search Alone community for more than a year.
Okay? They're struggling. Again, I don't
have a magic wand. But as I talked to them,
what was happening? They stopped network.
They left their job search council. They
weren't updating their candidate market fit
to the changing market condition. I'm like,
"You have to do everything. You can't get
passive." One of the concepts, Lenny, I talk about
is you've got to be the I in village. There's
no I in team. Well, there is an I in village,
okay? And the I in village is that when I'm
saying you've got to ask for help, you got
to be a part of job search council community,
you have to be independent and accountable and
responsible. I'm not saying you're not going to
become passive independent. This is how you become
more independent. This is how you stand up and
be even more accountable and responsible. This
is how you can do the best search possible
in the market conditions that we have.
So the advice here is if you're
struggling finding a job,
this is a solution. Join a council, bring
people on board with you, update people on
your progress. These are the things that break
you out of that funk that you're probably in.
And it will still be hard. It will still be
hard. I wish that weren't true, Lenny. Now,
I will tell you that, look, what's the difference
between now and the dot-com depression of 2000,
2001 and 2? The difference is that we were
a much smaller industry then. And people had
been in web jobs only for a couple years, where
now we've got people who are in jobs for 10,
15 or more years in tech who have never
seen a downturn, have never seen a market
like this. We've never seen a tech market
like this. It will improve at some point,
but right now it's tough. And I can't change that,
but I can provide tools, I can provide community,
I can provide heart and smarts, so that you
can get the best job you can get right now.
Speaking of advice, is there anything else along
the lines of candidate market fit
before we move on to more tactics?
Just that, again, that you're going
to resist the narrowness of it,
every bone in your body. Just know that that's
what everyone is feeling. But go watch... I
have this great video online of... He was
a VP of product. He was initially masked,
but VP of product at Nike. I met him through
Marty and Chris at Silicon Valley Product
Group. He joined one of our product councils,
and then he decided to leave. And he was like,
"Phyl, I love you, but this candidate market
fit stuff, no. You're wrong. It needs to be
[inaudible 00:46:57]." And so he went out and he
actually spoke to a bunch of VCs and like, " We
don't have any idea what to do with you. You
have to tell us something really specific."
He was like, "Oh, man." So he went, he's
like, "Phyl..." So he redid it, bam, bam, bam.
I tell another story in the book about Dee. She
was a chief data officer of a large company in
tech, wanted to become a CTO. She had a technology
and engineering background, as well as data. She
spent a year spinning her wheels alone. I said,
"Join a job search council." She figured out her
candidate market fit. It turns out she was a
great fit for a mid-size regional bank CTO.
And within three weeks she had three offers. A
year, nothing. Within three weeks, three offers.
So I can't guarantee that you're going
to get three offers within three weeks,
right? I'm not saying that. Some of you, it
might take you six months or a year. And the
more senior you are, Lenny, the longer it is. If
you're a CEO, it's going to take you a long time,
unless you happen to be the CEO of Chipotle,
who just became the CEO of Starbucks.
Yeah. Yeah, I know you're creating a
page that we're going to link people to,
which is, I think... Is it phyl.org/lenny?
Yes.
Okay, cool. And is it going to have this
template to help you work out your market fit?
There'll be a link to where you can download not
only that template, but all the templates. You
don't even have to join a job search council
to get all this stuff. I hope you do. Again,
it's free. I will say, early on people were
like, "What's the trick here? This is free,
and you're going to charge me." No. No, this
is free. Why am I making it free? Because,
one, I can, which is cool; second,
this is in honor of my mom; and third,
I want to create a private safety net for the
ravages of creative destruction. It's great. A
lot of positive consequences, but there's
negative ones. And I just don't love the
idea of charging people for this. I charge
people for other things, but not for this.
And we'll link people to the things
you charge for so they can support
you and benefit you in other ways,
or benefit themselves in other ways.
Benefit them and me. That'd be awesome.
Let's talk about some other tactics. You
mentioned this idea of playing to win,
and I think within that, there's this kind of
OKR in mission tactic. Let's talk about that.
50%, Lenny, of the people who read my book, join
a job search council, and follow everything I've
described, the people don't do what I'm about
to tell you, it is the biggest mistake and miss,
and I'm really sorry about this. I'm on a
campaign, right? So here's the thing. When
you start to interview and negotiate, you've got
to be in charge. This is collaborative coaching.
I want you to play to win, not to lose.
Now, when people hear me say that, they
translate it in their brains into, "Oh, Phyl is
saying that I've got to be a ruthless negotiator."
If anyone who knows me know that ruthless is
just not how I am, at least in this sense. No,
no, I'm like, "What I want you to do," and it's a
great tactic that we stumbled upon, and it's one
of the best tactics in the book, and I really hope
we can get the other half of the people who are in
the community to do this, and your listeners who
aren't involved who decide to join also do this,
when you start interviewing, I want you to create
your own version of the job description. I want
you to do it privately, Lenny, and I want you
to create what I call a job mission with OKRs.
Now, most job descriptions, they suck, Lenny. The
company doesn't know what the eff they're doing.
They don't know exactly what they're looking
for. But I'm not telling you to say that to them,
just to be clear. I'm telling you, "I
want you to create your own job mission
with OKRs." This is key. It needs to be with
OKRs. Now, your audience knows what an OKR is,
objectives and key results, and I assume I
don't need to explain that. It needs to be
something where you are saying, "Here's
what I think I'm going to be accountable
for. Here's what I'm going to actually...
the outcomes I'm going to deliver," right?
At the company that you join.
At the company you join. Now, you'll keep it
private at first because drafting it... This
thing has multiple benefits. The first is drafting
it will help you understand and develop great
interview questions to ask them to clarify,
what is this job? And they'll be impressed by
that. Okay? The second thing is, once you've had
a couple of interviews, and it's a draft... Now,
it's not a full, final thing. This is so
important. I want you to pull the hiring
manager aside and say, "Hey, Lenny, you're the
hiring manager. I've thought about what the role
is. I want to make sure I'm understanding it
correctly. Can I share something with you?"
I don't want you to email it. I want you to
do phone call, Zoom, or coffee or whatever.
Lenny, can you imagine how hiring managers feel
when they get this job mission with OKRs? I was
talking to a senior guy at Amazon who's hired more
than 2000 product leaders and others. He said,
"Phyl, no one in..." He's part of our product
account. He said, "No one in my life has ever
done this. If someone did this, it would blow my
mind. I would hire them on the spot." And that's
the message I want these folks to understand.
We talk about silver medals, Lenny. In the
job search, the silver medal sucks. At the
Olympics, hey, it's pretty good. You get to
be on the podium. But guess what? Silver medal
is... It's almost worse than... Because you were
almost there. And we have a number of videos and
other things where we talk about the difference,
in many cases, between getting the
silver and gold has been doing the job
mission with OKRs. Companies say, "This is what
distinguished you. This is what..." We were like,
"Who is this person?" They're already thinking
about what they're accountable and the outcomes,
and naturally they're thinking about it
better than I am, which is fantastic,
right? So it raises the odds, but it
also does something if you present it...
Again, Lenny, you're the hiring manager. I
show you my job mission OKRs, and you're like,
"Oh, this is fantastic," but you also say,
"Oh, this thing you have here, this OKR,
this isn't part of the role. Well, that's
helpful to understand, but this thing that
you don't have listed is." "Oh, really?" Lenny,
how many times... I'm going to ask people in the
audience to raise their hands. How many times have
you taken the job A that turned out to be job B?
Everybody just raised their hands, Lenny.
So this helps to address that, right?
And then if you get the offer, and again,
this raises the odds of getting the offer,
it then sets you up to negotiate what I call
the four legs of the negotiations tool. This
is not hard negotiation. This is something the
company loves. I actually say, you get an offer
and it's like whatever, $250,000 base with a
30% bonus. This may be a director or whatever,
or senior manager. Maybe it's an 800 base if
you're more senior, whatever it might be. I
want you to go and talk to the hiring manager, if
possible. Hopefully not the recruiter. We'll talk
about that. And I want you to say, "This is great.
I want to talk about money, but before we do,
I want to think about some of the things that
will set me up to see succeed in this role.
I think there's like $10 million of tech debt
here. Does that sound right to you? And are we
on board that that'll be priority one to
eliminate the first day I start the job?"
We had two CPOs, both interviewing at private
equity firms, private equity-owned companies,
about the same size, SaaS companies. One had tech
debt of 20 million, one had tech debt of 10. I
told them both, "You got to talk about that in
the..." So one talked about it in the negotiation,
and the company was like, "Oh, that's great."
They wrote a check on day one. Six months later,
the tech debt was relieved. They updated
the systems. They were able to get into
innovation. A year later, they got promoted
to a GM role in addition to their CPO role,
and then a year after that, they were being
interviewed for the CEO role. The other person,
where there was 10 million of tech debt, was kind
shy about asking, sort of mentioned it, they were
like, "Oh, we'll talk about it when you get here,"
but they didn't really commit, and they never
addressed it. One month, six months, 12 months, 18
months later, he's looking for a job. This is the
opportunity cost of not being set up for success.
Now, again, don't hear this as antagonistic. We're
not antagonistic here. We're trying to say,
"What's going to help me succeed?" So one CPO
recently was negotiating... I'm not just talking
about budget for tech debt or whatever. If you're
a senior person, do you think that team needs more
training? Do you need to send them over to Marty's
workshops, over to my product councils, right? Get
them into Lenny's community. The company was like,
"You're negotiating the training budget
of the team that you don't even run yet-"
You're negotiating the training budget of the team
that you don't even run yet while we're talking
about your salary? Who are you? We love you,
we're going to pay you even more. Lenny,
companies love this. And even if you're a junior
person, you're not going to negotiate budget,
but you can talk about mentorship, professional
development, will you be able to attend
conferences or training? Again, and this is, we're
not hard negotiating this, we're saying, "Here's
what I think I'm going to need to accomplish
the OKRs that we've already agreed upon."
This is really cool advice, I want to make sure
people super understand it. So an example of tech
debt. This person asked, "I need $10 million
budget in order to address this tech debt."
Yeah.
I see. So it's not like, "I believe we will save
$10 million if we spend on time." It's like,
"Here's how much this team will need
and I will need to be successful."
I'm going to need a check
for $10 million on day one.
I guess you're right, someone
would be shy asking for that.
Or that was $20 million actually,
that was the one that asked for it.
That was the 20 million, that was right. And
again, it was not... Yes, people feel really
shy about this, but the companies love that
they understood what it was going to take.
I will tell you what, if the company doesn't
like this, it's a huge red flag. Huge red flag,
it means they're not serious. But if you're
talking to them, "Hey, I think we're going to
need train the team. I'm going to need to hire
three more ICs," or the design function is weak,
or whatever it might be. And then you're
like, "Do you agree? Do you see it this way?"
And they're like, "Yeah, that's right.
Good. Wow." You're already like bang,
bang, bang. We haven't even finished negotiating
your salary. And this is so counterintuitive,
Lenny. I'm the queen of counterintuitive
stuff. Kelly Marcus said it's counterintuitive,
right? But this is as well. People think they're
going to lose the opportunity when it actually
wins them. Now, of course, if they marched in
and said, "Damn it, you have to do X and Y,"
right? That's not what I'm talking about.
"Hey, here's how I see it. This is the
OKRs. I think we're going to need this.
Does that make sense to you?" And you're
having a collaborative conversation about
how you need to be set up for success.
And by the way, if they say, "No, I hear you. I
believe you, but no," then you make a judgment
decision. I'm not always saying you turn that
away. Well, especially if you need a job,
but you're now going in eyes wide open.
You are not going to be able to believe
that tech debt initially. You're going
to have to work within that constraint.
So I love that we're getting into negotiation
advice by the way, because I was hoping we'd
get there. So the advice here is identify
something that you'll need to be successful,
and your finding is that when you ask for,
and it seems like a financial investment
as a part of you joining, ends up
leading to a better comp for you.
Yes, and I will say that there's less negotiating
room today than there was two years ago because of
the market that we're in. And the data all bears
that out, and we see that. But here's the other
piece of data. So I want you to ask for things
that tie back to the OKRs that you've already
agreed on with the hiring manager. This is how
this thing connects together, right? It's like
Legos, and then we come to the money and you've
had this lovely conversation. You've shown them
how much you're invested in succeeding. See,
Lenny, the problem that every hiring manager
has is distinguishing be someone between someone
who is a good talker, and someone who can actually
make things happen. You know this, right? And this
is true every from individual contributor to CEO.
By doing the job mission of the OKRs, and by
showing them that draft, you are showing them.
Not telling them, showing them that you
take initiative, that you're accountable,
that you can make things happen. And then in
the salary negotiation, by talking to them
about what you need to succeed, you're showing
them that you really want to succeed. And guess
who that benefits? That benefits the company,
obviously. I want you to do that first and then,
okay, so then let's talk money. Now, 87% of
the time, Lenny, when you ask for more money,
you get it. Now, that's a longitudinal statistic,
meaning over many years. It's going to be lower
in a moment like this, but you can still
ask, and people are afraid to ask. Again,
don't ask in some shark way like some of
my friends in business might do. Some M&A
negotiators, whatever. No, ask, are you open?
Unless it's a deal breaker. If it's a deal
breaker, just be open about that. But if it's not,
let's say they offered you whatever it is. 400
base with up to 100% whatever in some RSUs
or options, blah, blah, and you really wanted
450. Lenny, you can say, "Hey, are you open
to 450? That was really what I was hoping
for. What I think I'm worth, are you open to
that? Is that something we can talk about?"
And most of the time they say yes. They may not
get you to 450. They may be like, "You know what?
Yes, thank you. Let me get back to you." Or,
"No, we could go to 420. Does that work? Great."
You make it sound very easy.
Here's the thing-
I hate negotiating. Yeah, go.
I do too. And I talk about this
in the book and Jason Fried,
who you know. Jason Fried's got this great
thing where they have all very clear bans,
37signals, well, at Basecamp. He's like,
"Because no one's trained in negotiation,
how can we expect people to negotiate?" And
there's another thing Marty says about my book.
He says what he loves is that companies
have all of these resources. They've got
lawyers and HR people, and you're there alone.
That's why you need your job search council.
This is when you really need to ask for help
because every bone in your body is going to say,
"I'm not going to negotiate. That's going to make
it worse," and it almost never does. And again,
you could be a jerk about it, that won't be
good, but that's not what I'm talking about.
I'm talking about collaborative conversation.
I'm talking about what you need to succeed,
showing them that you're thinking about resources,
support, budget that will help you deliver on the
things that you signed up for. And then asking,
are you open if they didn't quite hit your range.
Yeah. The way you phrase it,
make it very low risk to ask.
Yeah.
Do you have any specific advice on
doing this over email, over phone call,
or in person? Is there something you're
like, "Definitely do it in this way."
Strongly, strongly want you to do it either in
person or over the phone live with the hiring
manager. Now, some companies won't let you
do that. You have to talk to the HR person
or whatever. But as much as you can work with
the hiring manager, even if it's to say, "Hey,
I just want to run by you some of the things
I think I need to succeed in the role before
we talk money with the hiring manager,"
or whatever. With the recruiter I mean,
and they'll go to bat for you behind the scenes
if you do that. Not guaranteed, but more like.
Yeah, that's totally true because oftentimes you
don't really have a specific
budget as a hiring manager.
Right.
So to you it's like, "Sure,
450, let's make it happen."
That's right. Now some companies like know
this and they're like, "You have to talk to
the person we designate the internal recruiter,"
but you can also get back to that hiring manager,
and even informally. Again, if you've built
a good relationship and everything is about
building good relationships, Lenny.
I want you to be a good interviewer.
I want you to ask good questions. I want
you to listen. I want you to present that
job mission OKRs. It shows how innovative
and how much you take initiative and how
much you're thinking about this and how much
you want this, right? Every step of the way.
This episode is brought to you by Dovetail,
the customer insights hub for product teams.
Understanding customers is a critical part
of good product development, but it's so much
harder than it should be. Whether it's finding
insights and large volumes of customer calls,
crawling through feedback, or finding out what
you already know, getting the full picture of your
customers is slow and full of friction. This is
where Dovetail comes in. Dovetail is the AI first
customer insights hub that automates end-to-end
qualitative data analysis and insight discovery.
Their latest AI features automatically
break down your calls into key moments,
themes, and digestible summaries so that you
can get to the heart of customer problems fast.
When you need quick clarity on a decision,
you can use Dovetail's AI powered semantic
search to retrieve supporting data from
across your organization, summarize it,
and create video highlight reels that you
can share with your team. Get access to all
of Dovetail's latest AI features on their
professional plan. The best news is that
listeners of this podcast can get an exclusive
30 day Dovetail Pro trial today. Just go to
dovetail.com/lenny, that's dovetail.com/lenny.
While we're on this topic of negotiation and comp,
is there anything else there that you might
want to share that might be helpful to people?
In the book, before you do the listening tour, I
ask people to do what I call the gratitude house
exercise, which is to think about who are all the
people in your life who have helped you get to
where you are today? I mean, you could talk about
your third grade teacher, you know what I mean?
I'm just talking on, I just want you to do that,
and I want you to do that because everyone has
this idea that they're alone. We have all received
enormous help to do what we're doing, whoever we
are. Even the [inaudible 01:05:51] was born to
a mother, and they did not make it themselves
for their first several years of their lives.
We all are born of mothers. We all are born as
families and communities. Some better or worse. I
had a pretty tough childhood, but there was love.
I want you to do that gratitude house exercise,
and then it can sometimes surface people that
you'll go talk to in the listening tour.
Might not talk to your third grade teacher,
but you'll go talk to some. Now when you're going
into interview, I ask people to take a moment and
re-reflect the gratitude house exercise, remind
themselves of everyone they're carrying with them,
to imagine that they're on your shoulders. All of
those people, including your job search council of
course, and everyone you've talked to and you're
listening to, you're walking in with 50 people,
Lenny, okay? Even people who tell me, "I
don't know anyone." Now, that is not true.
You might not know as many people as I do, okay?
That's understandable. My job is to know people,
but everyone knows some people and you bring them
with you even metaphorically, so that you feel
not alone when you're going into that interview.
The other thing I say with the interview and the
negotiations is you've got to go do the debrief
right afterwards, Lenny. Because we all have
these cockamamie ideas about what happened.
We think we did terribly when we did well, we
think... We need to talk it through with someone
else who can help us parse exactly what happened
and really where we're at. I had a woman who was
a director of product, she was interviewing for
a VP of product roles. She texted me after the
interview, "Oh, I screwed it up," this and that,
this and that, "but they really liked me
and we're going to go to the next round."
I'm like, "Wait a minute, wait a
minute. Something is not true here."
This is just your own imposter syndrome and
inner critic. That's another exercise we ask
people to do, by the way, is what we call
the inner critic exercise name the critic.
Mine is Tub Tour. I was overweight when I
was a kid and my dad called me Tub Tour.
I learned that tactic from Julie Cameron
from The Artist's Way, she recommends that.
Yes, she's great. Love that book. By the
way, it's on my bookshelf back there.
I love that. I think I called mine Jim. Yeah,
we had a really good episode. I don't know if
you saw with Joe Hudson, he has a whole
series of advice on your inner critic,
and his point, and I'll point to it is
your inner critic is always lying to you.
I did see that episode. I love it. We all have
it. People think, "Oh." Everyone. And that's
what I love about this moment we're in too, Lenny.
I started in therapy in the 1980s. In the 1980s,
you did not share that you were in therapy, okay?
Today, we have tennis stars talking about their
emotional well-being and their therapy and how
they're doing. It's beginning to normalize in
some really important ways that emotions, they're
not bad. They're actually really important to
the decision-making system, but they can go
off in certain ways that can really hurt us.
And it feels like these councils
are like a lite therapy for people.
Yes. I would never want to say the word therapy
because of course that implies certification and
training, but there's a therapeutic aspect
to it. I feel comfortable saying that, yeah.
Okay. So on this gratitude house, just come back
to it real quick. The reason that is powerful is
that gives you confidence to ask for stuff to
believe in yourself. You're worth something-
Gives you confidence to walk in there as who
you are, Lenny. Not as your inner critic,
but as the whole good person that you are. And
when you show up, this is one of the reasons job
search councils are so important because if
your anxiety and fear starts to run away and
erode at your confidence, it will hurt
your interview. You will not show up
well. So you're not going to even, even
in a down market you're going to get even,
you won't even get the jobs that your candidate
market fit suggests you're good for in that
down market. You're going to slide down a few
more notches, or you just won't get offers,
and then you're going to get paralyzed
and feel like you're really worthless.
And if anyone watching this has been out of
work for a while and feels that, let me just
tell you, you are not worthless. You are not
worthless. I want you to invest in yourself,
to prove that to yourself that you're not
worthless. You are worth the investment of
this time and energy. I'm not asking you to do
this for me, I'm asking you to do this for you.
You got tingles when you said that. That was a
really powerful message. I'm glad you said that.
Thank you, Lenny.
So yeah, so we're on this topic of playing to win.
And what you just said is along the same lines is
just remember, you're playing to win. You're
not trying to lose, you're not trying to find-
Not lose, just be really, I just
can't say anything. I just can't
rock the boat. I'm not asking you to
rock the boat. I'm asking you to take
charge and demonstrate the power of who
you are. These companies will love it.
When I asked a lot of people to ask you what
you're amazing at, one of those common themes is
really good at just asking for help and teaching
people how to ask for help, which was actually
an topic for a recent newsletter post by one of
my newsletter fellows, Natalie. So let's talk
about it. Talk about why this is so important, why
you spend so much thought and time on this topic.
First, I want to shout out my mom again. So
my mom's name, her nickname was Chic, C-H-I-C.
Her friends and family and I dedicate the book to
Chic, and she started that first council in 1960,
and she asked for help. Of course, she taught
me to ask for help, and to start councils. And
of course, when I was very young, I didn't want
to do what my mother said, right? You're not. But
I ended up in a bad situation and she's like,
"You've got to ask for help," and I asked my
high school teachers for help. I was an alcoholic
at the age of 12, Lenny, and things were really
spiraling downwards. I was no longer living with
my mom, there's a whole long story about that. I
was in a pretty unsupportive position, and she's
like, "You've got to ask for help." And so I did.
And OMG, Lenny. I mean, I was carried by these
teachers. And I also have to give a shout-out,
and I'm going to cry now to my girlfriend in
high school, Karen Kavanagh, whose family had
very few resources. They were struggling, but
they made a home for me, and I couldn't have
done it without them and some of my other friends
and my teachers. I worked a full-time job by the
age of 16 and I was going to high school, and I
was in a tough situation. It was transformative,
Lenny. It was transformative. Did I feel like
asking for help was a weakness? I did. Did I
think people were going to think less of
me? Absolutely. I thought all the things
that people think, and it is not what happens.
Now, there is a warning here. If you ask for help
poorly, and I'm going to define that, it does end
up leading to bad consequences. What do I mean by
asking you poorly? I mean, if you don't do your
homework, if you're asking for someone to do it
for you rather than advise and support and give
you perspective, we all know that. I get these
emails, Lenny. So when I started the product
councils, Marissa Mayer was a founding member,
right? Marissa Mayer at Google and Miriam Moheed
at Amazon. And as Marissa's reputation grew,
suddenly everybody wanted to talk to Marissa.
So I got all these random emails from people
I've never met. "Oh, I've got software, would
you please introduce me to Marissa? I think
she'd want to license it or buy at Google."
I'm like, "Who are you? What? That is the
dumbest." Of course, I'm never
going to answer that, right?
If they had reached out to me and said, "I
know you don't know me. I have this small
software company. I'm not well-connected, but
I would love your advice on how to grow this
business and what you would do if you were
in my shoes," which I have never received,
Lenny, even though I've written about it and
said about, I would've done that phone call.
And then if they have said,
"Well, can I talk to Marissa?"
I'm like, "You have not earned that yet.
That's not a statement about your worth.
It's just you're not ready for that conversation."
So you can do it poorly. But if you do it well,
if you've done your homework and you're open, oh
my gosh. There's four counterintuitive rules here.
Asking for help is not a sign of weakness,
it's a sign of confidence. It both requires
confidence and strengthens it, Lenny. That's
number one. Two, it's not a taking activity,
it's a giving activity. If you do it well, you're
actually being giving to the people you ask. This
is really counterintuitive, Lenny. This is what I
teach in my product councils. I'm like, "You have
to ask for the money." If you ask for help and
you're open and vulnerable, you're a smart person.
So at one point, Marissa came in and said, "
Listen, I'm developing a new product. I want
to present it to the board, but I'd like your
feedback on it first, and what do you guys
think?" Am I approaching this in the right way?
People were like, "What?" Google was already
a public company at this point. Wow, that, they
were just blown away. They were so happy to help.
So if you've done your homework and you ask
someone who has some expertise in the area
that you have, and you do it in this way, "I'd
love your perspective and thoughts and how would
you approach it?" People feel given to, they
feel given to. Here's the thought experiment
that'll prove it. Imagine that somebody that you
respect comes to you for help on an area that you
have expertise. And they ask you in this way, how
are you going to feel, Lenny? How do you feel?
Like they value. Like they value my opinion-
You feel honored, and you feel excited,
and you love giving. Everyone loves giving,
it's a part of human activity. And you
learn more when you give, of course,
because it helps you see something new.
Asking for help is not a sign of weakness.
It's not a taking activity, it means you're
becoming more independent, not independent,
and it doesn't hurt your reputation, it improves
it. Something I did not understand when my mom
was trying to tell me to do this, Lenny. And
it took the experience to drill into my head.
And then I will tell you, I won't name
names, but one person that you asked,
who's a prominent product person who's worked
at great companies, right? He said ask him about
asking for help. I think he would agree with this.
He'd been a member of the product councils for a
long time. I think it took years before he really
embraced it. I've seen many people, they're like,
"Bill, I know you keep talking about this asking
for help thing." And I know there's something
to it, but it is transformative, Lenny. It is
transformative if you learn to ask for help well.
I can tell you about Brad Smith at Intuit who
toppled the stock price there. But he was a
GM. He became a CEO. He was a GM. He ran a project
and he didn't do it well. He lost $300 million for
company. He thought, okay, that's over. But they
came to him and said, "What's your lesson here?"
He said, "I didn't ask for help. I was pigheaded.
I didn't listen to my team." That's a great
lesson, and if you really internalize that,
then it's worth it because you're great in
other ways. And he ended up getting to the CEO
role. And what did he do? He joined a council,
right? And he asked for help. Boom, boom, boom.
Stock price goes up 7X in his tenure, okay?
Kenneth Chenault at American Express. Joins in
the 1980s, one of the few African Americans in
professional roles there. Ends up as a CEO and
chairman of the board. First African American
chairman of a Fortune 50 company. You ask
Kenneth Chenault as I did, how'd you get
there? He asked for help. And by the way, what did
he do once he became CEO? He got on a CEO council.
And by the way, who asked for help? Well,
this is going to blow your mind if you.
Warren Buffett. People think Warren Buffett
only listens to himself and Charlie Munger
who passed away last year. That guy asked for
help. Well, it doesn't ask anybody for help. He
asked people he respects and so on, but that
guy asked for help. Every single leader I've
ever worked with that has done well asked for
help. And I have data in the book. 85% of the
people get to a senior role credit asking for
help to help get them there. 85% of the people
in a junior role say they're afraid to ask for
help because they think it's a sign of weakness.
Perfect.
It's literally the same number if you can
believe that. I couldn't believe it when
I did the data. I was like, "What?" But it's
really, and guess what? If you don't learn to
ask for help and you're a junior person, you're
going to remain a junior person most likely.
When you say ask for help, what are some
examples and common times and uses of
asking for help? Because it could be like, "Hey,
can you just look at this email for me?"
Or is it like, "I'm struggling with this
project?" What are some things that you've
seen when people think ask for help do this.
One of the things that Kinshaw talks about is
what he calls defining reality. So it's a CEO
at American Express, he was constantly just going
around and asking different people in the company
and outside the company, "How do you see things?
What are you seeing? What are you thinking?
Help me understand your perspective," right? So
that's a form of asking for help, for sure. Okay.
Reviewing my email absolutely is a great form of
asking for help. If you're sending a good email,
an important email let's say, and let's say you
have a history of maybe sending emails that don't
get well received, you go ask for help. And by the
way, I have a whole workshop where I teach people
how to use ChatGPT with some communication models
to help you with that email. So there's ways to do
that with ChatGPT. But I still, if it's a really
important email, want you to have eyes on, right?
There's a woman who became the president of
a digital retailer in the United States about
five years ago, and then she realized that she
had significant technical debt. The project,
they were trying to build a new platform, and
it was stuck. So we convened what we call a peer
coaching call, and I also talked about this in the
book. We got three other presidents of retailers,
online retailers who had re-platformed and
spent an hour, just one hour with her asking
them for help. "What would you do if you were
in my position?" I mean, bing, bang, boom.
So when people get a new job, by the way, I tell
them, do a first 90 days peer coaching call. I
want you to talk to people who are in that
role today. Not at that company necessarily,
but they're a director of product, they're
a VP of product, whatever it might be. And
I want you to say, "Hey, I'm starting this
job. Here's my job mission with OKRs. What
would you do if you were in my shoes? What
mistakes have you seen others or yourself
make that I need to avoid? What should I focus
on? Here's what I'm thinking for my 30, 60, 90."
Whatever it might be, I want you to do a
first 90 days call. Now, let's say you're a
director of product in a job is going well, and
you want to get to a VP of product role. Well
then, I want you to do a career evolution call
where you're talking to VPs of product. "Okay,
I'm a director. I want to become a VP. How
do I get from A to B? Will you tell me?" And
that's another peer coach you call. So these
are the things we do in the paid community,
in the product councils and stuff.
But you can do these on your own,
right? And I tell people how to do them
on their own in the job search councils.
Perfect.
Are these helpful answers?
Absolutely. I think all these examples you're
sharing is exactly I think what people
are wondering. Just like, okay, I see.
Yeah.
Feels like it's not-
Can I share one more?
Please.
That's so great. So Bradley Horowitz joined Google
in 2008 as director of product. He had come from
Yahoo, but he was initially intimidated. He
had a weekly meeting with Jonathan Rosenberg,
who was the SVP of product, with Susan Wojcicki.
Susan just passed away tragically. Absolutely
fabulous person by the way, if people don't don't
know her, go learn about her. Marissa Mayer,
and also another director of product named
Sundar Pichai, right? Who is now the CEO of
Google. And Bradley, he was nervous, he
didn't know how to be in that meeting.
One of the things I tell people, when you ask
for help, use your emotional intelligence,
use your product council if you're in a job or
your job search council, if you're looking to
get feedback on, am I thinking about this well?
Because I don't want you to ask the wrong people
for help. Someone who's going to take advantage
of that. You have to be thoughtful about this.
He was picking up vibes from Sundar that he
was very approachable, that he lacked guile.
Bradley told me Sundar just made it easy for
him to say, "Hey, after one of these meetings,
could I ask you a couple of questions?" And he
says, first question he has is, "Is this meeting,
is it just me or is this meeting intense?"
Sundar was like, "Oh, no, no,
this is intense. I feel the same way you do
and I've been here for a couple of years."
So they start to build a bond, and that's a form
of asking for help. It's like you're checking, is
your experience the same as mine or am I missing
something? And then Horowitz who felt relieved at
this point, felt more trust with Sundar, decided
to ask him another question and this question. And
by the way, now Bradley, he's kind of embarrassed
that he asked this question, although I'm really
happy that he did, I told him this.
He asked this question, he basically
said, " I haven't been here very
long, but you, Sundar, you strike me."
"I haven't been here very long, but you, Sundar,
you strike me as a really thoughtful person and
great leader. Why is your remit just working on a
toolbar for Marissa?" Whoa. Heard the wrong way,
that could sound like an insult or something,
rather than an honest attempt to understand
the culture of Google and how it operates. But
again, he had trust with Sundar at this point.
And it was an open and vulnerable question, and
it was great. Pitch I basically said, "Listen,
I don't worry about title or scope or any of
that. I've really been focused on just doing
good work and letting the right things
happen. That's the culture of Google." I
will tell you that that was more true of the
culture of Google in a way that's not so...
You have to be a little more politically aware
at Google today. But the point is not so much the
exact question he asked, but that he was open and
vulnerable. He was thoughtful about who he asked,
and it really made a difference in terms
of his entry into Google and eventually
led him to the VP of Product role. Of course,
Sundar came into the CEO role down the road,
but that's what I'm talking about, right? He was
part of the product councils, Bradley. You need to
have that sounding board so you can be thoughtful
about... I teach people how to map and figure out
who their allies are and their blockers and play
what I call positive politics. That's all in my
next book, Never Lead Alone, just to give a
little. Don't worry, at least a year away.
When I write a book, I do... I did 400 drafts of
Never Search Alone. I had a couple of thousand
people help me with it and 200 people read it
and use it. I had 2,500 comments and 400 drafts.
I like to really dock through this stuff. I'm
doing the same with Never Lead Alone. That's how
I know it works, by the way. I'm a prouded
person, Lenny. I mean, that's what we do.
[inaudible 01:25:56]. That's amazing. Let me ask
one last question around the art of asking for
help. So we've talked about when to ask for help a
little bit. What are just a couple tips for how to
do it well? You know, people come to me and like,
"Hey, can you look at this email?" And be like,
"No. I'm pretty busy. I don't know
if I have time to look at an email."
Have to think about the relationship,
right? Again, showing that this random,
small software company wanted to talk to Marissa
Meyer. I didn't know them, they didn't know me,
and they didn't know Marissa. That's not going to
happen, right? Lenny, if your mom or your close
friend or your colleague who you work closely
with says, "I want you to look at this email,"
you're going to respond in one way. If some
person, let's say in your podcast community,
which is great, wants you to do it, I mean,
you have thousands of people there. You can't
do that. People come to me for job search
advice in the job search community. I said,
"I can't do that. I can't scale that.
That's what the Job Search Council and
the Slack community is there for. I appreciate
you asking, but that's what the deal is there."
You got to think about the relationship.
Listen to your emotions. This is where, again,
emotions are really important for decision
making. If your emotions are telling you,
"I don't know if I trust this person," don't get
all open and vulnerable with them. I want you to
learn to ask for help in a counsel format where
it's really safe. You can flail around. You can
ask in fakakta ways. There's ways to ask for help
where it's like... Have you experienced this,
Lenny? Where I want you to do me a favor, but I'm
actually acting like I'm doing you a favor. Lenny,
I have this person to talk to I know is
really going to be great for you to talk to,
when really I'm trying to get you to give me...
Whereas I should said, "Lenny, I have a favor to
ask. Would you be willing to do this?" You just
say yes or no. That's the other thing, I really
want you to be honest with people about what
you're asking. I never want you to hide the ask.
That is really good advice. A
lot of times it's just, yeah,
okay, if this is just a favor for you, absolutely.
Yeah.
[inaudible 01:28:06]
I mean, if people would say to me,
"I have a favor to ask. Would you
be willing?" "Yeah." Most of the time
I'm going to say yes to that, you know?
Yeah.
Do you get cold introductions, Lenny?
Where people introduce me to
someone else without asking.
Yeah. It's not a super common,
but it does happen, for sure.
It almost never is someone you want to talk to.
Yeah, that's right.
It's not like, "Hey, let me introduce
you to Sergey Brin," you know?
Yeah.
It's [inaudible 01:28:32]. No. It's
like they're trying to help somebody
and you're doing them a favor,
but they're not being honest.
Yeah. Okay. That's amazing advice. Phyl, we
could talk for hours about so many things.
You're involved in so many other things I want
to hear about, but maybe one last question before
we start to close out our chat. Just a broad
question, is there anything else that you think
would be valuable for people to know or leave with
as kind of a final note around either job hunting,
asking for help, anything else? And then
I'm going to ask you to share all the things
that you do for people that maybe could
benefit from one of these other programs.
When my book came out, we did a book party in
New York and the host of it, very senior product
person, got up and said, "The most important
thing about this book that I learned," and they
run a Job Search Council, "was, and I said this
earlier, but I want to come back to it, everyone
feels anxious and insecure in the job search."
Lenny, everyone. It's built into the fabric
of how capitalism operates. It's not something
problematic in your head. It's the instability
of the system, which gives it its dynamism, but
which also creates trends in security and fear.
Everyone feels that, Lenny. You are not alone.
But my saying that is not enough. What I say in
the book is that this book is like a cookbook.
You don't get the calories from reading it. You
got to actually make the dishes. To experience
what I'm saying, you need a Job Search Council
and you need to go like, "Oh my gosh, it's really
true, I'm not alone. Even Lenny. Lenny feels this.
Holy, I respect Lenny. Wow, look at everything
Lenny has done and created, and he feels this
way. Maybe I'm not crazy." There's so much
else to this, but that is such a core point.
That's such an important point to leave
with. And just to build on exactly what
you just said about me, this strange
life that I've created for myself,
I originally called the project
Avoid Getting a Real Job because
I was worried about that. I forced
myself to try something else instead.
That's amazing. That's amazing.
That's great. Well, thank you,
because you have created something that's
really meaningful to a lot of people, Lenny.
Thanks, Phyl. So have you. I'm so thankful
that you made time to share so much advice.
I think this is going to be one of
the popular episodes I've done. I
think it's going to help a ton of people,
but we're not done yet. Tell us about some
of the other stuff that you've got going
on. You've mentioned product councils,
you do coaching, just so people
know what else might benefit them.
21 years ago I started these product councils.
And by the way, I like to show this Marty Cagan,
and I go back to the late nineties, early... He
was actually a client of mine when he was at eBay.
Wow.
And I'll tell you what happened. We were
about to sign a project and he decided,
he called me up. Literally, we were
signing that day. He called me up,
"Phyl, I got bad news." "I
mean, what are you telling me?"
Now?
"I'm leaving."
Come on.
"I'm leaving and I'm starting something." And
he started the Silicon Valley Product Group.
Oh, wow.
But why am I saying that? Because that was
around the time that I started the councils and
I started with Marissa. Basically, I went out and
did a listening to her Lenny and I said, "Listen,
I think for those of us left in the digital
world after this depression, I think we need
a place to come together that's not a conference
with sponsors and people that are all trying to
sell each other. We need a private, safe, secure
environment to really talk. Does that resonate
with you? Do you want that?" And they were like,
"Yes," so I started this thing and Marty has been
involved from day one. He has sent me something
like 30% involved with members we've had over the
years. We've had a couple thousand members and he
just sends people over, which has been amazing.
And so we have product councils for VPs and CPOs.
We also have an associate council program for ICs
and new managers. We started that a couple
of years ago. It focuses on women and people
of color and LGBTQ, but not exclusively. So you
can be a white guy who's straight, whatever, and
you're a product manager. What we care most about
is if you're willing to ask for help, and you're
really committed to being there for each other
and being a part of this community and activity.
And so that's what I've been doing for years.
And I have a great team and amazing... Teresa
Torres was one of the moderators of our private
councils, by the way, and great friend, and been
on the podcast here. Gino, obviously great friend
of yours. She asked me to really emphasize asking
for help and share some of the stories that
I did. She's just been such an important part
of my life. I can't say enough about her.
We've got those and we have CEO groups and
we have [inaudible 01:33:31]. That's my day job.
That's sort of what pays the bills and I've been
doing for 20 plus years now. But then I also have
a series of other learning communities. I'm one of
these, I read. If you asked me, "If you had one
job title, what would it be?" Reader. I read,
Lenny. Books are machines to think with. Books are
machines to think with. And I'm on a campaign to
get more people reading more because... And
product leaders need to read more. I have a
whole bunch of book recommendations on my Lenny
page, by the way, that are for product leaders,
and we can talk about a few of those. But I
also run something called the Reading Odyssey,
which is a partnership between scholars
and readers at Harvard, Cambridge,
for lifelong learning and curiosity.
I run the World Business Reading Group
for high school students. It's a high school
business literacy. Not financial literacy,
business literacy program based on the philosophy
of Warren Buffett and Charlie Mugger. And taught
by really senior executives, like partners at
venture capital firms, hedge funds. And I'm an
investor. We have this amazing faculty. It's pro
bono. We're all volunteer. We have a small charge
for middle class families and it's free for
anyone who can't afford it. And it's a summer
program and it's going gangbusters. What else?
Oh, Slow Art Day. So one of the things I teach
people is that you need to develop mentors. Most
people do not have mentors, Lenny. 95% of the
people in my community of senior product leaders
do not have mentors. And mentorship programs, it's
like the typewriter. Our parents or grandparents
have them, but we don't have them. The companies
don't offer. One of the ways that everyone
listening to this podcast today can get a mentor,
you can get what I call a dead or distant mentor.
Warren Buffett is my mentor, he just doesn't know
it, which is great. I don't have to listen
to everything he says and he doesn't have to
take my calls. Steve Jobs is my mentor. And
when I talk about mentor, I don't mean just,
hey, I'm a fan, or I like the products, or
I read the biography. I mean really study.
If you really study Jobs, you have to come to
1997. He's interim CEO. So he was fired from Apple
in '84, '85. Actually, after the Mac came out. He
wandered the wilderness for 10 years. He created
a company called Next, which wasn't next. And then
in '95, '96, Apple buys the operating system from
Next, and the company is in really bad shape
and makes Steve the interim CEO. Interim. They
wouldn't give him the full title. They're like,
"Ah, the business is so terrible. You're going to
destroy it anyway. Whatever. You'll be interim."
And he does a bunch of stuff, but he gives a talk
in 1997. He's got tattered hole jeans. There's
300 people at the developers conference. They
all are pissed off. And he gets up there and
he says, "You have to start with the customer,
not with the technology." And that's what we're
doing it at. People talk about that customer.
If you really study Jobs, that's what he did.
And what does that mean? I can tell you there's
a lot of product people, Lenny, who talk about
customer and don't really focus. And if you
really study that moment and study what Jobs
did, it can inform your decisions and actions.
So one of the things that Jobs also talked about
was the power of art and that everyone needs to
go to art museums and that you need to be
inspired and it will help you think about
design if you create great products. So I started
a company, something called Slow Art Day, which
has now been in 1,500 museums around the world.
It teaches people how to slow down and look. And
especially for Lenny's podcast, I am making free
both the teacher materials, the leader materials,
and the participant materials so that all of your
podcast listeners who are running product teams
can go to a local museum and do an offsite and
develop more visual literacy, empathy, connection
with each other, and an understanding of art that
will help them be better [inaudible 01:37:46].
That is amazing. I'm going
to try to do that myself.
It will blow your mind.
So you mentioned Marty Cagan
and Christian a couple times,
and Marty Cagan described Chris as the most
interesting person in the world. I feel like
you deserve that title. You're doing so
much and so much good and so much variety
of things. It's really impressive. And the
amount of impact you're having is wild.
Thank you. It really means a lot.
I'm just saying it how it is. I'm really
thankful you've shared so much wisdom on
this podcast with everyone. I think that's going
to help so many people. We're also not done yet.
We've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Phyl, are you ready?
I am ready for lightning round.
Here we go. And you've talked about books. I
imagine you're going to have an answer for this.
Yes.
What are two or three books that you've
recommended most to other people?
Of course, I've recommended hundreds, but right
now what I recommend is Creative Destruction,
and I'm going to give your listeners the link
to the right book, it's by a group of French
economists. It's a little bit academic, but it's
so important. It's so important for product people
to understand. It is so important. More jobs
get created because of creative destruction.
There's not net job loss. There's more jobs
created. AI is going to create more jobs,
not destroy. Everybody got that wrong. Almost
everybody, except the people who understood
creative destruction. But you have to be close
to the frontier. That's where the job creation
happens. And product people, you got to be close
to the frontier. You got to do whatever you can.
If you're at a company that's not close to the
frontier, do stuff at... I was working at Moody's
Investor Service and I built one of the first
2,000 websites back in the early nineties,
Lenny. I was doing all this stuff outside
of work. That was bringing me closer to
the technical frontier and was changing my
candidate market fit. So I recommend that book.
I also, of course, I recommend Marty's books. Now,
I want to just say again, I don't want you to just
read Marty's books, listen to his podcast, the
great interview you guys did here at Lenny's. I
want you to read and reread those books as if
he's your mentor. And rereading is important,
Lenny. And people say, "Oh, I listened two or
three times speed on the audiobook." You are not
going to have that deeply inform your decision
making. Now what I'll do is I'll read a book
and then I'll listen to it as a reinforcement,
or I'll read it and listen to it at the same
time. For the important books, Lenny, you got to
read them more. And Marty's books are important.
The last book I'll recommend is The
Manual. It's a short introduction to
Stoicism. People misunderstand Stoicism. They
think Stoicism means repressing your feelings.
That is not what Stoicism means. It means
understanding and accepting your feelings,
but not necessarily always being driven by them.
Incorporating them. Your feelings are an important
part of your decision-making system, but they
shouldn't rule you. And it's a really important
book. I have driven a lot of sales with that book
because I really hammer it home in my book. So if
you go on to Amazon, you'll see the book that's
most bought along with my book is that book,
right? I have other books I recommend that
are on my website, but those are two or three.
Amazing. On the listening to things at fast
speed, I sometimes meet folks that listen to
the podcast and they're like, "Oh, this
is what you sound like at regular speed,
because I just listen to every
podcast fast." Second question,
do you have a favorite recent movie
or TV show you've really enjoyed?
So there's a great new TV show on Apple TV that
is not getting the audience that it deserves.
It's called Las Azules. Las Azules, the Blues.
It's about the first women recruited onto the
police force of Mexico City in 1971 or 2.
Of course it speaks to me because 1970s,
these are women and my mom and how close I was
to her and what I... I saw the world through my
mother's eyes, Lenny, and it really shaped me.
It's a great TV show. I love that. Of course,
I love the show that I've always
recommended and everyone's now seen it,
I hope. If they haven't, it's been out for a
while, but it's... Oh, the name just escaped
me. The American football coach who goes
to England and becomes a soccer coach.
Oh yeah.
How can I forget this? I've
recommended it so many times.
That's the guy's name, right?
The character, Ted Lasso.
Ted Lasso, Ted Lasso. Thank you. So the kindness
in there. And by the way, a great message around
asking for help in that. The last thing I'll
say, of course, is the Inside Out movies. The
second one came out this summer. Just the way
it's normalizing emotions, again, and helping
us start to talk about emotions. Really love
that. Okay, what else in the lightning round?
So there's this next question that I cut. I moved
to other questions, but I wanted to bring it back
with you. It's about your favorite interview
question. You help a lot of people interview
and interview better. I'm curious if there's a
question that you've heard that you really like.
If you are interviewee for a job and it's
a senior level job, I want you to ask,
"Tell me about a time that you, the company,
brought in a senior level person and it failed,
and why?" Because they often fail bringing
senior level people into companies. So ask
them what happened and why, and figure out how can
we avoid that outcome. And hopefully they're going
to have a good answer. I have a whole bunch
of questions in my book, but I love that one.
I also love, if you are on the other side, if
you're hiring and you want to check references,
I have the most amazing question. The
most amazing question. By the way,
this is the best thing I learned in my two years
at the Harvard Business School. I learned this in
my running and growing a small business class.
It's like the best thing I've learned. It is,
if you want to get references, what you do
is you want to leave a voicemail or you could
send an email, whatever. And you want to say,
"I'm about to hire Lenny. Okay, if it would
be a huge mistake if I didn't bring him on, if you
think he's amazing, then call me back. Otherwise,
don't bother." And that gets around all the
legal blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, and it's
just it cuts through. I love that question. I
don't know if that resonates with you as much.
Yeah. So is the idea if you don't hear back
from them, they're not necessarily amazing?
Yeah.
Wow.
Yeah. You're leaving that space there. And by the
way, I love doing that for back channel. When you
start a job or when you are accepting an offer
or interviewing, I want you to back channel that
boss a little. Talk to people who've worked with
them, if you can. Use your network and ask them,
"Would you work with this person?" And even
say, "Hey, if I called you and told me I was
interviewing with this guy and you should only
call me back if you thought I should take the job,
would you have called me back?" You'd know,
and so you can do a form of it that way.
Do you have a favorite product you've
recently discovered that you really love,
whether it's like a digital app?
I'm going to give you a very different
kind of answer than I would normally give,
but I'm hoping you and your community will
appreciate this. So I did recently discover it,
but I'm going to talk about a book, Lenny. So
25 years ago, a guy named Robert Strassler,
who was a business guy, he started teaching
at a special high school for kids who were
dropping out. And he was teaching them some of the
classics like Herodotus and Thucydides, expert,
and they couldn't get it. And the books were
terrible because there was no context, so he
spent 10 years and he reinvented the format of a
history book. There are 120 maps. Each of them he
drew specifically, and they're only relevant to
the previous one or two pages. Okay? There's a
margin summary in plain English for each paragraph
describing what that paragraph just said. He got
the top scholars in the world to write two-page
appendices on their expert topic, things they've
written hundreds of books about, hundreds of
pages about, you have to do it in two pages.
And by the way, the publishing world wouldn't back
it. He funded it himself. He hand drew the maps.
He spent two years creating a concept index, not
just a keyword index. And it's just blown apart
the whole industry. Completely disrupted. He sold
hundreds of thousands of copies of these books.
They are a masterpiece, Lenny. They have Landmark
Series. Landmark. They have new ones coming out.
Every product person, in my opinion, should go
look at this and look at the product design of
this book. It is masterful and it teaches you a
lot about usability and the reader experience.
I want product people, Lenny, to get out,
who are doing digital work to get out of
the digital world and look at products outside
the digital world for inspiration and thinking,
because I don't want you all looking at the
same stuff. You're going to just create the
same stuff. I love tools like Calendly, which
I just didn't... I've been using for years,
but no one could get it right until they got it
right. Those are great. How's that for an answer?
That's incredible. So what is it
called again and where do you find it?
And it's going to be on the Lenny page. If you
get on [inaudible 01:47:12], if you do Landmark
Herodotus or Landmark Thucydides,
either one, you'll get there. Yeah.
Oh my God. Sounds incredible. Great
choice. Do you have a favorite life
motto that you often like to think back
to and share with friends or family?
Of course, we talked about asking for help, and I
say that a lot. But I also love, and I said this
earlier, books are machines to think with. And
as product people, Marty and I talk about this
all the time, we have to be thinking. And I coach
people all the time, how can I think more? You've
got to read more because books are machines to
think with. Good books. There's a lot of bad
books in the business world, but good books.
Good books, thoughtful books. Books that'll
help and shift your perspective, whether it's
history or science. I read widely, and I want
you to do the same. Books are machines to think
with. That's probably one of my greatest lines.
Final question. Usually I try to make this fun,
but I want it to come back to something practical
for people. So to leave people with something
they could do this week to help them find a job
or help them improve the chances of finding
their job, what's something you'd recommend?
I have one very simple thing. Go to Phyl.org
and sign up for a Job Search Council.
There we go.
It's free and it will transform your search.
Is it a good [inaudible 01:48:34] answer,
or were you looking for
something different, Lenny?
Beautiful answer. It also is exactly what I
would've asked you next, which is just where
do people go find the stuff you're up to and learn
more about things that we've been talking about?
Yeah.
There's phyl.org and then there's phyl.org/lenny,
which has a lot of the templates
and things that you referenced.
Yeah.
Amazing. Final actual question,
how can listeners be useful to you?
That's such a lovely question. So on the Lenny
page at Phyl.org, I outline some ways. We're
raising $100,000 right now to build a platform
for job seekers. It will remain free for job
seekers. Part of what I'm doing is I'm doing
a speaking tour on AI, and I'm taking all my
speaking fees and putting it to this, but people
can also make a donation just to that. They can
also volunteer. And we're looking for, if
anyone's a Salesforce admin, I'd love to
have you volunteer with us. If any of you have
really good PHP experience, let me know. If any
of you are really good at Typeform or Formsite,
which is a tool I don't like much. By the way,
if anyone from Formsite is listening, your tool
sucks. You need to really improve the product
there. There's a lot of different ways that
you can help, but those are some of the things.
But most importantly, tell someone who you
know in your life who's looking for a job,
that there's a community here for you that's free,
that has all these smart tools and resources and
people who are genuinely here to help you and
who will help transform your search in this very
hard moment. People ask me, "Is this good in the
hard moment?" This is born out of hard moments.
In a great job market, it's easier to say,
"Oh, I can just grab a job." You need to
be more thoughtful in the down market. Now,
I think you should be in the up market too.
This is our moment to be there for people. This is
what. And I would love, so many people still don't
know this, Lenny, we want millions of people.
We want to help millions of people. We have
20,000 hours of volunteer time already. We want to
have millions of hours of volunteer time. We are
changing something about the way capitalism works
with this community. We are changing this negative
consequence of creative destruction that people
have just been left to fend with on their own.
Well, I'm excited to be helping spread the word.
Phyl, you're wonderful. Thank
you so much for being here.
Thank you, Lenny.
Bye, everyone.
Bye. Thank you, everybody.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to the show on
Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite podcast
app. Also, please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review, as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.