You've noticed a significant shift
in how SEO works with the rise of
AI answers being integrated into search results.
Transparently, I thought this was going to be an
apocalypse. Up until AI Overviews, whoever won
on that long form piece of content would get that
first click. But now that doesn't exist anymore.
What should people do to be
successful in this new paradigm?
Think of SEO as a product. The product managers
are the people that should be thinking about this
SEO question because it's a product question.
Product people need to think about how do we
position this to the user that is not going
to find out about this from a social channel,
that's not going to be attracted by
an ad? This is a user that's doing
their own self-discovery journey.
If you can't answer the question
about what is it that someone's going
to do a search on, then don't do SEO.
To a lot of people, SEO is kind of this dark art.
It is not a dark art. It is simple. I think
step one is the step that almost
everyone misses on SEO, which is.
Today my guest is Eli Schwartz. Eli is a
growth advisor specializing in SEO and has
helped companies like Quora, Coinbase,
Tinder, LinkedIn, WordPress, and Zapier
develop and execute their SEO strategies. He's
also the author of Product-Led SEO and has a
very refreshing take on how to think about SEO
and win at SEO. Recently, he's been spending a
lot of his time analyzing how SEO changes with
the rise of LLM chatbots, Google giving you the
answers straight in the search results, and
also how to utilize AI in your SEO strategy.
In this episode, we dive deep into everything that
you need to know to be successful in this new AI
paradigm. As Eli shares in the conversation,
Google is just now rolling out changes to how
search works and is greatly increasing how many
searches include an AI-generated answer at the
top of the search results. So things are going to
start shifting under our feed pretty quickly. If
you're at all thinking about SEO, working on SEO,
or are just curious about how search is evolving,
this episode is for you.
If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in
your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's
the best way to avoid missing future episodes
and helps the podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you Eli Schwartz. Eli, thank you so
much for being here. Welcome to the podcast.
It's a real honor to be here.
You've had some amazing guests,
and I'm honored to be counted as one of them.
It's completely my honor. You've been working
on SEO for a long time. You've been helping
companies figure out how to win at SEO for a
long time, over a decade. And we were chatting
about what's happening in SEO, and you told me
that you've noticed a significant shift in how
SEO works with the rise of LLMs, with the rise of
AI answers being integrated into search results.
And so I thought it'd be awesome just to
spend an entire episode talking about what
people need to know about what's changing
in SEO and how to be successful in this new
paradigm of SEO with LLMs and AI being
prevalent. How does that sound to you?
That's an awesome idea. I really like what's
happening with AI in general for SEO because
it's causing everyone that cares about SEO
traffic, whether that's a PM or that's a CMO or
that's a CEO, to really be forced into pivoting
their thinking about what SEO traffic means
because the tactics around SEO haven't really
changed. It's always been the exact same thing.
My last full-time job was out at SurveyMonkey,
and I was moonlighting on the side. And I was
introduced to a CEO of a big company and they
were asking me about my approach to SEO. And
I wanted to close it. I wanted to get this
consulting engagement. And the CEO says to me,
"So essentially what you're telling me is I
need to find my keywords, put that into content,
and then build some links. Is there anything else
you're going to do for me? Why should I pay you?"
And it stunned me into silence because essentially
that is and was SEO, and then that forced me
to really pivot my thinking around what SEO
might be. And I pivoted my thinking and I've
worked with many companies around how they should
think about SEO and what SEO traffic should mean,
but others have not because those tactics did
work. And LLMs and AI in general is forcing people
to think again, how should SEO work? How should
I be driving business from the search channel?
This episode is brought to you by Pendo, the
only all-in-one product experience platform for
any type of application. Tired of bouncing around
multiple tools to uncover what's really happening
inside your product? With all the tools you need
in one simple-to-use platform, Pendo makes it easy
to answer critical questions about how users are
engaging with your product and then turn those
insights into action. Also, you can get your
users to do what you actually want them to do.
First, Pendo is built around product analytics,
seeing what your users are actually doing in your
apps so that you can optimize their experience.
Next, Pendo lets you deploy in-app guides that
lead users through the actions that matter most.
Then, Pendo integrates user feedback so that
you can capture and analyze what people actually
want. And the new thing in Pendo, session replays,
a very cool way to visualize user sessions.
I'm not surprised at all that over 10,000
companies use it today. Visit pendo.io/lenny
to create your free Pendo account today and
start building better experiences across every
corner of your product. P.S. You want to take
your product-led know-how a step further? Check
out Pendo's lineup of free certification courses
led by top product experts and designed to
help you grow and advance in your career.
Learn more and experience the power of the
Pendo platform today at pendo.io/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Brave Search.
Brave Search is the private independent search
engine that doesn't bias or sensor results. Brave
Search and its answers with AI feature are for
free to all users on desktop and mobile devices.
With Brave Search, you get real answers faster
served from their own independent index of the
web. Their AI search engine can give lightning
fast, incredibly accurate results for almost
any question. But Brave isn't just AI answers.
It's also a powerful traditional search
engine with real innovations versus big
tech options. It fights bias and SEO spam. It
brings a cleaner results page with fewer ads,
Reddit threads in the search engine
results page, powerful local results,
and even community- driven ranking options.
Tired of big tech's same old list of links?
It's time to try Brave Search. Visit
brave.com/lenny to get started. That's
brave.com/lenny. So just to set a little
foundation, talk about just what is it
that's changing in search and in SEO
with the rise of AI answers and LLMs.
So essentially Google and other tech companies
had their hand forced by OpenAI and ChatGPT.
Google claims to have invented the concept
of LLMs and they may or may not have,
and some of the early OpenAI employees were
Google employees. But ChatGPT came on the
scene at the end of 2022 with this ability
to ask any question and then get a written
out answer. And suddenly people are like, well, I
don't need a Google and click all these results.
So there started this conversation of you don't
need Google anymore. Google is ending. Even more
than that, you don't need SEO. You don't need to
optimize anything because the entire world will
just be given to you. We'll dig into that. I don't
think that's at all correct, and I don't think
anyone, whether you're doing SEO as your full-time
job or whether you're receiving SEO traffic as a
part of one of your primary marketing channels,
I don't think anybody has to worry about that.
However, Google was worried about it, and I
think one of Google's primary stakeholders
is really Wall Street. So if Wall Street
suddenly thinks that Google is a has-been
company and they're not interesting anymore and
they don't want to maintain investments in them,
their stock price goes down. And that hurts
Google's ability to recruit employees. It
hurts Google's ability to raise money and
invest in all the interesting stuff they do.
So Google has to satisfy the curiosity and
the interests of the general world and general
investor by saying, "Oh, that OpenAI thing, we
can do it too. That's not that big of a deal." So
then Google responded, badly, of course, first,
by launching what was then Bard. So they said,
"ChatGPT, look, we've got our own version," and
they did a public demo. It didn't work out well
at all and their stock price actually went down.
And then they fixed it and then their stock
price went up. But they also had to have an
answer to this concept of, is search dying?
Does anyone need to search anymore when the
entire world can just be given to you? So
they launched what at the time they called
SGE, Search Generative Experience, which is
essentially ChatGPT in a search result. So they
launched that, but they launched it as a beta.
And there were huge issues with what they
were doing there because there's monetization
issues. Everything they do comes from ads. The
majority of their revenue comes from ads. So
if you're going to show this AI answer on a
search result, then you also can't have ads.
You need to go all in on one of them. That
was one issue which they actually have not
solved yet. Another issue they had was liability.
So if they have a generative response that tells
you to do something awful, like I think there
was one where it may or may not have been fake,
a lot of people made some fake ones, that told
you to jump off the Golden Gate Bridge. Are
there liability concerns? Because Google now
is the publisher. They're not a search engine
that told you how to find out the answer to that.
They told you to do it themselves. And the third
issue there, which is another liability concern,
is it plagiarism? So those are the things that
they worried about. So they took about a year to
test this thing, which was fascinating because
we're tech people and most of the listeners
are tech people. Google is very much a launch
fast kind of company. They reveal something and
then it sort of rolls out very, very quickly.
They're not the kind of company that says we're
going to launch something and then they take
a year to do it. So AI Overviews, what was then
called Search Generative Experience, launched at
Google I/O this past year, in May of this past
year, and they renamed it to AI Overviews. And
it's that. It's essentially ChatGPT in a search
assault. They launched it to great fanfare.
Of course, it was live right away. They
said it was only going to be logged in users
only in the US. Obviously they always have
concerns about launching things in Europe,
because Europe's a little bit more litigious
than the US. And once they launched it,
suddenly they started getting these screenshots of
Google told me to jump off the Golden Gate Bridge,
Google told me to put glue on my pizza,
which, of course, Google didn't do that.
They just crawled things from around the web.
I'm surprised that Google didn't predict that
because the exact same thing happened with
ChatGPT and Google is much bigger and a much
more interesting target for people that want
to share those things in social media. So
Google launches it, and that was a little bit
embarrassing, so they rolled it back somewhat.
But what's even more interesting is they've given
up on this rollback. Or not given up, they've gone
back into it and they've relaunched it, and now
it's on so many more search results. I'm seeing
it on most of the search results that I see. And
on top of that, non-logged in users are seeing it,
so in incognito users or users without any history
with Google are seeing it, and they've just
launched it in the UK. So this thing is coming and
it's really going to be affecting search results.
To maybe help people understand why this
may impact SEO, if it's not obvious,
is it pushes results down. People get
the answer right there. They don't have
to click your links. And then there's also
the sponsored links at the top of the page
that already are pushing you down. So basically
your stuff is harder and harder to find, right?
Actually, it's not that it's harder to find,
your stuff becomes less relevant. And that's
the part about SEO that I'm excited about. So SEO
was exactly like that CEO said to me years ago,
it's just about creating some content. And then
it's just this race to the top of getting your
ranking results on that top keyword. So years
ago, I worked at a startup where we were in the
automotive space and we wrote content about cars.
And a word we liked to rank on was cars. The
homepage was ranked for the word
cars. We bought tons of links,
and we were just a cars website. Obviously
that's not something anybody could expect to
do now because you don't search like that. You
don't search, "Oh, I need to buy a vehicle. I'm
going to use the word cars and see what comes
up," because cars means a lot of things. Cars
is a movie. Cars is a kind of car you drive. Cars
could be a go-kart. It could be a lot of things.
So no one's going to think about
those search results. However,
SEO is still geared towards those top of funnel,
those big keywords that people cared the most
about. So now a lot of those keywords are
going to be moving into these AI Overviews.
I don't want to just focus on Google, although
I think Google's going to own the entire search
page forever, at least for a very long time.
But other engines, whether it's Perplexity or
whether it's Claude or whether it's Meta, they
all have this opportunity to give AI Overview
type responses. That I think, those top of funnel
kind of queries, are a great fit for what's going
to come out as an answer. So if you're looking
to go on vacation and you want a beach vacation,
you can ask a very explicit question about give
me a beach vacation that is not in America,
but is a two-hour flight from X airport.
That's the kind of thing that you could do
in a Google search, but would take you a very
long time to do. And those are great answers
from just getting a paragraph. And then from
there, you move into the mid-funnel. So now you
do this query and Google suggests to you that
you should go to Cancun. Or sorry, not Google,
but whatever that answer is suggests to you that
you should go to Cancun. And now you're in the
mid-funnel and that's where SEO begins to matter.
So the reason why I think this disruption is so
big is because the journey changes, the discovery
changes. So whereas before if you were a travel
site and you were able to rank on best beach
vacation within two hours of the United States,
that's your ranking result. And then
you have your long piece of content
and you have your ads and you can monetize that.
That all changes when you can still rank number
one on that, but you're all the way at the bottom
of the page. The AI answer, whoever that's from,
whether it's again from ChatGPT or Google, tells
you where to now start doing your deeper search.
So just to maybe mirror back what you're saying
is the discovery step of search is going to be
swallowed up by LLMs that give you direction.
And then once you have a sense of what you want,
then you go back to Google and that's where
potentially the opportunity continues to remain.
Absolutely, and I think that's where things
are good. That's where I'm excited by the user
experience for search, because I don't think
the user was best served by, I don't know,
U.S. News or Forbes writing out where the best
beach vacations are within two hours of the
United States, with that piece of content that was
written by a freelancer who's not a travel expert.
So now you're going to get that information
also from not a travel expert. You're going
to get an AI summarized answer, and that
will give you more clues and more ideas to
do a deeper research search. I think
that's where the user's best served.
Okay, this is fascinating. Let's definitely
spend more time there so people understand
exactly what that means. Before we get into
that and what people should do to win here,
what impact have you seen on SEO and search
results and the space of SEO as these things
have rolled out? Have you seen numbers of
like, this is declining, this is growing?
Transparently, I thought this was going to be
an apocalypse. So I shared about a year ago
that it's going to be an apocalypse. We have not
seen it yet, and a lot of people are declaring
victory that there's no apocalypse
because we have not seen it yet. However,
this thing just launched in a way that
I think it will start impacting traffic.
So prior to the last couple weeks, it
was not available on logged out search.
It was only on logged in search. And even
more than that, on that logged in search,
Google had rolled it back significantly because
of those embarrassing things that happened in
May and June when they first launched it.
They're only just now launching it broader.
And I do think we're going to see impacts.
Of course, another challenge with pinpointing
and impacts is they're rolling algorithm updates
that are happening, which we'll also talk about,
and that will mask what's happening. Because if
you've been hit by an algo update and suddenly
you recover from the algo update, you'll
see more traffic, but you might have seen
more traffic but on a lower base because
these AI Overviews are changing things.
So I think if you take all those steps back and
you look at this from a journey perspective,
there's no way that it won't be impacting
search. It's just going to be hard to find.
And there'll be certain examples
where it is extremely prevalent,
and there'll be others where it won't impact
things at all. And I think the riding line is
the journey. We're in the funnel that user is.
So if you are WebMD and you're writing content
about the human body, just generic content that
has existed since medical journals were created,
AI Overviews are going to be fantastic at giving
you that answer. You have a headache and you're
just like, "Well, this headache's not going away.
Should I take more Advil or should I take a nap?"
And then you find that WebMD article and you
get to page six and it tells you that 0.2% of
people that have a headache actually have a
brain tumor, and you don't need that anymore
because Google can tell you you're good, you
should take a nap and drink some more water.
WebMD was competing with Healthline and other,
Cleveland Clinic and Dallas Clinic and all these
other hospitals, and it's totally unnecessary to
go and look at all these results and go through
six pages of information about headaches.
So a site like that will be impacted by
AI Overviews. An e-commerce site, maybe not.
It depends where in the funnel that user is.
As you're talking, I was reminded of
something that I forgot about with my
own experience. I used to have a website called
whenishanukkahthisyear.com, because it changes
every year and it's just the date. That was
the whole website. It gives you the date of
Hanukkah this year. And I put ads on there and
made 10 bucks a year, and then Google came in
and just gave you freaking answers right inside
the search result. So I've experienced this.
So it's even more than that. So what you are
referencing is structured data. So that's a very
easy thing for Google to tell you when is Hanukkah
in 150 years from now? It's in a data set. What's
happening now is Google's taking this unstructured
data from content and building it into structured
data. So you could ask a question of what is the
likelihood of a baby needing to go to the hospital
because they're showing this sort of symptom.
And again, instead of reading all that content
and making a decision, Google could take all
that unstructured data, not just Google, again,
ChatGPT or Claude can take all that unstructured
data, and give you a statistic based on everything
they've read. And that's very helpful to
users. And I think, again, users benefit.
And then a user might find out there's
another piece of information where I'd
actually like to read a medical paper, or that
now I'd like to Google and find the closest
doctor to me who has certain hours. That's a
Google search. That's not an LLM AI search.
And just to clarify, I didn't intend
to say that that was AI oriented.
That happened a decade ago. So
yeah, I totally, totally agree.
Well, I just thought that was interesting
to really drill into the difference between
structured and unstructured, because unstructured
is actually where Google is disrupting everything.
So this entire idea of SEO, again, up until
2022 was monetize unstructured data. Whoever
wrote the longest piece of content on
best beach hotels in Miami and then
built the best links to it, they would win.
They win whether it's ads or win whether it's
hotel bookings. Now, Google can start
you off at the top of that and say,
"These are the best beach hotels based on
all the people that have written content," or
actually Google's own unstructured data from the
reviews and give you that. And then you can say,
"Okay, I'd like to go to this hotel,
or I'd like to stay in this city."
So help us understand even deeper
this distinction between top of
funnel and mid-funnel. So when people
are maybe winning at one or the other,
what does that look like? What are some examples
of like, here's a top of funnel type of search
that Google's going to eat and here's a
mid-funnel experience that you can win that?
So in general, SEO has always been more at the top
of the funnel generally, because you're curious
about something. So let's say you're looking
for a new software. You're looking for new
podcasting software. So you search for top podcast
tools, and you get back a list on let's say G2.
G2 and all the sites like G2, like the Gartner
sites like Capterra, all going to be massively
disrupted. So you would get back a list from
G2, which would give you out all the software.
And you would look at some and it would say,
"This one's geared towards enterprise. This
one's geared towards small podcasters. This
one's free," and then now you've narrowed
down your list to these three tools. And that's
when you start doing those searches. Now you're
mid-funnel. Now let's say you've chosen Riverside
and you've gotten enough information from those
other searches. Now you start searching Riverside
price, Riverside capacity, Riverside bandwidth.
That's bottom of funnel, and that's where
you'll now go buy Riverside. However,
at the top, you were doing top podcast
tools. So again, up until AI Overviews,
up until this entire concept of LLM, whoever won
on that long form piece of content would get that
first click. But now that doesn't exist anymore.
You just go to Google and Google tells you,
"These are the tools. Oh, you're looking for a
new CRM? This is what a CRM is. You want to know,
do you need a CRM or do you just need a calendar?"
Look at that and Google will just tell you in a
paragraph, and now you've redirected your search
somewhere else into middle of the funnel. So I
think that's where SEO always should have
been because that's where conversions could
potentially happen. However, SEO never was
there before because the way most SEO measures
its performance and its success is rankings.
So they would say, "Well, it doesn't really
matter if we convert on the word CRM. But
look, we're number one, so we're winning."
First of all, as a user, this sounds great.
I'm so tired of just all search results just
being a bunch of SEO pages, just with a bunch
of BS answers. And so I really prefer, Google,
just tell me. Just tell me what I need to
know. The other piece is if you really think
about what Google has been trying to do, they've
been trying to do this is like, here's our best
shot at giving you an answer to this question,
and here's links that'll point you to an answer.
And this is just a better version of it where it
takes all the actual information and just gives
you the end result. So it makes a ton of sense
that they're doing this and the technology has
finally allowed them to do this. Okay, so let's
get to the, I don't know, $64,000 question,
million dollar question, what should people do?
What should people do to be successful in this new
paradigm that as you're describing is in motion?
It's just starting to now happen. And it may be
catching people off guard because they've thought
it's already been out and things are okay,
and you're saying it's actually
starting to actually move quicker.
I think it's fascinating, I'm honored to be one
of the few marketers on your product hard test,
but I think of SEO as a product. And I think the
product managers are the people that should be
thinking about this SEO question because it's
a product question. There are users that are
coming in from the search channel. What is
the product that I need to create for them?
What is the experience that I need to create
for them? So typically, it was thought of as
a marketing challenge of the product people
have created this thing for me, and now I
expect the marketers to go and do the SEO thing
for it. But there's a mismatch. So for example,
I find very often when I talk to SaaS companies,
I don't think SaaS in general should do SEO.
But very often when I talk to SaaS companies,
they have created a product for whatever user,
and then the marketers are expected to
make that product fit into the thing that
the search results are around. And it doesn't
work because that's not what they're looking
for. No one asked the question of what it is
that they're looking for. So now that SEO is
changing and you really need to think about this
mid-funnel and you need to think about a user
experience and a buyer experience when they're
doing the search, I think it all comes together.
And this is where the product people now need to
think about how do we position this to the user
that is not going to find out about this from a
social channel, the user that's not going to be
attracted by an ad, the user that's not going to
discover this tool from a trade show. This is a
user that's doing their own self-discovery
journey, and this is what is the thing
they're looking for and how do we position this
product in a way that they're going to find it.
So that's what everyone should be doing,
product really collaborating with marketing
and discovering what is it that the user
wants and showcasing that. I was recently
talking to a company in the health space.
They have an app. It's a health app. And
we talked about their marketing. Their SEO in
general was they write thousands and thousands
of blog posts. AI has allowed them to
do things they should never have done.
They wrote thousands of blog posts about health
in general. I told them they shouldn't do that
in general, but they wanted me to experience their
product. So they gave me a code to download their
app, and their app is awful. It's a bad product.
So they're trying to do marketing that doesn't
fit for a product that doesn't do the thing
they say it's going to do. If they fix the
product and understand the user, now it becomes,
well, if I'm a user looking for this product,
what are they looking for? How do we
showcase that, again, in the mid-funnel?
Can you help us make this even more real?
Maybe go through an example of a product
you worked on or one that's doing this
really well in terms of going from, hey,
they want our product. What's the journey
look like? What's a good example of that?
So the earliest example of where I discovered
on this process was about 10 years ago,
I met the CEO of Zapier, Wade Foster, and he was a
co-worker of mine. I had invested in this company,
and he asked me to meet with him to just discuss
SEO. They were doing something that no one needed.
They had this product which zapped things
together, but no one needed it because they
didn't know it existed. But people knew
that they needed things to work together.
They just weren't looking for Zapier.
So in my discussions with them,
in our SEO experiments that we came up with,
we said, well, people are looking for let's say
Gmail and they're looking for Salesforce. They
know that Gmail doesn't connect to Salesforce,
they know Salesforce doesn't connect to Gmail,
but they're looking for ways to pair it together.
So what if we created as a product a marketing
way to showcase that this product of zapping
Gmail to Salesforce and Salesforce to Gmail
exists? And that's what we did. So we built
that at scale for everything that could work,
and that was the experiment that I did with them,
where everything would be available and it creates
this flywheel of, wow, if Gmail can work with
Salesforce, what else does Gmail work with?
Can it work with this other tool I have? And
that's a, again, early example where I stumbled
upon this idea of people are looking for that
other thing that you could do, showcase the
fact that your product could do this thing.
I had no idea that you were involved
in Zapier's SEO work. That's one of
the most legendary successes of SEO. Very cool.
Total accidental. Whenever people
ask me about programmatic SEO,
and I know we have to dig into that,
what programmatic SEO is, they're like,
I want to imitate Zapier. It's always great
to mention that I helped through that.
That's amazing. Okay, so the lesson
there is you realized that the key,
the opportunity is to teach people what they
could accomplish with this product. There's
this awesome product doing amazing things. They
have a need they're searching for, say it's like
Gmail and Salesforce, and how do we help them
see there's something really interesting here.
Yeah. I actually have a better one for you.
Great. Let's do it.
So I worked with Tinder for a couple years. One
of the biggest challenges I ever had with SEO,
especially as a consultant, is getting
things done. And I worked with amazing
companies and there's great people, but
then they run into this wall. In my book,
I talk about one of the earlier stories I had
of this where I worked at a company where I was
hired by the CMO and we built out a great plan.
And then we go to the CEO who brings in the CTO
to discuss our plan, and the CTO says, "I don't
have engineers for this. So you decide whether
you want to work on the product or you want
to work on this marketing thing you've done."
And then we didn't do anything because they
never resourced it. But I worked with this
really great product person at Tinder,
Udi Milo. He was the chief of growth.
At Tinder, Udi Milo, he was the chief
of growth, and he really saw a problem
where Tinder had never done SEO. All of Tinder's
inbound came from the word Tinder, and he is like,
"There has to be upside for SEO if they've never
done it before." So that... he was convinced of
that. He was willing to drive forward on this
idea. So when we started working together,
the first thing we came up with is what is someone
going to be searching when they look for Tinder?
And it's not online dating. That's a single word.
We're not going to write out long-form content
around everything related to dating because that's
not the Tinder product. You're not reading a piece
of content about how to fall in love and then
somehow converting into Tinder. But in our user
research and in the discussions we had on what the
investment we can make into SEO was we discovered
that Tinder is a loneliness-solving problem,
loneliness-solving solution. So you're lonely,
you've gone to a new city, you don't know anybody
you'd like to solve your loneliness problem. So
because you're in a new city, it occurred to
us that this is a local thing. So we're going
to look for anything related to local. So what
we built out is if you look for online dating
in many cities around the world... This
is beta. It remained in its beta state,
but if you look for online dating in many cities
around the world, you're going to find a Tinder
page, which gives some examples of places
you can go on a date. And more than that,
it gives you Tinder as a solution to
solve the loneliness problem you have.
So what changes here with the rise of AiO
reviews and things like that? Is it this
is where... this is how future of SEO looks
versus just keywords and endless block posts.
Actually nothing changes here with AiO
reviews because if you're looking for,
you've gone to Dubai. You've just... You've
gone to Dubai. It's a brand new country,
you've never been there before, and you're
lonely. So you look for online dating in Dubai,
and you're going to get... Again, AiO reviews
might tell you what the dating scene is like.
It might tell you where to go on great dates.
However, it doesn't allow you to solve the
loneliness problem you have. The
loneliness problem you have is a
mid or bottom-of-funnel problem. You're
still going to click on Tinder's result,
no matter what the AiO review does. So that's
where I think SEO should be is you need to be in
the buyer journey with the SEO you're creating.
And it doesn't matter what AiO reviews does or
doesn't do because you're still solving the
mid-funnel problem with your SEO solution.
Let's go in a direction I was going to
say for later, but it might be useful now,
which is, say, somebody's just sitting
there at their desk thinking, "Hey,
I want to be... I want to start doing some SEO.
I want to be successful at SEO. Haven't really
done a ton here." With this new world
of AI and LMs, what would be step one,
step two, step three to move down a direction of
starting to poke their toe in the water of SEO?
I think step one is the step that almost everyone
misses on SEO, which is be the user. Try to
understand who your user is. And there've been
so many companies, and SurveyMonkey was a great
example. One, I spent seven years at SurveyMonkey,
and when everyone got onboarded at SurveyMonkey,
they gave you a SurveyMonkey account and told
you that you should run a survey. I think later,
in the later years, they forced everyone in
their onboarding time to use a survey... run a
survey with people in the company, but before
that, no one did. So they had this account,
and they never did a survey. So they had zero
customer empathy for why people use the tool.
And then, when you think about it from a product
and marketing standpoint, you're thinking about
it as a work challenge rather than a customer
empathy challenge. So the first thing anybody
should really do around anything that they're
trying to do SEO is try to be that customer. So
if I am a user of this SaaS, I'm building SaaS,
and I want to market this tool, what is a user
going to look for? What's the problem they're
going to look for that would make them want to
do a search? And earlier, I referenced that I
don't think most SaaS tools should do SEO. And
the reason is because a lot of times, when I
talk to SaaS companies about SEO, I ask them
this question, and they give me a blank stare.
So if you can't answer the question about what
is it that someone's going to do a search on,
then don't do SEO because SEO is about appealing
to that user. If you can understand what the user
should do around looking for whatever product you
have, then that's the first step for SEO. So who
is this user? Who am I marketing to? You're sort
of creating this persona in your mind. Step
two is think about the asset you're going to
create. So pivoting over to what he talks about
Tinder. So we understood that it was a user that
was solving a loneliness problem any in the world
because that's what Tinder does. It solves that
loneliness problem in any way you want, of course.
And now we had to think about what is it that
we're going to create. We know it should be
global, of course. We would know we want it to
be programmatic, which is something we should
dig into like difference programmatic versus
editorial. We know we want to be programmatic
because no one wants to in position of writing
a page out for every town or every city or
every neighborhood in the entire world. So
we want it to be programmatic. What things do we
need to pull into that? And then the third step
is really building, and we're on a product
podcast. Of course, to the product people,
you're building the product for that
SEO user. So where do you get those
inputs? What does this page need to look like?
So again, the reason I think SEO needs to be on
product is because the inputs for SEO aren't
the way many people think of SEO, which is a
piece of content optimized for Google based on the
keywords I've chosen. I think of it as a product,
which means you need design resources. You need
engineering resources. Of course, you need a
product manager to really oversee the building of
this. You need user research. So it's, again, more
than just a piece of content. So going through
those steps, again, it's understand who your user
is, decide what it is that you need to create for
that user. And the third is envision this product.
So I think there's a really powerful point
here that might be... people might not get,
which is the user needs to be
thinking of something they will
go to Google to search for to find your product.
So it's if they're... if nobody is searching
for the thing that you're building in some way,
there's not going to be an opportunity for
you to win an SEO or and benefit from SEO.
Are there any examples that come to mind to
you of B2B, SaaS companies that just like,
"This is not... There's no SEO opportunity here,
just like no one's searching for this thing."
Most of them. [inaudible 00:35:30]. One of my
first consulting clients, right, when I left
SurveyMonkey was Mixpanel. So, I mean, I just left
my job, and I'm going to take any client that I
have. I have some awful clients that I took, but
Mixpanel was not an awful client. It was just an
eye-opening client where we're trying to do SEO,
and I'm doing SEO and exactly the way that CEO
had told me SEO should work, and he was going
to do it himself. So I told them the keywords.
We came up with the content. We built the links.
We did all the stuff SEO was supposed to do, and
it didn't work. And we were sitting there, and I
asked them to show me the user journey. They have
a tool that does it. That's what Mixpanel does.
So someone clicks on a search result and they
land on this piece of content, which we did
research and we know what people look for,
but why is it that it doesn't convert? And
then I realized that there were other problems
to this conversion, which is Mixpanel is a
product you integrate in your entire company.
You don't just do a quick Google for it and be
like, "Oh, analytics. Yeah. I'm going to tell
everyone we got to do it and it's going to be live
tomorrow." Also, Mixpanel is expensive. So again,
it's the kind of thing that there's friction of.
You don't just click from a search result and
then decide to just purchase it. You can't even
purchase it on your credit card. I don't believe.
So those are the issues, and that's why I think
SaaS is not the best fit for SEO because if you
think about that journey, the problem doesn't
necessarily exist. The SaaS solves the problem,
but only once you know that problem exists. And
getting people to know that problem exists is
typically not an SEO challenge. It's typically
a brand challenge. You make a viral video of
you didn't realize that you could use this
tool we've created to solve your problem,
but no one is necessarily searching for
a problem they didn't know they had or a
solution they didn't know could exist. So that's
where the breakoff is. And then the other issue,
of course, is now they know the problem
exists, but it's not an SEO journey.
So I had another eye-opening experience early in
COVID when I was... everyone was home, and there
wasn't a lot of things to do. Google reached
out to me about a role on their team on Google
Cloud for doing SEO. And there wasn't a chance
I was going to take it, and it seemed like an
interesting thing to go through a hiring loop and
stay at home. So I had a fascinating experience
interviewing because every time the... first
it was the hiring manager and every time it was
someone on that team that started the interview.
They said, "Are there any questions that you have
for me?" And then I spent the next 45 minutes
asking them all the questions like, "Why are you
doing SEO? What kind of keywords would you want to
do? What does this SEO journey look like?" Because
for Google Cloud, they only have two competitors,
Amazon and Microsoft, and no one is going to do a
search and be like, "Oh, Google's number one for
this term I searched. Let me just go buy it."
There's a decision-making process. You bring...
There's a committee decision. So SEO sort of made
no sense for that even to be included as a part
of a marketing channel. And at a grand scale,
Google Cloud should not be doing SEO. At a small
scale, a lot of SaaS tools shouldn't be doing SEO
because there isn't necessarily an SEO journey.
I get a lot of pushback from companies when I
tell them. They're like, "Look at all the SEO
we've done." But that plateaus really quickly.
This is really fascinating, and just
to maybe reframe what you're saying
because there's kind of a couple elements
of this. It's not necessarily that people
aren't searching Google for the problem. So
I'm thinking of Vanta SOC 2 stuff. It's not
like people aren't SOC 2 certification. It's not
like they're searching... they're not searching.
And what I'm hearing is the bigger issue is they
will never buy your product from that experience
and that journey. It may educate them a little
bit and may teach them, "Oh, Vanta exists," but
they're never going to become customers. They need
to talk to salesperson. They need to involve bunch
of stakeholders. So it's basically a sales
motion. It's not a product-led SEO motion.
Yes.
Is that right?
Cool. Pulling on that thread a little
bit further beyond maybe even B2B,
just how does one decide if
SEO is an opportunity for you,
and also just how much should you invest
in this opportunity just to explore it?
So we have to really put away the myth that SEO is
free because it's absolutely not free. There's a
cost in time. There's a cost and resources, and,
of course, there's the direct expense for SEO.
So if you're deciding that you should do SEO, so
now we have to go through this evaluation. Again,
this is where I think of it as a product
where you have all these product ideas and
what should you spend time and money on. So SEO
is a channel you may or may not want to invest in.
So say there's a SaaS tool, and they're convinced
there's an SEO journey, people do search for this
solution. When I was at SurveyMonkey, we generated
a couple of hundred million dollars a year off of
organic traffic because it was a freemium tool
where you search for the prodem... the problem,
you find the solution, it's free, you sign up
for it. If it works for you, you end up paying,
and that's the revenue we've generated from
organic. So say there is a journey, so people
do search for it, and it makes sense to invest in
SEO now is when you'll decide how much should you
invest in it and how you should invest in it.
So typically, [inaudible 00:40:32] again,
for SurveyMonkey, it was around creating content.
It was around templates. It wasn't very expensive.
But let's say there's a company that does not have
a content team. They don't have a product yet that
people are going to search for. They don't have a
product manager that's going to be overseeing this
SEO process. So say you need to hire this PM, or
you want to hire an agency, a typical SEO agency,
I mean, you're not going to spend $500 on an SEO
agency. It's going to be upwards of $10,000 just
because that's the cost of someone's time.
So it's $10,000 a month, $120,000 a year,
gets even more expensive if you have a full-time
employee. So that's one expense you're going to
outline. Then, you're going to add in all
the supporting resources. You need a CMS.
That costs money. You need an engineer
to support them. That costs money. You
need a potentially design. You need content.
So it can really add up quickly. And now you
look at that investment, and you say, "For
this tool, if I invested a million dollars
a year in SEO, do I expect to make back
a million dollars a year soon, right?
SEO will always make back money if it's the right
fit, but soon. So SaaS tools, especially startups,
they need to make that money back soon. Or if they
took that exact same million dollars and put it
into brand ads, or they put it into influencer
campaigns, or they put it into just traditional
paid marketing on Meta and Google, would you make
that million dollars or $1,000,001 back faster?
And that's where I think the evaluation should
happen instead of this default, "Well, I just got
my funding. I need to invest in SEO because
it's free, and everyone does SEO. And look,
my competitors do SEO." It should really be
this thoughtful strategic decision-making
process of how much will this cost me all
in and is this the right use of funds.
Amazing. So I think this is really
important. It's not that you won't
benefit from SEO. It's not that SEO isn't
an opportunity. It's that you have much
bigger opportunities in other areas. Most
likely, if you're a B2B SaaS companies,
because the journey isn't fully online, you're not
going to convert by just reading a bunch of pages.
Absolutely.
Super fascinating. Yeah.
Yeah. There was once a company I met, there
was a SaaS tool, they were in a gardening
space. [inaudible 00:42:39] they made a SaaS for
gardeners, and they were insistent on doing SEO.
And they asked me to look at a proposal they got
from an agency for $15,000 a month, and it was all
content. And then I asked them how their users
found them. How did they get all the customers
they had that paid them? How did they find them?
They said they go to these gardening shows
around the country, and they have a booth, and
each booth costs them $10,000. So I said, "Instead
of spending $15,000 on SEO, you can get... you can
go to all these shows for the exact same budget,
and you get users who are interested, they're
in market, they try your tool out at the booth,
and then they leave and they're leads that you
could follow up with. Instead of investing in me
like, hope it works. It's sort of free. There are
searches for it, but it's not the right searches."
The takeaway here is if you're thinking about
whether SEO is worth an investment for you and you
see all these other companies doing SEO winning
with SEO, think about how much will this actually
cost us. And I think the most important takeaway
for me here is if you don't think it'll convert
online if you think sales is the core motion of
the process, it's probably not a good ROI for you.
Absolutely. Yeah. Really think about
what are the trade-offs. Again,
from a product standpoint, there's
always trade-offs. So what are the
trade-offs to investing in this
channel versus another channel?
And I think what I've seen, there's
all the... the way I think about it,
there's four actual growth engines... there are
four core growth engines. SEO, paid, virality,
and sales. And what I find is, eventually, large
companies do them all. Unless you're a consumer,
you don't do sale. And so it's not like SEO
should you never do. It's I think the main
point here is earlier stage, when you have limited
resources, probably not the best use of your time.
I think there are companies that should probably
never do SEO. [inaudible 00:44:24] going back to
what I said when Google Cloud, I don't think that
Google could ever say... really pinpoint that
there was a customer that they got purely from
SEO, and you're going to do all sorts of weighted
attribution. And maybe that person did discover
Google Cloud from a piece of content or piece
of SEO asset, but they never would've converted
with all those other things that they've touched.
And it's not like you're saying, "Don't be
on the internet and don't will make it easy
for people to understand who you are, don't
have a great site, don't have other pages
writing about you. It's just don't...
You don't need to spend time optimizing
the search results for Google Cloud. You're not
going to benefit significantly from that work.
Yes, I mean, again, go really digging
into this user journey piece. I don't
think restaurants typically should have a
website. Not only should they not do SEO,
but I don't know that they should have a website.
Hot take.
Because if you think about the buyer
journey for a person looking for food,
they don't typically go to a website. So
if you're looking for pizza, and again,
a lot of pizza shops have websites. But if you're
looking for pizza, you're going to Google Maps,
DoorDash, Uber Eats. You're not going
on Google and saying, "Pizza near me,"
and then browsing the websites and just
making a decision about where to eat lunch.
Again, if you're choosing how to cater your kid's
birthday party, that might be a different thing,
but you're not browsing and saying, "These are
the places I'm going to go right now." But more
than that, it's expensive, and there's no way
that that pizza shop knows that the website they
have with the soft music playing and their menu
that comes up in flash, which is expensive, does
a single thing for them. Most of their orders are
going to come again through those other platforms.
Yeah, I hate restaurant websites. One thing
I read once that explains why what restaurant
websites are so bad is restaurant owners are
big on just like what is the experience when
someone enters my restaurant that they go
through the vibe, and they do that on the
website. They're like, here's the music, and
here's the imagery, and here's the animations.
And nobody wants that in [inaudible 00:46:19] on
their website. Just like give me the hours and
location and your menu. You mentioned a couple of
things that I want to drill into a little bit. So,
one is just how long SEO should take for you
to see results. Two is just expectations of
what does good conversion look like. What
does it tells you this is actually us,
a journey that could work for us well enough that
SEO might work? So maybe those two questions.
So those will be custom for anything. And
I hate to use the word, it depends because
I think whenever consultants say it depends,
they're just... they're throwing their hands
up and saying, "I don't really know. I'm not...
I don't have an opinion on this." And it's like
when you go to a doctor, and the doctor's like,
"Well, it depends." I mean, you could be dying,
or you could just... need to take a nap,
right. So there's a custom answer here,
and it comes down to what the company is and what
the expectations are. So how long it takes, that
depends on what you're building. So if you're...
if there's an... Again, with Tinder, it took
us a while to actually build anything.
So it took us all this time to build for ideate
them, build and then to see results. But once we
built, and I love working with big companies that
are well-known brands, because what we build,
as soon as it's available on the web, it's
like this turning a huge ship. It starts driving
revenue and starts being super effective because
it's there. Something didn't exist, and now it
exists, and it drives revenue. Smaller companies,
it may take many months before Google notices. It
may take many months before the demand is there.
With Zapier, I think it took them a couple of
years before they even saw any results because
nobody's looking for it. So it comes down to what
it is that you're building and how quickly users
will come and find and need that solution.
Then, as far as what the expectations are on
conversions, that also is really depends on what
it is that you're looking for. There's... Some
companies are building media, and they [inaudible
00:48:09]... I mean, again, I think most companies
should just not write a lot of content unless
they're a media company. But if you are building
media and you're monetizing that content from
a media standpoint, so maybe it leads, maybe
clicks off the page into leads, or maybe it's CPM
advertising, so then your conversion is... what
you're trying to do with SEO is get a lot of page
views because the more page views you get, the
more clicks off that page you get into something
else. If you're a SaaS tool, then your conversion
should absolutely be whatever a MQL should be.
So you... And again, I think most people don't
do this correctly with SEO. They used the wrong
conversion metric, which is top-of-funnel ranking.
"Oh, I'm ranking. My SEO is successful. I'm number
one for this." Instead of, "How does this benefit
me?" There was a company I was working with, a
SaaS tool. They're in a two-sided marketplace
they worked with... in an HR space, so they
only monetized one side of that HR space,
but all the traffic was on the other side of the
HR space. So when we were talking about their SEO
conversion problems, I suggested that they delete
all the content that was on the wrong side of that
marketplace because they didn't convert at all.
And there's no... And this is a common
misconception. People will think you get a benefit
from traffic. Google sees, "Oh, I get all this
traffic from search. They think I'm a very good
website. So even though none of this converts for
me, I should have a blog because blogs are good."
It doesn't really work like that. I mean, maybe
if you're this massive website and I don't know,
let's say, get millions and millions of visits,
then you can build some sort of authority and some
good experience in Google, and now you can launch
something else, and you don't have to worry about
needing to build up that authority. But generally,
driving traffic to something that doesn't
convert for you wouldn't be a good idea.
So really understanding what is it that you're
trying to do with SEO traffic, that's your
conversion metric. So it could be MQLs, could be
page use, could be dollar conversions, it could be
people picking up the phone or watching the video,
but it has to be some sort of conversion. So for a
startup, it might mean that they... you're getting
links. I mean, at a minimum, people reading your
content deciding to link to you and give you
social shares. That might be something you put
in a pitch deck. Whatever it is, there has to be
a conversion metric that matters for the business.
So just to give someone that's starting to do
this something concrete to look at. When you
come to a startup and help them with SEO, what
do you usually track as a sign this is working
that we should keep investing? What's... What
are the couple metrics that you look at most?
The first is really understanding what is
it that they care about. And rankings could
be something they care about if someone
else cares about it. So, for example,
if they're going to put in their pitch deck,
"We're number one for this tool," and investors,
they don't know that that doesn't convert. So that
might be something that we should care about. They
should be number one for that tool. If it's MQLs,
so they just need people filling out lead forms.
So really understanding who it is that they're
trying to attract with SEO that's the metric we're
going to use. And again, I don't know why SEO...
this happens with SEO but not any other channel.
No one doing paid marketing will ever say, "This
is how many times I'm number one on this search,
or this is how many clicks I get, or look at how
much I spent." There's really a, "We spend this,
and we're this efficient. This is what we drive
from that." And SEO really needs that same rigor.
So what I'm hearing is look at if you're in
B2B leads coming in through SEO, track that,
or rank potentially if that's like a vanity thing,
you can show investors and you're saying
traffic alone, because usually in decks I see
and investor updates almost always the metric
I see is traffic we're getting through SEO.
Yeah, total waste of time.
Amazing.
Yeah, I mean, unless there's a
reason for it. So if you're a
media company and traffic means
that that number keeps going up,
then yes, it matters. But if you are driving
leads and that traffic number goes up, you're
not driving more leads from SEO. You're getting
worthless traffic. It doesn't help the business.
Awesome. Okay. Back to the question
of just how long it takes just to
give someone something here that they
can tell... that can tell them when it
makes sense to keep going or move on.
Say you're just taking a shot at SEO,
how long should you give it to make a decision
this is working for us or not? Or is it always,
"There's always something here, keep
working." How do you decide keep doing or not?
When you're building out an SEO effort,
and I'm going to keep going back to this,
it's a product. So you're building out a
product and you're creating milestones.
So you say we're... it's going to take
us this first month to ideate on what it
is that we're building. It's going to...
In the second month, we're going to build
out a PRD for engineers to start working
on. In the third month, they're going to
start working, and they're going to ship this.
Now, if you start missing all those milestones,
so I mean, this is a common problem in consulting
in general, you miss all those milestones, and
then some will say, "What's... We've been working
together for six months, and we have nothing to
show for it." And you can point very specifically
to all those milestones that were missed.
So that's the result of not shipping or not
meeting the milestones that the SEO didn't work.
So as you're meeting those milestones, you can
say, "Well, we launched, and our expectation
was that after the first month of launching, we
would have X amount of pages indexed. Did we meet,
or did we miss that milestone?" And then you
can say, "SEO is working at a small scale."
And I've seen in many companies it takes a really
long time, but eventually, when you look back,
you see this hockey stick, but while you're
in it, you don't necessarily see that.
Awesome. Okay.
Okay. Let me share an example of one that
worked really quickly. So this was also an
interesting one, and I was at SurveyMonkey,
and I was introduced to the CEO of Quora,
who was interested in doing more SEO. So Quora had
never done SEO or never done SEO effectively from
a product standpoint. And there were a couple
of things I was able to recommend to them, and
within three months they had quadruple traffic. So
it really will depend on what is it that's holding
things back. In Quora's case, they weren't showing
any answers. So they were really pushing to get
people to log in before they saw any answers.
So I encourage them to show the answers. Yes,
they were going to be giving way answers for free,
but they were also going to be giving answers to
Google. So that was number one. That they were
able to quadruple traffic. And the second thing
is they had no way that Google could navigate
within the site. So when you came to Quora,
and it's like this again, so they
reversed the suggestion I made,
but I think it was 12 years ago. So when you
came to Quora, and when you come to Quora today,
you see related questions. So you see
a question and then there's related
questions. And that's the way a bot or
a human will navigate through the site.
If they create a sitemap, they did this
in the past, and if Quora's listening,
you should do this again. If you create
a categorized sitemap where you can say,
"These are all the questions on health and from
the sitemap, again, it's HTML sitemap, not just
an XML sitemap and way even a user can navigate
through it. This is health, and this is health
page one and health page two, and you can navigate
through this entire site. Then a search engine can
navigate through the entire site, and all of the
questions and answers are discoverable." So when
I made that suggestion to them, within a couple
of months, they were able to quadruple traffic.
There's so much here, and there's so many
valuable insights. One that I think is really
recurring that I think is really important to
people is the point that you're making about
your SEO content pages should solve... should
be a product, AKA should solve problems for
people as they're trying to understand the
space and the potential problem they have.
So correct me if I'm wrong, but kind of the advice
you're sharing is there's less opportunity in just
generating tons of blog posts that just have a
bunch of content. And the opportunity is more
things like Zapier and Canva with templates
and Notion and Quora where it's just like,
"Here's the answer." It's just like actually
help them solve the problem. And with that,
"Here's how our product [inaudible 00:56:03]
help you solve that problem further." Is that...
It's really building a product around what the
company is attempting to monetize. So Canva is
building templates because then they're going
on to monetize that templates by having other
people build off those templates with upgrades
and subscriptions. But if a company was... Let's
say there was an enterprise version of Canva, and
they didn't monetize those templates, so putting
out a bunch of free content on the internet that
just looked good wouldn't benefit. So it always
comes down to what is it. What is the product that
you want to use? So going to mention the templates
did at SurveyMonkey, so the survey product.
If someone looked for a template of a survey,
they wanted to make a survey. So we were not a
survey product, and we just monetized off the
survey templates that would not have done anything
for us. So copying someone else's version of
programmatic doesn't do anything. And generally,
doing programmatic for the sake of programmatic,
so just to have content, wouldn't do
anything unless that programmatic fed
you into exactly what your product did. So
Zapier, they did programmatic. It feeds you
into making other zaps between different
products. Tinder, we did programmatic.
It fed you into, "Oh, well, you would
like to solve your lonely... We showed
you that your loneliness problem is
solvable in the city you're in. You
have to solve that problem by downloading
the Tinder app." And I've never used Tinder,
only used it from a marketing standpoint, but
[inaudible 00:57:26] Tinder gates you. So if
you'd like to get the advanced Tinder
experience, you have to pay. And again,
they're... it's all part of that buyer
journey, and anything you're building SEO for,
it has to be a piece of that buyer journey. So
programmatic, blog posts, anything you're doing,
if there is no product journey for it,
there's no user journey, it just stops.
That's an amazing clarification. So again, it's
another point you've been making of traffic alone
is not valuable if it doesn't convert. And so
you can look at a Canva, you can look at Notion
at Airtable with all these templates, copy
that. But if that isn't the thing people,
will buy from you and monetize
it's not going to be worth doing.
... Will buy from you and monetize.
It's not going to be worth doing.
Yes.
Awesome. I'm excited to
chat with Christina Gilbert,
the founder of OneSchema, one of our
longtime podcast sponsors. Hi, Christina.
Yes. Thank you for having me on, Lenny.
What is the latest with OneSchema? I know you
now work with some of my favorite companies,
like Ramp, Vanta Scale, and Watershed.
I heard that you just launched a new
product to help product teams import CSVs
from especially tricky systems, like ERPs.
Yes, so we just launched OneSchema File Feeds,
which allows you to build an integration with
any system in 15 minutes as long as you can export
a CSV to an SFTP folder. We see our customers all
the time getting stuck with hacks and workarounds,
and the product teams that we work with don't have
to turn down prospects because their systems
are too hard to integrate with. We allow our
customers to offer thousands of integrations
without involving their engineering team at all.
I can tell you that if my team had
to build integrations like this,
how nice would it be to be able
to take this off my roadmap,
and instead use something like OneSchema, and not
just to build it, but also to maintain it forever?
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many
horror stories of multi-day outages from
even just a handful of ad records. We are
laser-focused on integration reliability to
help teams end all of those distractions
that come up with integrations. We have
a built-in validation layer that stops
any bad data from entering your system,
and OneSchema will notify your team
immediately of any data that looks incorrect.
I know that importing incorrect data can cause
all kinds of pain for your customers and quickly
lose their trust. Christina, thank you for
joining us and if you want to learn more,
head on over to OneSchema.co, that's OneSchema.co.
Okay, so coming back to AI and its impact on SEO,
can you use AI to help you with this,
and use AI to create content for you?
AI is a tool. Everyone says AI is a tool, it's
not a solution. You can use AI to create content
if the content you're creating is a part of that
journey. For example, before AI content really
came on the scene, because AI's been around for a
while, Jasper's been around for a while, Writer's
been around for a while before ChatGPT. Before
these tools, a lot of ways that companies created
content for cheap is they went on Fiverr, and they
went on Upwork, and they just created content.
A lot of that content, completely worthless.
If you're just creating content for the sake
of content, and you paid someone on Upwork $50
for their content, now you can use an AI tool
and just create the content, the same worthless
content, for free. AI as a tool is a tool creating
something that's not necessarily useful for
the end journey of the company and for the user
journey in general. However, if the content you
were creating was pretty useful, and now you're
using AI to create really useful content for
cheaper and better, of course, you can use it.
An example of a place you can use AI content is
if you're an e-commerce site and you're selling
your own products, of course, you can use AI
content to write product descriptions. It's not
a content website. There's a lot of big companies
out there, and if anybody wants to look at some of
the e-commerce sites and how they do SEO, a lot of
them have large SEO teams. The typical JCPenney,
the Nordstroms, the Macy's, they have a
lot of content on their category pages,
but if you look at the keywords that drive traffic
to those pages, it's the products on the pages.
If you're looking for shoes, the fact that
a Macys.com page will have a lot of content
about what shoes do doesn't do anything for the
user. They're just looking for shoes, and then
there's shoes on the page. I think Macy's actually
ranks pretty well on those kinds of things. Using
AI content to write more fluff content that's
not necessary would just be a waste of time.
Using AI content to feed in a product,
and describe what that product is,
and maybe some features of that product which
help a user, that's not hurting your SEO,
because what you're trying to optimize for
is the product and the product name itself.
Got it. Basically, don't use AI to generate entire
blog posts. I know people are doing this all over
the place, but absolutely leverage AI to help
you add to existing pages, descriptions, titles,
things like that, which I can see why Google,
Google would've no idea that you were helped
to write this thing with AI, right, if it's just
a small part of the page versus the entire page?
In their documentation, they say that
AI itself is not the problem. It's the
helpfulness, the usefulness of the
content that would be a problem.
You don't have to name names or reveal anything,
but do you know of a bunch of companies using AI
now to generate tons of high successful pages,
high converting pages in some way? In this way?
There's this hatred of AI content by users
in general. I think once companies declare
that they're using AI, people get upset
about it. It was a Red Ventures company,
I think it was CNET that said they were using AI
to create content. I think they got in trouble
because they said they're using AI to create
content, but if they had not said they're
using AI to create content, I think their
entire model would've been very successful.
There's no reason you can't take in, they
take 10 products, and they want to review
10 different products. There's no reason you
can't tie that all together, have AI write
the original piece of content, and then have
a human editor just review it. I don't know,
years ago, it's not AI, but it's sort of like AI,
but there are sports websites that will take in a
lot of the things that happen in the sports game
to merge it all together into a piece of content.
If you look at any earnings reports on public
companies, it's sort of the same thing. Their
company will issue, they'll file their earnings
report, and then now it's AI. Before AI,
it was basically like Mad Libs kind of
content. It would extract pieces of the
earnings report and then it would write a blog
post, which is actually fairly useful. I don't
think there's an issue with it itself. I
don't think users have an issue with it.
I think if you read that old piece of
content, again, on earnings reports,
it's pretty obvious that it wasn't written by
a financial journalist, but it was useful. You
got a quick summary, you didn't have to go
into the SEC and read an earnings report.
There's this guy, Noah Smith, he's on Twitter,
he's got a newsletter called No Opinions.
It's awesome. He had this tweet about how we're
approaching an age of a ton of slop of content,
just a lot of really bad content generated by
AI for better or worse, this is related to SEO,
but it makes me think about just how
much bad stuff we're going to see.
To your point, it doesn't matter
whether it was generated by AI or not,
people will gravitate towards and
Google will gravitate towards stuff
that is useful and good, whether
it's written by people or not.
This is a huge issue for Google, because the
amount of content being created is enormous,
and it's growing exponentially. Google's
trying to crawl everything. They now have
more content to crawl, which becomes more
expensive for Google, and which is why you
have this backlash by Google against many
websites, because they're trying to clean
the index to save their own costs and to protect
the users from having to see this awful content.
The crazy thing for LLMs is now to be trained.
They're trained on content on the internet in a
big way, and they're struggling with not training
their LLMs on stuff that AI has written because it
becomes this, a bad direction that LLMs will go.
They're trained on themselves. Anyway, something
I wanted to come back to around AI, which is
AI Overviews. I imagine many people are like,
"How do I get into that answer? How do I get
my product into the answer that Google gives
at the top?" Is that something you recommend
people try to do? Is that something you can do?
I think of AI or AI Overviews as a branding
exercise. Getting into the AI Overview,
and Google has links, I mentioned this earlier
that Google has links within the content,
and I think a lot of what Google does is around
potentially liability protection. They're having
links. They're saying, "Well, we didn't tell you
to jump off the Golden Gate Bridge, this website,
which we summarized, told you to jump off the
Golden Gate Bridge," or, "We didn't plagiarize.
We just linked to the piece of content. We may
have extracted more from the content than we
were supposed to, and the law hasn't decided
that yet, but we linked to it, so it's fair."
Right now, Google has these links in the content,
and it sort of links off of it. I did a survey on
LinkedIn, and I was surprised by the answer. I
thought most people did not click on the links.
I got a couple hundred responses, and it's sort
of 50/50 and based on my SurveyMonkey experience.
It's not a statistically significant survey in
general, but it will never go to 99% and one.
That's fairly indicative that people are clicking
the links, which surprises me, because I don't
think that the links are necessarily meant by
Google to be useful, which means that AI Overviews
is essentially duplicating search results.
You have this AI Overview which summarizes,
then you have a link so you can link off of it,
and then beneath it, you sort of have the exact
same thing. That's the challenge that Google has
to work through. For a company to show up in AI
Overview, it's a brand challenge. If your link
shows up there, then you likely were showing up
beneath it in the ranking results, so you've
already done the work you're supposed to do.
If you're showing up in the AI Overview mentioned
as a brand, like, these are the top CRM tools,
you're showing up as a brand, that means
you've exercised brand efforts and it's
working out. I don't know that companies
necessarily want their content to show up
because they're giving away their content for
free. They want to be showing up in a way that
benefits them. If you show up as a brand, you've
done good branding, but if you show up as a link,
it means Google has stolen your content,
and people may or may not click off of it.
Along this lines of brand and SEO,
do you have any... That's always this
question of are we investing in brand? Do
we just want people to be aware we exist,
or are we trying to actually drive
conversion? Any advice on how to
think about brand building and SEO,
especially with this world of AI?
The biggest myth in SEO is that you could
just build links, and link building is the
secret source and the secret sauce to growing
your SEO footprint. That's totally wrong,
because the way most people build
links is they buy these guest posts,
or they pay for links on low authority websites
that sort of look like they might have authority,
and it doesn't really benefit anyone
because no one's reading these sites.
It's funny that everyone complained about Google
as this really, really smart, all-knowing LLM,
and at the same time, they think they're dumb
enough to fall for these guest posts that are
on websites that no one really read. The right
way to build links is to build a brand. It comes
part and parcel of what you're trying to do.
If you're building links, and going back to
all the SaaS examples we talked about, so
if you've created a bunch of content that
is not relevant for the product you're trying to
sell, building links to the content that doesn't
really benefit the product, doesn't really
benefit, the links don't benefit the product.
If you can build this product that's
awesome and everyone loves and wants to use,
and you get not links, but mentions,
and links might be mentions now,
because the way a link before LLMs and the link 10
years ago was actually an HTML link. Now, Google
can read content. They can say, "Well, you've
been mentioned here," that's pretty good. Now,
we acknowledge that this might be the brand, and
this might be the match for that kind of thing.
That's helping to build that brand. In general,
I think of any SEO effort as promoting a brand,
building up a brand, rather
than building a product,
and then separately building out an SEO effort,
which has content that may not be relevant,
and links from websites that are certainly not
relevant to content that's not relevant. It
all comes together as being one big effort. The
same thing you'll do on PR, you'll do for SEO.
Awesome. Okay. I'm glad we touched that.
There's a few other directions I want to go,
so I'm going to bounce around a little bit
and cover some of the other stuff I wanted
to extract from your deep experience
in this space. One is you've mentioned
this idea of programmatic SEO a couple
times versus editorial. Maybe first,
just clarify what those two directions are,
just for people that don't exactly know what
you mean. Then two, what's your general advice for
which direction to go, programmatic or editorial?
It might be obvious at this point, but I'm
going to say it's dependent on the user, but
essentially, what programmatic is is it's taking a
bunch of data sources and building out a page that
is a combination of all these data sources. In my
book, I talk about two of my favorite programmatic
SEO companies. One of them was created by a
past, well, it's not created, the strategy was
created by a past guest of yours, Luc Levesque,
who introduced us, and that was TripAdvisor.
TripAdvisor took in all these data sources of,
"This is the hotel, these are the cities," and
then it allowed UGC to combine into one
comprehensive page about each property.
TripAdvisor did not write a piece of content on
every single hotel. They don't write a piece of
content on, "Here's this long form blog post as
an influencer on the Waldoff Astoria of New York,
and here's a long form blog post about
the Marriott Marquis in San Francisco."
They built it all from a programmatic
standpoint. They took all these data sets,
they took all the countries in the world, they
took all the properties, and they merged into one
comprehensive page, which has dominated the top
of search results since the beginning of the
time. They still own it. That team has cycled
through many, many leaders, many different,
a lot of different things, and they're still
number ones. It's the strategy that has allowed
them to build that brand and to dominate it.
The second example is Zillow. What Zillow did
is they solved an early problem many years ago in
the real estate space, which is no one understood
what the value of a piece of property was.
Zillow took in all of those data sets. They got,
some of them are government data sets, some of
them are their own comparison data sets based on
other home sales. The government can say a house
is worth one price, and based on their comparison,
Zillow can completely disagree with it.
They're building in these data sets,
and they're taking photos from realtors,
they're taking neighborhood data, they're
taking school data, and that's a programmatic
SEO page. SEO is the only channel to bring in
traffic to each one of these pages. They're
not going to do paid traffic for my house,
they're not going to do paid traffic for your
house. The only way someone would find that page
on Zillow, either they start at Zillow.com
and then just navigate through it, or they
Google it. Those are programmatic SEO efforts.
On the flip side is editorial. Editorial would be,
in TripAdvisor's case, writing out that long form
piece of content around each hotel, each city, and
all the things they've done. Zillow would be the
same. Zillow would take 500 million properties and
write out an editorial piece of content. Neither
of those would be a fit for their model, and it
would be extremely expensive. Say each piece
of content would cost a thousand dollars, that
would be cost prohibitive for anyone to do.
Going back to my distinction based on the user,
what is it that the user's looking for? Is the
user looking for the value of a home? They don't
need a long form piece of content. They need a
piece of content or a page that just says what
the value of that home is. TripAdvisor's
case, they're looking for a single thing,
a rating, or maybe they need some of that
UGC, but really, they're looking for that
rating. That long form piece of content, there's
a purpose for it, but not on TripAdvisor's site.
Understanding, what is it that the user needs
will help solve, do you approach this from an
editorial standpoint, or do you approach
this from a programmatic standpoint? Some
of the companies I mentioned earlier, like G2 and
Capterra, which are completely being disrupted,
so they're being disrupted by editorial,
but they're also being disrupted by Google
itself with their AI Overviews.
If you look for the top CRM tools,
you have G2 or you have Capterra, but you
also have Forbes writing out a long form
piece of content on what Salesforce is, what
HubSpot is, and that's probably unnecessary.
I think generally, you would, programmatic is
the better path and the most common success
path is what I'm hearing. What are things you
need in place to be successful in programmatic
SEO? Like basically, you just need some sort
of data source that you own. Is that just...
What's a checklist of like, "Here's what
tells you you have a big opportunity here?"
Programmatic is the right solution when there's
scale and when there's a user use case. If there
is not, you create scale for nothing. An earlier
version of programmatic, again, pre a lot of the
internet companies now, is building out a piece
of content for every single zip code in America.
Say you offer some sort of local product. You
would build out a page for every single zip code
that is, in theory, programmatic, but users
don't look for it, and Google has completely
disrupted that with their own local products.
Programmatic can always be something. I see
programmatic mistakes all the time, where websites
look at, they say, "Look, we're making reviews of
software. There's 10,000 different softwares in
the world. We're just going to make out a page
for each one and we're going to combine it with,
I don't know, a city." You can make programmatic
pages like that, but there's no use case. Really
knowing what programmatic solution to use comes
down to, "Is this something that someone would
actually be looking for? Does this page itself
provide a solution?" Zapier provided a solution
because someone was looking for that combination,
but there are many tools like Zapier, which
try to be Zapier, but they're not looking for
that solution. Going back to some of the template
companies you mentioned, I don't think a lot of
companies that make templates, they're making
programmatic, but there's not a use case for
every single one of those templates. They've
made programmatic for no [inaudible 01:15:53].
Again, SurveyMonkey was one where we had
a fat head of templates we could make,
but it wasn't a long tail. We could make a
hundred templates, but we couldn't make 10,000.
I want to do a rapid fire of SEO myths.
Before I do that, I know that you spent
a lot of time actually reading the recent ruling
against Google and their whole deal with Apple,
and you were telling me it revealed there were a
lot of interesting stuff about their strategy and
where search was going. Let's spend a little time
here, just what did you learn doing that exercise?
It's fascinating. It's 286 pages. I
basically read a book. It was a verdict.
Oh, geez.
I would say that the judge or the clerk that
wrote this verdict has a better understanding
how the SEO works and how digital marketing works
than most people I meet in digital marketing.
Wow, I did not expect to hear that.
Yeah. This verdict explains how Google decides to
rank a page. The verdict explains how the auction
model works in ads, in Google Ads. I think that's
fascinating. Talked about the comparison between
social media. This court really understood a lot
of the questions that were posed to them. For
example, Google tried to say that they're not
a monopoly because they're social media. The
court analyzed that question and said, "Social
media is not a comparison to Google search."
Google tried to say a lot of the things they did
were non-monopolistic because there's alternatives
like Bing. The court really analyzed a lot of
these things. Why I found it fascinating was,
again, a lot of the testimony was public,
is the summary of how the court put it
all together in a verdict. A few of the
things I learned is one, the market share,
Google's market share. That's been a number
that no one really liked to talk about.
Google would say, "Oh, we think it's like
80%," because they didn't want to be viewed
as a monopoly. Microsoft would say, "Well, maybe
we have 20%." I just found a recent document from
Microsoft where they claimed to have a lot
of market share in search. In the verdict,
it says that Google has 98% of mobile searches.
I forget whether it said that the court said it,
and it said Google didn't disagree, or
that came from Google's own documentation,
but 98% of mobile searches.
The thing that I thought was
most fascinating from the verdict is how much the
default partnerships that Google has contributes
to Google's success. The plaintiff in the case
was the Department of Justice suing Google for
being a monopoly. However, I don't know what the
word is, but one of the complainants in this is
this company, Neva, which was a search engine
started by a past Google, I think it was like
a head of research or something. A senior
person at Google created a new search engine.
A lot of the trial was focused on
how Neva could not be successful,
despite having a better search engine, despite
having a better experience for users, because they
didn't have any of these default distribution
agreements. That's the part that I thought
was most fascinating. Google has these default
agreements with Apple, and they also have Chrome.
They have all these inputs into Google searches,
which means that I don't think there's a chance,
and this is the biggest takeaway, I don't think
there's a chance that ChatGPT, or Perplexity,
or Claude, or any of these other LLM
startups, because they're startups now,
even OpenAI is a startup with Microsoft's
investments, still a startup. I don't think
they have a chance at really unseating
Google purely from a quality standpoint.
That's what a lot of the documentation in this
verdict is about is how much a force of habit,
how much the brand, and how much the
distribution agreements Google has,
drives searchers to Google. There were a couple
of very interesting insights. One is that Bing
tried to give itself to Apple for free, and
Apple said there was absolutely no price that
they would take to use Bing search within Apple.
Another one was Mozilla had a partnership with,
I think it was Yahoo, and they did a rev share
deal with Yahoo, and everyone switched back to
Google. When people say, "Well, SEO is dead,
everyone's going to go to OpenAI," and you just
look at the 25 years of Google's existence and
what they've built, I really don't think so. I
really think distribution and the force of brand
will keep almost everything Google has today.
Now, why is Google fighting back so
hard to build AI Overviews? Well,
I think there's two answers. One is, like I said,
Wall Street. They really want Wall Street to think
that they care and they're doing this thing.
The other is losing small percentage points
to ChatGPT costs Google a lot of money, so it's
worth it for them to invest in it, but I don't
think that they have any fear about not being
the most dominant search engine in the world.
Well, isn't the idea with this trial that this
may change, and they may lose that default status,
whether it happens or not, that's the whole
game here, right? It's like maybe they can't
be that anymore, and that maybe opens up.
I think that's the opportunity potentially.
I don't think so. Yeah, I'm no legal
expert. I don't know what the DOJ will do,
but what's interesting, if you saw Google's
press release when the verdict came out,
so Google tweeted, "We thank the court for
recognizing that we're the greatest search
engine in the world, and more to come." They're
going to fight back, and it's almost like a bully
being declared the world's greatest bully.
They're like, "See, told you we're strong."
When reading the verdict, it actually
said, "There is no competitor. Google is
the greatest search engine. They have 25 years
of great data. They've done a fantastic job."
I don't see any way that those, if
they break the default agreements,
Apple actually loses all that money Google's
paying, and then users will still Google. That's
not what will do it. I think the only thing they
can do is figure out how to prop up a competitor.
Yeah. I think that's an interesting takeaway.
People will go to Google, will switch to Google
even if it's not default. There's actually a
really interesting takeaway from Ben Thompson's
analysis of this stuff, and I will point to
the podcast episode. I think that shifted my
perspective on this, because when you hear Google
is paying Apple to be the default search engine,
it sounds nefarious and unfair. The deal
is actually revenue share. They give them
a percentage of the revenue from the ads, which
ends up being $20 billion, something like that,
a lot of money for Apple. Anyone else can come
to Apple and say, "We will give you a revenue
share of our searches also." It's just nobody is
as big and can pay as much. If you think about it,
why can't Google come to Apple? "Hey, we will
send you tons of money by doing the search for
you and giving you a large percentage
of the ads that we are doing for you."
It's weird to not allow that
if you really think about it,
but it's also unfair, because no one else
will ever be able to compete with that.
Yeah, and that's what the court said is like
Neva didn't have a chance because of that. One
other point is, so I did this survey, this
was years ago when I was at SurveyMonkey,
I did a search market penetration
survey to figure out who used what,
like Bing versus Google. On my survey, I
was generous. I threw DuckDuckGo on there,
and I came back, I had thousands of responses, and
came back that I had 1% of people use DuckDuckGo.
I didn't realize it, that DuckDuckGo didn't
actually know what their market penetration
was. When I shared the survey, Gabriel Weinberg,
who's the CEO of DuckDuckGo, hit me on Twitter
and he said, "Can you share the data with us?
We really would like to see it." This was,
let's say 10, 12 years ago. In the verdict,
it said that DuckDuckGo's market share is 2%.
I came back with 1% 12 years ago. DuckDuckGo,
I think they raised a hundred million dollars.
They have all these brand partnerships. They
have, at baseball games, they have their logo,
they've done everything, and all they've been able
to do is get from 1% to 2%. There's a lot there,
and Google being Google, I don't
see anyone knocking them off.
Fascinating. Well, thanks for sharing your
takeaway so that we don't have to read this
report. Before I move to rapid fire SEO myths,
is there anything else along the lines of AI
or SEO that you think is really important to
share that you want to leave listeners with?
I think the most important thing to leave
people with is SEO is not dying. There will
always be a world where users are requesting
their own information. One of the reasons
I think these home assistants, whether
it's from Google, or Apple, or Amazon,
have never taken off, is because you don't
have choice. You talk to your Google,
and it gives you only one answer. You talk to
Amazon, and it gives you only one answer. Like,
"I want to buy toilet paper," and Amazon
just buys you whatever it decides to buy you.
There will always be a world where there needs
choice. One other piece from the verdict is Google
believes that we're in the very early days of
LLMs, and even with all the machine learning they
do and understanding users, you will always need
real user data, which Google has on past searches.
I think users will always be requesting their own
information, and there's never going to be an AI
that understands you so perfectly, it's
going to know that for you personally,
you would like to click result number five.
That's the best fit for what you're looking
for right now, which means that there always
needs to be multiple choices to make. Yes,
most clicks are probably going through
the first one, two, or three results,
but there needs to be seven, 10, multiple pages
of Google, because some people do go to those
other pages. I think that's the most important
thing to underscore is that all of this means
that search changes, a lot of top-of-funnel search
goes away, but in general, there's always going to
be a world where people are doing the searches.
Then the last piece on that really is when you're
looking to do something with search, you're
looking to take an action. Companies benefit
from those actions. Say you're a hotel, and you
want people to sleep in your hotel and pay you
to sleep in your hotel. The aggregate number
of people needing to take that action and pay
you for it does not change even if search
volume gets cut. If you're selling shoes,
people still need to buy shoes.
If you're selling information,
though, your media, if you're WebMD, yes, your
revenue declines, because that information that
you now aggregated and curated and gave away
for free in return for people clicking on ads,
Google is now going to give away for free
in return for no one clicking on ads.
Interesting. I wonder if there's an
investment arbitrage opportunity of
predicting which businesses will decline
with this and which will thrive. Anyway,
I want to talk about SEO myths. I know that you
have a few things, and we've talked about a few
of these, I think, of just things that you
know people believe about SEO, but they're
actually wrong. Let me just ask you, what are
some myths that people get wrong about SEO?
Probably the biggest one we've said over and
over is they even need to do SEO. There's this
always default assumption that you've raised
money, you have a marketing team, you should
do SEO. I think that one is really worth putting
to bed is think about that user journey. Should
you do SEO? It's a question like, "They ask
about other channels, should you do brand..."
It's a question like they ask about other
channels. "Should you do brand marketing?
Should you take out an ad in Times
Square?" And no one will say, "Well,
I just raised a million dollars.
I should totally take out an ad
in Times Square." And congratulations
on being in Times Square, by the way.
Thank you.
No one will just decide, "Oh, I've
got money to burn, let me just burn
it." So somehow SEO becomes this thing
of like, "Oh, I've raised money. Now,
I need an SEO team." So that's I think the first
myth that's really important to just put to bed.
Awesome. What else?
Link building. So link building is brand
building. So it's thinking about how you're
going to build a brand and have people mentioned
to you. And when you're doing link building,
you're creating a relationship between
the piece of content that has linked to
you and the product or whatever you're trying
to monetize. So that should be link-building.
Just getting the idea of getting links on...
An HTML link will equal SEO success, again,
I think that's completely wrong. And then I
mean probably the biggest myth in general is
thinking that Google itself is a black box.
So I think there's nuances to how you rank,
and no one can really unearth what is it that
will you be number one and what it is that will
make you be number three. But the basic idea of
how you build SEO is very simplistic and Google
has a best practices guide on what it is that
you should be doing, which is build a website
that Google can understand, link to the pages
in that, write content that is helpful and that
users want to read. And those are the basics.
And starting with that is how you're going to
build an SEO strategy that improves upon it.
But the idea of if, "I take all three of these
steps right now. I'm guaranteed to be number
one," I think is something that is completely
incorrect. And there's an assumption that if you
do a lot of things around SEO, you're going to
be successful. And I think that that's incorrect.
Yes, there are nuances. But for the most part,
you get from most... Zero to 10, you can get
to step eight by just doing the best practices.
Oh, wow. It sounds very empowering.
I like the sound of that. Maybe just
on that thread briefly. If someone
wanted to start down the road of SEO,
I know you're going to be a little bit
biased because you help companies with this,
but do you recommend bringing someone like you
in first or having someone just give it a shot,
listening to this podcast, reading some
books and blogs, or something else?
Yes, so I am biased. I think they should
have the right people give them advice on
SEO. So if someone wants to be... If they
validated that there is an SEO effort,
paying for help on SEO, it goes back to
that resource discussion we had before.
So if you want to hire a growth advisor,
a growth advisor might be very expensive,
but you squash a learning curve so you
don't make as many mistakes as fast.
If you hire someone in-house, and a lot
of times they see this with roles where
I'm helping companies hire someone for SEO, they
don't have a lot of budget, which means they're
going to have someone that doesn't have a lot
of experience. So is that the right decision
to make? If you're hiring an agency, agencies
are typically expensive, and agencies a lot
of times get paid on deliverables. So are the
deliverables they're doing worth paying for?
An easy deliverable that a lot of
agencies produce now is content,
but that goes back to our earlier discussion.
Do you even need the content? It's very easy for
agencies to sell content as deliverable because
it's something they actually deliver. Delivering
strategy the way most of my growth advising works
is very difficult because I don't have a strategy
to offer in a proposal because I haven't developed
a strategy, and we don't actually see the fruits
of that until we implement the strategy. But
agencies can end-run that by just saying,
"Oh, you pay us on a monthly basis and these
are the things we're going to shift to you."
Something that I wanted to touch on, which
might be a myth and might not be a myth. But I
think you're going to say it's a myth based on
what you said about Google being so dominant.
There's a lot of talk about TikTok and Instagram
replacing Search for people. I actually do search
TikTok a lot now for like, "How do I solve this
problem? How do I cut a watermelon? How do I,
I don't know, find a cup for my baby?" It's
really good. What's your take on TikTok and
Instagram videos basically replacing a lot of
searching for Gen Z, especially, and younger kids?
In the Google Verdict, I think Google's said
this before. 63% of Gen Z uses TikTok to search.
Oh, wow.
Yeah. I think that's just a headline
number because it comes down to,
you said it over and over in the podcast, user
journeys. So there's going to be things that are
more appropriate for TikTok or Instagram,
and there are going to be things that are
more appropriate for Search. So I think
if you're doing top-of-funnel discovery,
you're going to maybe watch TikTok
videos to learn more about the topic.
But as you go into the mid-funnel, so say you
want to... A popular TikTok search is around
travel. So you want to go on a trip. You want to
go to Southeast Asia. You don't know where exactly
you want to go. So you might want to watch a
bunch of videos and see influencers and see
experiences. But now you're ready to book. And
you want to book a hotel. You want to book your
flights. All of that is not going to happen
on TikTok. All of that's going to happen on
Google Search. So that's the mid-funnel again.
A lot of search will move different places, but
ultimately, Google is still the right place to do
those searches, to do those mid-funnel searches.
So maybe it was more inappropriate that there
ever wasn't TikTok for you to get those better
experiences. For those top-of-funnel things, you
had to suffer through reading awful content that
was written only for SEO purposes, and now you
get rich dynamic content that comes from TikTok.
And one interesting piece on this is if TikTok
does get banned in the US, which looks like it's
likely, a company that will pick up all of that
users is YouTube. So YouTube has YouTube Shorts.
And again, we're looking at a potential monopoly
with Google as Google tries to put those YouTube
Shorts to solve the problem that TikTok was now
solving. So that will be kind of interesting.
Oh, man. Google all the way down.
Yes.
A thought I had as you were talking about
this idea of mid-funnel versus top funnel
is a simple way to think about the
mid-funnel is where there's intent.
You actually have intent to now buy a
thing, a specific thing. Yeah. Cool.
I mean that's what it is, but it's a buyer
journey. So at the top of the funnel,
you're curious. You don't know if you have intent.
And in the older way of doing SEO where you only
focused on top of the funnel, you only focused
on rankings as a KPI, which I think is sort of
the incorrect way of doing things. There is
no intent. So you showed a KPI that matched
with a non-user, which matched with a non-buyer.
As you move down the funnel, there is intent. So
there is a user and there's less traffic. There's
always going to be less traffic at the middle of
the funnel. But that doesn't matter because your
KPI is closely related to your business metrics.
Let's do a couple more myths if
there's anything else that we missed,
and then we'll wrap up and get to our very
exciting lightning round. Is there anything
else that you think is an important
myth that people get wrong about SEO?
I'll touch on one more myth, which is
that technical SEO is an easy solve
to any SEO problems. So there's been a
lot of Google updates recently. Again,
I think... I don't like to defend
Google because in reading the Verdict,
I think that Google did some pretty evil
things. But a lot of what Google has been
doing is pushing back on the things that
users hate. There's a lot of bad SEO content
out there. So Google's trying to get rid of a lot
of this bad SEO content in their recent updates.
When sites get hit by these updates, they try
to solve the problem that they think happened
to them by doing technical SEO. So they'll
reach out to me or to someone like me and say,
"Can you do an SEO audit and understand why our
traffic has suffered?" The reason their traffic
has suffered is because they've done things that
were not really useful for users and they sort of
polluted Google. They need to solve that problem.
Technical SEO has a place. So if you have a large
website with tens of millions of pages, if you're
Zillow, how you link to each listing, if you're
Airbnb, how you link and allow Google to crawl a
site and understand a site, very, very important.
If you have a hundred-page website that sells
a SaaS tool, technical SEO is probably going to
be less important. So spending money and time
on technical SEO would be a waste of time. So
I think that's another big myth is you solve SEO
problems with the right SEO solution rather than,
"Let's do an audit or let's get better links or
my page..." Page speed is another one that...
Agencies like to sell on... If things related
to page speed, Google keeps changing the words
of what that is, but it doesn't matter as much.
Because at the margins, yes, maybe if you're Kayak
and you're competing, you get Expedia, and Kayak
is maybe slightly faster, maybe that matters. But
if you're in a space where you're competing
against lots of slow terrible websites, it
doesn't matter at all. So spending a lot of money
on making that fix is not the right thing to do.
I like how you just make SEO feel much
more approachable and simple and something
that you could just do and not have to
again figure out the dark arts that...
It is not a dark art. It
should be for most things,
it is simple. And then there are tons of
companies out there get in a lot of trouble,
and there's billions of dollars to be
made on doing the right SEO. But a lot
can be unlocked by very simplistic SEO. PMs
that don't really have an SEO background can
do enough SEO to make a lot of money for the
company without needing to be an SEO expert.
I love that. That's actually how it worked
at Airbnb. The PMs work in SEO were not like
historically SEO legends. They were just
PMs figuring out SEO and they had a really
big impact. So that really resonates with me.
Eli, is there anything else that we haven't
touched on that you think is important to
you or something that you think might be
useful to people to leave them with before
we get to our very exciting lightning round?
Yes. So I think we talked about how
to decide whether to resource SEO,
but we didn't talk about how to understand
what the expectations are from SEO. So this
is something I came up with while I was working
at Faire, which is a very interesting company.
So it's F-A-I-R-E. They are a wholesale Shopify.
They were launching in a new country, and they
wanted to understand what the upside of launching
in that country was from an SEO standpoint. So
the way most people do SEO forecasting is they
do a bottoms-up forecast, which is they look at
keywords. So say we want to sell a pair of shoes.
You do a bottoms-up forecast, you go onto a
keyword research tool, and they're all fairly
the same. Look at how many people search for
shoes every month. And then you try to estimate
what your ranking would be on that word shoes,
and then you estimate what you click
through it would be, and then based on
that, that's your clicks. And then you get a
conversion rate, and that's your bottoms up.
And you make an assumption that the word
shoes in that tool didn't capture all the
people that search like white shoes and black
shoes and running shoes, so you just gross it
up. You just pick a number and you gross
it by 10, and that's your SEO forecast.
Now, the problem with that is that usually it's
too small. So you get this number and now you're
pitching to launch in a new country. I want to
launch in Japan and sell shoes. And you say,
"Well, I think I can get 500 users because based
on the way I got here, this is my click-through
rate and this is my rankings and I'm 500 users."
And no one will ever fund that. That's too small.
Now if you're launching in a new country, it's
actually fairly easy to figure out what your
SEO upside is because you can take the population
in the country. So this is not something Pharoah
sells, so I don't have to... So I'm not giving
away anything. But say you're launching shoes.
You're launching a new product website that
you're selling shoes in a country like Japan.
I'm going to guess. I don't know
the actual numbers for Japan. So
say Japan has a hundred million people and
you're selling shoes. And you're not going
to sell shoes to a hundred million people.
We're only selling shoes to men. And let's
just divide it in half. 50% of Japan is men, so
we got 50 million people that would buy shoes.
But now, we're also going to say, "Well, there's
older people and younger people and we're not
selling shoes to them." So now we can take 25
million and cut that in half. And then from there,
again, we're selling shoes on the internet. Not
everyone buys shoes on the internet. Some people
buy shoes in a store. Some people buy shoes on the
internet. So you take some percentage rate of the
amount of people that are going to buy shoes on
the internet and say, "We'll take 10% of our 25
billion people in our market. 2.5 million people
buy shoes on the internet and we want to do SEO
for 2.5 million people. And our expectation is
we want to get this number of market penetration,
whether it's 10% or 50% or 100%." And there's
your number and multiply that number by the
amount of shoes they're going to buy every
year and your AOV and there's your forecast.
And that may be inexact. And you can tweak
those numbers up or down. You can say, "Well,
my AOV was wrong. My market penetration was
wrong. I was wrong on the total population.
I didn't realize that in Japan, no one bought
shoes on the internet." But at any point in time,
you can go back and adjust your forecast.
Whereas if you're doing this bottoms-up forecast,
it's actually in many cases wrong to begin with
because the keyword research volume is wrong.
I worked with some really fascinating
companies where the largest query in
their space was the biggest query. So
I worked with WordPress. So WordPress,
the word WordPress is the biggest query in
the web development space itself. There's
no other word that's as big as WordPress. And
the number that every single keyword research
tool had was completely wrong of what Google
Search Console said for the word WordPress
is, "When you're building these forecasts based
on keyword research tools, that first number that
you build the entire forecast off of if it's
wrong, your forecast is wrong." So when you do
this top-down, it's a TAM forecast essentially.
When you do a top-down, you're closer to the
truth. Now, you probably aren't going to get to
the truth. I've never seen a product plan get
to the truth of what it could do, but it will help
you make a better decision than if you just guess.
Wow, this is a massive insight you're sharing.
So you're saying the keyword research tools are
not actually that accurate in terms of the
opportunity there. And why is that? That
begs the question. Why are they so off? What
are they doing wrong? What are they missing?
They have their own secret sauce for
estimations. So even Google, again,
for past monopolistic reasons, Google's not
allowed to give the real number that they see
on Google Ads for how many people search it.
They have to buy it from another data source,
and then give that out. I forget why. They're all
basically guessing. So they're using whatever sort
of proprietary algorithms to guess, which is
why a lot of them are not aligned because they
have their own algorithms. So you're using,
whether it's Semrush or Ahrefs, one of my
favorite tools is Similarweb, which Similarweb
has a lot of browser plugins, which snoop on the
way people are searching. So whatever it is that
they're... Because Similarweb has browser plugin,
but they're not seeing every single person's
search, so they have to use algorithms to
estimate how much the entire world would be.
And again, I don't know that any of them
could get close to truth was when
I... I worked with big companies
where there were keywords that I could look at
Google Search Console, some of them, the tools
were overestimating by 10 times. Sometimes they're
underestimating by 10 times. So I'm not saying
they didn't get the exact monthly number wrong.
I'm saying they got it wrong by many factors.
Wow, that's crazy. So your advice is... Do
you just ignore those numbers? Or is it just,
"Check it out but don't roll
it. Don't use that number"?
They're indicative. So I would say if you want
to know like, "Do most people spell WordPress
with a space or WordPress without a space?" It's
pretty indicative that people spell it without
a space. But if I were building a forecast and
say, "Oh, I absolutely choose this based on this
defined number." I don't think so. I can use
it for normalization. And I use them only for
normalization to understand how do people search.
And I really like user journeys and they're
helpful for understanding user journeys. But as
an exact science, it's hard to really use that.
That's wild. And so it's mostly useful
for order magnitude and comparing one
keyword to another relative in
this bit. Okay, interesting.
Yes. I mean I have a great example of how
wrong it could be in estimating traffic.
So there was a company I was working
with early in COVID. The public company,
their board member emailed them and said, "You
guys are getting crushed by your competitors in
COVID because look at your competitors. I'm
looking at one of these tools and you're at
the bottom and you're doing everything wrong."
And the CMO says, "What do I tell this board
member?" I said, "The board member is completely
wrong. This is the Google Search Console." And
Google Search Console is not perfect, but again,
it's real data and our Google Search Console shows
that our traffic has quadrupled in COVID, so it
doesn't really matter what this external tool
shows. So they're helpful. Tools are helpful. But
I don't think they are a source of actual truth.
Wow. That's an awesome point in closing.
One thing I had noted here that I want
to make sure you have a chance to
talk about is just you're really
passionate about helping people get into
SEO and also just becoming advisors the
way you are. Share what you think might
be useful to people along these lines.
As my own forecast and prediction, I think
the need for SEO expertise is going to explode
because a lot of what is happening in the search
layouts is going to mean that companies have to
pivot their approaches. So again, companies
focus on rankings, they focus on traffic,
and a lot of that goes away. Suddenly the layout
changes, the traffic changes. It's not necessarily
going to impact their bottom lines if their SEO
wasn't a right fit. So this is going to create a
lot of interest in SEO help, and I'm seeing this.
Over the last year, my own inbound has really
grown because there's a lot of questions as
things shake out. So there will be people
that want to go into SEO consulting, and
I think there's going to be a huge need
for it in growth advising in general.
What I would say is, and I had amazing
mentors along the way, some of your past
guests like Casey Winters and Yuriy Timen,
Ethan Smith, they're all guests with great
episodes, but they advised me and they shared
with me not on how to be a better operator, but
on how to do sales better, how to propose better.
And for anyone out there that wants to become
a growth advisor, I'd say that that's the skill
you really want to perfect. Communication,
sales, proposals, and not really worry about
being the best operator. You should be the best
operator, but that's probably the skills you
already have. And don't make an assumption
that because you're a good operator today,
you'll also be a great growth advisor. Build that
growth advising muscle by staying on your day job.
Don't quit your day job, and moonlighting and
practice selling, closing, working, retaining,
and that's where if you're successful
there, you can be successful on your own.
Amazing. And I know you have some posts that get
into this stuff that we'll link to you, right?
Yep.
Awesome. It's kind of think of yourself as a
product and the journey of working with you.
Yes. You're building a brand.
You're not building a consultancy.
I love that. Eli, this has
been amazing. And with that,
we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
Absolutely.
Here we go. First question,
what are two or three books
that you've recommended most to other people?
As has been apparent, I really like user journeys
and understanding people. So there's a book
called Small Data by I think Martin Lindstrom.
I don't know if I'm pronouncing his name right,
where he talks about understanding people and
understanding how people buy. And he digs into
that entire process. He actually goes and
lives in people's houses and watch how they
use different tools and toys. I always find
that book to be fascinating, and recommend
to people who want to understand users.
Simon Sinek's Start With Why. Again, the same
idea. Really understand what a product
a business is supposed to be doing to
understand users. This is specifically for
growth advisors and not necessarily for PMs,
but Million Dollar Consulting. It's a
book I read, recommended actually by
Ethan Smith many years ago. A fascinating book
on how to build a brand and become a growth
advisor. I ended up working with the author
as a coach for almost a year. Amazing book.
And then the last book that'd be remise
in not recommending is my wife's book,
which is How To Stop Caring What Others Think:
For Real. So it is a book for precisely that.
Understanding your own successes, not worry
about what other people think about you.
Beautiful. Is that in the background,
by the way? And if not, you got to put
it in your background, your wife's book.
My wife made the background. So
yes, it is in the background.
Which one is it? Which color am I...
Just so people recognize it. Oh,
the big one right there. I was wondering why
that one was a little taller than the rest.
Yes, this is the book.
There it is. Wait, move it up a little bit
so we can see the full cover. Oh, beautiful.
Stop Caring What Others Think. Beautiful. I need
that. For Real, I like the ends, but for real.
For Real.
I love it. Okay.
It may or may not be a Google Search query.
Oh, man. I see. I see what
happened there. Genius. Okay,
next question. Do you have a favorite recent
movie or TV show you've really enjoyed?
I was on a plane and I saw this movie Blackberry
and it looked like a documentary, so I don't know
if you've seen it, but it was fascinating. Because
it's one of those movies, it has a cliffhanger,
and you know exactly how it ends. And it is such a
fascinating movie. I didn't know all that history,
but they owned the entire smartphone industry,
and they went to zero. And it really charted that
journey and it makes you think like, "You can
never really rest on your laurels. You have to
create a product people want and understand
your users and keep selling that product."
And not be like, "Well, we're number one,
this will never go away." And great movie.
Funny, it was just recommended
by another guest very recently,
so there's trending up. It's been around for
maybe a year at this point. I watched it.
Yeah, I never would've watched
it if it wasn't on a plane. It
was totally... It seemed like a
plane movie, but it was perfect.
I watched that at home. And
I love just the technical...
Their ability to find clever ways to use
the cell networks, that felt impossible,
and that's what allowed them to all these.
I like the messaging and things like that.
That was really fascinating because I didn't
realize they basically reverse-engineered the
way the cell networks worked to allow what they
allowed. Yeah, awesome movie, and crazy story.
Next question, do you have a favorite recent
product that you've recently discovered that
you really love? It could be an
app. It could be some physical.
It's not a recent product and it's the kind of
thing I fall in love with over and over again.
And it might be cliche, but it's my phone. So
I recently traveled in Southeast Asia. I lived
there for a little bit. So I haven't been back
in eight years. And the things I was able to
do with my phone like traveling, Google Maps,
Waze, and ordering food. I went from multiple
countries and I was able to use the same app to
book rides and make payments. It was so useful.
Eight years ago, and I was there and I had to
buy a SIM card and my phone didn't really work
and I couldn't make payments. It changed my entire
experience. I almost didn't need a computer. So
falling in love with my phone again.
And then another one that... It's not
necessarily recent, but I absolutely love,
which is Grammarly. So I like writing. I
write all my own stuff. I don't write with
AI. Grammarly helps me to be a better writer.
You know what I've realized about Grammarly
recently? I just upgraded to their pro plan.
They're like the best product at upselling
you on their paid plan because they're just
right there in your face all the time. "Hey,
we have stuff. We have so many tips for you.
We have so much we can improve. Just pay a
hundred whatever bucks and we have so much
advice to make all your writing so much
better." It's right there in your face
all the time. They're so good at it. And
they got me. They got me. And I'm happy.
It's not like that much money in the scheme
of things if you're doing this full-time.
I'm so embarrassed when I use
Grammarly on my book and it
just shows up all blue and green. I'm
like, "Oh, man, if only I had known."
I actually have a copywriter on my newsletter
who's incredible. She finds a hundred things
every time to improve that even when I
think it's perfect. And interestingly,
she doesn't do what Grammarly suggests in more
cases than I would expect. So that's kind of
interesting I'm finding. But anyway, yeah,
Grammarly is great. I use it all the time.
Two more questions. Do you have a favorite
life motto that you often use yourself,
share with friends or family,
find useful in work or in life?
I don't know that it fits into a sentence,
but it's something I always encourage people,
which is to really think big and think long.
So I just started working with LinkedIn as a
consulting client, and I've talked to LinkedIn
about working with them for six years. So,
never give up. You meet someone and propose
something and suggest an idea you never know
where it'll go. I had that all through my
career with living in different places,
really not think about the moment of where
things will go, but just it's a relationship
you're building. You don't ever know where
anything will happen. So look at the big picture.
Love that. And kind of following
along those lines, last question.
Curious if something comes up here.
What SEO win are you most proud of?
I don't know if I could say most proud of. But
I really like what I do with Tinder because it
brought the entire journey together. There's
users out there that didn't know that Tinder
would solve a very specific problem, and it's
just there to solve that problem. And it's
not the way Tinder thought of themselves.
They thought of themselves as a dating app,
but it's a loneliness solution
problem that answers a Google Search.
This has been awesome. I think this is going
to help a lot of people think through SEO
and especially as they realize how things are
changing, they're going to have this resource now
to be like, "I see. This is what I should change.
This is what I should be doing." And I just love,
especially the pattern and the thread of, "It's
not actually that complicated. You can do it even
if you've never really done it before." So I
really appreciate you being here and sharing
all this wisdom with us. Two final questions.
Where can folks find you if they want to reach
out to work with you? Also, check out your book.
And finally, how can listeners be useful to you?
You can find me on LinkedIn. So search Eli
Schwartz, and you should definitely look
for my book. So the book is Product-Led SEO.
Actually, one piece on just your own personal
brand and your own personal rankings. It doesn't
matter where you rank if you search your own name.
So if LinkedIn shows up first for your name,
that's great because they're finding you. And
a lot of times, brands and people will be
very focused on where they're positioned,
but it's about the journey. If they find you, they
find you. It doesn't matter if it's number one.
And that also underscores that it's not all
about links. I believe for my own name and
probably for you too, I outranked LinkedIn.
And my book, so if you search Product-Led SEO,
my own personal website, which does
not have the best domain authority,
it outranks Amazon. So that should right
away disprove that it's all about links.
That's all about SEO metrics. It's really
all about the right fit. So be the right fit,
and you'll show up where you're supposed to.
And then users can be most helpful for me by
subscribing to my newsletter and giving me
ideas and feedback on what to write. I really
enjoy writing, and I really enjoy hearing from
people. So my newsletter is Productledseo.com.
It's so consistent across all your
things. I love it. Productledseo. Eli,
thank you so much for being here.
Thanks for having me.
Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much for
listening. If you found this valuable, you can
subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.