Boz, the CTO of Meta, said something
about you. "Working with Ami, she could
have the most profound disagreement
in the world and she would respond,
fascinating, you have to tell
me more why you think that."
I really enjoy being right and then
it turns out in the working world,
that did not serve me so great. I think
the hard part is sublimating your ego a
little bit and saying it's more important
to get to the outcome than to be right.
I love this very tactical piece of advice
when you're trying to come up with a metaphor
or analogy, think about what you want your
users to feel when you're using the product.
If we all agree that the feeling of
something should be, I'm sitting in
Dolores Park with my friends on a sunny Saturday,
then people will just naturally build
something that feels more consistent.
There's also this metaphor about the hill climb.
For me, the hill climb is all about the difference
between a local optimum and a global optimum.
You're standing on top of the hill, you're
looking down, you can see rolling hills,
the sheep, the grass, whatever, but then, way
off in the distance you can see a mountain. And
the thing that gets me through the valley
is remembering what the summit feels like.
Today, my guest is Ami Vora. Ami is Chief Product
Officer at Faire, which connects independent
retailers and brands around the world, and I
believe is the most successful and biggest B2B
marketplace startup out there. Prior to Faire, Ami
was employee 150 at Facebook, where she launched
the first Facebook developer platform and was
later head of product for the $55 billion global
Facebook ads business. She also oversaw the
introduction of ads on the Instagram platform
and most recently, she led product and design for
the largest messaging app in the world, WhatsApp.
In our conversation we cover a lot of ground,
including building your strategy skills,
how to disagree with people skillfully,
being a successful woman in tech,
using metaphors and imagery to rally your team and
get your point across, setting up effective goals,
plus a bunch of jokes in the lightning round that
you don't want to miss. This was a really special
and authentic conversation that I'm very excited
to bring to you. With that, I bring you, Ami Vora.
Ami, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Oh, thank you. I'm so happy to be here.
So, when I asked you about your goal for our
conversation today, you said the most amazing
thing, which I love. You said that your goal is
to be as authentic as possible and to show that
people can be pretty messy and imperfect at
times, yet still be very successful. I love
that so much. Let's definitely try to do this.
Is there anything else you want to add on that?
Yeah, I mean, maybe I'll just say a couple more
words on that. Actually, I feel like when I was
coming up, when I looked at people who were
successful, they seemed to have everything
figured out, especially the women. They were all
super women, where they respond to every email
in 10 seconds, they didn't seem to sleep, they
always wore high heels. They were just perfect
and I was just like, oh, I guess I'm never going
to be successful. That is not me. I love to sleep,
I waste time doing absurd things all the time.
And I'll tell you how glamorous my lifestyle is,
I'm currently working out of my bathroom. I'm
talking to you from my bathroom, which is where
I work from because I love my house, it's a
great house, wasn't meant for work from home,
three kids, two parents remote work, and it was
just the place with the most closing doors between
me and my children when the pandemic started.
And so it just took me a while to realize that
actually, it's all fine. No one's got it fully
figured out, you never know how someone else is
living. Most of us are winging it and learning
as we're going and learning through trial and
error and it's all normal. It's all fine and
I can do it and you can do it, and everyone.
I so love hearing this. This is something people
often want to hear more of on this podcast,
because there's all these stories
of here's all these successes,
here's all these things I did and everything,
it just always seems to work out. And we try to,
we have this failure corner on the podcast
where people share story failure. So I love
just setting that frame for this conversation
of just super being real and being clear that
there's a lot of things that go wrong behind
the scenes that people often don't hear about.
I for a long time felt like I was held back
because I don't have a plan, but I realized
that probably the most important thing is to just
acknowledge that that is true for me. That I'm not
going to be a person with a plan, and actually the
thing that has consistently served me is to do the
thing that feels right, go to the place that feels
like home, work with the people who feel like my
friends. Just work where when I put on the code of
the job, I feel like, oh, this is a place where I
could really be lucky, I could be creative, I'm
in the right spot, as opposed to feeling like,
oh, there is an end state that I know of and I'm
just going to have to work my way to that end
state. Whenever I get in that zone of, there's
only one outcome and I just have to get there,
I'm not my best. I'm not bringing the creativity
and the luck and the excitement in the same way.
Let me tell you about a product called
Sidebar. The best way to level up your career
is to surround yourself with extraordinary
peers. This gives you more than a leg up,
it gives you a leap forward. This worked really
well for me in my career and this is the Sidebar
ethos. When you have a trusted group of peers, you
can discuss challenges you're having, get career
advice and just gut check how you're thinking
about your work, your career, and your life.
This was a big trajectory changer for me, but
it's hard to build this trusted group of peers.
Sidebar is a private highly vetted leadership
program where senior leaders are matched with
peer groups to lean on for unbiased
opinions, diverse perspectives and raw
feedback. Guided by world-class programming and
facilitation, Sidebar enables you to get focused,
tactical feedback in every step of your career
journey. If you're a listener of this podcast,
you're already committed to growth. Sidebar
is the missing piece to catalyze your career.
93% of members say Sidebar helped them achieve
a significant positive change in their career.
Why spend a decade finding your people when
you can meet them at Sidebar today? Join
thousands of top senior leaders who have taken
the first step to career growth, from companies
like Microsoft, Amazon, and Meta by visiting
sidebar.com/lenny. That's sidebar.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Anvil.
Their document SDK helps product teams
build and launch software for documents, fast.
Companies like Carta and Vouch Insurance use
Anvil to accelerate the development of their
document workflows. Getting to market fast
is a top priority for product teams, and the
last thing that you or your developers want
is to build document workflows from scratch.
It's time consuming, expensive and distracts
from core work. You could stitch together
multiple tools and manage those integrations
or you can use an all-in-one document SDK.
Most product managers will tell you, paperwork
sucks. Anvil's document SDK helps teams get to
market fast, incorporate your brand's style and
give you back time to focus on your company's core
differentiated features. For your users, paperwork
often starts with an AI powered web form styled
and embedded in your application. From there,
you can route data to your backend systems and to
the correct fields in your PDFs via API. Complete
the process with a white labeled e-signature.
The best part about Anvil is the level of
customization their SDK provides. Non-technical
folks love Anvil's drag and drop builder and
developers love their flexible APIs and
easy to understand documentation. Build
documents software fast with Anvil, that's
useanvil.com/lenny, to learn more or start a
free trial. That's useanvil.com/lenny.
Let's actually spend some more time here.
I wasn't planning to go here yet, but this is
really great and important advice. I've just,
basically you're saying that a lot of your success
has come from following people that are awesome.
Can you just talk more about that, just what it
is you've followed and seen that has helped you
land in places that have worked out so well,
because clearly you've done incredibly well.
I mean, I think a lot of us are just like, you
have a spreadsheet in your head of the axes and
certainly when you're choosing between jobs, for
me it feels like, oh man, the rest of my career
hangs in the balance of making the exact right
decision and getting the exact right job. And you
work through all of this spreadsheet mass of, if
I took this job, here's what it would do for me,
here's where I'd be in five years, etc. And I have
that engine in my head also, but what I try to do
is work through the spreadsheets and then tear it
up because none of that stuff is actually going
to determine how good I am at the job. The thing
that'll determine... In my track record, the thing
that has determined it is when I walk through
the doors, do I feel like I'm lucky to be there?
So for me, it's actually a lot more emotional.
I try to just put on the coat of the job. When
I wake up in the morning, I'm like, what
would it be like if I were doing this job?
What would I think about on my commute? Who
would I have lunch with? Do I like them? What
problems am I going to solve today? And that
gives me an emotional response, which is just
much more telling than the spreadsheets of,
here's where I'm going to be in five years.
And for me, the thing that has led me to the
places where I do my best work is a feeling of
being at home, which is all about trust and
trust with the people around me. Can I walk
through and feel like these people are going to
have my back, they're going to let me take risks,
I'm going to enjoy spending time with them?
And that's where I feel like I've always just
been able to try more things and do better
because a big, trust is a big unlock for me.
I love this metaphor of putting on the coat
of the job, of just feeling out what it would
be to work there. I imagine that was something
that you did before you joined Faire, which I
want to talk about, but let me transition a bit to
talking about Meta and specifically, Boz. The CTO
of Meta was on this podcast a few months ago and
he said something about you that I want to read.
Oh, kind.
Okay, so you've heard what he said about you?
[inaudible 00:10:21].
Okay, cool. So let me read this and then I want
to learn from you how to do this. So here's what
he said. "Working with Ami, it was like watching
an alien because she could have the most profound
disagreement in the world with somebody and they
would say something that she thought was not just
wrong, but crazy wrong, and she would respond,
'Fascinating, you have to tell me more why you
think that.' And she meant it from the core of
her being. She saw this schism and rather than
reacting as if it was a threat, she reacted
with the most genuine and profound curiosity.
I just watched it absolutely tear down walls
between points of view. Embracing curiosity
in those moments of challenges completely
changed my life and I owe that to Ami Vora."
Oh man, I love Boz, what a great guy,
and so kind of him to say that. I mean,
I will say that this did not come naturally
to me. I really enjoy being right,
I love to be right. I think most of us love being
right, and at least in my childhood, part of my
identity was built on being the person who was
right and being the person who knew everything.
And then it turns out that in the working
world, that did not serve me so great,
it wasn't great to walk into things and be
like, all y'all are wrong, I am the only answer,
everyone please to listen to me and stop talking.
And what really happened was that someone pointed
out to me that not only... One of my old managers
pointed out to me that not only was I spending
a lot of energy trying to think through every
possible thing by myself so I could be totally
right, I was often not really coming to the
right answer. Other people have a bunch of
information that I do not have. And so I'm just
ignoring that, I was letting my ego overtake my
desire to get to the best outcome, which is just,
that's a silly trade off and an unnecessary one.
The thing that changed there is me just
saying it's more important for us to get
to the outcome and I very selfishly just like
to learn more things. And so by deciding that
I already knew everything, I was cutting myself
off from learning the things that other people
were really good at and it's so easy to
just open the door instead and say like,
hey, you seem to know something that I don't
know yet. Why not tell me about it? I'm going
to get better. We'll probably come to the right
outcome. Maybe you'll have a better time. Why not?
And so it was a little bit just accidental
evolution in that direction. But it's made
work and life so much more interesting to just be
like, hey, what does this person know that I don't
know yet? It means that every meeting you walk
into, you're probably not going to get bored and
I get bored a lot, but if you assume that every
person there knows something that you don't know,
then it's not just wait to get to the
right answer, it's like, discover the
thing that they know that you don't know and
it becomes just a little bit of uncovering.
For people that want to learn to be good at this
the way you are, a couple things that I take away
from the historian and the way you're talking
about this is, one is there's an enthusiasm of,
I disagree with you, but I want you to know I
really care about what you think. So there's
an energy of like, please tell me what I'm
missing. There's also this assumption that
a lot of disagreement is rooted in, we just
have different information, so tell me what
I'm missing. Can you talk a bit about just how to,
what you've learned about actually do this well?
Yeah, I mean, I think the hard part is just
sublimating your ego a little bit and saying
it's more important to get to the outcome than
to be right. And I think all of growth is a
battle with yourself, but this is one of the
hardest ones because we all want to be right,
we all want to protect ourselves and it
served us, many of us for so long to be
right. I just try to think about the feedback
loop of, I think all of life is feedback loops,
so I just started to think about the feedback
loop I'm creating of like, I was curious about
something. I learned something new, we got for
a better outcome. Probably the other person
felt better as well as I felt better. It's all
positive feedback and you do that a couple of
times and the positive feedback far outweighs the
desire to be right because now we're more right,
we're more right together. And so just
building that as a practice of just
noticing how much better things can get when
you can be open to them, has been really fun.
What do you think of this phrase that he
used that he remembers? Is that a phrase
that you find useful? Just fascinating, you
have to tell me more why you think that.
I do think that is a word that I say a lot.
I do say that a lot, because it's true,
it's fascinating that someone to look at the
same movie that I was looking at and come away
with a totally different understanding of
the plot. I could sit in the same meeting
as other people and they would leave with
just a different retelling of what happened,
and that to me is fascinating. Isn't that
surprising, that we can all see the same,
what we think are the same facts and walk away
with a totally different narrative? And when you
really go deep into that and you just understand
how people see the world, and that is helpful. I'm
curious about things, I like to know more things,
and so that just helps me know more things.
I feel like the hardest part of this for people is
you hear someone say something, say, okay, so our
mutual friend, Dan Hockenmaier, he's in a meeting
and he just says something that you are just like,
no, because he's got influence. He's a big
deal at Faire. Most people have this visceral
reaction of like, oh no, I really don't think
that's a good idea. Is there something you've
learned about controlling that bodily reaction of
like, oh, and then just being positive about it?
Yeah, I do think it is just that feedback loop.
It's not like I don't have the visceral reaction,
it's just that instead of interpreting it as this
is a visceral reaction, I got to shut something
down, it's like, this is a visceral reaction and
it's a chance to learn more. Just reinterpreting
some of the feelings in ways that are more
about opening than about closing stuff down.
Got it, so it's kind of like
a thinking you do of like,
okay, hey, let me frame this and
think about this [inaudible 00:16:28].
For me the most important thing is just taking
a pause. I think when you just take a pause,
your body calms down, your mind gets a chance
to breathe a little bit, and then your response
is going to be better, but you got to take the
pause because the immediate visceral reaction,
is not always... It's going to be primal,
it's going to be protective. It's just
when you take a pause you're like,
this is all fine, let's just learn.
I feel like more people are going to
start using this phrase, fascinating.
Fascinating.
When they hear something [inaudible 00:16:58].
It's kind of my tagline. There
were a few years where I had
to be careful about not saying it because
whenever I said it, people would be like,
she disagrees. So I've had to use a
thesaurus and expand my words I use.
No, that's such a good word. Maybe we'll
make that the title of this episode.
Totally.
What a great title that would be. So we've
been talking a bit about the bodily reaction
to stuff and our lizard brain almost, reacting to
things. It reminds me of this metaphor that you
called the dinosaur brain and how it applies
to product reviews. Talk about what that is.
Okay, so a lot of people on my team, they're
coming in to do product reviews and they're
worried about it. They're stressed out,
they don't exactly know what to show,
and the normal temptation is just to show as much
information as possible because that way you come
in and you think, hey, the people in this room
are super smart. I'll show them the information,
they will come to the right conclusions.
They'll probably make a better decision
than I'm going to make. So my job is to
catalog the information and present it.
And one of the first things that
I talk to people about is, okay,
for the purposes of this conversation, I'm going
to put myself in the capitally executive bucket
because that makes what I'm about to say less
offensive. Assume that executives have a little
tiny dinosaur brain. We all have a little
brontosaurus brain and we can really only
hold three facts at the same time. We will
never be able to go deep in the way that
you are able to do on everything that crosses
our desk. And so the best service you can do is
actually do the work of making a recommendation.
That's the way we're going to be complimentary.
The breadth that I normally have to look across
means that I'm going to be better at things like
pattern matching or giving you more context or
telling you stuff that's happening in the company
or the industry. But what I'm not going to be
better at is looking at all the information that
you looked at and coming up with a meaningful
outcome. That's what you're going to do and
my little dinosaur brain is going to be like,
okay, that sounds like a very reasonable pattern,
I've seen other patterns that look like this.
Okay, that sounds like an outcome, however,
it conflicts with this outcome over here. I
can tell you about that. Does that make sense?
Yeah, and I love that you put
yourself in that bucket. You
have a dinosaur brain also, it's not other people.
It's a pretty bad, bad look, but it's really true.
As you get more breadth, you are less and less
able to go deep on everything that deserves going
deep and you just end up doing a different service
than the people on your team, and recognizing
that as complimentary has been really helpful.
You have this phrase, my manager owns context,
I own the recommendation.
Kind of along the same lines?
Exactly, very similar. And I think the
thing that was helpful for me there is
that really unlocked what I was looking
for from my managers because otherwise
I wanted them to be exactly like me.
If I assume that I need to bring them
information and then they would come to
the same conclusion that I would come to,
that's very narrow. They have to be able to look
at the exact same information and process it in
the same way and come out with the same idea.
Whereas if what they're doing is complimentary
to me, then I can learn from everyone. They're
going to just have a different view, they're going
to have new information that I don't have, and it
gives me a lot more space to take accountability.
Is there any other advice that you could share
along these lines of just product reviews? So,
the big takeaway here is just keep
it simple and have a recommendation.
Keep it simple, have a recommendation. I
also think that, I think we misuse product
reviews sometimes as ways to get decisions and
actually, they should be ways to calibrate on
principles. So what you don't want is to come
to a product review for every single that you
want to make. Instead, what you want is to
come to a product review with one decision,
but the goal of that decision is to
walk out with principles about how to
make these decisions in the future so that
you don't have to come to product review,
but you still have this consistent and
coherent product that you're building.
And so I think when you flip the frame of
reviews to being less about, okay, I'm going
to bring this information to an exec, my manager,
whoever, and they're going to decide every piece,
you're not actually building that much more
capacity in the system. You're getting fast
decision making, but you're not changing who
can make really good decisions. And I think
you always want to change the org to constantly
make better decisions, and a way to do that is
when you bring these sorts of questions, what you
talk about is, why did you make this decision?
What are the trade-offs you have in mind? Who
are you optimizing for? What timeline are you
thinking about? What's the risk level we're
willing to tolerate? And then you don't have
to come back. You have enough information that
you can take those principles and run with them.
Is there a framework or a process you use
for product reviews that might be helpful
for people to hear? Just like a agenda or
a way of thinking about just how to set
up a product review for success? Because
a lot of people are trying to set these
up at their companies and they're like, I
don't know if we're doing this optimally.
Yeah, I think everyone's got... I think there's
so many different takes on frameworks. I don't
have a single system. I mean, actually I
think Boz has written about a bunch of this,
and I probably most agree with him. Where there's
different kinds of product reviews, it's like,
what are you trying to solve? What's the timeline
on which you're thinking about for these? Is it
a philosophy? Is it a strategic shift? Is it a
day-to-day product decision? And then keeping
it extremely short and pointed and then making
sure you walk away with principles, not answers.
I think there's a lot of nuance and
importance there of what you just said,
which is start with the problem you're solving.
What are we trying to do here? And the timeline,
I think that's also really useful
and important for people to hear.
I think the temptation is always
to err toward writing more,
and what I always really recommend people do
is write whatever you need to write and then
cut out almost all of it. What you really
want to bring to any forum, whether it's
a product review or a written inform or anything
else, is the minimal amount of information that
you need to make a clean recommendation because
then you are forced to be opinionated. Otherwise,
the opinion can get lost in all of this
information. You can hide behind, well,
all of these analyses seem to suggest, and instead
you should probably just say, looked at all the
data, there's three analyses that suggest this.
There's one that suggests that, we think that one
is inaccurate or worth taking the risk on. Let's
go. Any objections? Let me know. Any new context?
Let me know. That really forces you to deeply
understand and take an opinion on the material.
Final question, who do you like to invite to these
product reviews and your thoughts, rules, policy?
Yeah, I mean I do think that usually fewer
people is better. It leads to a sense of being
informal and that is really useful because
it lowers the bar on how complete or strong
these conversations are and I'd rather have a
less formal conversation faster than a formal
conversation and lose three weeks in the process
when we could have been building. I think it needs
to be cross-functional. I think one of the things
you want is cross-functional accountability. So
we want it cross-functional at the leadership
level and cross-functional at the team presenting
level. And I think those are normally the groups.
I think the thing that gets hard is you often cut
out the middle, where if it's a working team
presenting to the senior leaders on something
important, it's really hard because it means
people's managers are not in the room and can't
help the conversation or other things. And so
in order to do that, you have to really have
a bunch of implicit trust inside the team
that everyone will get the context later,
that everyone's going to be kind to everyone
else and you don't need a ton of air cover,
and that the managers trust their team
to present in the best possible way.
That is always a stressful
place for a manager to be,
where their success is riding in that
meeting and they're not there and they-
It's so stressful, it's so stressful. I think
anything you do to make it less stressful is
useful. But then there've also been times in my
career where I would keep the room itself small,
but because we were all trying to
calibrate on specific principles,
I would record or broadcast the reading to
anyone who wanted to see it, just so they
could all see the principles by which we were
decision-making and get calibrated on that.
So through your career you've transitioned
from being the person pitching the products
and being reviewed to the person
reviewing and being on the other
side. Is there anything being on this side
of it that you think is helpful for people
earlier in their career to know about
that experience, from your angle now?
I mean, I think for what it's worth, I
think I still do a fair amount of product
pitching in the past few years because
there's always someone else to convince.
That's true.
Especially if you want to do something
dramatically different. Really,
I think the biggest service for people who are
starting out a little earlier is that point
around bringing the recommendation, really
having the opinion and standing behind it
with conviction and doing what they need to
do to build that conviction for themselves.
Awesome. You've done this a number of
times already in this conversation,
and so I want to spend a little time
here, which is using metaphors and imagery
to make your point and get people to understand
what you're trying to say. So you have this code
of putting on the coat of the job and this
dinosaur brain, and so someone told me that
this is just a skill you have where you use
metaphor and imagery to rally a team, get
your point across, get people to understand what
you're trying to say. There's also this metaphor,
someone told me I need to ask you about the
hill climb metaphor. Does that ring a bell?
Yeah.
Okay, what is that all about?
For me, the hill climb is all about the
difference between the local optimum and
a global optimum. That sounds very abstract, but I
think a lot of the time when we're doing our job,
when we're doing life stuff, whatever you're
doing, you try to just get better and better and
you optimize your current system and then you feel
really good about it, and that is great. You're
standing on top of the hill, you're looking down,
you can see the, I don't know, rolling hills,
the sheep, the grass, whatever. But then way
off from the distance you can see a mountain,
one that's even higher than you can't even
see the top of it, and you have to decide,
are you going to take the risk of climbing
down your hill, crossing an unknown chasm,
and then climbing back up, just to get to the
same level you started at with more climbing to
do to get to that summit? And that is really hard.
I'm thinking of things like, maybe the first time
I saw this was like a lot of companies were really
good at desktop and you could see the mobile
mountain way out over there, but to get there
you had to really make a lot of trade-offs in
your core desktop business that you were not
totally sure were going to pay off when you
made it to the mobile mountain, and you had
to do a ton of work. You had to fundamentally
rewire a lot of what you're doing without a
guarantee that you're going to get there. I mean,
you can see it in life when you think about
new jobs or new moves or new relationships,
anything that you think about. You are
giving up something that is working
pretty well without knowing whether you're
going to make it to the top of that next
mountain. And that's been really helpful to me
just to place where I am on different things,
where you get the inkling that there is a
much better way to do this, there really is.
Is it going to be worth going down into the
valley, climbing up, keeping climbing? Is
that going to be worth it? Most of the time the
answer is yes, but it's helpful for me to know,
boy, this feels like a slog. It is supposed
to? Because I'm still in the valley and the
thing that gets me through the valley is
remembering what the summit feels like.
When you're on top of it and you're like, this
is great, it was absolutely worth it. My life
is better in these ways, we're able to solve
these problems in these ways. It was worth it.
I love that. It feels like a big value
of the metaphor, which I love is that to
set expectations, it's going to be really
hard for a little bit or we will slow down
what we're trying to do now, but the idea is
there's a bigger hill and a bigger mountain.
It's a bigger hill and it's worth it.
On this kind of broader idea
of metaphors and imagery,
is there something there that
you've learned of just like,
this works really well, I'm going to invest in
becoming better at this, or is this something
that's come natural to you? Anything you
can share about that skill and approach?
I think this one came from, I worked for a
manager, his name was Eric Antino, and he was
just a master of the metaphor and analogies.
And so whenever I would bring him something,
he would be like, how is this
product going to make you feel,
and when is the last time that you
felt this way? And you can say, oh,
I felt this way when I was hanging with my
friends in Dolores Park and he'd be like,
cool, tell me what it feels like, why that's the
analogy, what ramifications come out of that?
And one thing I like to do is try to build
an emulator for different people in my head,
because I've just had the good fortune of working
with an amazing number of very different leaders,
and so he's one of the people I tried to
build an emulator for where I'd be like, okay,
I see this thing. I don't know how to solve this
problem. How would Eric describe this? I've tried
to build one for Boz, which is all about principle
of decision making and principle of trade-offs.
There's a few other people where I'm like, I
don't know how to solve this problem. Can I load
this other person into my head and how would they
approach it? And that gives me a fresh lens on it.
And I really like metaphors and analogies because
I think especially as you scale a team, narrative
becomes increasingly important. Narrative can
carry so much weight and water where otherwise
it's similar to the product review point, where
either you can tell everybody exactly what to do
at every point or you can create a story that we
all agree on. And when we all agree on that story,
people just know better what to do. If we all
agree that the feeling of something should be,
I'm sitting in Dolores Park with my friends on
a sunny Saturday. You know what the iconography,
the designers know what iconography should
look like. You know what the communication
and join pattern should look like. You're not
going to build something cold and corporate,
you're not going to build something strobe light,
you're not going to build something flashy,
but you don't have to go and make all those
individual decisions. You can buy into the
same story and then people will just naturally
build something that feels more consistent.
This is such a powerful and important
skill. Is there an example that comes
to mind where you did this really well,
say at WhatsApp or Facebook of the story that
carried a lot of water for you and the team?
Yeah, I mean I think the product metaphor
we arrived at for WhatsApp was face-to-face
communication. Our goal there was to make it
so that every person in the world could feel
connected to the people they cared most about,
even when they were separate, even they're
distant geographically for whatever reason, we
were always going to be apart from the people you
cared about. And we really had to build something
that would work for literally everyone in the
world. People who are carrying these high-end
devices in western markets who are very tech
comfortable and savvy, and people in the low end
markets who were carrying these low end devices,
they weren't that familiar with technology,
it was maybe their first time online. We had
to build something that worked for everyone.
And the most universal form of communication is
face-to-face. When you talk to someone
face-to-face, you're not thinking,
how do I present? What tool do I have to learn?
You just open your mouth and words come out, and
that's the feeling that we wanted to create. And
that involved a lot of the app stepping back from
communication, creating spaces that felt really
intimate so people wouldn't have to think to
themselves, what kind of space am I in? They could
immediately map where they were in the app to the,
okay, I'm sitting around in my kitchen table and
people are joining and leaving calls just like
they're walking in and out of my living room, but
it is a family space and the family is there. Or,
in one-on-one disappearing messages, you're like,
cool, this is my close friend. We don't need to
keep track of everything that we're saying. We're
here for a little bit of banter, a little bit of
relationship, a little bit of quick, what's your
wifi password and stuff, and whatever's really
important, that's what we'll hold onto and
the rest is just day-to-day, normal intimacy.
That is super interesting. WhatsApp, one
of the main differentiators and benefits
is it's super fast. And I see completely how
it connects this idea of you're just like,
ideas, we want you to feel
like you're talking to someone.
And it's all really a small thing. It's
like a typing indicator is like someone
who's about to take a breath, give them a
second to talk, the two check marks lighting
up or someone's face lighting up when they
hear you, it's just a recognition of being
heard. These are all super small things, but I
think they add up to a feeling of being there.
That is super interesting. So I love this very
tactical piece of advice that you just shared
of just when you're trying to come up with a
metaphor or analogy, think about what you want
your users to feel when you're using the product
and when else have they felt that same feeling?
So interesting. And then this other point you made
of making this emulator of a person in your head.
I mean, it sounds a little
wild now that I think about it.
No.
That's robotic.
It makes total sense.
I get very bored a lot. It's another way to make
sure meetings are really interesting where you're
like, okay, let me see what that person is going
to say next. Let me put myself in their shoes.
Let me think about what they're reacting to and
why they're going to think that and how they're
going to see the world. And again, it just
gives me more toolkits because it means when
I'm stumped on something, I can be like, what
would Rob Goldman say? He'd say, look at the
dashboard. Have I looked at the dashboard? No.
Okay, let me go look at the dashboard. You can
load up these different skillsets that people
have been so generous with sharing with me.
What would be the Ami emulator? What
are people thinking when they loaded it?
Fascinating.
Fascinating?
Fascinating, probably the number one, no joke.
Is there an emulator you most often
come back to that you find most
useful in just in your day-to-day?
Who's the person that like, oh yeah-
I think those are the three. I think it
is like Antino's story. Story, metaphor,
analogy creation. I think it's like Boz's, if we
played this out, what principles are we using?
And if we kept on using those principles,
what would happen? And it is Rob Goldman,
who's an amazing metrics growth product leader
being like, look at the dashboard. I mean,
look at the dashboard, which is a
great central rooting part of my life.
This was so fascinating, fascinating.
It revs up.
I love this topic of just metaphors and
stories and visions and things like that.
It's something that a lot of people are
wanting to get better at. Is there another
example, per chance, that you could share of maybe
using a metaphor to rally team, get things done?
I mean, I think taking a sub part of WhatsApp
or when we talk about video calling. I really,
one the metaphors was sitting around in your
family room when you think about how to make
calls work, where when you're sitting in
a family room, you're not scheduling it,
you're not, I don't know, having this cold
corporate feeling, the way you do with
a conference where there's heavyweight
interactions, and instead there's just,
you can join and leave. It feels lightweight,
it feels like the space exists even when you're
not there. And so just creating things
like joinable calls, like that feeling
of people popping in and just paying attention
to whoever's there and letting them leave, but
the call can flow on without a super heavyweight
action that everyone needs to take. I think that
was another one where we were just able to agree
on the feeling and then you know what to build.
I was just using WhatsApp to do video call with
my mom. They were traveling to Italy and so-
That's great, that's exactly [inaudible 00:37:33].
I experienced it, it felt great.
Let me go in a slightly different
direction. One of my favorite posts of yours
is called execution beats strategy every time,
and I think another way you phrase it is,
execution eats strategy for breakfast. I
think you put that somewhere. I'd love to
hear about this because I completely agree.
I think a lot of people obsess with strategy and
vision and got to get this right and forget that
most of the work is execution. So yeah, I'd
love to hear just your take and insight here.
Yeah, I don't know if I coined execution
eats strategy for breakfast, I think a lot
of things eat other things for breakfast, but I'm
a believer. I do think execution eats strategy for
breakfast and that's something we used to say
a lot at Meta. It was just the most important
part and I was well-trained in that. That was one
of the key lessons that I learned there, and it's
because when you have... Look, strategy is super
fun. You get to think about all this pie in the
sky stuff. You get to think about if the world
operated in rational patterns and you could
predict the future, what is going to be the second
and third order effect? You get to use your brain
in a really fun, philosophical way, but customers
don't care. Customers don't care about your fancy
strategies and your five-year plan. They care
about the product that's in their hands. And
so anything that distracts you from thinking about
the product in your hands I think, or maybe worse,
takes you away from solving customer's
problems today, I think is a distraction.
And I think one of the things that you learn
is if you have great strategy, perfect strategy
but poor execution, you don't win because your
strategy never makes it to the market. And what's
even worse is that you have learned nothing.
You don't know whether it was your strategy
that was wrong or whether it was your execution
that was wrong, all you know is you didn't win.
Whereas when you have a pretty good strategy,
a good enough strategy, you're in the right
direction and you have perfect execution, you
still don't win immediately, but you know your
execution was great. So then you learn, what do
you need to do to improve your strategy? You've
got the execution machine, you go back, you update
your strategy, you relaunch, and you keep on doing
it until your strategy is perfect and then you do
win. And that's the lesson I repeatedly learned.
Is this advice a reaction to what you said,
where people, PMs let's say, are just like,
I want to work on strategy, we got to spend
all this time, get the strategy nailed,
and it's just like, okay, we also need to
execute and that's maybe even more important.
Yeah, I do think it's very glamorous
to work on strategy. It's so fun. It's
so fun to have the word strategy in your
[inaudible 00:40:11]. I don't know, we've
built a mythology around strategy being the most
important thing. And execution is not glamorous,
it is not like white-boarding by yourself and
pointing to things and coming out with the grand
vision. It is the nuts and bolts and sometimes
boring, sometimes grind it out work of like,
you got to bring the donuts, you
got to look at the dashboards,
you got to rewrite the spec. You got to just do
a bunch of the grinding, but that is what leads
to the customer's outcomes. That is what the
customer is eventually going to feel. They're
never going to see the whiteboard, they're going
to see that someone took the time to fix this bug.
This episode is brought to you by User Testing,
transform how you build products and experiences
with User Testing. Get fast feedback throughout
the development process so that you can build
the right thing the first time, make better
decisions that lead to better business outcomes.
Companies are being asked to do more with
less. They need to move quickly to build
experiences that meet changing customer
expectations and do so faster than ever,
all while minimizing risk and costly rework.
With User Testing, you have a trusted partner
in experience research. They empower user
research, product and design teams to make
higher confidence decisions with human insights.
Learn more today at usertesting.com/lenny.
Is this advice you give to your PMs on your
teams? I guess, how do you think about this
when they're trying to move up the ranks,
become better product managers? Is this just
a common thing that you often share, like
yeah, strategy is going to be amazing,
important. You got to get good at it,
but also make sure this is going great.
Yeah, I think about it a little bit in terms of
proportion of time you should expect to spend.
So I mean, there's no point next being on that
strategy, you can't have a bad strategy. So you
should spend some time, maybe it's like 20% of
your time, but the bulk of your time should be
confirming that strategy actually makes sense for
the customers. Getting it out there, building the
machine to constantly make it better, as opposed
to a perfect strategy. You go away, you build it
for a year, you ship it, the market has changed.
Customers have changed, their needs have changed,
competition, just the whole landscape has changed
and you probably could have solved those problems
more easily had you headed in the right direction,
but done it with more ongoing customer feedback.
In terms of this proportion, I imagine
what you see is as you get more senior,
more of your time spent on strategy,
less time on execution, right?
I don't 100% know that that's true.
I think again, even at high levels,
maybe the strategic directions become more
important to get mostly right, but I think
still most of your time is making sure they can
make it to market. I think you should still be
spending your time understanding what's slowing
people down and unblocking it. Understanding,
how is the market changing? Understanding
what the broad customer feedback is,
just constantly improving the system that you
are building. I think that's, I mean, how much
time can you spend thinking about the future,
as opposed to actually trying to create it.
That is really interesting advice because
I think most people imagine as you get more
senior, I'm going to have more time
thinking about vision and strategy,
not have to be in the weeds building things.
And I love this point you're making of even
as a senior exec, you're still, it's executing
in a different way, but it's still execution.
A different way, yeah. You're focusing on the
execution of the system a little bit more,
but you got to stay connected, I think, to the
customer and to what you're bringing to them.
I love that. Obviously, strategy is also
very important. You have this great quote
that I'm going to read here. "For strategy to be
useful, it actually has to change our behavior
as a team to create better customer
outcomes." Can you talk about that?
Yeah. I mean, I think again, some of the joy
of strategy is the philosophy and excitement
of thinking about all the long-term stuff that
will happen, but I try to always come back to,
what's going to change for the customer? If we
have all of these conversations and we come out
with this shiny five-year plan, but then we
change nothing about the products that we're
building or how we are building, what was the
point of that exercise? It made us feel good,
and there's something to making us feel
good. That is good, it's important for
teams to feel good and connected and this
is a good exercise for that, but it's so
much more powerful when it's an exercise that
translates into us doing something differently,
whether that's prioritizing different products,
whether that's changing our portfolio allocation,
like moving people to the things we think
are most important now versus things that
are going to be less important right now.
What's the change, or coming out with a
strategy that'll align people because we
have the story, we have the narrative, we
have the sequence. What's going to change for our
customers as a result of this strategy exercise?
Many people want to get better at strategy.
Often their performance feedback is become more
strategic, think better about strategy. What has
helped you become a better strategic thinker? Is
it just doing it? Is it a person that influenced
you heavily? Is it a book? What has helped you
and what do you often recommend to
people to get better at this skill?
I think I got that same feedback quite a lot,
actually, of needing to think bigger and be more
visionary, etc. And I still do, frankly, actually,
there's moments where I retrench way too far into
execution and worry a little less about long-term
strategy. So it's definitely my bias still.
The biggest thing that held me back from talking
about strategy was I didn't feel confident that I
knew enough to declare a strategy. It was
actually almost like a self-confidence,
imposter syndrome thing, where there were people
who could just say, I know how the world is going
to develop in the next five years, and let
me tell you, here's where we're going to be,
this is the dot on the map. And I was always
like, how could anything could happen? Who
would I be to say I know how the world's going
to develop and here's where we're heading?
And so for me, a lot of it was actually learning
the things that made me feel confident in my own
opinion. And there's a bunch of things that
do make me feel confident in my opinion. When
I talk to specific customers and I feel
like I can build an emulator for them,
like a customer on my shoulder where I can say,
oh, I talked to this person working in this job,
here's what they would say if I showed them this
product or this strategy. So, I think talking to
customers is a big unlock for me and feeling like
I have unique knowledge of the customer. I think
working through different product iterations
of, if we thought this was the right outcome,
what would it really look like from a product
perspective or a product portfolio in three
to five years? And which of those seems right
or rational or it will go the way I think the
world goes. I think asking for other opinions.
Sometimes I run surveys to the leadership team
where I'm just like, what percentage of our
revenue is going to come from small businesses
versus big businesses in three years? And if we
all agree on that topic, we should just take it
as the truth and we should just fill it. If we
disagree, then we should talk about it and we
should talk about the strategic ramifications
if we chose one path or the other path.
So for me, it was getting more comfortable
having an opinion, honestly, about how
the world was going to go, and also feeling
comfortable that we would be able to change
it when we learned that maybe that wasn't exactly
right. We would have the machine, the execution
machine behind it to try it out and then change
and iterate and improve with customer feedback.
At which point in your career
was this overcoming this fear
and uncertainty? Was it sometime within Facebook?
It was sometime within Facebook. It was really
when I was stepping into the bigger ads jobs,
getting to be Head of Product for Facebook ads.
I got feedback, I got a lot of feedback over
the course of my career and some of the
stacking of feedback was basically like,
you could be the smartest person in the room,
but it doesn't matter if people don't like you,
which is very complicated feedback and I wouldn't
give that feedback to anyone else, but I took it
very seriously. It was coming from so many
different places, it was coming from people
I'm really trusted. And so I went out of my way
to be more likable, which for me ended up being
shrinking myself a little bit and not
being so aggressive and not being so
opinionated, being more unobjectionable.
And the weird part is that it worked for a
long time. People were more likely to work with
me, they were more likely to say nice things. I
mean, I take this to extremes. I wore earth
tones for two years because I was just like,
I got to fade back a little bit. And then at
some point I actually had to do a leadership
job and my team was like, well, what do you
think? What's your opinion? And I was like,
you've been telling me not to have an
opinion for so long. And so it took a
little bit of work to get back to,
oh yeah, I have a lot of opinions,
I have a lot of thoughts. It is okay for me
to express. It is needed, my team needs me
to have these opinions and thoughts and be a
leader who can take ownership and be visible.
Thanks for sharing that. Do you
think that was the right approach,
going and indexing far to the other end and
then realizing that maybe that's too far,
or do you think you would've done
things differently looking back?
Yeah, it's one of my Roman empires. I think
about this every so often, way too much,
I think. Especially because I talked to other
senior women who received similar feedback and
chose not to act on it or did act on it, and what
happened to their paths were different. I think
where I landed is I wouldn't give that feedback to
someone else. And the way I do give that feedback,
actually, because I think there is a lot of
really useful information in that. The way I
do give that feedback is, you do need to be able
to work with a broader range of people and the
way to do that is to expand your tool sets.
You're not going to make yourself smaller,
you're not going to be any less of who you
are, but you are going to build new tools,
new keys to unlock new different kinds
of doors. And that is only going to
make you bigger and more powerful and more
expansive. But the end outcome is the same,
is that you can work with more different styles
of people, more different styles of problems.
I love that framing. There's an episode that's
going to come out before this episode with
this professor from Stanford, Jeffrey Pfeffer,
who teaches a class called The Path to Power,
which is how to become powerful in the
world. And he actually has a big lesson
that many people hate hearing, which is, you
don't need to be authentic in the workplace,
what you're trying to achieve, you're trying to
achieve stuff and you can do... You need to use
tools that you need to use to achieve the thing
you want to achieve. So sometimes don't be exactly
who you are and act in a slightly different
way, which is basically what you're describing.
More tools. I think that's
a theme that's coming up,
is just like, I'm all about more lenses,
more keys, more tools in general because
why not? Why not have access to
more different styles of things?
Something that you were talking about
subtly is the being a woman in tech and being a
female leader. I imagine you've gone through some
stuff that isn't what something men would've gone
through. Is there anything there that you want to
share or anything you've learned about just
being really successful as a woman in tech?
I think we've talked through some of them. I think
one, you get a different style of feedback and a
lot of the ways to interpret that feedback. I
think to this day, I get feedback that is about
walking a very narrow tightrope where not only
do you have to change a bunch of things and do
a bunch of things that are important, you have
to make people feel a certain way about how you
do them and the ways that they want you to make
you feel are diametrically opposite. Some people
are going to be like, be more directive so that
way everyone knows your thing. Some people are
going to say be less directive so people can
come to their own conclusions. Some people are
going to say move faster because there's
always more you can do. Some people are
going to say move less fast because otherwise
you're going to end up steamrolling people.
And a lot of it is personal, there's a bunch
research about how women get a lot more personal
feedback that is less about the content of their
role and more about their style, I think that is
still true and there's often a kernel of truth in
it. For me, this is forever work. I do have biases
toward execution and being directive and things
like that, but I think learning how to interpret
and respond to feedback has been a really
important point for me and making my choices of,
just because I'm getting feedback doesn't mean I
immediately need to respond to all of it. There's
a step in between where I can choose, is this
feedback I want to take action on in this exact
way? Am I going to look for more themes, take
action in a different way, or am I going to
say this is who I am and I understand the
trade-offs, I'm going to do a better job
of giving people context on the decisions I'm
making and why I'm choosing these trade-offs.
But actually this is part of how I want to
operate and I'm going to keep on operating.
And then I think we just give women weird advice.
Here's a hot take. I think we tell women things
like, you need to find a mentor and you need to
find a sponsor, and that's just another set of
hoops that we have that we tell women to jump
through that I don't think we tell other parts
of the population to jump through. I think we tell
women to unlock your future success, you've got to
find somebody who has made all the same life
decisions you have and who you look up to and
relate to, but who also had an hour every month to
be an oracle to tell you all the things you do in
your life. And it feels like yet another burden
where you're like, I don't know how to do that.
I had the extreme generosity of so many
wonderful leaders who helped me on my way,
but I didn't feel like I had this mentor
and for a while it was just like, oh man,
if I only had a mentor, I would know how
to do all of this stuff and it felt like
another weight that I needed to carry, which I
didn't. I had everything I needed, people were
so kind and generous, but I didn't recognize it
that way because we talk about it differently.
Thank you for sharing all that. I wasn't
planning on going in this direction,
but this is such important advice for say, young
women that are just getting started in the same
product. Is there any advice you'd want to
share to help them get to be the next Ami?
Oh, I mean number one, no next Ami, they're going
to be their next themselves. That is maybe the
most important thing, is everyone will only tell
you their own story. That's all anyone can do,
but the thing that I tell people is, don't
dampen who you are and your strengths,
just continue expanding.
Whenever you run into a problem,
just add more to the things that you can
do, the tools that you have, the way you
can express yourself. Just keep on adding
and growing and don't shrink yourself, ever.
I love that. I want to move to a different
topic. There's a few things I definitely
wanted to touch on while we had our
time together. One is that I hear,
now this is going to be a total tangent, but I
think it's really important and I'm excited to
talk about it. I hear you're really good at
setting goals and aligning incentives really
well for teams. One of your colleagues told
me you're best in class at building product
orgs and figuring out how product orgs can best
work with other teams. I'm curious if there's
any tricks or lessons you can share here about
what you've learned about how to do this well.
Yeah, I mean I think one thing is to try to
decouple all the things we're trying to do.
Sometimes when you give people direction, you're
like, okay, everybody just go get revenue or
everybody just go get GMV. And it seems obvious
because that's the thing you have to do as a
company, but there's only a few places where you
are guaranteed to get that and it's measurable
and you can do it. And that leads to what I call
toddler soccer, where everybody just runs to the
same surface or the same customer set or the
same exact product where you can do this and
it's measurable and you end up, everyone's
tripping on each other, everyone's trying,
nobody really gets contact on the ball, there's
no coordination. I have three kids, I've
watched a lot of toddlers play soccer. [inaudible
00:57:18], it's a very fresh, very fresh metaphor.
And instead, one of the things I like to
do is just detangle, okay, as a company,
let's think about our customers. Let's think
about all the things they're going to need
in their journey. Let's think about how we
will know how we will match our own metrics
to customer success. Let's play the entire
field. What would it look like if we could
detangle it so that every team we had internally
had a different goal that ladders into a goal
framework that's actually the thing that we need
to do to solve the full customer impact? And then
you don't have the same swim lanes problem. You
have plenty of room for people to make progress
on their lanes. They all know how they fit into
the bigger picture, and it just opens up a lot
more growth for every team and it makes sure that
we're solving the customer problem end to end.
Is there an example that you could share
to make this even more concrete from say,
WhatsApp or Facebook or Instagram or anything like
that, where you can share some of these goals that
you've like, oh, this worked out really well? I
know it's probably private information and partly-
It might be trickier. I mean, maybe going
back to the GMV example. Maybe instead of
motivating everyone on GMV, you motivate them on
GMV per surface and you divide up the surfaces,
or maybe you motivate them on actually different
goals that underlie. When you think about GMV,
what are all the various engagements, customer
engagements that lead to GMV? Can you goal on
those input metrics, can you goal on number of
people who visit, number of people who convert,
number of people who reorder, number, etc?
Rather than going strictly on the output.
So the core advice here is each team
should have different goals that are
part of this metrics tree that ladder
up to revenue, GMV, something like that?
Whatever, yeah. The thing that
best matches the overall customer
outcome that mirrors the company outcome as well.
Got it. And there's always this
balance between it's actually
the best metric versus it's something
they can move and understand and it's
easy to watch and it's movable
and things like that, right?
Yeah, and you have to have faith that
it is actually connected to that output
metric. You don't want to create a metric that's
disconnected just to make a team feel good. It
really does need to solve the customer problem
and that's reflected in company's performance,
but you can usually break it down into
smaller pieces and I think that breaking
down into smaller pieces and assigning
those out to teams, that's really helpful.
Is there anything else along these lines of things
you've learned about helping teams work
together and not play toddler soccer,
beyond having different goals that all
ladder up to the one that really matters?
I think there's value in also acknowledging that
teams are going to have different incentives. Even
inside a team like cross-functional
teams on the same pod or whatever,
are going to have different incentives, they're
going to come in with different information,
they're going to have disagreements. And
certainly, different teams inside a company
or different pillars inside a company,
different products inside, they're all
going to have different incentives, and I think
sometimes that feels like something is going
wrong when people disagree, but actually, that's
just a sign of healthy tension and knowledge.
I think the thing that makes tension healthy
is one, when you can acknowledge it and say,
yeah, of course there's tension. You're bringing
different information than I'm bringing. We should
be disagreeing. No one's a bad person, no one
is coming in with poor intent. Everyone's doing
the thing they are supposed to do and that
is a useful thing to do. And then you have
to agree on an outcome that you're aiming for.
If you disagree on what the company outcome is
or what the customer outcome is, then you've
got some structural stuff you need to work out
and normally you just have to escalate it, but if
you agree on like, we're all trying to move this
metric by changing this customer experience, then
all you're doing is having a conversation about
the best way to do that using the different
information that everyone is bringing. And I
think that's super important to just have
as a rational, open, explicit discussion,
as opposed to trying to hide it or pocket vetoing
or something else. Because you assume that when
someone disagrees with you that, I don't know,
there's something emotional or wrong about it.
But it's fascinating.
Exactly.
There's a piece of advice I once heard
from the Head of Product at Airbnb once
where we were trying to find, reorg
the business and try to figure out the
best org and his advice and something he
realized is, there's never the best org,
there's just the best idea we have at
the time with the here's the things
we know are not going to be optimal about
it and let's build processes around that.
I think that's my take on leadership in
general. Especially as you get more senior,
you can only make bad decisions. At some
point someone can bring you a problem,
you can recognize a problem and you can solve
it, and there's so much happiness in solving
that and tying a bow around it. But as you
get senior, the only problems you'll see are
ones that are fundamentally unsolvable because
otherwise, someone would've solved it before
they got to you. And so all you're doing is
choosing which branch of suboptimal you're
going to put your name on and describing the
principles you're using and the context and
the fact that it's suboptimal, but it's still the
best thing. I think that's a really hard thing,
is just to recognize and acknowledge that
increasingly people only see you do, make
suboptimal decisions and from a distance they're
just like, why is that person only making bad
decisions? And it's because those are your only
options. All you can do is choose the least bad,
the best possible for the time,
for the problem that's consistent
that makes sense with the framework, and
that's been a tough thing to learn too.
You said somewhere that as you get more senior,
you get worse at everything
because the problems get harder.
Yes, exactly. I mean, it's a kind of
dark view of leadership where yeah,
you can't fully solve problems, you have to say
no a lot people are unhappy with you. I thought
as you get more senior, everyone listens to
you and they like you and you could just say
a thing and then it happens and that is not
at all accurate. It really is, most of the
decisions you make are not going to be perfect.
And I think I'm all about just normalizing and
acknowledging those hard truths because otherwise,
I feel like I'm failing. And if I just know that
something is normal that it's part of the
job, then it's not me. It's just like, okay,
this is a fact of the job that I have to get
accustomed to if I want to have this kind of
impact. And there's something about having
the impact, being able to serve the customer,
being able to be part of this team, there's
something about it that is so worthwhile that
it's worth being terrible at everything
and being visibly terrible at everything
because that is the best way that I have
to have that kind of impact in the world.
I think this is really important for early ICPMs
to hear because they see their CPO and founders
making all these decisions and they're like,
what the hell? That's a terrible idea, why are
they doing this? What you're saying is just like
it's the best... Options are limited and then-
[inaudible 01:04:38].
... nothing's going to be optimal.
Yeah, no org is optimal. It's definitely
not. You can optimize for the people you
have and you can optimize for the products
you have, can optimize for the customers you
have and you can optimize for the technology
you have. Those are the options that you have,
and in every one of those you trade off
everything else. And so you just have to know,
there's not going to be a perfect where all of it
works and that's okay. That is part of the fun of
it. That's part of getting to do this work, is
continuing to improve, but it's hard. It's hard
when people, it's hard, especially when you want
everyone to think you're so great at everything.
This idea you mentioned of as a senior person
solving people's problems, feeling really good,
reminds me. Rolling to this, there's this
Harvard Business Review article from the '70s
or '80s or something about monkeys on your
back. Have you read this or heard of this?
Oh yeah, yeah, I did.
Where it's basically like as a
manager, [inaudible 01:05:28]-
You're trying to get monkey off
of your back on people's backs?
Exactly.
Right, right, right.
People come to you, Ami, here's my
monkey, please take it for me and
feed it for me and take care of it.
And your job as a leader is to keep
the monkeys on people's backs and help them
figure out how to feed this monkey themself.
It's a weird one.
To get it off their back. It's very visceral.
I want to talk about Faire and your current
role as a final section of our chat. First
of all, what was it like starting something
completely new after 15 years at Meta
at the various properties of Meta?
Yeah, I mean, I was so lucky. I had such an
amazing run at Meta. I got to work with amazing
leaders, truly great products. And I came to
Faire for the same reason that I've been anywhere,
because I believe in the people and I believe
in the mission. A lot of my family in India is
in wholesale and local retail, which is what Faire
does, and so it was also a very personal thing for
me too. I felt like I knew those customers. I'm a
huge fan of small businesses, I got to work with
a bunch of them in previous jobs as well.
I would say coming to Faire, I mean,
one of the things I always think about is
that especially as you are more senior,
ramping on anywhere feels terrible because you
expect to be as good at your new job as you
were when you left your last job, but you forget
that at your last job, you were there for years,
you had years to build up the vocabulary and the
cultural context and the network and the product
knowledge, and then you're stepping in somewhere
where you know none of that, but you have the same
expectations of yourself of being able to have an
impact and improve things and help your team. And
so I always just try to remind myself, it's going
to take time and what's most important is not for
me to try to come in and change everything
immediately, but to learn enough to be able
to change things like 60 or 90 or 120 days in the
future. And so that breathing helps a little bit.
It was also really interesting because Faire was
entirely new to me. It was a new business model,
it was a whole new set of people. It was a
whole new set of customer problems. And so
every interaction I just had to learn so much.
I had to learn, who is this person? How do they
see the world? What's the problem they're
talking to me about? What's the customer
impact, I think? So it was just a dramatic
learning curve, which I always really love.
Maybe the last thing I'd say is, again, I was
super lucky at Meta. I think I always had this
maybe deep-seated insecurity that maybe I was
only good at Meta. Maybe there was something
about that network of people and how great
they were and how well I knew those products,
and maybe I wouldn't be that successful somewhere
without that scaffolding. And so leaving and being
able to go somewhere else and lead through
change and a new place, a new customer set,
a new business model, that's also been
really, really affirming for me, honestly.
Well, you have a lot of fans at
Faire from the people I know there.
[inaudible 01:08:36].
And so clearly, things are going well, at least
as far as I can tell. Something that I think is,
Faire definitely has, and a lot of companies have,
is a very product minded visionary founder. And
CPOs classically last a year or two, and then
they're like, ah, this sucks. The founder just
tells me what to do and what's the point of this
role? And it's so frustrating. I'm curious just
what you've learned about, at least so far, about
working with someone like that as a CPO and not
just being this middle person between what the
founder wants to do with the team, this building.
Yeah, I mean, this is going to sound so naive,
but I literally didn't know how important it was
for me to have such a great relationship with
the CEO, because I always had great relation,
I was lucky, I had great relationships with
a lot of people at my previous jobs. I was
like, oh, of course it's going to be fine,
everyone's going to let me do what I want,
whatever. And I think I just got really lucky
because Max is an amazing CEO, who's also super
growth mindset and super open to talking over
ideas, even when they involve a lot of change.
So when I was onboarding, one of the
things I always like to do is write a list
of observations. I go out and talk to, I have
one-on-ones with a lot of people, and I write,
here's the themes that I'm hearing. Here's what's
going well, here's what's not going well. And
that's a way for me to both share what I'm seeing
and build some credibility and trust that way,
but also for people to give me feedback and
be like, oh, you're wrong about this, just
so I can correct my starting point of knowledge.
And with Max, I also wrote a parallel document of
hot takes. So once a quarter or so for the first
year, I'd write a document that was just like,
hey, for sake of provocation, if we wanted
to fundamentally change a few things, here's
ideas on what we could fundamentally change. And
Max, very, very well could have just been like,
hey, can you please just run product? That's
you're job, can you please do that? And instead,
he and the entire rest of the executive team were
like, yeah, let's step through these. Let's talk
about which of these we should try, let's talk
about maybe context you don't have for why these
don't make sense or why we don't do these.
And that was such a gift because I was able
to build such a great relationship, a trusting and
complimentary relationship with Max and the rest
of the exec team, and also that he took seriously
things that he really didn't have to that I have
so much respect for that, and I think I got really
lucky in just finding a great CEO and exec team.
Is there anything you learned about
this vetting process? Say you're a
founder looking for a head of product, A CPO,
any advice for how they might vet this person
to make sure they are good fit and will last?
What I'd say to everyone else is, make sure
you just have a mind meld with a CEO. Before
you decide to take the job, spend a day together,
understand how they think and how they operate,
and whether you're going to work together in
a way that feels really high fidelity and high
trust and you're going to have room. I mean, I'm
not a founder by any stretch and so when founders
ask me what should I look for in a head of product
or CPO, I say something a little bit different,
which is, make sure that you really need the level
of seniority that you are hiring. I think that a
lot of founders think, I need a CPO, I need a VP
of product, I need someone who's really senior,
when often the founder has a bunch of the
vision and knowledge, and what they really
need is somebody to build the product. They
don't need somebody who's going to scale the
team or build systems like they've got enough
of that. And so that to me is part of building
that complimentary relationship where the founder
and CEO know what they need and on the CPO side,
they know that they can mind meld enough
with the CEO to actually have an impact.
Last question. You started as an intern
in the PR department, I think, at Meta?
Oh, I started as a temp, actually.
At temp, okay, amazing. And then you ended
up leading Facebook ads and then WhatsApp
and many other things. Can you share that story
of just how you joined and how that happened?
Well, I had quit my last job. I knew that what I
wanted to do was be involved in all the wild stuff
happening in Silicon Valley in the mid 2000s. So
I'd quit my last job, I was traveling around the
world a little bit. I was living in New York, an
extremely blissful lifestyle. I was unemployed,
I was doing whatever I wanted. It was
some of the best time I've had in my life,
and eventually I needed a job, like you do. But
it was 2007 and the only place I wanted to work
was Facebook. You could hear the way people
talked about these products. People would say
Facebook is more important than than my car. It's
like how I connect with the world. It was such a
magical product, and you could hear that.
And I knew some people at the company
and I convinced one of them to introduce me
to everyone at the office. I'd made a trade,
I said, I'll buy you a fancy coffee at Coupa
Cafe in downtown Palo Alto, and in exchange just
introduced me to everyone, everyone you know,
take me around the office. So everyone I met,
I said, "Hey, I'm Ami, I really want to work
here. I'll do whatever you need." And the only
call I got back was from the Head of PR,
Brandy Barker, who said, "Look, we can't
hire you. We didn't interview you. We don't have
headcount. You're not really qualified." It was
just like 10 reasons. I was like, okay,
thank you for calling me. And she said,
"But we need a temp to review our press releases,
so if you want to come join a temp agency,
we'll tell them to send you here." And that's
what I did, I moved out to California and I
slept on people's couches and eventually they
hired me full time and I didn't look back.
And now you're on Lenny's podcast, what a run.
It's interesting, this reminds me of another
path to power rule from the Jeffrey PFeffer
podcast, of networking is one of the best ways
to acquire power in the world. So it's interesting
that now that seed has planted in my head. Anyway,
just A plug for that other episode also.
Ami, is there anything else that you wanted
to share or leave listeners with before
we get to a very exciting lightning round?
Sometimes people ask me who are working in
product, what's the one thing they should do
to be successful at product? And maybe the thing
I would say is, especially as an org scale or a
company scales, there's just a lot of distractions
that get between you and the customer. And so the
one thing that I would just advise everyone
to do is just think about the customer,
talk to the customer, be an advocate for them.
It's such a shortcut to everything else you need
to do in order to be successful, but it's so easy
for that to get lost when you're thinking about,
okay, how do I get alignment on my team? How
do I figure out my roadmap? How do I convince
people to join the company? There's all these
different things, but fundamentally, we're here
to create value for the customer. And the closer
you can get to that, I always found myself the
happiest because I'm building that feedback loop
with the customer, but also more successful.
Well, let me actually follow up on this because
this is really important and interesting. There's
a PM part of my brain of like, okay, but we
also got to move some metrics and sometimes
that metric isn't going to be moved by, we need
to do something specifically for the customer,
but it's something that will help the
business. Is there anything there of
just that balance of like, we need
to move over this conversion metric,
versus, let's focus fully on what does the
customer want and need? Any thoughts there?
Yeah, I think we often make things adversarial
that are not actually adversarial. It is very
rare for customer value to be different than a
company value on a long enough time horizon. There
might be short-term divergences, but really,
to solve, to create value for the customer,
you got to be around as a business, otherwise
you are creating zero value for the customer.
And so I think really, just starting with
the, what are the end goals and where does
stuff diverge in the very short term versus the
medium term versus in the long term? It shouldn't,
and really thinking about where you are in the
journey and how to place that. That always helps
me because our metrics should absolutely
be about long-term customer impact. It's
very rare if those aren't, and then
you're still able to be successful.
It comes back to our chat about
metrics and how to do those well.
With that, we've reached our
very exciting lightning round.
Cool, I'm ready.
Here we go. First question,
what are two or three books
that you've recommended most to other people?
The Year of Yes, by Shonda Rhimes. I almost
never read nonfiction. I love Shonda Rhimes,
made an exception for this one. It's about
just saying yes to things and finding your
voice when you do feel like you're sometimes
the first or the only or the different,
and what that feels like. And it was
very life-changing for me, actually.
That's an awesome pick. No one has
recommended that one yet. Reminds
me of an episode of Matthew Dicks, who has
a Ted Talk about saying yes to everything.
Really?
He just says, Chris, to say yes to everything
and his life is incredibly interesting as a
result. Next question, do you have a favorite
recent movie or TV show you really enjoyed?
I watch a lot of witty workplace comedies
from the mid 2000s. So I watch a lot of The
Office or 30 Rock reruns. Things are just very
comfortable that I already know everything,
there's no surprises. I'm not
great with new stuff right now.
I heard they're bringing back The
Office. There's a reboot happening.
Oh really? Let's see.
Yeah, exactly. Is there a favorite product
you've recently discovered that you love,
either digital, physical, anything?
Maybe a physical product that I really like.
I drink a lot of coffee and tea through the
day and it's just, I don't know, a calming
ritual. And so I have a Fellow's electric
kettle, that was my big work from home
upgrade. So I have this life for kettle,
I have a pour over kit. I have these
lovely colorful mugs that I like,
that has actually just made my day-to-day a
lot better, is just a little feeling of luxury.
I love that. I think we have that same kettle. I
also drink tea during every episode I have here.
Oh, yeah. You know it.
So we're on the same page. Next question.
Do you have a favorite life motto that
you often think about, come back to, share
with friends or family, in work or in life?
It is definitely not a motto. I feel like I know
people have mottos and I'm so impressed. I'm like,
you know what you are, you know
what you need. I am not that person,
but I have a piece of advice that someone gave me
very early in my career. Actually, it was Chamath,
he said, "You can either have more energy or
less ambition." And I was like, oh, that's a
little harsh, but also really true. And I think
about that, it's another of my Roman empires. I
think about it all the time where I'm like,
okay, if I want to have this kind of impact,
I'm going to have to do the work, I'm going to
have to try new things, I'm going to have to feel
uncomfortable, and sometimes I don't want to do
those things. I don't want to do all of that work,
and then I can't be mad if I'm not having the
impact. Those two just have to go together.
I also have to get lucky in all these different
ways, but the two have to go together and that's
been just a good governor, a little bit,
of how I think about what I'm putting in.
I love that quote. By the way, if people
don't know what you're talking about when
you talk about the Roman Empires, there's
a meme on TikTok where somebody said that
every man thinks about the Roman
Empire at least once a week. Right?
It's made me think about, what are all
the things I think about repeatedly
without really having trigger or
reason? And there's still a lot. I
don't think about the Roman Empire
though. That is not one of them.
I also don't think about the Roman
Empires, something's wrong with me. Okay,
final question. You can blame your colleague Barr
for this question. He tells me that you are very
good at jokes, you tell very good jokes. Do you
have a joke that you want to share by any chance?
I love jokes. There was a year at
Facebook where I posted a joke of
the week to the company and they're all terrible.
To the company.
Yeah, exactly. All right. Here's my favorite joke.
Great.
Why don't sharks eat clowns?
Why?
Because they taste funny. I'll tell
you one more and you can choose one,
you can choose which one. All right.
No, we're not cutting anything.
What did the zero say to the eight?
Something like us. Okay, no, I don't know.
Nice belt.
Nice what?
Belt.
Belt. Oh, I got it.
[inaudible 01:21:51].
I get it, I get it. I'm going to tell you a joke.
I just heard a standup share. How
do you turn an egg into a vegetable?
I feel like if you put a letter on it'll turn into
a vegetable name, but I can't think of the letter.
I love that you're really trying to analyze
it and get there because I don't know if it's
ever possible to actually get the answer. Okay, so
how do you turn an egg into a vegetable? Squash.
That is definitely my level of joke, definitely.
They're like, this is for your
kid. Go home and do this joke.
Ami, this was everything I hoped it would be.
I'm going to read again the goal you had for this
podcast, I 100% think we achieved it. To be as
authentic as possible and show that people can be
pretty messy and imperfect at times, yet still be
very successful. I think exactly what this podcast
ended up being. Thank you so much for being here.
Two final questions. Where can folks find you
online if they want to reach out and learn
more, and how can listeners be useful to you?
Oh, thank you, Lenny. It's been such a
pleasure. I write a blog on Substack at
amivora@substack.com. It's called The Hard Parts
of Growth, it's just about how even when you're
working in great places with great people at
great companies, sometimes things are hard and
that's normal. And so you can find me there. I
do the same, I crosspost to LinkedIn so you can
find me there. And how can people be helpful
to me? I don't know, just by being great, by
being kind and nice and making the world slightly
better. Yeah, I think that's what we can all do.
I love that, and I will link to
your Substack in the show notes,
so if where people want to check it out, and
I'll recommend it. I haven't done it yet,
but I'm going to recommend it for my Substack.
Thank you, Lenny, so much. This was such a
fun conversation. I've really enjoyed it.
I loved it. Ami, thank you so much
for being here. Bye, everyone.
Bye.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to the show
on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.