Is performance marketing just something
every company should be doing?
Hot take, paid is for everyone. If you look at
the way each platform is doing, Google, you have
to scroll pretty far down to get to an organic
listing. Meta, it's almost a pay for play now.
When you take over for an agency at a company,
you crush their performance within a month. I'm
curious to what you find they are doing wrong?
Instead of thinking about being on top of
the page, and that's like ego marketing,
I want to be number one. I want to
be there all the time. It's about
showing to the right person as often as possible.
Any other tips for people just
to experiment with the platform?
Each platform is different. The user behavior
is different. Make sure you're not too hard on
yourself if it doesn't work. It's okay to fail
because we're either winning or we're learning.
Today, my guest is Timothy Davis. Timothy
has led performance marketing for all of
Shopify for the past two and a half years, and as
a consultant has helped companies like Pinterest,
LinkedIn, Redfin, and Eventbrite kickstart
and scale the performance marketing teams.
In our conversation, we get incredibly tactical
on all things to performance marketing and paid
growth, when to start investing, how to
run signs of life tests on each platform,
what platforms to investigate and what platforms
to bet big on, what types of companies are best
suited to invest big on paid growth whether you
should invest pre-product market fit or not,
what agencies often get wrong and what to look
for in your investment when you're just getting
started? Plus, what your first three hires should
look like, tips for which platforms are most
interesting right now, a peek at Timothy's actual
reports that he runs to judge performance, if
you're watching this on YouTube and so much more.
This episode is for anyone who's trying to figure
out how to kickstart or improve their performance
marketing investment, and I guarantee you'll get
something out of this that'll make your
life better. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's the
best way to avoid missing future episodes and
it helps the podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you Timothy Davis. Timothy, thank you
so much for being here. Welcome to the podcast.
Yeah, thanks for having me. A long time coming.
Yeah, I'm really excited we're finally doing
this. I actually posted on Twitter for people
to suggest questions for this topic and there's
just so much interest in what we're going to be
talking about, which essentially we're going
to be diving deep into all things paid growth,
all things performance marketing. By the way, I
have a cold. For people, if in case you wonder
why I sound a little weird, but the show must go
on. I want to start with just setting a little
context for folks that aren't super familiar
with performance marketing and paid growth. When
we talk about performance marketing/paid growth,
first of all, are those two terms interchangeable
to you? And second of all, what falls under the
umbrella of performance marketing/paid growth?
Paid can be a lot of things. It can be online, it
can be offline, it can also even be affiliates.
Typically, when I talk about performance
marketing, it's about online only, but you could
argue offline could be performing and affiliates
could be performing and stuff like that.
They can be interchangeable, but I would
recommend if you are talking about it,
to specify which one you're talking about. Because
when you do say paid, because I'm in the industry,
I would just, "Oh, they do Google Search
and they do Meta and they do things like
that." But if you do offline and you just
say paid, we may be talking about things,
but missing each other on two ships passing
in the night. So I think historically,
people, when they have said paid growth,
have been fully focused on just online.
Just online. Okay. Got it.
But I would argue in the last couple of years,
you could definitely roll offline
into that conversation as well.
Okay. So performance marketing,
when someone hears that term,
it's essentially marketing that
you can measure the performance up.
Correct. Yes, nail on the head.
This episode is brought to you by buildbetter.ai.
Back in 2020 when AI was just a toy, BuildBetter
bet that it could cut down on a product team's
operational BS. Fast-forward to today, 23,000
product teams use purpose-built AI in BuildBetter
every day. First, BuildBetter uses custom models
to turn unstructured data like product and sales
calls, support tickets, internal communications
and surveys into structured insights. It's like
having a dedicated data science team. Second,
BuildBetter runs those structured insights into
workflows, like weekly reports about customer
issues, context-aware PRDs and user research
documents with citations. It even turns stand-ups
into action items that automatically get assigned
and shared into your tools. Plus, with unlimited
seat pricing on all plans, BuildBetter ensures
everyone at your company has access to this
knowledge. Truly, no data silos. In a world of
AI demos, over promising and under-delivering,
see why BuildBetter has a 93% subscription
retention. Get a personalized demo and use code,
Lenny, for a $100 credit if you sign up now at
buildbetter.ai/lenny. I'm excited to chat with
Christina Gilbert, the founder of OneSchema, one
of our long time podcast sponsors. Hi, Christina.
Yes. Thank you for having me on, Lenny.
What is the latest with OneSchema? I know you now
work with some of my favorite companies like Ramp,
Vanta Scale and Watershed. I heard
that you just launched a new product
to help product teams import CSVs from
especially tricky systems like ERPs.
Yes. So we just launched OneSchema file feeds,
which allows you to build an integration with
any system in 15 minutes as long as you can export
a CSV to an SFTP folder. We see our customers all
the time getting stuck with hacks and workarounds,
and the product teams that we work with don't have
to turn down prospects because their systems
are too hard to integrate with. We allow our
customers to offer thousands of integrations
without involving their engineering team at all.
I can tell you that if my team had
to build integrations like this,
how nice would it be to be able to
take this off my roadmap and instead,
use something like OneSchema, and not just
to build it, but also to maintain it forever.
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many
horror stories of multi-day outages from
even just a handful of bad records. We are
laser-focused on integration reliability to
help teams end all of those distractions
that come up with integrations. We have a
built-in validation layer that stops any bad
data from entering your system and OneSchema
will notify your team immediately
of any data that looks incorrect.
I know that importing incorrect data can cause
all kinds of pain for your customers and quickly
lose their trust. Christina, thank you for
joining us. And if you want to learn more, head
on over to oneschema.co. That's oneschema. co.
Is performance marketing just something every
company should be doing or is there certain
business models where it's like, "No, you're
probably going to grow through other channels
mostly like SEO or sales or word of mouth.
Hot take. I would say, paid is for everyone.
If you look at the way each platform is doing,
Google introducing AI, plus with paid taking up
the first four spots, you have to scroll pretty
far down to get to an organic listing. Meta, it's
almost a pay for play now. You have to do promoted
posts for people to even see your content. I would
say it does depend on the industry you're in. If
you're say, leaning heavily into influencer
marketing, that is still a paid component.
You may not be doing Meta ads, you may not be
doing paid search, but that is a paid component.
But I would say at baseline, everyone should be
doing paid search. The way I usually explain it
to people is paid search is user driven. You have
to type in a relevant keyword for your ad to show.
Anything else is more disruptive media. You're on
Meta and you're looking at pictures of babies and
cats, and then all of a sudden, you see an ad
for Shopify. You're watching a YouTube video,
maybe a YouTube podcast, and then in between, you
get advertisements maybe for Shopify, maybe for
Pinterest, maybe for Eventbrite. So all of that
being disruptive media may not make a whole lot
of sense for where you are as a business, but I
would say paid search being user-driven, having
to type in a relevant keyword for your ad to show,
should pretty much be for just about everybody.
Everyone should do it. Super interesting.
There's also the most companies grow through
one growth engine primarily, say word of mouth,
or SEO, or sales or paid. So for some companies,
paid will be most of how they grow like say, I
always think of Booking.com and Credit Karma and
just like most of their growth came from paid
growth online, paid growth. For some companies,
it's just like a layer, a small 10, 20% of
their growth. What are signs that you have
the potential for paid/performance marketing
to be most of your growth, like say 70, 80%?
I always say, where are your users? You will have
some data that will allow you to understand that
say right now, you're doing really well on TikTok.
Some would argue that's an emerging channel
right now. Great. If that's doing really
well for you, maybe you take... Because
that content could be used on something similar
like Snap, see how that does for you. You could
also lean into your Google Analytics or
whatever analytics tool you are using and
see if you're already getting users from that
platform. If you're currently managing that,
if you don't have a profile on there and
obviously, you don't have a presence,
it would be really hard for users to find you
and get there. But always look at the data that's
available to you within your analytics platforms
and say, "Users are already finding us here. How
can we turn that knob up to 11?" And you can
do that with paid. Because if they're already
finding you through that channel, what would
happen if you were to just turn it up to 11?
Is there an example of a company you worked
with that's known that as an example of that,
where you're like, "Oh, I see everyone's looking,
finding them on Google. Let's go turn it to 11."
Yeah. So there was a company I worked with
a couple of years ago called, Hairstory
and IPSY. I know, very funny. Guy with no
hair working on a company called Hairstory,
but they were doing really well from a Google
shopping standpoint. But when I started consulting
with them, we looked at the analytics and we
actually saw that they were getting a lot of
people from Meta and TikTok at the time. And
TikTok was very, very new and they didn't
really know what to do with it. So said, "We'll
do a small test." We can start on Meta with just
some customer testimonials. Let's see how that
does. We'll get interest in, build a funnel,
get retargeting, and hopefully get conversions.
TikTok was so new at the time that it was like,
"We don't know what's going to work. Let's
just try with what is currently available."
Then once we started doing it, we started
noticing, "Hey, this doesn't make a whole
lot of sense from a creative standpoint." We were
missing the mark of what we were using on Meta was
working, was not working on TikTok. So you can't
always just take what is currently working on one
platform and apply it to another because it is
a different user experience. It is a different
mindset that the user has when they're on there.
So that was an example of where we were able to
take those instances, look at their data and say,
"They're already finding us here. How can we turn
this up a little bit?" And I don't remember the
numbers exactly, but it was pretty exponential.
Okay. So the core advice here so far, is look
for where people are coming to you from today,
and then that gives you a sign of where you
should start to think about running paid ads,
performance marketing on those platforms.
Yeah. And also, there's a saying that my current
director likes to use, which is signs of life.
You can always do a very, very small test. You
can just put a little money into a platform,
see if there's a sign of life. If there is, then
you can pull back and say, "Okay, we have signs
of life. Now let's build a campaign around
that." There's no reason to say, "All right,
we have a signs of life. Let's now turn it up
all the way." Do we have the right creative?
Do we have the right campaign? Do we have the
right messaging for the users on this platform?
Then let's take that approach, as opposed
to just, "Hey, signs of life, great, go run
a hundred miles an hour." Make sure you're doing
the right thing when you get into those platforms.
Let's follow that thread. A lot of people run
little experiments on say, TikTok, and Snap,
and Twitter, and things like LinkedIn, and they
often don't see a lot of results and it's always
like, "Hey, did we do it wrong or is it the
platform's not working?" I know it's a very
difficult question to give like, "Here's how you
do a sign of life test correctly," But what are
some things that you think either people do often
wrong when they're trying to experiment with the
platform or that you just think they should do
when they're trying to look for signs of life?
The number one thing I tell people all the time
is use your own data, start with your own data.
So take the existing customer base you have, load
that up into the platform to build lookalikes.
From there, you can do... And I'll use Meta as the
example. You can do a 1%, all the way up to a 10%.
So 1% match, 2%, 3%, so on and so forth.
What I tend to do is build ad sets,
one at 1% because we know that one's going to
be highly correlated to what we're looking for.
Then a two to four, and then a five to seven,
and then an eight plus. More times than not,
the eight plus does not work, but there have
been times where it has, so it's, "Hey, let's
do it. Let's try it." But if you also have a very
limited budget because some people don't have the
luxury of having an unlimited budget like we do
in some of these other companies I've worked at,
just start with the 1%. See what that sign of
life is because you already know that this is
so tied to your existing customer base. If that
sign of life is giving you a positive signal,
now you have the information you need to
build a campaign you need to be successful.
What are these percentages referring to? You may
have mentioned it, but when you say 1%, 2%, 3%.
Yeah, yeah. So that is how closely tied
they are to that user's behavior on the
platform. So they're 1% tied to what they're
doing. They're visiting similar pages or they
have similar behavior on the platform, so
they're more than likely going to be tied
to what that user... They're not going to
be that user exactly, but they're going
to be very correlated to them where 10% is
pretty wide base that you're going to hit.
I see. So the smaller the percentage, the closer
they are, the closer it will look like there.
Yep, there you go.
How do you know if it's the creative
that is failing versus it's just never
going to work? Is there something that
tells you that's what's not working?
It's a million-dollar question, to be honest
with you. Because you could look at some of the
metrics that currently exist in the platform.
Click-through rate basically just tells you,
are the users engaged? Because start with the
target. You're getting the impressions are there.
Is the target right? That should be your first
thing. Yes, the target is correct. Users that we
want to see are seeing our ads, but they're not
engaging with it. That would be the first thing.
But the part that I think you're really trying
to ask is creative versus the content. Because
sometimes depending on the ad unit, you could
have a story creative that is literally the
creative has to stand on its own, not
necessarily the content that's in it,
but something like an in-feed creative
has a headline, a primary, a description,
and a creative. That's where honestly, the
only way you're going to get an answer to
that outside of the data that's available to you
like click-through rate, reach, frequency and all
those things to pull in more metrics, is a focus
group to understand, "Hey, when you saw this image
with this content, what was your result from it?"
Now, you can build a test within the platform to
do a control versus a test where say, you
take the creative with the same primary
and the same description versus a creative
that's just your logo with the headline and
the description and see what the results are.
But more times than not, you're not getting the
understanding from the user of, well, why doesn't
that creative resonate with you? And they'll give
you suggestions in the focus group. Why does that
work better for you than not? So that's a really,
really hard question to answer without having
those dialogue with the user to understand that.
Yeah, that makes a lot of sense. How long
do you recommend these tests run for these
signs of life tests? And I like this term,
by the way. I haven't heard this before.
Ideally, in a perfect world, you're going to hear
the word, statistical relevance. Mathematicians
will tell you exactly what that number is. And
I'm not going to pretend like a mathematician,
but a lot of times, it's budget constraint.
So there could be a VP finance. Anyone
like that could just come to you and just say,
"Hey, do you have $25,000 for this test?" You
only have 5,000. Just get that information,
get that data. You can then also build an off
size off of that. Hey guys, we worked with
our Meta partners, we worked with our Google
partners. We put $1,000 behind this test.
We know that our impression share was this,
our reach was this. If we were to put $10,000 into
it, this is the expected return we can get from it
based on the click-through rate, the conversion
rate that we got from the test that we ran.
Got it. So basically, we have
limited number of dollars to
spend. That'll tell you how long
you could run one of these for.
Yeah.
Any other tips for someone that's trying to
experiment with a platform early on for these
signs of life tests? So one is try a lookalike
that is the most targeted version of the
lookalike. So 1% you said, and then incrementally
grown and incrementally increase that percentage
as you spend more. Any other tips, I guess, for
people just to experiment with the platform?
Make sure you're not too hard on yourself
if it doesn't work. A lot of times,
companies I've either consulted with or worked
at, there was always pressure or there was always
a need to succeed at whatever experiment we
put into market. I believe in creating an
environment where it's okay to fail because
we're either winning or we're learning. And
more times than not, if we put something new
into a platform that we know nothing about,
we're learning the bells and whistles, we're
learning the functionality of it. Just know
there's going to be things you're not going
to understand because each platform is unique,
each platform is different, the user behavior
is different. So give yourself some grace,
understand that this may not work. And as long as
you're learning from it, you're going to be okay.
I love that. In terms of which platforms people
should explore, obviously there's Google, there's
Facebook, Instagram, what are the platforms
people should seriously consider at this point?
Google for sure. And when we say Google, let's
make sure everyone understands what Google
entails. Google is YouTube, Google is Google
search, GDN, Google Display Network. There's
a lot of things in Google that you can do. I
always say, if you have the creative available,
you should really, really be looking at doing
video because video is one of those things that
I'm very bullish on. It is doing really well when
you measure it the right way. And as long as you
can get that creative and get it consistently
just because you have one piece of creative,
if it's doing well, you do need to have that
creative refresh, kind of that flywheel going.
Make sure you're doing Google Search,
again, user-driven, YouTube, and Meta,
and Meta contains both Facebook and Instagram.
And then based on the data available to you,
if you do see users on TikTok, definitely
go after those. But if you're just starting
out and you just want to get your feet wet into
something, I would say start with Google Search,
then get into Meta. And if you have video
available, definitely get into YouTube.
Awesome. Okay. So Google Search,
YouTube, Facebook, Instagram,
TikTok. What about LinkedIn? Do you see
things happening there for say, B2B companies?
Yeah. LinkedIn is very expensive in comparison.
So just know if you're going into LinkedIn,
it's going to look almost three times more
expensive than other channels. The targeting
that's available on LinkedIn, knowing job titles,
industries, actually targeting people at certain
companies is very powerful. The example I always
tend to use is that I worked at a company called
SoftLayer. SoftLayer was acquired by IBM
because they were trying to build out their
cloud portfolio, couldn't do it. So they're like,
"Hey, let's do the next best thing and buy this
company." But when we were just SoftLayer, we were
trying to get Coca-Cola as one of our clients. And
you know those Coke freestyles where you can pick
whatever drink you want and put the flavor in it?
No, that's awesome.
Oh man, these are great. Maybe it's a cell thing,
but basically, you go up to a Coke freestyle and
say, "I want Dr. Pepper and I want cherry
flavor in it." Or you want Coke Zero with
cherry and vanilla in it, you can do that. It's
the freestyle you get to pick. The reason they
wanted it to be cloud-based is because there's a
ton of drinks in there. So you need to be able to
efficiently and effectively say, "This store needs
more Sprite or this store needs more Sprite Zero."
Because you have your whole portfolio in this one
machine, so you want to be able to update things
more readily. And it was between us, AWS and
Microsoft. And met with the sales team and said,
"What do we need to do to win this?"
Because it was a big ticket item for us.
And what we found out was they had two concerns
about us. It was recency and private security.
So what we did was we found out where the decision
makers were. So A, in LinkedIn, we took the anyone
who works at Coca-Cola, we want you to see ads
about security and recency. Outside of that,
we also geo-fenced it because you would think
Coca-Cola Atlanta, that's where the decision maker
sits, but they were actually in LA. So in LA, we
geo-fenced them, and we knew that they worked at
Coca-Cola. The next time the salesperson got on
the call with the team to say, "Hey, just wanted
to check in." He was like, "Hey, hey, I get it.
Security is fine. Recency is fine. We hear you."
That was great to hear because it was something
we were able to do on LinkedIn and we did it
in other platforms as well. But we knew we were
able to get not only to the decision maker, but
everyone around that decision maker to say, "Hey,
these guys may be the ones we need to go with."
Okay. So just to mirror back what you're saying,
you're saying you ran ads on LinkedIn targeting
the execs at Coca-Cola, trying to influence
them to overcome these barriers they had to
buying to working with you guys. Amazing.
I've seen people do that on Google Search,
but I've never heard of... It makes so much
sense to do on LinkedIn and it worked. And
did they know that you did this or they're
just like, "Oh, I just changed my mind"?
One of them was like, "We get it. We're seeing
it everywhere." We actually tried because at
the time, we didn't have an offline team. We
actually tried to buy the billboards around
the office as well, but I didn't know enough
at the time from an offline perspective of the
right people to talk to, how long it would take
to do it. So we were trying to pour it on hard.
That's incredible. I could see why LinkedIn
is more expensive. That's incredibly powerful.
And is the advice then that LinkedIn makes more
sense for higher LTV, higher CB type of products?
Yeah, exactly. I would not recommend
getting into LinkedIn and my LinkedIn
reps may kill me for this. I would
not recommend getting into LinkedIn
until you've tested Google and Meta
first. Now, you could be an enterprise
level company and it does make sense to start with
LinkedIn for sure, but depending on your audience,
I would say more times than not, it would be a
Google, Meta discussion before going to LinkedIn.
Okay. So just generally, start with Google and
Meta. Is there one or the other usually? I guess,
yeah, which one would you start
with if you had to pick one?
Always Google Search. I'm always going to say,
start with Google search, but it's also creative
dependent. If you don't have the right creative
for Facebook, it's going to be really hard
to convert because users are just going to either
be turned off by what you're putting out there.
And then also, depending on where your user base
is. If they're not on Facebook, it's kind of a
moot point. But if they're browsing around on
GDN or YouTube, it makes more sense to go there.
And then you said this insight about video
is performing super well right now and you're
recommending people use video. And the key there
is you need to be able to make videos, video ads.
Yeah. You got to make sure you have that flywheel.
And the flywheel is just people internally or some
company agency that can make video ads for you?
Correct. Yep.
Cool. I guess, is there any
advice there of just how to
do that or what ads work well or
anything there for someone else-
So yeah. The thing with YouTube is I always
say, start with emotion. If you can have an
emotional connection with the user, is
going to be way more impactful and way
more powerful than anything else. And to
take that further, when I say emotion,
I'm talking about comedy, I'm talking about...
I'm talking about happiness.
It's not necessarily just,
"Oh, we need an emotional connection with the
brand." It is just making sure the user feels
something after seeing your ad. Because then,
they're more times not going to remember it,
which then they will take a
favorable action after the fact.
That is super interesting. One last question
about platforms. Are there any other platforms
you see working for people that are emerging
maybe that people aren't thinking about,
Reddit, or Snap, or X, or I don't
know, anything along those lines?
When you say emerging channels, my brain
kind of goes to connected TV, podcast, VR,
advertising, audio/voice search, and even AI
stuff right now. I can tell you podcasts are
doing really well for the people that I know
are able to measure it correctly. Connected
TV is also doing really well. You can take
the, again, you're doing YouTube right now,
being able to take that creative and repurpose
it. But the VR stuff and the AI stuff,
that is stuff that is, I would say, very emerging
right now. Because to be completely transparent,
I haven't experimented with those things yet. I
kind of like letting other people be the guinea
pig and learning from them, and then if someone
comes to me and they're like, "Hey, we have
budget for this, let's go ahead and test it."
"Great. Let's go. Let's see what we can learn."
Awesome. Podcast ads. I'm glad you
suggested that. I'm a huge fan. Thank
you. They're working really well for a
lot of our sponsors and I'm very biased,
so you don't need to pay attention to me. But I
also think there's a lot of opportunity there.
Okay. Let's talk about when to start investing
in performance marketing/paid growth. So, say,
you're a startup, do you have any advice for
when it's time to start, signs of life test or
even... And then also, just when is it time to
scale to go like, "Okay, let's go big on this."
If you are a startup, typically, whenever I
consulted with them, it was what are the goals,
what are we trying to achieve, and when? Because
if you're looking for something quick, paid needs
to start immediate. And paid [inaudible 00:28:24]
started yesterday because SEO takes time. SEO,
depending on the market you're getting into,
if it's emerging, people may not even know
your product exists. There was a product I
was working on years ago that if you were
traveling to a hotel, and say, it was a romantic
getaway with you and your partner. And you wanted
the hotel suite or room done up with flower
petals, and champagne, and stuff like that,
they would do it for you. Well, they were
working with someone before that was like,
"Oh, we should totally be in paid search." And
if you look at the keywords that they were doing,
it was like, booking hotel rooms. It's like, "No,
that's complete disconnect." And they're like,
"Yeah, but we're trying to build awareness."
You don't want to build awareness through search.
You build awareness through display media-based
type media. When we transitioned all of their
money over at the time, and this will age me,
before Meta was a thing, when we transitioned
everything over to GDN, that's when the company
started really reaping the rewards. Because we
were building the awareness around the product.
So, it depends on what is the demand of your
product and market. If you're doing something
that is similar to another product and market,
you could do competitor, I call it coattail
riding. Say, Lenny, you and I create a product
that is similar to monday.com. We can go out there
and just start bidding on monday.com and say, "See
why Lenny and Tim are better than monday.com."
And start getting some people in interested,
maybe kicking the tires, starting free trials,
but they also have other keywords that they
can go after in market. But if you're going
after something new like hotel room, flowers,
and I forget what keywords we were bidding on for
that, it was years ago. People weren't thinking
of that. It wasn't something they were searching
for. So, it just really depends on, A, when do you
expect results because SEO can take time. And B,
what is the demand in the market for your product?
Some people use paid ads to drive
early growth to bring customers,
to help them figure out what to build kind of
pre-product market fit growth. Is that something
you recommend? Is that something you'd advise
against? Is that strategy that you've seen work?
Yeah. Product market fit is a huge thing.
We've run into some of this at Shopify, and
we definitely ran into this at IBM. So, for the
longest time, IBM is, "We're a global company, we
should be everywhere." But when we started looking
at the data, it was, "Should we be everywhere?"
For example, Africa, we were in the whole
continent. We weren't just in, say, South Africa,
or Egypt, or something like that. And the more
we dug into it, the more we realized the biggest
issue wasn't necessarily that users weren't
interested in our product and weren't purchasing
it, it was because we didn't have a product
market fit mainly from an operation standpoint.
In Africa, there are multitudes of different types
of currency. There's the franc, there's the rand,
there's the shill, and we were just, "Hey, USD,
thank you." So, of course, they weren't converting
unless they were going out of their way to make a
way to convert that. So, when we took a step back
and we said, "Okay, where do we want to start?"
It was South Africa. That's really where we were
trying to get, quote, unquote, "stronghold" in,
so we had to make sure we had the rand available.
Once we did that, we started doing tremendously
better because we had a product market fit. They
had demand for our product, and now we were
able to serve them, meet them where they were.
So essentially, you're saying probably not
smart to run a bunch of ads if it's not working,
if you don't have something people
actually want yet in that market?
Right. Or able to convert.
Because conversion is going
to end up being really low,
no one actually cares about what you're doing.
All you're going to do is really annoy the
users. Because, say, in the future they are,
"Hey, I'm still interested, but
I don't want to use that product
because I already tried." It's like,
"No, no, you can totally use it now."
"I already tried. I had a bad experience
with them." And some users will hold you
accountable to that. One bad experience
and I'm just never giving you my business.
Interesting. So, is that generally your advice
if you're startup, you're not feeling like you
actually have product market fit yet, should you
even experiment with and do signs of life tests,
or should you hold off until it's like,
"Okay, it's actually working, let's go."
From an operation standpoint, I
always want to make sure those
things are tied off. Yeah, it
doesn't make sense to, again,
if you have a major budget and you're trying
to get awareness into a market, great, yeah,
you can go after a market. But just know that
it's probably not going to convert very well.
Got it. So-
I wouldn't recommend it.
Okay, great. Awesome. Very clear answer. Let's
talk about the mistakes that you see companies
make when they're investing in performance
marketing. We got introduced through Casey
Winters's illustrious former podcast guest,
two-time podcast guest and asked them about
you. And he told me that when you take over for
an agency at a company that you've worked with,
you crush their performance within
a month. I'm curious to what you
see and find they are doing wrong that allows you
to be such a hero when you come in and take over.
I think agencies have playbooks. Now I've
worked at agencies, I did consulting for
a long period of time and it was never an
approach I took. I looked at each account
and each company as its own thing. But I think
a lot of agencies just come in and they go, "Oh,
this is like AB&C company. And this is what we're
doing. Copy, paste, done, move on." And they're
also not willing to get deep, deep, deep into the
weeds of stuff. I may get a little too far into
data than some other people. For example, I have
ops cadence that myself and my team follow. So,
within that ops cadence, we have things like
finance, performance, structure, keywords,
ad copy, quality score, targeting, et cetera, et
cetera. And then, within each of those we have
specifics. For example, the keyword subsection
is keyword granularity, brand versus non-brand,
search query reports, negative, so on so forth.
I feel like agencies don't necessarily get into
all of those things every single month where some
of those we're doing weekly, some of those we're
doing biweekly, and some of those we're doing
monthly. But they touch the things that they
think they need to touch. They turn on automated
bidding, they're doing their search query reports,
and then they just kind of move on with their
day because they have 50 other clients they
have to get to. Well, what about looking at your
conversions? Where are we converting? Have we
tested different landing pages? What is a better
user experience that we could be getting users
right now? It's a five-step process, can we get
it to a three? Partnering with PMMs to say, "Hey,
here's something that I think could help improve
our lead to conversion." Just stuff like that,
that they're too busy with too many other
things to focus really, really deep into those.
And typically, whenever I managed an agency in
the past and I consulted, I made sure that you
weren't stretched thin enough that you couldn't
do those things. Because I'm a firm believer in
hiring smart people and then getting out of their
way. But each week having one-on-ones with them,
just spot checking things, just saying, "Hey, I
looked at this. This doesn't look right. What's
going on there?" "Oh yeah, I do that on this
day." "Okay, great. Just making sure you're
covered." Because sometimes people won't
scream uncle when they should be screaming
uncle because they think it's a sign of weakness.
But let me know when you're overwhelmed. Maybe I
have a solution for you. Maybe there's a way
I can coach you to be better at something,
or we just need to hire more resources.
Because the client portfolio you have is five,
and when we took them on, they were all at 100K,
but now they're all spending 2 million plus.
We need to offload some of that from you because
you're doing such a good job that you've scaled
them up. Let's give you three clients instead
of five and hire someone to take those two.
So it sounds like basically they just don't have
the time to care and spend on all the things that
they need to be doing. And when you've held
companies, you actually go deep and you have
the time to do it well. I guess, when someone's
trying to find an agency or someone like you,
I know you don't do this much anymore. Any advice
for just how to know if they're going to be great?
Is it just agencies in general probably not a
good choice? Is it hire someone in-house? I guess,
what advice do you offer people that are
like, "Oh man, I want to avoid this."
Agencies are a good place to get things started.
Even when I was consulting, I would, honestly,
I'm a big believer in forward thinking, backwards
planning. So, if I'm taking this contract on with
this new client, what's the end goal for you?
If your end goal is to have this at performing
in $100 million spend, there's no way one person
can do that. So let's create milestones along the
way of making sure we're checking in and saying,
when is the right time to hire? Whether that's a
data scientist, whether that's a creative person
in-house or replacing me full time. There's no
reason that you should be holding a company back.
If anything, you should be helping them get to
that milestone. And I think that's why I've been
able to do so well for myself because I show that,
"Hey, I have the best interest for you and your
company." As opposed to how much more money can I
squeeze from you by holding onto you as a client.
I would say, agency consultant is a good way to
start. Because if you as a business owner,
you shouldn't have to log into, "Oh,
I haven't logged into Google in three weeks
to look at stuff because I'm doing payroll,
I'm doing HR stuff, and I'm meeting with
clients, and I'm doing sales." Start there,
get it to a good place. Create that milestone of,
"Hey, when we're spending 50K a month, I need to
hire somebody full time to take this over." And
just have that conversation with your agency
and your consultant. I think more times than not,
you will have a positive reaction to that. But if
you don't, I would say that's a major red flag and
probably someone you shouldn't be partnering with.
Awesome. Okay, so your advice is to get started
on paid growth, buying an agency or a small shop
consultant type person to get you started, have a
conversation. And when we reach a certain scale,
we're going to hire someone internally to run
this for us. And then, potentially, they'll keep
working with you. Potentially they'll start things
in their own. Or is the assumption they'll start
working with you, they'll become the owner of this
thing, or is it like we may transition you out?
That's a really good point actually. So, there
have been times where a client's like, "Hey, we've
reached our milestone. I want to bring someone
in." That person comes in, and say, they're an
expert in social media, like, "Hey, I still want
you to execute on Google and Bing, because that
is just not my bailiwick. I'll take over the
social stuff, but we do need to talk about your
fee. Maybe it does need to go down." "Completely
acceptable. Let's have that discussion, make sure
we're both aligned to what that should be." But
yeah, there have been times where they're like,
"Hey, we've reached our milestone. We got to
bring someone on." But that person that they bring
on is like, "Actually, I see expansion in this
direction, but I can't do this. Are you willing
to stay on, and help me with this? Great. If not,
I'll just have to find someone else who can."
I want to talk about the team that you build over
time, but later. But specifically, for this first
person that you hire, what sort of person is this
person? Is it like a data person? Is it a person
that's just done specific performance marketing
on channel? Or what do you look for ideally?
I'm a big believer in... There was a book written
by Nate Silver called The Signal and
the Noise. Are you familiar with it?
No.
So, Nate Silver is the guy who created.
FiveThirtySeven?
Yeah, yeah. And in the book, he basically... I'm
going to use the word art, I'm going to use the
word art, detailed the art of probability
statistics and applied him to real world
circumstances. It included case studies with
baseball, which of course I loved. Elections,
climate change, poker, stuff like that. And
I liked that book. It's kind of dense. But
the thing I liked the most about it was the
title. And just changing the title ever so
slightly to signal not noise. So typically,
whenever I hire people, I want to hire smart
people and kind of get out of their way. But
the biggest thing I want to focus on is what
is your thought process when it comes to data?
Because I can teach anyone how to do Google ads.
I can teach anyone how to do Meta ads. That is
not the hard part. It is the data part that is
the hard part because there is so much noise going
on in those accounts. They give you everything,
which is great. It's great that
they give you all this information,
but you can have someone that's "Oh, but
look at the reach, look at the frequency,
look at the CPMs, look at the CPC, look at the
conversion rate. Look at the cost per lead. Look
at the cost per MQL. Look at this." Hold on,
that's a lot of noise you just said. So what is
the signal and what is the noise? And let's make
sure we're focusing on the right signal versus
the right noise. And that has to be a data person
because there's a lot of data in these platforms.
\This episode is brought to you by Eppo. Eppo is a
next generation A/B testing and feature management
platform built by alums of Airbnb and Snowflake
for modern growth teams. Companies like Twitch,
Miro, ClickUp, and DraftKings rely on Eppo to
power their experiments. Experimentation is
increasingly essential for driving growth
and for understanding the performance of
new features. And Eppo helps you increase
experimentation velocity while unlocking
rigorous deep analysis in a way that no other
commercial tool does. When I was at Airbnb,
one of the things that I loved most was our
experimentation platform where I could set
up experiments easily, troubleshoot
issues, and analyze performance all
on my own. Eppo does all that and more
with advanced statistical methods that
can help you shape weeks off experiment time and
accessible UI for diving deeper into performance
and out of the box reporting that helps you
avoid annoying, prolonged analytic cycles.
Eppo also makes it easy for you to share
experiment insights with your team,
sparking ideas for the A/B testing flywheel. Eppo
powers experimentation across every use case,
including product growth, machine learning,
monetization, and email marketing. Check out Eppo
at geteppo.com/lenny and 10X your experiment
velocity. That's get E-P-P-O .com/lenny.
Everyone I talked to that's worked with you is
just like, "Timothy is incredible at working with
tons of data and finding the things that matter."
Someone told me that it actually comes from your
love of baseball, that you just go crazy with
stats and spreadsheets of baseball games, and
players, and things like that. Is there something
there that you could share that is interesting?
Yeah. So I played baseball my whole life, but
when you blow out your arm and you're as fast
as a sea otter, it's not very conducive for
you to continue chasing that dream. But the
one thing I always liked was the stats. Even as
a kid when I would watch baseball games on TV,
it's like, what's this guy batting? How often is
he getting on base? How many RBIs? Like, "Oh, this
guy is terrible average, but he has a lot of RBIs,
so that means if there's a runner on base, he may
not get a hit, but he's going to get that guy in.
So you want to make sure you put him in the right
spot in the batting order, so on and so forth."
I could talk about that for hours. But again,
that could be another thing where there's a lot
of data available, which one should you focus on?
And ultimately, what is the optimization you're
going to make to the lineup or to where you place
fielders on the field to ensure that we're doing
the right thing and becoming as efficient and
effective as possible? As far as dealing with all
that data, that is just, I would say, a skill I've
learned over time. Early in my career, whenever
someone was like, "Oh, we have this new project.
Who wants to work on it?" "I'll do it." I was
always just eager like a sponge. I wanted to
get in as much stuff as possible. I did SEO for a
portion of my career. I did email marketing. I did
affiliates. And then, eventually, I remember
the first time I saw paid, because again,
I was doing SEO where I was like, "Yeah, we're
going to do this and we think it's going to
work." But we won't know for about six months.
Someone showed me the paid platform. I was like,
"Wait, you know this is the keyword you're bidding
on. This is how many times the ad was shown,
how many people clicked on it? How many...
Wow, this is amazing. I need to get more
into this." And that's just kind of where it
started. And when I usually hire people and
we go through the interview process, I make
sure that they can be data focused. Really,
it's just ensuring that we're focusing on
that signal and not the noise. And one of the
interview questions I usually ask is I throw
a bunch of data points at them and then say,
"Out of all that, what would you do to optimize
the account?" And more times than not that they're
just overwhelmed. But the people that I like are
like, " Well, what's the purpose of the campaign?"
"The purpose of the campaign is to drive
conversions." "Okay, well, I would focus here,
focus on how many clicks we're getting, and
how many conversions, are we targeting the
right people?" Because who cares about how many
impressions you're getting? Who cares about the
reach? Who cares about the frequency? If the
goal of the campaign is to get the conversions,
that's what we should be doing. If it was
awareness, it's how many people saw it. If
it was a consideration, how many people were
getting into the funnel and are considering us
from a white paper download or a demo as the
product solution that they're looking for.
That's a great segue to the next question I
wanted to ask you, which is just metrics that
you love to focus on, pay attention to when
you're helping people with paid ads. A lot
of people think about CAC, a lot of people think
about return on ad spend, LTV to CAC. I know it
really depends on the goals as you said, but I
guess, is there anything that you find is like,
forget these metrics, these are kind
of the bucket that you focus on most?
Yeah, so for those metrics, I would say, I
really hope you have a great finance partner.
Shout out to Courtney and Nick the fantastic
finance partners I have at Shopify. Nick's not
there anymore. Sad cry emoji. But Courtney, we're
able to collaborate on those things. Understand,
this is the investment we're putting in,
this is the expected return, this is the
CAC that we can basically put a guardrail on.
You have to be within. So, hopefully you have a
really strong financial partner you can use for
those. But as far as the stuff that I focus on,
there are things that whenever we're looking
at accounts, we'll kind of hyperfocus on. For
example, Google will give you information about
what is going on with your ad copy and how to
ultimately show as often as possible. What
I'm showing here is a visual of brand versus
non-brand when it comes to expected click-through
rate, landing page experience, and ad relevance.
The reason I like building reports like this
is because it'll kind of show you where your
hole in the ship is. If you look on the left side
expected click-through rate, 75% above average.
Landing page experience, 84% above average.
Then you get down to ad relevance, a lot more
colors than there are green, only 35%
above average. So, for your brand ad copy,
the clear direction you have from the data that's
available to you is jump into the account and
make it more relevant. That will improve your ad
strength. And once you improve your ad strength,
that will improve your quality score. And more
times than, I think, it's a 12% increase in the
number of impressions you can get if you increase
from a below average to an above average for
the data that's available here. And then, on the
non-brand side, clear expected click-through rate,
you really need to be working on.
And that data is also available here
that you can kind of see. I put in red the one
for brand, your quality score being at a nine,
but your average CPC is $8. That is very
interesting. It should be, the higher your CPC is,
the lower your CPC should be. So that is an
investigation that's like, "Hey, here's a signal,
let's go do a deep dive." So there's further
reports that you could look at. Looking at the
ad strength again, average, excellent, good, or
poor. You can see clearly on the non-brand side
doing really well. They're doing really well here.
Most of their ads, 46 of their ads are excellent
and a bulk of their spend is going there. But
if we look on the brand side, you have one ad,
one ad that you could go in and just click pause
on, that is a poor. And look at that CPC $7.
So just turning that ad off by itself, not only
will... I'm a firm believer in that there's
an account level quality score, not just
necessarily a keyword or an ad quality score. So,
just turning this one off and removing it from the
account, this one ad could dramatically improve
your performance. And then, Google actually tells
you what you need to do to increase those strength
things. So this report is ultimately powered by
this one. So for your ad strength improvements,
they'll tell you, "Try adding a few more
unique headlines or unpinning some of the
ad sets. Try including more keywords in
your descriptions or your headlines." So-
Including more keywords in your descriptions
or your headlines. So they're actually giving
you this information, but more times than not, I
just feel like people are just missing this and
just not taking action on it. So definitely
some stuff available within the account that
will help you focus on that signal versus
the noise that you could be just getting
from the clicks, the impressions and all
those things that are available to you.
That was amazing. For folks not
watching on YouTube, you pulled
up actual reports from, I think, imagine,
past clients, is that what the data was from?
Yep.
Okay, so actual reports from past clients of how
you evaluate, and this is Google Ads, basically.
Correct.
Google Ads data. Incredible. Okay. And
so within those reports, you had poor,
excellent. How do you determine when something
is going great? Is that something you set,
like if it's above this threshold?
Is that a benchmark you have,
or is that Google telling you,
"This is poor, or this..."
Yeah, so that's Google telling you.
Okay.
There's sometimes where you'll work really, really
hard to take that poor to an average, that average
to an excellent, and there's just not a whole lot
you can do sometimes. It kind of is what it is.
But I would argue more times than not, people
are not doing those things to improve their ad
strength. So just if you have the change history
available in every account, in Meta, in Google,
if people are doing the test to try and improve
and get better, great. You have the right people
working. But if not, that's a clear indication
that there's definitely room for improvement.
Something that someone asked on
Twitter is for benchmarks around
any of the stuff. How do you know when
your CPC is good? I guess you just look
at... Do you look at Google telling you
it's excellent versus poor? How do you
know if your conversion rate is good?
How do you know if your CAC is good?
Yeah, every industry and every company is
going to be different, healthcare, lawyers,
those are some of the highest cost and average
CPCs I've seen. If I was to compare that industry,
say to a B2B industry, it would not be
very good at all. Honestly, what I would
tell the user to do, every single platform
has partners available, more times than not,
they're kind of like salespeople. I actually
really like the partners that we have at Shopify,
because I do feel that they are partners.
Shout out to Francisco at Google,
and Sami and Alana at Meta. And Nick, and
Sam, and Brian at LinkedIn, in case they
all hear this. But I think they're really great
partners, and they will give you that information.
They will actually say, "If you give me the five
people you consider to be your top competitors,
I will tell you if you are above or below a
certain threshold." Now they can't tell you CAC
because they would have to have transparency into
conversions. But click-through rate, conversion
rate, cost per click, things like that, they
will give you that information because they will
anonymize it, so you won't know who is who. If you
say, "My competitor's monday.com," they won't say,
"monday.com has a click-through rate of 5%."
They won't tell you that. But they will tell you,
"Of the competitors you gave us, and we added
three more in just to say, hey, we found some
people." And also to where if you only give them
two, you can be like, "Oh, it's one or the other."
That they'll give you that information because
they want you to succeed. Because if you succeed,
you spend more money on their platform.
So if you find out your average CPC is really
high, take the actions that are in the account
that tell you what you can do to lower it. But if
you find out that you have a lower CPC, you're
like, "Oh, great, I thought that was worse."
And then you can communicate that internally
to your team and say, "Hey, our average CPCs
may seem high, but in reality we got with our
partners, and we are on par with the industry."
Got it. So the advice is, don't
seek generic benchmarks for any
of these metrics. You can talk
to your rep at Google, Facebook,
LinkedIn, et cetera. And they'll
give you essentially the numbers-
Great summary. Yes, yes.
Amazing. Okay, going back to
the report you just showed,
is that a report you developed custom that
gives you, here's the most important stuff
to pay attention to? Or is it basically
an export from Google Ad Manager, and...
So these are all exports, so that this is just
the visualization of the data that's available.
So this all data is available in every account.
This is data available in the account, this is
data available in the account. Now in saying that,
there are more reports that we get into, like
impression sharing frequency. This is something
I tend to look at, that not a lot of other people
do. It's not about showing as often as possible
because that's what impression share tells you,
and that's kind of like ego marketing.
I want to be number one, I want to be
there all the time. It's about showing
to the right person as often as possible.
Instead of thinking about being on top of the
page, you should think about serving the right
user, which can be measured with our click share.
And then Google will put us on top of the page,
which we can see through our top impression share.
That's what this whole visualization is here for,
where I feel like a lot of people don't do this
type of visualization. And this can be done by
leveraging all the user data available on
Google, such as demographics, locations,
if any audiences, in-market audiences.
Testing different bid strategies and more.
So the data's readily available, but
it's just making the visualization
a little bit more digestible. And the
reason that I actually have two here to
show is because this is an example of when
I was working on an account back in 2023,
where we started making some changes. And you
can see that, clearly, our impression share,
I would say was baseline. It didn't really change
too much, but look at our click share going up.
Because now again, we're talking more to the
right people, not necessarily just everyone,
generic people. Versus this campaign that was...
This was the test and this was the control,
and you can clearly see that we were talking to
a lot of people, but no one cared about what we
were talking about. So this was an easy test to
call and just say, "This one's performing a lot
better." And then verifying the other metrics
still look good, conversion rate, number of
conversions, stuff like that. This one was the
clear winner, so we went in this direction.
This is super cool. I love that you're showing
this. And again, plug for YouTube to actually see
the charts you're talking about. I see one more
slide on this deck. I'm curious, what's there?
Yeah, so this one, I'm hoping you have show
notes that we can give a shout-out to somebody.
Yeah, absolutely.
Yep. There's a website called PPC Hero. What
I usually tell people is, "Terrible name,
great content." The actual website used to be a
little bit more cartoonish with superheroes on it,
but now it's, they've refined it. But the writer
there, his name's Jacob Brown. This is what he
calls the true competition metric. And again,
this is why I highly recommend we give people
the link to the article because this does get a
little dense. So what he does is that he creates
four new metrics with the Auction Insights
that are available. And two of those metrics
are position above rate when we show, and amount
of times they show and we don't. Added together,
and it will show how often a competitor
ranks above you in all auctions you're
available for. Using this type of lens is an
effective way to identify genuine threats.
Not that just, this data can be used to gain
comprehensive insights like determining your
position and impression share, but by creating a
baseline that you can see how this data changes
over time through different bid strategies,
keyword ad copy optimizations and more. This
is a very, very powerful one, because I do know
a lot of people are always concerned about,
"What are my competitors doing? How are they
doing it? Why are they doing it?" And with
all the smart bidding currently available...
Back in my day, it was all manual bid, so you
could change the bid ever so slightly, and then be
like, "Oh, now my competitor's showing above me,"
and this is even before Google gave us Auction
Insights data. This is now available to us in the
platform. Using this report will actually identify
a true threat, as opposed to making an assumption
based on personalization that maybe you're seeing
when you Google a keyword, or using a tool like
Semrush that ultimately is saying, "Oh, this
person's appearing above you. Well, let's run
this report and see if it's a genuine threat,"
as opposed to just maybe ego marketing going on.
Super cool. And this comes from PPC
Hero, is this what you're saying?
Yep.
Cool. We'll definitely link to
that. Are there any other tools
or workflows that you find really helpful
in analyzing this endless amount of data?
Please, audience, if you are using AI in
this way, let me know because a lot of
this stuff I do can be a little manual and
can be a little time-consuming. If they've
found ways to automate through AI where I can
provide the information that isn't sensitive,
that they will make it a lot cleaner, and a lot
more digestible, let me know. But a lot of the
things, I have templates that you can load the
data into, and it will just automatically give
you the result from it. But yeah, right now,
it is a little manual, but if there's a way to
automate this through AI, please, users,
contact me on LinkedIn and let me know.
Sounds like a startup opportunity right there.
Yeah.
Sweet. Okay, let's move in a slightly different
direction. Attribution, what a sexy, exciting
topic. So attribution, basically it's how do you
assign credit to a channel and to a campaign,
so that you know where growth is coming from,
what's working? What's the state of attribution
today? What do you find is helpful? How do
people do attribution well in today's world?
Yeah, I'm a big believer and proponent in
multi-touch. I fall into the camp of more
time decay. Historically, the research I've done,
users tend to forget very quickly where they first
found your brand. Yes, you should get credit
because this is the first time they saw your
brand or the first time they interacted with
it, for sure, let's give you some credit for
that. But definitely not the reason that they
ultimately converted. Linear is fine as well,
but overall, I do think attribution by itself is
biased. It does not answer the question of whether
the person clicking on or seeing an ad would've
converted anyways, even in the absence of that ad.
This is why numerous companies like Netflix and
eBay have done studies to get an understanding
of the incrementality of paid advertising
campaigns, whether that's conducting GeoX
or Conversion Lift tests at important slices
of the marketing channel. I know eBay was
very popular when they did that experiment. I
think it was like 2012, and I'll have a link
for you for that as well. Where they ultimately
decided to cut almost all of their brand spend,
because they found that users were already
going to find them through organic anyway,
so they were just kind of throwing money
out the window. And it was really hard for
competitors to get their ads at the top of the
page because their quality scores were so low.
Okay, so multi-touch is the way you like
to think about it. Basically give credits
to all of the channels that you
detected the user saw your ad on,
and less credit if it was further back in time.
Right, yep.
And then in terms of tooling, is there
tools you love? Is it stuff you build
in-house generally? How do people
go about doing this sort of stuff?
Yeah, I don't know if I want to
say I have been fortunate or not,
but most of the companies I've worked with, like
the big companies of the world, the Pinterests,
the Shopifys, the IBMs of the world tend to build
things in-house. So from a third-party tool,
unfortunately, I don't have a whole lot of
go-tos for that. So again, either that's a,
I've been fortunate or I've been sheltered.
And then, are there tools that you see people use,
or is it just really nothing amazing out there?
Yeah, none that I've seen that's like, "Oh
wow, that's amazing." I will always say, make
sure you're trying to leverage the in-platform
tools because the biggest thing with performance
marketing is the signal you're sending the
platform. Because if you are telling the platform,
"Oh, I want to get more of the users that are
doing this action," it's going to do a really
good job of giving you that. But if that action
doesn't equal business results, you're not helping
yourself at the end of the day. You're giving
it, again, a lot of noise instead of the right
signal. So try and leverage the in-platform
tools. Or if there is a tool you're using,
make sure it does allow third-party integration
through the Google, Meta, TikToks of the world.
Then let's talk about incrementality. You
mentioned this idea of how do you know if the
money you spent led to incremental growth that
wouldn't have happened if you didn't run that
ad. Is there any advice there, anything you've
seen about just how to think about incrementality
correctly, and not just give yourself all this
credit for stuff that would've happened anyway?
Yeah, I mean, there are many ways to judge the
effectiveness of growth overall. Like some of
the stuff we talked about before, brand metrics,
awareness, recall, things along those lines. There
are also, I know some companies look at leading
indicators like visits, and clicks, or tribute,
which of the efforts are linked to or perceived
drivers of actions. Like leads, conversions
to prospect, prospect to scale. But really the
results should be coming from either that GeoX
or Geo experiment or Conversion Lift. The results
of those experiments should ultimately fuel the
plans for what we call IAF, incrementality
adjusted factor, and will allow you to be
more precise and how efficient each channel is.
Ideally, by region, sometimes you just have a
holistic of like, "This is how Meta is, this
is how YouTube is." But if you don't have it
by region, don't fret, it's fine, just have it by
platform. And kind of like what does that look in
practice? When you're running a Conversion
Lift test, you intentionally do not show
your ad to some users when you win an auction,
and instead Google shows the next bidders' ad.
This is your control group, and adds up to some
opportunity costs that is estimated in terms of
impression share percentage, as well as spend
holdback. Spend holdback is like how much money
you will not spend because of this test.
And all of the platforms are willing to
partner with you on this, because Facebook knows
this, LinkedIn knows this. All of them know that
they are very visually-based creative assets
that are not getting as much credit as they
deserve. So if you go to any of them, if say
you don't have a dedicated rep you can call,
and if you ask for this, more times than not, they
are willing to partner with you in saying that,
if you're not spending enough, they probably will
not help you with this. Because there are certain
spend thresholds you do need to meet. But I would
say at least start there. And also if you're not
spending more than I would say 50K a month in
the platform, doing this is going to be a lot
more work than you're going to get result from,
you're just not going to have enough signal there.
So basically don't worry about running
incrementality tests when you're-
Yeah, when you're starting out.
Got it. Okay. And so basically to understand
actual incrementality, every platform has a way
for you to actually test it on the platform,
and the team there can help you run it.
Yep.
Awesome. Okay. Let's go back to talking
about team structure and how to build
your own performance marketing team. So we
talked about the first person that you hire
and the advice there was someone that's very,
understands how to find signal in noise. So
there's that one person, and your advice
there was maybe around like 50K. Was that
like an actual threshold that you usually
recommend, or is that just like an example?
Every business is slightly different.
I mean, if they're well funded,
50K may not... the threshold may be higher.
But yeah, everyone's different. 50K may be,
like if somebody said... If you were to just
say, "Hey, give me a number," I would say, "50K
to start having those conversations." Because if
you're at 50K, say for the month of June, great,
it's going to take us three months to hire someone
anyway, so at least start the conversations now.
Awesome. Okay. What do the first three
to five hires look like generally,
that you recommend for scaling
internally from its marketing?
So the first thing, like we said, someone
data-driven that can get into the platforms.
The next is going to be creative. Because I need
those two now working hand-in-hand, making sure
the creative is matching the tone and also the
performance that we're trying to achieve as a
business. And then third would be a dedicated data
scientist, a fully dedicated person. Because they
can help you with things like the incrementality
testing. They can help create reports that will
ultimately make everyone's lives better. They will
be able to build analyses that as a generalist
will not be able to do yourself. There's a
saying of like, "I'm not a data scientist,
but I like to play one online." Because what
they do, they ultimately make us look really
good. Because we're ultimately the ones reporting
on the performance of it, but they were the ones
that helped build that environment, and
build all those things for us to succeed.
And then in terms of the creative person,
is that like a graphic designer? Is it like
a marketing person? What's
the actual skill set there?
It would be more graphic design/branding. The
reason for that is because if you have a good
marketing mix, you're going to have... If we
keep it to a three-step funnel of awareness,
consideration, purchase, you're going to need to
build some brand equity in a specific direction.
You're going to need to make sure you're
communicating value, which now you're not being as
creative, you're being more directional. And then
ultimately the purchase is like, "Hey, click here,
convert now." So you do want to give them the
ability to still be creative. "Hey, I hired you
because you have a good creative eye and you're
good at what you do, but now we need to focus on
getting that person to convert." So you give them
a little free rein to be creative, but then you
also need them to be able to execute against that
creative, you need to get those users to convert.
And they're also writing the copy,
I imagine for the Google Ads.
I usually say that should be collaborative. The
performance marketer should be able to write most
of the ads, but I can't tell you how many times in
my career where I've written an ad and I'm like,
"This is the greatest ad ever written known to
man. People will write stories about this ad,
it is amazing." And it flops because I'm not the
target audience, more times than not. So I think
it should be collaborative, and no idea should
be left on the cutting room floor because...
Perfect example. I was working with ADT, the
security company. We wrote the most perfect ad
when Google Ads only allowed a headline and two
descriptions of 35 and 35. We got every single
value prop in there somehow, it was amazing.
And the ad that it was going against was dollar
sign, zero setup fee, dollar sign, zero install
fee. That ad won. It was like that is... No, how
did that... It barely uses any of the characters,
and it tells you almost nothing, but it won. Had
more conversions, a higher click-through rate. So
we took that, and we applied that with the value
props, and it did better. So it should never be
like, unless the idea is don't buy our product,
which hopefully someone is not writing
that ad copy. It shouldn't be left on
the cutting room floor. Always test it. Always
be willing to learn what works, what doesn't.
For this first hire, what's the title of
this person, usually in your experience?
Lately, it's been growth marketing specialist,
growth marketing manager, because they're going
to wear multiple hats. Like at any startup that
you're at, you're going to be asked one day to,
"Hey, I want you to do performance
ads," and then tomorrow it's like,
"Hey, I need you to help me build out this
spreadsheet for a spec sheet that you have
no idea what you're doing." So you're always
going to wear multiple hats, so just having
a general title like that to start out with.
And then if that person matures into a role,
you can make them more of a specialist. Or if they
start showing signs of like, "Hey, I really like
doing the social stuff, and we've scaled enough.
Okay, let me hire a paid search person." So yeah,
I always start with a general, and then as
the team grows, we get more into specialties.
So growth marketing person, it's
kind of like the broad umbrella.
Yeah.
And then are these people
sitting in Google Ad Manager
and Meta Ads and just like running ads manually?
At Shopify, we call it GSD, getting shit done.
I'm a firm believer in getting shit done. You
should be in the account, like I mentioned earlier
with that ops cadence, we have stuff we need to be
doing weekly, bi-weekly, monthly. The bigger
the company gets, the [inaudible 01:14:55]
you wind up in more and more meetings talking
about the things you want to do, and how you're
going to do it and stuff like that. But keeping
those people kind of sheltered away from that
and focused on those things, are going to drive
the best results for you, you possibly can get.
And that means hands-on keyboards in the
Ads Manager, tweaking things. Setting up
a calendar. I'm a firm believer in setting up
a calendar. "We started this test on this day,
that means this test will end a month from
now." Put a notification, so you have a cool
down period, and you report out to the org
what you did, how you did it, why you did it,
and then the results from it. And then, all
right, what we learned from this is this,
and we will be applying that to our next test,
and this is how. So yeah, hands-on keyboards
doing all of those things. So again, hiring those
smart people, and just getting out of their way.
I love that. In terms of how this team grows, you
mentioned when we were chatting, that you wait for
someone to cry uncle, to hire more and to add to
the team to kind of avoid bloat. Talk about that.
Unfortunately, we've seen a lot in the news
lately with a lot of tech companies letting
go of some really talented people, and that is, I
feel like just created bloated organizations. We,
every month, my current manager, Dean, created
this calculator that we look at that says,
"How much time are you spending in
meetings?" If you have any PTO coming up,
put that in there. Optimizations, reporting,
stuff like that to basically add up to how
many days are in the quarter? Because
every quarter... Well, not every quarter,
but most quarters you'll have vacation, or
you'll have, say, what we call a Shopify burst,
where it's we meet in real life to get shit
done in real life as opposed to remotely.
Put all that in there, and then what does
the number equate to? Oh, we're in the red
right now for these two to five people.
How many quarters has it been that way? Okay,
it's only this quarter. This quarter, we have a
summit coming up, or we have a burst coming up,
or we have a lot of travel because we're meeting
with partners, so on and so forth. So maybe this
is an isolated thing, let's go ahead and wait
till next quarter. All right, next quarter, it's
red again. All right, now maybe we need to start
having the conversation of, what this new hire
will take over, what they will be responsible for,
and how much work they'll be taking on and doing,
to replace some of this red that is going on.
And if it equates to a full head, great, we can
move forward, we've made our business case. But
sometimes it doesn't. Sometimes we're just red,
and we need to do a better job of making
sure, "Hey, we need to step out of these
meetings. These meetings are sucking out our
time and we don't need to be a part of it." Or,
"This launch, we don't need to be a part of.
We just need to be consulted on it. We don't
need to be in every single meeting every single
time, or every single communication." So just
making sure we're looking at the right things
before we decide to hire someone and making-
Just making sure we're looking at the right things
before we decide to hire someone and making sure
that we have stuff for them to do.
And red means they have more work?
Yeah. More days than there are in the quarter.
And so they basically estimate, "Here's how many
days I need to do the things I've committed to
for the quarter." And then it's like, "How
many actual days do you have this quarter?"
Yeah.
That is super cool. And so step one is, 'Okay,
if you're in the red, let's cut some stuff." And
then if they're still in the red and you've cut
stuff, then, " Okay, we need to start hiring."
Yeah.
That is very cool. Is that a Shopify thing
or is that something you do at your team?
I've done stuff like that at other companies
before, but kind of bringing it forward again,
I don't want to take the credit for it. Dean was
the one that brought it back up. It was like,
"Oh yeah, I used to do this. I don't
know why I stopped doing it." So it's
definitely something I've used
at other companies for sure.
That is super cool. You
mentioned this opps cadence.
Is that something you can describe just
what this cadence looks like of how you run?
Yeah. So I love me a spreadsheet. So
it's just a spreadsheet. And visually,
I'll do my best to describe it. Let's say column
A has those buckets I was talking about a finance,
performance structure, keywords, so on and so
forth. And then within those buckets ... Or
let's call those ... Everyone loves rocks
and pebbles right now, right? So that's
your big rock. Your big rock is keywords.
Then within that you have pebbles. Keyword
granularity, brand versus non-brand, search
query reports, negatives, so on, so forth.
And then within that we say how often we're doing
it. Are we doing it weekly, bi-weekly, monthly?
And then that allows us to ... If anyone in the
organization's like, "Hey, how often are you guys
updating ad copy?" Easy answer. "How often are
you guys doing search query reports?" Easy answer,
And it allows us to make sure we hold ourselves
accountable to those things because a lot of
times we have a lot we're doing, We're working in
Google, we're working in Meta, we're working in
YouTube. You could easily forget, "Oh, I didn't do
that. I got to make sure I do that again." So it's
a way to hold yourself accountable, but it's also
a way for me as a manager to go in and kind of
spot check that and make sure that they're doing
the things that need to be done in the account.
The core of this, essentially, there's
a spreadsheet that everyone aligns on
of here's when and how often we do
certain activity to operate this
performance marketing machine that you've built.
Yeah.
Awesome. And it's both internally so that
everyone knows, and then also when people ask,
"Hey, when are you going to do
this?" "Okay, here's the data."
Yeah. Yeah. So if a cross-functional
team or partner wants to know,
easy answer. "We got it for you right
here. Here's our whole opps cadence."
In terms of the team, something else folks
told me about you is that you're very
hardcore about training new people that
you hire. What does people mean by that?
Yeah. There's a book called ... I think it's The
First 90 Days, and in it actually has a graph that
shows when the person starts having impact and
how many days it's been. And more times than not,
it takes about ... We've all heard it.
90 days for someone to have impact.
I want to try and make that 45 days, if not
30. Most of the time it has to do with learning
the culture, learning the people understanding,
"Yes, you've done paid before at this other job,
but this is how we do it here." That's where the
opps cadence really comes in handy. It's like,
"Here's how often we do it here. I understand
maybe you did it monthly there, but we do it
here biweekly. And you're saying you used to do
it biweekly, we do it weekly and this is how."
And also giving them responsibility early on for
something. For example, Kat on my team was hired
8ish months ago. She was thrown into the fire very
quickly. It was like, "Hey, we have this campaign
coming up called additions. Here's everything
we did last additions. This is the results.
These are your responsibilities, these are the
expectations. Go. Go forth and conquer. As you
come along. There may be something that doesn't
make sense. I'm here by all means ask questions."
But what I've noticed is twofold. One, when
you're clear in what is expected of them, like,
"You are expected to do this when and you already
know how to do it. Great." Or also in one-on-ones,
I'll just open up the account and say, "Hey,
this is how I do it. Let me show you the way
I'm doing it and how quick it is for me. And you
can learn, even though we're remote, I'm showing
you as if you're sitting right over my shoulder
or we're face to face. This is how I do it."
So if you're doing something different maybe ...
One plus one is two, three minus one is two, and
that's fine. We both got to the same answer. But
if you're doing nine times five minus two times 12
divided by 15, nope, we can simplify this."
So making sure that they're efficient and
effective with their time, they're focusing
on that signal versus that noise and giving
them responsibility early on to really take
ownership of something. You can see that
people are a lot more quicker to pick up things
and start getting that flywheel going of, "Hey,
I want to have impact as soon as possible."
Versus, "Oh, hey, go read this handbook week
one. Week two, let me introduce you to the
team. Week three." It's like slow rolling.
"We can speed this up guys. We can get people
up to speed and making impact a lot sooner."
And also don't expect them to be perfect. You
can't expect people to be perfect right out the
gate. " I can't remember every little thing I need
to tell you, and there may be things I can learn
from you." I can't tell you how many times I'm
still learning from people around me. It's like,
"Oh, that's great. I didn't even think of that or
I haven't tried that. I should totally do that."
So just know that they're not going to be perfect
out of the gate, but giving them clear direction
and expectations, we'll get
them where they need to be.
I could see why your team is so effective and so
successful. This all makes a lot of sense. You
mind if I do a rapid fire set of questions that
people asked on Twitter about very specific stuff?
Yeah. By all means.
Okay, ATT, there was a huge change to
the way cookies and attribution and
tracking worked online and it felt
like paid ads kind of like, "Oh,
shit. That's not going to work anymore. It's over.
Facebook is dead." Clearly that hasn't happened
at this point. Just what is the impact that ATT
has had on paid ads and performance marketing?
We were just talking about this the other
day because we have ... Full transparency,
we have people fully dedicated to mobile
on the team, and I had reached out to
Sasha who's on the team and said, "Hey,
what are we doing with ATT? What are we
doing scan? All those things? Because has any
of our tactics really changed because of say,
low opt-in rates?" And the direct answer
I got from her was, "As long as we can use
scan to provide attribution and measurement for
iOS, we're fine." It's like, "Okay, that's very
straightforward. I appreciate it." So as long as
you're doing those things, you should be okay.
Amazing. That's great. So basically
the show goes on, things change, but
people find ways to work around it. Okay.
Creatives, how impactful are creative in
the performance of ads generally? Is that
like, "Holy shit. People are way under
estimating the power of a creative." Or is
it like, "Okay, it's like a fringe impact?"
Way underestimating the power
of creative. The best example
I can give ... Do you remember Dollar Shave Club?
Absolutely. Their video.
All right. There you go. You remember it. That was
creative. Now the person buying it may have
done a really good job of just targeting males,
but I would argue girlfriends at the time probably
would've been aware of it as well. Really good
creative should be doing a really good job of
telling a story. And if it does that ... Again,
going back to what we talked about at the very
beginning, if you get that emotion with users,
whether that's pulling at the hard strings or
comedy, it's going to have a lasting impact.
Okay. Chuck on Twitter asked, "When someone
steals your traffic, say in Google search
results and buying up keywords around your
companies, what should you do? Any advice?"
Yeah. So that actually goes back to the visual
that we showed and I'll pull it back up as I'm
talking through it. The biggest thing is just
know that anyone can do that. You can do it too,
if you are ultimately concerned
about it. But a lot of times
competitors could be doing it on accident. And
what I mean by accident is within Google, if
you're bidding on keywords, Google will do what's
called a close variant. If you were to do say
e-commerce solution, I bet you Shopify shows up as
a close variant at some point or Square or anyone
like that. So they could just be mismanaging
their account first and foremost. Don't give
them that much credit that they're doing this
maliciously or even doing it with intent.
And again, it will be in the show notes. If you
do pull this report and you do notice that there
is a clear threat that's going on here, first
things first, let's make sure that they're
not doing anything egregious like saying,
"Lenny and Tim are better than Monday.com."
You cannot be, if the brand is trademarked within
Google, they cannot use your name within the ad
copy. Google more times than not will disallow
it, but they could misspell it. I can't tell
you how many times I've seen Shopify spelled
with two I's because Google isn't catching it,
but we can always put in a claim to
say, "Hey Google, please remove this."
But if we do run this ...You can kind of see that
the orange line here, and for those that are just
listening. Orange line is rather consistent over
time. There is a two week period where it dips,
but it does come back up. There's another
line that at the beginning of this visual,
green is actually above orange. And if you look
at the green one over time it almost disappears.
So the reason I would say make sure you're looking
at this report, and it's not just ego marketing,
it could be an error. The issue could be
the green one, specifically, could have been
getting a close variant. They identified it, they
removed it. "Oh wait, a couple of weeks later,
we didn't fully remove it. Now let's remove
it completely. And now they're almost gone
completely." So make sure you're looking at
the data and reacting to consistent competitor
conquesting versus something that could just be an
accident or users not knowing what they're doing.
Amazing. And this is PPC Hero again,
right? PPChero.com or whatever?
Yes.
Okay, cool.
We'll share it.
Yeah. We'll link it to it in the show notes.
Okay. Last question. AI. You mentioned AI.
You're looking for AI tools to help you with
your workflows and analyze data. I guess is
there anything you've seen AI impact in the
work of paid growth and performance marketing,
or is it like in the future might, other than
obviously the algorithms on the platforms?
I remember having this conversation a couple
of months ago. AI, couldn't get away from it,
right? It was everywhere, and what we were doing
was leadership on know, "In all of our quarterly
planning, what are we doing about AI? How are we
using ai? What are we doing that's different?"
As always, I go to the partners and I say, "Hey,
what are we doing about this?" And Francisco at
Google, actually, he made a really good point.
"You guys have been using AI for years now. Smart
Bidding is AI. All of the recommendations within
Google Ads is AI. Ad copy recommendations is AI,
and that's always been in the platform,
so we've always used those things."
So it was kind of like, let's
reset the conversation of, "Hey,
this has been here. We have been using it, this
is how we've been using it and moving forward,
these are some of the things we think we'll start
doing." I do think it's having a huge impact from
a content standpoint and a creative standpoint.
Now, if those two kind of converge together,
you have a perfect storm, right? But it is
something that I keep a relative close eye on,
but like I said earlier, hopefully some of your
users can share more information with me. But
it's not something that I would say is overly
impactful yet, but I could see how it could be
used maliciously if you can do API connections
and things along those lines, for sure.
Wait, what do you mean by that?
Again, Google will disallow certain things,
but it takes time sometimes. If the term is
copyrighted in Google for ad copy, it'll disallow
it immediately. But say they need to do a check,
you'll see a lot of times under review or
pending in the account. But you'll also
see impressions potentially attached
to that. It's because Google's like,
"Oh, we'll serve a little bit of
it, and then if it's malicious,
we'll pull it back." I could see a way that
somebody could automate AI to where it's
always updating it to where it's like, "Oh, let's
just get a little drip here, a little drip here,
a little drip here." And that little drip
equates to a lot, but that's something AI
could help with a human doing that would just
take forever and be a total waste of time.
Got it. Just run tons of ads, just keep
trying, trying, trying trying stuff. Slip
through the cracks. You mentioned creative. It
actually came back to question I forgot to ask.
Going back to the team that you hired to run
this sort of stuff, you hire this one person,
growth marketer, specialist type of person, and
the next hire is a creative. What's a sign that
it's time to hire the creative person? Is there
anything there? Is it just like, "We have budget
and this is working?" Or is there anything
else of, "Like, okay, this is a good time?"
Yeah, if you're using a creative agency and
they're getting you everything you want and you're
happy with it, then it may not make sense to hire
a creative. But more times not what I've noticed
from creative ... Creative independence tend to
do better than an agency. The biggest difference
I see is that matching the right tone, matching
the right creative look and feel that you're
going for is accomplished way better in-house,
and also coming up with new ideas that you can
test quickly and iterate on versus, "We only
have so many hours with the agency this month,
or we only have so much budget we can spend
with them." Where if you have that person
in-house fully dedicated to the product
itself, you'll never run into those caps.
It feels like if anywhere that scenario
AI is going to empower that initial hire
to do more creative on their own, you would think?
Yeah. Yeah. And that's not always the best way to
go. I've seen some ads in there where it's like,
"Oh yeah, they're being scrappy. I see what
they're doing." But to your point, maybe that's
where AI kind of bridges the gap. Because I can't
tell you how many times in the past it's like,
Guys, we've got to be able to do retargeting,
but we have no creative to do." Google has the
dynamic ad builder and they've had it for I
feel like years now, and that was just like,
"Give us a couple of images and we will make a
display ad for you that should perform because
we're testing many different iterations of
it." Meta is probably going to come along
with something as well that it's like, "Give
us a picture of your product and we'll put
different backgrounds on it and test what works
and what doesn't." Things along those lines.
That makes so much sense. Timothy, we've
covered so much ground. This is everything
I was hoping it would be. Before we get
to our very exciting lightning round,
is there anything else that you think would be
important or valuable for listeners when they're
trying to do this stuff on their own? Any other
nuggets left that we haven't already covered?
Yeah. I said it at one point, but I'll
reiterate it. I'm always forward thinking,
backwards planning. Just as you're going
through it, "Where do you want to be and
ultimately how do you think you're going to get
there?" Because say your goal is to be on all
platforms. "I want to be on Pinterest, I want
to be on X, I want to be on everything." "Okay,
forward think. That's where you want to be. Now
let's backwards plan. "What can we do right now?
We can do search because that's only content
and that's keywords. We can do that. All right,
now we need creative, but where do we
start?" And then make iterations along
the way. It's just always forward think,
backwards plan, and that's for anything.
What are other examples of forward thinking?
Because in a sense everyone will be like,
"I want to be on every platform." I guess
what are other things that people think
about when they're like, the forward thinking
is like, "Oh, we want to win Google search." Is
that an example of forward thinking? What
else? What else should people thinking?
Yeah, exactly. What are those goals you want to
hit? One of the things that we look at is what
emerging channels to perform in it. "So what is
it going to take for us to consider this channel
a performing channel that is an always on, we're
we're adopting it as BAU? So that's going to take
a thousand conversions a month at this much spend
with this much lift associated with it. So okay,
we know what that looks like, so we're going
to backwards plan where we're going to start.
We're going to start with this one ad creative.
"Okay, that works. Then we're going to go to this
next ..." Because within each platform, they all
have multiple types of ad units You can use. Say
in LinkedIn, there's feed, there's conversation,
there's video, there's carousel. So it's what are
the milestones along the way that you're going
to do to ultimately get it from testing emerging
channel to perform them? So that would be an
example of something more micro than macro.
Got it. Well, with that, we reached our very
exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
Oh yeah.
First question. What are two or three books
that you've recommended most to other people?
Daily Stoic by far. A book I read every
day. Quick excerpt of what you can do
from a stoic philosophy standpoint. Great By
Choice is another good one. And Deep Work.
Favorite recent movie or TV
show that you've really enjoyed?
X-Men '97. Thoroughly enjoyed that.
But that may be a lot of nostalgia.
I actually never watched RRR when it first
came out. Highly recommend that. That was a
lot more enjoyable than I was anticipating.
The Playlist, which is about Spotify,
Welcome to Wrexham and Billion Dollar Code, also
on Netflix, about Google Earth. Very interesting.
Yeah, RRR. That movie is intense and
very long also. It's like, man, I
Three and a half hours.
... just have to split it up into different
days to finish it, but it is incredible. No
intent. Okay. Favorite recent product you've
recently discovered that you really love?
I drink too much caffeine and I've been trying
to cut it out and I kind of circled back to this
product I used to use called Magic Mind. It's
a little shot every single day. Tastes really
good and it does help with focus I find. If it's a
placebo, great, I don't care, but it's helping me.
That's amazing. I'm also a huge fan of
Magic Mind. I'm friends with the guy
that started it. So funny that
you love it. I drink it often.
Great.
I am on the subscription plan and
I think he uses Shopify to sell it.
He does. Yeah.
It all connects. Amazing. Do you have
a favorite life motto that you often
come back to share with friends or
family? Find useful in work in life?
Happiness is dedicated by expectations or dictated
by expectations. That can't be
more true more times than not,
and it's similar. That's why I said there's
two, and this one's similar to it. You won't
see it for what it is until you stop looking
through the lens of what you want it to be.
Amazing. It reminds me of an equation a
colleague of mine once shared. He wrote
a book of emotional equations or life equations.
It was happiness is reality minus expectations.
Yeah. Love that.
Okay, next question. Who's had the
most influence on you in your career?
Well, we mentioned him before, so I got to
bring him back up. Kasey Winters for sure.
We were at a wedding. He showed me the original
version of Google Analytics. For those of you
that don't know, it's called Urchin, and when
he showed that to me, it was, "Wait, you know
all of this information about users coming to
the site." I knew I wanted to do marketing,
but at that moment I knew I was going to do
digital marketing and watch him grow in his
career. He's watching me grow in my career.
We still balance each questions off of each
other. We cannot not have a phone call under
an hour. So definitely the most impactful.
Is there something about Casey Winters
that people may not know? He's a two
time podcast guest, huge friend of the show.
Casey is really good at tennis, like insanely
good at tennis. You want to know how good? This
is how good he was. In high school, he played
... I'm pretty sure it was our senior year. He
hadn't played in a year, maybe a year plus. He was
still ranked top 10 in the state of Louisiana for
tennis players. Hasn't played in a year and still
considered one of the top 10 players. Insane.
Did not know that. I actually played tennis in
high school, and so that's amazing. I did not
know this. Thanks for sharing that. Timothy,
this was incredible. I think this is going
to help a lot of people figure out [inaudible
01:41:28] marketing, run more paid growth ads,
figure out who to bring in to help them do this.
Thank you so much for sharing and for being here.
Of course. Appreciate the time.
Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
Lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.