You found that there's basically three
elements of most breakthrough startup ideas.
The three are inflections, insights and then
the founder future fit. Business is never a
fair fight. What inflections let the founder
do is wage asymmetric warfare on the present.
You reference this term that you
use occasionally, the term secret.
The way inventions happen is people get their
hands dirty, being awake to the possibility
that secrets are there. If you're living in
the future and you notice what's missing,
your intuition about what to build
is far more likely to be right.
This connects with that stat that you shared,
that 80% of your biggest returning
investments came from a pivot.
So startup never beats a big company by
executing better. The way startups win
is because it proposes a radically
different future. Disorients the
incumbent and chaotically moves people to that
different future. The rock is the inflection,
the slingshot is the insight that David
shoots at Goliath. We're looking to create
the conditions where we're going to get to play
an unfair game by unfair rules that favor us.
Today, my guest is Mike Maples Jr. Mike is a
legendary early stage startup investor and with
his firm, Floodgate, which was founded over 20
years ago, was one of the earliest pioneers of
seed stage investing as a category. He's made
early bets on transformative companies like
Twitter, Lyft, Twitch, Okta, Rappi and Applied
Intuition and has been on the Forbes Midas list
eight times. More recently, he's been spending a
lot of his time researching where great startup
ideas come from and what separates the startups
and founders that break through and change the
world from those that don't go anywhere. After
spending years reviewing his notes and decks from
the thousands of startups that he's met with over
the past two decades, he's uncovered three ways
that breakthrough founders think differently
and act differently. In our conversation,
Mike shares what he's uncovered along with the
pitfalls that he's seen many founders and startups
fall into, how to apply these pattern breaking
principles to large companies and so much more.
I've never seen anything like this sort
of research done before on early stage
investing and startups. And if you're a
founder, a product builder or an investor,
this will change the way that you think
about building successful products. Also,
as an added bonus, Mike has offered listeners of
this podcast a very cool offer. If you pre-order
the book at patternbreakers.com/lenny,
you'll receive a second signed copy
of the book for free. There are limited
number of copies available of this offer,
so if you're interested, I'd encourage you to
place your order ASAP. The book is coming out
July 9th. To take advantage of this offer,
go to patternbreakers.com/lenny. With that,
I bring you Mike Maples Jr. Mike, thank you so
much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Lenny, thanks for having me.
It is absolutely an honor.
It's my honor. What we're going to be talking
about in our conversation today is how to come
up with a startup idea and how to take the
first few steps to make that idea real. You
have a book coming out that is exactly this,
helping people understand how to do this. It's
called Pattern Breakers: Why Some Start-Ups
Change the Future. Let me just ask a broad
question. You're very busy, very successful
investor, why did you decide to write a book?
Yeah, a lot of things in life. It was kind of an
outgrowth of an accident and a outgrowth of being
down a certain rabbit hole. So about 10 years ago,
Twitch was acquired by Amazon for 970 million and
we made something like 85 times our money. And
normally, you'd think that's a really good thing,
it was a good thing, but I had forgotten
that I was even a shareholder of Twitch.
So I had to go to my LPs and I had to explain
to them, "Hey, I'm sorry I don't have this in
my financial statements, but do you want me to
restate them?" And they were all like, "Nope,
we're good. Just send us the money." And some of
them even sent me bottles of champagne and stuff
and the good kind. Then I started to
kind of feel a little bit unsettled.
So how was I shareholder and Twitch? I'd
invested in a company called Justin.tv that
had morphed into two companies, Socialcam and
Twitch, and then Socialcam got bought. And so
I just thought that was the company. I'd been
investing for about 10 years and I noticed that
80% of my exit profits had gone from pivot.
And I also noticed that all the ones that
had seemed to do well didn't necessarily follow
the best practices that everybody talked about.
I didn't see the Twitter guys doing the business
model canvas, for example. And I didn't see the
Justin.tv Team even as they morphed into Twitch
being who I would hold up as the most functioning
management team I ever saw. A lot of it was pretty
crazy and wild and random. And at the same time,
I was helping founders shut down their companies
and they had seemed to do all the right things.
They'd done the business model canvas, they'd
done customer development, they'd done all the
things you're supposed to do, hired well, they
would've been a Harvard Business School case
study except for the fact that they failed. And
so the genesis of this project was really like,
"Okay, should I just retire before I get exposed?
Is this just all random? Am I just lucky or is
there something else worth understanding?"
And as I started to develop conviction about
what those things were, I started to talk to
people about it. A lot of people said, "Oh,
you should write a book. Founders
ought to see this. It'd be really
valuable for their thought process in
coming up with their startup ideas."
This episode is brought to you by Enterpret.
Enterpret unifies all of your customer
interactions from Gong calls to Zendesk tickets
to Twitter threads, to app store reviews,
and makes it available for your product team.
It's used by leading product orgs like Canva,
Notion, Loom, Linear, and Descript to accurately
integrate the voice of the customer into your
product development process, helping you build
best-in-class products. What makes Enterpret
special is its ability to build customer-specific
adaptive AI models that provide the most granular
and accurate categorization of all your customer
feedback. And also connect customer feedback to
revenue impact to help product leaders
confidently prioritize things that will
actually move the needle for your business.
If you want a custom model built for your
organization so that you can automate
your feedback loops and prioritize your
roadmap with confidence, get in touch with
the team at Enterpret.com/lenny. That's
E-N-T-E-R-P-R-E-T.com/lenny. This episode is
brought to you by Anvil. Their document SDK
helps product teams build and launch software for
documents fast. Companies like Carta and Vouch
Insurance use Anvil to accelerate the development
of their document workflows. Getting to market
fast is a top priority for product teams. And
the last thing that you or your developers want
is to build document workflows from scratch.
It's time-consuming expensive and distracts
from core work. You could stitch together
multiple tools and manage those integrations,
or you can use an all-in-one document SDK.
Most product managers will tell you paperwork
sucks. Anvil's document SDK helps teams get to
market fast, incorporate your brand's style and
give you back time to focus on your company's
core differentiated features. For your users,
paperwork often starts with an AI-powered web
form styled and embedded in your application.
From there, you can route data to your backend
systems and to the correct fields in your PDFs
via API. Complete the process with a white
labeled e-signature. The best part about Anvil
is the level of customization their SDK provides.
Non-technical folks love Anvil's drag-and-drop
builder and developers love their flexible APIs
and easy-to-understand documentation. Build
documents software fast with Anvil, that's
useanvil.com/lenny to learn more or start a
free trial. That's use, A-N-V-I-L.com/Lenny.
Amazing. I'm even more excited to get into
the meat of this. I was already excited.
Before we get into that, just can you share
a bit about the work that you did to uncover
these insights? I know you have hundreds of
decks of all these early-stage companies you've
looked at, what is the work that went into this?
Yeah, so there's a movie that came out a few years
ago called Trainspotting, right? And there's these
guys, these dorky old British guys in anorak coats
who chart the comings and goings of trains like
it's the most interesting thing in the world.
They'd put it in their journals and everything.
I'm that way when it comes to startups. I have a
database of any startup where you would've made
more than a hundred acts on your first check. And
what I want to do is I want to get a time capsule
for those startups. I want to understand what did
it look like not after it succeeded, but what did
it look like at precisely the time you would've
needed to decide whether it was an interesting
opportunity. So I have the original pitch deck for
what was at the time called Air Bed and Breakfast,
which I foolishly passed on, and you seem to
have made a good career decision in joining.
Later, but yeah.
I have the pitch deck for Pinterest. I
have the pitch deck for all of these that
we either passed on or said yes to.
And the reason I want to do that is
it's easy to misremember how things really
happened. And what I find is even the founders
themselves, we have a tendency to remember
knowing more than we really did at the time.
And so I really wanted to do the best job I
could of understanding exactly what it was like,
what was the origin story of this idea? How
did they come up with it? If they pivoted,
what caused them to pivot? When did they
first start to encounter success? What was
the reason for that? All those things.
And I had to be really careful in the
questions that I asked because for example, you
don't ask, "Why were you successful?" Because
then they'll offer their reasons they thought
they were successful. What you want to do is
you want to say, "Okay, I noticed here's the
seed pitch deck and you called the product X,
but now the product's called Y. When did you
make that change? Why did that happen?" And
so you're trying to do the very best you
can of asking a very non-judgmental set
of questions that are going to give you a
non-judgmental set of answers so that you
can kind of be like a detective and kind of get
to the root cause of why these things took off.
Incredible. And I think what's also
important is you have access to more
data and more unique data than most other
people because you invest so early stage.
Yeah, I think the other thing is I just have
a pretty simpatico relationship with founders
usually, and so I can kind of push for the
real, and they're not... I'm like, "Look,
I won't share anything you don't want me to
share. I'm just trying to understand." And
so when you have these informal relationships...
that's the other thing I learned is you try not
to show up in a conference room interviewing them
like a normal interview. You try to glean these
facts over time with informal discussions
and in the midst of talking about other
things as well. And so I think that that was
part of what was really valuable about the
exercise was sort of the opportunity to get the
unvarnished wild story of what really happened.
Amazing. Okay, so let's get into it. Your
book's basically broken up into two parts,
how to come up with an idea and then the actions
you need to get right to move forward an idea,
and you have a really cool way
of framing how to do this and
then we'll get into it. But maybe
frame these two parts real quick.
So I'll give it my best shot. I mean, the main
thing is that business is never a fair fight. So
the incumbents start out with an advantage,
and the default is they will maintain their
advantage. And so the startup has to decide
that it wants to fight unfair. And so how
does a startup fight unfair? It has to harness a
different set of powers than are obvious to most
people. For example, better doesn't matter
when you're a startup, because better is an
extension of the present. Better is when you
think the future will resemble the present,
but only be slightly different. The way startups
win is by being radically different. A startup
wins by avoiding the comparison trap entirely.
So like when Lyft launched ride-sharing and
then Uber closely followed with UberX,
nobody after riding a ride-share said,
"Oh, how's that different from taxis?"
It was just self-evident how different it was.
And so that's what we mean by forcing a choice
and not a comparison. So the startup capitalist,
it turns out, is a different type of capitalist.
A corporate capitalist makes money by persistently
compounding, makes money by extending their
advantage, makes money by having a moat,
makes money by doing things well over and over
again in a compounding way. Startup has none of
those things. There's nothing to compound. And
so the way a startup wins is they just change
the subject. They deny the premise of the rules
and propose something completely different. And
that was the original notion behind pattern
breaking was you want to have an idea that
just radically breaks the pattern that can't
be compared to anything that's come before,
and that's when the startup
has a chance to play offense.
So coming back to the two parts are coming up with
the idea and the actions that you got to take. So
let's dive into coming up with an idea, and this
is where I want to spend most of the time because
I think this is where most people get it wrong
or everything starts with the idea. So I think
there's a lot of meat here. And what I love about
your book is you have a very succinct limited
number of things that you've uncovered that are
elements across successful companies, pattern
breaking companies. So within the idea bucket,
you found that there's basically three elements
of most breakthrough startup ideas. Can you share
the three and then let's talk about each one.
Yeah. The three are inflections, insights and then
what I call founder future fit. Or another way I
phrase it is, "Is this from the future." But those
are the main three things that I've observed
tend to suggest breakthrough potential. And
here's an important thing. You'll notice I
didn't say the implementation. So one of the
things that I learned is that if you have the
right insight, and we'll get to some of this,
you have a first mover advantage into the future.
And so a lot of times your first implementation
won't be right, but if your insight is correct,
you can navigate the implementation to the right
implementation to get product market fit. But
what we need to understand is there need to be
these underlying forces underneath the idea to
give it the power to escape the gravitational
pull of the present. That's what we want. We
want a set of powers that we could observe
that make it worth pursuing and make it worth
navigating the product to the ultimate place.
So let's talk about the first power.
You call it inflections. What is an
inflection? Why does it matter?
What does an inflection look like?
An inflection is an external event that creates
the potential for radical change in how people
think, feel, and act. Inflections happen
external to any startup or any company for
that matter. So we've brought up Lyft a little
bit ago, so maybe we'll use them as an example.
So the inflection that enabled Lyft was the
iPhone 4s shipped with a GPS locator chip. And
one of the things that that illustrates is,
for example, Moore's law is not an inflection,
an improvement curve is not an inflection. An
inflection, I'm a little persnickety about,
it's a turning point. And so in math, it's a
turning point on a curve where the slope changes.
But in tech startups, it's a point in time where
something new gets introduced that creates new
empowerment for the first time possible. And so
people talk about timing and why now? Inflections
for me were the unlock. You could have had the
idea for ride-sharing before the iPhone 4s, but
it wouldn't have mattered because the riders and
the drivers wouldn't have been able to locate each
other well enough. If you'd waited too long after
the iPhone 4s, it would've been obvious. And so
there was this window of time, this magical moment
when a new type of empowerment was possible for
the first time ever. And the companies that the
founders who understood that were in a position
to offer that kind of empowerment in the form
of a radical product that changed the future.
To make it even more real for people. What are
some other examples of inflections
either in the past, in the present?
Another example would be the cameras
getting better on the smartphones,
which enabled Instagram. So Instagram was at the
convergence of a few inflections. First of all,
there were smartphone adoptions. There were
just more of them. And so they crossed like
10 million smartphones, but then you had the
cameras getting a lot better. You had more of
them connected on Wi-Fi. You had the networks
having better upload speed for smartphones. So
all those factors converged and made it possible
for Instagram to offer a product that was good
enough to take most of your photos with.
You didn't start to think, "Oh, I need a
digital camera separate from my smartphone.
Now I can just use my smartphone everywhere I
go." But Instagram could have come out in 2008.
It probably wouldn't have worked it probably,
or it wouldn't have worked to the extent that
it did. Its window of timing was just right.
What are some other examples? The locator chips
in the smartphones powered other companies as
well, it powered DoorDash, Instacart. They
had different insights which we'll get to,
but there were lots of different ways to harness
that power. One thing I love about inflections,
and this kind of goes really old school, is just
because you have a power doesn't mean you know how
to use it, right? So the wheel was mounted
horizontally for 500 years before somebody
mounted it vertically. So originally people
used the wheel to make pots, and that was a
good innovation because it accelerated making
pots, but then somebody decides to mount it
vertically, and now you're propelling wagons
and you just change transportation entirely.
And so most people don't realize that the thing
that's underneath us or the thing that's in our
hands or the thing that's in our pocket might
have a power that when unleashed could change the
future. And it's one of the very special things
about founders that are great is they recognize,
they notice things that we don't know. All of
us tend to just follow the patterns we've always
followed because most of us tend to assume
that tomorrow will be similar to yesterday,
but sometimes the founder will notice
an inflection. And I find that kind of
inspiring because inflections are all around us
all the time, but most of us just don't bother
to look. Most of us are so busy going about our
day to day that we don't notice the emergence
of a new empowering thing right under our nose
or right in our pockets, but some founders do.
It makes me think about ChatGPT when it came out,
it was sitting on top of an existing model and
it just gave people a new interface to use it,
and all of a sudden, everyone crazy, they're
like, "Oh my God, that's the future." But it
was already there. You couldn't chat with
it the way that people wanted to chat.
Like Michael Saylor, once I was talking to him
and he said, the Romans could have invented the
printing press a lot earlier. They had sandals
that would make marks in the mud. You could have,
in theory, drawn the connection between
those marks in the mud and the ability to
have movable type and letterpress, but nobody
did. And so quite often these inflections,
they'll just go unrecognized for a while,
but they're always there. They're always
there. They're there right now. In the
ambient atmosphere, there's somebody
about to harness an inflection that most of
us would just walk right by and never see.
Wow, my mind is racing, what's out there
right now. Obviously AI is top of mind
for a lot of people. I know you're
stickler for what is an inflection,
what does not? Do you consider AI an inflection?
I would say that I would probably be a little
more specific about it. So I might say that
certain large language models are an inflection
because when I think about an inflection,
and one of the things I emphasize in the book is
stress tests. So it's funny, founders never really
come to me and say, "Hey, can you help me come up
with a good idea?" They would think they're weak
sauce if they had to do that, right? So usually
what's the more common occurrence is they'll say,
"I've got this idea, what do you think about
it?" And so what I can say to them is, "It's
not my place to have an opinion, but let me just
ask you, does it embody one or more inflections?"
And if it does, there's a few we could stress test
that we can say, "What is the specific new thing
that was just introduced? How does it empower
people? How does it specifically empower specific
people in specific ways? And under what conditions
might that empowerment be realized? And under what
conditions might it not be?" Because nuclear power
has existed for a long, long time, but we haven't
built any new nuclear power plants in 50 years.
And so just because you have a power doesn't mean
it's going to get used. It could get regulated
out of existence. Customers could decide they
don't want it. And so we want to answer all three
things. What's the specific new thing? What is the
specific form of empowerment it offers and to who?
And under what are the empowerment conditions? So
like with the selection for Lyft, the inflection
was the new thing was the iPhone 4s with the GPS
chip, the empowerment was you can locate anyone
within one meter accuracy with an algorithm,
and that's going to be pretty much anybody with
a smartphone. And that's a lot of people. And
in order for this to be met, people are going to
have to want to share their location information
with applications. The government's going to have
to not outlaw GPS chips and phones. Apple's going
to have to keep wanting to ship GPS chips
and phones. And we felt like those were
pretty reasonable bets. We felt like it's pretty
likely those empowerment condition will be met.
Amazing. I was just going to ask for
an example. You already provided one.
What about in terms of Twitch?
What was the inflection there?
I think there were a couple. The first was the
shift towards user generated content and sort of
internet celebrities. Justin Kan wanted to be an
influencer before there was a term to describe it,
right? He was really building the product
that he wanted for himself. But right before
Twitch or right before Justin.tv, which
was the original company, Time's person
of the year had been you, and they had YouTube
on the cover of the magazine. And so you had,
that was a major turning point in how
entertainment was happening. But simultaneously,
broadband penetration had reached critical
mass. The CDNs were getting really good,
we thought that they would get better. And so
you were in a situation where the conditions
to live stream video for the first time
broadly over the internet were being met.
Whereas you could have done that even two years
before. In fact, Kyle Vought had to invent some
pretty miraculous stuff to even make it work
when they did. But you could see how, okay,
once video starts streaming on the internet in
real time, that could be a thing. You could just
see how that would be a thing if it worked. And so
I'd say those are the inflections. Airbnb, company
close to both of our hearts for different reasons.
They benefited, I think from a couple things. One
was the proliferation of customer reviews online
and people's trust of reviews as a substitute for
trusting the brand of a hotel. But then also
Facebook Connect made it possible to pass
people's profile information. And so the guest
and the host didn't quite seem like as much of a
stranger as they might've. And so there were a few
things that happened at the same time, and then
the great financial crisis. And so you had people
upside down on their houses needing to find some
way to generate income. So all of those things
came together at the same time to help Airbnb.
The examples you shared are a good reminder that
the inflection doesn't have to be technological.
You shared a few of the categories of types
of inflections. Can you just do that again?
I love that question, and I'm glad you reminded me
because here's a really recent example. When the
laws were changed because of shelter-in-place for
telemedicine visits, it used to be illegal to do
a telemedicine visit across state lines. But now
all of a sudden with COVID and shelter-at-place,
not only was it made legal, but it could even
be reimbursed by the healthcare system. And so
that's an inflection because it empowers patients
to access more doctors, and it empowers doctors
to access more patients, and it also changes
the delivery mechanism in an empowering way.
In no event was that a technology change, that
was a regulatory change that allowed technology
to be empowering in new ways, but it was a
specific new thing that meets that condition.
It empowered specific people in specific ways,
and there was a new set of empowerment conditions
that ended up being made. And one of the things
that we would ask at the time was, once COVID and
shelter-at-place goes away, are they going to
revert back to the old laws? And if they did,
that would've been a problem. And so that would
be the empowerment condition, but it's a fairly
robust way of stress testing any inflection,
right? Is to ask those three or four questions.
So there's regulatory inflections, big changes in
regulation, there's technological, there's also,
I think you implied an attitude, like
the way people see [inaudible 00:26:35]
Yeah, there can be a belief inflection.
Belief.
So for example, during COVID, the amount of
telemedicine visits exploded. And so as a result,
there was a permanent change in people's
belief about whether they would want to do
a telemedicine visit. Before that, the technology
was there, but a lot of people just didn't do it.
The doctors didn't want to or decide to, or the
patients didn't want to decide to. But now all
of a sudden people were doing it, they're like,
"This is much better. I'd much rather do it this
way than go visit the doctor and wait in line
and all that stuff." And the doctor's like,
"I'd much rather do this than have these people
backed up in my office." I would argue that here
we are doing a podcast on a video platform,
even though it's not Zoom, I would say that
Zoom was another example. The idea of people
working from home a reasonable number of days
a week is a permanent condition, I think is
another inflection that happened with COVID.
And so are those the three,
regulatory, technological, and belief?
Those are the main ones. And I would say
that in many ways you could say that from
a macro point of view, it's two things.
It's technology changing enablement,
and it's people socially changing their
beliefs and their patterns of behavior.
And either one of those changes can be an
inflection because either one of those changes
can represent a turning point in
one's capacity to change the future.
Amazing. Okay.
... point in one's capacity to change the future.
Amazing, okay, so we've talked about
inflection, the next bucket is,
in the next element of breakthrough companies
that you found is an insight. Talk about that.
Yeah, so unlike an inflection, an insight does
come from the founders. An insight, I like to say,
is a non-obvious truth about how one or more
inflections can be harnessed to change people's
behavior. So in the example that we gave earlier
with Lyft, the inflection was the iPhone 4S,
insight was, oh, that means you could do Airbnb
for cars. And so, you had to have some type of
a creative insight to see that. Now, what was
non-obvious about it, or non-consensus about it,
who's going to want to get in a stranger's car?
That's crazy, right? And thank God ... I mean,
if there's one piece of goodness about us
passing on air bed and breakfast design,
Anne and I were like, man, nobody's going to want
to stay in a stranger's house, that's crazy. And
at the time, air bed and breakfast, the host of
the guest stayed in the house at the same time,
and the host would feed Pop-Tarts or something
like that to the guest the next morning.
This is right around the time of the Craigslist
killings and stuff, where this is just scary
and kind of crazy, couchsurfing as a service. But
by the time we saw what was Zimride at the time,
what became Lyft, Anne and I were much more
prepared to believe that insight than we
would've been because we'd foolishly passed on
Airbnb. So that's a really important aspect of
insights. So the insight needs to leverage
inflections, but this is the subtle part,
it needs to be non-consensus and right, not
just right. So in the world of opportunities,
if you're right and consensus, you still don't do
that well. And an idea that is right but consensus
has a couple problems to it. One is, if it's
consensus, it's probably not radical enough.
Because when you think about it, human
beings are conditioned to like things,
and so, if everybody likes your startup idea, it
means it's too similar to what they already know,
what they're familiar with, which means
it's probably too similar to the consensus,
it's too similar to the incumbents, and so,
the best startup ideas have this trait where
most people don't like it or are even hostile
to it, or just kind of meh about it. But some
subset of people are just like, where have you
been all my life? This is amazing, I love this.
They fall irrationally in love with the idea.
And so, most of the great startups that I've
seen have that attribute to them, and
the reason is that a great startup,
unlike a conventional company that proposes
the future as an extension of the present, so
that ... Normal companies forecast, they say, I'm
going to look forward from the present and forward
project what the future will be. Great founders,
pattern breakers back cast, they say, it's a given
that the future has to be radically different
for me to be a big winner, and so, I'm going
to look for radically different futures and work
backwards from those radically different futures.
And so, the radically different future comes from
that thinking different, thinking non-consensus.
And then, it's the different actions that
get you to say, okay, now I'm out in this
different future, but right now, I'm all alone
in this different future. I have to get people
to come join me in that different future, and
I have to find people who are ready to move
with me to that different future. And that's
where the pattern breaking actions come in.
And not everybody's going to move at first, and
so, I can't waste my time with people who won't
move, I can't waste any URGs of energy on anybody
other than those ready to move or are about
to move. And then, I need to co-create the
future with those early believers. And so,
great startups happen when a subset of people
in this world buy into the founder's insight,
and then move with them to co-create that
future. And then, eventually, what was a
heresy becomes the conventional wisdom as more and
more people start to realize the advantage of it.
There's so many threads I want to follow here,
one is the Airbnb story. Interestingly enough,
I had Jessica Livingston on the podcast recently,
and you probably know this, but Paula Graham and
her did not like the Airbnb idea. They all were
like, this is a terrible idea, we are going to
assume they will change the idea, but we love
the founders, we're going to take a bet on them.
So I was introduced to the guys by Michael Seibel,
who was one of the co-founders of Justin.tv
Twitch, and Michael introduced me to Brian Chesky
before they applied to Y Combinator. So Michael's
like, they're not even close to ready to apply to
YC, but he thought that I maybe would think that
it was the right kind of crazy. I get pitched by
a lot of ... I'm not very off put by crazy ideas.
I could see why.
And the meeting was totally discombobulated,
so room full of cereal boxes, I'm like,
what's up with this? Why is there cereal here?
And then, he can't get the product to work,
and I'm like, okay, that's okay, let's
just look at the slides. And he goes, well,
Michael Seibel told me that you don't slides,
you like demos. And I was like, that's true,
but it's not working. So we're like, 20 minutes
into this meeting in a room full of cereal boxes
just looking at each other. And you can't win
them all, right? You win some, you lose some.
I wouldn't blame myself if I
were you, [inaudible 00:33:37].
Here's the other thing that's hilarious about
Airbnb, so they do this thing because they can't
pay their rent. They put up this WordPress
site to pay for their rent because there's
a design conference in San Francisco. In the
meantime, they're brainstorming startup ideas,
so they wanted to do a startup together, but it
never occurred to them at first that air bed and
breakfast was the startup idea. They're like, we
just need to use that to make money so we can go
do a real startup. And so, that's the irony,
too, is that, you look back on it and almost
smile at the fact that they didn't know what they
even had at first, it was almost an accident.
There's a lesson there of,
you find something that works,
and even if you don't think it's a
big idea, don't take that for granted.
Oh, I very agree. And the other great lesson is,
you don't want your initial startup bets to be
too big to fail. You want ideas that are small
enough to fail a lot because you don't want to
be attached to success, you want to be able to
just try things and play with stuff and tinker
with things because you don't really know
where the fractal of new insight is going
to reveal itself. And so, there is a little bit
of play to this that I think is pretty important.
Do you remember some of the ideas
they were brainstorming, by the way?
I don't. I wonder if even they do.
Yeah, probably not, probably not.
It's probably in The Airbnb Story, their book.
I feel like them failing in your
demo helped prepare them for YC,
and that's what helped them get in, so I
think that you're a big part of their story.
And to make it even more painful, I'm in the
book. Somebody called my wife Julie the other
day and said, is that your husband in the Airbnb
story? And we get the book, and there's a chapter,
and it talks about how hard it was to raise money.
And they weren't dissing on me as a dumb VC,
they were like, look how bad we were at
presenting this at first. It was just a
complete catastrophe presentation. But that's
another good lesson for me, too, I learned a
very permanent lesson from that, which is, just
because the presentation's good or bad, it has
nothing to do with whether you should necessarily
invest or not. Sometimes you have to be awake
to the possibility of what it's going to be
regardless of how messed up the presentation is.
What was their evaluation at that point?
Oh, this hurts to ... I think he offered me a
chance to invest it at $1.5 million valuation.
But now they're a $100
billion business, I believe.
Oh, yeah, I would've made like, 6,000
times more money or something like that.
Okay, great, [inaudible 00:36:14].
Thank God I said yes to Twitter and
Justin.tv, and we said yes to Lyft and Okta,
because if we'd seen all of those and
passed on all of them, I'd be apoplectic.
I think that's what's interesting
about your stage of investing is,
you just need a couple to work out for you to win.
Yeah, that's right. And by the way,
it's true when you're a founder, too,
if you do this right, you only have to be
right once. And so, that's really important.
Coming back to the insights lesson, one thing
that you brought up when we were chatting about
this is the importance of being surprised and the
power of surprises. Can you talk a bit about that?
Yeah, so there's a couple of things about
insights that I think are really important,
and this is one of them. I believe that there
can't be a recipe for breakthrough. And why is
that? Well, recipes exist for things that
have already been discovered, so if I give
you a recipe for making a cake, somebody has
probably made that cake before, the exact way
they're defining it. And so, breakthroughs,
though, by definition, haven't happened yet,
they haven't been discovered. The general theory
of relativity had to be discovered by Einstein,
and the idea for ride-sharing had to be
discovered by the ride-sharing companies,
or Airbnb, by Chesky and Nate and those guys. And
so, what you want to adopt is the right mindset.
And how do you adopt the right mindset?
You interact with new technologies at the
cutting edge, but you actively savor surprises.
And when you think about it through the lens of
a breakthrough and what we just said, it makes
sense, because if you want to find a breakthrough,
you want to be surprised, you want to discover
the undiscovered, you want to know something
you didn't know before. Because if all
you do is an experiment that proves,
that validates what you think, you didn't really
learn anything, when you think about it, you just
doubled down on your existing understanding or
opinion. I learned this lesson from Scott Cook,
who was the founder of Intuit. Whenever he
would be presented a new product, people would
present the idea to him, and he would say, what
were your three biggest surprises as you were
coming up with this plan? And what he would find
is, quite often, they couldn't name any. And he
felt like when people can't name the surprises
they came up with, they're too brain locked on
what they want. They have the agenda they have,
they want validation, rather than truth seeking.
And so, if you're an authentic truth seeker,
you're always hoping to be surprised, and you
think of surprise as a gift, because you think,
wow, maybe I encountered that surprise before
anybody ever has. And so, that's kind of what we
mean. And you want to construct your experiments
so that you're in a position to be surprised.
So a good example would've been what the guys at
Chegg did. So Chegg was wanting to see if people
would do textbook rentals, so they created a fake
site called Textbook [inaudible 00:39:21]. But
here's where Osman and Aayush were very savvy.
Rather than just test whether people would rent
a $100 dollar textbook for $35, they tested an
arbitrary set of prices, all the way up to
$75. And so, they had the demand preference
curve at different prices. And Textbook [inaudible
00:39:42] wasn't a real site, so you'd get to the
shopping cart and it would give you a 404 error.
But we could tell that people wanted to rent
textbooks, and the surprise was that they would
rent them for more than we thought. We thought
we need to get at least 35, but some students were
willing to pay 75. And so, that understanding was
huge, if we'd only done an experiment to validate
the hypothesis of, yes, will they rent it for 35,
our pricing model would've been totally different
from, oh, wow. And when you think about it,
it makes sense, the student didn't want
to keep the textbook. Econ 101, I'm going
to give it back anyway, so 75 bucks is less
than 100, I can buy beer with the extra money.
So that would be an example of the surprise.
But most of the startups that have had great
outcomes, I find, there was a kind of surprise
like that. Being non-consensus is not the same
as being contrarian. Being contrarian is another
form of conformity because it's still relative
to somebody else. Most of the great founders I
see, they almost feel guilty that they found this
secret, but they earned the secret by tinkering
with the future and noticing surprises, and
having their noticing filter tuned to volume 11,
where most of us wouldn't notice it, most of us
would just pass the secret right by because we're
looking to validate what we think is already true.
You referenced this term that is also
one I love that you use occasionally,
this earned secret. Can you talk a bit about
that? It's basically the same idea that you
uncovered something by trying things that no
one else has seen yet. Is that the general idea?
So to me, secrets are earned. A lot of people,
I think, have the wrong idea of what vision is.
A lot of people tend to think visionaries as
like, they have a special pair of binoculars,
and they can look out farther than the
rest of us can. But in my experience,
that's not how inventions really happen, the
way inventions happen is, people get their hands
dirty and they learn about what's missing in the
future because they're getting their hands dirty
with what's new about it. And so, they earn the
secret by going down this rabbit hole of exploring
something at the cutting edge for its own sake.
And just like I'm a trained spotter for startups,
they become a trained spotter for this new thing
that they're excited about. And they frustrate the
people around them, they'll be at a party, and
everybody's talking about the basketball game,
the Celtics against the Mavs, and somehow that
reminds them of the fact that they want to test
prices for textbook [inaudible 00:42:17]. But
they're that interested, it's the last thing
they think about when they go to bed, the first
thing they think about when they wake up. And so,
that's where I find most of the really great
earned secrets come from, they're earned in
the sense that you earn them by getting your
hands dirty, and you earn them by being awake
to the possibility that secrets are there
or that just most people aren't looking.
This connects with that stat
that you shared, that 80% of
your biggest returning investments
came from a pivot. It all connects,
where you're just trying stuff, you're
learning, seeing things people haven't tried.
That's right, and in the early days of product
market fit, I like to say we want to answer a
very simple but profound question. What can we
uniquely offer that people are desperate for? And
if we have an insight, that makes us unique.
Now, if a customer doesn't like your idea,
a couple of things could be true. One is, your
insight could be wrong. If your insight's wrong,
you don't have a startup, you should just stop.
The other thing, though, that could be true is,
your implementation is wrong. So you had
the right insight. So like Okta, at first,
they wanted to do cloud systems management, they
thought that they needed to do problem resolution,
but when they showed it to customers, they
were kind of meh about it. And they said,
well, why are you meh about this? And they said,
well, it's not a top priority. And they said,
what is your top priority? And
they said, identity management.
So they had the right insight, which was,
customers would struggle to manage cloud services,
but they had the wrong implementation of the
insight, so then they came back with identity
management, and it worked. So if somebody doesn't
like your idea, if they're not desperate for it,
either the insight's wrong, the implementation's
wrong, or you could be talking to the wrong
customer. Some people that Okta talked to wanted
to integrate it with on-prem software. And in
that case, their opinion's irrelevant because
they're not an innovative customer, they're not
living in the future, they're not going to give
you product requirement ideas that are additive
to your strategy. And so, you want to be, right
insight, right inflections, right implementation,
right early believers that you're talking to, as
you iterate towards product market fit. And if
you're not succeeding at product market fit, then
one or more of those variables isn't working yet.
I think this might be a good time to
remind people that you don't need to
have every one of these for your business to
potentially be a huge success. It's more that,
the more you have, the more likely it is that
you will find something massive. Is that right?
That's right. And this is the hard part about
being non-consensus and right is, you don't
know for sure that you're right at first, you
only know that you're non-consensus. And so,
you have to be willing to risk being wrong to be
spectacularly right. And so, what you're trying
to do, though, is pursue opportunities where
the odds are massively in your favor. And so,
I kind of return back to, business is never
a fair fight. And so, if I'm a founder,
there's a universe of ideas I can pursue. The
mistake that a lot of founders make, and it's very
understandable, they say, I want to go after big
market opportunities. So they analyze big markets,
they find unserved customers with unmet needs
in under-addressed markets, so then they go
build a product to go solve that problem.
And that's very appealing, because it seems
obvious, and the dots connect forward in an
obvious way. But unwittingly, it buys into a
context, it buys into the current definition
of the market, which was already set by the
incumbents. And so, what you instead want to do
is pursue a slightly more ambiguous opportunity,
but one that harnesses these powers. Ones
where you look at the inflection and you say,
wow, that's really powerful, you look
at the insight, and you say, yeah,
I know that this is going to be, in the future,
I know that this is where things are going to be
radically different someday. I would rather have
those things present and be willing to pivot the
product than not have those things and have a
much clearer idea of what the product should be.
Funny enough, one of my biggest investment
successes that exactly what you're saying
you shouldn't do, which is, they looked at a huge
market with a bad incumbent and built something
better, and it's working. But I think, again,
it's not that you can't win that way, your point
and your research shows that your chances are
a lot higher doing something totally different.
That's right, and I would bet that this
company ... I don't know enough about it,
I don't know what it is, but it wouldn't
surprise me if they harnessed inflections
in some way that was disorienting to the
incumbent. It wouldn't surprise me if they
found a way to use inflections to fight an unfair
fight. What I try to do with the insights is,
I realized there was a theory behind it. A theory
is not a recipe, it's an explanation. And what
inflections let the founder do is wage asymmetric
warfare on [inaudible 00:47:11]. And the insight
is the vessel that they use, right? It's kind of
like, the rock is the inflection, the slingshot
is the insight that David shoots at Goliath. And
so, that's what we're looking for, we're looking
to create the conditions where we're going to get
to play an unfair game by unfair rule to favor us.
Great segue to the third bucket and the third
element of Breakthrough Company's
Future-Founder Fit. What is that?
Yeah, so this is one of my favorites.
So a lot of times, people will say,
what makes a great founder? And there are some
common traits, passion for the idea, persistence,
resilience, all these things that people talk
about, passion for the users. But what I find
is that there's no canonical best founder. So Marc
Andreessen started Netscape as a programmer making
minimum wage at the University of Illinois.
And everybody thought the digital highway
at the time was going to come from Time Warner or
from Microsoft Network or from the US government,
nobody thought that some kid was going to do it
from the bottoms up. But it turns out that Marc
was tinkering with a set of inflections around
the World Wide Web. And right around that time,
Microsoft introduced a better version
of Windows, and right around that time,
the Pentium processor came out, so there were more
and more people [inaudible 00:48:36] graphical
user interface computers at the very
time that browsing started to happen.
But let's take another company more recent,
Applied Intuition, makes simulation software
for autonomous vehicles. If you're going to sell
a giant contract to the CEO of a car company,
he needs to look at you across the table and
think, these guys can do the job. So Qasar and
Peter, they'd grown up in Detroit in Michigan,
they had worked at car companies in the past,
in the big three, and then, they worked
inside of Google at Waymo and Google Maps.
And they'd had a successful startup before,
and so if you looked, what is a team from
Central Casting to do this, it would be them.
And so, what I mean by Founder-Future Fit is,
there's a set of traits that a founder can
have that make them ideally suited to a certain
type of future. Sometimes they're really young
first-time founders, Mark Zuckerberg, Bill Gates,
Paul Allen, we just gave the example of Marc
Andreessen. In that case, usually they're at
the cutting edge of a new technology and they have
a beginner's mind, and they aren't even encumbered
by the old way of looking things. It's like, the
entire world lives in Cartesian coordinates and
they discover polar coordinates, and they don't
even have to translate between the two because
they never understood Cartesian coordinates.
And so, in that case, their knowledge about
the future is more valuable to success than
their knowledge as business people. But in the
case of Applied Intuition, if you're selling
very large contracts to enterprise customers,
they need to believe that you could do the job. If
you're Okta and you're doing identity management
for cloud customers, they're going to trust Todd
McKinnon from Salesforce way before they're going
to trust a college dropout to do that job.
And so, I like to say Founder-Future Fit is,
who knows the most about this future? Who has
the most intrinsic motivation to pursue it? Who
has the best network and keeps the best company
in that ecosystem of the future? Those are the
types of things that ... Founders that show
up differently on those dimensions usually do
better because they're more likely to understand
what to build in the first place, and they're
more likely to convince early believers to
believe in their ideas in the first place.
So it's not that these people have some vision
of the future that is more accurate or more
incredible than everyone else, it's that their
background, and even the way they look, matches
the problem that they're going after. So in this
Applied Intuition case, you're saying the founders
look like people that a CEO of GM would be like,
I trust these people to build this thing for me.
Yeah, Louis Pasteur once said, chance favors the
prepared mind. And when I started working on this
book, for the first time, I really understood
what he meant. Chance favors the prepared mind
because a prepared mind attracts luck. A prepared
mind is better positioned to notice a breakthrough
than other minds. And a prepared mind sees
the breakthrough, sees around the corner,
because they're thinking about the subject all
the time. And so, most people think that the way
you come up with good startup ideas is to try
to think of a startup. And I like to say, no,
that's exactly wrong, what you do to come up with
great startup ideas is, you live in the future,
and you notice what's missing in the future. And
it's axiomatic, if you're living in the future,
there will be unbuilt, missing things, because if
it was all built, you'd be living in the present.
And so, if you're living in the future and you
notice what's missing, your intuition about
what to build is far more likely to be right.
So Andreessen didn't do the Mosaic browser because
he thought there was a market for browsers.
He didn't even know about a digital highway,
he was trying to make the internet immediately
more useful for him and his team. And his
intuition about what to build was very good
because he was building the thing he wanted that
was missing in the world. In the case of Okta,
they knew all the early Salesforce customers,
but the principle still applies,
those customers weren't equal,
they were lighthouse customers. It was kind of
like when I was at Silicon Graphics, I didn't
spend time with normal movie studios, I spent time
with industrial Light & Magic, because I thought,
if we solve their problem, they're going to
take us to the Promised Land. All the stuff
we build for Industrial Light & Magic will be
the stuff that everybody wants someday. And so,
not all customers are equal, you want to
find customers that live in the future.
I love this point. Justin.tv is
another great example of this,
where he just assumed the future, everyone's
going to be watching each other's reality show,
so he built his own backpack with a camera
[inaudible 00:53:34] just to stream himself.
Yeah, and the Justin.tv example is a great one,
too, because in Justin.tv, he built the thing
that he wished he had, even though it was a
terrible idea. But it embodied attributes,
it embodied these inflections of these insights
that led them ultimately to Twitch. Ironically,
Justin's second company, Atrium, most people
thought that that made sense, automating legal
tasks. And Justin's a great founder, but
Justin just didn't like the legal field,
he had no passion for it. When he started Atrium,
his passion was to be a higher status founder.
And I've got a podcast with him recently
where he talks about this, where he's like,
I wanted to be as big as Patrick Collison and
Brian Chesky and Drew Houston. But it turns out,
that's not a very good reason to start a
company. Founder-Future Fit is ultimately
about authenticity, and it's about, who is the
most authentically matched for that different
radical future? And whoever that team is has
a really big head start at getting product
market fit. And product market fit is
the game, whoever gets it first wins.
This episode is brought to you by
Webflow. We're all friends here,
so let's be real for a second. We all know
that your website shouldn't be a static asset,
it should be a dynamic part of your strategy
that drives conversions. That's Business 101.
But here's a number for you. 54% of leaders
say web updates take too long. That's over
half of you listening right now. That's where
Webflow comes in. Their visual first platform
allows you to build, launch, and optimize web
pages fast. That means you can set ambitious
business goals, and your site can rise to
the challenge. Learn how teams like Dropbox,
IDEO and Orangetheory trust Webflow to achieve
their most ambitious goals today, at webflow.com.
Okay, so there's inflections, there's
insights, there's Future-Founder Fit,
to make this super real for, say, a product
manager sitting at a company right now,
I want to start a startup, or someone just
starting to ideate on ideas, what are some
things that you recommend they start to do this
week, next month, to start to find a big idea,
or to start an idea? It doesn't have to be a
big idea, an idea that'll take them somewhere.
The number one thing I like to say
is, get out of the present. And so,
people talk about getting out of the building,
and of course, we should, but getting out of the-
And of course we should, but getting out of the
present is a little bit more subtle than that,
right? So William Gibson was right when he said,
"The future is already here. It's just not evenly
distributed." So most great startup ideas come
from a future that exists right now today. And
so what I like to say to people, and this is
a question that I always ask when I'm pitched,
"Is this from the future?" And then some
people will say to me like, "Hey, I have a
mental health startup. Mental health is a huge
problem. It needs to be solved." And I'll say,
"Why is your idea from the future?" "Well in
the future I believe mental health needs to
be solved." I'm like, "That's not what I'm
asking. I'm asking what part of the future
have you been living in that gives you the
right to have an opinion about the future?"
So I like to say, "If you're not living in the
future, your opinion about it isn't valid."
It's like saying, "I think a customer will do X."
And you've never talked to a customer. I'm like,
"Okay, your opinion's interesting but irrelevant."
And so the only relevant opinions about the future
come from people who are living in it and
coming from people who understand what's
new about it in a very visceral way. And
there are people who do a good job of this,
like Maddie Hall who started Living Carbon. She
was working at Zenefit and at first she tried to
think of a startup and she had ideas that weren't
that good. She had a laser tag idea and a few
other things. But then she decided to go follow
Sam Altman for a year to be his chief of staff.
And Sam Altman visits the future multiple times
a day with people. And so that's what led her
to this idea that for Living Carbon, which does
genetically modified trees. I mean, it couldn't
be farther away from Zenefit, right? But
she saw Microsoft was about to spend a lot
of money, a bunch of other companies about
to spend a lot of money on carbon takeout.
She saw that the genetic engineering technology
was getting good enough that you could engineer
these trees. She married the inflections
with the need and then off she went. But
she was basically sampling a lot of different
futures until she found one that she liked.
I love that example because it makes
it very real what living in the future
looks like. So one is spend time with
people that are very far along on some
edge of technology or the way people behave.
Another you shared is a work with a company,
say that you work with a silicon
graphics industrial related magic...
[inaudible 00:58:34] magic.
Yeah.
Yeah. So McCracken had a term for it that I've
always liked lighthouse customers. And so the
lighthouse has this light that shines out
and obscures the fog. And not all customers
are equal and some customers are living in the
future and those customers are gold. And those
customers will, if you solve their needs, take
you to the promise land. So yeah, you can build
what's missing for yourself like Andreessen did
or Zuckerberg or Steve Wozniak or Bill Gates,
or you can build something for lighthouse
customers you have a good relationship
with. Or if you can do neither of those things,
the number one question I get asked is, "Hey,
that's great if you live in a supercomputer
lab or if you were selling to Industrial Light
or Magic or all the Salesforce customer. I'm
not one of those. I'm a second year student
at Stanford Business School. I'm a product
manager at company X, I'm whatever the case
may be. That's where the Maddie Hall example
is really powerful. Because Maddie proactively
got out of the present in a very intentional
way. So I love her example as a case study.
What signs tell you that a company is one
of these lighthouse companies living in
the future or a person is just like, you just
feel it, they're so far ahead of everyone else.
Usually it has to do with how tech forward
they are. There was a time when a lot of
people didn't think the cloud was going
to be a thing because it was insecure.
And I'm not going to host my important
data and let somebody else have it. But
there were a set of customers who really
excited about the cloud and they tended
to adopt certain kinds of products. When
I used to work in client server startups,
you knew that the early adopters were people
who were using relational database servers
and scalable front end programming interfaces and
things like that, were trying to have distributed
apps that they would roll out. You could tell who
was trying to play offense with the new trends.
Awesome. Okay, before we move on into actions,
is there anything else you think might be
useful to share in terms of helping people
come up with an idea, find a great idea?
The number one thing about the ideas goes back
to the not playing the comparison game. So
the thing that I see people underestimate
when they come up with ideas is the threshold
of desperation required in the customer. So we
want to solve problems for desperate people and
it's like if we have powerful inflections that
really empower and we have something unique,
there should be somebody who is irresistibly
drawn to that empowerment. They should say,
"Oh my God, this is incredible. This is a
game changer. I can't unsee that." Why is
that important? I like to say that if a customer
has the ability to do something other than what
you do to solve their problem, they won't be crazy
enough to do business with a startup. So customer
has to be so desperate that when they see what
you have, they're like, "I've got to have it."
And so I like to say, "You want to force a choice
and not a comparison." If everybody's selling
apples, I can't be a 10 times better Apple. I want
to be the world's first banana. And I want to say
to people, " You may not want bananas, you may
not like them, you may not value the advantage
of bananas, but if you value banana-ness, I'm
the only person that's got it." It's like,
"Come to papa." And so that's like an insight
feels like that. And in the early days, don't
spend any of your time with people who love apples
because you're not going to convince them and
they're going to waste your time. What you want
to do is find everybody in the world that values
the advantages of bananas as soon as possible,
not wasting any time on the people who don't.
And so I'd say that that kind of wraps up the idea
of insights is it like we want to force a choice
and not a comparison. Nobody looks at the Tesla
cyber truck and says, oh yeah, well how does that
compare to Ford F-150? And you may hate the cyber
truck, you may think it's stupid, but nobody's
neutral about the cyber truck. You want to have
a product that people can't be neutral about,
but that the people who magnetize positively
to it just can't imagine a world without.
I love that. And going back to your banana
example, you want just a few people to
be just like, "I need that banana."
No matter how much you're charging.
That's right. And even if it's halfway ripe,
because that's the other thing, they need to
be willing to tolerate the fact that you can't
execute very well because how could a startup
execute really well? They have no resources.
And so the only chance for a startup to win is
to win on a playing field where better doesn't
matter where execution isn't as important as,
"Got to have that thing. I'll take any version
of it you give me because I am desperate for it."
Speaking of execution, good segue to the second
part of the chat, which is basically you looked
into what do the most successful companies
and founders do differently? And you also
found three core things that they all do and
many of them do. Movements, storytelling,
disagreeableness. Let's talk about each one,
pick whichever one you want to start with.
Yeah, so we've talked about thinking different,
but it's like the problem though is that asking
people to abandon the familiar for an uncertain
tomorrow is a provocative act. All startups are
fundamentally disagreeable. There are disagreement
with how things are done, there are disagreement
with the pattern of what is. And so we need
as founders to persuade others to change their
habits with our pattern breaking actions. And so
what the pattern breaking founder does is they
create a stark dichotomy between the world that
is and the world that could be. And they create an
irresistible desire on the part of early believers
to move to that different future with them. And so
I like to say there are three aspects to acting
different, right? One is the other storytelling
and the other is disagreeableness.
And so the movement piece is the front
and centerpiece because most people when they
think of movements, they think of it as more
like social movements like Civil Rights Movement
and Martin Luther King, or they think of there's
artistic movements like Cubism and Picasso. But
fundamentally, a movement is a different way of
developing a market than how most marketing people
think about developing the market. Most people
when they think about marketing, they think,
"Okay, I've got a set of targets, I've got a set
of programs. I've got inbound and outbound. I've
got these things I need to do." What a movement
does is it leverages a grievance of a minority
against the tyranny of a majority. And it takes
that and animates it in a way that those early
believers are emotionally committed to moving.
So early customers are not animated by pragmatism,
they're animated by belief. Early customers,
early employees, early investors don't decide
to go into business with you because of the
practical reasons that you unlock. They do it
for aesthetic reasons. They do it because they
believe what you believe. And so a movement is
basically a set of people with the same belief
moving together to a different future. And when
you think about it's equally the same, right,
for the civil rights movement. And a movement
is a way to crystallize the choice. If you
believe in civil rights, you can't be half in on
that. You either believe that it should be about
the content of people's character, not their
skin color. You can't be sort of not racist.
You either believe or you don't believe.
The people who followed Martin Luther King
bought into the aesthetically better future that
his movement promised. And it turns out, and I
don't mean to equate, that was a pretty important
movement, right? It's like some movements are more
frivolous. I say an artistic movement. But the
notion is similar in that there's a set of early
believers who believe they've been enlightened
about something that the rest of the world doesn't
get yet. And they think that the startup founder
is sort of like the prime mover of that movement.
And then what happens is that startup markets
happen because the movements accumulate and
accelerate and more and more people join them.
And what was once heresy becomes the accepted
conventional wisdom and now the company's no
longer a startup, it's a company, and now all of
a sudden it is a valid market and all of a sudden
they're the status quo and they got to watch out
for the next set of disruptor. So the movement
is the first key thing I think in all of this.
Is there an example? Lyft obviously comes to
mind with the pink mustaches just as the future.
Ride-sharing was a movement. In my early days
starting Floodgate with Anne, we thought that seed
investing was a movement. And so we thought that
there was going to be a day where seed funds would
be a permanent feature of the venture landscape,
but people didn't believe that in the late 2000s.
And so we're like not enough that we just succeed
and invest in good companies. We need to get the
best LPs in the world to buy into this. We need
to get Phil Horsley and Horsley Bridge and Dave
Swenson at Yale and people who are respected in
the ecosystem to say, "Yeah, I buy into that." And
so it was really important to us to get the right
early believers in our movement. Judith Elsea at
Weathergage, who had just started a new firm.
One of my favorite examples is actually an
old one, Clarence Bird's eye. So you go into the
supermarket and there's frozen food aisle. Well,
Clarence Bird's eye discovered how to
flash freeze food when he was up in the
Arctic looking at Eskimos, and they were
flash freezing their fish and he wondered,
could you do it for other things? And he found
out you could fruit and vegetables, but it wasn't
enough to just flash freeze the fish or the
fruits or the vegetables. You had to convince
the trains to have a refrigerated car. You had to
convince the supermarket to have a refrigerated
aisle. And so he had to start a movement where
a whole lot of people simultaneously believed
in this idea of being able to eat food in a
more convenient way, not always in season,
not always grown locally from where you were.
And so all movements have that characteristic
where you kind of start with a higher purpose and
then you move people to that different future.
I'm trying to think about what
are current movements that are
happening. One that might be
a movement is with LLMs just
this bet that transformers are the
future of how this is going to work,
that just more compute is the answer versus trying
to find something else. Does that sound right?
Another one that I really like is Tesla. So
Tesla's mission says, "Accelerate the world's
transition to sustainable energy." They don't even
say they're a car company. So Tesla doesn't say,
"Here's why we're better than Ford and
Toyota." And this is really important,
right? Because the great movements do
appeal to a higher purpose. They don't say,
"I'm better than company X. I'm Avis,
I try harder than her." They appeal to
a more aesthetically higher purpose future. And
then they show that this startup is the vehicle
for that movement to be actualized, which
is kind of a good segue to storytelling.
One other quick example I'm thinking
about linear is kind of pushing this
movement of craft and design
and experience matters in B2B
software. And you shouldn't settle
for something that you don't love.
Very much so. And you know what, Chesky, I don't
think he even knew he was fully doing this at
the time, but Chesky did this brilliantly with
Airbnb. So he created a movement around living
like a local. And so the other thing that a
movement does is it turns the greatest strength
of the status quo into its biggest weakness.
And so Brian never said, "Hotels suck. Death
to the Four Season." He just said, "Hey, look,
when you go to Paris, you have a choice. You can
hang out in the Four Seasons and it's going to be
just like the Four Seasons everywhere else in the
world. It'll be in the middle of the town, or you
can live in Paris like a Parisian." And he's like,
"I don't have to say that the Four Seasons is
bad for you to decide to choose me. And oh,
by the way, if you want to stay in the same kind
of hotel everywhere you go, I'm not for you."
But so now let's say you're four seasons, your
whole business is predicated on doing a good
job of having a common experience that people
could accept and that they're used to and that
they expect. And so now you've taken all of the
stuff that you invested decades in and turned
it into something you have to apologize for
all of a sudden. And so the great startups,
they create movements not so much
by criticizing the incumbent,
but by showing the weakness in the strength of the
incumbent. And then just saying to the customer,
"Hey, look, you decide it's not up to me
to decide what's bad about Four Seasons.
It's up to you to decide whether
you value my difference or not."
It reminds me of counter positioning
from Hamilton Helmer's Seven Powers book.
A hundred percent.
So to make it even more practical for people
that are like, "Oh, I need to come up with a
movement for my startup. That's why things aren't
working." It sounds like it's kind of here's how
we want the future to look and why we're doing
this. And then it's a combination of marketing,
positioning, messaging, repeating it, social
media, imagine is that roughly how to think about?
But I would also say that it's about
storytelling. And so storytelling,
there is a science to storytelling. And so for
example, the hero's journey, you have somebody
in the world that is the hero, let's say Luke
Skywalker on Tatooine, dusty planet, he's bored
out of his mind. And then a mentor shows up and
offers them a call to adventure, Obi-Wan Kenobi.
And at first they resist the call, but then
something bad happens in this case, Luke's like,
"Hey, I can't come with you. I got chores to
do for Aunt Beru and Uncle Owen." But then he
comes back to his place and it's all burned down
the storm troopers killed his aunt and uncle. So
then he accepts the call. The mentor has a tool
and a magic. In this case, it was the lightsaber
was the tool and the magic was the force.
And they need those things because the hero
has to have a reason to credibly believe that they
can beat the bad guy. And so then what happens is
you find co-conspirators along the way, Han Solo,
Chewy, ultimately the princess. You rescue her,
you blow up the death star, you beat the empire,
and then emerge, transform. They even get medals
at the end of the movie, right? Now, it turns out
that the exact same thing applies for startups. So
if we take the Lyft example, let's just say I'm a
rider. In the past, the world that is taxi suck in
[inaudible 01:14:10]. I can't even get one. And
when I get one, it's gross and it smells bad and
it's late, and they won't take my credit cards.
I have to have cash. They can't rely on them to
get me there. I guess my alternatives to park, you
can't ever get parking people break into your car.
That's the world that is.
Logan and John would engage in a call
to adventure, "Try this ride-sharing app. It shows
cars on map, you know where they're all the time,
they come within five minutes, fist bumped the
driver." Now, this was where the genius of the
pink mustache came in. So the pink mustache
honored the fact that a lot of times people
resist the call. It's scary to get into stranger's
car. So the pink mustache made it seem a little
bit less scary. When you see these cars driving
around in San Francisco, you're like, "Hmm, what's
up with that pink mustache?" And you're talking
to your friend and they say, "Oh, it's this new
thing called Lyft. It's pretty cool. It's an app
if you've seen it." And so Logan and John did,
among the best I've ever seen at honoring
the fact that people might resist the call.
But then part of the story is languaging. This
was the genius of Twitter. They didn't call it
Microblogs, Inc., right? They created a metaphor
around tweeting birds. The Tesla was this way,
right? It wouldn't have survived a comparison
with a Porsche of 9/11. The seats weren't as good,
the radio wasn't as good, but Elon was telling
a story about a different future. And when you
bought the Tesla Roadster, you weren't buying
it for practical reasons. You were buying it for
aesthetic reasons. You were buying it because you
thought that that future was something you wanted
to be part of. So the storytelling primitive
ends up working spectacularly well for startups,
right? We need to describe the world that is,
we need to describe the world that could be,
which is that different future. We need to
understand, and this is important that your
job as the founder is to be Obi-Wan, not Luke.
So the founders sometimes make the mistake of
thinking that they're the hero, but they're
not. The early believers are the heroes,
and it's the job of the founder to tell a story
that emotes early believers to want to move with
them and co-create the future with them. And the
story you tell an employee is different from the
story you tell an investor is different from
the story you tell a customer because all of
them have a different idea of what their hero's
journey. If you're an investor, maybe your idea
of being a hero is to make a hundred times your
money and be on some fancy list and make money
for your LPs. If you're an early customer, maybe
you're a hero by solving an important business
problem and getting recognized for it in your
company. If you're an early employee, maybe
it's you want to work on something you're excited
about with really awesome people that don't waste
your time with politics and bureaucracy,
all of those are different journeys. All
of those are different transformational ways
to self-actualize. And we have to meet those
people where they are and give them a reason
to want to come with us to the world to be.
I had Nancy Duarte on the podcast. She is one
of the most famous presentation designers,
and she had exactly the same advice.
When you're trying to tell a story,
you basically bounce back between the world
that is, the world that could be. What is,
what could be. What is, what could be,
and just keep going back and forth.
A hundred percent. In fact, Nancy is the person
who helped me understand this better than any
single person. So Nancy would show me how Steve
Jobs's iPhone launch speech. She'd be like, "Okay,
well now notice what he does. He shows how bad
phone suck now. They have styluses, they have
keyboards." And then he talks about what could
be, you could combine an internet communicator,
you could combine an iPod, and he goes back
and forth between how bad the current state of
things is, how it should be, how bad it is, how it
should be. Introducing the iPhone, how bad it was,
how awesome it's going to be, how awesome it is.
When you look at his speech, he's masterful at
toggling. And by the way, the same is true. Abe
Lincoln with the Gettysburg Address, "Four score
and seven years ago, new nation, now we're in
a civil war. We need to preserve what we stand
for as a country. We need to go win this
war." But he kind of goes back and forth
drawing a tension between what has happened in
the world that was, and the world that could be.
Something that I was thinking as you
were talking was, I've seen too many
founders spend so much time crafting this
amazing story and vision of their product,
and they have this really
cool blog post and big idea,
but nobody really cares about their product
yet. Do you have any advice of just make sure
you're building something people want above all
else. And the story is a layer on top of that.
So many startups I see the first slide is like,
"We're Acme AI software. We're located in San
Francisco, we're funded by X and Y VCs." That's
not storytelling because you're talking about
yourself, right? And if you're trying to make the
person in the audience the hero, they don't care
about you yet. They care about how you're going
to make them a hero. And so when you kind of say,
'Okay, if I'm pitching VCs, what I really need
to do is help them understand why they'll be
a hero if they invest in my company according to
what makes them feel heroic." What you present is
different, but what a lot of startup presentations
do is they take their sales pitch and they rehost
it for every other audience. They rehost it for
the press, for investors and for employees and all
that. And that's wrong because what you're doing
is you're talking about yourself to different
people, but what you want to do is describe the
world that could be, the stakes that are involved,
and then each of those individual audiences, you
want to meet them where they live in the world
that is, and show them how they can engage in a
transformational journey to the world it could be.
And also share your amazing stats and
backgrounds and market size and all that stuff.
Yeah. Although it's funny, I've found that
investors are the same. Investors, ultimately
they believe or they don't believe. A lot of
times, this is the other thing I see happen,
is the poor founder will get advice from 20
different people about their pitch deck. And
a lot of the people giving them advice are not
believers in that different future. They're
giving generic startup advice or they'll go
pitch a bunch of firms and they didn't consider
who's prepared to possibly believe, who isn't.
And so then they get objections to their pitch
from people who aren't going to believe anyway,
and then they try to have a slide to meet that
objection. And before you know it, you have what
I call a Franken deck. And so you have this huge,
gigantic presentation trying to anticipate every
objection, and the person who was ready to believe
you in the first place doesn't know what you
were trying to say because you obscured it
with all this other stuff. And so I find that
just like with an insight, it's okay if most
investors don't like your idea, what you want
to find is the ones who are prepared to move
with you and make sure they absolutely know why
they should. To me, that's the ideal pitch deck.
I love this advice. And just to be clear,
this is like seed and pre-seed before there's
a lot of traction, a lot of data and like that.
Exactly, exactly.
So what's your advice to a founder that's
trying to iterate on their deck is it's
just like, "Don't show it to too many
people." Is it, "Stick to your guns."
Okay, here would be my succinct
advice. And other than that,
there's about a million details. Slide one, you
say what you do as if I literally know nothing.
So it's not, "We're Airbnb, we're a marketplace
for unused residential housing space." Bad. But
you'll get advice that says to do that
because VCs think marketplaces are hot,
residential real estate's big. What you
should instead say is something like,
"We're Airbnb, we let you rent an extra room in
your house." Because now as the VC, I'm like,
ah, I know what you do. And there are a lot
of pitches, I'm 10, 15 minutes in and I'm
trying to understand what they do, but I don't
know. So you just say, "Here's what we do."
And then the second thing that I say to people
is, I think your second slide ought to be,
here's the thing we know that's not obvious. So
when I was raising fund one for Floodgate, I would
go to an LP and say, "We believe that there's a
gap between Angels and VCs. VCs are writing $5
million checks. Angels $250,000 checks. We believe
that 500,000 is the new 5 million because of Lean
Startups. We believe that there will be a new
type of category funds called seed funds. Now, if
you don't believe that, nothing else I'm about to
say is going to make any sense to you, I can just
give you your time back." [inaudible 01:23:06].
But then once, if they did believe that or they
were in a position to lean forward, now when they
start mentioning my competitors, I say, "Okay,
well, recall Peter Fenton works at Benchmark,
he's not going to compete with me because why
would Peter Fenton leave Benchmark to start Seed
Fund doesn't make sense. The only people who are
going to try to compete with me from the big
funds are the people who aren't performing."
But if you set the context of what your insight
is, you can always come back to it. When they
bring up competitors, you can always come back to
it when they bring up objections and you can say,
"Hey, remember I'm just telling you we need to
agree on this insight for this to have a chance
of being great." So what do we do? What's
our insight? And then slide three is what,
if any, proof points do we have? We have
any customers? Do we have great founders?
Is there something happened already that should
cause you to believe that my insight is vowed?
I love this. I love this tangent we went on...
... site is out.
Love this. I love this tangent we went
on. Let me come back to the actions that
you found the most successful startups end
up taking. We've talked about movements,
we've talked about storytelling. The third is my
favorite, I'm excited to hear you talk about it,
which is disagreeableness. What is that about?
Earlier, I'd mentioned that you want to
escape the comparison trap when you have
your insight and when you have your idea,
in creating movements and telling stories,
you want to break free from the conformity trap.
We always are under pressure to conform in this
world, and people use the pressure of conformity
to prevent us from exploring things outside of our
limits. There's a book that I love called Jonathan
Livingston Seagull, where there's a seagull who
wants to fly at infinite speed, and all the other
seagulls are like, "Look, we're just destined to
eat crap off the surface of the ocean. That's just
what we are. We're seagulls." He ends up getting
banished from the flock because everybody thinks
he's crazy. To me, the great founders are kind of
like Jonathan Livingston Seagull. They're willing
to pursue something that they're obsessed with,
that they think has to happen in this world, and
they're willing to sacrifice their status in the
socioeconomic sometimes dominance hierarchy
because fulfilling the mission is ultimately
more important to them than fitting in.
You can't stand out if you always fit in.
The only people who are different can really make
a difference. That's kind of the mindset. I like
to say a startup is a fundamentally disagreeable
act in the first place, and there's going to
be times you need to be disagreeable. I've seen
this time and again. I hear people say to me, "I
want to work with a founder who's coachable." I'm
like, "I'm not really sure." Sometimes I used to
joke that when I would meet with Ev Williams, my
whole job was to give him advice that he ignored.
I would say to him, "Hey, Ev. I don't think you
should raise that much money, because I think
you'll spend whatever you raise in 18 months, no
matter how much you raise." He said, "Man, so you
mean that startups almost always spend their money
in 18 months regardless of the amount?" I said,
"Yeah. I call it Mike's Law. It almost always
happens, because once you have the money,
all the pressure is on you to spend it."
He is like, "Man, that is a really good
advice. I'd never thought of it that way
before. That sounds right to me." Well,
he proceeds to go raise a shitload of money, but
he did stuff that I didn't think he should do,
but it worked. I liked that in him. A lot of
people would say, "Well, doesn't it bother you
that he didn't listen to you that much?" No,
because he was disagreeable, and he was the
right kind of disagreeable. He didn't say, "Pound
the sand. I'm not listening to you. La-la-la, I'm
covering my ears." He listened and he understood
what I thought the truth was. He just believed
a different truth than I did, and that's fine.
My job as the investor is to just help them see
what my perception of the truth is, honestly. If
they decide to go in a different direction, that's
great. They're the founder, they're the genius.
All of them, not all of them, but a whole lot
of them are more disagreeable than history lets
on. My dad worked for Bill Gates when he was
at Microsoft. Bill Gates is not a warm and fuzzy
dude. He was tough. He was a hard ass. But great
people are inspired by hard asses, as long as
the hard ass makes ... You meld the steel in the
heat of the flame of high standards. Sometimes
people can't work for Elon Musk for very long,
but almost everybody I know who's worked for
him really respects him, because he has high
standards, and he's not trying to win friends and
influence people. He's trying to land on Mars,
and if you're going to land on Mars, you got to
be disagreeable some of the time. I just find that
that is a trait that is under-appreciated
in these great founders quite often.
What you just shared reminds me of a
recent podcast episode of Jeffrey Pfeffer,
which I know you listened to, where he talks about
the rules of power, how people acquire power,
and the last rule is, "Understand that once you
have acquired power, what you did to get it will
be forgiven, forgotten, or both." Your Bill
Gates example, I think, is a good one where
people look at him as such a nice dude when, as
you said, he was not so nice a lot of the time.
Here's the other thing, and by the way, I listened
to that episode from beginning to the end, and I
thought it was fantastic, because the next thing
I want to do is go to Professor Pfeffer and say,
"Can we cast these seven principles through a
pattern breaking lens?" Let's assume you're a
startup capitalist, you're not at a company,
because changing the future requires you to
acquire a different form of power than you
would, say, in an organization. But as I was
listening to it, I was like, "These principles
all apply to pattern breakers, all of them,
every single one." The other one is that I think
that he said, "Not everybody's going to like you.
If you want to be liked, get a dog. But if you
want power, there's certain things you're going
to have to do and reconcile yourself with."
Acquisition of power has this notion of you've
got to wield the carrot and the stick. If all
you do is wield the carrot, you won't create
enough activation energy for people to move to
that different future. Sometimes you do have to
use the stick, and sometimes you have to realize
that people are going to use your desire to fit in
against you. They're going to say, "Oh, you can't
do that. That's illegal," or, "You can't do that,
that's unethical," or, "You can't do that.
You're being some tech bro, bad guy." A lot
of what I find with the founders I work with,
ironically, before they win, they have to have
the courage to be disliked because people don't
like their idea. They think it's stupid, lonely.
But then after they win, it's even worse, because
everybody says you cheated or you're a bad guy or
you broke the rules or you're too powerful, or,
"Who gave you the right to decide what the future
should be?" They get criticized unfairly
in the other direction after they succeed,
but in the end, it comes with the territory.
It's part of the job description, unfortunately.
Yeah. Elon goes through a lot of that.
Something I saw you tweet recently along
these same lines is that most successful
companies, there's tons of chaos internally,
and everyone working at these companies
is like, "This place a mess. How is this
even working?" But your finding is
that that's very common and normal.
Especially in startups. There have been
times when I've said things like, "Execution
doesn't matter," and people can misinterpret
that. When I mean execution doesn't matter,
I don't mean people shouldn't get things done or
people shouldn't say, "What did you do this week?"
But when I think of execution in a corporate
sense, corporations in theory should always
win. They have big management team, they have
more experienced people, they have customers,
suppliers, partners, brand, so a startup never
beats a big company by executing better than
the big company. Startup wins over the big company
because it proposes a radically different future,
disorients the incumbent, and sort of chaotically
moves people to that different future.
But like every startup I've ever seen, on
the inside was wild. It was like a capitalist
mutation. It was trying to find a beaked finch in
the Galapagos Islands that's never been discovered
before, and it's all ambiguous all the time,
and people are arguing about what the right
direction is all the time. It's just messy, but
movements are messy. That's what comes with the
territory. A friend of mine, Robin Roberts, once
said, "Make your mess your message." It's so true.
Oh, man. That's so funny. I love
it. I have a couple more questions
before we wrap up. Before we leave the
actions categories, is there anything
else you think is important to share, any
other lessons that we haven't touched on?
I think, Lenny, I don't know if you've consciously
tried to do this or not, but on some level you've
created a movement. No one has ever engaged
people with product management sensibilities
the way you have. I go to your site, and you
even have merch for product managers. I'm like,
"What?" I imagine the early posts that you wrote,
it probably felt kind of lonely. It's probably, "I
wonder if anybody's even reading this stuff," but
it starts to accumulate. More people start to read
it, more people start to tell their friends about
it, and now all of a sudden, it kind of becomes a
thing. In many ways, Lenny's podcast and Lenny's
blog and Lenny's newsletter are all examples of
facets of this movement that you're creating.
But your movement is not just about the stories
you tell or the guests you have or the podcasts
or the write-ups you have. You have a point of
view about the centrality of a product manager
in companies and in businesses and in the future,
and honoring that the way Nike honors
athletes. The point of view is the movement,
just like the point of view is the company
when it's a startup. This point of view is
the story. It's the place that people want to go
that got animated by the beliefs that you share.
Fascinating and flattered. I have no
intention of starting a movement. I could
see what you're saying. That sounds
like a lot of stress, but I guess-
I think you already have, whether
you met to or not, I think you have.
All right. Well, I do have swag, and if you're
on YouTube, this is our best-selling item, a hat
that just says "Product Manager." People love it.
I have it in the background. [inaudible 01:34:26]
Can I wear one if I'm still not one?
Absolutely. You've been one, and so forever
product manager. I'll send you a hat.
Hopefully, I can get grandfathered in for my past.
Forever. Forever PM Mike. Okay. I just have
one more question, and this is around your last
chapter, which I think is going to be useful to
a lot of people. Your last chapter is about how
to apply a lot of these principles to working
at a company. Say you're not a founder, a lot
of these principles still apply. What advice can
you share for people, say, a PM, instead of large
company to help them find pattern-breaking
ideas, big ideas within the company?
The first thing I think is important to understand
is that everything about a value delivery system
when you're doing a pattern-breaking idea
is different from a normal idea. The mistake
that most companies make is they say, "I've
got this new pattern-breaking idea. It needs
to be a third of my business in 24 months
or three years or whatever." Bad strategy.
Let's take a company like, say, Apple, when
they did the iPhone. The iPhone was a whole
new thing. It was driven by, in this case,
Steve Jobs the founder. You couldn't reconcile
it with the original business of the Mac and
not really even the iPod. You had to treat
it as a totally different thing, and that's
really hard for companies. Companies make the
mistake of engaging in a pattern-breaking
product, but they make it too visible
or it's a career-limiting move if it fails.
Pattern-breaking products have different types of
leadership, different types of go-to-market motion
as we've described, different types of ideas,
different risk profiles. Instead of saying this
company or this business is too big to fail,
I need to make small bets that can fail a lot.
The same is true with mergers and acquisitions.
If I buy a company, I need to ask, am I buying a
pattern-breaking company to break the pattern of
my business and go in a radically new direction,
or am I buying a company that's an extension of
my current business? Neither is wrong per se, but
the way you think about risk varies enormously.
Some examples that I have in the book of good
examples are the iPhone, Steve Jobs, AWS, but some
people objected. They said, "Okay, that's easy for
the founders to do because they're founders of the
company, and that's Steve Jobs and Jeff Bezos."
The other example I like is Skunkworks with
Lockheed. When they created a fighter plane in
a very short amount of time, and that's how they
did it, they had an organization totally separate
from the main organization, somebody with absolute
power, and tried to make it not visible, tried
to make it be separate. Because when you make
it visible, you start to drift it back into the
tractor beam of acting like a pattern-matching
corporation. Another good example back in the day
was Don Estridge at IBM when they did the IBM PC,
but it's almost always an autonomous business
headed by a maverick, and you're trying to do
something discreetly different rather than
a better version of what you've already.
This aligns very well with, we had two recent
podcast episodes talking to PMs at companies
that are doing zero-to-one stuff, Mihika and
Tanguy. Tanguy had a really interesting tidbit
along the lines you just talked about where
he set up his team in a totally different time
zone so that people that wanted to bug them just
were sleeping during that time, and they weren't
even online so that they could just focus on
the work they were doing, and it worked out.
I'm mostly through that episode, and everything
that I've listened to so far, I'm like, "Okay,
that totally jives with what I've seen." The
other person has an interesting take on this
is Vinod Kochblok. Vinod basically thinks
that what companies should do is take some
portion of their profits, let's say 10% of your
profits, and invest it in projects likely to fail,
but with wildly asymmetric upside if they succeed,
and then make them not visible to the mothership
in the early inning. It's your willingness to
fail that lets you have breakthrough success.
Any coin that says can't lose bad on one side of
it might as well say, can't win big on the other
side. It's your willingness to fail, and it comes
back to departing from the consensus, right? It's
your willingness to fail that enables success, and
every time you depart from the consensus, there's
a chance you'll be wrong, you'll underperform
the consensus, but it's your willingness to do
that that lets you outperform it. But there's no
shortcuts, right? The coin that says can't lose,
says can't win on the other side, and
lose big says, win big on the other side.
Mike, this episode is so full of nuggets,
tactical advice, amazing stories,
everything I was hoping it would be. Before
we get to our very exciting lightening round,
is there anything else that you think
might be useful to share with folks
that are trying to start a company
or are already along with a company?
Yeah. The one thing I would say
is that it's a lonely existence,
and it's okay if most people don't like
your idea. It doesn't mean you're right,
but it sure as heck doesn't mean you're wrong
either. There's not enough people in this world
willing to stick their neck out for things that
they believe that they see before the rest of
us. Just for what it's worth, if anybody
in your audience is one of those people,
you have just my utmost respect and affection. I
hope that in those times when it's tempting to not
believe, it comes with the territory every great
founder has faced, and it doesn't make you wrong.
Amazing. What an empowering, inspiring
way to end it. Mike, with that,
we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
Okay, here we go.
Here we go. First question,
what are two or three books
that you've recommended most to other people?
A book called The Five Regrets of the Dying,
Top Five Regrets of the Dying by Bronnie Ware.
She was a hospice nurse, and she would talk
to people in the last 90 days of their lives,
and she would find out the things that they'd
wish that they had done in their lives that
they hadn't. I always thought that that was a
good book, because it reminds you about what's
important, and it reminds you that it isn't going
to last forever. Someday, it'll be the last day.
There's another book that I really like called
Chase, Chance, and Creativity by a guy named James
Austin, and I think that it's a good book because
it talks about how certain people tend to attract
luck more than others and actually that luck is
created, you do make luck. I am just fascinated
by this idea of luck and how it can be harnessed.
I'd say those two. There's a whole bunch of them.
I've always liked all of Clay Christensen's
books. The other one that I kind of liked
that I read recently is by Robert Greene, The Laws
of Human Nature. I liked that one a lot as well.
Then Nancy Duarte's book, Resonate, we talked
about Nancy earlier, I like that book a lot.
I'm buying that first one immediately. That
sounds incredible. I need that book. Regrets
of the Dying. I found it on Amazon as you were
talking, and I'm buying it. Good pick there. Okay,
next question. Is there a favorite recent
movie or TV show that you've really enjoyed?
I really liked the movie about Enzo Ferrari,
and I have this huge affinity for 1960s cars,
and the way that they replicated
these 1960s Ferraris I just thought
was magical. I thought that the
guys that did the special effects
and just the attention to detail
I thought was just extraordinary.
I have not seen it. Quick aside,
as I was buying this book,
your book was recommended on
Amazon for me, so good job.
Oh, good. Okay. Here we go.
Good job, Amazon. I will point people to where to
find it at the end of this series
of questions, but next question,
is there a favorite product that you have
recently discovered that you really like?
When I was young, before I got into computers,
I had a job as a professional calligrapher,
and so I really like using calligraphy pens. Not
long ago I sort of discovered the world, it had
been a long time since I'd reconnected with that
hobby, I discovered the world of vintage fountain
pens. My favorite product of recent times,
everybody will be like that sounds esoteric,
but it's a Mont Blanc 149 first generation
celluloid pen. It was right after World War II,
and it was the Germans coming back saying,
"We've still got it." It was just a product for
the ages. It has a flexible nib. Fountain
pens don't work the way they used to. They
used make flexible nibs so that you could
write the way scribes wrote in the 1800s
and stuff. But then people in the modern world
break those nibs, and they use ballpoint pens
anyway. But when I use these old flexible pens
from 1900 to the 1940s, they're just magical.
There's just nothing like it. Nobody's ever been
able to equal that experience in modern times.
Wow. I got to try one of these pens.
Yeah. I'll give you one of them so
you can at least get a feel for it.
Wow. I'll give you a product
management hat, I'll get a pen,
a beautiful pen. I think I win in this exchange.
Two more questions. Do you have a favorite life
motto that you often repeat to yourself, share
with folks that you find useful to come back to?
I learned it from my dad. It sounds simple,
but it's kind of profound, "Do your best."
What he meant by that is he didn't mean be
the best, he meant that life is a gift. You
don't know how much time you're going to
have. Every day is the gift of your time,
and the best way to honor the gift of your time
is to do your best. There'll be times you won't
be the best, but if all you did was the best,
that's all you could do. I remember one time,
so I was a senior in high school, I'd already
gotten into Stanford, I'm totally psyched, I'm
going to go. Last week of the semester of senior
year, and I have a test the next day in English.
My dad's like, "Hey, how are you feeling about the
test?" I said, "It doesn't really matter. I get to
drop it, and I'm going to get an A in the class,
because I've got the goods, so I don't need to do
well on it." He looked so disappointed at me, and
he was like, "It doesn't sound like you're doing
your best." What he was kind of getting at was
that the people who achieve greatness, they think
everything counts. I always got a lot from that
with him. There'd be other times where I wouldn't
do so well on something, and he would say, "Well,
sometimes you make a careless mistake, but you
did your best. That's all you could have done."
The idea of doing your best I find to be very
profound, and it causes you to realize that the
best way to show up in the world is to be your
best self. There's only one you in this world, and
the more that you can show up as your best self,
you'll be impossible to compete with, you
won't feel the need to copy other folks,
you won't feel the need to compare yourself to
other people. You'll compare yourself instead to
the idea of perfection itself and whatever
that means in terms of your own ability to
do your best. To me, that's probably the
most important life lesson I've learned.
Wow. As you said, very simple but very powerful.
It's powerful when you truly internalize it,
right? When you take it beyond
an aphorism, it's very powerful.
It reminds me of your partner, Anne Marie
Coe's advice that she got from her dad,
which is I think maybe the opposite that
she shared on Tim Ferris' podcast of just
always do a world-class job at everything
you do. You're doing a world-class job.
Yep.
Amazing. Okay, I'm going to skip the last
question just to end on that, because that
was way too beautiful to Sully with another
question. Just to give folks a chance to figure
out where to buy your book, when it's available,
how to find it, what they should know, do share.
I guess there's two main ways, right? Well, we've
got a Substack. Not everybody's got to buy books,
right, so there's patternbreakers.substack.com.
Then I have a site, patternbreakers.com, but you
can also get the book on Amazon or anywhere.
It's already available for pre-order, I think.
Amazing. I usually ask people
how listeners can be useful to
you. I imagine it's check out the
book, share what you've learned.
My main goal is for the ideas to spread and to
help people. Hopefully, it will have achieved
that goal. But just anything that people can do
to help spread the ideas. Co-conspirators wanted.
I love these episodes where somebody like
you spends hundreds of thousands of hours
analyzing data and history and startups and
talking to founders and just synthesizing all
the things you've learned into a couple
of hours. I love this. Thank you, Mike,
so much for being here and for
sharing all this wisdom with us.
Hey. Well, thanks, Lenny. It
was an honor to be on your show,
and it's been fun to see you do so well.
Thanks, Mike. It's an honor to have you on the
show. Again, the book is called Pattern Breakers:
Why Some Start-Ups Change the Future.
Mike, thank you so much for being here.
Okay. See you, Lenny. Thanks.
Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.