What was it like managing me, Vlad? Most
importantly, how painful was it to manage me?
Man, how much time do you have?
I used to joke with people that you're
this Jedi, where you get crazy stuff done,
really hard stuff done in a really
subtle and a really unique way.
I've always used inquiry versus advocacy. A
lot of people approach a conversation with
a point of view and they begin advocating
immediately. "We should do this." Or, "No,
we should not do this." Me, I always take
the opposite approach. I inquire first.
I'm going to ask a ton of questions because I
fundamentally believe maybe there's something
I don't know and there's information that I
need to understand to make a better decision.
Is there something you can share about just
what you learned from Brian about thinking big?
I remember talking to Brian one day and he was
like, "Something just feels off right now."
And I remember asking him, "What do you mean? Our
numbers are open to the right." His response was,
"Things are just too calm." Sometimes you
want to create chaos in an organization
to push the organization to think
creatively and to actually make leaps
in product development. And I've always told
myself, "Don't be afraid to poke the bear."
What are some skills that you believe
helped you be as successful as you've been?
Impact, impact, impact, impact.
That's the only thing that mattered.
Today, my guest is Vlad Loktev. This is a very
special episode for me because Vlad was my manager
at Airbnb for many years, and he's the person
that I credit most for teaching me how to be an
effective product manager and product leader.
Within Airbnb, Vlad started as an ICPM,
five years later was leading product for the
core Airbnb business, the homes business. A few
years later, was GM of the core homes business,
reporting directly to Brian Chesky, managing over
a thousand people, including design, engineering,
and other functions. He's also one of Brian's most
trusted partners for most of his time at Airbnb.
Before Airbnb, Vlad was a founder. He's also a
senior PM at Zynga, where he grew the game
Words With Friends to over 14 million daily
active users. Even though Vlad recently moved into
venture capital as a partner at Index Ventures,
he will always be a product manager at
heart to me, and I'm very excited for
more people to get to learn from Vlad.
In our conversation, Vlad shares the
skills and behaviors and mindsets that most
contributed to his success, including a ton
of really tactical stuff. Also, the strategies
and tactics that he's found most helpful in
building and scaling a fast-growing org, and his
thoughts on Airbnb's current ways of working,
including their move away from traditional
product management and also their approach
of thinking very top-down, which I thought
was really insightful. And so much more.
This podcast, I guarantee, will make
you a more effective product leader,
and I'm very excited to share it with you. If
you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting
app or YouTube. It's the best way to avoid
missing future episodes and helps the podcast
tremendously. With that, I bring you Vlad Loktev.
Vlad, thank you so much for being
here, and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you. Excited to be here.
I think this is going to be an extremely special
episode. People will have heard in the intro
that we've worked together for many years.
And even more interestingly, you managed me
for many years at Airbnb. I've also told you
this before, but those years were probably,
not probably, definitely the most
transformative years of my career,
where I learned the most in the years that set
me up for the success I ended up having later
and also the crazy work that I do now. Let me just
say, I'm just really excited for other people to
get a chance to learn from you and to learn from
the things that you've learned that helped you
be successful and helped me be successful,
so thanks again for making time for this.
Yeah, of course. Excited to be here.
You were always a rock star. You were
a rock star back then. You're a
rock star today. Excited to chat.
I appreciate it. I don't know if I was a
rock star at the beginning, and this is
where my first question was going to
go, is what was it like managing me,
Vlad? Most importantly, how
painful was it to manage me?
How much time do you have?
Oh, no.
Jokes aside, I loved working with you, man. And
I have to say, the one thing that I always deeply
appreciated was that no matter how hard things
were, you always called out the elephant in the
room, and so you always told me the stuff I
did not want to hear. And large companies,
things are growing, lots of things are
happening. As a leader, you miss so many things,
and so hearing actually what's happening
and the reality of what you're dealing with,
it was just so, so helpful. I
deeply appreciated that about you.
Wow. I think it was just going to be
a love fest, but I feel like I was
able to do that because I knew you'd react
well and you needed to hear those things.
This episode is brought to you by Pendo, the
only all-in-one product experience platform for
any type of application. Tired of bouncing around
multiple tools to uncover what's really happening
inside your product? With all the tools you need
in one simple-to-use platform, Pendo makes it easy
to answer critical questions about how users are
engaging with your product, and then turn those
insights into action. Also, you can get your
users to do what you actually want them to do.
First, Pendo is built around product analytics,
seeing what your users are actually doing in your
apps so that you can optimize their experience.
Next, Pendo lets you deploy in-app guides that
lead users through the actions that matter
most, then Pendo integrates user feedback so
that you can capture and analyze what people
actually want. And the new thing in Pendo,
session replays, a very cool way to visualize
user sessions. I'm not surprised at all that
over 10,000 companies use it today.
Visit pendo.io/lenny to create your
free Pendo account today and start building better
experiences across every corner of your product.
P.S. Do you want to take your product-led know-how
a step further? Check out Pendo's lineup of free
certification courses led by talk product experts
and designed to help you grow and advance in your
career. Learn more and experience the power
of the Pendo platform today at pendo.io/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta.
When it comes to ensuring your company
has top-notch security practices, things get
complicated fast. Now, you can assess risk,
secure the trust of your customers, and
automate compliance for SOC 2, ISO 27001,
HIPAA, and more with a single platform, Vanta.
Vanta's market-leading trust management platform
helps you continuously monitor compliance
alongside reporting and tracking risks. Plus,
you can save hours by completing
security questionnaires with Vanta
AI. Join thousands of global companies that
use Vanta to automate evidence collection,
unify risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go to
vanta.com/lenny. That's V-A-N-T-A.com/lenny.
What I want to start talking about is talking
through and spending time on some of the
skills that you developed and some of the
skills that you're essentially world-class at in
my experience that I think might be helpful to a
lot of other people. I used to joke with people
that you're this Jedi, if they have Jedi powers,
where you just get crazy stuff done, really hard
stuff done in a really subtle and a really unique
way that I haven't seen other people work.
And to show the impact that has had,
your growth trajectory at Airbnb is pretty absurd.
When you joined, I think we were the same level
maybe. Maybe you're a level above. You're an ICPM
at Airbnb. And then five years later, you're head
of product basically for the homes business, which
is the core Airbnb business. And then a few years
later, you're GM for the entire Airbnb homes
business, managing a thousand people, designers,
engineers, research, marketing, and all these
functions. I want to spend a little time on some
of the things that helped you get to that point.
Let me just start with just a broad question.
Yeah.
What are some skills that you believe helped
you be as successful as you've been? And they
could be skills, maybe behaviors, maybe
mindsets that helped you be successful.
Well, first thank you for that introduction.
I'm a work in progress, so there are many
things that I am constantly working on. I think
for me, when I reflect on my journey at Airbnb,
it was more about the mindset rather than any
kind of skill. For example, my main mindset
was impact above everything else. Impact,
impact, impact, impact. And that's the only
thing that mattered basically my entire career.
And so I woke up every day and I asked myself
two questions basically. Number one, what are
the highest priorities for Airbnb today and
over the next three months? And then two, what
can I do to actually make a meaningful dent in
those priorities? What impact can I have? And I
always made sure that whatever I worked on was
very aligned with a top priority for
the company. And I would say if you
find yourself in a situation where you're not
working on the top priority of the company,
you should probably get a different job, because
at the end of the day, you're spending so much of
yourself and so much time at your job. You might
as well really go for it and work on the hardest
thing you can find, and somebody's willing
to give you a shot to build something crazy.
And so for me, I always thought about, what
is the hardest thing that I can work on? And
how can I drive the biggest amount of impact?
Now, oftentimes figuring out the priorities
is relatively easy. There's typically
clarity around what you have to focus on,
whether it's expanding a team and really building
out a specific team, whether it's growth rate or
focusing on the product quality or closing
deals and closing sales. You can typically
figure out what the priorities are. It's
oftentimes very hard to figure out how to
make impact and what impact even means.
And so for me, my motto there was always
just learn the drivers of the business. Put your
day job to the side for a second and just immerse
yourself in understanding why certain behaviors
exist on the product that you're working on. Can
you influence that behavior? If you do X, what
will happen, essentially? I spend a lot of time
actually blocking off on my calendar just time
thinking through the drivers with the question of,
what are the drivers that are going to
have the most impact for the business?
And I remember when we worked on Instant Book
together, I think this was back in probably 2014,
that was not a random project. There
was so much thought behind why we should
focus on Instant Book and what was the core
problem with Airbnb at that moment in time,
and what impact we thought we could have on
the overall trajectory of the company. Impact,
impact, impact was always just my motto, I guess.
Well, let's actually spend more time here
because this is such... Not only have I
seen you do this well, I've also seen the
impact this mindset has had. And I think
people listening to this might be like, "Yeah,
okay, impact, great. Work on impacting." But
I think there's so much power to this that
it's worth us spending a little more time on.
Yeah, let's do it.
What do people do that's not this? I
imagine many people listening are like, "Oh,
I work on things that are impactful. I'm doing
great." What is it that you see that's not this?
I think when a company matures, I think it grows,
many more people join the team, the company
gets bigger. At some point, a lot of people are
working on similar things. Teams start to form,
then the entire departments start to form. And
pretty quickly, I think a lot of people begin
to realize that you yourself are not in control of
many things and you actually depend on what other
people do. And so a lot of people, and I've done
this too, have focused a lot of energy day to day
on the dependencies, rather than the things
that you yourself can do in your day-to-day.
For example, what I've seen as the organization
scales, people transition from saying, "I can do
X," and they transition to saying, "Can the other
team do Y so that I can do X?" And I think that's
a very dangerous place to be, because at the
end of the day, you just need to let go of some
of these dependencies. You're not going to move
mountains every single day and you got to focus
on the things that are actually within your
control. Again, it's more of a mindset shift.
The other thing I would say is every
single project that we worked on at Airbnb,
we did back of the envelope math with assumptions
to help us understand the impact that something
would have. And you needed to at least... Now,
those assumptions could be completely crazy and
could be very challenging, but you at least needed
to think through the mechanics of what you have to
believe in order for this project to be a success,
and for it to then make a big dent and whatever
you're trying to achieve at the company. Every
single thing we did had that behind the scenes,
and we spent a lot of time on this to make
sure that we were focused on the right things.
I remember there was a project that
we were going to work on. I'm like,
"I think this is a big opportunity. Here's all
my thinking on it." And what I didn't have is,
"Here's the lift this could potentially drive."
And so what you did is you just created this flow
chart of all the levers of the business, and
then you're talking about this sub-lever here,
and if you move this 10%, here's the impact
on the potential business. And you're right.
It is actually a big opportunity,
but this is how you want to show it.
Yeah, totally. The other thing I'll say
is also equally important is saying no to
a lot of things. And it's actually really
hard because we are basically trained and
conditioned to say yes. You go to school. You
follow the rules. You listen to your parents.
You don't want to disappoint people. And so
when people ask for help, you help and you
want to be a really good teammate. But then at
some point, you realize that's actually not the
job. And if you were to say yes to absolutely
everything that you have to do at a company,
you would be distracted all the time with
tons of things that will not make impact.
And so I learned very early on how to say no. It
was hard emotionally. I've gone to many different
debates and conversations, but ultimately I think
maybe it doesn't win you many friends in the short
term, but in the long term, people realize that
when you say no to something, there's probably a
really good reason behind why that thing may not
be as impactful today, and maybe we shouldn't even
do it in the first place. And so I think doing
the back of the envelope math and being really
good at prioritization is one thing, but also
not getting distracted with all the noise and
all the different opinions that everyone's going
to have at a big company is another big thing.
Saying no is hard, so maybe two
quick questions here. One is,
do you have any tricks for how to
say no well, where someone's not-
Yes.
... pissed off? And then the
other question I'll just throw in,
you can take them however you want, is,
what's your heuristic on how much people
should like you as a PM? Because you touched
on people don't need to necessarily love you.
For saying no, first, you can't just be dogmatic
and just say no for the sake of saying no and just
disagreeing with people. You have to listen.
For me, the framework that I've always used
was inquiry versus advocacy. I don't know if you
remember, we've talked about it in some contexts,
where basically a lot of people approach
a conversation with a point of view and
they begin advocating immediately, meaning, "We
should do this." Or, "No, we should not do this."
Me, I always took the opposite approach, and I
still do. I inquire first. I dial up inquiry,
I tone down my advocacy, meaning I am going
to respect the other opinion. I'm going to
ask a ton of questions because I fundamentally
believe maybe there's something I don't know and
there's information that I need to understand
to make a better decision. In the beginning,
dial up inquiry. And then once the person
that you're talking to feels heard and
you actually have absorbed information,
and maybe you changed your mind, maybe
not though, that's when you begin to advocate.
Oftentimes you just come into these conversations
where everyone just advocates, advocate, advocate,
advocate, and you're talking past each other.
You're not even reflecting on what the other
person is saying. Sometimes when I talk too much,
I tell myself, "Wait, inquire. Dial down advocacy.
Just take a breath, take a moment, take a beat,
and actually ask some questions and see
why the other person feels so strongly."
I think that's such a good specific thing
you can do because I think a lot of people
want to do what you're doing. They're like,
"Okay, I'm going to listen. I'm going to ask
questions." But then they get a reaction.
Someone's like, "Hey, we need to change
this thing on the landing page." And you're like,
"No, that's a terrible idea." Or, "That's going
to take all this time. It's going to throw off a
roadmap." And there's this bodily, "Oh, no, I need
to stop this thingy." And so your advice here is
pay attention to, am I talking too long? I guess,
is that the advice? Am I talking too long? Am I
saying too much? And start just inquiring instead.
Yeah.
Awesome.
Totally. And lead with questions. Basically,
approach every conversation with curiosity.
Don't come in, because people usually when
they prepare for a meeting, I've seen many
PMs do this, and you prepare with, "Here is my
view, and here are the bullets that support my
view." And that's the wrong way to approach it.
I think when you want to go into a conversation,
you start the conversation with questions. Prepare
the questions that come from a place of curiosity
of the things that you want to know more about
and you want to learn from the other perspective,
and then check yourself to see if you still want
to advocate for the same point of view or not.
We had an awesome episode with Ami Vora.
She's CPO at Faire, and she is also extremely
good at this and a huge advocate of starting with
questions and understanding what she's missing.
Totally. Well, the other thing I would say
is, the other motto that has really helped
me drive impact, and I use the analogy
of the bear, and I've always told myself,
"Don't be afraid to poke the bear." And what that
means is don't self-censor. If you have a strong
view after you've really grounded yourself in the
truth and you feel like you've done your homework
and you've asked all the questions, if you still
disagree, if you still feel like we're going in
the wrong direction, don't be afraid to poke
the bear no matter how hard things get. It's
interesting because I think a lot of, especially
as an organization matures, you find yourself in
meetings with many execs, founders, et cetera,
it's often hard to voice your real opinion.
And you usually tone it down a little bit because
you're afraid of being the only one who disagrees,
or sounding stupid or things like that.
And so I remember it was probably 2014 or
2013 where I made a promise to myself, "I'm going
to always poke the bear no matter how hard things
get." Because at the end of the day, what's the
worst thing that's going to happen? Did I get
fired? Why would I even be afraid of that? But
if I do, I'll find another gig. Life is short.
You've done this really well, where I feel like
you've also always... I remember when we were
working on Instant Book, you've definitely
poked the bear, where you were like, "You guys
are wrong. This is how we have to approach
it." And I've always really appreciated it.
Thanks, man. Is there an example of maybe working
with Brian where you poked Brian and like, "No?"
Yeah, absolutely. I've poked the
bear many times. And by the way,
I've been humbled many times. It's not like I
poked the bear and I rightfully poked the bear.
Sometimes I learn stuff and I realize I was wrong.
A couple of examples that come to mind. One,
I remember having these debates with
all basically senior leaders at Airbnb,
just about every couple of years actually, around
how much supply should we have on the platform and
what kind of supply should be on the platform. And
there was one school of thought where we needed
basically... That school of thought represented
the view that we needed all supply out there
to be on our platform, regardless of if it was a
person hosting, it was a vacation rental, it was a
hotel. We just needed all supply on the platform.
I came at it from a very different perspective
where I felt like that wasn't actually our
mission from the very beginning. And although
I understood that in the short term, the numbers
probably would go up and you would choose growth,
but at the same time that wouldn't in the long
run be a point of differentiation for us. And
so I had a very different point of view, and it
was very hard in that conversation. Everyone's
excited. Everyone seems to be aligning around
the point of view to be the voice that's poking.
And this is like, "Nope, let me share why I think
maybe we should go in a different direction." And
it's when I remember telling myself that I am
here to surface and share information that will
help the group make a decision, that's what gave
me peace of mind to actually poke the bear and be
able to surface the things that I've seen.
The other thing is when we were working on
the Instant Book, change from Request to Book
to Instant Book for the entire marketplace,
that was very challenging. And I remember
getting up on stage in front of the entire
company and explaining why this is
actually good for humanity. Literally,
those words. Many people disagreed, and it was
not an easy thing to do, but had to be done.
And one thread that I've noticed across all
these things, and noticed working with you,
is it's not like just making a case
for something you could disagree
with. It's showing the data that
will convince them they are wrong,
or here's what they're missing. It's not like a
speech. It's, "Here's the data," and asking them,
"What data would you want to see to
convince you this might be not as you-"
Totally. I think I remember doing a Q&A with the
whole company on the Instant Book topic. This was
a very long time ago, but I still remember where
instead of, again, advocating for a point of view,
I just asked all the people that were
concerned what their main questions were,
and then we just tackled them one by one and
we would talk. There's just something very
disarming when you embrace the questions,
you embrace the negativity, and you have an
open mind that maybe there's some things that you
missed and some things that you didn't consider.
I love that. Okay, there's so many little nuggets
already through this that I just want to come back
to and make sure people take away of how to be
more successful. And this is not just as a product
leader, this just as a leader in any company. The
first is advice around thinking about impact above
all else. And the very simple heuristic that I
wrote down as you were talking is ask yourself,
"What are the priorities for the company? How
can I impact these priorities?" And to do that,
think about the levers that drive the business.
And where do I think I can make an impact to drive
these priorities and drive the business?
Two is inquiry first. When you disagree
with something or when you want to say no,
start with understanding, asking questions,
dialing up inquiry versus advocacy, versus,
"Here's what I think." Poking the bear,
which is really fun, just this idea of don't be
afraid to disagree with someone in power. And your
advice here is disagree with, "Here's data you
may be aware of here. Have you seen this? Hey,
check this out." Or, "What is it that
would convince you you're wrong?"
And then is there anything else I
missed? Otherwise, we'll go on to more.
I think that was great.
Okay, cool.
Don't poke the bear for the sake of poking.
Share the information that you think
will be helpful to make a decision.
Cool. Anything else? Any other things you've found
to be really effective in helping you succeed?
Oftentimes it's about also being able
to be impactful at a company that is in
hyperscale and is growing quickly. A lot of
it is actually just psychological. It's not
like there are these core skills. Sure,
you got to have some baseline skills,
but a lot of it is day-to-day regulating your
mind. And it's so easy to get lost in the sea
of projects, the sea of priorities, the
sea of opinions and, like I said before,
dwell on the dependencies that exist between
teams without actually asking yourself what
you can do in the moment to make an impact.
And for me, I've actually used two tools,
which, some of them you may remember,
that have helped me. The first tool,
this is again purely psychological, to
help my mind, it's the serenity prayer. I-
It's the Serenity Prayer. So the Serenity Prayer
goes something like this. "Grant me the serenity
to accept the things that I cannot change, the
courage to change the things that I can, and the
wisdom to know the difference." That prayer was so
powerful for me that I actually wrote it out on a
piece of paper, like on post-it notes, and I would
read that thing every other day. And it would help
me just take a step back from the day to day and
just put into context what's actually important,
and again, what is in my control today
and the things that I can actually do?
Wow.
So that, highly recommend.
Did none of that.
The other one, which you may
remember, is the shit bucket.
I do remember that.
So the shit bucket was a visual analogy
where I would take a piece of paper,
and some of it actually wasn't as visual,
it was real, I would take a piece of paper,
I would write down something that wasn't going
well, perhaps a dependency, perhaps a project,
perhaps a meeting that I was going to have
that I knew I was going to be frustrated,
or maybe we didn't even decide to go the
way that I deeply felt passionate about. I
would write it down, I would crumble a piece of
paper, and I would throw it in my shit bucket,
basically. And the rule was once I threw
something in the shit bucket, I couldn't take
anything out of the bucket, so I would not dwell
on the things that I just needed to let go of.
So this was a very powerful tool that, like I'm
a perfectionist, I just deeply care about many
different things, and I have a hard time letting
go. And so for me, it was just a reminder that
I need to let some things go and focus on the
things that matter. And I actually, I remember
even going into one of the ones with my direct
where I would sometimes lead. I could tell the PM
is a bit frustrated about how things are going,
and one of my first questions would be, "What
are we throwing in the shit bucket today?" It's
actually a very liberating thing that you can do.
And did you have a special trash that was your
shit bucket, or is it the regular trash can?
Every meeting room always had a trash
can, and I would always throw stuff
into the trash can whenever
I got upset about something.
It's like a different
dimension trash can or bucket.
Yeah.
Is there something you remember
throwing in that shit bucket that
would be an interesting example or story to share?
I remember there was one person
who I deeply wanted to hire,
who I felt was just phenomenal and would
be such an amazing addition to the team,
and I tried and tried and tried for a very
long time, and I just failed. I just could
not get that person to join. And at some point,
it became counterproductive and I had to let go,
and literally just wrote like, "Okay, getting
this person into the company," I'm like,
"this is not going to happen. I've got to
move on at this point." Just threw it in.
I love these two pieces of advice and it touches
on how mentally challenging it is to
be a leader at a hyper-growth company.
Yeah.
Is there anything you can share there about just
that part of the world? People see your career
like, "Holy shit, look at him. He's running
Airbnb's business. What an amazing life."
There's a lot of pain behind it. Is there anything
there that would be useful to people, you think?
There's a lot there. It's not like it was smooth
sailing for me every single year. I had plenty
of challenges just personally going through that
journey. You take a job and then you're sometimes
just not prepared where it's going to take you.
And the reality is, every three to six months my
job changed, so I would just get comfortable
in the role I was in, let's say in the very
early days, I was literally an IC growth PM with a
tiny team, got pretty comfortable, and then a year
later everything changed, and I was suddenly
leading a team of 20. Then a few years later,
things changed again. I was leading a team of a
couple hundred. Then a few years later, again,
everything changed. And you just, everything
that you take comfort in, in your current role,
breaks. The process breaks, how you hire breaks,
how you spend your time breaks, the projects you
work on, everything breaks, and you've got to
reinvent yourself, and that is very hard to do.
So one thing that I've learned is you've got to
ask for help. It takes a village, right? You can't
just get there by yourself. And that's actually
something that Brian taught me, where, I mean,
this guy just grew. Every six months, it was like
a different person, and a lot of his secret sauce
is not being afraid to ask people for help who are
experts in the thing that you're trying to learn.
I mean, my motto is, "Ask for the impossible,
and sometimes you're going to be surprised."
There are people out there that are experts
in something who actually want to help you.
That's awesome advice. Also the Serenity Prayer,
so powerful. I did not know that about you. I want
to spend time talking about things you've
learned about scaling Airbnb and the org,
but before we get to that, is there anything
else that you think contributed to your
success individually as a leader,
any other behaviors or mindsets?
I mean, I think it's building teams and realizing
that sometimes, when you build a team, and this is
actually often misunderstood, I think when people
build teams, they try to make sure every person
on the team is good at just about everything. You
typically go through the process of here are my
strengths, here are my development areas. And
typically the development areas are you try to
develop just about single thing so that you can be
good at almost every single skill that exists, and
I just think that's the wrong mindset. Instead,
what I've learned over time, is instead of trying
to find people that are good at everything, you
need to look for people who spike on specific
things and then add them to a team with different
spikes. So there's no single person that spikes
on absolutely everything, that's very rare, but
they spike on something that's very crucial to the
team. And if you assemble different spikes on a
given team, that team is going to do great things,
as long as everybody inquires and everybody
starts asking questions, actually listens to
other people, versus just coming about that.
So even now, as an investor, when I look or
when I talk to founders, the first question in
my head is like, what does this founder spike on,
and how is that spike relevant to the problem that
they're tackling today, and how well does this
founder hire to bring other spikes to the team?
That's literally what I think about these days.
What are some examples of spikes, just to make it
even more real, things that people might be good
at? Is it like strategy, influence? What are some
things you commonly see that are spike skills?
Yeah, I mean, I think the very natural spike
sometimes is you get a domain expert. So there's a
specific field, let's take marketplaces, and there
is someone who just understands the mechanics
of how things work and just really spikes on
understanding how you can take certain drivers,
what you can do with those drivers and how you
translate those drivers to a measurable result.
There are people who spike on sales and who spike
on just being able to package something in a way
that other people cannot package it, right? There
are people who spike in process. There are people
who will literally, every day, think about how
to get people to work together really well, and
they just know how to get to the essence of that,
how to connect the dots between different teams
working together. Some people are really great at
product design. I've seen quite a few founders,
actually, who can tell you immediately about what
kind of interface is going to resonate with people
and what kind won't and why. So there's just some
examples, but there are many dimensions here.
Awesome. As a last question along these lines,
I'm going to share a few other skills that I
noticed you're incredibly good at, and how about
just pick one that resonates with you and share
some thoughts on how to get better at that and
why that's important. One is influence. You're
an incredibly strong influencer. You get a lot
of stuff done that I think people would be like,
"How did you do that? I have no idea what he just
did." Another is you're very good at keeping a
very high bar. That's one of the things I
learned from you, is just the importance of
keeping a very high bar and spending more time
on stuff. That's something I remember from you,
just like spend a little more time on
this doc, make it a little bit better,
refine it a little bit more, so that's two.
Another is just getting stuff done in focus
while also avoiding the limelight. You try to
not be in front and center. You haven't done
any other podcasts, I don't think you've written
a medium post, I don't know if you've tweeted,
but you try to just get stuff done behind
the scenes and not get attention from
everyone. So maybe those are a few. Is there one
of those that you want to spend a little time on?
Yeah. I mean, first of all, thank you
for saying that. Some of those resonate
for sure. I think the getting stuff done
and being hyper-focused on the job is,
it's something that's really important. I mean,
at Index here, we also say, "Keep the main thing
the main thing." And just like in investing,
same thing in operating. You've got to focus
on the actual job, versus all the other things
that you could potentially be doing. So to me,
I remember when I was actually hiring product
leaders, and there's some product leaders would
do lots of different engagements outside of
the company, whether it's investing, advising,
speaking, attending conference, all those
things, and they were huge red flags to me,
because it was clear that this person, there
was just something missing in their day to day.
They didn't try to put them, all of them, into
the thing that they were doing. And so for me,
it's really important when I hired people, to
hire people who were incredibly mission driven
and would dedicate every ounce of energy
to keeping the main thing the main thing.
Yeah, I talk about this on Twitter and
LinkedIn, this idea that people see
people like me and other PMs, tweeting,
sharing wisdom, and they're like, "Oh,
these are the best PMs. They know so much." But
in reality, the best folks, you as an example,
spend zero time on Twitter or LinkedIn. They're
just doing the job, trying to show great impact,
trying to make the business successful,
trying to build great products,
and I think it's important to remember you don't
need to be tweeting and writing medium articles.
Yeah, I mean, I think there are people who
find joy in solving hard problems, and the
joy you get from working on the hard problem is
fulfilling and you don't need to seek external
validation for the things you do every single
day. So yeah, I loved hiring people like that.
Let me zoom out a little bit. So we've been
talking a lot about the skills that you built
and the mindset that you built to be successful
individually, but also you managed large teams,
you helped scale Airbnb massively through
hyper growth, and there's a few skills I
noticed you're really good at that were
specifically applied to scaling an org,
building an org, building teams and things like
that, and so I want to spend a little time there.
You touched on this one a little bit, but
I think there's more here, around setting
priorities. You're incredibly good at setting
priorities and making sure everyone's aligned,
making sure the main thing is the main
thing. Can you just talk about what else
you've seen be important here, as a leader of a
larger, growing org, around setting priorities?
I have a lot of strong opinions here with
setting priorities. I would say the first one is,
and this was my motto for the longest time and
it still is, you've got to let fires burn. And
what that means is you can do it all. You just
need to let go of things that are not important
because if you have 20 different things that
you're equally engaged on, it just means you
don't actually know what is most important. And
so my motto has always been let fires burn. You've
got to be okay with some things not going well so
that you can dedicate most of your energy on the
few things that actually matter and the things
that are most important. And it's hard to do,
it doesn't feel good. Again, many people,
especially PMs, are perfectionists,
and so it hurts when things aren't going well,
and you've just got to learn how to let things go.
What I always did was I kicked off every
Monday with a leadership meeting where we
would talk about our priorities for the week. We
would not talk about longer-term priorities. It
was literally like for this week, what are we
trying to get done, and it could only be one
to three things, and we would jointly agree
on the fires that we would let burn. And so
then when my partner, my engineering
counterpart or my design counterpart,
would see a fire burning, they would know, yep,
we agreed that we're going to keep letting the
fire burn for now. And it was just really
important to be aligned as a team on that.
Now, the other thing that I've learned is
you've got to let other people burn fires too,
and it's very actually empowering. And oftentimes,
I remember, especially when you're leading a very
large organization, there could be teams and
many different leaders who you're working with,
oftentimes, people come to you and are
basically like, "We've got to do this
new thing to drive goal one, and I just don't
have enough resources. And we need to hire more
people, and we need to expand the resources
of this team." My first question always was,
"Well, what are your actual priorities and what
can we let burn?" Meaning do you actually have
to expand and do more things or can we maybe
reprioritize certain things and focus on fewer
things and put a lot more energy behind them?
But to have those conversations as a leader,
you'll also have to recognize that people on your
team are eventually in a really good position to
gauge what fires should be burning and which
are not to be burning. Now the one thing I'll
say though, is it could be dangerous, and there
are some things that you should never let burn,
because if you let them burn for too long,
bad stuff's going to happen. So I have a
few of those examples for me that I have,
over the years, learned to not let burn.
First, timelines, major timelines. This is like
huge product launches. Once timelines slip, you
basically establish precedent that timelines are
not as important and timelines can always slip. So
you never want to set the precedent let timelines
slip. So that, to me, was when there was a major
project and a timeline with significant slipping,
I'd never let that fire burn, immediately jump in.
The second is when there is disagreement
on a strategic decision or maybe even part
of the vision. If you feel like that exists,
like for example, if not everybody buys into
Instant Book or there's just some disagreement
about what supply should be on the platform,
you've got to squash that immediately. You cannot
let that fire burn because it can spread. I
guess if I follow the analogy, it can become a
wildfire, and then suddenly you have a team of
people who don't believe in what they're doing.
They lose meaning in their work, right, which
is just really bad. So you have to bring people
together immediately when you feel like people,
whether it's many or few people, do not
believe in the direction that the company's
headed. You've got to squash that immediately.
Then the third one for me, and this was a bit
painful to learn, but you never let a senior hire
process burn, meaning you will always, and this is
what I felt during my 10 years at Airbnb, I always
felt underwater, and I always felt like we just
needed to bring on more people who had experience
in certain things that we were doing. And anytime
I delayed or I was not fully engaged with the
hiring process, especially a very senior person,
it bit me for such a long time and it set the
whole team back. And so those are the three
things that I would never let burn, but you've got
to let a whole bunch of other stuff burn for sure.
Such counterintuitive and amazing advice.
You shared a bunch of examples of things
that you don't want to let burn. Are there any
examples you could share of things you let burn,
things that would surprise people or a story
that comes to mind of like, yeah, that's fine?
Sometimes you would have examples where
certain product launches didn't go well,
and let's say you weren't seeing it in the
numbers, the users weren't happy, like, okay,
that's sometimes you just need more time to
understand what's actually wrong. You don't
need to jump on it immediately, right? So that's
maybe one example of a fire that I let burn quite
a bit. And quite frankly, at some point, I had
so many teams that I was working with that I just
needed to prioritize even between the teams,
where this team is the number-one priority,
and I know that I need to be in design
reviews with this other team, I just,
I can't, because I have to be thoughtful about how
I'm spending my time in this given moment, and so
I actually have to deprioritize projects. And so
there are certain projects that were important,
but I let burn for a while because I just had to
spend my energy elsewhere. And then, of course,
I would, to myself, I was thinking, are we doing
too many things? Is this the right way to operate?
And I think this is really useful for
someone that, say, is an ICPM on a team,
that's wondering why the hell our
team is just wasting our time,
we're building all this stuff, it's not
working. Why isn't anyone doing anything,
why aren't they giving some resources, why
aren't they repurchasing, it's because they
know there's many other problems they're dealing
with, and they're letting this burn for now.
Yeah. And this was actually a learning for me
in an area where I would say I failed over time
is just general communication to the broader
organization. When you rise really quickly,
you tend to underappreciate, or I did, just how
important it is to communicate what, as a leader,
you're spending your time on and the areas that
you think are the highest priority right now.
And so eventually, I started doing a lot of all
hands, and I started sending the weekly thoughts
from Vlad or just like my random musings and
what's in my head. And I realized that sharing
that context with people is just so important, and
people actually want to hear from you. And it's
good to over communicate, and it can help people
understand certain things about their day to day.
I know that it didn't come naturally
to you. I mentioned that you kind of
like to be behind the scenes, under
the radar, not in the limelight,
so I could see why that wasn't
something you were doing initially.
Yeah.
Is there anything more you can share
there about what you learned about why
that's important? Why spend time
there? What happens if you don't?
Everybody wants to find meaning in their work,
and everybody typically wants to understand the
reasons behind a decision, and it's important
to share, to take like, I've done this myself,
where you just make a decision and you
move on and you go on to the next decision,
and it's actually so, so helpful if you take
10% more energy and time to now bring everyone
along around why a certain thing was decided,
because it's going to help them, just themselves,
make better decisions, because now they have a
lot more context about how this decision was made,
and they can learn from that moment. So
that's partly why it's important. I mean,
for me, it didn't come naturally to
me. I'm like a pretty, I don't know,
I'm a deep introvert. I shy away from many
different things and it had to be a learned thing.
I think you're also a really good example
of something I talk about here and there,
is you can be really successful in very different
ways. I'm also introverted. I think we're similar
on the spectrum of colors or the personality test,
and you've been really successful. You can also be
incredibly successful as a very extroverted
person or someone that's very analytical,
and you're a great example of someone that's more
reserved and is introverted, as you said. And I
think it's important for people to know you can be
incredibly successful as a PM, as a huge leader.
Totally.
From that place. This episode is brought to
you by Eppo. Eppo is a next-generation A/B
testing and feature management platform built
by alums of Airbnb and Snowflake for modern
growth teams. Companies like Twitch, Miro,
ClickUp and DraftKings rely on Eppo to power
their experiments. Experimentation is increasingly
essential for driving growth and for understanding
the performance of new features. And Eppo
helps you increase experimentation velocity
while unlocking rigorous, deep analysis in a
way that no other commercial tool does. When
I was at Airbnb, one of the things that I loved
most was our experimentation platform, where I
could set up experiments easily, troubleshoot
issues, and analyze performance all on my own.
Eppo does all that and more with advanced
statistical methods that can help you shave
weeks off experiment time, an accessible UI for
diving deeper into performance, and out-of-the-box
reporting that helps you avoid annoying, prolonged
analytics cycles. Eppo also makes it easy for
you to share experiment insights with your team,
sparking new ideas for the A/B testing flywheel.
Eppo powers experimentation across every use
case, including product, growth, machine learning,
monetization, and email marketing. Check
out Eppo at geteppo.com/lenny and 10X your
experiment velocity. That's geteppo.com/lenny.
Okay, so just to summarize the lesson we just
talked about, mostly is let fires burn.
Basically, don't feel like you need to
solve every problem as you rise in the ranks.
And I think this applies even if you're not the
top of the org, even if you're a manager of
managers, even if you're manager of nobody.
Yeah. Maybe the other thing I'll mention, and as
I reflect on setting priorities and just working,
I think a big lesson for me is that chaos is
good and chaos is actually great. And sometimes
you want to create chaos in an organization to
push the organization to think creatively and to
actually make leaps in product development. And
so, I mean, I kind of, as I reflect on my life,
I like cleaning up messes, I like when things
are very organized, I liked when there's a lot
of clarity on how things are put together,
and chaos is scary, right? And I think that
this is very natural for a lot of people, for
chaos to be scary, but I've seen examples when
just a bit of chaos is so, so helpful. Just to
give you an example, I remember me talking to
Brian one day, and he was like, "Hey, I just don't
feel good. Something just feels off right now."
And I remember asking him, "What do you mean?" I
was like, "Our numbers are up and to the right,
we're chipping quickly, everything's great.
What do you mean? What are you unhappy with?"
And his response was, "Things are just too calm. I
don't like it." And I was like, "Okay, what do you
mean? Calm is great," like I operate in calm.
And he then picked a project that he thought
was important - I think it was actually host
onboarding at the time - and of course, on this
project, I remember we had this perfectly crafted
timeline. We're going to design this for the next
four weeks and then we're going to start building,
and we're going to deploy in certain pockets of
users, we're going to learn, we're going to
iterate, et cetera, very rational timeline.
And he said, "Yeah, I don't care about any of
that. We're going to design this in 24 hours."
And I was just like mind blown own, right, like,
one, how? Two, the ripples that's going to send
through the organization, because I knew all
the people that were involved on building this,
and we had this whole neat flow. And we did design
it, actually, in 24 hours, well, it took a little
bit longer, but we designed it very quickly,
and what I learned in that moment is that ...
Very quickly, and what I learned in that moment
is, that was actually an example of chaos that he
inserted into this very calm building process,
and that chaos forced us, with our artificial
time constraint, to dial up our intuition and to
think a bit more creatively than maybe we would
have in the past. Now, that didn't always work,
because there were examples of this where you're
just like, "I don't know what the answer is. I
need more time to design this, and to think about
this problem." There were definitely examples
of that, but there were many examples where it
was actually a great forcing function to
go with your gut and actually innovate.
That's an amazing story, and it
reminds me of something else,
just to take a quick tangent here. Brian
is incredible at just asking people always,
"That's a great goal you have there.
What would it take to 10x that goal?"
He'd get to the FP&A projections, and he's like,
"Great. How do we 10x this?" I found that to be
really scary, but also, really effective in
helping people think a lot bigger. Is there
something there you can share about just what
you learned from Brian about thinking that big?
I think it's less about hitting the goal. I think
a lot of people, when they see really big goals,
they get immediately afraid of the
goals, because they think, "Oh my God,
I don't know how to hit this. If we don't hit
it, what happens?" You start thinking about all
the downstream consequences. The reality is, it's
not about hitting the goal, it's about thinking
how to hit the goal, and going through that
creative journey of, what does the world need
to look like for this to be true, this crazy
goal to be true? How should we think about it?
Oftentimes, it pushes you to test extremes, when
the whole world is going to operate this way,
or nobody in the world is going to operate
this way versus something in between. Usually,
it's when you start testing the
extremes that you begin to realize,
"This is the path that we should actually take."
Yeah, I've found exactly the same thing, just
thinking backwards from what is the best possible
thing we could do, versus incrementally forward
ends up unlocking a lot of big ideas. Something
I imagine is in people's minds as they hear
some of this stuff, like designing something
in 24 hours or thinking 10x bigger is, "I
don't want to work that way. That sounds
incredibly stressful. That sounds really hard."
You mentioned this, that this isn't necessarily
for everyone. Not everyone needs to work at this
company, or work this way. Part of it is hiring,
is finding people that want to lean in, to
work really hard. Other people don't. Is there
anything there, of just, this is actually
really hard, and it's not for everyone,
but it also ends up being successful, and you end
up having a good time a lot of times afterwards?
I find that those sprints, where, "Design this
in 24 hours," brought a lot of connection to the
team, actually, and they were my most fun moments,
actually, because you're forced to let go of a
lot of constraints. All these organizational
dependencies disappear, all the stuff that's
noise, and you can just start building.
For me, especially when you're not doing
this by yourself, and you're doing this with
a team of people, it was deeply rewarding,
because you were all working together just
shooting the shit, and throwing a whole bunch
of ideas out there. No idea was too crazy.
Now, it's not for everybody. I actually,
in the interview process, when I would
hire PMs, I was always, not always,
in the early days I had to learn this, but in the
later days, I always set expectations about how
we work. I think some leaders do this, it's the
anti-sell sell, where I will share the worst day,
or what I think you will think as a candidate
what the worst day would be at Airbnb, and
then still ask you if you want to join the team.
I would basically tell people, "We're going to
work day and night. We're going to work weekends.
The direction is going to change. The strategy?
Out the window every three months. The projects
you're working on today, we're going to kill
three weeks later. The road map that you are right
now auditing as you're deciding your offer, when
you actually join after you took some break from
your other job, it's going to completely change."
I think the common thread there is, "Everything
is changing all the time. You've got to be cool
with that if you want to join this team,"
and totally fine if that's not for you.
I love that. It makes me think of something
when my colleague used to say to me is,
"If you haven't changed teams
or your desk in six months,
something's about to happen.
Something's about to change."
Totally.
This unsell idea, there's a recent podcast
episode where someone did something similar.
He called it the unsell email
where he sends the candidate,
based on all the things he heard from the
candidate during the interview process,
"Here's all the things you probably won't
love about working here." And the recruiter
was always really mad at him for like, "Don't
send that. My numbers are really going down
because of this email." But longterm, it
ends up being really successful for them.
I mean, you're going to probably
hire fewer people that way,
but you will hire the right people. So I
think then you're going to actually have
a team that you can rely on for years
and years and years as things change.
Just have to align incentives with
recruiting on that piece of it. So,
one other area I wanted to spend time on
is basically org design and hiring and
people. So you were very good at building
really effective teams, prioritizing them,
bringing in amazing talent. What can you
share about things you've learned about
as the company is growing and org
is scaling about org design hiring?
So for me, one of the hardest things
about building teams and going through
hyper growth was the fact that you're going
to lose a lot of friends on that journey. You
just have to be prepared to say goodbye
to your friend. Meaning when you start,
you build really deep relationships with people.
When you're a smaller startup, you typically have
one-on-one interaction and you know everybody
and you have that connection with people. And
the reality is, if the company is
truly going through hyper growth,
most people are not going to scale. It is very
rare for somebody to scale with the company.
I mean, we actually, so at Index, we
wrote a book, Scaling Through Chaos,
and there was this crazy stat where basically when
you look at many, many companies that reached a
thousand people and were successful, when you look
back to the first 10 employees, you realize that
only two to three of those ten first employees
stayed with the company when the company reached
a thousand people. And that's just so indicative
of what will actually happen in practice.
There are certain skills that you have that are
good for in the specific domain for a period of
time and that time is not universal forever.
At some point, everybody taps out and so just
having that realization is, it's tough. It's
tough emotionally. It was one of the hardest
things for me as a leader, and I would say the
way to break out of that is to ask for help and
to try to learn as much as you can about what
the next role for you is going to look like. So,
that's one thing that I've learned.
I would say another thing is that all
org charts suck. There is no good org chart.
Every single org chart has problems. So you
can be organized around business units, you
can be functionally organized, you can be
organized around problems, and the reality is
every single one of those constructs sucks.
There are pros and cons to each approach. If
you organize yourself into business units,
the problem you typically run into is silos.
When people start basically advocating for
their business unit with little regard for other
business units, if you're functionally organized,
sometimes you create too many dependencies
across the organization, and it becomes this
matrix way of working, which could be challenging
and as a result could be slower to ship product.
Those are just examples. These are not
universal issues, but those are examples
where regardless of how you're organized,
there are going to be problems. So for me,
one learning was if you're having a problem
and you're trying to solve this problem,
reorganizing and a new org
chart is rarely the solution.
It's not about the boxes and how you configure the
boxes. It's about the people in those boxes and
it's about how those people work together because
you just need to understand the cons of working
a certain way. Then how do you design a process
around your org structure to make sure that people
connect and work really well together? So, my
advice there also to founders who I talk to now,
focus a lot less energy on actual org design,
study the different types and just pick one
and once you pick one focus on the people,
the culture and how people work together.
That's really interesting. So basically you
think people are overthinking org design?
Yes.
How do you think about incentives
and goals and how that impacts all
that stuff? Because there's people and
then there's like, "Here's your goal,
here's how you're measured," and that's what
they're going to work on in this thought.
I mean, I think incentives come down to
culture, and it's what you set as the
fiber of your organization. So again, I think you
can align incentives. And people will be excited
to make impact on the organization regardless
of how an organization is actually organized.
That's a really interesting takeaway,
because I think a lot of people think about,
"If we just org this and put this person here
and create business units, things are going
to start moving." And you're not saying don't
think about that and don't necessarily do that,
but you're probably putting too much weight
on that actually solving your problems.
Yeah, I mean, I think you want to certainly
study different ways of organizing and the
pros and cons, but just know that no matter
which choice you make, it's going to suck,
and there are going to be problems. And
you just need to go into it with wide
open eyes and then create process to
make sure that whatever the cons are,
if people are in silos, well, then
you got to have a really good way of
bringing people together and creating the right
incentives to make sure people collaborate. So,
there's all these other things that I would say
are much more important to focus your energy on.
Awesome. Anything else along these
lines around org design or hiring
they think is really important
or has [inaudible 01:00:46]
Hiring, the one thing that is universal
for me and always has been is mission
over domain expertise. Basically,
mission over domain expertise,
mission over skills. I think that if you have
that raw horsepower and you're deeply... You
just love the mission so much, you can build
whatever skills are necessary for the job.
As an operator, I've loved taking bets on
people who are maybe earlier in their career
who have energy, who have drive, and who are
deeply thoughtful and deeply resonant with the
mission that we're working on. Because at the
end of the day, strategy changes, orgs change,
teams change, everything changes all the time, and
the one constant I think is actually the mission.
And when gets really, really hard when your
company almost collapses, like we did during
COVID, the thing that gets you through those hard
times is the mission. If you don't have mission,
you don't believe in the mission, you lose
meaning in your day to day and you start
to disengage from the company. So, I think
that's actually the most important thing.
So what I'm hearing there is potentially
if you're just hitting it at your job or
you think it's just not going anywhere, it
might be that you don't actually care that
much about what the company's trying to do in
the mission, and maybe there's not a lot that
can change for you to actually be happy there
because you don't actually care. Fascinating.
Something that I wanted to come back to real
quick, a lot of your advice comes back to impact,
impact above all else, drive impact, focus
comes back to what is the most important
thing to do. Something that I think about a lot
is how do you be successful within a company,
and one of the levers is go to a place and
a team that is driving impact. Do you have
any advice there around just where you're
best suited to be successful within an org,
coming at it from or impact is most happening?
I mean, I always thought about it as
the combination or almost like this Venn
diagram of there's one circle, which is all the
different priorities that are important. Then the
other circle are your strengths and where you
spike, and the intersection of the two is the
place where you should be and sometimes you're
not quite there at the intersection and you're
kind of gravitating towards that intersection.
You're building a specific skill that you're
already naturally pretty decent at, but
you definitely want to double down on it
as you're learning more about the priorities
and there's a match there. The worst thing
I think you can do is just sit in a
job where you're not being impactful,
you're not working on the top priority and you're
just wasting your life. Our time is short on
earth. You might as well wake up every day and
work in the hardest thing you can, where you
can truly based on who you are and the spikes you
have, make a dent and whatever is going to happen.
And I also have the serenity prayer
ready to go when things get really hard.
So, what I want to do right now
is summarize many of the things
that you've shared before we get
to talking about Airbnb today and
Brian Chesky's approach to product. I
guess before I try to summarize stuff,
is there anything else you think is important
or behavior-wise that we haven't touched?
No, I think we've...
We've done a lot. Cool. So this is almost a
Vlad's guide to being a successful product
leader. I don't have it all summarized
here yet, I just have a bunch of notes,
but I thought it'd be fun just to try. So one
is, and the way I would think about this as
you're listening to this is, "What can I do to
be more successful as a leader in a company?"
And this is all kinds of stuff that I
100% agree with is effective. So one is
impact above all else. Think about
what is the company prioritizing,
what is important to the business, how
can I drive impact there? And to do that,
think about the levers in the business that move
that and then find ways to work on those things.
This idea of inquiry first when you disagree
with something, shift your mindset to asking
questions and then along those lines when you
disagree, this idea of poking the bear, sharing,
"Hey, here's why this might not be right.
Here's why you might be wrong about this.
Here's data that I found." Or, "What data would
help you understand maybe you're wrong here?"
What else? Saying no, being really good at saying
no, and this comes back to impact and focus. Let
fires burn, really powerful idea. Don't feel
like everything has to be solved. I am similar
to you where I feel like anything's in order
and clean and organized, and so this would be
very hard for me. But such a powerful lesson
of it's okay if things aren't going great.
And I love your advice of align with your
team on, "We will let these things burn for
now." Anything you want to add, by
the way, as I'm going through this?
No. Got to let everyone be a
pyromaniac. It leads to great things.
Awesome. So along those lines, embrace chaos, let
things be chaotic sometimes because some of the
best things come out of that, and as you shared,
Brian sometimes just introduces a little chaos to
get people out of their safe world a little bit.
This idea of a shit bucket. If things are just
like, "I hate this thing and it's not going
well, I'm just going to throw it in the shit
bucket for now and that's just how it's going
to be and I'm going to move on so I could focus
on impact and important things." Amazing.
What else do we have here? So many little
notes here. Be prepared, says your organizing
front teams. Be prepared to lose friends that
you had at the company as you rise and as you have
to do things that maybe they're not aligned with
or happy about that are helping their career.
All org charts suck, nothing's going to be
amazing. Don't over focus on the org chart.
Focus on the people and the culture. Oh yeah,
the mission above all else. Just like if things
are not going well, it might be people aren't
aligned with the mission of the company. Is there
anything else off the top of [inaudible 01:06:34]?
It's so interesting when I think back to my 10
years, things that I actually remember the most
are these moments with other people and not some
project or some product launch that's going super
well or us doing really well with metrics. The
things that really made I think Airbnb special,
and now that I think back to those 10
years of my experience that I deeply
just resonate with are those little moments.
And one example, and this is why culture is
just so important because these things
don't just happen organically. You have
to be thoughtful about building culture, and
then I think you create a place where these
little things can happen. So for me, I don't
know if you remember your experience when you
first joined the company, my most memorable
experience at Airbnb is the human tunnel.
And it was just this thing where I remember it
was my first day and I was standing behind this
giant wall and there was silence in, I think,
it was a cafeteria. I was like this huge huge
room and then somebody like this engineer
runs up to me and says, "Hey, go around to
the other side of the wall," and I turn and
suddenly the room just explodes in cheering
and clapping and everyone yelling my name.
And everyone is basically doing a human
tunnel with their hands. Literally every
single person at the company at HQ,
including the founders. And then I run through
under everyone's cheering and I jump into this
beanbag while everyone's chanting my name. That
was my first day, and here I am, I don't know,
12 years later, 13 years later. I still remember
that as one of the most amazing moments of the
entire journey and I immediately felt accepted.
And I wanted to contribute to the team,
and a lot of the reasons why... There were
many moments like that throughout my 10 years
and it was a result of how we hired people for
certain core values and were very intentional
about just helping people integrate into this
crazy company that was growing superfast.
That was an amazing story. I feel exactly the
same way. I went through a similar experience
when I joined. And obviously, the human tunnel
eventually didn't scale and people started
doing it per team versus the entire company. We
could do a whole episode on Airbnb culture and
learnings from that. Interestingly with the human
tunnel, it started I think with the founders,
but it ended up being they had no involvement in
these tunnels. It was just employees knew that
this is the thing we're going to do for every
new employee, and so I think it's interesting.
I guess just spending a little time on
culture and learnings from Airbnb about
the value and power of culture, is there
anything there you take away with two other
companies you work with now of just how to
set up a great culture, how to do this well?
I would say there's no single playbook. I would
say the one thing that comes to mind just being
really intentional and thoughtful about it and
actually dedicating energy to it. Just as much
as you spend time building product, hiring people,
is you got to spend just as much energy actually
thinking about culture and your core values.
And so core values are very, I would say,
indicative of what the culture will
be. So those two are very linked and
once you think about core values, I remember
what worked really well was you don't just write
your core values in the document somewhere
and then no one ever opens it. The key is,
regardless of what the core values are, you want
to make sure that those core values are prominent
in just about every single thing that you do.
So when you hire people, you hire for certain
core values, and at Airbnb, we had core
value interviewers up until, I mean,
my entire tenure basically. Even when we had
thousands of people already at the company,
when we were hiring people, everybody had to
pass core values interviews, so it was very
ingrained in how we hired and what we looked for.
Then even performance reviews and promotions,
no matter how much impact you made, no matter what
you did, if you were not also exemplifying core,
you didn't get promoted. You didn't get to
the next level, and so even in our performance
conversations, those core values were very
present in the day to day. And then of course
they were also printed everywhere. They were just
physically everywhere all the time, so I felt like
every single person around me always knew what the
core values work, and so that's my biggest advice.
It's like, don't copy some other company's core
values. Instead, just be intentional about what
matters to your organization and then make sure
that those core values are freaking everywhere,
part of every single process.
Otherwise, no one's going to care.
Just to reinforce what you're saying, have
been gone from Airbnb for five, six years now,
and I still a 100% remember the core values.
I'll go through them real quick. Be a host,
be a cereal entrepreneur, which is cereal as the
cereal story of Airbnb, champion the mission and-
Simplify.
Simplify, although they tweak
that one or they cut it.
And then embrace the adventure.
Embrace the adventure is my
favorite. I love that one the most.
See years later, you'll still remember.
Exactly. Every frame matters was the
other one they decided to cut out,
because they realized something they learned about
core values that I thought is a really interesting
is they shouldn't be aspirational,
they should be who you actually are,
and so there's a period where the founders are
like, "We're not actually amazing at this thing,
so let's just remove it from the core values
and reduce the ones we're focused on."
What I also really liked is that there were
tangible examples always of about what it meant
to embody this core value in your day-to-day
work, and so then it was very tangible for
people versus just some overarching embrace the
adventure, like what does that actually mean.
Then just to make sure people get this point
you made about this core value hiring team,
which is really unique, I don't know if
anyone else does this, is there's people
trained to interview in core values and they
were a specific volunteer team. That part of
the interview process, one of these people
came in and they interviewed for core values,
which was meant to represent what the
founders were looking for initially.
I mean, it was also very telling
how, I remember, it was an honor
internally to be selected to be a core values
interviewer in the first place. Most people,
large companies are like, "I don't want
to do any more interviewing. Oh my God,
I'm in interviews all the time."
Here, people were like, it was a
sense of this emotional proud moment when you were
basically given the keys and somebody said, "Hey,
we actually think you would be fantastic
at helping us think about how to make sure
every single new hire embodies these core
values." I think that was so powerful.
Amazing. So again, we could spend an entire hour
on the culture of Airbnb and all the things we've
learned there. It's actually a good segue to
the last area. The last part I want to talk
to you about, which I think a lot of people are
probably wondering about as we have been chatting,
which is about Airbnb's current ways of working.
So, we had Brian Chesky and the podcast,
most popular episode of the podcast turns out, and
he shared his approach to product, which a lot of
people are like, "huh, that's unique and different
and I don't necessarily want to work that way."
Other people are like, "This is amazing.
This is exactly how I want to operate, and
so I'm going to make my company work this way."
The way he described Airbnb is it kind of moved
from bottom-up, experimentation driven to very
top-down, "We're going to have one roadmap. I'm
going to be involved in everything." Product
managers and our product marketing managers
and all these things that I think people are
like, "Wow, that's really new and interesting."
You actually worked through a lot of
that. You went through that transition.
I think technically you're a product
marketing manager when you left Airbnb?
Yep.
So you're a really good example of that. You
reported to Brian during this time. Thoughts
now that you're removed from Airbnb
on that way of working, pros and cons,
right for everyone, maybe not right for
everyone? How do you think about this stuff?
So first, I guess, let me zoom out from Airbnb
for a second and then we'll go into the concrete
details of what Brian said. I don't think you
should copy another company's ways of working.
The reality is it is how a company operates is so
unique to the founders, to the leadership team,
to all the employees, and the domain
potentially, moment in time. Because
how companies operate also evolve sometimes
over time and just certain different ways of
operating might be needed. So, I wouldn't
just copy someone else's way of operating.
It just copies someone else's way of operating.
Even at Airbnb, it was just very interesting.
For us, it took us a long time to figure out how
to operate, right? Actually, we did it for a long
time, explain and give clarity to people of how we
should even operate in the first place. Because,
so we hire people from Facebook and Amazon and
Google and Netflix and every Apple, every company,
right? And every person would come in with their
own preconceived notions of how they want it to
work. And oftentimes those opinions differed. And
so because we never actually stated the Airbnb
way for a very long time, sometimes it would be
chaotic, right? People just wouldn't know how to
operate and then you go from team to team, teams
would just operate very, very differently. And
that was a problem. So I think here the lesson for
me was not necessarily there is one way to... Like
every company should operate this way. And it's
much more about picking an explicit way to operate
and then voicing it to every single person so
that everyone has clarity on how to do their job.
I think the worst thing is people just don't have
clarity on how to do things day to day. They don't
know how to drive impact and they're just like,
what am I doing with my life? So that was kind
of one lesson. Now specifically going double
clicking into Airbnb and where we moved. So I
think one of the things that Brian mentioned was
being top down, right? I actually think top down
is this construct that has negative connotations
associated with it quite a bit. And it's often,
at least in the context of Airbnb, I think
misunderstood. What people think top down...
And I've had many by the way, many of these
conversations with folks, right? So most
people think, oh, there's a leader here in an
ivory tower sitting somewhere. It's a voice
from the team making a whole bunch of
[inaudible 01:17:07], right? And everyone
else is like powerless and can't do anything.
That's not actually a reality of top down. Now, in
that room where we made many of the hard decisions
with Brian, the reality was he asked a shit ton of
questions, right? Again, he didn't advocate in
the beginning. He would come in with tons and
tons of questions and he would listen. And of
course sometimes, he would disregard certain
things that he heard because he had very strong
conviction, a different direction. But he listened
and oftentimes he would also change his mind,
right? And so as a leader at Airbnb for so long,
I never felt like I wasn't listened to or like he
was just making these random decisions. I always
had an ability to influence and an ability to
voice where I felt like the company should go. So
yes, he made a lot of decisions, but he made sure
he was informed in those decisions and then many
of us were Contributing to all the information he
needed to make the decision, which is then also
why he wanted every leader to be in the details.
Why did he stress that for himself and every
single leader on the team? It's because when
you get into that room, right? And you start
discussing many different directions you can
go, if the leaders in that room can't tell you
what's actually happening with the business,
then why they're there in the first place,
right? You can't then make a good decision with
that group of people. So then suddenly your team
of 10, you have to blow up to a team of 30.
And if those people are not in the details,
then you got to like what? Bring in 50 people?
And so at some point you need to make sure that
leadership is actually in the details, understand
what's happening, and can help bring to light
information that's going to help somebody make
the right decision, right? So that's why top-down
and being in the details to me, they were actually
very connected and they made a whole lot of sense.
Now, the one thing I'll say is at some point when
you are working on many things, it is challenging
to be in all the detail, right? And if you mandate
that product cannot ship without certain people
being in every single detail, sometimes you could
slow it down, right? And that could be a con of
that way of working. I would argue for us at
Airbnb, the quality of what we were releasing
kind of suffered because we were just push, push,
push, ship, ship, ship, and people were shipping
across the board. And I did feel as a leader,
like I wasn't proud of some of the things we were
shipping. And so I appreciated the intentional
slowdown at the expense of our goals to get to a
higher quality bar and then amp up velocity again.
After everyone had a better understanding of what
quality actually was. So we kind of had to
slow down for a bit to then speed up later.
And I think a lot of it is Brian always wanted to
make sure that every leader would be able to make
decisions and have really good judgment, and he
wanted to teach what that meant. And I actually
really appreciated that over the years. Now, if
you were to go back to semantics and say, Hey,
were we top down, bottom up? Those are just
semantics, I would say we were actually... If
you really think about it, we were neither.
Because bottom up you could always through
certain channels, voice information. Again,
if you didn't self-center and you were not
afraid to poke the bear, you had an ability
to voice information. So from that sense,
lots of information that came bottom up. But
then at the same time, there was also a lot of
conviction and intuition and context that came top
down. And because for a lot of these decisions,
there was so much conversation. The reality is I
think the way we operate was actually somewhere
more towards the middle on a day-to-day basis.
Which is why for me, I thought it was great.
We had a boss on the podcast, CTO of Meta. And
I always thought of Meta as a very bottom up
organization where anyone can run experiments,
they're shipping things all the time. He's like,
no, we're very top down. We tell people,
here's the things we're building this year.
Here's our big bets, here's what we're going
to prioritize. And so I think to your point,
a lot of people don't necessarily understand
what that means and see things as bottom up
versus top down. Any other pros and cons? Just
real quick on working this way? I think a lot
of people are... A lot of founders are like, maybe
I should move my company this way. Maybe I should
just be involved in everything. Maybe we need
to move PMs to product marketing managers. Is
there anything else that's maybe a pro or a con
in this approach that might be worth sharing?
Yeah. I mean, I think what you need to recognize,
right? Is which decisions and what part of the
company do you have special... Like do you spike
on and where you have edge and where you can help
make the best decision. And then I would argue
then as a leader, then it is your job to be
involved in those decisions, right? For Brian, he
always spiked in product, in design and marketing,
right? So he was very natural. He was
basically the CPO, right? That's why he
was in all those decisions because those were
his spikes and that's where he helped everybody
move forward in a certain direction.
I think for founders, you just need
to recognize what do you spike on? What
are the specific things that you have,
this great insight that other people do not and
immerse yourself in a lot of those decisions,
right? And there's some things that you might
need to let go of, right? That are maybe not
as important or maybe certain things that you
won't add much to the conversation, and you
have someone who you trust who's going to uphold
a certain quality bar or whatever, whatever. So
it's just being thoughtful about where you spend
your time and leverage your strengths, basically.
Final question along these lines,
very specifically around this whole
product marketing manager move. To me,
it feels like mostly like a rebrand of
PM with some marketing work. And in my eyes, PMs
already should be doing marketing and thinking
about adoption and growth and all these
things. And so I'm curious, just your take,
do you think this is the future for PMs in
general? Do you think this is just a funny
thing that Airbnb is trying and it doesn't really
make a big [inaudible 01:23:42] on just this
idea of PMs should be product marketing
managers and we don't need PMs as PMs?
I kind of felt like... And I was reading about
this in the news when it blew up. I mean it felt
a little overblown me, to be honest. Just
like you said, a lot of PMs at the company
were thinking about how to talk to users about
the products they were shipping, and they were
basically marketers to some degree, right? So
I would say the rebranding of product manager,
it did do some important things like shed project
management and establish an entire function that
focused on making sure things are moving in the
right direction from a project perspective. And
it highlighted the importance of marketing or
maybe just it wasn't as highlighted before,
but it was already happening at the company. So
for a lot of the product leaders at the company,
it was very liberating. Because now you
actually don't need to worry as much about,
let's say timelines and coordinating things across
teams and departments and functions, that there's
a function that does that, and your job is a
lot more user-centric and thinking through how
to tell the world about what you're building.
And so it was a welcome change broadly. Now,
does that apply to every company and
PMs do things this exact way? No,
it depends. I think it's actually challenging
to find product managers who are also really
good marketers. And so I think it's actually
a rare skill set. The art of marketing and
the art of talking, conveying what you're
building in a compelling way to people,
it's a craft on its own, and you have to build
that over time. And so there are many product
managers that haven't exercised that craft. And
so of course they can't just immediately snap
their fingers and become good at it, right? It
takes years to learn that skill. So it kind of,
again, depends on the people, it depends
on the organization. There's no blanket
statement in my opinion where it's like PMM is
the way or PM plus PMM is the way, it depends.
And just to clarify the function
you mentioned that kind of took
off some of the load of PM is
program management, I think is-
Program management. Yes.
And they basically took on
timelines staying on top of
priorities and the project
manager part of the PM role?
Exactly.
Awesome. If you think about it this way,
it's actually the best version of the
product management function, not dealing with the
project management and thinking about the product,
the experience, the launch, the
marketing, growth. It's pretty-
I mean, we had many product
managers internally always say, oh,
we feel like we're doing very tactical work.
We want to be much more strategic. And boom,
this change actually makes the job significantly
more strategic if you weren't doing that already.
Awesome. Okay, I'm glad we spent time on
that. One last question before we get to
very exciting lightning round. We've talked
about so many things that have gone really
well. You incredibly successful, leader, person,
PM. You've worked on so many successful projects,
all these skills you've worked on that
have been really helpful to you that
we've been talking about. I want to take us
to Failure Corner. I'm curious if there's a
story of failure that you could share where
you failed at some point in your career and
what that was and how that impacted you, how
that helped you potentially in your career?
I failed a lot. We've talked about the positives.
There were also on my journey, a lot of humbling
moments, still have them, lots of failure. I
would say the one moment I remember, this was
probably in 2018-ish. This was at Airbnb. It was
a pretty dark time for me, and I felt overworked,
overwhelmed, and I just wasn't a happy person.
This was a time where we were still scaling very,
very quickly, and I just felt like... I don't
know, I wasn't keeping up as much as I was in
maybe the earlier days. And I remember thinking
to myself like, oh, my God, am I going to tap
out in 2018? Is this it for me? And it was just
hard for me because I was also a perfectionist.
I wanted to help as much as I could. I had
great ambitions and dreams that I like.
I'm going to keep going with Airbnb for a
very long time. And I think in that moment,
I kind of hit rock bottom at some point. And I
actually remember during that time realizing that
so much of my identity was Airbnb and my job. That
I had trouble separating myself as a human being
from my work. And just realizing that was tough.
I lost friends. I lost a lot of relationships.
I lost many of my hobbies. I didn't spend as much
time as I wanted to with my family and my parents.
And at some point I was just like, I think
in order for me to be a better leader, I just
need to be a much more balanced human being. And
that's where ironically, I started spending less
time on work and I became way more effective.
Because I was just more centered as a person.
So I reached out to people who I lost touch
with. I spent much more time with my wife and
my parents. I started gaming again, and all the
little hobbies that I lost along the way. And it
just made me happier. And because I was happier,
I felt like every hour as a result was much more
impactful at the end of the day. So yeah, that's
one thing that I think about quite a bit. Like
you can't just... It's really great when you
pour your heart and soul into something. I
think it is very fulfilling, right? Also, you
got to think about how to balance yourself as
a person. And if you lose sight of everything
else in your life, it's a recipe for disaster.
I appreciate you being really real with these. A
lot of people just share something that's not as
real. And so I appreciate you doing that. And
I love the advice of if you're going through a
really hard time right now and are feeling burnt
out and sad about your career, maybe just do less
and maybe lean into your personal life more and
that will help you be more successful in both.
Yeah. You got to find joy in the
little things again. And if you
don't find joy in little things, I don't
think you can show up with an open mind
and the curiosity that you need to be
successful in whatever job you have.
I love that. Vlad, before we get to
our very exciting lightning round,
is there anything else that you wanted to share
that's on your mind that you thought would be
good to leave listeners with? We covered
a lot, so there may not be anything left,
but is there anything just to give you a chance?
No. I mean, I'm deeply thankful for
the experiences that I've had. I mean,
I've learned so much. I look back and there
are definitely many lessons, but let's also
be real. A lot of it is luck, right? And a lot of
just stuff just happens and it happens to go your
way. So when things are hard, the one thing that
I just want to maybe share is don't be too hard on
yourself and cut yourself some slack. As long as
you're waking up and you're actually pouring your
heart and soul into something and you're truly
giving it your all, that's all you can really do.
Amazing advice. This might come up again
in our lightning round. With that Vlad,
we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
Yeah, let's do it. Let's do it.
Ding, ding, ding. First question,
what are two or three books that you
recommended most to other people?
So I love Sci-Fi, Red Rising was one of my
favorite books. And then the Silo
series. Highly, highly recommend.
What do you think of the TV
show version of the Silo series?
What's that?
There's a TV show of the Silo series now.
Read the book though. Watch it after read
the book. Reading the book is way better.
I agree. I don't know if you actually
watched the show, but it's completely
different story. It's like 90%, just a whole
new story. I don't know what's going on there.
Foundation is similar. I don't know what
they're doing these days, movies, crazy.
Amazing. Okay. Do you have a favorite recent
movie or TV show that you've really enjoyed?
There's a TV show that I've enjoyed for a very
long part of my life. It's called Survivor.
I've heard of it.
Everyone's probably heard of Survivor at
this point. The show is not dying. It is
actually very fun to watch and there's
new twist every single season. And so
I've probably watched, I think 35 seasons or so.
That's out of control. Do you feel like you
would do well in Survivor if you were to go?
Well, I think I would do well.
My wife thinks I would die.
[inaudible 01:32:50] to find out.
Okay, if I can nominate you for Survivor,
I'll [inaudible 01:32:54]. As long
as you don't die. Next question,
do you have a favorite product that you've
recently discovered that you really enjoy?
So one is actually a product that I cannot
live without. I discovered it in 2016. Discord,
I cannot live without Discord. It is one
of the products that I use for hours and
hours every single day. I'm in all these
gaming communities and it's so much fun.
I love that you use it for gaming, not for crypto.
Just chatting with players and actually
hanging out. Yeah, love Discord. The product
that I recently got introduced to is a game. It's
actually a pseudo board- ish game called Gobbler.
It's an advanced version of Tic-tac-toe. And so
me and my four and a half year old daughter play
this before bedtime every single day. She was
just started schooling me at Tic-tac-toe. And
so I needed to upgrade. Gobbler, if you haven't
played, it adds a new dimension where pieces can
gobble other pieces. It's almost like playing
in 3D a little bit. It is super fun to play.
Wow. It's funny that she was schooling you
to Tic-tac-toe, which my understanding is
you just tie all the time. It's amazing
that she found ways to keep beating you.
Yes. I think that it says
more about me. I don't know.
Okay, Gobbler. Next question, do you have a
favorite life motto that you often think about,
repeat back to yourself, share with friends
or family [inaudible 01:34:13] in life?
You never know. And it's a very simple
motto. And what that means is to me,
even when there are things with low
probability, shoot your shot. Take a
chance. Take a leap. Sometimes you're going
to be surprised at how things turn out.
Beautiful.
Final question. A tradition at Airbnb
is to ask new folks a fun fact about themselves,
which is always a hard question on the spot,
but I'm going to ask you anyway. Is there a fun
fact about yourself that would be fun to share?
Well, I kind of shared maybe a little bit of
it. I absolutely love Survivor. And so I have
tried to get on Survivor multiple times, and
that is actually my dream to get on that show.
So if anyone out there watching who happens to
cast for Survivor, I am here. I am available.
And I will probably not do very well, but
maybe I'll be entertaining. I don't know.
This is your casting video right here.
This is it. All right. Survivor people,
let's get Vlad on. I think you would kill
it. I could see this is all the skills
we've talked about, I think would
be incredibly [inaudible 01:35:20]-
[inaudible 01:35:20] though.
[inaudible 01:35:25] the fire. Oh, my God.
Vlad, this was amazing. I'm so happy we did
this. What a special episode. I think for
everyone that listens to this episode and
goes through it all is they will and guarantee
they'll become a better leader in so many ways.
And so I'm really happy that we did this.
Two final questions. Where can folks find
you online and who would you want to
reach out to you? What kind of folks
are you working with these days? And then
finally, how can listeners be useful to you?
Hit me up if you want to chat on LinkedIn,
I'll respond and we can grab a coffee or Zoom
or something. I mean, I'm an investor now and I
love spending time with early stage founders. A
lot of those early stage founders actually
happen to be product managers at some point
in their career. So I just love chatting
with folks about the problems they're
facing or the ideas they have when they're
thinking about starting a company. So yeah,
if you're tinkering with cool things,
hit me up and would love to chat.
And is there a segment of startups you're
most focused on, just for folks to know?
I bet on people. So for me, that was always
one of my learnings. I love meeting people
that take me into a whole new dimension
that I didn't even think was possible. Now,
I do love consumer because a lot of that is my
background. And so I try to focus on consumer,
but at the end of the day, I'm
focused on people. And so I
go into many different directions
where people [inaudible 01:36:37].
Awesome. All right. And how
can listeners be useful to you?
If you want to chat, hit me up.
Cool. Healthy, find really cool
startup opportunities to invest in.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Thank you,
Lenny. Thank you so much. This was
super fun. Thank you for having me on.
It's absolutely my pleasure.
Thank you, Vlad. And bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If you
found this valuable, you can subscribe to
the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can
find all past episodes or learn more about
the show at lennyspodcast.com.
See you in the next episode.