People overlook this often.
Sometimes people are not
buying your product because it's only
half of the solution. David Ricketts,
who's a Harvard professor of innovation,
uses the example of mac and cheese.
Kraft Macaroni & Cheese dinner.
Kraft had figured out powdered
cheese to support the war effort,
but you can't really sell powdered cheese
on its own. Then they found this sales guy
who was putting the powdered cheese and a
box of macaroni together with an elastic,
literally combining them, and now you'd
buy it because it was a ready-made dinner.
I think a lot of us don't look at our
product and say, "How is it being used?"
Today, my guest is Alistair Croll. Alastair is
the author of Lean Analytics, which was one of
the most influential early books on how to use
data in helping you build your startup. He's also
multi-time founder, runs conferences all over the
world on data, AI, and technology and government,
and most importantly to me, convinced me to
leave a nice cushy job to start a company
over a decade ago, then helped me build that
startup and eventually sell it to Airbnb and,
in many ways, was one of the most central figures
in my life that led me to doing what I do now.
Lucky for us, Alistair is about to release a new
book that I am very excited about. It's called
Just Evil Enough. Essentially, it's a study of
loopholes and how to get people to pay attention
to what you've built, which increasingly is the
hardest part of launching a startup. Alistair
shares 11 specific strategies for finding
subversive ideas to get your ideas out, how
to shift your mindset to think more subversively,
why it's so essential for startups and founders
to think this way these days, plus dozens of
examples and stories that make this advice very
real. This episode is for anyone having trouble
getting anyone to pay attention to your product
or anyone thinking about starting a company
to get your mind starting to think this way.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. It's the best
way to avoid missing future episodes and
helps the podcast tremendously. With
that, I bring you Alistair Croll.
Alistair, thank you so much for
being here. Welcome to the podcast.
Thanks for having me. It's awesome to be here.
And it's awesome to have you here. We've
known each other for a very long time. You
helped me with my startup back in the day.
When I heard you were writing a new book,
especially one called Just Evil Enough,
I knew that I had to have you on here
to talk about it. I thought it'd be good
to start with just the story behind this
book. Why did you decide to write this
book? Why does this book need to exist?
Thanks. Good question. The reality is that I'm a
product manager, and I've been a product manager
all my life. Even as I've been running events,
I've been working on the products behind them.
I've worked with a ton of startups thanks to
Lean Analytics, which I'm sure we'll get into
a bit. The product managers are in many cases
missing the point. My sense is, when you talk
to a product manager, they're so consumed to
the next feature and what to do, and that's the
kind of concrete objective thing. I think many of
them are doomed because they ignore go-to-market
strategy. They ignore distribution at their peril.
The reality is that the only thing that matters
is, do you have an unfair advantage? Have you
figured out a way to capture attention and turn it
into profitable demand? That's an afterthought or
not even a thought. So the more startups and the
more founders that we can remind that distribution
matters and that subverting the norms and getting
the system to behave in a way that gives
you an advantage is important but better.
To give people some examples of the kind of
stuff that you write about in this book and
set some expectations of what we're going
to be talking about, what are some of your
favorite examples of companies that are today,
I don't know, huge, awesome, people love them,
but maybe early on did some stuff that either
people don't know about or a little subversive?
I think that's an important point. It's
not that they did something evil. It's
that they did something to use a system
in a way its creators didn't intend.
This episode is brought to you by WorkOS. If
you're building a SaaS app, at some point your
customers will start asking for enterprise
features like SAML authentication and SCIM
provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in, making
it fast and painless to add enterprise features
to your app. Their APIs are easy to understand so
that you can ship quickly and get back to building
other features. Today, hundreds of companies
are already powered by WorkOS, including ones
you probably know, like Vercel, Webflow, and
Loom. WorkOS also recently acquired Warrant,
the fine-grained authorization service. Warrant's
product is based on a groundbreaking authorization
system called Zanzibar, which was originally
designed for Google to power Google Docs and
YouTube. This enables fast authorization
checks at enormous scale while maintaining
a flexible model that can be adapted to even
the most complex use cases. If you're currently
looking to build role-based access control or
other enterprise features like single sign-on,
SCIM, or user management, you should consider
WorkOS. It's a drop-in replacement for Auth0
and supports up to one million monthly
active users for free. Check it out at
WorkOS.com to learn more. That's WorkOS.com.
This episode is brought to you by Hex. If
you're a data person, you probably have to
jump between different tools to run queries,
build visualizations, write Python, and send
around a lot of screenshots and CSV files.
Hex brings everything together. Its powerful
notebook, UI, lets you analyze data in SQL,
Python, or no-code in any combination and work
together with live multiplayer and version
control. Now Hex's AI tools can generate
queries and code, create visualizations,
and even kick-start a whole analysis for you all
from natural language prompts. It's like having an
analytics co-pilot built right into where you're
already doing your work. Then when you're ready
to share, you can use Hex's drag-and-drop
App builder to configure beautiful reports
or dashboards that anyone can use. Join the
hundreds of data teams like Notion, AllTrails,
Loom, Mixpanel, and Algolia using Hex every day
to make their work more impactful. Sign up today
at hex.tech/lenny to get a 60-day free trial
of the Hex Team plan. That's hex.tech/lenny.
An obvious example is Netflix. Netflix started
out, they needed broadband. They didn't call
themselves Postalflix. They called themselves
Netflix. Clearly, they wanted to use the network.
But a lot of people forget that Blockbuster had
streaming first. Streaming wasn't a good play at
the start of the online video industry because
the penetration of broadband in the US was very
limited. So Netflix got the US Postal Service...
They misappropriated the US Postal Service and
turned it into an on-demand, very high bandwidth,
but very, very high latency broadband network by
sticking DVDs into envelopes. Blockbuster missed
that completely. That was the key. It wasn't,
"Can I stream video?" It was, "Can I get all of
North America to receive a video in two days and
use a website to order the next one?" That's an
obvious example, but there are other tactics.
I love the story of Whitney Hess when she
was launching Bumble. She used the tactic we
call the top-shelf tactic where she put up these
posters in universities as if it was made by the
university. It basically said, "No Facebook,
no Instagram, no Snapchat, no Bumble." Well,
she's exploiting this medium called university
walls, which are a really unregulated
platform for distributing your message. But
she's also sending this subversive reminder
to people that she's one of the four top
applications that the university doesn't
approve of. Nobody told her she could do that.
Is that evil? No. Is it clever? Hell yeah.
I love these examples. Just to even make this
clear to people, a lot of founders have some
kind of growth strategy. They have a sense of
how they're going to grow their product. It's
going to be, "Okay, we're going to win on SEO.
We're going to win on paid growth." What I'm
hearing from you is it's not enough to just like,
"Here's the lever, here's the engine that's going
to grow our business." What you're finding is
that most of the successful companies we know
about or the most successful found not just the
way to grow, but they did something subversive.
And often it's something unprecedented. A lot of
these tricks are now known. There was a time when
things like an invite list, where if you invite
someone, you get an earlier spot in the invite,
there was a time that was the first time.
The Dropbox model of when you invite someone,
you both get more storage. That was cool
the first time. If it works, it just becomes
marketing. If it doesn't work or it becomes
illegal, you stop doing it. So the key isn't,
"Go do those things." By all means do the things
that work. The key is to go find your own.
I think that finding that go-to-market
strategy, that unfair, unprecedented,
we call them zero-day marketing exploits, is as
important as building the right product feature,
having a seamless onboarding process and
so on. So my co-author, Emily, and I,
it turns out we've both been obsessed with this
stuff for the last 10 years. So we met and started
comparing notes. Emily lives in Ireland, and
so she has a whole list of examples I hadn't
heard of and vice versa. So it was really fun
to... Even between Europe and North America,
there are tactics that have worked there that
are untried in the North American market.
Awesome. The book is called Just Evil
Enough. I know it's important to you
for people to understand. It's not like, be
evil, do evil things. It's just evil enough,
just a tiny bit of sliver of do something that
people don't expect or that's taking advantage of.
Well, there's a reason for that, too.
By definition, your startup is like a
disagreement with the status quo, and the
status quo was created by those in power,
so they're naturally not going to like it when
you don't play by their rules. They very quickly
label you as evil. So the name's kind of tongue
in cheek. It definitely gets people's attention.
But the rules and the lessons in there...
There's a line that we didn't quote in the
book from an old song by Chris de Burgh. I
think we didn't want to pay royalty rights
for it. It's called Spanish Train. At the end of
the song he says, "And far away in some recess,
the Lord and the Devil are now playing chess.
The Devil still cheats and wins more souls. As
for the Lord, well, he's just doing his best." I
thought, a lot of times people on the right side
of history believe their causes are so just that
they let them speak for themselves as opposed to
realizing they have to fight for them. We think
it's pretty important that, even if you are coming
at it from a position that you believe is very
valuable and useful, you still have to recognize
that you're going to have to get the world to
behave in a different way if you're going to win.
As we were starting to record this, I didn't
actually know this until just a few minutes ago
that the title of the book and the concept
originated with when we were working on my
startup and the advice you gave me. Can you talk
about that? Because I didn't actually know this.
Years ago, you and I were part of a startup
accelerator called Year One Labs. It was built
on this new idea called The Lean Startup. Ben
Yoskovitz, I think, one of the other founders
with whom I wrote Lean Analytics, had fallen in
love with this new Lean Startup methodology. So
Ben was kind of obsessed with this idea of The
Lean Startup, this new book from Eric Ries, that
said that the goal wasn't to lock yourself away
in a garage for a year and build something nobody
wanted. You should get out of the room and test it
and so on. A lot of the accelerators at the time,
you'd come in for 90 days and you'd kind of polish
the product and hope it sells. So we said, "No,
let's do it in a period of a year." So I
think we convinced you to move to chilly
Montreal in February from San Diego
from Webmetrics to launch LocalMind.
December.
December, right. I just remember-
[inaudible 00:11:37] Igloofest.
... the Igloofest in February with the frozen
eyebrows. Canada is as cold as they say,
folks. As far as I remember it, LocalMind was this
product that would let strangers answer questions
about a place. For example, where's a good place
to get coffee in Times Square? You guys had tested
whether strangers would answer questions by
geofencing tweets and then asking strangers
a question and seeing what percentage would
answer. It was like 95% of people would answer,
which was great. Then you found the problem
was that people weren't asking questions,
and you kind of hit a roadblock. We were
suggesting that you fake-asking questions
on the platform so people could get a sense
of what it was like to answer questions.
As far as I remember the question, we had a
conversation about whether this was evil. You
said, "I'm not evil." I think I said, "I'm
not saying be evil. I'm saying be just evil
enough." That always stuck with me because it is
so important to understand the boundaries of what
you can do if you are essentially disagreeing
with the status quo in order to prove that
your idea's better. So I've always talked about
this idea of not being evil but being just evil
enough to provoke the change that's required
for your product or startup to be successful.
Thanks for sharing that. I
do remember that, actually.
The other phrase I remember from the conversation
was that someone said, "We're being Boy Scouts.
We're being too much of a Boy Scout," and
that really helped us think a little more-
I think that might've been Ray Luk.
Yeah, that sounds like Ray. Oh, man. What's
interesting is once we started doing that,
sending questions to people in a location that
were from the app itself, we realized we could
collect data about what's going on there. This was
just passive data about what's happening in a bar
or restaurant. It's kind of like what... I don't
know if you get this in Google Maps, Google Maps
does this now, when you leave a place, they're
like, "What was it like here?" through the app.
Yeah, "Or was the bus crowded?" I was talking to
Scott Belsky about Behance. I know you've had him
on before. We were both speaking at Techstars in
New York a little while back. He said that for the
launch of Behance, he reached out and asked all
these influential designers to join his platform,
and they said no. Then he said, "Oh, okay, pivot."
"Hey, I'd like to do an interview about you for my
platform," and they said, "Oh, sure." He said, "By
the way, is it okay if we go and grab your design
content for the blog post?" "Oh, yeah, sure." But
the added advantage of that wasn't just the social
proof of having all these famous people on the
platform. It was that people who then followed
could see how these famous people had done their
templates, so it gave the new users a sense of how
to behave when they got there. So in your case,
asking questions yourself shows people the kinds
of questions to ask. It's obviously one of the
good strategies for fixing a cold start problem.
So say at this point people are convinced,
"Okay, I need to think about some way
to think a little more creatively, be just
evil enough with the way I'm thinking about
growing my startup and my product." Let's
talk about how to actually go about doing
this. Say a founder or a product person is
sitting down, "Okay, I want to think of some
ideas," what are some steps that you recommend
folks go about to come up with some ideas?
The underlying idea of the book is that you've
got to get the system to behave in a way its
creators didn't intend. That's a hugely important
idea. But to do that, you need to understand your
startup is a disagreement with the status quo,
so you got to recognize what is the status quo.
The first thing that we talk about is this
idea of system awareness, to be aware of the
system you're in and understand it, and then to
find a novel approach within that system. Then,
and this is often really difficult for startups,
to be disagreeable enough to be willing to do
something others either can't or won't. So
we think of subversiveness as a skill you can
learn. We spend a lot of time understanding
it, talking to neuroscientists, and finding
examples throughout to history. It comes from
system awareness, novelty and disagreeability.
One of my favorite examples of system awareness
is a Stanford prof named Tina Seelig. She gave the
Stanford engineering entrepreneur class $5.00 in
seed capital, five days to figure out what to do,
and two hours to do it. Then each team in the
class would come back for three minutes and
present to the class and say how they had turned
that $5.00 into the maximum revenue. It's a great
idea. So most people, if you ask them how to do
that, they're going to go out and they're going to
buy a lottery ticket or they're going to buy some
lemonade ingredients and set up a lemonade stand.
Some of these students, they're Stanford
graduate students, they're pretty smart.
Some of them went and got bike pumps, and they
offered to test people's bike pressure for free
and then pump it up for some money. It turns
out they made even more money when they asked
for a donation. They did pretty well. They
turned their five bucks into like 200 bucks.
Another class did a slightly different thing.
They went to restaurants and stood in line at
fancy restaurants and got the pagers and then
sold their space in line during premium lunch
hours. They made about $250. It's a good
exercise. Talk about a thing, if you want
to find out if your team can innovate, try
this with your company, whether you're a big
company or a small company. I guarantee you
people will suddenly realize how hard it is
to go to market. The winning team made $650, $605,
somewhere in that range. You know what they did?
I'm so curious to hear.
What would you do?
Oh my god, I can't even. [inaudible 00:17:03]-
Let me recap because this is important. You got
$5.00 in seed capital, you got five days to plan,
two hours to execute, and then you're going to
present your findings in front of this class,
the graduate class of Stanford
entrepreneurship for three minutes.
So I listed four things there. The winning
class sold its three minutes to a company
that wanted to recruit Stanford grads.
It's brilliant, right? They made an ad.
[inaudible 00:17:30].
What are you going to say as the professor? "Okay,
yeah, well done," because they recognized the
system they were in. They took a step back
from what they were told they had and they
looked at what they actually had. So I think
that's a great example of system awareness,
seeing the big picture of what you're in.
Once you see the big picture, now it's time
to mess with things. This is the second thing,
which is like novelty. There's a great example,
Gymshark, which is a pretty big athleisure,
athletic wear company in Europe, not so big
in North America. They're great with messing with
social media. Right around the time that Camo came
out, they had a bunch of B-list celebrities wish
a guy named Jim Shark a happy birthday. Then they,
of course, put... I think three or four weeks
later, Camo added 6,000 words to their terms of
service for consumer videos. Gymshark had all
these celebrities wishing Jim Shark a happy
birthday. That's like, "Hey, we noticed
that our name was a homonym for some guy,
and people in North America don't
know who we are." Is that silly? Sure.
Even reverse graffiti. There's companies that
would start to spray signs on the floor, like the
British Intelligence Agency did a recruiting ad,
spraying it on the sidewalk because there's no log
against cleaning up, so they just got a spray hose
and wrote stuff. I know these sound like silly
ideas. Even Coinbase. Coinbase bought a 60-second
Super Bowl ad where they bounced a QR code around
the screen for 60 seconds. Is it stupid? Yeah.
They were ranked the worst of 64 Super Bowl ads.
But they got 20 million hits, and their servers
fell over. So that's a novelty thing. Just seeing
a thing that's different, zagging when everyone
else is zigging. So if you're aware of the system
and you find a novel way to do it, that's like
two-thirds of the way to being subversive.
A lot of these sound like they're these
one-off marketing stunts where you probably,
like the Coinbase example, drive a bunch
of traffic to your site, it's awesome,
you do really well, and then it kind of fades
away. I kind of call these things turbo boosts
where you can just boost growth for a little
bit and then they go away. Is there thoughts
you have around just the value of something
like that versus you also need to figure out
a way that grows your product sustainably, like a
paid growth engine or SEO or something like that?
Absolutely. There are lots of examples.
I'm giving you funny examples for this.
But the companies that do well are the
ones that use this kind of thinking to
change their value chain. Think about
furniture. For thousands of years,
furniture was something that you described and
then someone built, and then they delivered to
your house. That was furniture. Then IKEA went,
"Hey, if we flat pack this stuff and change the
design, we can put it in containers, people can
build it themselves at home." So they took the
value chain of furniture creation and they
messed with it. In that case, they delegated
one of the stages of furniture creation to
someone else. That completely changed the
furniture industry. So that's not a one-off thing.
The trick is to find these kinds of approaches
that are fundamental to your business
model. For that, you have to look at,
how do you differentiate? Like what do you do
for reframing? How do you change the manner in
which the product's delivered? Who's doing
it? Who provides certain steps and so on?
So we get into that a little later once
we get beyond the idea of subversiveness.
Awesome, okay. What I love about this
advice is helpful both for your actual
long-term growth strategy and
also to just drive spikes of
growth when you're looking for
ideas there [inaudible 00:21:01].
For sure. That's one of the distinctions
we draw. Some of these sound like growth
hacks. I'm not a big fan of growth hacks. A
growth hack traditionally is sort of product
agnostic. So when you move your mouse off the
screen and it pops up a little window saying,
"Hey, why are you leaving?" there was a time that
was cool. Now that mouse doesn't care what kind
of website you are. We like the term zero-day
marketing exploits because it's the difference
between a script kiddie and a proper hacker.
In this case, it's like the difference between
a growth hacker and someone who is genuinely
trying to subvert the dynamics of the industry
they're in. That takes a very big perspective.
I'll give you another example that I love. There's
a researcher named Zachary Hambrick who did
some work with sailors as the Navy was trying to
restructure how it hired. He gave the sailors this
dashboard. It had four quadrants. One corner was a
fuel gauge, and when it got to a level, you had to
press a button. One was add two numbers together.
One was like some word thing. One was press a
tone. In the middle was a scoreboard. So your
job was to monitor these four consoles and try and
maximize your score. So as soon as it needed your
attention, you'd attend to it. Then unbeknownst
to these sailors, about halfway through the test,
he changed the scoring so that one of
the four quadrants represented 75% of
the points. So now doing the math would get
you more points. Some of the sailors changed
their behavior. They recognized this one
thing was contributing more. They hammered
on it and they'd do really well. Other sailors
did what they were told, super conscientious.
Now, the Navy has always recruited in the
military people who do what they're told
and are super conscientious. Turns out the people
that don't do that, we call them disagreeable. We
say they're sloppy. But there's a difference
here between people who are playing the game
right and people who are questioning
whether they're playing the right game.
One of the things I love as an example of
this is poker. In poker there are rules.
The rules tell you which cards win, which hands
are stronger, whose turn of play it is. But the
strength of your cards isn't how you win in poker.
If that's how we played, it would just be a game
of statistics and it would be incredibly boring.
You win by bluffing. You win by subterfuge. You
win by looking for your opponent's tells. But
we never talk about that in business school.
There's this woman from the 1600s. Her name is
Deu-la-Deu Martins. She was married to the king
of a city state who went to war. She was left
behind to guard the castle. The enemy shows up,
and the castle is pretty well fortified. She
realizes they have about two weeks worth of food,
and then they're going to get captured. So she
rounds up all the flour in the castle. She bakes
a bunch of bread. She goes up to the parapets,
and she throws it over into the awaiting army
and says, "You look hungry. Let us know if
you need some more food." And the army leaves.
That's a very valid strategy, but we don't
talk about those kinds of strategies. Was
it evil? No. Was it clever? Yeah. The coat
of arms of this town is two crossed loaves
of bread. But we don't talk about that kind of
thinking in business and in startups enough. I
think I'd like to normalize this kind of
disagreeable thinking, this idea that...
I know from listening to your Evan LaPointe
podcast that you're high on agreeable thinking,
so I'm here to tell you, you need to
embrace some disagreeability, Lenny.
I'm glad that you're here to help me there. This
also reminds me of my chat with Rory Sutherland,
who's extremely good at this. One very
tactical piece of advice he had is spend
a lot of time on doing the things everyone
all agrees on is the smart thing to do.
Then once you've done that, set time
aside to do the things that are very
irrational and crazy. Thoughts on that just
as a way to find time [inaudible 00:24:54].
Well, I love Rory. In fact, Emily and
I are meeting him in London for dinner.
Amazing.
He read the book and said some
very nice things about it.
I love that.
I think Rory's example of the wine list, which
you've probably heard, the wine list is a system.
I can't sell you a gin and tonic for 50 bucks
because you know how much it costs to make one.
But I can sell you wine for any price because you
can't make it that way. But when someone shows up
at the table with a wine list and hands it to
the most powerful looking person at the table
who opens it and says, "Red or white?" you
have now all consented to order wine. So the
wine industry and the wine in a restaurant is a
system, and you're beholden to it. I think Rory,
more than maybe anyone in the world... I asked
Emily who her perfect... who would she want to
read this book if it was anyone, and she said
"Rory." I think more than anyone in the world,
he just sees the world through these
system lenses that are incredible.
I love this idea of zero-day exploits
that you've mentioned a couple times.
Is there anything else there just as a
way to think about how to come up with
clever ideas to grow your product and business?
I would say, once you've got the subversive
mindset, which again is like system awareness,
novelty and disagreeability, then you have
to kind of scan the market. We have this
framework called the Recon Canvas that splits
the market up into the product, the medium,
and the market. That's another hot take of mine
is I think that product market fit's overrated.
You have to actually think about product medium
market fit. Marketing textbooks were written in
a time when the medium was one-way, one-to-many
paid broadcast. That's completely changed. Today,
it's any-to-any. It's perfectly valid to build an
audience first, then figure out what to sell it,
then make the product. But we still talk about
product market fit. Two companies with the
same product sold to the market, one wins and the
other doesn't. It's often because of their medium
strategy. The medium is both the platforms
you're in and the norms of that platform.
So we have this thing called the Recon Canvas that
helps you scan across the product, the market,
and the medium. If you want inspiration
for some clever ideas, I think Burger
King is better than almost anybody at this
stuff. When they launched their mobile app,
the thing you want for your mobile app is you
want as many installs as possible and you want
geolocation turned on. So they said, "Everyone can
have a free Whopper, just order it from the app,
drive to the store, and pick it up. But the catch
is you got to order it from a McDonald's parking
lot." That's genius, right? They also edited the
Wikipedia page for the description of the Whopper,
and then made all the home speakers go read it by
making an ad that said, "Hey, okay, Google, what's
in a Whopper?" They do a whole bunch of things.
But a great example of their understanding of
the medium, in 2019, they started liking all
these posts from influential posters from 10
years before, and they offered no explanation.
People are like, "Hey, Burger King, why are you
liking my old posts?" Because the reality is
if someone likes your posts from 10 years ago,
it's either a bot, a stalker, or you're about
to get sued. It's probably one of those three
things. So Burger King starts liking these
things. Now, if Burger King had just liked that
person's latest post, they would've missed it.
Someone likes one of your posts, you have enough
followers that it may get lost in the noise. But
if it's something from 10 years ago, because of
the mechanics of the platform, you'll see it.
Burger King says nothing. Influencers start
getting upset, "What's going on? What's going
on?" Then finally the reveal, they say, "Hey,
we've been liking some things from 10 years ago
because sometimes the past is great. You know
what else is great? Funnel cake fries and we're
bringing them back." Millions of free impressions,
not just because they understood that they had
a funny message, but because they understood
the mechanism of the platform, that by liking
something from the past, someone would notice
it. So understanding the mechanics of the
platform, the norms of the platform and what
are done there is so important to a got-to-market
strategy these days, but we think it often gets
overlooked. So to answer your question, I think
scanning for opportunities across product, across
market and across medium, and we spend a lot of
time in the book talking about how to do that.
This Recon Canvas, I know it's hard to visualize
a canvas grid thing, and we'll link to it in the
show notes, but just to help people get a
better sense of what they're going to be
thinking about to scan the market, there's
three columns, is that how you describe it?
Yeah. The canvas actually has three rows.
Three rows.
That's because there's an objective, a collective,
and a subjective way to look at the world. Then
it has a section for product, which we
divide into the features and the messages,
a section for the medium, which is the platforms
and the norms, and then a section for the market,
which is the attention you capture and
the actions you create. So it's a really
good checklist when you're putting
together your go-to-market strategy.
Make sure you've thought about all of
those, what winds up being 18 squares.
The idea is you look within each
of these cross-sections to see
if there's an opportunity to do something a
little subversive and [inaudible 00:29:52].
Right. You go into each square and you say,
"What's the status quo here? What's the
normal behavior?" what we considered
unorthodox or unusual. We have five or six
case studies for each of those rectangles.
There's like 160 case studies in the book.
There's a reason it took so long to write.
As you were talking about medium, I think of
a recent example of a really clever marketing
stunt/subversive tactic. This company Runway,
basically it helps you track your company's runway
and finances and things like that. They did this
really clever strategy where they sent all these
influencer types on Twitter a package. It arrives.
It's a bag with a lock on it, and the lock
says, "This will open in three days," and
there's a countdown that's counting down,
and you can't look inside until this lock
unlocks. So everyone on Twitter's just like,
"What the hell is this? I got this lock. I don't
know what's inside. I don't know if I should break
it open or just wait." The way I think about this
is when someone gets their mail, they in theory
open it immediately to see what's inside. So they
found a really clever way to make it a moment,
like a launch event, where everyone unlocks
it and then starts tweeting, "Oh my God, I got
this sweet bomber jacket and all the swag." Now
Runway's doing some awesome [inaudible 00:30:58].
Yeah, it's forced unboxing. When Ben and
I wrote Lean Analytics, we came up with a
strategy to announce the book. We found about 15
people that we knew who would talk about it in
say nice things, [inaudible 00:31:10], Eric Ries,
Tim O'Reilly. Over a period of about seven days,
we sent each of them a scheduled message with a
click-to-tweet message. So, about every 12 hours,
one of them would tweet something about it.
But each of those things had an analytics tag,
a Google Analytics tag in it, so it was like
UTM_campaign equals Eric Ries, campaign equals Tim
O'Reilly. So now we knew who was doing it, Julian
Smith and so on. So every 12 hours it'd be a new
thing, a little more lift, a little more lift.
Then when they were all out there, we started
comparing them to one another. "Well, more
people are clicking Julian's, but more people
are pre-ordering Tim's." Then these guys started
competing with one another. That's our second
hack. Then the third hack was we documented all
this, and then we wrote a blog post explaining how
we hacked the launch of Lean Analytics that
was proof that we knew how to do analytics.
I think there's a certain amount of credibility
in brand building that comes from how you do this.
You're sending a message to the market. Burger
King is sending a message to the market, and it's
pretty cheeky that it's the underdog, which
is very consistent. Liquid Death has some
hilarious marketing campaigns. We can't tell
you how, there's a bunch of things people told
us that we can't actually attribute, but they
do not go ahead with a campaign or an ad unless
it gets 50% disapproval. That's like their
North Star metric: 50% of people hate this.
That's awesome. I love that just as
a heuristic for how to know if your
thing is subversive enough. Is there anything
else along the lines of just someone's like,
"Okay, I want to think of ideas to come
up with really clever subversive ideas,
get people's attention"? You've talked
about this Recon Canvas that basically
gives you a whole bunch of areas to look.
Is there anything else along those lines?
Well, the real meat of the book, once
you get beyond the Recon Canvas and
this subversive thinking stuff, we looked
through probably 300 or 400 case studies,
about 160 made it into the book. These aren't
just case studies from business. They're also
things like Genghis Khan and Deu-la-Deu Martins,
Nevil Maskelyne, who was hired by Big Telegraph
to stop the spread of the radio. There are
some crazy stories out there. Billy Butlin,
who convinced the British to pay for all his theme
camps so he could become a holiday camp king in
England. What we found was these 11 tactics that
keep showing up again and again as patterns or
meta-patterns. You can't steal the tactic, but
you can apply that tactic. So if you can figure
out how to get this disagreeable mindset and
then you can scan your market, your products,
and your medium for these vulnerabilities,
and then you can apply one of these tactics,
that's a very good method for coming up with
a set of candidate go-to-market X or zero-day
exploits. Then we have some rules for how to
prune through them and figure out the good one.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta.
When it comes to ensuring your company has
top notch security practices, things get
complicated fast. Now you can assess risk,
secure the trust of your customers, and
automate compliance for SOC 2, ISO 27001,
HIPAA and more with a single platform, Vanta.
Vanta's market leading trust management platform
helps you continuously monitor compliance
alongside reporting and tracking risks. Plus,
you can save hours by completing
security questionnaires with Vanta
AI. Join thousands of global companies that
use Vanta to automate evidence collection,
unify risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go to
vanta.com/lenny. That's V-A-N-T-A.com/lenny.
Well, let's talk about these tactics. I love
that that's where you went. I know that it's
going to be hard for people to remember here's
all these 11 ways. I know the book gets
into all these things, but can you just
either run through them real quickly or
just go through them [inaudible 00:35:08]?
I'll give you a quick one. Salesforce.com is a
classic example of bug into feature. Salesforce
had a crappy product at the start of the internet.
It was using this thing called AJAX that kind of
made the web interactive a little bit if you
reload it often enough. But it turns out that
that also made them really simple. They were
competing against these companies, like Vantive
and Clarify and Remedy, that cost millions and
millions of dollars, took years to install,
whereas they could be installed with a URL. So
they took their weakness, which was, "We are very
low feature," their bug, their weakness, which
is, "We have a very limited feature set," and
they turned it into an asset, which is, "We are
simple." In fact, Salesforce's logo for all was No
Software despite the fact that they have their own
programming language. So that's a good example of
looking at your weaknesses and turning them into
strengths. That pattern shows up again and again.
Before you move on to the next one, just to
highlight that one. I love that one. Basically,
the idea there is think about, what's the
limitation? Were you behind or potentially
worse than your competitors? Then think
about, how can we turn that into a benefit?
Often it's not that you have to turn it into a
benefit. It's that it's already a benefit for
a target market you have ignored. If your
product takes a lot of time to configure,
maybe there are prosumers out there who are
white labeling that stuff. "Oh, okay, that's
a new segment." So it's this whole strategy. I'm
a product manager. Our tendency is to want to make
the product just one more feature. The reality
is your product may already be a perfect fit for
a market you're ignoring. In fact, one of the
tactics is called buyer upgrade. Buyer upgrade
is where you are already selling the perfect
thing, you're just selling to the wrong person.
Mr. Clean's Magic Eraser started out as melamine
foam for aircraft insulation until the company
noticed that people were wetting it and using it
to clean stains off things. It turns out there's
a much better market, which is people want to
clean stuff, an apocryphal example. I was talking
to a company that was selling drones invented for
bridge inspection. Bridge inspection is actually
a really dangerous job. There are people who are
continuously exploring the bridge for cracks and
stuff. The city council doesn't really want to pay
for it. It's a cost. If they find something wrong,
well, they're going to have to fix it. Who does
care? It turns out the insurance companies. So if
you go sell to an insurance company and you
say, "Look, just don't sign off on bridges
unless they have this drone," you have 100%
close rate with everybody who needs insurance
for their bridge. That's a good example
of figuring out how to upgrade your buyer.
There's a great example of this. Hitachi makes
a personal massager. You may have heard of this
device. Hitachi was not selling a lot of these
personal massagers. But it turns out there's
a very specific use case for these personal
massagers that the Japanese management company
did not want to mention. So they partnered
with a company called Vibratex with the only
condition being that Vibratex is not allowed to
mention that the product was made by Hitachi. So
sometimes the buyer upgrade is getting out
of your own way. But that's a tactic that
people don't often think about. We're sort
of stuck with our target market. There's a
sense of "We were wrong" when you acknowledge
that a different market wants your product.
Amazing example. So the tactic
here, just to mirror back,
is if your product isn't working for people
that you're trying to sell it to today,
maybe there's a different market that loves
it. You don't have to change anything about
what you're actually building. It's just
a different target market. It's a tactic-
Or even a different buyer.
A different buyer at the
same company, essentially.
Yeah.
Awesome.
In fact, at Coradiant, we used to make this
web performance analysis thing. It took me
years to figure out we should stop selling
it to operations and start selling to the
marketing department. Then I learned to say,
"Analytics shows you what people did. We show
you if they could do it." Within three months,
Fidelity, Salesforce, and LinkedIn had bought
our biggest product, just because I learned
how to explain it to a different customer.
Great example. What else?
Access is another one. Now, this sounds
obvious, right? Do you have access to
something other people don't? You got to be
careful here. Generally, rich white dudes like
us have access to people that others don't. But
it's important to mention that this is a tactic
because often people have some kind of access.
Jessica Scorpio, when she was launching Getaround,
which was a car rental-by-owner service, she
had access to one of her VC's friends who had
an early Tesla Roadster. So she brought it to
CES. She let people drive it around, and it got
lots of attention. It also proved that you could
get fancier cars on the platform. MasterClass,
the founder of MasterClass went to school with
Dustin Hoffman's daughter. Use that access. It's
not necessarily there, but if you've got access,
take a step back and say, "What can I do that
other people can't in my personal network? Do I
have access to a resource at a different price?"
Oftentimes, that's the thing that gives someone an
advantage, but we're kind of ashamed to admit it.
An example of Runway shared, I think one of the,
I don't know, levers the founder had is he knew a
lot of fancy people. So he's like, "Hey, I'm going
to send you something. Can I have your address?"
Oh, for sure. Before Bumble with Tinder,
Whitney was traveling around to sororities
because she was a sister. She'd give a talk at
a sorority about her startup, and then she would
get all the girls to install it. Then she'd go
across the street to the fraternity and say,
"Hey, all the girls are on this app."
That's an access strategy. Another one,
bait and switch. This is a common strategy.
Bait and switch can be evil unless the buyer
is delighted with the thing you've switched them
for or you also deliver the thing you promised.
Just evil enough, yeah.
A classic example of this is Tupperware.
Tupperware promoted dinner parties in post-war
America where women were being told to go back to
the home after having helped out in the war effort
and weren't very happy with that. Tupperware came
to market. There was a huge number of people out
there who wanted to run their own businesses.
So the bait was, "Hey, come to a dinner party,"
and the switch was, "Oh, by the way, become
a part of this multi-level marketing scheme."
There's a company called Energage that does
HR software. It's pretty hard to get people
excited about HR software. So they launched this
thing in conjunction with local newspapers to
promote the Best Workplaces Survey every
year. Used their tool for surveys. Every
company wants its employees to fill out
the survey. So now you have the survey,
you fill it out, and then the newspapers
published the best workplaces. They get to
sell ads to those companies. Then Energage
gets to call the companies and say, "Hey,
I've got all this data on your employees.
Wouldn't you like to see what it says?" So
that tactic of maybe the thing you're selling is
an exciting, but can you sell something that is
and then use that initial transaction to switch
to something that you actually wanted to sell?
The key, again, is they actually have to
be excited about this thing
that came up out of nowhere.
Either the bait has to be free, in which case they
[inaudible 00:42:05], or the bait has to be you
have to also give them the thing you promised, or
they'd be so happy about the thing you switched
them with that very few complain and you can
resolve those complaints [inaudible 00:42:17].
Awesome.
We make that point. Like, "Here's
how to actually not be a con man."
Great. All right, what's next?
Combination is a big one. People overlook
this often. Sometimes people are not buying
your product because it's only half of the
solution. David Ricketts, who's a Harvard
professor of innovation, uses the example of mac
and cheese. Kraft had figured out powdered cheese
to support the war effort, but you can't really
sell powdered cheese on its own. Then they found
this sales guy who was putting the powdered cheese
and a box of macaroni together with an elastic,
literally combining them, and now you'd buy it
because it was a ready-made dinner. I think a
lot of us don't look at our product and say,
"How is it being used?" There's an example,
1-800-MATTRESS in the States. They used to have
this thing where... What's the one thing you
care about that should be added to your product if
you are trying to sell mattresses to New Yorkers?
Delivery? Install? I don't know.
No, removal.
[inaudible 00:43:12] mattress.
It's really hard to get rid of a mattress in
New York City. Some people would... Like, "Oh,
yeah, we'll take away your old mattress." So
you just look at the value chain and you go,
"Wait, I'm in business of delivering and selling
mattresses." One step before you in the value
chain is get rid of the old mattress. But if
you just change your product and slide the
value chain over by one block, "We include
mattress removal." They're like, "Oh, yeah,
these guys are going to replace our mattress.
I don't want a new mattress. I want a replaced
mattress." It's that kind of mindset. So what can
you combine it with? Often, it's just before or
just after the product that dramatically
simplifies the offering for the consumer.
These are great. All right, what else?
There's a great one called arbitrage. Arbitrage is
knowing something other people don't. Obviously,
you can achieve that by lying to them. You can
achieve that by finding out sooner. There's all
kinds of ways you can commit arbitrage. One of my
favorite examples, this came to us from a guy Rob
Passarella in New York, there's something called
the Chappe optical telegraph. In, I think, 16th
century France, obviously the speed of messages is
very important for the war effort. So the French
set up this optical telegraph. It was a bunch of
towers. You could see each tower from the other.
They had these gigantic stick figure semaphores
that they would pivot to send messages. Basically,
you'd sit there and you'd look, and when that
semaphore moved, you'd write down the message and
you'd send it to the next one. This way a message
could travel across France at like 500 miles an
hour, way faster than a horse. It's great.
Of course, because there's an advantage here,
some bankers figured out how to pay off the
Chappe telegraph operator to introduce an
error in the message in Paris which would allow
the person in the stock market in Burgundy to
know what the Paris markets are doing before the
news got there and trade on it. That is too evil.
But can you find out in advance of something?
Early on in the days of certain social platforms,
the analysts were all trying to figure out,
were they actually seeing growth? It turns out
that in some of the early social platforms,
you could look at the number of the message
or the number of the user's account in the API,
and you could infer growth from that. The data's
right there. Is that illegal? Not really. It's
right there, but it's certainly an advantage.
So what can you find out early that others can't?
Now, a more concrete example, this is Farmville.
Pincus and Zuckerberg were very good friends.
Zuckerberg told Pincus that apps were going to
be allowed to post to user's timelines. This is
why Farmville grew almost overnight. At one point,
it represented a massive proportion of Facebook's
revenue is that Farmville would post these things
saying, "Hey, Lenny, Alistair needs your help
getting some grain for his cows or they're
going to die." So there's a good example of
knowing something before other people did.
I also think about the high-frequency trading and
the arbitrage they found of just moving closer to
the data centers and just buying land right next
door to where the trading [inaudible 00:46:24].
There's actually a case of the Nikkei
terminals, which computed the Nikkei
index. They weren't getting the Nikkei index
from Tokyo. It was being computed locally on
the terminal. Someone figured this out so they
could compute the Nikkei index from the source
stocks rather than waiting for the terminal to
tell them, and they could beat the market for a
significant amount of time. Rob also told us,
I think it was him, he said, "A hedge fund is
an organization formed to discover something
that will be illegal and do it until it is."
Yep. Makes me think about billions,
which feels a lot of evil.
Yeah, absolutely.
Cool. Let's do a few more.
Aggregation, this is a pattern we see over and
over again where one player in the market takes
data from many places and then modifies it in
some way. That could be that they are using it for
affiliate links, that's pretty easy, or selling
the data, not that interesting. One of my favorite
examples, and I actually helped put together a
case study at HBS when I was teaching there with
Srikant Datar, about a guy named LP Maurice.
I think you might know LP. He's a Montrealer.
I do.
He had a company called Busbud. LP was traveling
the length of South America, and he was trying to
find bus schedules, and they're almost impossible
to get. So when he got home, he decided to make an
app so you could order, kind of like Kayak for
bus rides, which doesn't sound that exciting,
but bus tickets are a multi-billion dollar
industry. So he got people around the world
to send in these bus schedules. He put them all
in one place. Then he went to the bus companies
and said, "Hey, how about you let me sell bus
tickets?" None of them wanted to hear from him.
So what he did was he used automation
to create thousands and thousands,
I think it's millions and millions of pages of bus
tables, properly structured JSON data. You had to
automate this thing. I think you actually had
to get three separate Google Analytics accounts
to manage all the data because it was beyond the
capacity of one of them. Then for search engines,
this is like catnip, like well-structured data
that's not available everywhere else. So now
he becomes the default destination because he's
aggregated the data for a particular kind of data,
bus ticket data. Then he allows you to go in and
say, "I want to go from here to here," shows you
the route. But the bus companies still aren't
going to pay him money. So he puts a button on,
it says, "Buy my ticket," and sends them
to those companies. Then the next time he
calls the companies, he goes, "Hey, have
you noticed on your analytics that 20%
of your traffic is coming from me? We should
probably talk." Now they're willing to trade.
So aggregating data, consolidating it, putting
the bait out there like the catnip for the
search engine or whatever. Sometimes this can be
done badly. One of the examples we think is too
evil is Get Satisfaction. Get Satisfaction
was a complaint site on the internet where,
basically, they went and crawled the internet
for all the complaints about Sony, and then
that's the first place you're going to complain
about Sony. Then they'd extort Sony and say,
"Unless you buy from us, we're going to tell the
customers you don't care about them." Probably
too evil. You shouldn't assume consent. But that
pattern of aggregation shows up time, and again.
It's interesting there's a trend across all
these examples you're giving, which is you're
solving actual problems for people in different
ways, and you're finding a new way to solve that
problem or help them be aware that you're solving
this problem. In this case of the bus schedules,
people really want that information, like Google
wants it, but also people want schedules that are
easy to read, and you've just found a really
interesting way to get [inaudible 00:49:51].
Almost every one of these tactics looks awesome
in hindsight. Some of these are very basic things.
One of the most basic marketing tactics, and Rory
can talk about this better than I ever could,
is reframing. When you look at positioning,
you're looking at two dimensions. Let's say for
toothpaste, you have the dimension of sex appeal,
"Fresh breath lasts all night," that was Colgate,
then you have the dimension of clinicality, which
is like, "Four of five dentists agree," that was
Crest. So in the early toothpaste wars, you had
Colgate versus Crest. You were either brushing
your teeth because you want to be sexy or brushing
your teeth because you wanted to be healthy.
Then along comes Tom's of Maine. Remember, this is
1970s, you got your tofu from a health food store.
Dr. Strangelove has lines about fluoride being
a government conspiracy. So you show up and go,
"Oh, we're unfluoridated. We're natural. We'll
tell you the ingredients on the label." You've
given a segment of the market a different,
better way to think about the value you offer.
Reframing isn't just about competing on existing
dimensions. It's about giving the customer a
different set of dimensions. That won't happen
for the whole market, but it'll happen for one
of those segments. In this case, the framing was
orthogonal. If you are a hippie natural person,
you reject clinical science and you reject
traditional beauty norms, so you're orthogonal,
you're perpendicular to both sex appeal
and healthcare. So it's a perfect position,
and Tom's of Maine used that and, obviously, two
years later introduced a fluoridated formula and
got into grocery stores or into pharmacies.
So being able to reframe things. I mentioned
Liquid Death. But when people talk about
positioning, they often look at the dimensions
of that are there and say, "How do we compete on
those?" or they go, "Hey, we're really good at
this thing. Let's make that the dimension."
The dimension only matters if a lucrative,
reachable target market thinks that it is the
dominant criteria for deciding about the product.
And is reframing one of the
tactics [inaudible 00:51:55]?
Yep, reframing would be one
of the tactics for sure.
Okay, awesome. Is it interchangeable with
positioning, or do you think of
those two [inaudible 00:52:02]?
We actually think that positioning is simply where
you are on a grid. Reframing is drawing the grid.
Got it. I have an awesome episode with
April Dunford, who's I think also Canadian-
Yep.
... where she goes deep into positioning.
I think she'd probably disagree with you
because I think to her it's
really important that when
you're positioning, you're thinking about
your competitors and how you're different.
I would argue that you can position
against your competitors. It is far better
for someone to choose you instead of rather than
over your competitors. When the electric car came
out, the traditional framing for electric cars
was range and sustainability. Then Tesla started
racing them against Bugattis. For a certain
segment of the market, meaning rich coastal VCs,
faster, better performance was a new way
to think of electric cars. Before that,
if you look at the ads from the Prius and
stuff, they didn't mention acceleration
time. They explicitly didn't put it
in there. So Tesla came up with a
much better dimension for a certain target
segment. I agree, April's absolutely right,
if you're in an established competitive market
where you're bidding for RFPs and B2B. But
if you're disagreeing with the market, you're
probably disagreeing with how it scores value.
You were talking about fluoride briefly. My
mind went to, I'm trying to decide if fluoride
is actually good or bad for our kid. There's so
many debates out there for [inaudible 00:53:27].
As a British person with all my
teeth, it's served me very well.
Okay, that's my current position. It
feels like a good thing, but there's
so much stuff out there. Ah, no
fluoride [inaudible 00:53:35].
Well, let me talk to you about regulation.
Ooh.
Regulation is like a thing people often don't
think about. In Germany and in Austria, you have
organ donor cards where you get to approve whether
or not someone gets your organs if you're killed
in an accident. German and Austrian populations
are almost identical. Austria's opt out. You're
going to deliver your organs when you die unless
you explicitly say you don't want to. In Germany,
you have to opt in. They're not donated
unless you explicitly do so. Germany has
12% organ donors. Austria has like 99.6%. So
all your growth hacks ain't going to get you
from 12% to 99.6%. So it may be important for
your business to change the regulations either
to allow what you're doing or to compel people
to do the thing that's currently optional.
But a lot of startups don't look at regulatory
change as a viable strategy, and yet it can be.
It's also a great way to find loopholes.
I love the story of parklets. For a while,
urban agitators would build these little two-hour
long parks in the parking spot in front of their
coffee shop, and every two hours they'd take
it away and put it back because the law didn't
actually say it had to be a car that was parked
there. Then there's this guy in England who said,
"I want to make a little park in front of
my house," but the law says it has to be a
car. So he built a park on a car. Then
the local town government said, "Well,
you're going to have to take your car in and get
it smog checked once a year, so it's not going
to last." So he bought this historical van that
was not required to be smog checked. So he just
has a park in front of his house that's the
back of a van parked there. Loopholes happen
all the time. We think they're funny, we think
they're clever, but there are a lot of cases
where you can find a loophole and use that to do
something possible that wasn't otherwise possible.
Let me see how many we've gone through so far.
I'm just going to go through the list so far,
and I'm curious if there's anything else.
Turning bugs into features, upgrading,
buyer upgrade, access, bait and
switch, combination, arbitrage,
aggregation, reframing, and regulation,
I think, was the last one you shared.
Then earlier on we talked about misappropriation
with Netflix, misappropriating the US Postal
Service. Then the last one is sliding the window.
Sliding the window is a bit more nebulous,
but it's about the Overton window and the realm of
what's considered acceptable. A lot of companies
have strategies that rely on a certain segment
of the market being okay with something that
wasn't. So we talk about some examples of
the normalization of gay marriage through
Will & Grace and things like that in there.
There's a good example of this. There's a
company in England, I think it's called Bodyform,
that was the first to use red liquid in ads for
female hygiene products and tampon products.
For a while it was literally illegal to use red
liquids in those ads. When they finally did it,
all the women were like... I'm telling Emily's
version of the story. One of the nice things
about having a female co-author, you get to see
a whole other perspective that isn't normally
part of a lot of marketing conversations. But
Emily's point was like, "Every single woman let
a sigh of relief. Finally, someone said the quiet
part out loud." There is a tremendous advantage to
understanding that one part of the market already
has an Overton window that's different
from the mainstream market. Then you can
appeal to that, and they will respect you for it.
Amazing. These are 11 very concrete ways to think
about ways to get above the noise, get people's
attention, be a little subversive. There's always
this talk about thinking from first principles
and thinking outside the box and being innovative
and creative. I love that you have put together,
"Here's the 11 ways that people do it." How do you
suggest people use this? Is it like get a room,
get some people together, brainstorm and
go through this list? Any advice on just
how to operationalize, coming up with
ideas knowing that they have this list.
This is somewhat magic. It takes a lot of
time. It's a skill you can learn. It's a
muscle you develop. I would say spend some
time thinking about how to be disagreeable,
understanding the system you're in, and then
use the need for novelty and disagreeability
to temporarily let yourself think like a super
villain. We have some tactics for this: ignoring
the guardrails, embracing absurdity, not pulling
your punches on wording. I've had people go,
"Oh, I can't possibly do that in my marketing."
Remember Blair Witch? Remember The Blair Witch
Project? They literally killed their actors,
well, not literally. But according to the web,
they had people out there trying to find
the actors. They listed them as missing on
their movie page. They did literally starve
their actors. They actually underfed them,
and they played weird scary noises outside their
tent at night. They even gave them conflicting
information. They got so much attention because
they were hyperbolic about how they positioned
things. Wes Kao talks about the spiky point
of view. I think those are super important.
There are some other techniques that we
found. There's this really interesting
innovation formula called TRIZ, which is a
combinatorial way of overcoming obstacles
by combining unrelated fields. There's
something called construal level theory,
which is how you bring distant ideas closer to
change how you think about them. So we go through
a lot of the neuroscience of how to pick good
exploits and brainstorm properly. Then finally,
I would say we talk a lot about pre-mortems,
figuring out how things might go wrong. Asking
counterfactuals: Is the opposite true?
Would this be better if I did it a year
ago or a year from now? What does a smart coach
conclude given the same information without you
sharing your conclusion? So there's a lot of
techniques for, how well can you test this?
What would convince you if you were wrong?
This is kind of deep canvassing yourself.
I know the book's not out yet. I'm curious if
you've worked with a startup or if a startup's
applied these tactics, if there's
a story there of something that's
emerged out of a company you've
worked with thinking this way.
I will tell you, I've worked with four startups
using this, and every one of them has found a
go-to-market strategy. It's been awesome. I
suspect that Emily and I are both going to
get a lot of consulting requests after this just
because it's really interesting to implement this.
We did a workshop at Startupfest. Startupfest
is a big conference in Montreal that I've been
running with Phil Telio for a while. We did
a workshop this summer, and people actually
had workbooks they were completing while we did
it and stuff. It's definitely applicable. Too,
I want to throw out to Wes and Gagan here
at Maven. They asked Emily and I to put
together a course, which we haven't launched
yet because we haven't finished the book yet.
It basically forced us to rewrite the book
to make it much more applicable, less about
anecdotes, more about frameworks you can use.
Yeah, I think we will have done the right thing
when I go to product management meetings, and
instead of people talking about their feature,
they're alluding to their zero-day marketing
exploit. But the dumbest thing in the world
is to talk. That's the thing you want to not
tell anyone about. But if you're talking to
an investor and you don't have a zero-day
go-to-market exploit that creates attention
and turns it into sustainable, lucrative
demand, you are probably going to fail.
This makes me think about a
tweet I just saw about how,
with AI, it's so much easier to just
build stuff, just build a quick app,
that the chance of success start to shift
more and more to distribution and growth
because it's so much easier to try stuff.
So I love that you're giving people a guide.
I do a lot of work in digital government with this
conference called FWD50. Last year, I told people,
when you're launching a battleship, you can't
push a software update and change the hull.
It's shipping. So you take the risky parts,
and you put them at the end. As a result,
you write the spec up front, and then you do
the plan for testing and all this other stuff.
But the entire pattern, every pattern we have
in the Western world for mass production of
something, whether that's software development
or shooting a movie or building a battleship,
you do the easily changed stuff up front. You
can change a feature in the spec in a day,
you can change it in the code in a week, you can
change it in production, if at all, in a month. So
thinking about what's scarce and what's abundant,
what's hard and what's easy generally informs the
process that we use to deliver any product to
market. We do not step back and say, what has
technology done to change the relative risk and
the relative fungibility of each of those steps?
If I'm building software, it may now be easier
to use an LLM and Figma to build 10 prototypes,
show them to citizens in government, see which
ones they like, and then document the one that
works. Because now documenting the thing well
that works is the risky part. That's actually
the harder part because that's what's going to
get passed by legislators and stuff. So just
because we used to write a spec in the right
code doesn't mean that's how we should do it.
I think for any organization, reevaluating the
processes that you assume are correct based on
what technology has made hard or easy, that's
how big companies fail and small companies win.
How are you leveraging these lessons
and tactics in getting your book out
and getting your book [inaudible 01:03:21].
Well, I've already told you. I'll give you an
example. Early on, we did a survey to find some
stuff out about pricing and customers and
we said, "Look, if you answer this survey,
someone will get a free hour-long consulting
Zoom presentation with us. You can use it for
your conference or whatever. We don't care." The
problem with that is you are disincentivized from
sharing that survey with other people because you
want as few people on the survey as possible. So
we created two teams, Team Orange and Team Black,
and we said we would choose the survey winner from
the survey that had the most people submitting to
it. It immediately caused people to go, "I'm Team
Orange. You should vote Team Orange." You look
at the problem, you find a way to move around it.
I will say that we have built a technology for
the readers to be able to see case studies. Each
of the case studies in the book has a QR code
next to it that takes you to a webpage that has
much more content, but also the video of the ad or
the links to the resources. So we have a list of
places where you can find weak signals to start
looking for exploits. There's a page for that,
which we can keep updating over time with new
intel. Let's just say that those case studies do
some special things. There's a tech stack behind
the case studies. It's one of the reasons that
we couldn't just go with a traditional publisher
because traditional publishers don't like it when
you have a QR code. They don't like it when
you own and retain the intellectual property
rights to the book. So in order to mess with the
world a little bit and practice what we preach,
we had to actually go through a fairly
unusual publishing [inaudible 01:04:54].
As maybe a final note, again, I want to
come back to you want to make it clear,
you're not actually saying do evil things,
do things that are going to hurt people.
Maybe just share that sentiment again because I
think it's easy for people [inaudible 01:05:10].
Sure, and we actually devoted an entire chapter
to this called Don't Actually Be Evil. There are
certain things like abuse, like assuming consent
and acting without approval, lying or using dark
patterns, breaking the law or even the intent
of it, ruining your reputation, which is usually
bad. Those are all bad things, and we say,
"Don't do them." There are some pretty egregious
examples. There's a company called Afterlife that
was crawling obituaries. Then when you'd search,
you'd find out that someone had died. Funeral
home operators were getting flowers for people
five years after the funeral. These guys
were charged in criminal court. That's pretty
obviously bad. But there's these other nuanced
examples. You know the Chrysler PT Cruiser?
Mm-hmm.
It's a terrible little car, right? It's the
worst car. Do you know why that car exists?
Mm-mm.
The PT Cruiser was actually built for a very
specific reason. It wasn't built to sell cars.
In America, every car manufacturer has to
meet fuel efficiency standards for its car
line and its truck line. It turns out that
Chrysler's trucks were terrible on fuel.
So what happens is the automakers decided
they would make this terrible little car
called the PT Cruiser that's technically a truck,
according to the definitions of a flatbed truck,
and there's certain things about it, a removable
backseat or something. I don't remember what it
is. But what it did is it brought the average
fuel consumption of Chrysler's truck line below
the federal guidelines so that it could continue
to sell bad trucks. Is that illegal? No. Is it
too evil for us? Absolutely. I think there's
lots of examples that we provide. We try to
draw an Occam's razor: Don't ever assume
consent, don't act without permission,
don't punch down, don't break the actual
law, don't use dark patterns and so on.
I love that you have touched that. I'm glad
that we came back to that point. Alistair,
is there anything else you
want to share with listeners
or leave listeners with before we get
to our very exciting lightning round?
Well, they should all buy the book,
obviously. It's dumb not to ask.
You can go to buy.justevilenough.com if
you're interested. But more importantly,
we really want to hear examples. This stuff
is just fun to talk about. Every one of these
stories is hilarious. We really wanted the book
to feel like part frameworks and useful text,
because Lean Analytics was very prescriptive
and that worked really well, but also partly
going to a cocktail party and sitting next to
a fascinating person with weird stories to tell
that you kind of learn from. If we manage to
navigate those two, then we're happy. So if
people have examples of subversive thinking they
want to share with Emily and I, we'd love to hear.
What's the best way for them to share that?
Well, justevilenough.com has a website
there. We have a few things that are
surprising that I think people will see
in the next few months as we open them up.
I'm acroll and Emily is emilyjaneross on most
platforms. So those are probably the best ways.
Okay, cool. We usually get to that at the
end, but I'm glad that people now know. I feel
like this episode's get a lot of people's minds
buzzing. I'm excited to see how people use some
of these ideas. With that, we've reached our very
exciting lightning round. Alistair, are you ready?
I am.
First question, what are two or three books
that you've recommended most to other people?
Dan Davies has a book called The Unaccountability
Machine that I have literally made an entire
conference theme out of this year. It's
fantastic. Jonathan Haidt's The Righteous Mind,
which really made me lose faith in
reason and rationality. I got to say,
the best marketing textbook ever is
Dan and Chip Heath's Made to Stick.
Is there a recent favorite movie
or TV show you've really enjoyed?
The first movie I have ever watched a second time
on the second night is David Fincher's
The Killer, which came out on Netflix,
with Michael Fassbender. It is the absolute
embodiment of self-awareness. I just loved it.
Is there a favorite product that you've
recently discovered that you really love?
This sounds silly, but yeah, I bought this
$100 folding second screen for my MacBook.
They're like 100 bucks now, and they power
off a USB-C cable that also is their HDMI
thing. I find myself much more productive
with a second screen and being able to put
one in my laptop bag that's the same size.
There's a bunch of different brands. Yeah,
just $100 second screen LED that
plugs into USB-C on your MacBook.
Is there a brand that you like best that
people can search, or it doesn't really matter?
I don't remember which
brands [inaudible 01:09:39].
And honestly-
This is another thing we didn't really talk about,
the reality of branding on Amazon. Brand
names don't matter anymore. It's like,
someone threw up on a keyboard and that's
the name of the company now for half the
products you buy on Amazon because that's
not how you actually choose the product.
There is value to a brand, but it's much
less so. If you don't know the brand,
you don't worry about it as much as you used to.
I think Anker, A-N-K-E-R, is a good example of a
company that was just one of many power companies,
but they did their packaging
right and their products right,
and now they're a well-known name. So
it takes real work to escape that trap.
Interesting. Two more questions. Do
you have a favorite life motto that
you often come back to, find
useful in work or in life?
My company, which is just me, is called
Solve for Interesting. Because all my life
when I've tried to solve for fame or for safety
or for wealth, it hasn't gone as well as when
I've just solved for what's interesting. But
I think the motto that informs things the most
that I work on these days is, "It's amazing what
can get done when nobody cares who gets credit."
These are both great. Final question. We worked
together for many years back in the day in
Montreal on my startup. I'm curious if there's
another memory that comes to mind or a story
or something that you think back
to during that time when we were
working together on this tiny,
little startup back in Montreal.
I think we went tobogganing
down a giant hill, didn't we?
Hmm, [inaudible 01:11:08].
Didn't we go up to [inaudible
01:11:09] to my mom's cottage with Eva-
Yes.
... and we went tobogganing down a giant sled?
You got into this big inner tube, is that right?
I think so. Also, the two words I learned
on that trip are toboggan and toque.
Definitely, I think, as with everything else, you
really live life large. When you got to Montreal,
you just leapt in full in, and I was just so
happy. For someone who was from San Diego...
I moved from San Diego to Montreal. That's
how we met down there. Moving to Montreal is
a lot. It's a different language. It's
a different culture. As Colbert says,
"It's Europe with normal toilets." I think it was
so great to see you jump into everything that it
had to offer for your time here, and I love the
fact that you've just kept doing that. It's great.
Thanks, Alistair. My memory of
that is I arrived at the airport,
I landed in Montreal from San Diego where
it was very warm into a winter. Ben,
who you mentioned, took me straight to a
department store to buy all my winter gear,
like an actual jacket and shoes for
the snow and stuff for my kitchen.
There is one other thing. We don't
have to put this in the recording.
Yeah, oh, okay.
So Year One Labs, we used a hackathon to bring
people in rather than the usual application
form. I don't know if you remember, it was
Sean Lynch, who has done a bunch of product
stuff but was the head of Google Cloud, came
up and we all built stuff on this new Google
Cloud platform that they wanted some users on. We
gave a bunch of the different startups a weekend
to build something. I think you went out with
someone and built a thing that used Foursquare
check-ins to figure out where people had
been before they went to a restaurant-
I forgot about that.
... and where they went after. On Friday
you said, "This is our plan." You went
off and did it. Then on Sunday, we all did
these presentations. You got up and went,
"So our product lets restaurant owners know where
their customers had been before, where they go
afterwards. Here's our beautiful slide deck. We
have a working prototype. And oh, by the way,
we sold it to three companies." Ben and Ray
and Ian and I went, "Yeah, they're probably
in." I don't know if I remember that correctly,
but that story's in my head for some reason.
I definitely remember building that. I don't
remember us selling it to anyone. I imagine
maybe we got some folks using it. But the whole
idea there was I was just always thinking about,
"How do people find out about your product?
How do people find out about your restaurant?"
I was just like, "Well, where do people most
come from before they go to your restaurant?
So maybe find that place and then go advertise
there so more people come to your restaurant."
Yeah, it was people analytics. That was like-
That's right.
... [inaudible 01:13:51] Foursquare was new.
But all three of us afterwards were like,
"Dude, even if that's a bad idea, he can
make 51 more of those and one won't suck."
It all worked out. Alistair, what a journey.
Thank you so much for being here. What a special
episode. Two final questions. You already
mentioned this, but just remind people,
where can folks find you and the book online,
and how can listeners be useful to you?
Buy.justevilenough.com if they want to pre-order
the book. We're actually going to do a bunch of
webinars for people who pre-order because we see
their email addresses, unlike when you just buy it
on Amazon. So we're planning on doing a few things
between now and when you actually get the book. So
you can buy the book on buy.justevilenough.com.
There's the usual newsletter sign up,
subscription stuff. I think the account is
EvilEnough on most social platforms. Then,
yeah, tell us your examples of subversiveness in
action. We would love to use our own aggregation
play and be a clearinghouse for subversive
thinking that doesn't suck. So we'd love to
hear all the examples we can. It's too bad
Emily couldn't join us here. She's brilliant
and hilarious, so make sure you follow her.
She's emilyjaneross on social platforms, too.
Amazing. Alistair, thank
you so much for being here.
Thank you.
Bye everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.