You have done 30 years of work and iteration
and refinement. You're here just to tell us,
"Here's the most important thing you
need to know and here's how to do it,
based on all that time I've spent." Help
us understand, what is a bullseye customer?
Every ambitious founder wants to
build a product for everybody,
but it doesn't start there. Amazon started
just selling books, or Facebook was just
profiles for college students. So a
bullseye customer is the very specific
subset of your target market who initially is
most likely to adopt your product or service.
Why this of all the things that you
can focus on of a startup journey?
It helps you get really deep in understanding
who are those people and understanding what
they need. It helps you prioritize the feedback
you're getting, and it just gets everybody as
a team much more aligned on, "What are
we doing, and what are we doing first?"
You have this Bullseye Customer Sprint
that your book describes. You basically
give people a plan for how to figure this
out in a day, which sounds like a dream.
The basic formula, the way I think about it,
is five and three in one. So it's five bullseye
customers and three very simple prototypes,
and then we conduct those interviews in
one day while the whole team is watching
and debriefing and kind of thinking about what
are the key big takeaways at the end of that.
Where do you start?
So step one is...
Today, my guest is Michael Margolis. Michael
has been a UX researcher at Google Ventures
for almost 15 years, where he's worked with
over 300 companies to help them get unstuck,
move faster and build something that people
want. He helped develop the Design Sprint method,
made famous by the book Sprint, and more
recently wrote a book called Learn More
Faster: How to Find Your Bullseye
Customer and Their Perfect Product,
which essentially helps you identify and refine
your ideal customer profile in a single day.
I've said many times on this podcast that one of
the biggest mistakes founders make and product
teams make is not being very clear and very narrow
with their initial target market, and I've been
looking for a book and a guide to help people
figure this out. This book is that. And also,
this book is completely free and available online
as a PDF. Michael is not looking to sell books or
drive leads to Google Ventures. He genuinely
simply wants people to avoid pain and avoid
wasting time building something that nobody needs.
In this episode, we go step-by-step for how to
identify your bullseye customer, how to
interview people, how to recruit people,
and how to refine your idea to build something
that people actually want. This episode is both
for founders and also for product teams at larger
companies who want to avoid building something
that nobody cares about. If you enjoy this
podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow it
in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's
the best way to avoid missing feature episodes,
and it helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you Michael Margolis.
Michael, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you so much. I'm thrilled to be here.
So we're going to be going really, really
deep on how to very clearly and also just
very quickly identify your bullseye customer,
which some people refer to as ideal customer
profile or ICP. There's differences there. We're
going to touch on that. But you wrote a whole
book about this very specific topic. I have
it right here. It's called Learn More Faster,
and the subtitle is important, How to Find Your
Bullseye Customer and Find Their Perfect Product.
And interestingly, this topic has actually
come up a bunch on recent podcast episodes,
so I've been telling guests, "Hey, we're going
to have a whole podcast episode about this very
specific topic, which I'm very excited about."
So Michael, again, thank you for being here.
Thank you a ton.
This episode is brought to you by Eppo. Eppo is a
next-generation A/B testing and feature management
platform built by alums of Airbnb and Snowflake
for modern growth teams. Companies like Twitch,
Miro, ClickUp and DraftKings rely on Eppo to
power their experiments. Experimentation is
increasingly essential for driving growth and for
understanding the performance of new features,
and Eppo helps you increase experimentation
velocity while unlocking rigorous, deep analysis
in a way that no other commercial tool does.
When I was at Airbnb, one of the things that I
loved most was our experimentation platform
where I could set up experiments easily,
troubleshoot issues, and analyze performance
all on my own. Eppo does all that and more,
with advanced statistical methods that can
help you shave weeks off experiment time and
accessible UI for diving deeper into performance
and out-of-the-box reporting that helps you
avoid annoying, prolonged analytic cycles.
Eppo also makes it easy for you to share
experiment insight with your team, sparking new
ideas for the A/B testing flywheel. Eppo powers
experimentation across every use case, including
product, growth, machine learning, monetization,
and email marketing. Check out Eppo at
geteppo.com/lenny and 10x your experiment
velocity. That's get E-P-P-O .com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Paragon,
the developer platform for building native
customer-facing integrations with third-party
apps. Are native integrations on your product
roadmap? Whether it's to ingest context from your
users' external data and documents or to sync data
and automate tasks across your users' other apps,
integrations are mission-critical
for B2B software products today.
But building these integrations in-house costs
an average of three months of engineering,
according to the 2024 State of Integrations
survey, which results in difficult roadmap
tradeoffs. This is why engineering teams at
Copy.ai, AI21 and over 100 other B2B SaaS
companies use Paragon, so they can focus
their efforts on core product features,
not integrations. The result? They've
shipped integrations seven times faster,
all while avoiding the never-ending maintenance
that comes with rolling your own integrations.
Visit useparagon.com/lenny to see
how Paragon can help you accelerate
your product's integration roadmap today,
and get $1,000 in credit on their Pro and
Enterprise plans. That's use P-A-R-A-G-O-N .com.
I want to start with giving you a chance to just
share the work that you have done over your career
that this framework and process is rooted in,
because it's based on a lot of hands-on
work with startups and founders. So just
talk about the work that you have done that
has led you to this process and framework.
Yeah, so I've been doing this kind of product
and UX work for over 30 years. So the work
that I'm going to describe here is kind of
the culmination or the synthesis of about
30-plus years of that. There are a lot of
different pieces that I've picked up along
the way and recombined and adapted for this.
So started out studying anthropology. My first
job was working in educational software as an
editor, so it was kind of introduction to UX,
my introduction to usability testing,
and went from there to working at a
boutique product design innovation studio, so
basically consulting with big companies like
Alcoa and DuPont and Ericsson, and so learning
really deep ethnographic research techniques,
very big, long, expensive consulting projects.
And then from there, I went to Walmart.com. So
going from there to Walmart.com was really
learning to take those techniques and
compress them and accelerate them. Walmart
is really all about execution, about scale,
about everyday low cost and speed, and so
I had to really compress those techniques
and make them much, much faster and learn to
combine deep ethnographic discovery work with
usability work, and getting lots and lots of reps.
From there, I went to Google. So I was embedded in
the Gmail team early on, in 2006. And so what we
did there was then combining these also at scale,
doing this kind of innovation at speed. You can
see this trend of getting faster and faster. One
of the things we did a lot there was, the way
I would do the research is with watch parties,
so teams would be able to see it. Google
had invested in lots of video conferencing,
streaming from the labs, one-way mirrors, a lot
of things early on, so the teams were involved
and they were seeing and watching this stuff.
So a lot of those techniques I brought then to GV,
to Google Ventures, when I joined in 2010. So
I was the first UX research partner in venture
capital at the time. Still, I think maybe
there was one other person in this role.
And so took a lot of those techniques and
recombined them and have adapted them and
experimented over the last 14 years, working
with hundreds of different kinds of startups.
We have a very broad variety of founders
and product people that we're working with.
So over the past 14 years, we've really
gotten to experiment and gotten to work
with them and be kind of a small piece of
the journey that they're on to learn and
answer these fundamental questions that they
have about their products and their people.
How many companies/founders have
you worked with at this point,
just to give people a sense of the scale?
It's hundreds. So I've conducted, at this
point, over 300 hands-on research sprints
with them. We also work with many, many others
where we're just doing tons of office hours.
Just to give you a sense, it's anything
from biotech to healthcare to security,
food. I've worked with farmers.
It's really all over the place.
What I love about this podcast and guests
like you is you have done 30 years of work
and iteration and refinement, and then
you're here just to tell us, "Here's
the most important thing you need to know, and
here's how to do it, based on all that time I've
spent." Perfect. What ROI we're providing here.
Okay, so your book and your process is about
finding a bullseye customer. Help us understand,
what is a bullseye customer? And in particular,
is there any difference from how most people
think of the ICP, ideal customer profile?
So a bullseye customer is the very
specific subset of your target market
who initially is most likely to adopt your product
or service. And so compared to when we talk to
founders about their ICP or the personas
that they come with, this tends to be more
specific even than they usually have gotten.
And the reason that this concept of bullseye
customer has become so important to us is we've
seen this as really key to accelerating teams.
Every ambitious founder wants to build a product
for everybody, and we're investors. So at GV,
we want them to be successful and to have these
huge markets, but it doesn't start there. To
build to successfully, usually you have to be much
more focused and much more specific. So you can
look at lots of companies, right? Amazon started
just selling books or Facebook was just profiles
for college students, et cetera, et cetera.
So helping founders be very specific about who are
you going to start with, who is that very distinct
group that is most likely initially to adopt,
helps streamline a huge number of things. So it
helps you prioritize, what are you building? It
helps you get really deep in understanding who are
those people and understanding what they need. It
helps you prioritize the feedback you're getting.
You're often getting just a ton of input from
investors, from friends and family if you're
talking to them, from lots of people who kind
of seem like they're in your target market, but
it helps you kind of win away some of that stuff
and be like, "Which parts of this are important?
We'll get to you. It's not that we're not going to
eventually serve you, but initially, here's
where we're going to focus." And it just gets
everybody as a team much more aligned on, "What
are we doing, and what are we doing first?"
I love that the incentives,
as you just referred to,
of a VC like Google Ventures are so aligned
with, help figure out what most will help a
startup. I love that this is a good filter for,
what have you seen most cause trouble for an
early-stage startup? And it's interesting
that this is where you ended up going.
Let's spend a little more time here in just why
the bullseye customer/ICP is so important. Why
is this the thing, of all the things that
you guys have seen along the early stage
of a startup journey, you have decided, "This
is where we need to focus and help people"?
Having them focus on the bullseye customer is
a way to help them focus and prioritize what
they're thinking about building, what
the questions are that they're asking,
and who it is that they need to target and build
for. And so all of those things, once we can help
them narrow that down and decide, "Who are
we really focused on and who are we setting
aside until later?" it helps them prioritize
their roadmap, it helps them prioritize the
feedback that they're getting and gets the whole
team aligned and moving together much faster.
Yeah, it makes sense. Basically, everything
trickles down from who the heck are you selling
to, because it's the pains you're selling for
them. How do you find them? So I love that, and I
totally agree. And again, this has come up a bunch
on recent podcast episodes, just how essential
this is and how underappreciated this often is.
The other thing I love about what you're
describing is you're focused on speed. I
love that as you move through your career,
it's like, "How do we do this faster and
faster?" And what especially love about
your approach is you basically give people
a plan for how to figure this out in a day,
which sounds like a dream. What a dream come
true. In a day, you can change the trajectory
of your startup by getting very clear on who
you're selling to and your bullseye customer.
Awesome. Let's start getting into it. So describe
the sprint. So you have this Bullseye Customer
Sprint that your book describes. And by the way,
this book is freely available. You can download
the PDF. We're not trying to sell books here.
This is just like, use this. You'll be better off.
Yeah. There's learnmorefaster.com,
there's the book, there's all kinds
of resources and templates. Yeah. Please, grab it.
Okay, cool. So describe the sprint, high level,
how it's laid out and the core pieces of it.
Yeah. The basic formula, the way I think about it,
is five and three in one. So it's five bullseye
customers and three very simple prototypes,
and then we conduct those interviews in one day
while the whole team is watching and debriefing
and thinking about what are the key big takeaways
at the end of that, and so that's all as a team.
And you mentioned a few of these key ingredients,
and I think things that people may be surprised
about, specifically, you don't need to talk to
a ton of potential customers. You build a
number of prototypes, which is interesting,
versus iterating on a single prototype. And
there's a few other elements. So can you just
share some of the key insights, the key unique
ingredients to the sprint market experience?
Yeah. So one is bullseye customer. We talked
about that, right? Again, bullseye customer is
that very specific subset of your target market
who's initially most likely to adopt your product
or service. So we want to recruit that group
of people. And one of the reasons that we do
that is if the whole team is in agreement, I have
five people who match that, and everybody's like,
"Yeah, yeah, those people, those are the ones
that if they saw this, we're pretty sure they'd
be into this. They'd want this. We agree."
And so that way, after we do the interviews,
depending on what the feedback is, they can't
really dismiss it. They're like, "Well, we all
thought that..." And it's fine if it didn't, if
they didn't want it or they reacted in certain
ways. That's what we wanted to learn. But upfront,
we were able to identify and say, "Yes, yes. Those
really we think are the right people." That's our
hypothesis. So first is five bullseye customers.
The next part is about qualitative interviews.
So there are lots and lots of different kinds
of research methods, but what I've found over
doing this for many years is that the biggest
bang for your buck is doing these kind of deep
qualitative interviews where I can dig in and
understand people's stories, understand their
motivations, understand past experiences, "Why
did you do this in the past? What have you done
in the past? What's worked? What hasn't worked?"
Having the whole team watch that and understand
and build that kind of empathy and understanding
and hear those stories is very powerful.
But then we do those in small batches. So
rather than do an interview on Monday and then one
on Wednesday and then a couple on Friday, we clump
them. Ideally, it's in that one day, so I bang
out five one-hour interviews in one day while the
whole team's watching. Sometimes we do it across
two days, depending on time zones and things
like that, but the idea is that they're clumped
together. The reason for that is if you do them
in a clump like that, then the patterns are just
much more obvious. At the end of the day, it's
just really clear what were the big takeaways.
It's not going to answer every question that you
ever had about your product or your customers.
But the big things that you set out to answer,
it's pretty clear, like did it work? Did
it not work? Which parts were good or bad?
All these kinds of things. And the whole team
has watched it, and so they have that sense.
And that idea of just doing five of them, you hit
what's called data saturation. This is the thing
in qualitative research where the common version
of this is everybody, after four or five, is like,
"Oh, for God's sakes, please don't let me sit
through any more of these. I get it. I'm hearing
the same things over and over. I understand.
Let's move on and do something different,
change the customer, change the prototypes,
whatever." So qualitative interviews in
small clumps, and then we compare prototypes.
And so this kind of comes from that time I had
at Walmart where I sort of see the whole world as
a shopping process. And so there's something very
valuable, just the way any of you have shopped
for anything, right? You don't look at just one
thing. If I showed you just one thing, you'd have
some feedback and you'd have an opinion about it,
like, "Let's shop for a couch. I like the
color. The cushions are uncomfortable.
I like the fabric," or not. And that's
helpful and that's interesting to hear,
but as you start looking at two or three, then
you start having this different reference points.
And when you're testing with customers, it's
not up to them to come up with these different
possibilities of what could be, and so
if I'm presenting those, they're like,
"Oh, that's interesting. I like the way this
one has cushions that are made out of down,
but this other one is really interesting because
they deliver it. Oh, but I like this because it's
a style that I like and they actually take away
my old couch." So then I can compare and contrast
across these different possibilities, these
different distinct value propositions. And I'm
not looking for a winner but this comparison.
The other big benefit of having multiple
prototypes is it helps teams avoid getting
too wed to one specific idea. So you can get a
little over-committed. There's a risk that you get
over-committed to one idea, you're polishing that,
you're working on it, you're too committed to
that. And this pushes teams to think of new,
different possibilities, and you can be a little
bit more neutral and a little bit more objective
if you're not all so bought into one thing.
So comparing prototypes becomes very powerful.
And then the other thing is making this a team
sport. The watch parties are a key example of
this. And I'm livestreaming it, so the whole team
is all watching it these days. Typically, people
are pretty distributed, so I'm doing it over Zoom
and they're watching the livestream independently.
And then one of my partners, so Kate Aronowitz or
Vanessa Cho, got amazing design partners I get to
work with, are often facilitating that back room.
And so what they're doing is they're helping the
team... We have a structured process for taking
notes, and then in between each interview,
they're debriefing. So I have this spreadsheet
that I use that's like, "These are the key things
we wanted to get out of this." And so they're
going through and just capturing that, like,
"What just happened in this interview? Let's make
sure we have the high level." And at the end of
the day, we have a way to all capture, like,
"What were our big takeaways? What happened?"
But the magic of all watching it and processing
it and discussing it and debating it through the
course of the day is that everybody is aligned.
We've all seen it. I don't write a report. I
haven't written a report in, I don't know,
10 years, because at the end, when we capture
those big takeaways, the team has captured it.
We do it through Google Form, it shows up in
the spreadsheet, and we kind of discuss it.
And then everybody's just raring to go do the
next thing. Everybody's aligned, and there's this
incredible amount of momentum from the team after
that. They're like, "Let's go do the next thing."
It's clear what we need to do and what we learned.
And sometimes the next thing is do this again and
adjust so we can build more confidence. But the
make it a team sport has been this very powerful
tool for building consensus, building alignment.
Especially as teams are growing and people are
going to start up running in different directions,
it's like a chance to come together and make
sure, like, "Oh, where are we? What are we doing?"
Awesome. That was really helpful. So just to
summarize the key elements of this approach,
there's a bullseye customer concept of just a
very narrow people wedge, almost, of who would
most want this thing, and we'll talk more
about that, making it qualitative versus
surveys or things like that, comparing
prototypes, and making it a team sport.
Okay. So we're going to actually go into more
detail of each of these steps just so folks
can... Basically, what I'm hoping to do is
they... Folks listening to this can do this
tomorrow or next week. There's a little
prep time. Before we get into each step,
when do you recommend people do this?
When in the stage of a journey? Can
you do it many times? Any just
context there before we dive in?
You can do it many times. The key times to do it
is... At a high level, it's before, hopefully,
you've invested a lot of time into building
something, a lot of energy and the team's
energy and money that goes into the building.
So it's usually before you build something,
maybe if you're expanding into a new group of
customers, so you were killing it in the UK and
now you're trying to get into the US market and
that's different, or you worry it's different or
you're not sure, it's a good time to check.
Or maybe you were selling to enterprise,
you're doing very white-glove,
high-touch sales to enterprise,
and now you're going to shift down to maybe a
different tier of customers and you're trying
to set up some more of a self-serve kind of
a sales motion. You need to understand that.
Another common time is when you're selling but
something's not going quite as well as maybe you
hoped it was going. You've already launched
and you want to just kind of troubleshoot,
like, "What's going on? We have some traction,
maybe, but it's not what we wanted," or "We're
getting that very polite, encouraging feedback,
which sounds good, but it's really no. Let's go
dive in and find out." So those are the big
key things of the times of when to do it.
Okay, let's actually get into the steps. I
believe there's six core steps to the process.
Okay. Yeah.
Okay, cool. Where do you start? What's step one?
Yeah. So step one is what I do is I plan about
a 45-minute meeting with the team. Again,
it's really important to have that core team
together and have this conversation about what
are the key questions, basically, "What do
you wish you would know about your product,
about your customers? What's getting in the way?"
One of the most common ways that we ask this is,
basically, "What keeps you up at night?"
because founders and product people
have... There's a bazillion things that
they're kind of bubbling in their head,
that they're worrying about. But that often gets
them to step back and be like, "Oh, what I'm
really unsure is this. What's going to happen?
How will people respond to this fundamental
concept or this idea or how will they use it?"
I have a set of questions that I'll go through
with them to help prompt and elicit, "What are
those big things that you wish you knew? What
would have to be true for this to succeed? What
are your hypotheses and what are your assumptions
about the product, about the customer? Who do
you think this is or not, and why? What are those
nagging debates on the team, those kinds of things
that keep coming up over and over and you're like,
'Oh, for God's sakes, let's go get some
information and answer the question'?" It's some
of these things. So we have that initial meeting
to kind of detail, what do we need to answer?
Awesome. And this informs other... I
imagine, all the things you do next.
And so in the PDF [inaudible 00:23:55]
too, in the show notes, you can see all
these questions and run through them yourself.
Okay, cool. So that's step one. What's step two?
So step two is, based on what you want to learn,
now let's figure out who is the bullseye customer
that we need to talk to to answer that question.
It all starts with those key questions that you
have, because if the question is about, let's
say, big questions about onboarding, well, if the
questions are about onboarding flow, then you're
going to want to talk to new customers, somebody
who's fresh to this to see, how do they get
through or how do they understand what this is?
Whereas if you're talking about something that's
a new feature that's already in your product,
then you'd be talking to existing customers. So
that's an example where if I understand what the
questions are, I can kind of work backwards
to understand, who do I need to talk to?
And then based on that, what I do is run what
I call a bullseye exercise. So it's, again,
essentially another kind of interview. Get
the team together, and I pepper them with a
lot of questions to figure out exactly who is this
bullseye customer that we've been talking about.
And the reason I love doing this as a team
is that what happens invariably is having
that conversation before we've even gotten to
any interviews is super clarifying for a team,
because they tend to get a shorthand
about who their customers are.
And this is a way... And I just keep asking
questions, like, "Well, what do you mean by
that? So when you say you're building a delivery
service for people who get specialty medications
delivered, specialty prescription medications,
who exactly is that? It's not everybody."
And so we start narrowing it down. So they
start having those conversations, debates,
arguments about who it is, and just having that is
really clarifying for the team. Like, "Oh, well,
I hadn't thought about that. Yeah, I guess it's
true. Maybe it's not everybody who has that. It's
only people who have this kind of condition
or this set of conditions or these needs."
And to follow that thread real quick, I imagine
people's natural inclination is not to narrow
it too much, because there's always like, "Why
would we exclude this big market opportunity?
Why would it have to be so narrow?" Can you
just speak a little bit to just why it's so
important to get very, very narrow? Andy
Johns, on a newsletter post I wrote once,
he described it as, "It should feel
comically narrow." Does that resonate?
I love that. Yeah, I hadn't heard that phrase,
but I love that. Yeah, comically narrow is
exactly what it is. And there are times that
teams will just be like, "Oh, for God's sakes,
Margolis, this is too much." The reason that
I do that is I'm pushing them to identify a
person who they all would agree, "This person,
if we present this value prop that we think
we're going to build and this problem we think
we're solving, we are all convinced... Or it's
our best guess." It's fine if you're not sure,
but, "We are pretty convinced that that's the
person who will say, 'Yeah, I need this thing.'"
I'm kind of running an experiment, right? It's a
way to reduce variables for me and then to get
that specific, and then I recruit a bunch of
the people who match that very particular set of
characteristics. And they're people, so there's
still some variation, but it's a way for us to
test that. If there's too much variation, then
what happens? At the end of the day, you're like,
"That was kind of a mush. I'm not really sure what
we learned. Was it because it was just people had
mixed feelings or was it because there was just
not enough consistency? We had too many variables
in there. I don't know what we learned here."
So I think what's nice about this is this initial
list you're making of bullseye potential customers
and attributes is not exactly going to be
who you go after. Once you figure this out,
you want to be very confident these group
will absolutely love what you're presenting,
because you're trying to learn as much as
you can from the people that most love it.
And then from that, you can get a little
less narrow to actually pitch your product.
Right. And most often what happens is we do this,
we define it our best, right? It's our hypothesis.
It's our best guess. The team is always very
expert. I'm not. I'm always showing up as the
noob in whatever this business is. The team is
expert, and so this is very informed. It's not
like we're guessing. But we go through this, and
by the time after we've done these interviews,
the goal is to figure out, "Was this right or
not? Or in what ways do we need to adjust?"
That's a big piece of the outcome, is adjusting
that definition of your bullseye customer.
And often what happens is through the course
of that Bullseye Customer Sprint, you learn,
"Oh, it turns out there's actually this other
distinguishing characteristic we didn't realize,
or maybe it validates what we knew." But
often, "We didn't quite realize that. This
other thing is popping up where we're seeing
heat from people. Oh, wow, that's interesting.
Let's dive in a little more." I mean, I
can walk through an example if you want.
Yeah, that'd be awesome. Then-
[inaudible 00:29:03].
Yeah, yeah. And I think even just like,
what are some examples of attributes?
What's the list of attributes
you should be thinking about?
Let me just give you an example. I think a
lot of this stuff we're talking about, it
starts to get a little abstract. So I was
working with a company that was developing
a new delivery service for people
who have specialty prescriptions,
medications. So these are the kinds of
medications that are expensive and for very
specialized chronic diseases. This is not
the kind of thing you're getting at Rite
Aid. And there's something very special about this
company, and then I can mention that afterwards.
But the fundamental thing for them to figure out
was, before they can build out the logistics of
this, they're trying to figure out, "Do we need
to target something that is for delivery like
ASAP?" These are really important medications
for very serious diseases. Is it like, "Oh,
my gosh, I need the next pill. Get it to me
as fast as you can"? Or is it like, "Well,
I can wait till a day or two, but I need it
between 2:00 and 2:15 PM," like if I knew that?
And then who exactly is this bullseye customer?
We want to know, what's really the fundamental
issue or problem that we're solving here?
And so they wanted to answer those questions.
And so we go through this process, and so those
are the key questions. And then the customers
that they're after, I know, okay, well, it's not
going to be everybody with specialty medications.
And so as we start teasing through that and
thinking about it, I want to think about,
what are examples of other products that somebody
has used that would make them more likely?
So a good example there is, have you had other
things delivered? Food? Have you gone through
this kind of process before where you've used like
Uber Eats? Because if you have never had anything
delivered like that before, that's going to be too
many humps to get over to get the person to accept
their medications coming by delivery. So they've
probably used Uber Eats or something like that,
and they've been on the medication for a
certain amount of time. So it's somebody who,
this is kind of a chronic thing. It's
not like a one-off acute situation.
They needed to find people who had a certain
kind of density, so how rural were they living,
how urban was it, because of the way they were
going to do the deliveries, somebody who was
responsible for their own medications. So we
don't want somebody who's in some kind of a
healthcare setting where somebody else is taking
care of it, or maybe their spouse or partner
is managing their prescriptions. These are the
kinds of things that we're starting to look for.
And another typical exclusion criteria
is I don't want somebody who knows
too much. Your core bullseye customer, I want
somebody who's pretty typical. So in this case,
if I were to find out that somebody was
a pharmacist or worked in healthcare,
they're like, "Oh, yeah, that's probably not
a typical customer. If I just have these five
precious interview slots, I probably don't want
that, so I'm going to exclude those people."
So we went through and did this and then
generated these different prototypes to express
a range of different recipes of value props and
what this might be. So the range is things from,
it can be delivered in an hour or it can
be delivered over a four-hour window,
or it can be delivered, "We'll get it there
as soon as we can get it there, but we're not
quite sure when it'll be coming. You just have
to be home and available," these kinds of things.
So went through this exercise, and what rose
to the surface as we were doing these is that
there were certain customers for whom this was a
much, much bigger issue, for whom they needed to
be there and know when this thing was showing
up. It turned out having that distinct window,
a predictable, narrow window of when
this was going to arrive was much,
much important than ASAP. These are important
medications. They're not waiting until the last
pill is gone. That's not what's happening here.
But knowing when it was arriving... And it turned
out that the scenarios where that was critical
was things like, it's a refrigerated medication.
This can't be sitting out on my stoop, right?
It's cold chain. Or there's for some reason an
issue where I'm especially worried about
theft or something because of what the
medication is or where I'm living or weather.
So there are these very particular scenarios.
So then going back to this idea of the bulls-eye
customer, you realize, "Oh, wait, so it's a subset
of customers who have refrigerated meds. That
seems like a much higher value problem that
we're solving here." And so we ended up running
this again. So I re-recruited with people who
had that subset of kinds of medications and
issues and also were dissatisfied with the
status quo of their existing service and were not
available to just kind of be around. So they were
busy and whatever, and they needed this window.
So we ran it again. We were like, "Oh, yeah,
there it is." So that second group of people,
you just start building this confidence in
the match between what you're building, what the
problem is you're solving, and who exactly you're
building it for. And in that case, you could
see, "Oh, yeah, that is the right bullseye.
That's why there's this very narrow, specific
group who's much more likely to adopt this than
everybody who has specialty medications,
because the need is just much more acute."
I love this example. Intuitively, it
all just makes sense as you describe
what you landed on. And this is what people
call product-market fit, what you're describing,
where somebody has a pain that you are solving
and they need it badly. What does it look like
when you find that group of... What do you
notice qualitatively, just like this tells
you this is it, this is the pole that people
talk about when you say product-market fit?
I avoid the phrase product-market fit
with this stuff, and we can talk about
that because I think that's kind of
interesting. When you find this match,
what happens in the qualitative interviews
is that you can sense the energy and the
excitement and the enthusiasm. It comes across.
Especially as you do a bunch of these, you can
tell. There's a difference. And so that's what
you're looking for, is people who are then like,
"Wait, is this available? Is this a thing? Can
I sign up for this?" It's that kind of thing,
or they're really leaning into it and
you qualitatively can just see it.
One of the things I thought was very interesting
was I was recently speaking to a founder whom
I'm doing another round of this with a new set
of concepts. We had done a project a while ago
and actually killed the project. So through
going through Bullseye Customer Sprint with
something that he was doing, we did three
rounds of it, and finally, he was like,
"Yeah, this is not... I'm going to focus on
the other part of my business." And he said,
"We killed the project." And what he told me was
two things that were really interesting to me.
One was, "This saved me a huge amount of pain."
We ran through this, we had to do some work to the
Bullseye Customer Sprint, but the product that
he was going to build, it was hardware, it was
software, it was this whole subscription model. It
was going to be a big, complicated thing to build.
We had mocked up a bunch of prototypes and I'd
used some free prototypes when we interviewed.
It killed the project. That was super valuable to
him. He saved a huge amount of time and effort.
The other thing that he's mentioned to me
was that through going through the process,
he learned what no looked like. So he could see,
"Oh, I'm getting kind of this neutral, positive,
encouraging feedback." And as we did this,
he realized like, "Oh, they don't want this."
Right. It's not that big of a deal to them.
It's not that. And it was by doing this, and
you see it enough times, and he felt like
that was one of the most valuable outcomes for
him, is like, "Now I know what no looks like."
That makes so much sense. It feels like
that's almost... You could almost argue
that's the biggest value of this, is just avoid
wasting time building something nobody wants.
Totally. And as a researcher and as
a VC, if I can save a company and a
founder and a product team from going
down some path or too far down a path,
that's huge for everybody. They have so
much energy to go do the other thing.
And again, this is another reminder why it's so
important to go so narrow, because if you can't
find anyone that is thrilled this exists, you're
in trouble. This is your chance to find the most
thrilled people, the most specifically pained,
and if you can't find that, that's a problem.
Yeah. In the same way, we define this bullseye,
and then when I go recruit and try to find them,
if I can't find them, I usually take that
as a sign of something also. I'm like,
"I don't know if these people exist."
And it could be... Sometimes they're like,
"Well, we went too narrow." I'm like, "Okay,
well, let's go back and we'll see which of
these are flexible. How do we soften some
of these requirements? But if, in fact,
I just can't find these people, these people
that you're imagining exist who want this thing,
I'm not sure how you're going to sell
to them." Not that I'm the final arbiter
of whether these people exist, but
it's something you should go check.
Yeah. Okay. So to give people a little bit of a
framework of how to help them identify these
narrow set of attributes, share some of a list
attributes to think about to help them narrow.
And how many narrowing attributes would you
recommend? Is it roughly, heuristically,
is it like three? Is it five? Is it seven?
It probably gets down to... Yeah, it's more
like seven. I mean, that's roughly. It depends.
The way I think about it is kind of in these
three groups. So there are inclusion criteria,
there are exclusion criteria, and then
what we found very important are triggers.
So by inclusion criteria, this is usually
pretty easy because the team is like, "Yeah,
these are the people we want in the group. It's
people who are taking specialty medications for
these particular conditions. We can build
that out." The exclusion criteria I find
is a place to dwell and help a company
really think that through a bit more,
to brainstorm that, because as we talked about,
it's harder for teams to set people aside, right?
And so it's thinking about, what are reasons why
somebody maybe is not the best customer here,
not yet? And that could be things that we
talked about was maybe they have too much
expert knowledge here. They're not really a
typical person. That's not who I want to talk
to. Maybe they're using a competitive product
and they're already locked into that. I don't
need to talk to them. Or they've had some other
personal past experience that's going to just
make them not a good candidate, like I'm working
on FinTech and this person is in bankruptcy or has
had identity stolen. I want to help them,
but that's not our first place to start.
So these exclusion criteria are critical,
and then these triggers are specific events
or situations that somebody's been in that makes
them particularly ready or ripe for the solution.
So sometimes the way that looks, sometimes
the examples of that can be you're selling
a new cybersecurity platform for something
and there's a new CSO has come in. There's
a new sheriff in town, and they're looking to
revamp things and rethink, and so it's a time
when somebody's open to considering new options.
Or something's gone wrong, right? Somebody's in
a situation where something's gone sideways and
they need a new solution for that kind of thing.
Or we were working for an insurance tech company
and they were targeting millennials. So the idea
was the people who were in this particular
demographic, in this time of life, they would
be buying life insurance. And what we found was
everybody was saying, "Well, we should buy life...
Yeah, it's one of those things. I should take care
of that. Yeah, I should take care of that. Oh,
yeah, I really need to get life insurance."
But people who had... The trigger was, "Oh,
you just had a baby?" or "You just got
married?" And now people are like, "Oh,
this is actually on my to-do list. I
need to go get this done." And so I'm
in a completely different mindset, that's
the person who now is your bullseye. It's
an example of a trigger that somebody's like,
"Oh, yeah, now I need to go do this thing."
Awesome. I know in the jobs-to-be-done framework,
there's a term for that that's like it kicks off
the vector to get them to do something.
I forget, there's term in that framework.
So I have your book up in my hands right now,
and I'm looking at the list of attributes
and questions that you ask to help narrow down.
So let me just read this, because I think it
might be helpful just people to hear, like if
I'm trying to narrow, how do I narrow them?
So it's like, are they new or an existing user
of your product? What sector or industry are
they in? What's the size of their organization?
Have they used a competitive product? Is there
disqualifying personal experiences, as you
described? Is there disqualifying professional
experiences? What's their title, role and
responsibility? What's their geography?
Are they the buyer or the end user?
Are they distributed? How is their team
organized? Their budget and income, their
life and work settings, trigger events,
as you described. Are they a VIP?
What is that one, real quick?
Yeah. So I was having this
conversation yesterday with a company.
Oh, cool.
I met with them, and so what I asked them was,
"What makes one customer or
another more valuable to you?"
Oh, okay. Yep. Got it. So it's
like, are they especially important?
Yeah. Is there something about... For them, it
was this really interesting, again, way to start
thinking about distinguishing characteristics.
Like, "Yeah, what is a valuable customer to us?"
They're at an early stage and they were attracting
a lot of people and different kinds of personas,
and they're trying to figure out, what's the
pattern here? Who matters more to you or not?
Awesome. So basically, you answer all these
questions, you see which of the seven-ish
attributes seem to be most right, and that's
your bullseye customer that you start with.
Right.
Awesome. Okay. Should we move on to the next step?
Sure.
Let's do it. What comes next?
So once I have that set of criteria and the
team is all aligned and agreed on what that is,
they're like, "Yeah, yeah, those are our
people," so then I start thinking about how
I recruit them. So to do that, for most people,
unless I'm looking for something that's very,
very specialized or hard to find, what I do
is I create a screener questionnaire. So I
translate these criteria into, essentially,
a set of questions that will help me filter
out people, to know, if people respond to this
questionnaire, who are the bullseyes in there?
And so part of the trick there is to
write a questionnaire in a way that
I'm not telegraphing the right answers, and
so that I kind of am in the control seat so
I can pick out and identify the people. What
I mean by that is if I were to say, "I will
pay $125 to anybody who is a product manager who
listens to Lenny's podcast," and all of a sudden,
I'm going to get a bazillion people who are just
like, "I will take that $125." I'm like, "Well, I
don't know, do you actually listen to the podcast?
I don't know. Hopefully you do. Everybody does."
But if I can ask the question in a different way
in terms of, "What are some of the podcasts you
listen to? What are the kinds of people you
follow?" these kinds of things, and then see,
where does that show up? Or even ask it as an
open-ended question, like, "Where do you get your
most trusted information as a product manager?"
and start to see and then be able to pick those
people out, because what I've wanted to do, one of
the key things in those bullseye criteria are that
they're very concrete and very measurable things.
It's not just, "Oh, this person is an active
shopper." That's not very helpful to me, because I
need to translate it into this questionnaire. So I
need to know, what is active shopper? That means
somebody who is purchasing certain kind of item,
whatever we define, three times a week.
Yeah, that's active, right? So we have
some very particular, very measurable, concrete
things. So then I'm writing this questionnaire.
And typically, what I do is I rely pretty heavily
actually on User Interviews. Respondent is another
one of these kinds of services. So I can
post that questionnaire and get responses,
depending on what I'm looking for, pretty fast.
So I can recruit in a matter of three, four days,
typically, depending on what I'm looking
for. And I've been able to get surprisingly
specific people that way. And so that is a huge
shortcut for me to be able to recruit that way.
This episode is brought to you by Enterpret.
Enterpret unifies all your customer interactions,
from Gong calls to Zendesk tickets to Twitter
threads to App Store reviews, and makes it
available for analysis. It's trusted by leading
product orgs like Canva, Notion, Loom, Linear,
Monday.com, and Strava to bring the voice of the
customer into the product development process,
helping you build best-in-class products faster.
What makes Enterpret special is its ability to
build and update customer-specific AI models that
provide the most granular and accurate insights
into your business, connect customer insights
to revenue and operational data in your CRM or
data warehouse to map the business impact of
each customer need and prioritize confidently,
and empower your entire team to easily take
action on use cases like win-loss analysis,
critical bug detection, and identifying drivers
of churn with Enterpret's AI assistant wisdom.
Looking to automate your feedback loops and
prioritize your roadmap with confidence,
like Notion, Canva, and Linear? Visit
E-N-T-R-P-R-E-T .com/lenny to connect
with the team and to get two free
months when you sign up for an
annual plan. This is a limited-time
offer. That's enterpret.com/lenny.
Where do you find these people? How
do you contact them? Where are they?
So through User Interviews, they work
with the panel and they basically-
Userinterviews.com?
Yeah, userinterviews.com.
Oh, amazing. That's very easy.
Yeah, it's super easy.
So it's not like LinkedIn cold email, cold pings,
not [inaudible 00:47:24] DMs, things like that.
No. I mean, in previous days,
I used to use Craigslist,
and I did a lot of some pretty crazy shit
recruiting people through Craigslist. I
had people once meeting me at a hotel room
to test a robot through Craigslist. But no,
User Interviews is much more legit and very
fast. And there are other services like this now,
but it's been one of the big changes
that speeds a lot of this stuff up.
That's way too easy. And how many
people do you reach out to to go
through a screener, roughly, to get to five?
So it will depend on what I post and how much
response I get. It has been somewhat hard for
me to predict. There are times I do it and the
responses just start rolling in. So the times I
get like 400 responses, basically download it into
a spreadsheet and just start sifting through. As
a reference, I have my criteria, and then I'm
just trying to find who matches, who doesn't.
Okay, so it goes to hundreds.
It can be hundreds sometimes if I'm looking...
I did one recently, I was looking for a very
particular group of AI engineers. That did not
get 400 responses. That was a very hard one to
find. That was an example where there was this
very particular group that we were looking for,
and I was like, "Do these exist?
This thing that you're solving for,
I don't know... This is pretty hard to find
these people. I'm not sure they're existing."
Yeah. And to your point, that's a
sign. I think there's a nuance here of,
if this group is not only hard to find but hard
to reach and get them to talk to you at all,
that's already going to make your
life hard building this company.
Right. The caveat there is there are times when
you need to talk to somebody who's just very hard
to find or hard... They're not going to be on
User Interviews. So I've done a lot of work in
the past with oncologists, with Flatiron Health.
Oncologists are not on User Interviews. They don't
care about my $125. They're busy doing something
more important. And so if I'm doing that,
I need to find a different way to approach that.
So then I'm thinking about, where do these people
kind of cluster online or in person, that I might
be able to target them? There's certain forums or
certain conferences, these kinds of things.
Or I'm doing snowball recruiting. If you're
building a product for oncologists, you hopefully
probably have some contacts with oncologists, and
you can kind of work through their network, find
one person, they can recommend another person. You
still want to filter them and make sure that
they are matching your core criteria, but it
requires different kinds of techniques to find
those kinds of folks. Professional associations.
I almost want to go down that track because
I feel like there's a lot to learn there,
but I'm going to stay focused and keep going
through our steps. But let me take a quick
tangent. So as you were talking, I actually wrote
a post in the past on how to identify your ICP,
and I put together a table of the very first
ICP for some of the biggest B2B SaaS companies
that I pulled up here. So let me just give
a few examples of how narrow some of these
companies were when they went out to
sell their product. Let me do a few.
So Gong, which is one of the biggest B2B SaaS
companies, their first bullseye customer,
as they described it, was... Look how narrow
this is. Their ideal customers were software
company selling in English, selling via
video conferencing, selling software
that cost $1,000 to $100,000. Linear, their
focus was two to five-person startups using
GitHub and Google Auth at a founder-driven
product company. Let's see one more. Augusta
was really funny. Companies with less than five
employees in California who have no contractors.
See, what's interesting to me about those is
that I would go even deeper and more specific,
because some of those things are... And that's
fine. I don't know internally how they actually
describe the details of it, but some of those,
you want very concrete, measurable things to be
able to tease apart like, "Well, how founder-led
are... How are you behaving? What other products
are you using in your stack that this fits
or doesn't fit?" These kinds of things.
Yeah. So it's interesting because
when people saw this, initially,
they were like, "That's crazy how narrow
they're getting." And I love that you're like,
"That is not narrow at all. You
should go so much more narrow."
Because if I had to recruit those people-
Yeah, it's too broad. And I think that's an
important point here is this exercise, you
get more narrow to do this research, but that's
not your actual ICP, as you described. Okay, so I
understand what you're saying now, more and more
of the difference between bullseye customer and
ICP. The bullseye customer is for research to help
you identify a broader ICP, your business targets.
Yeah. And I think this actually touches on
another important point, which is that this
is a learning exercise. So that's what
I'm describing, is how do we learn more
faster? And this is different from selling, right?
So what I hear a lot is people are like, "I'm on
customer calls. We're selling all the time." And
obviously, you can learn a ton from selling and
pitching and meeting with companies and potential
people who seem like maybe they are customers. But
that mode is very, very different from what
I'm describing, which is to learn, to run
these experiments as fast as you can. And there's
something, just even a mindset in how you approach
the conversations, that's fundamentally different.
So there's this term that I love that Ed Schein
coined, which is humble inquiry. And so he frames
it as humble inquiry is the gentle art of asking
instead of telling. To me, that's this fundamental
way that I think about even just conducting these
interviews. So if you're in a selling mode,
and I encountered this over and over with heads
of product and founders, is that if you're...
They're very good at, and they're very used to,
and they're required to just sell all the time.
And they're pitching their VCs, they're pitching
their customers, but that's very different
from learning and being... In humble inquiry,
you basically have to be vulnerable.
And I can always do it because I'm not
the founder, and I've always present myself as
like, "I don't know the space. I'm an idiot. Can
you explain it to me?" But asking questions
and being vulnerable and giving the person
you're asking the higher status is a difficult
thing to do as a founder when you're selling,
because you don't want to be vulnerable and
express that you don't know. And people I
come across, they're very nervous about that.
So there's something that's very distinct here
about a learning mode versus a selling
mode, selling and telling versus this
idea of humble inquiry. So I think that's
actually an important distinction here.
I love that. And I think it helps that you're
finding randos on User Interviews that you
don't have to worry as much about versus finding
great intros through VCs that you do worry about.
Right.
Awesome. Okay, so we've been talking about the
step of recruiting your bullseye customers. So
you find these folks, you filter the screeners,
you pick five, and you schedule them for the
same day. Is there anything else in
that step that is important to cover?
You have to make sure they show up, make sure
you're compensating them sufficiently. This is
something where I'm not giving $20 Starbucks
cards, because somebody's going to blow you
off. When I have those five sessions
and the whole team queued up to watch,
I want people to show up. So I'm
making sure I'm reminding people,
I'm making sure that they're responsive to me when
I'm asking them to e-sign an NDA ahead of time.
Am I hearing back from them? And I'm paying
for most typical kind of consumer things,
like 125 bucks an hour for them to show up
and do this, so it's worth spending the money.
Recently did something where I was talking
to attorneys. I was paying their hourly
rate. I was paying like 400 bucks an hour for
them to show up, but I need them to show up.
Yeah. Good point, good point. And I
love that it's 125, not 100. Is there
like you've seen a difference there,
that it's something more than 100?
I think that that's based on whatever the
policy is at Alphabet that somebody set.
Oh, okay. I see.
So that's the standard that I'm-
I see.
... I'm going with.
Funny. Okay.
And it also has just seemed to
work. People are showing up for
that. So if people weren't, then I would adjust.
And do you do backup people just in case
someone doesn't show up? Or it's just like,
"All right, I guess we have
four," whenever it does happen?
I actually don't. So User Interviews, by working
with them and by doing some of these other things
along the way where I am making sure people are
responding to me during the course of the week
leading up to it, "Did you sign my NDA?" I send
a reminder, "Are you responding?" I can tell if
they're engaged. If somebody's essentially
ghosting me, I'm getting nothing, I'll just
swap them out. But I don't use alternates
and I have very, very high follow-through.
Great. Okay, what's the next step?
So then the next step is to figure out your
prototypes. And so what I want to do with
those is I want to create, again, these three
distinct examples, three distinct recipes of
the possible features and distinct variables
that we want to present in these interviews.
As I said before, ideally, I can find a
competitor's products and use those as free
prototypes. I love doing that. It's surprising
to me that often people don't do more of this,
and I think that there's sometimes a sense that
it's cheating or they're worried they're going to
copy it or something. I'm like, "Well, whatever."
If you haven't studied your competitor's products,
and not just gone through it but
seen how people respond to them,
you're just missing something, right?
So what we do is work out the details of the
variables that we're going to spread across these
prototypes. So there are certain features and then
certain variables across, that I kind of imagine
spread across these different things. For example,
we were talking about delivery of specialty
medications. So imagine one of the attributes is,
who's delivering it? Maybe one version is a
pharmacist is going to come, one is it's just
a delivery courier guy, and then another one,
in this case, actually, it was a drone company,
so a drone is dropping this thing off. We could
talk more about what it was like to test that,
but there are different variables here.
The other option is, say, the size of
the delivery window. So it'll come in two
days, but you can narrow down in a 15-minute
window. This one is as soon as possible. You'll
just have to be home to wait, this kind of
thing. So we're developing this range and then
creating these prototypes that are very simple.
They're just PDFs, really. Very flat, there's no
functionality. A lot of it is really a writing
exercise to articulate, what's the distinct value
prop and what's the brand promise and the problem
you're solving for each of these prototypes?
So you want to make it look as real as possible,
so it looks like a home page for the product,
right? It's the box around this thing. So you
don't have to build anything, you're just
describing it and putting whatever you need
to illustrate and convey that. But they need
to stand alone. I'm not going to pitch them or
narrate to them, and just create those so that
I can present those three distinct recipes.
And these calls are usually over Zoom,
in your experience, at this point? Cool.
So these are kind of just like in Figma or
exported just images you're showing people?
Exactly right.
Sweet. More and more on this podcast, people
are sharing ways how AI is making prototypes,
actual product prototypes
so much easier to create,
so I imagine people are going to move
to functional prototypes more and more.
Yeah, they may. I think the thing that's important
is to not get distracted by that. So here,
the benefit to keeping it simple is that
you're not too wed and too committed to
anything. Build only as much as you actually need
to answer the question you're trying to answer.
That's a great point. So it's like, even
if you can create an awesome prototype,
don't do that, probably. Just keep it flat design.
Awesome means very crisply describing the
distinct value proposition and problem you're
solving in a way that people get it. They're
like, "Oh, I understand what this one is,
and then I can compare it to these other
ones. And I understand what the features are,
and I can have that conversation." It's about
the value prop, it's about making sure that
they understand what it is. It's not this
kind of marketing speak where you're like,
"Wait, what?" You just have to be
super blunt. "This is what it is
and why this is awesome and why this one
is awesome," and then they're shopping.
I love that. So basically, as you've said, it's
a writing exercise. It's like the headline,
the positioning seems to be the most important
part to nail versus the design of it.
Right.
Awesome.
And I design them enough that they
look different from each other. So
it's not version A, version B, version C,
because in the course of the conversation,
with all the observers, I want it to be clear
which prototype somebody is talking about.
Awesome.
So the green one versus the
blue one versus the red one,
right? So then when the observers can
keep track... Otherwise, you're like,
"Wait, what? Which one are they talking
about? I don't know what's happening."
Awesome. Okay. Anything else that is
important to note on the prototype step?
Proofread it carefully. People get
stuck on errors, and then it undermines
the validity and the credibility of the
prototype. So proofread it and make sure,
because otherwise people are
like, "Uh, that's not right."
That's such a good tip. So
just have someone else read it,
like someone else that hasn't been
working on [inaudible 01:01:09]-
Just check them carefully.
... anything wrong. Cool.
Okay, so what's the next
step? So you have these prototypes,
you've got the schedules interviewed-
Right, so you have people coming. You're
scheduled, so people are showing up on
Thursday. We're going to start doing interviews,
so you have to draft your interview guide.
What these interviews are going to look like,
in the course of that watch party, it's five
one-hour interviews. Each interview is a two-part
interview. So the first part of the interview
is this discovery interview where I'm asking
people about their existing and past experiences
and attitudes and opinions about whatever this
part of their life is. "How did you previously
get your medications delivered? What worked? What
didn't work? Tell me about a time when it totally
went sideways. Tell me about a time it worked
perfectly." So we go through that and have that.
About halfway through that interview, I shift to
comparing and contrasting these prototypes. So the
comparing and contrasting is I'm presenting each
prototype and people are responding to that and
telling me what they see, what this is, and then
the responding to what each of these prototypes
is, what they like, what they don't like, what's
important, what's not important. Some parts that
they don't comment on is fine. If that just
doesn't even register, that's good to know. And
then I'm having them compare and contrast.
So by having three different prototypes,
it's enough for them to then sort of step back
and not pick a winner, but be able to say, "Oh,
I like this aspect of this one. I like the fact
that this one's being delivered by a pharmacist,
but I really prefer that this other one is a
15-minute window," for example. And so they're
kind of teasing out, what are the best pieces of
each of these? And that's really what I'm looking
for through the course of this conversation,
is I want to grab the best bits and pieces,
the best Lego pieces, so I can then go construct
the ideal version next, because none of these...
Again, I'm not going to build probably any
one of those. I'm looking for the best pieces.
And through the arc of that conversation,
by doing the first half where I've had the
discovery conversation, it gives me a huge amount
of context to understand their feedback about
the prototypes, because there will be times
when they'll say things or tell us something,
and because we heard the first part...
They'll tell us something about the prototype,
and because of what we heard in the first part,
we'll understand why. Like, "Oh, it's because
they had that other experience in the past where
that thing went totally haywire, when something
like that happened, and they don't have trust
in that. Now I know why that's the situation."
And it's very, very, very common that when
teams are watching this, they're always like,
"For Christ's sake, Margolis, would you just get
to the prototypes? Why are you just talking to
them about all this other stuff? And you're
just chit-chatting with them. Ugh. Show them
prototypes." And so we always have to remind
people, "No, no, this is really important."
Partly, you're also just learning a lot. You
hear those stories, which is what you want
to get, but it provides a lot of context for
understanding their reaction to the prototypes.
I love all that context that you shared. This
is the step I think where everyone gets kind
of scared or afraid or thinking they're doing
this wrong, they're biasing people. So in the
book that we'll link to, you give them a guide
for how to write out this whole interview guide.
I have the book here, and I'm just looking at
an example where it's like there's the warmup,
there's the introduction, and then it's like
your current experience with this problem,
cost, depends on the problem space.
But I love in the warmup, big smile. "Hi,
thanks for helping me with this. Thanks
for signing the NDA. I'm dialing in from
Seattle. Where have I reached you?" And
then it's like, "How's the weather where
you are?" So it's all these nice little
questions you can ask to keep it light,
and then just a few examples of questions
you ask in this example where it's about
the medication. It's like, "Do you currently
have prescription medication that you have
to order and refill? How many? If I may
ask, what are they? When was the last
time you filled a prescription?" and on and on.
So it's kind of this whole set of questions just
to help understand their worldview around
this problem and the context around it.
And the way that I think about it is that I'm
building an arc in that conversation. And so it
starts, like you said, it's just chit-chat about
the weather and where you are and whatever. Do I
care what the weather... I don't care what
the weather is like, but what I'm trying
to do is build some rapport fast with somebody.
Again, it gets back to this idea of humble inquiry
where I'm trying to build a connection with the
person. I'm trying to make them feel comfortable,
because they usually are showing
up, they want to make you happy,
but they don't really understand... It's awkward.
It's super weird. Like, "I'm going to talk to this
weird dude. He's paying me to tell him what turns
out to be a bunch of personal stuff, and we're
never going to talk again. But am I doing a good
job?" It's odd. And so I'm trying to put them at
ease and I'm trying to encourage them and make
it clear they're the expert in this situation,
but they don't really know what's going to happen.
And so I'm building this arc slowly, hopefully
not too slowly, to get them talking. So one of
the most important things is when you're doing
that interview, smile. You have to start with
the big smile. Even if you're on the phone,
it totally changes the way your voice sounds.
And what I'm often looking for in those first
few minutes is, are they smiling back? Can I get
the person to smile back at me? And then I'm like,
"Okay, we're good. I'm getting them
responsive and getting them talking."
I love that tip. And again, I think a lot
of people that aren't researches are just
going to, "Oh, I don't know. This feels weird."
Something that should be reassuring is mostly,
you're just asking questions. It's
on them. You're just asking questions
and your job is not to say anything,
almost, just keep asking questions.
Yeah, and to be really genuinely curious. I
think that's really... Again, it's to this
mindset, this difference between selling... I
have to genuinely want to understand and see
the world and my product through their eyes.
And you're going to hear stuff that is wrong,
you know doesn't make sense, or you're like,
"That's weird. What is that?" And you just
have to, not dismiss that, but dig in and try
to understand, like, "Why do you think that?
What gives you that impression?" That's what
you're trying to learn, right? And just smile,
genuine curiosity, and focus on that person
in front of you will get you pretty far.
Any other tips on this step
for folks that are like, "Okay,
I'm going to try this myself. I'm going to
start interviewing folks"? Any other tips,
anything else important you
think is worth mentioning?
Yeah. Practice, it makes a difference.
It's a hard skill. It seems like, oh,
everybody talks to everybody, but it's different.
When I do these, and I've interviewed thousands of
people at this point, I have a different character
mode that I put my head in. And so I literally,
before I start an interview, I stop, I take a
deep breath, and I kind of put on that smile
and I put on my listener character where I am
embodying these things, this extreme curiosity,
this focus on the person, this engagement,
which is quite different from my normal,
more cynical, skeptical personality, to the
point where if my kids have overheard, like,
"Who is that dude? Because that does
not sound like Dad, whoever is talking
to that person." But it's a different mode
in my head where I'm in interviewer mode.
Maybe that's just me, but you might
develop kind of that other character,
especially if you're a founder used to
pitching, you can have your listener character.
Okay. That was an awesome tip. Okay, and so
I think then the next step is the final step,
which is the watch party
where you actually do this.
Yeah. This is awesome. So this is like
our magic hack for banging all this stuff
together. Everything is coming together in
this watch party. So in this watch party,
we have... Again, I'm conducting
the interview. I'm off on Zoom,
one-on-one conducting these interviews. In
the watch party, Vanessa Cho, Kate Aronowitz,
my amazing design partners, often are facilitating
the group there. And so what they're having the
team do is take notes and go through these
debrief sessions in between each interview.
And so we have a very particular way that we
structure all of that, and it's very important
that the team is all in there and watching and
doing this together. So I'm in Zoom, I have it set
up so it's livestreaming to them. So they're not
in my Zoom. It's not like 20 of us with a bunch of
heads watching the person. It's really important
to me that it's just me and the customer that I'm
talking to directly. So they're all livestreaming
it. They're taking notes, so they're in a Google
Doc, or Notion or Doc or whatever
you want, collaboratively doing that.
And so people are assigned roles, so take turns
taking notes, because it's pretty intense. We
have people manually taking notes and not using
AI to take notes. The reason for this is, what
we've found is we want people to lean in to this
experience. We want you to focus and engage and
pay a lot of attention, and if you know somebody
else is taking notes, it tends to maybe make you
lean out a little bit, or maybe you check your
Slack or you're looking at email or something.
And so it's about keeping you really engaged
and working. So it's a working watch party.
So we take turns, we've assigned roles so people
know, "Okay, interview two, Lenny and Margolis
are going to be taking notes. That's fine." And
then there's also a Slack channel, usually, in the
background, because there's a lot of other
chatter, like, "Wait, what did they say? They're
talking about this. They mentioned that product.
Has anybody heard of that?" So that's really
important kind of going in the background. Vanessa
or Kate also monitors that, so that's the way that
somebody can pass me notes to ask specific other
questions. I can't do the interview and track
the notes and Slack. My brain can't handle that.
So they're in there, and then I have a chat window
open just with Kate or Vanessa, and so they'll pop
me questions as they come up. We usually ask teams
to be pretty judicious about that, because if I
get a question like that, it could go a certain
way, as you know, right? You ask a question,
you don't know where it's going to go. And so if
it's really important or you see something where
clearly I've misunderstood something, clarify it.
So they're taking notes. This debrief is in a
spreadsheet that I've set up so that there are key
things that we wanted to learn, and so those are
specified in that spreadsheet for each study that
I'm doing. I'm like, "These were the key things."
Those are not the questions that I'm asking in
the interview, but they're the things, again,
these key questions that we wanted to learn,
which is different from what I'm asking. And
so we're just capturing in that half hour, the
decider, whoever owns the product or the founder
is leading that because they're the decider. And
they're leading, getting input from everybody
and filling in and answering those questions.
So then you can imagine you have... That
first column is that set of questions,
so those are the rows of the questions, and
then each participant is another column. So
we're doing participant one, we're capturing
it after the second one. So we end up with
the detailed notes. We have the recording of my
interview. Those are the thickest, deepest levels
of this. Then we're distilling it down into this
debrief sheet for each one, and so then you have
a spreadsheet that's like the high level steps.
You can look across it at the end of the day.
At the very last thing, at the end
of the day, after the final debrief,
we do a big takeaways form. So I create a
Google Form, and it just is basically like,
"How many interviews did you watch?" just to
check, and then, "What's your first big takeaway,
second, third? How would you adjust your
definition of the bullseye customer here?
What do you think are the next steps or what are
your big questions, open questions and concerns?"
And so each person then takes 5, 10 minutes
independently, separately, individually,
quietly, and just everybody mutes their video
and fills that out. And it's a way to grab a
snapshot from the whole team of like, "What did
we really learn? This was the important things
that we had set out to do. What did we learn?"
And it captures that. So then again, that fills
out a big spreadsheet and we then review that. The
decider kind of goes through it and talks about,
"What are the key patterns? What are the
things that we've learned here as a team?"
And there's this remarkable amount, usually, of
consensus, of alignment about, "What is this?
What do we need to do next?" What I love seeing is
that, quite frankly, one of the most common things
across all of these businesses, all these sites,
all these studies, is that one of the things that
people say we need to do next is more research.
Even though these are all teams who've said,
"We talk to our customers all the time," we
go through this and they're always like, "Oh,
yeah, this looks really different than what
we were doing. We didn't know this stuff."
One of the other things I want to mention
is we do this thing before the watch party
where we get everybody predict what
they think they're going to learn.
Oh, I love that.
And this is really valuable for a bunch
of different reasons. So it's a way to
capture a snapshot before we do the
interviews of, what do you actually
think is going to happen? And we have to
push people to be specific. It's not, "Oh,
we'll find out what they think of our concept."
Yeah, yeah, I know we're going to learn that,
but what do you actually think is going to be
the outcome? People will prefer ASAP delivery
of their medications, and whatever. What is
your hypothesis of what's going to happen here?
And that helps me do a couple things. One
is it helps me make sure that I'm tailoring
the interview guide and everything the
right way, because it's another check,
like am I understanding what you want to
get out of this? It's a snapshot of what
we wanted to learn. And then what happens is
after we go through the big takeaways at the
end of the whole study, it's very valuable to go
back and say, "How does what we learned compare
to what you thought?" because there's this...
Any researchers out there listening to this
will be familiar with this idea. There's this
hindsight bias that happens, which is as you've
gone through the process, it's very difficult
to remember that you didn't already know this.
And so after you've gone through a research
study, very often, people are like, "Well,
that seems obvious. We kind of knew that
that was going to happen." You're like,
"No, no. Let's look back at a day ago, what we
all thought. And we actually have learned a lot,
which is awesome. That's the goal. We've learned
it an enormous amount." And it's not to catch
anybody out, but it's really valuable to
have this snapshot and to, quite frankly,
just help show the value of the research, like,
"We learned things. Or maybe we didn't. Maybe you
were all right, which is awesome. And now we
know, and we can move forward twice as fast."
The point you made about how most people after
this are like, "Wow, this is not what I expected
and I want to do this more," I know that feeling
so well. Every time you're like, "No, I don't need
to talk to customers. I understand what we need to
build," and then you do, you're like, "Holy shit,
why aren't we doing this all the time? What
are we doing?" That's such a powerful feeling.
Yeah. There's this other thing that I think is
worth mentioning that I've come across, which,
when we do this set of predictions, so again,
it's across all different kinds of businesses,
all different kinds of domains, there's
certain patterns that I've noticed that
show up over and over about mispredictions.
There's a pattern of the kinds of things
that show up over and over that I think of
as these common blind spots, and I think
it's attributed... I can attribute it to this,
there's this concept of the curse of knowledge.
So I'm working with lots of teams who are
deep experts in their space. I'm not. I'm
always showing up as the noob, like, "Okay,
what is your business? What are we doing?"
But they have deep expertise. And
when somebody has deep expertise,
it's very difficult to imagine that other people
don't know what you know. It's very hard to put
yourself in their shoes, right? And you just
think, "Well, doesn't everybody know this?"
And so what that leads to is these
key blind spots that are very common,
which is there's an overestimation of how
much your customer knows about the thing,
maybe how big a problem they even perceive it
to be, how much they're willing to pay for it,
which is connected, and where they are on their
journey to be ready to buy this thing. Like, "Oh,
wait, they're not ready yet? Wait." Right? They're
not there yet, or we haven't figured out who the
right people are who are the bullseye, but people
overestimate those kinds of things. And it's
really common blind spots that we find over and
over across a lot of businesses with expert teams.
That makes sense. Most startups realize what
they're trying to build, nobody really cares
about. So I get why that happens often.
Okay. Is there anything else in this
step of the interview that you think is
really important to mention? Otherwise,
I want to hear what you find are some
common pitfalls and mistakes people make.
A couple things, I guess, about the watch party,
that I would make sure... The team needs to be
there, and they need to show up for all of it.
And this is the whole team, like
all the engineers, designers?
Well, yeah. I mean, so the way I like to...
What we found... because sometimes we do this,
and at a maximum, we had 40 people show up. That's
still our record, which is awesome. The more,
the merrier. I want the whole team to see
this, because part of the shortcut of the
watch party is I'm not doing a report. I don't
need to go persuade or explain people what
happened. You all saw it and we went through
it together, and everybody's aligned and gets
what's happened. But it can make some of these
other aspects of the process a little unwieldy.
So what becomes important is to define, who's
the core product team? Everybody's welcome,
but there's a core product team who's probably
taking notes. And also, for us as the outsiders,
we know those are the opinions... That's who's
really building this thing, who's making the
decisions and is going to have to own this and
have to build it or actually do all the work.
So distinguishing about who is that core product
team, they need to really be there for all of it.
Other people, if there's some other engineer on
another project and they want to come in and see
one or two, awesome. Love it. But everybody else,
the core team, you need to be there for all of it.
Where do you find people often
make a big mistake, waste time,
have blind spots, maybe, along this process?
The time that it doesn't work as well. There
are times I get through, and you're just like,
"Ugh, that just didn't work well." It's
because, for one reason or another,
we did not select specifically, we didn't recruit
specifically enough and weren't picky enough
about bullseye customers. So if you up with a
combination of people who was a little mushy,
like you let the bullseye bleed a little
too much, in the end, you're like, "Yeah,
I'm not sure what the conclusions are
to draw here. It just feels mushy."
And so whenever that happens, I always kick
myself. I'm like, "Ugh. The team took control
of the recruiting because it was their customers,
and I just wasn't picky enough or we didn't narrow
it enough, or they included some people who
were experts that they already know and they
talk to all the time. Ugh, it didn't get what
we wanted." And that can be frustrating. So
you just have to really be disciplined and
picky about having the right people in there.
Which comes back to where we started,
just seven attributes. I really like that,
just giving people a heuristic. There's
like seven-ish narrowing attributes of
who you're recruiting to get it really specific.
Yeah. And ideally, you get... Through going
through this process, what I want to do is
get to a point where a team can narrow down
to a point where, actually, there's one or two
attributes that you realize later, that's
the thing. "Oh, it's people on specialty
medications that are refrigerated cold chain.
All the other stuff, maybe not as important."
You figure out that's the distinguishing
characteristic, and so now if I have
some giant funnel or a set of leads or
all these things I need to prioritize,
I can streamline all this other sales motion
or something else that I'm doing. I'm like,
"We'll expand it, but for now, that's
how I'm going to prioritize people."
There's some rubric or some couple questions or
characteristics that are really the key ones.
This reminds me of, actually, with Linear,
something smart they did is they had a wait list
when they first launched, and the wait
list was their questionnaire. What do
you call it? The screener. So basically, the
wait list was a screener survey. It's like,
"What do you use for auth? What do you
use for hosting your code?" And then
they pick those people that most match
what they actually can do that day.
That's brilliant.
Yeah. So there's a lot of overlap
with this exercise and then,
hey, you actually launch. Any
other blind spots or pitfalls,
anything else that you think people often run
into other than not getting narrow enough?
Put more weight on past experiences than on
people's predictions of what they would do.
Classic. Classic user researcher advice.
Yeah.
Say more.
I described, I do these two part interviews.
So that first part is having people describe
and explain past experiences, what
they've done, what's important to them,
et cetera. I put much more weight in
that as building the trajectory of,
what will this person accept or value or
avoid, what do they think are barriers,
to then showing a prototype. They're like,
"Oh, I would totally do this." And you're like,
"That does not sound at all consistent with what
you just described to me, so I'm going to be
somewhat skeptical of your prediction of what
you would do or what you think might happen."
It's not about the customer. We're all terrible
at this, predicting what we're going to do, and
so I just put much more weight in what has this
person shown and demonstrated in the past as their
behavior and their attitudes and opinions. And so
I really try to get teams to anchor more on that.
I love that. I think everyone always hears
this and then they still fall for this,
because it's like, "Oh, great, they're going
to use this. Awesome. Let's build it. They
told us they would use this immediately." So
what I think back to is your advice of like,
look for extreme excitement. That's more
of a signal that maybe they actually will.
And the other thing that you
alluded to is confirmation bias,
right? And we encourage people in the watch
party... We give people rules about how to listen,
and we encourage people to make it okay to kind of
police each other a little bit and jokingly like,
"Oh, it sounds like you're confirming your
own bias about people would do this thing
that you thought they would do." Try to
keep each other honest about what you're
actually hearing and try to be as neutral
and objective about what you're hearing.
I love that. To the signal that they're
excited, it reminds me someone's quote
once was, "Look for their pupils to dilate to
sense how excited they are about something."
You can just see it. You do a bunch of this and
you'll know. And if you don't know,
you're like, "It's probably a no."
Which is how everyone always describes what
product-market fit feels like. You just know
it. If it's not obvious, then you don't have it.
Okay. Michael, we did a lot of good work here.
We've gone through the entire process,
solved everyone's problems. I'm going to
skip the lighting round just to keep this
episode shorter. Is there anything else
that you want to leave listeners
with before we wrap up?
One thing I've been thinking about and
recently getting to experiment with,
which I'm pretty excited about, is
how to apply these methods in biotech.
So a big piece of the GV portfolio is in biotech,
developing new therapies, new treatments. That's
a very different-looking kind of business than
a lot of digital enterprise, consumer kind of
products that I work with. What I think is really
interesting is as I work more with those people...
And so those are years, right? And they're doing
science, so nobody's calling me when they're doing
science. They don't need that help. They get to
a point where there is some productization of it.
You need to figure out like, "Oh, actually,
how is this going to fit into a physician's
workflow? How will patients react to this
relative to some other possible treatment
or other things that are out there? How do we
encourage more people to accrue onto a clinical
trial? How do we think about a clinical trial
as a product and streamline that and make sure
we're targeting the right people and increasing
the number of people who are getting on there?"
So what's been interesting is as I work
with teams... I mean, talk about expert
teams. As I talk to people who come from that
tradition, I don't know what else to describe it,
is they're doing similar work, but they don't seem
to describe themselves as product managers. They
have other kinds of titles. They come from like
patient education, they have these other titles,
but they're doing similar kinds of work. But
they come from this other place, and so it's
really... And they talk about TPPs, target product
profiles. It's like this different language and
this different world to me, but it's the same
things, the same methods and the same stuff.
So the idea of bringing some of these methods
there, as I've been getting to do more recently,
is really exciting to me because
it feels like there's a... Partly,
it feels a little greenfield, and partly, it
just feels like the impact there is huge for
some of those things. So that's something that
I've just been thinking a lot about recently,
is just kind of excited about those kind of
opportunities. And also just kind of curious,
I don't know, to hear from some of your listeners
if they're doing some of this in those spaces.
This is a good segue to two final questions
that I ask everyone, so perfect. One is just
share where people can find your book if they
want to go deeper, if they want to practice it
themselves. And also, do they reach out if
they want to work with you on this sort of
thing? So just share what folks can do if
they want to learn more. And then, coming
back to what you just said, how can listeners be
useful to you, maybe share cool biotech stuff?
So learnmorefaster.com, you can go grab a
free copy of the book. There's all kinds
of demo videos of me doing interviews. There's
all kinds of worksheets and resources. They're
using a really nerdy researcher playlist there. So
please just go grab stuff. It's all free. Again,
I'm not selling anything. I'm just really
eager to get people to try this and use
it. And please tell me, in terms of how you
could help me, tell me your stories. Try it,
let me know what works, how you adapt it,
how it applies even to places that aren't
early-stage startups. I assume some of this
is relevant there, so please let me know.
Ways you can reach me to let me
know is michael@learnmorefaster.com,
you can just directly send me a note there.
I can't guarantee I'll reply to everybody,
but I'll read it all. And I'm on LinkedIn,
is probably a really great place to reach me.
And it sounds like you also
answered that last question,
how can folks be helpful? It's just like,
share their experience with... Awesome.
Yeah, totally. Just tell me your stories. How
did you use this? What did you use it on? What
worked? What didn't? How should we fix it? I'm
excited that we were able to opensource this,
that GV was able to do that, and so part
of that is, help me update it and fix it.
Awesome. And just to clarify,
if folks want to go really deep,
do you work with companies just ad hoc? Or
how does that work, just so people know?
I work with GV portfolio companies, so-
Okay, okay, got it. So go work
with GV. Okay, there we go. Great.
Yeah, my full-time job is
UX research partner at GV.
Awesome. Michael, thank
you so much for being here.
Thank you a ton. I've loved
this. This has been super fun.
Awesome. I love to hear that. Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to
the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.