Make sure you go somewhere where you have a good
engineering partner. Because if you have great
ideas of what to build but you can't get them
built, then you go nowhere. So that has to be
part of your evaluation criteria that you meet
and value your engineering partner before you
join. And then I think what's really important
is that you're aligned. You understand your roles
and responsibilities and where you're going
to divide and conquer and where you're going
to be aligned. You don't want any of this ...
Like people in the organization, they ask mom,
they asked dad and they got different opinions and
playing one against the other. That doesn't work.
Today, my guest is Tamar Yehoshua. Tamar is
currently president of product and technology
at Glean, one of the most successful enterprise
AI companies out there right now. Prior to joining
Glean, Tamar was chief product officer at Slack
for four years where she led product design and
research as the company scaled 10Xed their
revenue, went through IPO and then got bought
by Salesforce. Tamar also led product and
engineering teams at Google, where for many
years she was responsible for the Google search
experience. She also spent five years at Amazon
as director of engineering and vice president at
A9.com. She was also a venture partner at IVP and
has been on board of directors for ServiceNow,
Snyk, RetailMeNot, and Yext. In our conversation,
we get into all kinds of juicy advice, including
why companies don't have to be run well to win,
why you don't need a career plan, the two
habits she credits most for helping her succeed
throughout her career, what she learned from Jeff
Bezos and Stewart Butterfield and Marc Benioff,
how to build stronger cross-functional
relationships and a bunch of advice on
AI including how it will likely change
your jobs, examples of how she and her
colleagues are already using AI to be more
productive in their work and what she's
learned about building AI-based products that are
non-deterministic and can be very unpredictable.
This episode is for anyone looking to level up
as a leader and get a better sense of how AI will
change your job. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in
your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's
the best way to avoid missing future episodes
and it helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you Tamar Yehoshua.
Tamar, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you so much for having me.
I've had so many people recommend you
coming on this podcast. I'm really
happy that we're finally doing this. I want to
start with a question that I've started to ask
people who have had extraordinarily successful
careers, which you've had. So let me ask you,
what are one or two specific skills or mindsets
or habits that you think most contributed to
your success during the course of your career
that you think might be helpful to people who
are trying to figure out how to accelerate their
career or just be more successful in their career?
One of the things that I think is overlooked
is do a really good job at whatever your job
is at that point. People have a tendency ...
Especially product managers are very ambitious
and they want to get to the next level
and they're always eyeing the next job,
but you're not going to get the next
job unless you do really well at the
job that you're in. Knock it out of the park.
However simple, however easy it may be to you,
do a great job. And in tech jobs, there's
table stakes. There's table stakes of you
need to be technical, you need to know the latest
technology, you need to understand your product,
the product you're working on. No matter
what your role is. You have to understand
it deeply. You need to understand metrics. So
especially product managers have a wide breadth
of things that they need to understand.
So those are a given. You need to do that.
This episode is brought to you by Explo, a game
changer for customer facing analytics and data
reporting. Are your users craving more dashboards,
reports and analytics within your product? Are
you tired of trying to build it yourself? As a
product leader, you probably have these requests
in your roadmap, but the struggle to prioritize
them is real. Building analytics from scratch
can be time-consuming, expensive, and a really
challenging process. Enter Explo. Explo is a fully
white labeled embedded analytics solution designed
entirely with your user in mind. Getting started
is easy. Explo connects to any relational database
or warehouse, and with its low-code functionality,
you can build and style dashboards in minutes.
Once you're ready, simply embed the dashboard
or report into your application with a tiny
code snippet. The best part, your end users
can use Explo's AI features for their own report
and dashboard generation, eliminating customer
data requests for your support team.
Build and embed a fully white labeled
analytics experience in days. Try it for free
at explo.co/lenny. That's E-X-P-L-O.C-O/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Sprig. What
if product teams knew exactly what to build to
reach their goals? From increasing
conversion to boosting engagement,
these challenges require a deep understanding
of your users, something that you can't get
from product analytics alone. Meet Sprig, a
product experience platform that generates AI
powered opportunities to continuously
improve your product at scale. First,
Sprig captures your product experience
in real time through heat maps, replays,
surveys, and feedback studies, then Sprig's
industry leading AI instantly analyzes all of
your product experience data to generate
real-time insights. Sprig AI goes even
further with actionable product recommendations to
drive revenue, retention, and user satisfaction.
Join product teams at Figma and at Notion by
uncovering AI powered product opportunities at
scale. Visit sprig.com/lenny to book a demo and
get a $75 gift card. S-P-R-I-G dot com/lenny.
So now the question is the difference
in leadership and executive roles and
when you're getting there. So how do you start
transitioning? So after you've done a great job
at everything and you understand the core skills
that you need, another thing you really need to
know is understanding people and motivations.
And when you're building products, you have to
understand why does somebody want to use your
product? What problem are they solving? Why do
they want to click on that button? What's going to
make them feel good when they click on it? What's
going to give them delight and what's also going
to make them feel bad and frustrated and what do
they not want to do? So you need to understand
motivations in people for building products
and for building teams and organizations. So just
like why does somebody want to click on a button,
why does somebody want to join your team? Why
do they want to work hard? What are they trying
to accomplish? What's the goal for their career?
So you have to be able to read people, ask lots of
questions to understand them. And I'll say one
thing that really helped me, this is a strange
segue, but my father was a psychiatrist and when
I was growing up, we would have family occasions,
go to events, whatever, and afterwards in the car
ride back, he would always give his perspective of
analyzing what happened at the event. What this
person was thinking. Why did they say this? And
then he would quiz me of, "Why do you think
they did that?" And it was really interesting
because it taught me to see the whole room.
To see how people react. Like Lenny, if you
say something and somebody else is there, look
at the other person. What's their face saying?
You can understand so much if you're paying
attention. So I think when you want to build
for people and lead organizations, it is about the
people and understanding them and motivating them.
I love this advice. I feel like we could
do a whole podcast on just this topic. So
on this last point about understanding
people, is there an example of this in
either a product you built of just like, "Oh,
here's something I noticed about someone using
Slack or Google or Amazon that changed the way
I think about building this specific feature."?
One of the things that I caution product managers
about is that you don't want to be too overly
reliant on metrics and you want to also have
an intuition. You want product managers who
understand intuitively their customers
and their product and sometimes you'll
make decisions because you just know it's the
right thing to do because it feels right and
it usually is right if you understand your
product well enough. How do you get good at
it? Ask a lot of questions. Don't assume
you know. Marc Benioff would always say,
"Have a beginner's mind. Go in assuming that
you know nothing and listen to your customers,
listen to the people." Because I also see this as
you're building a feature and you think it's the
best thing. Because of course everyone's going to
want it because you worked on it and you're going
to put it front and center in the interface
where everybody's going to see it. Well, no,
you got to earn that right. And that is another
thing that people do is they want the thing they
worked on to be right there, but it might not be
the most important thing that a person needs at
that point. So have perspective. Have perspective
of what your users are actually trying to achieve.
Going back to your first point about
doing a great job at the job you have,
I imagine some people hear this and the advice is
do a great job at the job you're already doing,
and they may feel like they are, and there's
other reasons they aren't being promoted. Is
there an example from your career or a story
you could tell of just like to clarify what
doing a great job look like where it's
not just like I hit my goals. It's like,
here's what it looks like. Here's
how you actually get ahead.
Are you helping the business move forward? So
it's not about I achieve what I was asked to do,
but did you build something that people actually
used? It's not about just launching something and
did you do the right thing for the company? And
that is different. It's a different mindset. Did
you enable the entire organization to be more
productive despite you? I remember very early
in my career I was working as an engineer and
I was offered a job to manage a team that was
across different programs. I took a vacation,
I came back and I said, "I don't think this
team should exist." It was my first management
job and I wanted to be a manager. And I said,
"Here's why I don't think that this team
should exist. It's not the right thing for
the company. It's not going to be productive."
And my manager was so stunned. He was like,
"Wait. You're saying no?" I'm like, "Yeah,
because here's how you should organize
it." And then he's like, "You're right, and
I'll find you something else," and he did.
If I were to put this into one
word, it's impact. Drive impact.
Yeah.
Amazing. Okay. Going in a different direction,
we were chatting before we started recording
this and something that you shared with me, and
some people may be really surprised to hear this,
but I completely agree with this take,
is that you don't need to be a well-run
business to win. I've seen this myself. I'd
love to hear your insights here and especially
where you notice this. What parts of
your career noticed this to be true?
I love working at well-run companies. It's more
fun, your people are happier. I like running a
well-run team, so I aspire to have a very well
run team and to work at a well run company.
But what I've seen is when a company isn't well
run like IT isn't working, marketing is broken,
there are not enough people in HR, there's a
lot of turnover. All of these things I've seen
that they're not correlated to the company being
successful. So I can think of a couple examples
right now of companies I know ... Not Glean,
where I'm working today. Where there's high
executive turnover. Where people get yelled at.
There are lots of people fired. There's reorgs
all the time. People I talk to are super unhappy,
but the numbers are amazing. They're growing like
crazy. And the opposite sit is also true. I can
think of one company I know really well, amazing,
CEO, well run, well oiled machine, everything.
Hired good executives and they flat lined.
So you just see it. You see it over and over again
and people get very upset about these things that
aren't working. And one of the things that I try
and do is give a perspective of what matters and
what doesn't. And it might even be to the sales
team because you get all these requests for
features all the time. If you did every single
one, it would be impossible. Even if you did,
80, 90% of them won't matter for the success
of the company. But then there are some that
really matter. So what are the things that really
matter? We always talk about product market fit.
Nobody really knows what product market fit
is. Everybody has a different explanation,
but it means people want to use your product.
That they're clamoring for it. So you've built
something that people value and that people value
and that solves a problem for them, but that's
also not good enough. You need to build a great
product, but you also have to have distribution
and you need to have a sales team that works. And
you have to have enough money in the bank to get
there. So those are probably the things that are
the most important. I might be missing something.
And then within each of those, there's the
things that really mattered and there's so
many features that we built at Slack that were
the most important features ever that failed
and nobody used so it clearly didn't have an
impact. And you can see that in retrospect,
but I think after being at multiple different
big companies and small companies, I have that
perspective of let's just make sure that we
do the right things and don't get too worked
up about all the things that are broken because
every startup has so many things that are broken.
So I think a really interesting insight here
is that if you're working at a company that
is just chaotic and it feels like
we don't know what we're doing,
I don't know how this thing is running, I don't
know how this will continue to be successful,
your experience is it ... Is it that most of
the successful companies you've been at are
just chaotic internally and aren't incredibly
run and that's normal, that's very typical?
Until they get to a certain scale. Now, once
you reach a certain scale and you've already
conquered the market, then you need to be well
run. Then you bring in professional managers
and things are about the cost and executing and
getting all the ... Once you get to over 5,000
people or 10,000 people, you got to have things
that ... Then you're a growth engine. You have
to know what phase you're in and what's important
at that phase. So it isn't that at every phase,
chaos is okay, and also some chaos is okay and
some chaos is not okay. If you're changing your
strategy all the time and you're changing your
direction and you're changing projects on people
all the time so that they can't actually
achieve anything ... So this is again,
so you can't simplify it that some chaos is
okay and some isn't. And also some chaos is
right for you as a person. There are some
really great companies I would never work
at because they don't fit me. They're not
a company I would enjoy going to work in
the morning or they're not aligned with what I'm
good at. So just because a company is doing well,
if the chaos is chaos and something that's going
to make you upset and unhappy don't work there.
Is there a correlation there? Just like companies
that have strong product market fit, things are
just breaking as they're going through hyper
growth? Just thoughts on why this is the case.
A lot of it is that because if you are
in hyper growth, you've got customers
coming at a really fast pace, you're growing
your company really quickly and the number
of employees and it's just really hard to keep
up. Because things in the infrastructure break,
things in the communication breakdown. You've
got at any given point 50% of the company has
been there less than six months. But you
have to grow really fast because once you
hit product market fit, if you don't, then your
growth will stop. So if you're suddenly growing,
especially if you're an enterprise company, you
have to have salespeople, if you're a consumer
company or systems have to keep running as you
scale. And look at companies like MySpace, well,
they died because their product got too slow. And
so some companies have initial product market fit
and then they don't keep up. So I do think a lot
of it is it's very hard to grow that fast. And so
things really do start breaking, but then once you
get all the right leadership in place, processes
in place, then it starts to get better. So it
goes through ups and downs in level of chaos.
There's one takeaway here that product market fit
solves a lot of problems.
Strong product market fit.
Well, no product market fit is
a death sentence. I would say
it more like that. If you built a product
that people aren't really excited to use,
then you don't have a company because it's very
hard to do that unless you have distribution
machine and then you catch up over time.
But we will not name companies like that.
So there are other ways of doing it, but
yeah, that is the most important thing.
Yeah. I will say during my experience
at Airbnb, I absolutely saw this. It was
just nonstop chaos. And I always felt like,
well, how is this continuing to operate and
succeed? Things are just out of control.
Everything's changing every six months.
I don't know what's happening here. And I
think a lesson here is just that's normal
for a hyper growth business that has
strong product market fit. But again,
not a good excuse to just allow chaos. And
it's not like chaos means success, right?
And it's not a good excuse to not have an
organization that's functioning. You should still
strive to have an organization that's functioning
and keep people happy and motivated and all that.
Great. Okay. Another maybe contrarian
opinion that you hold along the career
track is that you don't need to plan your
career. I also 100% agree with this. I had
no plan for my career. I never knew where
the hell I was going to go. I never had
this vision of here's what I want to do.
I just followed things that were pulling
me and things that seemed interesting. I love
that you also tell people this. I'd love to
hear your insights here. Especially for someone
that's either struggling with their career or
just stressed. They don't have a plan or their
plan's not working the way they wanted it to.
Really recently I was talking to somebody in
their twenties who was asking me for career
advice. Should I be a product manager, et cetera.
And I'm trying to put together my five-year plan
and I said, "I never had a five-year plan."
So to be clear, some people need that.
That's the kind of people they are. They want the
planning. I said, "It's great if you want that,
but I never had it." And the person I was talking
to just relaxed and they're like, "Oh my God,
that's so great to hear because I have no idea
what I want to do in five years." I'm like,
"I still have no idea what I want to do in five
years. I've never had an idea what I want to do in
five years." Early in your career you have a lot
more angst about it because the forks in the road
are more significant because they can go, do
I go get an MBA or do I go work for somebody?
Do I be a product manager or an engineer? And
those really take you in very different paths.
And I meet a lot of kids in their ... I
shouldn't call them kids. My kids are my
kids' friends. But a lot of people who are
younger in their career who are struggling
with this a little bit. So what I believe,
and I've always believed is that you follow
people. You learn the most from people. I don't
look for domains. Some people have a domain,
like I'm super interested in climate or whatever
and they really want to work in that area and
that's fine so maybe within that area. But you
follow people who are the best at what they do.
So it's not good enough to follow somebody who
you like. You want to follow somebody who's either
the best product thinker or the best engineer
or the best salesperson. And so that you will
learn the skill of how to be the best at that.
So you follow people where you're going to learn
the most. And a way to do that also is you look
at where the great people are going. So you want
to go to companies where there's also a nexus
of great people because they together will do
great things. And even if the company fails
or succeeds, but not as much as you'd like,
you still have those connections. Everybody talks
about the PayPal Mafia and how they've gone on
to do things. I was super lucky to be at Google
for so many years and I spent a lot of time with
Googlers that I met and that are all working
in different companies now because you build
those relationships by working together. So
if you follow people and where you're going
to learn the most and you go step by step, I think
that's a great way of progressing in your career.
That's such tactical advice. And I've seen this
work for a lot of people that just go where their
favorite former employees work. And not favorite
to your point, but the people that they most
respect and have been most impressed by. And
I think it's such an easy thing to do. It's a
really easy heuristic for understanding where to
go. There's something Marc Andreessen once shared
that I'm reminded of when you say this. There's
a term for this, I forget the actual term, but
there's certain companies have this gravitational
pull where they are acquiring all the best talent.
They're currently the gravity in the space and
everyone awesome is going there. And you have to,
as a company, know you're one of those
companies or you're the opposite. You're
losing all the people and they're all going to
this other company. I guess any thoughts on that?
Yeah. And it's really bad when you don't have
a gravitational pull. It's super hard. I would
say that one thing that if you're a
manager, I always advise managers,
go somewhere where you can recruit. I got a piece
of advice from a friend that I thought was amazing
advice as a leader. She said to me, "Take a
job where if you hire people, it's going to
make their careers." I was like, "Whoa." Because
I was getting offers for some turnaround jobs.
And if you think you can turn around, great.
But if you're going to hire the best people,
you want to make sure that it's going to be a good
place for them and that they're going to learn and
they're going to grow. And so you want to do
right by them. And you really earnestly want
to say you can make your career by coming here.
And I thought that gave such a higher bar for
every job I was looking at as a leader that I
thought it was just amazing advice. And then
on the flip side, on the negative side, some
people are putting too much emphasis on where
will I get a big financial return? And I've
found that financial returns are the hardest
to predict. You know who's good. You know who
you want to work with. You can predict where
you're going to learn. Because even if a company
fails, you learn a lot. But predicting financial
success is so hard because you don't know what's
going to happen with the market, with the world,
with crypto, and Meta AI. And people who
do that and say ... I had one person say,
"I took this job because I'm a mercenary. They
just paid me a ton." Did not work out for him.
And I feel really bad when people do that,
but I think that it's a dangerous thing to do.
I imagine some people hearing this
advice are going to feel like,
"I'm not going to get a job at
OpenAI or Glean or other awesome
companies that everyone wants to go
work at." Any advice to those folks?
There's lots of good companies and
there's lots of smart people. You
don't have to be at the top brand. And
if you go somewhere where you're going
to learn and it's going to get you there.
I made mistakes. I went to some companies,
multiple companies that failed or stopped growing
and didn't do well or didn't have all the right
people. Careers you don't make every step is to
the right place. You remember in what you cited,
all the companies I went to that did well, you
left out all the ones that I went to that didn't
do well. And so then people will assume that
every time I made a job change, it was to a
company that did well. No. That was not the
case. So if you focus on that learning bit,
you will get there. And there are lots of paths.
There isn't just the OpenAI or Glean or Anthropic.
Awesome. And again, I love how tactical this
is. If someone is trying to figure out where
to go work if they're unhappy in their current
job or don't have a job right now is just make
a list of the people you most respect
that are the best at the thing they do,
see where they work and there's your list of
companies to potentially go after. There's a
lot of benefits to this as you shared. It's
not just helping you pick the place to work,
it's the network. It'll level you up. Is
there anything else along those lines that
is helpful for people to think about
why this is a really good strategy?
Skills can't be taken away. A company can fail,
but if you learn a skill, you
will always have that skill.
I love that. And I've totally seen this to
work, so I really love that you're focusing
on this advice. You've mentioned places you've
worked and folks you've worked with. You worked
with folks like Jeff Bezos, Stewart Butterfield,
some of the top product thinkers, leaders in the
world. So let me just ask, what's one thing you
learned from Jeff Bezos and Stewart Butterfield?
Probably can't narrow it down to one, but I'll
talk about Bezos first. I was very lucky to join
Amazon early when I still ... I had quarterly
meetings with Jeff Bezos. And this was before
AWS launched, so it was before Amazon was known in
the Valley. This is another example. I went there
because I went to work for Udi Manbe who started
A9 and he was talking to me one night trying to
recruit me and he spent two hours on the phone
with me telling me how amazing Jeff Bezos was. And
this was before there were any books on him. And
that really convinced me to go there. So there's
a lot written on Bezos. Read his shareholder
letters, read the books about him, read Colin
Bryar's Working Backwards. The Everything Box
I think it's called or The Everything Store.
The Everything Store. Yeah.
There's so many good books and there's so much
to learn about how he works. So I won't try and
cover those things. The things that stood out
to me from the meetings I had with him were
a couple of things. One, a lot of people have
written about these six pagers, so he doesn't
believe in PowerPoint. You write a six pager
about ... It's like studying for the final exam
is writing these six pagers. So you go into the
meeting and there's the people around the table,
his executive team and him. First he does
not speak until everybody around the table
speaks. So he goes around to all his leads and
said, "What do you think? What do you think?
What do you think?" And I'm sitting there like,
"I don't care what anyone think. I just want to
hear what Bezos thinks." But he wants to make sure
that it's a team effort and that he's listening to
what everybody in his organization thinks.
And he always spoke last. He is by far the
smartest person I've ever met in my life. I've
worked with a lot of smart people. But his ability
to go deep in any domain and nail the core issue,
and remember. We would've quarterly meetings and
from quarter to quarter he would remember things
that he had talked about before and then he would
go into the architecture of search and why are
you doing it this way or that way? And you're just
blown away that he knows that. For me, the biggest
takeaway from those meetings was his consistency,
which is he had principles that it made it easier
for you to operate in his company because you knew
what he cared about because he always had these
principles. Everything had to be customer driven,
everything had to be relevant for the customer.
He hated icons. That was just the thing. You had
to write what they were because people couldn't
figure out what they are. So anytime you showed
an icon, he would get annoyed. But you would go
in and after a couple of meetings you're like,
"Okay. I know what he's going to ask about. I know
how he's thinking and I know what his principles
are." And I think that consistency enables you
to operate a large organization more effectively.
And then there's one other thing that I really
remember was one of the few really small meetings
I was in with him and we were presenting
working on a new product, and I was like,
"Our competitors have 10 times as many people as
we do on this." And he looks at me and he said,
"That is your advantage." And then he goes into
his talk about how it's a hill and it takes seven
years to build a product. You can't look at it in
the near term. You have to be in it for the long
term. You can be sure I never went in and said,
"I need a lot more resources." So that was Bezos.
Awesome.
Stewart. Again, I went to Slack because I wanted
to work with Stewart Butterfield. I think he
is the best product thinker in the Valley.
He's not working in product right now. He's
taking time off. But he's got this combination of
long-term thinking and in the details. So in 2014,
he wrote a master plan for Slack, which was
build a product people love, build a network.
That's Slack Connect. Build a platform that makes
all of your other SaaS products more valuable.
That's Slack Platform. And then do some magic
AI stuff. Magic AI stuff took a lot longer, but-
That was part of his plan
early on is magic AI stuff.
It literally was. There was a grid with four
boxes in 2014 and it never changed. That was
his master plan and what we worked on each
year changed. But somebody recently asked me,
"You guys did Slack Connect much later?" I'm like,
"Yeah, but it was always part of the plan." It was
always part of his vision. So he saw forward in
the vision, but he also was very much into the
details. And I think the thing that I learned
from him the most was the power of prototyping.
And that even though he was such a great product
thinker, he would always say, "I can't tell you if
this is going to work. I have to feel it. I have
to try it. And a mock-up doesn't tell you what
it's going to feel like." And he would push people
to do prototypes, not incremental of just to get a
feature out, but really to think. Very soon after
I started, we launched ... I hired a design lead,
Ethan Eismannn, and he led a redesign of
the new information architecture for Slack.
I worked with Ethan at Airbnb.
Oh yeah.
He was head of design for the search
experience and the search team.
Yeah. Ethan is awesome. And he came in and his
first task was to work with Stewart on this
redesign. And Stewart came in and said, "I want
you to take everything in the interface and put
it behind one button." And everyone's like,
"That's never going to work." And he's like,
"Do it. Just do it." And so we had our prototypers
... We had also engineers, front-end engineers who
were really good at prototyping, literally
took everything in the interface and put it
behind one button and he said, "This is how
you're going to see what you really need in
the interface." So we were never going to ship
that, but it was the beginning of the redesign.
Let me tell you about a product called Sidebar.
The most successful people that I know surround
themselves with incredible peers. When you have a
trusted group of peers, you can discuss challenges
you're having, get career advice and just gut
check how you're thinking about your work,
your career and your life. This gives you more
than a leg up. It gives you a leap forward. Having
a group of trusted and amazing peers was key to
my career growth. And this is the Sidebar ethos,
but it's hard to build this trusted group of
peers on your own. Sidebar is a platform for
senior tech professionals, director to C-level to
advance in their career. Members are matched into
peer groups to lean on for unbiased opinions,
diverse perspectives and raw feedback. Guided
by world-class programming and facilitation, all
running on Sidebar's technology Sidebar enables
you to get focused tactical feedback
at every step of your career journey.
If you're a listener of this podcast, you're
already committed to growth. Sidebar is the
missing piece to catalyze your career.
93% of members say Sidebar helped them
achieve a significant positive change in their
career. Check them out at sidebar.com/lenny.
As a product leader, how do you think about
just the time it takes to create a prototype
in something like this? As a pm I'm just like
a lot of times we don't have time to build this
whole prototype. We got to ship stuff, we got to
hit these calls, we got experiments to run, we'll
just build it and see how it goes. How do you
think about making time for something like that?
If you're doing it right, it'll be faster and
you need to have an engineering infrastructure
that enables prototyping. So some engineering
infrastructures are too heavy and they don't
actually enable prototyping. We had a problem with
our mobile apps that it was too hard to prototype
and we actually redesigned our mobile apps until
we got to the point where it was easier because
our desktop app was pretty easy to prototype.
But you have to have a layer of abstraction
that enables you to do that, and you have to
have engineers who have a prototyping mindset,
and if you build multiple things and you have
this mindset as I'm willing to throw it away,
you write code that is never going to make it
to production so you can just crank it out much
faster and then you can see what works and then
you build the production code. Until you actually
get to your end goal of something working faster.
But you need the engineering team to have the same
mindset. The product and engineering have to work
together and design because design is just in it.
Sometimes you can get design engineers who are
doing the prototyping. So your first prototypes
are like Figma prototypes, and then you get
prototypes on real data. When I was at Google,
one of our teams, a front-end team, I
remember we hired a bunch of prototypers
and our head of front-end engineering said to
me one day, this is my secret weapon. This is
how we move faster. So I do think it's
a mindset shift and a tech stack shift.
We're going to talk about AI later,
but it's also getting easier to build
prototypes with AI. There's this
video recently that went around on
Twitter where an eight-year-old girl was
building an app and in like 45 minutes,
she built a chatbot using this product
called Cursor. So I think that'll unlock
a lot of great product on opportunities and just
accelerate this sort of work. I asked about Jeff
Bezos and Stewart Butterfield. I'm curious if
there's another leader you've worked with that
maybe is less known that you also learned a
ton from that might be worth talking about.
I think that there are people who are really,
really good at what they do. So Marc Benioff is
an amazing marketeer. His marketing mind ... After
the acquisition, I got the opportunity to onstage
with him at Dreamforce for ... Because Slack was
a new shiny thing so of course Slack was going to
be in the keynote. And so I was in the Benioff's
keynote two years in a row. And so I watched how
he approaches his keynote and the whole thing
around Dreamforce. Dreamforce is incredible at
the impact that it has on the ecosystem. And so
I think that as a product, people don't think
of him as much, but as his marketing
abilities are amazing what he's done.
I've written posts about how various
companies got started in Salesforce
history. Always comes to mind where they go
to conferences where's there's no software
mascot walking around. And I remember
they did something around one of their
competitors where they just created
some real controversy around someone.
Well, they went into their competitor's conference
and stood outside their competitor's conference.
Mm-hmm. Right. That's what it was.
This is in the Beyond Software. This
is in his book that he wrote about
the early phases of Salesforce. And it
takes his guts. He pushes the envelope.
I love that. It's a really good
point that people don't think of
Marc Benioff as a marketer. And that's
interesting that that's maybe the main
thing you took away from him is just
the power of marketing and the skill.
He approaches his marketing
presentations like a product
person approaches their building their product.
Amazing. Okay. Speaking of former colleagues,
I asked one of your former colleagues, his name
is Fuzzy Khos. He's now the CTO of Notion.
You worked with him, I believe at Slack.
And at Google.
And at Google. Wow. Okay. So
I asked him what to ask you,
and he said that you're amazing at building
strong cross-functional relationships,
especially with engineers. I know you used to be
an engineer, so I get where that skill come from.
What can you teach people about building stronger
cross-functional relationships, especially
PMs to build better relationships with their
engineers, designers, other folks on their team?
Probably the most important thing that a product
leader does because if you have great ideas of
what to build, but you can't get them built,
then you go nowhere. So one, make sure somewhere
where you have a good engineering partner. So
Henderson was the co-founder and CTO of Slack,
and I couldn't have asked for a better engineering
partner. He's just awesome. And that has to be
part of your evaluation criteria that you meet
and value your engineering partner before you
join or you know that it's not the right one and
the organization is willing to make a change. So
that can happen too. You can go in and understand
that something has to change, but that is a very,
very important thing of what you're doing
and what you're assessing when you go in.
And then I think what's really important is that
you're aligned. You understand your roles and
responsibilities and where you're going to divide
and conquer and where you're going to be aligned.
You don't want any of this ... People in the
organization, they asked Mom, they asked dad
and they got different opinions and playing one
against the other, that doesn't work. So one,
you have to know that you're not going to do that.
So if somebody would ask me something that it was
in Cal's domain, I'd be like, "Did you talk to
Cal?" I would never try and go around him. So we
were very clear on, you're going to drive this,
I'm going to drive this. And if it was unclear,
we'd talk and we would say, "Okay. Who's
going to take this one?" And we would do
all our reviews together. And so all of the
OKR reviews, we had weekly exec reviews,
we had the updates on our OKRs, so we did them
all together, but I knew here's the things that
he was going to ask the questions on and dig deep.
And then when I was, he would take a back seat,
but of course we could ask questions in each other
things, but I knew that he was taking ownership
and he knew what I was taking ownership of.
But I think the bottom line was respect. Is that
you have to respect and trust that they actually
will follow up on what they say they will. In Cal
and Fuzzy were amazing at that. I would go to
Fuzzy and be like, "Hey, we need more mobile
engineers because this one product is not going
to ship." And he's like, "I'm on it. Got it." And
that was all I needed to do. And obviously if he
couldn't do it, he'd come back to me and, "Hey,
there's going to be a problem." But it was like
just things got done. That's the best part of it.
You talked about being aligned, which I love and I
fully have seen that power of that of you and your
engine manager, design manager being aligned on
... And you tell me if I'm wrong, but specifically
on what goals you're trying to achieve, what
success looks like, things like that. Are there
any tactics you found to create that alignment?
And also if there's anything else you want to
add to the point I just made about what it is
you're specifically aligned on, that'd be great.
One, you got to spend a lot of time together.
There isn't a way around that. And you have
to document things and make sure that you've
talked it through. And if you don't agree with
something and you're not sure it's a priority,
you have to speak up and you can't just be like,
"Okay, whatever.", and then go to somebody in
your team and be like, "Oh God, that that CTO,
why did he make this decision?" That just
doesn't work. So I'm a very direct person.
So if I don't think that something is the right
priority or is working, I will be very clear. We
had different forms, so I'll be very tactical
here on the forms that Cal and I had together.
Perfect.
We used OKRs to drive our processes and
we would have the teams present OKRs to
us. When the team got too large, it got
to be too much time to go through every
team's OKR review so we had a Slack
channel for each team, their OKRs,
a planning channel for each one. And people would
post a doc and then a Slack video of going through
the major points. And we had a time limit of how
long they were allowed to be. And they would say,
"Here's our OKRs, here's the things
that you would pay attention to." And
then Cal and I would do a marathon and
we would watch them all together. And-
In a room sitting there watching them together?
Correct. And then we would say, "Do we have any
follow-up questions?" And we put in channel our
follow-up questions to the team. And sometimes
there'd be five to 10 teams that we would then
have a follow-up meeting with. We would say
that this is a really high priority project or
there are a lot of questions that we have, and
then we would do a meeting but we were always
doing those meetings together. So that was the OKR
reviews of getting the alignment. And by asking
the questions, we could then ... By it just being
us, we could dig into the team. And we each had a
chief of staff, so it was the two of us plus
our two chiefs of staff, and which they also
did a divide and conquer and they worked really
well together. They were both long time Slack
employees. So for years they had ... One had been
an engineering director and one had been a TPM.
And then every Monday we had a Monday meeting
where we reviewed the progress on the top OKRs
and red, yellow, green and don't talk through
the green ones, only talk through the red ones
and what are the issues. And again, both there.
And then we had a weekly meeting with the four
of us where we would just go through any issues
in the organization, what's going on, what's not.
And the four of us is you,
the CTO, the chiefs of staff.
Yep. And sometimes we would invite
people. Like there's an issue with QA,
so we'd have the QA leader come in and
present to us. But we tried to limit the
number of meetings with teams. So it'd
be like the Monday meeting was the big
meeting that you had to be there and you had to
be able to talk to your project and that was it.
There's so much awesomeness here. I love the
idea of this Async share your plan in a video
instead of meetings with everyone in real time.
And you could just do a lot of the stuff Async.
We iterated every quarter, just like you
iterate on a product. So every quarter
we would say did the OKR planning work or
not, and then we would adjust. So we got to
the point where at one point we added up all
the hours of OKR reviews and all the people
in them and it was some insane number,
like 300 and something and we're like,
"This has gotten out of hand." So then we're
like, "We have to do something drastic."
And that's when we moved them to Async. It
was also right after Slack Clips launched.
Got it. That's the video feature. Very
cool. Then I know you launched huddles,
right? Slack Huddles? Did you
use that as a part of this or
eventually you just get people into a
little huddle asynchronously and talk-
Sometimes. Absolutely. We would be in the
reviews and we would huddle with somebody
to ask a quick question. We use Huddled
all the time. I still do. I love Huddles.
I love it. One crazy thing about Slack is
people in Slack don't actually use email
internally. It's like all in Slack. It's like
the actual vision of Slack working within Slack.
No email unless you're dealing
with somebody external. And no,
it's mostly Slack Connect anyway.
Anyway. Wow, that's amazing. Okay. I
have one more question around product
stuff and then I want to talk about AI. So
I was reading your newsletter on Substack,
which we'll link to and you share this really
interesting insight that I've experienced myself
that I'll quote you here. One of the mistakes that
I see a lot of product managers make is they over
index on people who are going to be unhappy with
the products they're launching. And basically your
advice is not to worry so much about making users
unhappy, which I think is counterintuitive to
some people. Can you just talk about this lesson
and I'd love to hear what product you launched
that made people unhappy that you realized, oh,
maybe we don't need to worry about this as much.
I saw it more when you unlaunch things, you take
things away there's always some set of users that
are using a feature that nobody else does, and
then you take it away and they're super unhappy,
but there are more people you're going to make
happy. So a product manager gets caught in this
trap of the vocal minority and the number
of people using your product ... Depends on
what phase. Are you a Google? Are you Slack? Are
you a Glean? But the number of people using your
product today is usually unless you're a Google
far smaller than the number of people who are
going to be using your product tomorrow. So
design it for the bigger number of people who
are going to be using it tomorrow. If you have
to redo the UI and the Who Moved My Cheese,
people will be unhappy, but all the new people are
going to be like, "This is so much easier." Then
do it and deal with the people who are unhappy.
But the trick is you have to be respectful and
you have to be transparent and you have to
explain. You have to go to people and say,
"This is why we made this change." And you have
to be authentic. You can't be dismissive and
you can't have marketing speak. You have to really
say, "Here's for real why." And you have to listen
to your audience. You don't want to alienate your
early users because most people ... If you made a
good decision on why you moved this or why we
stopped using Slack calls and moved to Huddles
and you have to do it over time and give people
choice and then give them enough time to move.
So you have to do it in the right way. But
if people feel heard, it makes a difference.
I have an example that's not a product example,
but I think is a really good one. It's a
leadership example. So when I was at Google,
there was always a controversy about something,
but there was a controversy about ... It was
Blogger or something. I can't even remember what
it was. It was like we made a change. We were like
50,000 people at the time. There was an engineer
in my team, an IT engineer that was super unhappy
about the change. And I knew Rachel Whetstone,
she was in charge of all of PR and global
policy at Google. So huge job. And I emailed
Rachel and I'm like, "Hey, do you have an
FAQ or something that can help me? Because
I don't know why you made this change and that
I can help explain to the engineer in my team."
She did not respond to my email. She picked up
the phone and she called him. I had no idea she
did this. She just called this IT engineer and
she listened to him and she heard why he was
upset and she explained her reasoning. He was so
blown away that she called him that he completely
changed his opinion and then he told everyone
else in the org. And so it had this effect.
And I learned a lot from watching her do that.
She never even told me she did it later. She
just did it. You just act. You're authentic.
You listen to people and you're transparent.
It's so funny. This reminds me of a parenting
book I'm reading right now that a former guest
recommended called Listen. And the core thesis
of the book is when your kids are acting up or
they're getting off track, so much of what they
need is a sense that you're connected to them,
a connection which is rooted in
you listening to them. And so all-
My favorite parenting book ... I don't know
if this is the same one or a different one,
it's How to Talk so Your Kids Will Listen & How
to Listen so Your Kids Will Talk. Maybe it's
the new name of that book, but it's so good and
it's so true in everything and also in products.
So whether you're in a forum and explaining to
customers, whether you're enterprise customers,
you're explaining, you're hearing
them out, people want to understand.
Amazing. There's so many applications of
just the power of listening. Okay. Well,
not quite a segue, but let's talk about
AI. You're at the epicenter of AI now
with Glean. How do you anticipate AI will
change our jobs and product? What do you
think people may be aren't recognizing
it, realizing it? What have you seen?
I'm going to give you a little bit of my history
with AI to get to that point. When AI was a
completely different technology stack ... I
have a master's in AI. So I started working
in AI when ... It's evolved so much. And then of
course at Google using it for auto complete and
search. It's transformed so many times. But then
with this last transformation of GenAI ... And
that's what brought me to Glean of seeing this,
meeting lots of AI companies and like, "Wow.
This is really going to transform how we work."
And it's just fascinating seeing these products.
I was one of those people like, "Oh yeah, it's
going to be so far away." Until I saw GPT3. And
I think AI, we are underestimating how much
it's going to change how we work. It's not
going to be sudden from today to tomorrow because
people haven't figured it out yet. They haven't
figured out how exactly to leverage it. But
the people who have are going to be so far
ahead. They're going to be far ahead of everyone
else because they're going to be working faster,
they're going to be working better.
And in five to 10 years, I think the
lines between product managers and engineers
and designers are going to blur because AI
will enable product managers to build
prototypes, to build designs. Designers
to build a pro like Figma already has their
Figma AI. You can press a button and you can
get your initial prototype working. You've
got all the co-pilots. So they're not quite
there. You still, like with Copilot or with
Cursor, you need to be an experienced engineer
to know when it's getting it wrong, but they're
going to keep getting better. I think people
have to be careful about not getting left
behind, but their jobs aren't going to go
away. They're just going to change. I'm of the
believer that we're just going to have a lot more
software. But I talked to engineers and to PMs
saying, "Yeah, I tried that. It doesn't really
work." And then go back to how I worked before.
And that's a dangerous spot to be in I think.
For people that get anxiety hearing this
where they're feeling they're going to be
left behind and like, "Oh my God, I don't know
enough time to do this or I don't know what I'm
doing here." Do you have any advice for what's
something someone can do to not fall behind?
Use the products. This is what good PMs should do
period. Always be using new products. It's not a
unique thing for AI. When mobile came out, PMs
needed to be using mobile apps all the time to try
them out, see what the UIs are, see what's working
and what isn't. And the same goes even more for
AI. Use ChatGPT. If your organization has Glean,
use Glean. Use Claude. Try them all. Try them and
see what they do. I was talking to a product
manager I know who is more forward-thinking
and loves playing with new products and he
had this use case that blew me away. So he
said ... And this was a couple of months ago, so
before ... It was right when Gemini had expanded
the context window. So his product had a Discord
channel and he took the transcript from the
Discord channel, which was huge. And he fed it
into Gemini the entire channel and then used it
to ask questions. Like what is the sentiment of
my product? What is the most requested feature?
What are the things people are unhappy with?
This never would've occurred to me. It's like,
that is so smart. And he's like, "It was like a
goldmine." Do you know how long it would've taken
him to read? And he just wouldn't have done it.
So think about for the argument, oh, I'm too
busy. Well, if you use these products it's going
to be a leverage on your time. So you get a lot
of articles sent to you, summarize them, use AI
to summarize the articles. We use Gong at Glean
to record all our sales calls. We have a Glean app
that will read all the Gong transcripts, put them
in a spreadsheet in a certain format of who the AE
is, etc. And then summarize all the top requested
features from all the Gong calls. And it took a
while to get it right. At first the summarization,
the prompt wasn't good enough and would give us
features that our salespeople would recommend
and didn't distinguish that this was actually the
customer. So you have to tweak it. It's not going
to work out of the box. But then we got it to the
point where it worked and these things really save
time and you have to use your creative juices as
a PM to figure out how it can help you and have
patience to iterate and keep trying because the
models that we have today can do a lot already.
Yeah. I love your example of the PM and what they
did with the Discord channel. Is there anything
else along those lines that either you've done
to leverage some AI tool to be more productive or
folks in your team have done to be more productive
youth, either your product leaders or other folks?
So many examples. So one that I did
really recently is I wrote a prompt
in Glean to help me get the status of
features. And we have a Launch Cal,
and you can look at Launch Cal it'll say a date.
But then is it really the date? What are the
outstanding issues? So it will look at our
Launch Cal and it will see if there are any
open year tickets, what the Slack conversations
are and the customers who are beta testing it,
bring all these together to tell me, okay,
launch date is this according to Launch Cal,
but here are all the open issues and here are the
open conversations that people are talking about.
So then it can give me the confidence level of
the future looking. So I can run the prompt,
just put in the name of the feature. So I
don't have to read all of these channels.
So this is a prompt that I built two weeks
ago because we're advancing our prompting
capabilities. And so I was testing it out and
I was like, "Ooh, I could do this." So that's
another example and engineers are using it for
automating part of the incident management of
I got an incident, how do I see were their
previous incidents that were similar to it,
where they're not. And so these are the type
of things you can look at to help you. But the
simplest, simplest is there's so much news.
Let me just paste in all of these things and
summarize them. As a product manager at Gleam,
here are all the latest news. What do I have to
care about? What's impacting me and potentially
competitive to any of the products that I have?
And putting that into say
Claude or ChatGPT you're saying.
Yeah.
Yeah. I think that beginning of the prompt
is something a lot of people don't know is
the power of just giving it a role like you are a
product manager at Gleam. From that perspective,
give me this summary versus just summarize this
and that ends up being really powerful right.
A hundred percent. And you can compare
what is Claude's PR saying that ... They
just launched Claude Enterprise. How is Claude
Enterprise different from OpenAI Enterprise?
Again, you can do it yourself, but these micro
improvements in your productivity help. For my
newsletter, I interviewed Claire Vo who came
out with ChatPRD. And so product managers
are using is. We're just starting to evaluate it
internally, so I haven't personally used it yet,
but it's super cool and you can use ChatGPT to do
a PRD. And ChatPRD, it's more templatized and more
frameworks of how to do that. And again,
these things are going to keep getting better.
Claire's been on the podcast,
she's going to be speaking at the Lenny
and Friends Summit coming up October 24th.
Oh, cool.
Yeah. A crazy stat she shared. She's making six
figures off this product that she
builds on the weekends ChatPRD.
So cool.
Incredible.
But it also shows what you can build with AI.
Right. It's just her. I think she just recently
hired some engineers to help because she has three
kids CTO at LaunchDarkly and just is building
this on the side making a hundred thousand plus
dollars. Incredible. I want to add a couple
of things here. So one is for folks looking
for ideas for how to use AI tooling for their
PM job. There's a couple of posts I've written
that I'll link to in the show notes just to put
that out there of just a bunch of PM sharing,
here's what I've done with these various
tools. Another thought I'd love to get your
take on. There's a lot of fear that the PM job
be replaced by AI. And I've recently realized
that it's the opposite. I think the PM role is
the best positioned to thrive in the world of
AI because if you just think about you have
a tool that can just build a thing for you,
just like you're staring at this blank
thing that can build anything for you,
which function would you think would have
the best chance of asking it of what to
build and how to articulate what to build best?
To me, it's clearly Product People. They're best
at figuring out what to build, what matters most,
where the impact's going to be what customers
need. Not to say other functions don't also have
the skills, but I feel like of all functions,
PMs have the most of that specific
skill. I'd love to get your take on that.
That. I think that AI, the one thing it's not
good at is being creative. So if you're a PM
who's doing the grout work, it's going to take
your job away. But if you're a PM who actually is
strategic and can pull the pieces together and be
creative and think how you do something that it's
going to differentiate. Because it's not going
to give you that leak. It'll say, here's what
customers are asking for, here are the problems
today, but you have to figure out how to solve
it. So in some ways it might weed out the good
from the bad PMs. Because there are a significant
number of PMs who are more just execution. And
I think that part of the job hopefully will be
lowered because I hope a lot more of the execution
will be able to automate updating Jira and all
these things that just take time and creating even
little Launch Cals, which PMs have to do manually
now. So hopefully a lot of that work goes
away and then people can be more creative.
And I think designers and PMs are going to blend
because the best designers I've worked with are
product thinkers and a lot of really good PMs can
also design. It depends on what kind of product
you're PMing for. So I agree with the caveat
that it will become harder to be a great PM.
Wait, say more about that. It'll be
harder to be a great PM because many PMs
are doing things that are mostly project
management and that's the stuff that-
Yeah. Let me rephrase. It's not going to
be harder to be a great PM, but to be a PM,
the not so good PMs jobs will go away.
The great PMs will still have great jobs.
Yeah. I totally hear you. So in a sense there
might be fewer. You might need fewer PMs,
but I think that applies in theory to every
function. Fewer engineers. Fewer designers.
I don't think you'll need fewer. I think you'll be
able to do more things. Think about every company.
Our head of sales came to me the other day, "You
need to hire more engineers because we just have
so many things we need to build." I'm like,
"When have you ever worked in a company where
you thought that you didn't need more engineers?"
You always want people to build more stuff. So I
don't think you're going to need fewer. I think
you're just going to get so much more done.
A lot of people are building AI into their
product. Glean is obviously an example which
integrates LLMs, which innately are
non-deterministic and hard to know if
they're going to provide anything good. Sometimes
something really dumb comes out. Do you have any
advice on working with these very complicated
systems that don't necessarily ... You can't
control and building them into your products?
Anything you've learned that might be helpful?
My first week at Glean was eye-opening in
learning some of these things. But let me
first just explain what Glean does for people who
may not know. So Glean was started as enterprise
search. Glean reads content of all your SaaS apps.
So it reads the content from Microsoft, Google,
Slack, Salesforce, Jira, like any SaaS tool that
you use, it indexes it and enables you to search.
So it started as just enterprise search and using
AI. So it was an AI search using BERT models and
using vector embeddings in 2019. Because the
early engineers at Glean came from Google and
Google created BERT to enhance search. And so it
was obvious that they would be using ML techniques
for search. Then GPT3 came along and added a
natural language interface, a chat interface.
You can ask the question in actual language and
get an answer, and it basically is a knowledge
graph of your organization. So you can ask any
question. Think of ChatGPT for your enterprise.
Ask any question about your enterprise.
So people understand search because they
understand Google and you put in a query and
then you refine it. But chat interfaces, people
still don't really know how to use.
If you look at the stats from ChatGPT,
from what I understand, the retention is
fairly low. People use it, they play with it,
and then they don't get back to it because it's
not in their workflow and they have a hard time
figuring out what they can and can't do for it.
When I got to Glean the first week I met with
the assistant quality team and one of the biggest
issues they have is people trying to use Glean for
things that there's no way it could know. Like
what should my top priority be next week when
we don't even know what your priorities are. But
then there's golden cases that are just amazing.
The example of refining queries and searched
years for people to understand how to do. And
it took a lot of features of auto complete and
refinements at the bottom of the page. So we need
to build in those things, guardrails to help
with the change. To help suggest, oh, Lenny,
here's what you could do. Here's a prompt to find
out the status of your feature that Tamar built.
So how do you give people guardrails so that
they understand what is going to work and what
isn't going to work? Because this whole, I don't
know what I can ask. And then on top of that, the
non-deterministic. An enterprise CIO will go use
ChatGPT on the weekends, but they come to work and
they expect their software to be deterministic.
So how do you help educate users about that?
And then the other thing I'll say about using
LLMs is the industry is transforming so rapidly
that you need to make sure that your product
gets better as the LLMs get better. And that
too many people are building things to make
up and compensate for the LLMs that all that
work is going to go away. So it's okay to do
it to understand that it's going to go away,
but that can't be your differentiator. You
have to understand that your differentiator
is something that will continue to be
there as the LLMs get better and smarter.
And as part of that, because
the LLMs get so much smarter,
everyone else will become awesome. And to keep
up, you need something that is actually outside
of the LLM that continues to differentiate you
and is better than what other people are doing.
Well, yeah. That your whole product
gets better as the LLMs get better.
That makes sense.
It's a frame of a of mind of how you
approach the value add you're having.
Awesome. Tamar, to close out our
conversation, is there anything
else that we did not cover that you think
is important to share or you think might be
helpful to leave listeners with before we
get to our very exciting lightning round?
I in my decades of working in tech, have never
been working in an environment that's moving
so quickly and it's really exciting. It's
super energizing and it's also scary. But
you have to change how you're working.
You have to change how you're working so
that you can keep up because it's going
to be an interesting decade ahead with
all these new tools that are coming
out. And staying ahead will be hard,
but it's also, there's so much I think richness
and opportunity here. So I advise people to get
in the thick of it and try it out because you'll
be surprised at how many products we can build.
I love that. I can't help but drill in
one level deeper. Is there anything you
found to help you stay ahead and help you
stay aware of what's happening? Are there
newsletters you find useful? Chat, podcasts
that just help you keep up to date on where
things are going? Is it like a person
you look to like, "Hey, what's new?"
There are definitely AI newsletters that I
look at. There's AI podcasts that I listen
to. I now have a commute, so in some ways
that's good because I get to keep up on the
AI podcasts. So I just try and listen. I'm
trying to build some prompts for myself to
make it easier to say ... Take in ... I haven't
perfected this, but the ChatGPT voice mode where
you can load it. Somebody who I just hired it
at Glean was saying he does this. He loads up
stuff before his commute and then he'll be like
summarize these articles and then he can ask
questions to it. So I need to up my game there.
But I definitely have a list of Ben's Bites and
The Neuron. Those are good summaries and I
like Gil and Sarah Guo's podcast. I listen
to Cognitive Revolution. There's too many
of them right now, but I pick and choose.
Awesome. Okay. We'll link to those ones you just
mentioned in the show notes. We'll have Gil and
Sarah Guo's podcast, it's called No Priors. I
was actually just listening to it on the way
here. Sarah is going to also be at Lenny's and
Friends Summit. She's going to be moderating a
panel between Kevin Weil and Mikey Krieger who are
the CPOs of Anthropic and Open AI. So there we go.
Another quick plug for lennyandfriendssummit.com.
I think it's lennyssummit.com.
Awesome.
With that Tamar we've reached our very
exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
I am ready.
Okay, let's do this. First question,
what are two or three books that you
have recommended most to other people?
So one book was recommended to me by Shashir,
the CEO of Cota. When I started at Slack,
he recommended the book Switch: How to Change
Things When Change Is Hard by Chip and Dan Heath.
And it's such a good book. And it's about how
do you set a path for people to follow. It's the
whole elephant and the rider. So setting the path
but yet motivating people to go down the path. And
I read it. We had an all hands about ... I don't
even remember the topic. It was something that
we were like all up in arms about that we had to
do. And I had just read the book and after the all
hands I went up to store it and I'm like, "You
did that all wrong. You need to read this book.
That is not how to get people motivated." And
he read the book and he's like, "You're right."
So it just changes how you think in organizations
to affect change. So that's on the organizational
leadership. And one book I really liked was a Team
of Rivals. It's a book about Lincoln and putting
together his cabinet during the Civil War. One,
I just learned a lot about the Civil War that I
didn't really know. And it's about, again, a
book about leadership and it is fascinating.
I don't think anyone's recommended
either of these. So love them.
Next question, do you have a favorite
recent movie or TV show you really enjoyed?
I don't know if you like British murder mysteries.
I don't know either.
It's a niche thing, but there's a guy named
Anthony Horowitz and the latest series he
did was called Magpie Murders. And it's
just an intricate story so I enjoyed it.
Very niche but amazing. Do
you have a favorite product
you've recently discovered that you really like?
Well, I'm going to give two. One is tech and one
is non-tech. So non-tech I
really like dark chocolate.
Actually just like a dark chocolate bar.
A really good dark chocolate that's
simple. Like no frills, none of this.
Just dark chocolate. And I discovered this
chocolate called Bisou chocolate. It's a
guy in Oakland who makes it himself. Super
niche. He was selling at the farmer's market.
And it's just like if you want like a
simple play, no nuts, no anything just-
No sea salt.
Great pride in the beans he resources them from.
Wow. It's called Bisou with a B?
Yeah. Bisou as in Kiss in French. And then on
the tech side, the honest answer is Glean. I
was listening to your podcast with Nikita who said
that people over 22 don't use new products except
at work. And that stuck with me. The new products
I usually use are at work and I use Glean 10,
15 times a day. I use it so much and it changed
the way I onboarded. It changed the way I work.
Even the simplest questions, you don't bother
people, you don't interrupt people on Slack.
You're like, "What's the latest status with this
deal? What's the last time we talked to them?"
I meet somebody at a conference and I can quickly
say, "Have we ever talked to this company before?"
And I can just get an answer.
Or without asking an engineer,
"Where's the latest design doc?" It has
really transformed how I work. So I know
it's cheating in that it's the product I
work on, but it's the actual honest answer.
And for folks that haven't heard of Glean,
it's one of the most successful B2B AI
companies out there. It's like a very
large successful business and company
that if you haven't checked it out,
you should definitely check it out.
As our investors say, it's one of the AI
companies that's actually making money.
Very few of those. Awesome. Two more questions.
Do you have a favorite life motto that you often
come back to, repeat yourself, share with
friends or family and work or in life?
I have one that my father told me when I was
being really indecisive about what college to
go to. He was really bored of the conversation and
he said, "There are no right decisions. You make
a decision right." And it is so true. Because
you never know what's going to happen in life.
You just have to commit to whatever you're doing
and have no regrets about it. You can't be like,
"Oh," 10 years later, "what if I had
taken that job over there?" It's like
you make your success based on how you
approach the decisions that you've made.
So if you feel regret about something,
this is a good one to pull out of just
I will make this the best I can make
it, and that's all the best I can do.
You can move forward.
Move forward. I love that. Last question,
I know you're a parent. I'm a new parent.
I have a 14-month old at this point.
Is there a piece of parenting advice
that you learned early on that you think
might be helpful to me or folks that are
new parents or something you've just learned
yourself that you think might be helpful?
14 months. I think the best parenting book
I read besides the How to Talk So Your
Kids Will Listen & How to Listen so Your Kid Will
Talk is, I think it's called Healthy Sleep Habits,
Happy Baby. We are much happier when we sleep
well. We perform better at work when we sleep
well. Children need to sleep. So making sure
that they sleep well. And sometimes that's like,
I did the whole sleep training, cry until you
fall asleep and my kids still speak to me. So
it was okay. That is the basic things. Make
sure that their basic needs are met and then
as they grow up, share your life with them.
So a piece of advice I was given was analogous
to Talk so your Kids Will Listen is when they
had come home from school. You can't just say,
"How was your day?" Say, "You know what? I
did a podcast with this person and it was
super interesting because they talked about this
or that." Or, "I'm massively screwed up and I
should have asked them this or that." And they'll
be like, "Oh my God, I was at school today and
this is what happened." If you share your life
with them, they will share their life with you.
Such good advice. I really appreciate it.
Tamar, thank you so much for being here.
You're awesome. We got through so much great
stuff. Everything I was hoping we get through.
Two final questions. Where can folks find
you if they want to read up on more stuff
that you share and just follow you online
and how can listeners be useful to you?
Find me on LinkedIn and I have a subject
called Practical Intelligence where I've
been interviewing practitioners who are working
with AI. It was my way of learning. I started
when I was a VC. Trying to continue doing
it. And how can I be helpful if you are a
customer of Glean, I'd love to know what
you think, what works and what does more.
What's the best way to share that with you? Is it
like messaging on LinkedIn, subscribe to Substack?
Message on LinkedIn, or comment on your-
On [inaudible 01:16:50]. Yeah.
Yeah. Those would probably be the two ways.
Awesome. Tamar, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you for having me.
Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.