all right hello everyone okay okay Sarah you're the queen of AI investing this is a phrase never ever to be used again but it's
great to be here with both of you um so I had two different ideas for our final discussion the first was a product off
because these two men have the merge to to prod button both of them and I was like oh please just release everything we know is coming over the next six or 12 months ignore all internal guidelines
um the second was we just redesigned Instagram together since they've both actually run Instagram before uh both of these got fully shot down and so instead I think we'll just
like trade notes among friends like lame I know but uh but really excited to hear from you both anyway uh so this is actually a relatively new role for both
of you Kevin let's start with you like you've done a bunch of really different interesting things like what was the reaction you got when you took the job from friends and the
team uh generally excitement I mean uh it's I think it's one of the most interesting and impactful roles there's so much to figure out um I've never had
such a challenging interesting uh Sleepless product role in my life uh it's it's got all the challenges of a normal product role
where you're trying to figure out who you're building for and what problems you can solve and things like that but normally when you're Building Product You're Building off of kind of a fixed technology base right you know what you
have to work with and uh and you're trying to build the best product you can here it's like every two months computers can do something computers have never been able to do before in the
history of the world and you're trying to figure out how that changes your product and the answer should probably be a fair amount um and so it just it's so
interesting uh and fascinating to see on the inside as AI gets developed but uh I've been having a blast Mike what about you I I remember hearing the news I was like oh I didn't know you could convince the founder of
Instagram to go work on something that existed already yeah my favorite three reactions like people who know me were like that makes sense like you're going to like have fun there uh the middle people were like why like you don't have
to work like why are you doing this and like then if you knew me you know me like I can't not and I think that like I couldn't stop myself and the third was like oh you could hire the founder of Instagram which was also fun and it's like I mean not many people could but
like there's like probably a list of three companies that would have been interesting um and so yeah there's like a range of reactions depending on how well you knew me and how like you've seen me in my like uh semi-retired state
which lasted like six weeks and I was like all right what are we doing next um so we had dinner together with a bunch of friends recently and you I was
like impressed by the childish Delight that you had around like yeah I'm learning about all this Enterprise stuff like tell me if it's about serving customers that are not all of us with
Instagram or uh just you know working in a a an organization that's research driven like what's the biggest surprise so far I those are two I think both very worthwhile pieces of this role that are
like very new to me as well like I um when I was 18 I made this like very 18-year-old vow which was like every year of my life I wanted to be different like I don't have the same year twice and I was like it's why like you know I didn't there's been times where I was
like oh like another social product I'm like doing that again first of all like your bar is like really distorted and second of all like just would feel like too much of the same thing so yeah Enterprise has been wild I'm really curious about your experience with that
as well like you're like you know uh your your feedback GL I actually imagine it's a lot more like investing is far longer right you're like you have that initial convo and you're like I think they like me and then you're like oh no
it's now in like some requisition State and it's going to take like six months before they like even get to deployment before you know whether it's right and so like getting used to that pace we're like what why hasn't this shipped yet they're like Mike you've been here two
months like this is like it's making its way through the VPS like it's going to get there eventually so like getting used to different timelines for sure but like the part that is fun is actually getting the feedback in the kind of Engagement where you're like once it
gets the deployed you have somebody that can call you and you can call them and be like how's it working for you like is this good like whereas users like you're doing like data science and Aggregate and like sure you can bring in like one or two people but it's like they won't
they don't have enough financial incentive writing on telling you where you suck and where you're doing well and like that's been a different but also like rewarding side of that for sure ke Kevin you've worked on such a wide range
of products before how much do your instincts like apply yeah I was going to add on to the Enterprise Point too um and then I'll get to like the other interesting thing about Enterprise is it's not necessarily about the product
right there's a buyer and they have goals and you could build the best product in the world that all the people at the company might be happy to use and it still doesn't necessarily matter
exactly um I was in a a meeting with one of our big Enterprise customers and they were like um this is great we're really happy da D you know the one thing we
need is we really need you to tell us 60 days before you launch anything and I was like I also would like to know 60 days
so very very different actually and it's interesting right because at open AI we have a consumer product and we have an Enterprise product and we have a developer product so we're kind of doing
all at once um Instinct wise in I'd say in like half the job it works you know when you have when you
have a sense of the product you're trying to build you know we're getting towards uh you know the end of shipping uh Advanced speech mode or something or you're getting towards shipping canvas
and you're making final touches trying to understand who you're building for and like what you know exactly what problems you're trying to solve it it works then because it's that's a little bit more like the tail end of it is
shipping a normal product but the beginning of these things is nothing like that um so uh
like there will just be these capabilities that we don't know you you have some sense as you're training some new model that it might
have capability X you don't really know nor does the research team nor does anybody right you're like I think this might be possible and it's kind of like coming through the M statue but it's
this emergent property of a model and you know so you don't know whether it's going to really work and you don't know whether it's going to be like 60% good
or 90% good or 99% good and the product that you would build that would make sense with something that works 60% of the time is Super different than 90 or
99% of the time right so you're kind of just waiting and you're you know at least like I don't know if you feel this checking in with the research team from time to time like hey guys how's it
going how's that model training uh any any insight on this and they're like it's research we're working on it you know it's uh we don't know either we're we're we're we're working through this
at the same time and it's I mean it makes it super fun because you're kind of like discovering things together but very sort of stochastic too it's the thing it most reminds me of like from
the Instagram days where like apple like wwc announcements you're like this could either be awesome for us or could like absolutely like cause chaos for it it's like that but your own company is the one kind of disrupting you from within
which is like a very like it's very cool but also like oh this might totally in my product road map now yeah uh what does that cycle look like
for both of you you described it as um you know like peering through the Mist trying to look at the next set of capabilities I mean can you can you plan if you don't know exactly what is coming
and what is the iteration cycle to discover new things that should belong in your product I think like on the intelligence side you can sort of squint and see like all right it's advancing this way and so the kinds of things that
you'll want to do with the model and start building the product around that so I I there's three ways right intelligence feels not predictable but at least on like a slope that you can kind of watch there's the capabilities
you decide to invest in from the product side and then do fine-tuning with the actual research teams um so something like artifacts we spend a lot of time between research I think the same was true with campus right like you're doing
a like co-design co- research co- finetune and that's like I think a real privilege of getting to work at this company and getting to do design there and then there's the capability front so maybe speech mode for open a for us it's
the computer use uh work that we we released this week you're like all right 60% all right got good yes all right yeah and like so what we try to do is embed designers early in the process but
knowing that like you're not placing a b like the the experimentation talk was saying like your um your output for experiment should be learning not necessarily like perfect products you're going to ship every time I think the same is true when you partner with
research like your outcome is hopefully demos or informative things that like could spark product ideas not like a predictable product process where you're like well it's this der risked by now which means it's going to look that way
when research comes along I've also one thing that I've really enjoyed because research is at least parts parts of research are very product oriented especially on the post-training side like Mike was saying and then parts of
it are really like academic research at some level and so you we'll just also occasionally hear about some capability and we'll be in a meeting and you'll be like oh I really wish we could do this
thing and a researcher on the team will be like oh no we can do that we've had that for three months and we're like really what does that like okay where do I learn more and they're like oh well we
didn't think we didn't we didn't know it was important so you know I'm working on this other thing now um but you do just get like magic happening sometimes
too uh one thing like we think a lot about when we're investing is actually like can you do anything with a model if it is 60% successful at a task instead
of 99% and unlike lots of tasks that's closer to 60 right but the task is really important valuable like how do you how do you think about that internally in terms of evaluating
progression on a task and then what what types of things you like put in sort of the burden of product to make it graceful failure or to like sort of
cross the miles the user versus you know we just need to wait for the models to get better I'd argue there are a lot of things that you can actually do when something is 60% right you just you just
need to really design for it um you have to expect that there's a human in the loop a lot more than there would be otherwise like if you look at uh take like GitHub co-pilot right that was kind
of the first AI product that really open people's eyes to like this thing can be useful not just as you know Q&A but for really economically valuable work and
that launched I don't know exactly which model that was built off of but I mean it was multiple Generations ago so I guarantee you that model wasn't perfect at anything related to coding I think
it's gpt2 which is like pretty small so yeah I mean and so but the fact that it was still valuable for you cuz if it got the code you know some significant fraction of the way there that was still
stuff you didn't have to type yourself and you could edit it and so there are experiences like that that I think totally work I think we'll see the same kinds of things happening with um with
sort of the the shift towards uh agents and longer form tasks where you know it may not be perfect but if it can save you five or 10 minutes that's still
valuable and even more if the model can understand where it doesn't have confidence and can come back to you and say I'm not sure about this can you actually help me with this then you know the the combination of human and model
together can be much higher than 60% I also find that 60% this magic 60% number like it's kind of lump I made it up five minutes ago that was a takeway 6% that
is our new that's the Mendoza Line of uh of AI like I think it's often very lumpy where like it'll do very well on some tasks and not well on others and I think that also helps like uh when we ever run
like pilot programs with customers is really interesting when we'll get like the same day feedback from two different companies when be like it's solved our whole problem like we've been trying to do this for three months thank you other be like it was way off it's like worse
than the other model and so like uh it's also humbling to know that you have your own internal evals but like the rubber hitting the road and actually seeing the model out in the world is where it's kind of the equipment of like you do all
this design and then like you put it in front of one user and you're like oh wow I was wrong uh the model has that feeling as well we like we try as hard as we can to like have a good sense but then people have their own custom data
sets they have their own internal use they've prompted it a certain way and like uh so that delies that sort of almost like bodal nature of when you actually put it out in the world I'm curious if you feel
this I think there's a very real sense in which models today are not intelligence limited they're eval limited yeah they can actually do much more and be much more correct on a wider
range of things than they are today and it's really about sort of teaching them they have the intelligence you need to teach them certain specific topics that you know maybe weren't in their original training set but they can do it if you
do it right yeah we've seen that all the time where like um uh there was a lot of like exciting AI deployments that happened in like you know maybe three years ago and now they're like we think the new models are better but we never
did evals because all we were doing was just shipping cool AI features three years ago and like the hardest hump to get people over is like let's step back and like what does success actually look like for you like what problem are you solving like often the pm has rotated so
it's like somebody's inherited it and then be like all right what does that look like all right let's some evaluations what we've learned is like Claud is actually good at writing evaluations and also grading them so like we can automate a lot of this for
you but you have to tell us what success looks like and then let's go and actually iteratively improve our way over there and like that is often like the difference between like 60% of a task and like 85% of task if you come
interview at anthropic which maybe you should uh at some point maybe you're happy in your R maybe not um uh you'll see one of the things we do in our interview process actually like make you get uh a prompt from like crappy eval to
good and like just we want to see you think but like not enough of that Talent exists elsewhere so we're trying to get that like if there's one thing we can teach people that's probably the most important thing writing eals I mean it's
I actually think it's going to become a core skill for PMS we actually had this and maybe this is like a little inside baseball but I thought this was interesting like internally we had our research PMS who like work a lot on
model capabilities and model development and then we had our like more like product surface PMS or API PMs and we ended up realizing that like the job of a PM in 2024 202 5 building AI powered
features looks is looking more and more like the former than the latter in a lot of cases like uh we launched uh like our uh code analysis and like basically Claud can analyze csvs and write code
for you now and the PM there was like getting it 80% of the way there and then having to hand it over to the PM that could write the evals then go to like fine tune and like prompt I was like that's actually the same role like the quality of your feature is now gated on
how well you have done the evals and the prompts and so like that PM like definition is definitely just mer now yeah absolutely I we we set up a boot
camp and like took every PM through uh writing evals and like what it was like difference between good and bad evals and you know we're we're definitely not done there we've got to keep iterating
and getting better on it but it is such a critical part of of making a good product with AI yeah as part of this recruiting call for any of the people who want to be good at building AI
product or research product in the future um we can't come to your boot camp Kevin so how do we develop some intuition for getting good at this eval
and iteration L I actually think it's something you can you can use the models themselves for like you were talking about you can ask the models at this point what makes a good eval give me you know I want to do this can you write me
a sample eval and it will it will be pretty good yeah I think that's like that goes a log way I think there's also this question of like it's and I if you listen to like everybody from like Andre
carpath to others who have like spent a lot of time in the field like nothing beats looking at at data and so like people often get caught up um being like well we already have these evaluations and the new model is like 80% there
rather than 78% we can't [ __ ] or like you know it's worse and I was like have we looked at the cases where it fails and you're like oh actually this was better it's just our grader is not as good you know or um it's funny like again a little inside baseball you know
like every model release has the model card and some of these model uh these eiles we've seen like even the golden answer I'm like I'm not sure a human would say it or like I think that math is actually a little wrong like getting
100% is going to be really hard cuz even just grading them is very challenging so like I'd encourage you to like the way you build the intuition is go look at the actual answers even to sample them be like all right yeah maybe we should
evolve The evals or maybe like The Vibes are good even if the eval is like tied so like getting real and getting like deep on the data I think matters I also think it'll be really interesting to see
how this evolves as we go towards longer form more agentic tasks because it's one thing when your evals are like I gave you this math thing and you were able to like add four-digit numbers and get to
the right answer you know it's easy to know what what good looks like there as the models start to do more uh long form more ambiguous things go get me a hotel
in New York City you know what's what's right there a lot of it will be about personalization uh you know if you ask any two humans who are perfectly competent they're going to do two
different things so your grading becomes much softer and it you know it'll just be interesting we I think we'll have to to evolve yet again like speaking of having to reinvent stuff over and over again I think a lot like when you think
about and I think both Labs have some concept of like this is what capabilities look like as things evolve like it looks a little bit like a career ladder like what bigger and longer Horizon tasks are you taking and maybe like eval start looking more like
performance review I'm in performance review season so this is the metaphor that's in my head sorry but it's like you know like did the model like meet your expectation of like what a competent human have done did it exceed it because it did it twice as fast or
like discovered some restaurant you wouldn't have known it greatly exceed meets most like it starts being like more nuanced than just like right or wrong let alone you have humans riding these eval and the models are getting to
the point where they can often beat humans at certain tasks like people prefer the model's answers to a human's answers and so if your humans writing your evals like yeah you know so what does that
mean uh what okay evals are clearly the key um we're going to go spend a bunch of time with these models teaching ourselves to write EV vals what are their skills should product people be
learning now you you're both on that learning path I think uh prototyping with these models is a thing that is underused like our best PMS do this where we'll get into some long
conversation about like should the UI be this or that and before our designers have even like picked up their figma like our our often our PMS or sometimes our Engineers will be like great I
prompted Claude I did like an AB comparison of what these two UI could look like let's try them and I'm like oh this is really cool I'm like play that out and like we'll be able to Pro protype much like a far greater variety
and evaluate um like on a much faster scale than before so like that skill of like using these tools to actually be in prototyping mode I think is a really
really useful one that's a good one I would also I you you sort of said this but I think it's also going to push PMS to go deeper into the tech stack yeah um
because it's and maybe that changes over the years like that if you were doing like database Tech in I don't know 2005 maybe it required you to be able to go really deep in a different way than it
would if you were doing database Tech now like layers of abstraction get built and you maybe don't need to know all the fundamentals but it's not like every PM needs to be a researcher by any means
but I think having an appreciation for it spending time and learning the language and gaining intuition for how this stuff works a little bit I think will go a long way I think the other piece like you're dealing with this like
stochastic non-deterministic system which like eals are our best attempt to do it but like product design in a world where like you're not in control of what the model is going to say you can try
and so like what are the feedback mechanisms that you need to close that Loop like how do you decide when like the model's gone astray how do you collect that feedback in a in a rapid way you know like what are the guard rails you want to put in like how do you
even know what it's doing in aggregate like it's a much more like you're understanding like the output of this intelligence across a lot of outputs over a lot of people every single day it
just requires a very different set that like oh the bug report is you clicked on the button and didn't follow the user it's like that's a pretty knowable kind of problem right and and maybe this will change you know 5 years from now when
people are used to it but I think we're all still in the mode of adapting to this sort of non-deterministic user interface ourselves uh and certainly people who are not you know tech people here in
this room working on Tech products who are using AI are are definitely not used to it like it goes against all of the intuition that we've built up for the last like 25 years of using
computers uh and so like the idea that you're going to put in the exact same things normally if you put in the exact same inputs computers give you the exact same outputs and that is no longer true
uh and it it it's not just that we have to adapt to it Building Products we have to also put oursel in the shoes of the people who are using our products and think about what this means for them and there's like I mean there are downsides
to it there also really cool upsides and so it's fun to kind of think about how how you can use that to your advantage in different ways I remember like we we did like a lot of like rolling user
research at Instagram so we have like the same like or researchers would bring in different people every single week whatever it was like prototype ready would get put through it and we do the same thing at anthropic but what's interesting is like for those sessions
what would often surprise me is like how users were using Instagram there's something interesting about like their use case or like their reaction to a new feature and like now it's like half that and half what the model did in that situation you're like oh it did the
right thing this is great so there's like this like very like almost like a sense of Pride maybe of like when it reacts well and you're like in a user research environment and then like also the like frustration you're like oh no
you misunderstood the intent and now you're like 10 pages down into this answer and so like it it's also like maybe a little of getting Zen about like letting go of control and you know what's going to happen in those
environments yeah you have both worked on these consumer experiences that taught new behaviors to you know many hundreds of millions of people uh
quickly uh these AI products are happening actually faster than that right and you know if if PMs and Technical people don't have that much intuition naturally for how to use them
how do you think about educating end users at the scale you're both working with on something that is so unintuitive I mean it it is kind of amazing how fast we all
adapt uh I was talking to somebody the other day and they were telling me about their first wayo ride who's ridden in a whmo who rode one here yeah if you haven't ridden in a whmo you're in San
Francisco ride AO to wherever you're going when you leave here it's a magical experience but they were like my first 30 seconds I was like oh my God watch out for that
bicyclist right and then 5 minutes in it was like oh my God I'm living in the future and then 10 minutes later it was like board scrolling on your phone like
you know how quickly we become used to something that is just absolute magic yeah um and I think I mean cha PT is less than 2 years old MH and it was
absolutely mind-blowing when it exist or when it when it first came and now I think if we had to go back and use the original whatever it was GPT 3.5 I think the horror yeah yeah like no everybody
be like GH so dumb how could I Poss you know and and you know the stuff that's that's happening today that we're working on that you guys are working on it all feels like magic 12 months from
now we're going to be like can you can you believe if we use that garbage because it's going to I me that's how fast this thing is moving but it's also amazing to me how quickly people adapt because I mean as much as we try and
bring people along like there are also um there's just there's a lot of excitement people understand that this is like the world is moving in this direction and um we've got to try and
make it the best possible move that we can but uh it's it's happening and it's happening fast one thing we're trying to get better at and that's is also letting the product be like educational in a
very little away which is like a thing we did not do early and now we're changing is just tell Claude more about itself which was like you know it's in its training set that it's you know uh artificial intelligence created by
anthropic whatever but now we're literally like and here's how you use this fature we Shi because people would ask and again this came from user research because we'd be like they would be like how do I use this thing and then Cloud would be like I don't know have you tried like looking at it on the
internet you're like no that's un helpful and So like um uh like we're really trying to ground it and then at launch time we're like you know it's a process were improving but like it's it's cool to now see like this is the exact link to the documentation like
here's how you do it like I can help you stuff by St oh you're stuck I can help you here so uh these things are actually very good at solving uh UI problems and like user confusion and like we should
use them more for that yeah that's got to be different when you are um you know trying to do like change management in an Enterprise though right because there's a there's a status quo for how are you doing things there's
organizational process like how do you think about educating entire organizations about productivity improvements or whatever else can come I think the Enterprise one is really interesting because like even like these
products have like millions and millions of users but like the power users are very much I think still like early adopters people who like technology and then there's like a you know long tail whereas when you go into Enterprise you're deploying to like an organization
that is like often there's folks who are like not very non-technical and like I think that's really cool actually seeing fairly non-technical users get exposed to like a chat powered llm for the first
time and then getting to see it then you have the luxury of like getting to run like a session where you teach them about it and like have educational materials um and so I think we need to learn from what happens in those and
then say like that's what we need to do to teach the next 100 million people how to use these these these uis and they're usually power users internally and they're they're excited to teach the
rest of people and you know like with open AI we have these custom gpts that you can make and organizations make thousands of them often and it's a way for the power users to make something
that makes AI easier and like immediately valuable for the people that might not know how to use it otherwise um so like that's one cool thing you find the pockets of power users and they
actually will sort of be evangelists I I have to ask you then because you you know your organizations are both like all power users right so you know you're living in your little
pocket of the future uh I'll ask about one thing but feel free to redirect Mike how am I supposed to use computer use this is amazing like what are you guys doing yeah well internally like we're I mean
this to Kevin's earlier comment around like when is it going to be ready all right like go this like it was pretty late breaking like we like had conviction that it was like this is like good and like we want to put this down
like it's early still and it's like still going to make mistakes but like how do we do this as well the funniest use case like while we were beta testing it was like somebody was like I wonder if I can get it to order us a pizza and like it did and they're like great there's do like the the moment where
Domino's shows up at your office and it was ordered entirely by AI is like a very was a very cool like seminal moment and then we're like oh but it's Domino's but like you know like but like it was definitely like amazing yeah uh but it
was AI you know so it was all it was it was it was good it also like ordered quite a bit of pizza so it was like maybe hungrier than intended uh some early things that we're seeing that we think are really interesting one is UI testing which is like I was like at
Instagram we had basically no UI tests because they're hard to write they're like they're brittle um and they're like often like a little bit like oh like we moved this button around and like it should still pass that was the point of the PR but like now it's going to fail we're going to have to like do this
whole other snapshot um and like early signs are like computer just works really well for like hey does it work as intended does it do the thing that you want it to do and I think that's like been been very very interesting and then what we're starting getting into too is
like what are the agentic things that just like involve a lot of like data manipulation so we're looking at it with our support teams and our finance teams around like those PR forms are going to fill themselves but like it's very
repetitive you of have data in one Silo you want to put it in a different Silo and it just requires like human time like I keep using the word drudgery when I talk about computer like can we automate the drudgery so you can focus
on the creative stuff and not like the you know 30 clicks to do one single thing Uh Kevin I I think we have a lot of teams that are um experimenting with
o1 you can obviously do much more sophisticated things you also can't use it as a one forone replacement if you're already using right one of the you know gbd 40 models or whatever in uh in your
application like can you give us some guidance what are you guys doing with it internally so I think one thing that people maybe don't realize that actually a lot of the most sophisticated
customers of ours are doing and that we're certainly doing internally is it's not really about one model for any particular thing you end up putting together sort of workflows and
orchestration between models and so you use them for what they're good at 0 one's really good at reasoning but it also takes a little bit of time to think and it's not multimodal and you know has other limitations you Define reasoning
for the group I realize it's a basic question but yeah so uh we people are I think pretty used to the concept the like scaling pre-training concept you go
gpt2 3 four five whatever and you're doing bigger and bigger runs on pre-training these models are getting you know smarter and smarter um like they or rather maybe they know more and
more but they're kind of like system one thinking right it's it's you ask it a question you immediately get an answer it's like text completion yeah sort of if I ask you me asking you questions
right now and you just have to stream one Tok at a time keep going don't think it's amazing actually how much human like your intuition about how other humans work will often like help you in
intuiting about how these models work um you know you asked me a question I got off onto the wrong like sentence it's hard to recover the models totally do
the same thing um but uh so you've got that that sort of larger and larger pre-training 01 is actually a different
way of scaling intelligence by doing it at uh at query time basically so instead of system one thinking I ask you a question and immediately tries to give you an answer
it'll pause same thing I would you know you would do if I asked you a question I said solve this Sudoku do this New York Times connections puzzle you you would start going okay these words how do they group together okay these might be these
four well no I'm not sure could be you know you're you're like forming hypotheses using what you know to refute these hypothesis or affirm them and then
from that continuing to reason on it's how it's How scientific breakthroughs are made it's how we answer hard questions um and so this is about teaching the models to do it and right
now you know they'll think for 30 or 60 seconds before they answer imagine what happens if they can think for five hours or five days um so it's basically a new
way to scale intelligence and we feel like we're just at the very beginning you know we're at the like gpt1 phase of um of this new form of reasoning um but
in the same way it's not you don't use it for everything right there are sometimes when you ask me a question you don't want me to wait 60 seconds you I should just give you an answer um so we end up using our models in a bunch of
different ways together so for example like cyber security you would think not really a use case for models they can hallucinate that seems like a bad place
to hallucinate but you can a like find tune a model to be good at certain Tas asks and then you can fine-tune models to be very precise about the kinds of
inputs and outputs that they expect and have these models start working in in concert together and you know models that are checking the outputs of other models realizing when something doesn't
make sense asking it to try again um and uh so like that ends up being how we get a ton of value out of our own models
internally it's like specific use cases uh and or orchestrations of models together designed sort of working in concert to do specific tasks which again
going back to like reasoning about how we work as humans how do we do complex things as humans you have different people who often have different skill sets and they work together to accomplish a hard
task I can't let you guys get away without without telling us something about the future and what's coming and so um you don't have to give us release
dates I understand you don't know but uh if you if you look out I I think the furthest anyone can look out in AI right now is like well tell me if you can see the future but like let's say like 6 months 12 months like what's an
experience that you imagine is going to be possible or prevalent I think a lot about um like to Breaking the well I think a lot about this all the time but
like the um two maybe two words to be like plant seeds in in everybody's mind like one is proactivity like how do the models become more proactive like once they know about you and they're monitoring like they're reading your
email in a good not creepy way and they're like uh because you authorized them to and then they like you know spot an interesting Trend or you start your day with something that's a like um like
a proactive like uh recap of what's going on some conversations you're going to have I I I prid some research for you hey your next meeting is coming up like here's what you might want to talk about I saw you have this like presentation coming up here's the first draft that I
put together like that kind of proactivity I think is going to be really really powerful and then the other part is being more asynchronous so like uh I think o1 is like early UI in this exploration which is like it's
going to do a lot and it's going to tell you kind of what it's going to do along the way and like you can sit there and wait for it but you could also like be like it's going to think for a while I'm going to go like do something else maybe tab back maybe it like can tell me when
it's done like yeah I expanding the time Horizon both in terms of like you didn't ask a question it just told you something I think that's going to be interesting and then you did ask a question and you're going to be like great like I'm going to go reason about
it I'm going to go research it I might have to ask another human about it like and then I'm going to like maybe come up with my first answer I'm going to vet that answer you'll hear back from me in like an hour like Breaking Free of those
like uh constraints of like expecting an answer immediately I think will let you do things like hey I have this like whole like mini project plan like go flesh it out or like not just like I want you to like change this one thing
on the screen but like fix this bug for me like take my PRD and like adapt it for these new market conditions like adapt it for these three different marketing conditions that emerg like being able to push those Dimensions I
think is what I'm personally most excited about on the product side yeah I completely agree with all of that that um and it's the models are going to get smarter at an accelerating rate I think
which is also part of how all of that uh comes to pass another thing that will be really exciting is seeing the models able to interact in all the same ways that we as humans interact you know
right now you mostly type to these things and you know I mostly type to a lot of my friends on WhatsApp and other things but I also speak I also can see
and uh we just we launched this advanced voice mode Rel relatively recently I was in uh I was in Korea and Japan having
conversations and I would just I would often be with somebody with whom I had no common language whatsoever before this we could not have said a word to each other and instead I was like Hey
chat gbt I want you to act as a translator when I say something in English I want you to say it in Korean and when you hear something in Korean say it back to me in English and all of a sudden I had this Universal translator
and I was having business conversations with another person uh and it was magical and you think what that can do like not just in a business context but think about people's willingness to
travel to new places if you don't ever have to be worried about not speaking the language and you've got this like Star Trek Universal translator in your pocket you know and so experiences like that I think it's going to become
commonplace fast but it's magical and I'm excited about that in combination with all the stuff Mike was just saying oh one of my favorite pastimes
now just you know since uh voice mode release is actually watching there's a genre of Tik Tok of well this just speaks to how old I am like there's a genre of Tik Tok where you just like uh
it's just young people talking to voice mode like pouring their heart out using it all these ways where I'm like oh my God like there's this old term being like digitally native or mobile native
and I'm like I like pretty strongly believe in this AI thing and I would not think to interact in this way but people who are 14 years old are like well I expect the AI to be able to do that and
I love that have you ever given it to your kids uh I haven't yet my kids are like five and seven Kevin knows them so we but we'll get there I mean mine are eight and 10 but like on a car ride
they'll be like can I talk to chat GPT yes and they will ask it the most bizarre things they will just have weirdo conversations with it but they're perfectly happy talking to an AI yeah
actually one of my favorite experiences and maybe we'll close and ask you for like the most surprising Behavior kids or not is uh um like when my parents
read to me like I got L I was lucky if I got to choose the book and it wasn't my dad being like we're going to read this physics study I'm interested in right my kids I don't know if it's just like parenting in the Bay Area but my kids
are like okay Mom make the images right I want to tell a story about the dragon unicorn in this setting I'm going to tell you exactly how it's going to happen create it in real time and I'm
like like that's a big ask I'm glad you believe and like know that's possible but it's it's a wild way to like create your own entertainment too what is the um most surprising Behavior you've seen
in your own products recently I think it's a behavior and a relationship like people really start
understanding the Nuance of like what Claud is we just have like a a new revenge of the model and it's like they get the Nuance like it's like I guess the behavor behavior is like almost befriending or like really like
developing a lot of like 2-way empathy around what's happening and then like the is like oh you know the new model like felt like it was smarter but maybe a little more distant but maybe you know and it's like it's like that kind of
like Nuance which like you like I it's it's given me as a product person a lot more empathy around like you're not just shipping a product you're shipping like intelligence and intelligence and
empathy are like what makes like interpersonal relationships important and if somebody show up and they're like I was upgraded like I say know I scored 2% higher on this math score but like I'm Different in this way you'd be like
oh I got to adapt now and maybe you know be a little worried about it so like that that's been an interesting Journey for me like understanding the mentality for people that when they're using our products yeah Model Behavior is
absolutely a product role like the the personality of the model is is key and there are interesting questions around how much should it customize uh versus how much should you know open AI have
one personality and Claude has some distinct personality and are people going to use one versus the other because they happen to like it I mean that's that's a very human thing right we're friends with different people because we happen to like
different people better than others and it's um that's an interesting thing to to think about we did something recently um and it sort of went viral on Twitter
people started asking the model based on everything you know about me based on all of our past interactions you know what what would you say about me and the model will will respond and it will like
give you give it a description of what it you know kind of thinks based on all of your past interactions and it is this sort of you're you're starting to interact with
it almost like some sort of person or entity in interesting ways and um anyways it was fascinating to see people's reaction to that Kevin Mike thank you so much for
doing this and giving us a glimpse into the future thank you so much