You're early growth PM at Facebook.
You're head of growth at Instagram,
you're VP of product at Instacart. You're
now director of product management at YouTube
and I've heard that you've had a lot of
impact on a lot of different cultures.
I found this framework travels with me.
It's got these five components to it,
vision, skills, incentives, resources,
action plan, and you need all of those
to have change. And then within those
buckets you've got to figure out what are
the right levers that you need to pull?
What are the things that are missing?
You're really big on something
you call understand work?
What I call the anti-paren of what
we want to do. Someone says, "Hey,
you know what? This would be great to build." And
you go pull data to go justify why that would be
great to build. Call that identify, justify,
execute. First you have to really understand
from first principles what is actually
going on. So understand, identify, execute.
You wrote this legendary blog post called How
to Choose Where to Work and What to work on.
There's impact that you're really trying to drop
and the impact is only achievable by looking at
set of variables related to the environment,
the set of variables related to your skills.
Today's guest is Bengaly Kaba. Bengaly was
an early growth PM at Facebook where he was
responsible for how people make friends on
Facebook. He was Head of Growth at Instagram
where he helped scale a platform to over
1 billion users. He was also VP of product
at Instacart. He's also worked with tons
of amazing startups as a Growth Advisor,
including Twitter. He's now Director of Product
Management at YouTube where from what I hear,
he's already made a huge dent. This
conversation went long because there
was so much gold to be extracted from
Bengaly's head and I could not stop
myself from learning everything I could in
our time together. This episode is for anyone
looking to level up their product and growth
chops or also just do better in your career.
We dig into his framework for how to choose where
to work and what to work on. The importance of
spending time on something he calls understand
work, his adjacent user theory and how it can help
you drive growth. A bunch of advice for coaching
product managers and managers of managers,
tons of lessons and stories from his time at
Instagram, Facebook and YouTube and so much more.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. It's the best
way to avoid missing feature episodes and
it helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you Bengaly Kaba.
Bengaly, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Thanks for having me. Excited to be here.
So many previous guests have recommended that
I get you on this podcast, which I already
knew. Funny story, when I first launched this
podcast, I asked you to be on it. You're like,
"Sure." And I included you on my launch
poster of all the guests that are going
to be on the podcast, and then you decided to
take on a very hard work and jobs that kept
you from having time, and so I'm really
excited that we're finally doing this.
I'm glad we're finally making a
reality. Sorry about that, Lenny.
No sweat. You actually mentioned to me that
somebody came up to you in Zurich and was like,
"I'm excited for you on Lenny's podcast."
Yeah, it was crazy. I was visiting a team that
I managed there about to get back on a plane to
go back to SFO and just standing there doing some
work, minding my business and I get on the plane,
I'm talking to a colleague and someone comes up
to me, I don't think I've ever seen them before,
and said, "Hey, sorry to interrupt you. I'm so
excited for your podcast with Lenny. I can't wait
for it." And then just walks away and I was like,
"What is going on right now? Lenny is a big deal.
I don't even know how this person knows me." And
that's how I knew Lenny, that I had to reschedule
with you because I was like, if people are coming
up to me and telling me that they're excited,
I was like, there is a lot of anticipation. And
Lenny, the power of your reach now is legit.
That is hilarious. That's a new
strategy for me to get people on
the podcast just say they're going to be on
the podcast and then the pressure will start.
Oh yeah, I mean, totally.
Okay, so there's two broad topics that I
want to spend our time on today. I want
to talk about career advice and growth advice
and they're both essentially growth oriented,
one's career growth, one is product
growth. How does that sound?
Sounds perfect.
This episode is brought to you by Wizard,
empowering product leaders to ideate and
iterate faster than ever before. With the power
of AI. As a product manager, I often spend
hours taking screenshots and then annotating
them with feedback for my team. With Wizard,
I can simply upload my screenshot and Wizards AI
will turn them into a fully editable UI design
that I can then take, make tweaks to and then
share with my teams in minutes. And when I want
to get really creative and explore totally
new ways to improve our product experience,
I can use Wizard's AI to generate new design
concepts from simple text prompts and turn
them into interactive prototypes effortlessly.
There's a reason that over 2.6 million people
have trusted Wizard to accelerate every phase
of their product lifecycle and speed up time to
market. Developers can even export UI components
to React and CSS to speed up their development.
Wizards drag and drop editor is super easy to
use and you can collaborate in real time with
your entire team. Even your CO and customer
service teams can contribute. Unlock all of
Wizards game changing AI powered features and
more with 25% off Wizards Pro annual plan.
Visit uizard.io/lenny and use code: Lenny
to check out today. That's uizard.io/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Mercury. Mercury
knows your financial operations are complex. It
doesn't have to be this way. I've been a super
happy customer at Mercury for over a year now,
and it's honestly hard to imagine a better online
banking experience can exist. Most founders and
finance teams have to couple together a patchwork
of tools to reconcile transactions from different
sources, work extra hard just to get a holistic
view of cash flow and have maps to company
priorities, and struggle to get answers from
platforms that all speak different languages.
Mercury knows that there's an art to simplifying
this complex patchwork with new bill pay and
accounting capabilities, you can pay bills
faster, stay in control of company's spend
and speed up reconciliation. The end result
is the precision, control and focus that
startups need to transform how they operate.
Apply in minutes at mercury.com and join over
200,000 ambitious startups like mine that trust
Mercury to get them to perform at their best.
Mercury, the art of Simplified Finances.
Mercury is a financial technology company,
not a bank. Banking services provided by Choice
Financial Group and Evolve Bank & Trust. Members
FDIC. So let's maybe start with the career.
You wrote this legendary blog post called How
to Choose Where to Work and What to Work
On that a few people have mentioned to me
was really impactful in their career. And just to
remind people of your career path, which they'll
hear in the intro, but just to give people
a reason to listen to your advice on career,
you are early growth PM at Facebook, you're Head
of Growth at Instagram, you're VP of Product at
Instacart. You worked with a ton of amazing
startups as an advisor, including Twitter,
you're now Director of Product Management at
YouTube. This is a career that many people would
dream of having. So let's just spend a little
time on this topic of how to choose where to
work and what to work on. And I know you kind of
have this framework in this post, so maybe that's
a good way to start out just how you broadly
think about where to work and what to work on?
Yeah, that blog post that you're referring
to actually came out of a personal struggle
that I had when I was at Facebook and trying to
decide what my next move should be. I felt like
I was kind of stuck. I felt like I was working
harder but not seeing incremental benefit to the
work that I was doing. And I knew that I needed
a change, but emotionally I understood that,
but I couldn't really have an objective way of
thinking about it. And so I really pushed myself
to figure out what is actually going on with my
situation and how do I create a way that I can
rely on objectively to understand what's actually
going on? And so I looked at that situation and I
wrote that post and the framework is really that
there's impact that you're really trying to drive
and that is the thing that is the most important.
And the impact is only achievable by looking at
two sets of variables, a set of variables related
to the environment, a set of variables related
to your skills, and really breaking down each and
understanding what's happening in the environment
bit by bit and what's happening with your
skills and where are you hindered structurally
within the environment? Where are your skills
kind of lacking and what do you have control
over? And using that whole kind of output, that
framework to decide what makes the most sense.
Why is impact the key output of
this equation? I think for a lot
of people that isn't necessarily
the intuitive variable that they
think is important to focus on. Why is
that so important in your experience?
Yeah, I mean I didn't really know how to think
about what the right thing to optimize for was
initially, and I realized that it's not
compensation. Compensation is a reflection
of the input, the impact that you're having, and
you're leveling how [inaudible 00:09:12] you are,
how much scope you have is a derivative of
how much impact you're driving. The more
impact you're driving at your company, the more
people feel like you can operate independently,
you can drive real results the more that scope
they'll give you. So really impact became the
thing to optimize for. It is the import and
compensation becomes an output based on that.
I think this is a really important point that
is easy to miss and this is what I always tell
people when they're looking for ways to
get promoted and do well in companies,
just find ways to have more
impact. Can you maybe make
it even more concrete? What does impact
mean to you when you talk about impact?
Yeah, I mean, so impact can be a lot of things,
but I think for a product manager for example,
it's really one, helping to drive extreme clarity
about where the problems with the product,
where there's opportunities and what is the right
focus and prioritization? That is actually a form
of impact. Just creating the clarity that people
need to understand and believe in the investment.
The reason why I name this and it feels a little
counterintuitive is that the more senior you get,
the more there are questions of are
we even investing in the right place,
right? Is this area, is this team, is this org
the right investment? And so being able to even
create the clarity that there is opportunity, it
is the right thing to do, it is strategically and
structurally important, is a form of impact. And
then actually delivering on that impact, showing
that you can make progress quickly, that you can
deliver fast lane wins as Casey Winters would say,
or medium and slow wins and then actually showing
that you can do this again and again is how you
actually validate the impact that you can see
where the opportunity is and what's going on.
Awesome. Okay. So this equation
is impact equals environment type
skills. Can you talk a bit about
how to work on these two elements?
So the environment was the one to me, that I
think is most people overlook and I overlooked
when I was first thinking about this. Environment
in this case, I think I kind of discreetly named
a few things. One is your manager, then there's
the resources. So what kind of team do you have?
Is your team staffed appropriately? Do you
have the right P&L, whatever budget to get
the things done that you need? Then there's a
scope, what is in your remit versus not in your
remit? Because if you don't have enough scope,
then you can't actually focus on the things that
are most important. The team itself, the skills,
relative skills of the team, your compensation
in some ways is part of the environment
because if you're not compensated fairly,
you don't believe you are, then it's hard to feel
like the work that you're doing is meaningful.
And then there is the last part is the company
culture. So to what extent is the culture a place
where you feel supported, included, you feel like
you can do your best work? And so you are really
looking at each one of these variables, and I look
at this every year and I say, "How is my manager
doing?" How do I think about my manager?
How do I think about the resources I have,
the scope, the team, the conversation, the company
culture and to what extent? And I score them,
I score them as a 1 means it's kind of neutral.
A 2 means that I'm greatly benefiting from this
situation and something even closer to zero is
I'm not in a good place. So I assign a score
in quarter point increments, 0.25, 0.5, 0.751
up to 2 every year. And I really ask myself,
what is the state of each one of these and to what
extent do I believe that they can and will change?
Wow, I love this. So there's this
formula, impact equals environment
times skills. Within environment there's
these five variables and they add up to 10?
Yeah.
If they each give you two points. That's so
cool. Okay, so the five, just to be clear,
your manager, the resources you
have, is teams number three?
Mm-hmm.
Compensation and then the culture of the team?
And then your scope as well.
And then scope. Okay, got it.
It's actually six, yeah.
Oh, there's six. Okay, got it. So it's
up to 12. So the idea here is you score
each of these of how you're feeling,
how the environment is contributing to
the impact that you're delivering. And
if one of these is not a great score,
that's an opportunity to improve your
impact, which will improve your career?
That's right, and you have to really
be honest. I think part of what
makes this framework so powerful for me at least,
is that it helps you to be honest around what are
the things that are limiting your ability to have
impact and for your skills to really land? And to
what extent do you believe that you can help
to change or try to influence the change in
the environment? Because no one wants to be in a
place where there's a bad culture and the culture
is a bad fit for you, but if you're not really
thinking about it objectively and naming that,
or maybe it's the culture of the team
that is not the right place for you,
so it really forces you to evaluate what's
going on around you that's limiting your impact.
Is there an example from your career you
could share where one of these was not where
it needed to be and either helped change
it or realize you had to get out of there?
When I was actually at Facebook, I was running the
team that does all the people recommendations and
it was a great team. I actually had a massive,
massive team. I had 30 engineers I was working
with, 15 machine learning engineers and 15 front
end and back end engineers. And so great team,
incredible team, lot of resources, ton of scope.
In some ways it was too much scope and to me
that was problematic because I really needed to
build out, I felt like multiple teams to support
the work that we were doing or to break it up;
because it was, I mean the pace, the velocity you
can imagine at Facebook was incredible. And I felt
like between all of the work that we needed to do,
the amount of engineering capacity that we
had and the amount that was on the table,
I felt like I wasn't resourced in a way where I
felt like I could actually deliver on all of the
things that were necessary without burning myself
out. And I felt like I was burning myself out and
I couldn't really see the forest through
the trees because there was so much to do.
And so that was a situation that I didn't
really understand how to navigate at that
point in my career. And there were two
or three manager changes concurrently,
and so I didn't have a manager to lean on that
I felt like I had a relationship with to help me
to navigate that space. And I felt like the scope
was actually too much for what needed to be done,
and so I needed to find a better kind of fit
for me. There was nothing wrong with the team,
it was a great learning environment,
but it was the confluence of scope
and manager and all happening at
once just wasn't a good fit for me.
A lot of people are in these situations
where they'd say they go through this score,
they identify I have way too little scope,
way too much scope like you described,
and there's always this question of can I
actually make a change or is this just not,
am I not in a position? Especially, I see
product managers, there's just always a lot of,
I can't actually change anything. What
do you often tell people around this that
just feel like there's nothing I can do here
and my manager sucks, what am I going to do?
Well, I do think one of the things that I
recognize is your manager. Not all of these
variables is created equal and the manager is
the most important variable in the environment,
because a great manager who is empathetic,
who is aware of what's going on, who is a
great communicator, has the ability to move the
chess pieces around and to fix some of these for
you either immediately or in time. There's no
one other than your manager who can really help
to increase your scope or to help make sure
that the team has the right pieces in place,
or dial in some of the issues
that you might see in culture.
And so that is why people say they
don't leave a job, they leave a manager
because the manager is the one that has a lot of
the power to fix a lot of these variables. And so
really the question becomes like to what extent
have you been able to clearly articulate what are
the... And dispassionately articulate, what are
the challenges that you're having, you're seeing
across some of these variables with your manager?
Help them to tie it back to how it's impacting
your work and see if they can help you to
create a plan to alleviate some of these things.
That's super interesting. Then your experience
with the manager is kind of the core of a lot
of these variables. Is there anything you
recommend to people if their managers is
not someone they like, is it just try to
find a new manager or potentially leave?
You're never going to always like your
manager, right? That's not the... The
goal isn't to like your manager. Ideally,
you respect them and they respect you, you
feel like there's things that you can learn from
them. Finding a new manager is always an option,
but I guess sometimes the real question is, is
actually spending time to try to understand what
is your manager optimizing? A lot of times I think
there is a big disconnect between an IC focusing
on their discrete area and try to optimize
for local maxima, versus understanding, okay,
my manager's thinking about these things and this
is how I fit in, and understanding maybe they have
a gap to understanding why your area is important.
Or maybe there's stuff that's on your manager's
plate that is actually adjacent to your remit that
if you understood that they were optimizing for,
you can take that on and you would find more
synergies with what they're trying to do.
I love that advice.
Let's talk about the other side of this
equation. We've talked about environment,
let's talk about skills. What do you advise there
for folks that want to improve their skills?
The skills part is really, really big and it's
something that requires I think, consistent
evolution of your own abilities. And so I broke it
out in that blog post kind of communication, your
ability to influence your leadership, strategic
thinking and then execution, actually getting
things done. The communication above these,
again, not all of these are created equal. I think
communication is the one that tends to be the most
impactful. And you see this in a lot of ways. You
see this for people who are poor executors
but incredible communicators and they seem
to continue to rise and rise because they can tell
a great story, but when you look under the covers,
there's nothing there. There's no substance there.
So communication for better or worse is one of
the most important things. But building out
your skills I think is really just kind of a,
it is an interesting time to be in product and
to be in tech right now because you have so many
more ways to build out your skills than what
previously existed. Just so many incredible
blog posts like your podcasts and blogs,
there's so many incredible people who've
come on here who tell you things like how
to go to market, how to think about B2B SaaS
and metrics. And so listening to you, reading
Ben Thompson, understanding his mental models,
if you go to look at Elena Verner or whoever,
there's so many thought leaders who are out there.
So I think being a voracious reader is really,
really critical because it helps to build your
toolkit and you need arrows in your quiver to
really understand how to think about the right
framework and the right mentor at the right time.
One thing I also tell people is people think about
mentorship as like, I have a mentor, Lenny is
my mentor, or John is my mentor. I tell them,
it's actually better to have a stable of mentors.
You want to have three or four. And ideally,
what you do is you meet with each one of them
once a month on a different Friday of the month.
And so you might have three or four people
on every Friday you're meeting with someone
different. And the reason why this is so
important is because if you, Lenny, are
a mentor to me and you're busy one Friday and we
only meet once a month now I don't have anyone to
talk to for two months. And you're going through a
lot of things and you're not really able to bounce
ideas, or build skills or learn how influence
others, but if you have three or four mentors,
you have someone different to talk to every week.
And if one or two of them cancel, you still have
two people to talk to that month and you still
can continue to grow and to build your thinking.
So that's something I always recommend. And
then the last thing I actually talk about is,
when it comes to execution, I think people don't,
especially product managers, don't do enough of
watching and learning from others. There's an art
and a science to product management. And in a lot
of ways I come from a background of education and
in a lot of ways in product management, it's very
similar. You want to watch how well the people
hone their craft, how they deliver, how they
lead teams and kind of steal things from them.
Figure out, well, wow, Lenny did this really,
really well when he was at Airbnb. It was really
incredible. I'm going to take that. I'm going to
take how he runs that team, or how he landed that
framework, or how he communicated this message
and note it and use it in my own toolkit later on.
And so if you're really a student of product, you
can't just be a student of theory, you've got to
be a student of practice too, meaning you're going
and you're looking, it's like, "Hey, I'd love
to sit in your team meetings. Can I come watch?
Or your PM meetings or your leadership meetings."
And you are really like doing that for the sake of
learning is really, really incredible. And that's
some of the ways I talk about building skills.
Is there an example of that latter lesson
that you learned from someone that comes
to mind of watching someone and
like, oh, I'm going to do that.
Earlier in my career, when I first got to
Instagram, I wasn't the first Growth PM,
but I was one of the first and a guy who was there
before me, his name was Georgia Lee, he actually
stood up the growth team and ended up leaving six
months right after I joined. But I watched, George
was a really good listener. He had just a really
incredible ability to be in a room and hear what
was going on, to recast it back and make sure that
everyone felt good about where we were and what
was being said and the path forward, and really
crystallizing the action items and also how people
felt about what the next steps were. And walking
out of that meeting, it felt like he always had
buy-in and clarity and was helpful to
build trust. You can see him almost
winning trust in every moment of that meeting.
And that was something that I really admired,
and learned, and kind sought to
emulate later on in my career.
That's an awesome example. It comes back to the
skill of communication that you talked about,
just the power becoming really good at that. And
this is such a simple skill you just described,
is just recapping, here's what we talked
about. Here's what we're going to do.
Here's the decisions we made. Here's action
items. It's not actually difficult, it's just-
It's not, actually. But what was magical about the
way he did it. It's like he would name people and
their contributions and show how all of this
came together into what is the path forward.
That is amazing.
And it's the communication, but it's
also the other side. It's the other coin,
the side of communication, which is eliciting to
figure out how you communicate back to others.
So good. Following up on something else
you talked about, which is mentors. Anytime
someone talks about finding mentors, everyone's
always, how do I find a mentor? What advice do
you share with folks of how to find a mentor
to help? You say once a week or once a month?
Where I see people find the most success is they
ask. They tell people what they're working on or
what challenges they have and they say, "Do you
know someone who I might be able to learn from
who has done this or has good thinking about this
recently?" So instead of just going to someone
saying, "Hey, can you be a mentor?" Coming to
me and say, "Hey, Bengaly, I'm actually trying
to figure out how do I change the way this team
operates because we need to go from this model
to that model, but here's some of the challenges.
So do you know someone who's actually really good
at changing the way teams work or really good at
communicating a new vision that I can talk to?"
And so that I think is really important
because what you do is you're creating a seed,
and the seed is there's a triad and you have the
person who's looking for the mentor. You have
the recommender, the recommender, and then you
have the potential mentor. And the recommender
is basically saying, "Here, there's common
purpose between the two of you and I can see it,
and I think this is important, so I want
you all to come together." And that triad
in that moment creates a higher affinity,
highly likelihood that the person who needs
the help and the person who you're connecting
them with are going to see mutual benefit from
one another. And I think I find that just doing
that and seeding that and being really focused
on what the opportunity or the challenge is,
tends to lead to better connections as opposed
to just reaching out and saying, "Hey, I
like your style. Will you be my mentor?"
So essentially share with folks you
trust, here's what I'm working on.
See if they recommend someone that could
help you with that specific skill versus
assuming that there's this person
that can help you with this skill?
That's right.
I love it. Going back to your advice on career,
something that you wrote about in your post
plus folks have told me you're really big on,
is this something you call understand
work? Does that ring a bell?
Yes, it does.
Okay. Talk about that and why that's important?
I certainly cannot take credit
for understand work. This
is part of an old Facebook framework of
understand, identify, execute. What I-
Facebook framework of understand, identify,
execute. What I probably will say is I guess I've
been the shepherd for understand work in other
companies. I've taken it from my time at Facebook
and Relink Institute or rigorously at Instagram,
then at Instacart and when I helped with Twitter,
now at YouTube. The way I like to talk about
it with my teams is that first I tell a story
actually, and the story is we've all had a moment
where we have worked on something with a team,
super excited, finally it launches and we go out
to dinner and we celebrate. And we're celebrating,
everyone's juiced. It's great night. You go
back to the office the next day and you look
at the metrics and the metrics are flat
and everyone's a little bummed. Why did
this happen? Right. Why are the metrics
flat? What happened? We worked so hard.
And ultimately when you unpack it, you realize
that you built something that you thought was
going to be a good idea, but you really didn't
understand a lot of key components of what people
really needed, what pain points really existed,
or what were the alternatives and what the real
value of those alternatives were in the market, or
exactly how the product needed to work, what the
flywheel or what the experience needed to be. And
so that is what I call the anti-pattern of what we
want to do and I call that identify, justify,
execute. Right. Where you identify something,
someone says, "Hey, you know what? This would
be great to build." And you identify that,
then you go pull data to go justify why that
would be great to build and then you sink an
ungodly amount of time working on it in order to
make it work, but it ultimately doesn't succeed.
And that is the anti-pattern to what is kind
of like the Facebook kind of way of thinking,
which is understand, identify, execute, right?
So first you have to really understand from
first principles what is actually going
on. So when we talk about understand work,
there's a few ways to think about it. One is, it
is an intentional affordance in your execution
to do the work that helps you to de-risk a
project and to learn what's going on. When
I say an intentional affordance, meaning you put
it down like Lenny is going to work on this thing.
Right. Lenny as a product manager is going to
write a strategy. Janice as a designer is going
to design a prototype, whatever the thing is, and
you put it down as actual an item as opposed to
assuming it's going to happen in the background.
We don't make an affordance for understand work,
then the work doesn't get done and
everyone's just sprinting on execution.
And so it's a planned intentional time to
the team's bandwidth to figure out what is
it that we need to do to understand what's
happening. And so for example at Instagram
we did a lot of understand work of what makes
for a good connection? Right. How do we want
to think about that? How do we want to make
sure that we're actually growing a graph,
a social graph that makes sense? And so I might
work with data science to do understand work,
to pull a funnel and look at the different types
of connections for different types of users and
make it make sense. Right. And engineering might
do understand work to instrument logging to make
sure that we have the data that we need
in order to tell the story. And so you're
doing this understand work to basically better
understand the gaps in knowledge. What's also
really interesting is that understand work helps
you to clarify what is a root cause, or what is a
job to be done, or what is the right use case?
And because the team adopts this mentality,
it becomes this forcing function for execution. So
when someone says, "You know what we should build?
We should build this." You have a team that's
enabled and empowered to say, "That's a good idea,
but we don't actually understand these three
things before we start working on that. So maybe
we should do understand work to make sure that
that is actually the right idea." Right. And so
what you end up getting by embracing this concept
is two things. You get parallel paths of work. So
every sprint, let's say you do a three-week sprint
or a three-month roadmap, you're executing on the
things that you have a lot of conviction around
and you're also doing understand work in parallel.
And so at the end of the sprint you have learnings
from what you executed. Wow, that test or that
launch worked really well. We should double down.
Or Wow, that test or launch didn't work. Here's
how we should pivot. And you have insights
from the understand work and you use both of
those to plan the next sprints or roadmap. Right.
And so because you have this parallel path, you
end up getting this velocity multiplier over time.
Right. So the next sprint, and the third sprint,
and the fourth sprint, every subsequent sprint you
de-risk new ideas, you've gotten more clarity. And
so you do more execution, you do better execution
and you move faster and the things you ship,
you have a higher win rate on the things you
ship, right? And your shipping, I remember when
I left Instagram, this is many years ago, but we
had 15 teams and we might've been running 12 to
20 experiments a quarter a team, and I would
say probably 60 to 70% of them were positive
and shippable, which is incredible. I mean, you
think about and multiple and the magnitude of
that and it was because we were so effective at
de-risking and understanding what was going on.
This is really interesting. I imagine
many people listening here are like,
we put time into understanding, we run
experiments, we write strategy docs,
we use research. What is it that you think people
are, where do you think they're missing? Is it
that you dedicate people's actual time, like
you're just doing understand work instead of
building a new thing. For this next sprint,
you're just going to be telling us what the
problem here or opportunity is. How
do you actually operationalize this
versus just what people probably already
do, which is user research, data dives?
What I found is a couple things. One is when your
team does not fully understand a problem space,
the balance of work tends to be
higher. I think when I started at
YouTube we were doing 60% execution, 40%
understand work. Right. And over time,
as we understand more and more, the mix shifts.
Now my teams are probably doing 80% execution,
20 to or 85% and 20 to 15% understand work.
And so it's not just about writing a strategy,
it's about saying, okay, if we have these
themes of stuff that we want to work on,
what do we know with confidence because the
data tells us and what do we need to understand
because we don't have the data, we don't have
the research, we don't have the insights? And
really being honest with yourselves around what
are the things that are low to medium effort
but high likelihood of being impactful
because you have the data and what are
the things that you are interested in perhaps
doing, but because you're missing something,
you're missing research or feedback from
users or data or some insights or strategy.
You should actually say, I'm going to go
do this before I do something else. Right.
An example of this is one of my teams ships
paid virtual goods in the live experience on
YouTube. And that's a really, really important
and hard problem space. And when I joined,
we didn't really fully understand the whole
live ecosystem, like how we lived in that live
ecosystem, how our products worked, where the
biggest opportunity was. So the first and most
important piece of understand work was instead
of shipping iterations to the current product,
we needed to actually get the funnel of what
was happening. Right. Like what's happening
with how many people are watching live every
day, how many people are clicking through,
how many people are seeing our experience,
how many people actually buying it? We didn't
really fully have the experience mapped out and to
understand where were the gaps and where are the
problem space is in, where should we be focusing?
And so we had to do that. And that was understand
work for multiple people, for multiple
teams. We had to do on the engineering
side, we needed data science as analysis. We
needed the PM to go and dog through the experience
to figure out what was broken. All of that was
intentional and an affordance on our roadmaps.
What's interesting about this is that this is
very counterintuitive to how people would probably
approach, hey, we need to speed up execution, we
need to speed up growth, we need to ship more,
execute, go faster, do more. And what you're
saying is you find the impact comes from actually
slow down how much we're doing and spend more
time understanding to execute more intelligently.
That's right. Slow down and speed up.
Fascinating. Because it's interesting, I have a
bunch of questions that emerged out of folks that
you've worked with and many of them are around
how you turn a culture around, speed things up,
and drive growth in a really meaningful way. And
it sounds like this is one of your key strategies,
is get people to spend more time understanding
before diving into a bunch of stuff.
It does sound counterintuitive,
but if you actually think about it,
what is a better outcome? Is it a better
outcome to just ship more faster now,
but most of the things aren't unimpactful? Right.
Or is it a better outcome to ship fewer things
but really work on making sure that you're
shipping them in the best way and de-risking
a lot of other things so that a year later your
win rate's higher and your velocity is higher?
Yeah, I think counterintuitive is the wrong
word. I think it makes sense. I think it's just
no one does this. Usually everyone's like, move
faster, we need more and ship more experiments.
Well, I mean this is the irony of growth, is
people think growth is overnight success and
it's not. Right. It is a lot of short wins
and short-term execution for a longer-term
gain and really understanding you have a lot of
short terms towards the longer-term outcomes.
So that people can take away this lesson, can
you help people understand just when you say
understand work, like what does that look like
generally? Is it just a dedicated time to dive
into data and answer a bunch of questions you've
sent them? Is it running experiments to test
hypotheses? What does that usually look like
when you're, here let's do 40% understand work?
The understand work sometimes comes from
me, but most often comes from the teams
themselves. And every function can do and
should be doing understand work at some
point. Right. And so it really depends on what
the function is. So for an engineer, it could be
looking at the code and saying, okay, we want
to improve this. I need to do understand work
to understand do we need to refactor this code
and how scalable is it and what do we need to
do to make sure that we can execute fast and
make sure that we're not going to have a lot
of start and stop? That could be understand work.
It could be actually instrumenting the data and
making sure that we actually have full visibility
into what's going on. Data science, like we work
a lot with data science doing activation metrics
and understanding proxy metrics. Right. That's
understand work because it helps us to figure
out what we need to build and where to focus.
For product management, sometimes understand work
is figuring out the partnership strategy ahead of
actually launching the product because you need
to go figure out how the pieces are going to come
together. Right. And so it really just depends
on what the function is. But when I say it should
be coming from the bottoms up, what I mean is I
encourage the team when we plan a sprint or plan
a roadmap, to ask a question to identify the key
themes that they need to work on. And when they
ask a question on a key theme, also ask what else
do we need to understand to make this happen? And
in that planning session, to make sure that you
are including cross-functional partners. So it's
not just product design and data science and Inge,
you also include go to market, you also include
marketing because if you're not inclusive, then
you don't really understand what the issues are.
My PM brain is afraid of creating too
much understand work and nothing getting
done. How do you find that balance of
we're going to be understanding for
hours and days and weeks and months and
not shipping much? How do you do some,-
I tell them, you have to ship. I mean, you always
have to ship, right? Sometimes I give them,
sometimes it's helpful, especially early on
because it takes a while for people to get their
head around why this is so critical. I say, we
should choose, sometimes I'll give them guidance.
We should choose three to four understand projects
that are going to really help this roadmap and
figure out what they are. Right. So choose your
top three or four and then let's talk about it.
And I'll give them guidance. Or I would say figure
out... There should always be some execution.
So initially you're looking for low effort,
high impact things to execute against. Right.
And so build a portfolio of work to
do every sprint or every roadmap,
some of which should be low effort, high
impact, some of which should be medium effort,
high impact. And sometimes understand work
actually looks like doing a cheap test, doing
a test that's going to help us to learn as fast as
possible that we think is a good enough experience
that can inform us. Right. And so identifying
ways to do that. And so it's really about just
managing expectations and helping people to
be clear that the goal is to ship the product,
but you want to ship the things that you have
more confidence and understanding versus not.
So I think a big takeaway here is if you want
to have more impact, move faster, try to spend
a little more time understanding the problems
you're going after in the opportunity space.
That's right. Right. I'll give you a very tactical
example is when I joined Instagram in January
2016, believe it or not, the onboarding,
the sign-up flow at Instagram had literally
no logging to it. It had logging of how many
people started and how many people ended. Right.
And I joined in January and it was like we had to
write a roadmap. And so the roadmap looked like
this. Okay, we know this amount at the top of the
funnel and this amount at the bottom end of the
funnel. And there was eight steps in the funnel
and we don't know what is going on. Right. So the
first bit of understand work was we needed
to do the instrumentation of that funnel as
fast as possible to get the data to figure out
where the drops were happening and what to fix.
But because we knew of what was happening at the
top of the funnel and the bottom of the funnel,
we can go and play around with the
experience and see what was broken.
So we ran a bunch of tests of stuff that
was obviously broken to see what would
improve. Right. And so it was like a mix. And
so what we did was we set up time where we did,
the beginning of like the first couple of
weeks, add the logging, ship it to code,
re-evaluate in the middle of the quarter, look at
the full funnel and then add more things that we
can do later on once we got that. But in order
to get that done, that involved understand work
with growth marketing to figure out what
was the schemas for the instrumentation,
right, the engineering to actually do that
logging. Right. Data science to like pull
together funnels and dashboard it, all of
that had to come together all at one time.
I really like just this concept of calling
it understand work. I think that alone is a
powerful tool because we're going to
spend more time on understand work.
It feels like it gives meaning to stuff
that otherwise people would brush aside.
Right. Where it's just like, no,
no, let's just ship stuff. Let's
just try stuff. Let's just test
the step. We'll see what happens.
That's right.
Is there anything else you have seen and often
do to help a team you join move faster and
grow bigger? And I've heard that you've had a
lot of impact on a lot of different cultures,
so I'm curious if there's anything
else that is really effective.
I've found myself in a bunch of interesting
situations where I had to come in and help
improve cultures or change cultures around teams.
I found this framework, I don't even actually
remember where I got it from, but it travels from
computer to computer with me and team to team,
and it's called managing complex change. I
actually think I got it from business school
or something. And it's really interesting. It's
got these five components to it. There's vision,
skills, incentives, resources, action plan, and
you need all of those to have change. Right.
Team needs to have vision, they need to have the
skills, they need to have the right incentives.
Sometimes some teams are incentivized to do
some things versus others. You need to have
the right resources in the right places and you
need to have a clear action plan. And what I love
about this framework is if you can visualize it
and maybe you can share it with your podcast.
Yeah. We'll put it up on the screen on YouTube
so folks can see what you're talking about.
Basically what it does is it shows where
if you're missing any one component,
you get different outcomes. Right. So
if you're missing the vision component,
you end up in a state of confusion or if you're
missing the incentives, you end up in a state of
resistance because people aren't incentivized to
do the right work. Or if you're missing an action
plan, you end up in a state of false starts. So I
use this, and I think about this a lot actually,
because when you come in as a leader, as
someone who's supposed to influence change,
you have to really observe what's happening and
figure out what are the challenges anecdotally
and what are you observing? And then I figure out
where I can plug in and what I can do to make the
teams better. And what I tend to find is moving
from the right side to the left side of this,
like action plans are easier to institute. Right.
So if I see a team that's struggling to execute,
I wonder do they have the right type of
PRD framework or are they communicating
well? Do they have the right type of team meeting
structures? Those are kind of lower hanging fruit.
It's a lot harder to change vision and skills.
It will come in time. But what I also have done
over the course of my career is I've built this
deck that comes with me of different skills that
matter. Right. What are different skills, what are
different frameworks, how do we think about it,
to help level teams fast? Right. Because I find
that sometimes you walk in and not everyone is
grounded in the same mental models or concepts.
One example of this I talk about a lot is
Instagram. Instagram had just this fantastic
culture of thinking about how do we ship high,
high quality product, right, and what does
product craft mean? And so that is something
that I came to YouTube and my teams particularly,
they didn't have a mental model for product craft.
So I found myself talking into an echo chamber in
some way. So I had to build a deck that showed,
okay, here's how I think about product craft.
Here's a framework for it. Here's how I think
about all of these different things.
And so now we have a shared language,
shared communication for, and a repository
of skills that we're going to build.
So I'm looking at this image that we'll have
up. So in this case, their skills weren't
necessarily there, which in this framework
leads to anxiety. And so what I'm hearing,
essentially you come into a team, you're like,
what am I feeling? Is it confusion, frustration,
the wrong thing? And that kind of tells you
which of these buckets to spend time on.
That's right. And then within those
buckets, you've got to figure out
what are the right levers that you
need to pull? What are the things
that are missing? How do you really focus
and where do you kind of spend your time?
So interesting. I love that this
image is just like this very grainy,-
So old.
Screenshot from some old
McKinsey deck or something.
Yeah. It's from like 2006 PC or something.
I love it. So you have this thing,
you have this deck. You just come
in with all these tools in your tool
belt. Is there anything else in that
list of things that you bring with you
to help change culture and help teams,-
Yeah. I think one thing I think
about a bunch is I come from,
my background's a little bit different than a
traditional tech executive. There was actually
three phases to my career. I was in education for
six years, taught in inner city DC and then was a
dean of a boarding school in Switzerland,
which is a little bit of a plot twist.
Oh, wow.
I went to business school and I worked on Wall
Street for a bit, and then I left my job on Wall
Street, quit and started a startup. Startup
was a glorious failure as many startups are,
but it was like a very non-traditional path
towards tech. And I think a lot of my time in
these other industries actually shapes the way I
think about products and product management and
actually changing teams and building teams. And
what I mean by that is I think there's a lot of
similarities between education and
product management believe it or not.
When I was interviewing for my first set of jobs
in tech, recruiters would say to me, "How does
your background relate? I don't really see it."
And I would tell them, "When I was in education,
I would walk into a classroom of 24, seven-year
olds, and these kids owed me nothing. And the
only way I could be successful or impactful is
I needed to be able to be a strong communicator.
I needed to be able to have a clear vision
of what was going on. I needed to be able
to influence them in a believable way such
that they would get on board with what needed
to be done for 270 days of the year." It's like
when you walk into a room as a product manager,
engineers, designers, researchers go to market.
Nobody owes you anything. And the only thing that
you're going to do in order to be successful
is you need to be a strong communicator. You
have a clear vision of what's going on and you
need to be able to influence them to do the
things together of what matters, right? It's very
similar skillset, just different domain expertise.
And so because of that, right, I've really adopted
a mindset of how do I coach my teams? How do I
enable them? Because it's really about the sum
of the parts versus me being a top down leader
saying, you have to do this and you have to do
that. And so I think a lot about that in both
approach and the processes that we create. And to
give you a couple of classic typical examples of
this, there's two things I want to call out.
One is there's this, actually this education
framework, it's called Bloom's Taxonomy. I think
it's changed over time, but when I learned it,
it was basically a pyramid and the pyramid was,
Bloom Taxonomy describes what's the different
levels or order of critical thinking you need
in order to be a master of something? And at
the bottom of the pyramid was knowledge, and
then it's comprehension, and then application,
analysis, synthesis, and evaluation. Right.
And so going up the pyramid, it means it's
higher order thinking. And I think about that a
lot and trying to understand where are my teams
struggling? Do they have the core knowledge that
they need? Do they understand it but they can't
apply it or they apply it, but they're not
able to analyze it across different business
segments? Right. And you can use this framework
not only with the ICPMs and the teams themselves,
but also for your managers, like what is breaking
down? And in using that and attaching that to the
skills that we want to build to figure out how do
you fill in those gaps? Right. And it really is a
grounding for me, a grounding mental model for how
do you build teams that are actually affect them?
How do you meet people where they are as opposed
to just saying, hey, you need to figure this out?
Right. I find that too often in tech and also in
product, people are ask to figure things out but
not given the support to get there, and there's
no way to really connect the dots for them.
Amazing. I'm pulling up the Bloom's
Taxonomy. So essentially if you see a PM
struggling, which you try to do is figure out
which of these things do they not have? How
are you not supporting them? How can
you support them better? So it could
be they don't have the skills, they don't
have the understanding. What are some of
the other things that often you find that
maybe hinder a product manager's success?
A lot of times they might have the understanding,
but they haven't had a chance to apply it to
a variety of different scenarios or haven't
seen it applied to multiple scenarios. Right.
So oftentimes you might understand a concept like
machine learning, but you haven't actually worked
on it in against multiple scenarios. So you
maybe have one way of doing it that doesn't
make sense and you need to have two or three,
and you don't even know that two or three ways
of doing it exists. Right. That is often a common
failure point. Right. Or it's maybe you know how
to apply it, but you can't synthesize why this
thing that you're doing actually matters for the
business context. Right. Oftentimes that becomes
a challenge with managers. It's like they know
what to do, but they don't understand how to tie
it back to the business context and the overall
strategy needs and so where to prioritize. Right.
And so what I find is that when you're trying to
manage managers, you're really trying to live
at the top of the pyramid. You are responsible,
managers responsible for basically owning that
pyramid for all of the areas that they operate,
but they need to be able to live at the
top of the pyramid across all of them.
They need to be able to synthesize
and evaluate what's happening for
each product team that they own in order to
kind of make the bigger picture connections.
By the way, I loved your metaphor of
product manager, like this group of
seven-year-olds where you have to learn
how to manage, influence, communicate.
Yeah.
It's great.
Yeah. I mean, they're not like
a group of seven-year-olds,-
It's the skills.
But I think it's actually, it's,-
Yeah, the same skills.
Huh?
The same skills you,-
Same skills.
Yeah.
I mean, I think it's true. I found it
actually significantly harder for me to
get 24 seven-year-olds to believe in what
I was doing then to walk into a room with
Kevin Systrom and Mike Krieger and explain
to them what's the strategy for growing the
next 100 million users on Instagram? These are
very logical adults who can reason with you,
and you got a classroom of kids. It's not quite
the same. So those skills are really critical.
I love that. I definitely want to
ask about your Instagram days. Is
there anything else in this bucket of
wisdom of, you kind of talked about
things you've learned about how to manage
product managers and managers of managers.
Is there anything else there that might
be helpful to folks that you've learned?
One thing that I also think about a lot,
and I don't know if this is just a me thing,
but I think about PM as a team sport. Right.
Leading product teams is really about...
Leading product teams is really about being the
coach and helping other people to see what their
role is on the team and to maximize them. People
talk a lot about product as you're the CEO,
and I don't actually fully believe that analogy.
If you think about it as a team sport, there's a
few things that shake out. One is not everyone's
going to be a star player. But not everyone needs
to be a LeBron James or Kobe Bryant. You need role
players. You need really strong role players. You
need people who feel valued in their role, and
you need to understand how to groom those role
players and how to make sure that they have the
right seat at the table and the right place. So
I think it's, yes, you're the conductor
of the orchestra, but you're really more
than that. You're really the coach of the team.
Another thing I think about a lot is I have a good
friend who's a college basketball coach, and he
taught me about this idea of your coaching tree.
This is a really important concept, especially
in college basketball. You, as a head coach, you
take a lot of pride in who are your assistants.
Who is your first assistant, second assistant,
and third assistant? And where do they go on to
be head coaches? And what legacy do they have
because you were able to instill a bit in them?
The coaching tree of a Mike Mike Krzyzewski, the
coaching tree of a John Calipari, these esteemed
coaches, not only because of what they've done,
but because of the tree that they've built.
And I like to think about this as well, because I
think it's really important for product leaders,
think about what is their leadership tree. Who
have you helped to build up and help to grow and
help to get to their next wall? And so I think
about this a lot. I have people who I've worked
with who are running growth at Stripe or the
CPO at Chief or now running stories at Instagram
that were on my team in the earlier days. And
their success is my success, and I'm proud for
them, and I'm happy for them. And I think it
kind of reinforces this mentality that it's your
responsibility to coach people up to greatness.
So what I'm hearing is you put a lot of
value in your team on them coaching folks,
whether they're managers or even ICs is helping
them understand that it's important to coach
folks on their team and help them develop,
that it's part of your job, essentially.
That's part of your job. You are trying to
build a repository of skills and repository
of knowledge and of team velocity. And the only
way you can do that is everyone is...
So rising tide has to lift all boats.
Amazing. And interestingly, that
probably teaches you how to do your
job better because you're in teaching,
you actually learn things a lot better.
That's right. That's right. And
it forces you to figure out how
can you get things off of your plate so
that you can go work on bigger things.
Yeah, and how good does it feel when folks
that you used to manage go on
to do bigger and better things.
That's right. That's great.
I want to talk a little bit about growth
within YouTube. I heard that you haven't
been there for that long, and apparently
you've already... Two extra, three extra more,
something important within YouTube. I don't know
exactly the details, and people are very impressed
with the impact you've already had. And apparently
a lot of the success there and other places is
how you think about growth through flywheels.
You always look for the flywheel that helps
drive growth. Can you just talk about either at
YouTube, ideally YouTube, whatever you can share,
because that's pretty impressive, especially
for a company that scale that you're making so
much impact, or other places, just how
you think about flywheels and growth.
Well, it's very generous of you. I wouldn't
say, look, we've done some really good work,
some good work so far at YouTube, and it's been a
journey. I do think a lot about flywheels. I think
it's actually a lot of growth is really
understanding what is the value profit,
all of the different points of the experience,
especially if you have a multi-sided marketplace.
A multi-sided marketplace for YouTube is like
the creator and what the creator is trying to
achieve both from an engagement perspective, but
also for me for a monetization perspective. And
then for the viewer or the purchaser, where
is their hat? What are they trying to do,
and where are they missing the opportunity?
I can't really go into specifics a bunch with
YouTube, but what I would say is this is that
one thing that I always do when I come in is I
try to push my teams to really dog food
products in their adjacent user state,
if you will. And what I mean by that is often,
a product that you and I use that we've been
using for years isn't actually the product that
we're building for other people. Like a power
user who's using a product has... There's so much
history and there's so much informed knowledge on
how that product... for that product to actually
create a great experience for you that if you were
to go and create a new Gmail account and look at
YouTube today, I guarantee you it's a completely
different and significantly worse experience.
And there's a lot of obvious opportunities missed,
especially with what is the flywheel and why
things are working or not working if you don't
actually go and use things in a new state.
And an example of this when we talk about
YouTube is a lot of the YouTube graph for
searching stuff is based on what have you
watched in the past? So if you go and search and
you search history, it's going to be about like,
well, what have you watched in the past or what
have you searched for, and what can we show you
that's going to be what we can better predict?
But if you don't have a line of search history,
then they're not going to do as good
of a job. And so that's not a direct
translation for what we were doing. But
for me, I work on freedom monetization,
and there are really important flywheels around
what does it take for a creator to make content
that can help them to monetize? How do we
get that content to people and where to what
extent are we getting that content to people,
and how do we make sure that people feel good
about what they're receiving, the people who are
paying. And all of those flywheels have to work.
And so part of what I've been able to do is really
think about how do we connect the dots in a story
that the teams can uniquely understand, can help
them to lean in even more and have clarity and
purpose of work. Sometimes, what's super
important about the flywheels actually is
enabling for your teams to know what to work on
and what not to work on. And then it also helps us
to understand what do we know and what do we not
know about creators and viewers and monetization
operations so that we can do the understand work
to improve the velocity and to prove the impact.
And that's really where we've been focused. And
so I did a lot of this in YouTube, but I also did
this in Instacart, really thinking about when I
joined Instacart, one of the big questions I had
was like, how will people in their daily lives...
How's their daily life actually reflecting in the
purchase experience? Are we making it easy
for them? Because when you buy groceries,
you're not going to going grocery shopping
because you want beautiful ingredients in your
fridge. You're going grocery shopping because you
actually have a meal to put together. So are we
actually reflecting the real job to be done,
which is I want to buy tacos, I want to make
Taco Tuesday. Can we make it easier for people
to find the ingredients for tacos, as opposed to
having them sort for tortillas and tomatoes and
avocado? And so it's really thinking about what
is the job and then what is the flywheel to make
that happen, and how do we make this come to life?
There's so many things that I want to follow
up on here. First of all, I realize that all
of the things you worked on, I am a daily active
user of or weekly active user. Twitter, YouTube,
Instagram, Instacart about weekly active
user, I think that might be. Yeah. Wow,
nice job. You got me. You got me in
the flywheels of all your flywheels.
I was not intentional, but I'm glad my
efforts had improved joy, just a little bit,
Nice work.
... ideally.
Okay, so a couple takeaways here. One is you
think about the value prop at every interaction
of both sides, if it's a multi-sided marketplace
or if it's just like, "Why would I be doing this?"
So it's like, "Why would I send an invite to my
friend? Why would I share this photo? Why would
I open up Instacart?" And then you think about
the jobs to be done during the day of a potential
user and how can we flow into that versus not
connect to their actual day-to-day experience?
And is the product actually working? As
I'm doing this, I'm looking and saying,
"Is the product actually set up to deliver
these things? Do we actually see it work or
not?" I think there's a lot of assumptions
that the product works, but a lot of times
teams will surprisingly build the pieces of
a flow but not actually build the experience,
the output. They don't design it in a way where
you're getting the real output that you need.
That's such a easy to miss point you're
making here, which is you just think about,
"Hey, I have Taco Tuesday. I'm actually
as a product manager on Instacart. I'm
going to open up the app, and use it
in this use case and see how it goes."
That's right.
And most people don't do
that is what you realized.
Most people don't do that. Another example of
this, this was years ago, but at Instacart,
Instacart made it really hard to reorder stuff,
super hard to reorder. And it was shocking to me,
because when I thought about it, when I go to
the grocery store, 90% of the time I'm getting
the same stuff. It's like maybe not every
trip, but over the course of a month or two,
you've got a list of things that are part of your
staple, and then occasionally holiday time I went
some peppermint bark chocolate or something.
There's random snacks you're going to throw in,
but there's... And so when we looked at the data,
it turns out, after five times when you go to
Instacart, 90% of your order was the same. But
when you wanted to reorder, at least back then,
you couldn't go and reorder easily. You had
to dig and find it like seven or eight clicks.
And when you did reorder, you had to reorder
the whole thing. You couldn't take pieces,
you couldn't take, I want to take the milk and
the blueberries. And so you think about growth,
you think about what does it mean to
grow an Instacart? What does it mean
to actually drive better retention? Well,
it's actually really important to make it
easy for people to make the next order. And
so the product wasn't really built for that,
though people have the best intentions in mind.
The adjacent order.
Yeah, exactly.
I imagine that was maybe one of the
biggest growth wins in Instacart
history is just the reorder the same
thing, because I do that all the time.
Yeah, you would be surprised.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta.
When it comes to ensuring your company has
top notch security practices, things get
complicated fast. Now you can assess risk,
secure the trust of your customers and
automate compliance for SOC 2, ISO 27001,
HIPAA, and more with a single platform, Vanta.
Vanta's market-leading trust management platform
helps you continuously monitor compliance
alongside reporting and tracking risk. Plus,
you can save hours by completing security
questionnaires with Vanta AI. Join thousands
of global companies that use Vanta to automate
evidence collection, unify risk management,
and streamline security reviews. Get $1,000
off Vanta when you go to vanta.com/lenny.
That's V-A-N-T-A dot com slash Lenny.
You mentioned this concept of adjacent
user kind of adjacently, but I think it's
worth spending a little more time here.
It's like this term you popularized and you
explained it somewhat, but maybe explain a
little bit more. I think it's really powerful
for people and how do you think about growth.
This was something that came out of actually
my time at Instagram. It was a framework that
we came up with because Instagram really was,
at that time, we grew so fast that the people
who were using Instagram in February were
completely different than people who were
using it the following October and then
the next January. I think when I joined,
we were at like 440 million monthly actives.
January 2016, at the end of that year we were
at 636 million, grew like 47% that year. And
so when we talk to users, first half of 2016,
when we talk to women in the US in their 30,
they're like, "Why would I have an Instagram?
I have a Facebook account." Literally people said
that, it was that long ago. And then a year later
it's like, "Of course I use Instagram. Instagram
is my everything." The world changed so fast.
And so when you're in a hypergrowth product,
it's really, really important to understand
who your users are today and the persona of the
user, what motivates them, why they're using it,
but then also to understand who is the next user?
Who is the user who could be using this product,
but for some reason it doesn't work for them, and
understanding who that adjacent user is and when
you are actually starting to see that adjacent
user adopt the product. And one of the ways you
start to see the adjacent users starting
to adopt the product, especially with the
data, is you start seeing cohort curves decline.
You start seeing the people who sign up today,
three or six months from now, they're signing up
and they're doing a worse job. Nothing's changing
the product, but just the understanding of
how the product should work is different.
They might be less tech savvy. On a scale
of an early adopter versus late majority,
they might be closer to the late majority. And so
we saw this at Instagram. We always knew working
on our registration flow, and at one point we were
converting at some insanely high percent, and then
three months later it would go down by 15%, not
because anything was broken, but just because we'd
broken into new markets. You bring on people in
India or you bring on people in the Philippines,
and their understanding of how it works, the
phones they use, et cetera are all different.
So really, the core of their adjacent news was
a few things. One is like you have to understand
who's using your product today and why. And when
you're growing at some really strong pace, 30, 40,
50% or more per year, you've got to be on top
of who you believe the next user is and why.
And then you also have to be the adjacent
exactly, use the product like them and see
how it's working, what's broken with it. And so at
an Instacart, the adjacent user, the original user
might've been like an office admin who is going to
buy this thing every week because of during happy
hours and team staff. But then the next adjacent
user might've been the mom of three or four or the
dad of three or four who's home with the kids
and they need to depend on Instacart, versus
later on it might be they're a single person
in New York who does this out of convenience.
But what they're optimizing for, how they use
the product all changes, and the functionality
and the abilities are fundamentally different.
So you have to be them, you have to watch how
they use the product, you have to talk to them,
and then have to visit them and literally see
what they're doing in real time in order to make
sure that you're enabling the right jobs for them.
I love just the visualization of the
adjacent user. Basically your growth is
going to come from non-existing users. It's
the users right outside that circle of...
That's right.
... pre-users are today, and you need
to think about what do they need that
existing users maybe don't need. You said
that this is most powerful for hypergrowth
companies. Is this something you think people
like all companies should be thinking about
or is it a lot less important if
you're not a hypergrowth business?
So it's a great question. I think it's essential.
It's mandatory for hypergrowth. I think it's very
helpful if you have a product or a company
that is not growing what you want it to be.
And so you are focused on capturing more share of
wallet instead of expanding your audience. And so
sometimes you can imagine a cosmetics company,
for example, that's like digitally enabled. You
can imagine that they've hit a ceiling in terms of
the growth of their users, and they're really just
trying to get people to buy more product, but
maybe the people who want to use their product
are missing something from your current product.
Maybe you're missing different skin tone shades,
or maybe you're missing certain types of tools.
So really talking to who is just outside of your
current user base, who's coming to your
product and looking around and not buying
and understanding what are their needs and
figuring out how do you enable for them,
how do you build the right experience for them
in order to become adopters of your product?
So what I'm hearing is spend some understand
work to figure out who your potential users are,
That's right.
... and then use the product as them and see what
is missing. I imagine user research goes into
this. You're not actually going to understand
necessarily all the things they need. So it's
probably fine folks in that cohort and
see how they use the product. Awesome.
Yeah.
The question I had on my mind as you're talking,
you've come into so many companies and helped
them with growth. Where do you find most of the
opportunities often lie? Is it like onboarding,
activation? Is there a trend like
that you're like, "Here's probably
there's going to be opportunity
here," or is it super mixed bag?
Usually it's somewhere in the onboarding to
habit-building experience. What does it take
for someone to actually understand the value,
that first moment, that first aha moment in
the product? And a lot of teams, it's shocking
how many teams don't really understand what that
moment is for them. And then also how do you
get them to build habit around the product.
Oftentimes, a lot of people equate growth to top
of funnel, and that is also critical. I think
having the right top of funnel motion is really
critical and building on that. So I think there's
one part of, it's like once you have the right
top of funnel motion to get people to come in,
how do you help to make sure of the defining
value and the building habit and their routine?
Because that's the thing that helps you to
compound over time. If you're bringing a lot
of people but they're not staying around,
then you just have a leaky bucket and it
doesn't matter how big your top funnel is.
So making sure that that first-month and
two-month, three-month experience is great.
And then the other part is really figuring
out how do you build compounding growth loops
where it's not just one way of acquiring people,
but you're building two and three and four ways
that layer onto each other that help you to really
supercharge your engine of acquiring people.
So at Instagram, if you kind of look at where
Instagram is and how I [inaudible 01:10:28]
and grew, there's a lot that goes into it,
but if you actually unpack the top of funnel for
what worked at Instagram, there's certainly a
component of it, which was our core component,
which was invitations, where people inviting
you and making sure that those invitations
work and they work well and that people,
their friends are coming on, you get notified.
But another part that goes unspoken,
still critical to this day was the celebrity
partnerships was critical, because basically
they had this wonderful partnerships team that
basically took Instagram and taught celebrities
how to use it, how to make it work for them, how
to tell their own story and be their own brand,
and that was a critical growth funnel because with
that, you had the ability for them to create these
celebrities and celebrity creators to set the
norm for how the platform gets used, but they
also were getting picked up by the news and
the media for all the stuff that's happening
in the celebrity world, which then added
onto this other growth level, which was SEO.
And so every time a news article came out, they
would link to the creators or the celebrities
Instagram account or that particular post. And
so you have this whole SEO engine that worked.
And the SEO engine was because you have
both web, which we launched at Instagram,
which created the canonical SEO tables, and then
you had all of these inbound links from these
celebrity sites and news media, but then what you
also had is you had embeds for Instagram and all
of these different sites, like a news article,
whatever, the posts, Lenny's podcast, Instagram
account, and those embeds help with SEO juice.
And so you have not just the invites,
but now you have the celebrities, now you have
the SEO component. And then we would do a bunch
of paid media on top of that using a lot of those
signals. And then we have our own content. And so
you would have all of these different growth
engines compounding each other. So every time
the invitations got better, every time we've got
more celebrities, every time SEO gets better,
it's like magnifying the top of funnel, and
at the bottom of the funnel or mid-funnel,
making sure that people are retaining and getting
value and staying around over the long term.
That is so interesting. I had no idea this
was such a core part of the early growth
strategy. Everyone's always talking
about reality and word of mouth,
all these things. And you're saying partnerships
was a key part of the early growth strategy.
Huge. It's huge.
That's so funny. Never something people talk about
in growth, this partnership. It's always is like,
"Oh, there's a couple of companies that
really had success from partnerships in
BD." How early was this a big part of the
strategy? How early in the history of,
I mean the partnerships team was there before
I joined. It was a very savvy and astute thing
that Kevin and Mikey set up. The partnerships team
drove a lot of the word of mouth around Instagram,
but it was the partnership's work in combination
with the product work that actually helped to
allow a lot of that to land. It was our ability
to think outside the box and understand that we
needed to have a web presence because it was
critical for international growth and it also
helped with SEO. And so the idea of launching web
really drove and actually increased Instagram's
growth by 10% the minute we launched it. And
it was something that George Wang, who was
there before me, had the idea around. It wasn't
really something that Kevin and Mikey believed
in initially, but we had to prove to them that
it was really impactful and one should launch.
Then they understood why it was impactful
and all of the effect of it. But web was
really critical for driving so much SEO, which
helped support a lot of the celebrity work and
the partnerships work, because now every time
creator or celebrity did something on Instagram,
every news media article picked it up and it
just helped to drive searches in Google searches,
which helped to make Instagram
part of the cultural zeitgeist.
This is so interesting, because everyone
imagines Instagram, virality, word of mouth,
like SEO and partnerships sounds like a
core part of Instagram's early growth,
which I don't think anyone ever talks about.
No, that's huge.
Wow.
I mean it was part of Facebook's growth too,
but I think a little bit differently. It's not
as much partnership, but when you Google
someone now, you Google someone's name,
oftentimes, Instagram is one of the first five
things that comes up for the average person,
Yeah, right.
... now, by design.
LinkedIn, Instagram, Twitter.
That's right.
Do you ever see the video of Alex Jiu talking
about TikTok's growth strategy of this whole...
He had this metaphor, and he was trying to
grow off of Instagram, so his metaphor was
Instagram is like you're in Europe and you're
killing it. If you're in Europe and you're king,
you don't ever want to go to America. There's
no reason for you to give it up. And America
is TikTok in this case. He's like, "How do we
convince people to come to America and try moving
everything there?" He's like, "We need to go after
the people that are not doing well in Europe, who
want to be the king, and we're going to help you
become that king in America, or the President."
So he used the adjacent... Used that theory
on us, basically, is what you're saying.
That's right. He did. Drink up your shake.
Yeah.
Yeah. And I think the reason that strategy
worked differently is there was already a place,
so they couldn't execute what you did because
there's already celebrities already there,
and it's not like, "Come here." There's
no point. I already have a huge following.
So you make your own celebrities.
Make your own celebrities. Exactly. And
they went after the B-list, C-list people.
So it's interesting that people
look at Instagram, like, cool,
we're going to do partnerships, SEO.
But I think it's important to realize
things change when the market is a different
dynamic. You can't just do the same thing.
That's right.
It won't work as well. Is there anything
else from the Instagram early days that
maybe people wouldn't know or would be
interesting to share? Because you were
there quite early, and now it's maybe the
most thriving social network in the world.
One thing that's actually, I think, interesting,
as an interesting story that doesn't get talked
about a lot is I think the early Instagram was
built where... it was built in a way where every
follow was created equal. And what I mean by that
is if I followed you, Lenny, or if I followed Kim
Kardashian, I followed Selena Gomez, all follows
were treated like they were equally important. And
this is actually a really important fact. It was
a really important factor for a couple of reasons.
One, early celebrities who were adopting Instagram
obviously benefited from that, because a celebrity
is going to get a follow before an average person
does. It doesn't mean that their followers weren't
meaningful. It's just that when you have a
machine learning that's just optimized for a
click through a follow, then that matters.
But what ended up happening is we ended
up looking at the data, and I can't take
credit for this. My colleague at the time,
Rob Andrews, had identified this. He was the head
of growth marketing. He was a peer of mine that
basically, this is 2016-ish days, the average
person would come on Instagram and retain,
but then leave after 7, 8, 9 months. We'd
see a flattening in a retention curve,
but then we would see it dip again, which was very
weird. And we're like, why is this happening? And
it turned out that what was happening anecdotally
is that people were revving up Instagram,
following a bunch of people, following a lot of
celebrities, actually, because the celebrities
were being shown, and then when they actually
went to make their first post, a few months later-
... being shown. And then when they actually
went to make their first post a few months later,
none of their friends were following them. And
so there was posting into an echo chamber and
anecdotally people would stop using the product
because they felt bad. We hypothesized that no
one was liking or following or commenting on
their posts. And so we had to do this thing.
We called it the connections pivot, right in like
2016 ... Actually, 2017, where we had to convince
Kevin and Mikey that it was actually not the right
thing to do to prioritize celebrities to everybody
because we were basically biting bite your nose
to spank your face, whatever that is, because the
regular person wasn't having a great experience.
And so it doesn't mean that we shouldn't recommend
celebrities, but Jeff recommended celebrities to
people who are already on there. They already have
their graph. And the most important thing to do is
actually get regular human-to-human connections in
the first whatever, when people first sign up so
that when you let me actually go make your first
post, your friends would see it and you would
be validated and you would feel like, okay,
this is a police for me. I have a community here.
And so that connection pivot was critical. It
changed ... Literally, angle-changed the retention
on Instagram. And so if you about Instagram's
growth, there was a TechCrunch article about
Instagram's growth at I think 2017, 2018 when we
were going 40, 50% year over year. And obviously,
there was a lot that went into that skyrocket.
People think that stories was the sole reason
why we grew and story brought us a lot of people,
but we literally, our attention doubled over the
course of a year and a half. If you could imagine,
imagine if your bank account, the interest rate
doubles every month, you know what I mean? It was
incredible. This shift in making sure that people
got connected with their friends early on changed
the way that people perceive the value. And so
a lot of the top-of-funnel work that we did,
a lot of the activation work that we did
really paid off in spades ultimately.
Wow. I'm curious, what's the most impactful thing
you've shipped/led to in terms
of impact and experiment launch?
At Instagram, we saw this big problem where people
were logging out and not being able to get back
into their account. It was crazy. Hundreds
of thousands of people a day could not get
back into their account. It was because ... And
when I say could not get back into the account,
I mean they literally would try and 28 days later,
we would never see them again. And we thought it
was a problem because they didn't remember where
their email was, which email they signed up with
or what their actual handle was or what their
password was. We were losing 10, 12 million people
a year from what we called account access churn.
So we worked on this problem and we had spent
a lot of time in South Asia and Southeast Asia
trying to understand how to grow the product. And
from that time we realized that it's important
actually for people to be able to log out.
We don't want to restrict people's ability to log
out because there are many people in the world
who don't want to use background data because
they're on prepaid phone plans or they don't
have a lot of money and they want to share their
phone with a sibling and so they log out. And so
it's really important. And so we don't want
to take away that behavior, but we did have
to do a better job of helping them get back in.
So we did two things. One was there used to be a
time, and you can probably find it on Google if
you did an archive search where if you wanted to
log into your Instagram account, there would be a
tab for your email and then there would be a tab
for your handle. And we didn't really make it easy
for you to log in with your phone number either.
You had to get to the right tab and the right
place to get the right thing. And so we did this
omnibox experience where it was just like email,
phone handle, put it all in one place and we made
it super simple for you. And the second time,
if you tried it twice and it didn't work, if we
knew that you were on a trusted device, we would
just send you a text message and say, Hey, are you
trying to log in? That solved half the problem.
And then the other half, what we did,
and this still exists today on Instagram.
When you log out we say, Hey Lenny,
it looks like you're going to log out, do you
want us to save your credentials on your advice
so you don't have to worry about your password?
And then we later added an ability to have a
password. And that's all basically the other half.
And so just being really thoughtful around what is
actually the core job that people are trying to
do because a bad experience would've been like,
Hey, let's make it really hard for people
to walk out. And then how do we ... One or
two experiments really help people to get
back into the experience. And so what was
interesting was that we were able to solve this
... And this actually helped drive public 15,
20 million extra month active users a year, but
what was also super interesting was that it helped
us to realize that getting people back into their
account more drove more account content creation
on incident in ways that we didn't expect. And
so because we were getting people back into the
account, people getting into the second account
and getting into the third account and they were
going into their finsta account and creating
content more. And so that actually led to
the creation of a multiple accounts team,
which is what has made it easy for you to
navigate between accounts on Instagram today.
And so that was understandable actually coming
to life. It was, Hey, we're going to do the
understand work to figure out how to solve
account access issues and we're going to solve
it. And solving it, when we looked at the data,
we're like, Hey, why is all this account, why
is all this content creation happening? That
was not what we were expecting and where is it
happening? And it was happening from second and
third accounts. And so that made us realize
that oh, people were not only getting locked
out of their first accounts, but they were
actually creating a lot on the second and
third accounts. How can we make it easy for them
to get and navigate between their first account,
whether it's your account and a business account
or your account and [inaudible 01:24:19] account
or a bakery account, you know what I mean?
And so that created a multiple accounts team,
which I ended up owning and that ended up
even becoming a bigger effort after I left.
So that's an example of understand work, solve
a real problem, real-solve and solving massive
solution, massive impact, creating new data that
you didn't expect that drives new understand work,
which creates a whole new team to allow
you to move around your Instagram account
more seamlessly. And you can see this now
when you go to post, you can decide, okay,
I want to post as Lenny, I want to post as this
other thing, or when I want to write a story, you
can change anywhere. And that was all an effort
that originally came out of this realization.
I love how many of these huge impact
stories are just such straightforward,
simple things like just let people log in more
easily, help them log out more effectively,
fine, show them their friends versus celebrities.
So many of these stories are often just really
simple ideas that lead to such profound change.
The log-out example is interesting. At Airbnb,
we found the log-out was actually causing a
lot of churn also, but they went ... Initially,
they went with a simple solution of just extend
the session, log-out link instead of a week,
make it two weeks or three weeks or four weeks.
You pointed out with Instagram, people actually
wanted to log out. They're like, let's leave that
alone. Start with making it easier to log back in.
That's right.
Amazing. Man, you're so full of amazing
stories. I'm curious with Facebook,
maybe just as I wrap up here, is there
anything there? Because you were an early
growth PM at Facebook. You worked a lot on
friends and helping people discover their
friends. Is there anything in there
that would be interesting to share?
In my time, so I joined Instagram or
Facebook in 2014 and I was responsible for
people recommendations globally. And at the time,
Facebook was at scale and big and dominated North
America. And so really the focus area at the time
was South Asia and Southeast Asia. And we noticed
a lot of really interesting things, especially in
India. Facebook seemed to be broken from a people
graph perspective. The data was telling us people
didn't have as many friends in common. In the US,
it might've been on just making up a number.
On average, we saw 22 friends in common when
you make a friendship connection. But in
India, it was like seven, right? And then
there was a lot of friending and messaging
or friending and unfriending. We're like,
what's going on here? So we had some hypotheses
from the data, we ran a bunch of tests. Nothing
seemed to work and be a breakthrough.
So actually, at that time, I had to
propose and they agreed to do this. We needed to
do understand work. So we were literally on the
ground in India every three months took a team
of engineers with me. I'm talking like we're
in Delhi in people's homes and Mumbai, and
we went to go investigate what was going on,
watch people make friends, watch them use people
you may know and really understand what was
happening and see what was going on because we
felt like there was context that we were missing.
There was a lot of things that we learned. It
was mind-blowing. But one of the most interesting
things, Lenny, was that we watched people
try to make friends and we said, "Hey wait,
that's their profile page. Why aren't you looking
at it?" And they would say, "Well, that doesn't
have any relevant information for me, so I need to
go look in the pictures." They're like, "Well, why
doesn't the profile page have relevant information
for you? That's where the information's supposed
to be." And they're like, "Listen, this guy's
named Amit Kumar. I have 10 friends named Amit
Kumar. What is this page going to tell me?"
And they would scroll down, they'd be like,
"All of these fields are not relevant to me." And
so you look at it, Facebook at the time, it was
very Western-centric. It's probably still is, it
was like name, it was like school you went to,
job title, affiliations, that kind of stuff.
That's all Western paradigms. Some of these
people are like, my friends sell jeans at a
market. None of this is relevant. You don't
even know the name of the school. Sometimes it
might be a number or something. And so all of
the descriptors that we take for granted were
not relevant and the names were very common.
This was really illuminating. So what they
would do is go look at pictures and say,
is this my friend's car or is this my friend's
... Can I see my friend's animal and what's
available? And it was interesting because
the understand work, at least the more
realization. So we went back to Menlo Park
with the data, turned out ... We said, okay,
let's look at the data in a different way.
What are the most common names on Facebook?
And we looked at, and the top 10 common names
are Indian names. And the most common name was
Amit Kumar. And there was like 250,000 people a
month who used Amit Kumar who were real people.
So imagine you're in Bangalore and you're trying
to find your buddy named Amit Kumar. It's probably
5,000 that we could possibly recommend. So super
interesting was like the cultural context was so
different. So we had to get creative, find
creative ways to figure out how to solve it.
The power of understand work shines again. We
have a recurring segment on this podcast called
Fail Corner where ask guests to share a time they
failed in their career and what they learned from
that experience because a lot of people look
at your career and your story and just like,
holy shit, what a journey. I will never
be able to achieve this. Is there a time
when things didn't go well and something
that you took away from that experience?
Probably for me, I think my time at Instacart
was probably not my best time. I think I went
to Instacart with a vision of what I felt
the product could be or should be. And it was
I think a big story that I deeply believed, but
I was not, I think aware or in tune with what the
DNA of the company was at the time, which was
it was like a company that was really great at
operations because that was the core of what
they did. And they were really building out
a lot of their product experience and a lot of
what the new function. And so I think what they
needed at the time was a much more tactical
in the weeds, get your hands dirty, do, do,
do because they hadn't really seen that before.
And what I wanted to deliver in that experience
was more building the right systems, the right
people, the right processes so that we can figure
out how to institutionalize the work.
And I think for me that was probably
my biggest oversight is that I think
they needed more tactical and I was
more ... I don't want to say in the clouds, but
more thinking about where do we want to go with
the experience that we need to build versus
let me get deep in the funnel data. It felt
like it became loggerheads where I didn't
feel like I was probably either delivering
what they wanted or being supported in
the way that I wanted to be supported.
Is the lesson there to spend more time
and understand work before you take a
job to make sure you're aligned
with what they're looking for?
That is actually the lesson. And I think it's
part of that is it's doing that. One of my
takeaways is do that not only with the people
there but with the people who've left it to,
but the people who've left the company will give
you a perspective that is raw and different and
much more I think aligned with what you want
to hear. And it may or may not be the same,
but I think the people ... This isn't specific
to Instacart. Whenever you talk to people who
are at the company, they're always try to
tell you the best version of the company.
The people who left will tell you what the
worst version or their version and it's
on you to triangulate that
information, but you need both sides.
Love that lesson. Bangaly, is there
anything else that you want to share
or leave listeners with before we get
to our very exciting lightning round?
No, I think we've got a lot.
We have. With that, we've reached
our very exciting lightning round.
I've got six questions for you. Are you ready?
I am ready to go.
First question, what are two or three books
that you've recommended most to other people?
Few I've recommended most of them are
Over My Shoulder, actually Range by
David Epstein. I think are really critical PM
work really being able to be a master of a lot
of different things or somewhat deep in a lot
of different things. Deep Work, Cal Newport,
kind of clearing space to be focused and do
the things thinking about the most important
work in a deep and undisturbed way. And
then Start At The End by Matt Waller,
who's a behavioral scientist buddy
of mine. Really thoughtful book,
helps you really think about what you're
building, but in a way that's more holistic.
Do you have a favorite interview question that you
like to ask candidates when
you're interviewing them?
I've got a relatively new one that I love.
This works exceptionally well I believe
for more senior hires, whether they're
like group product managers, directors,
or even kind of senior ICs. I go through and
I think about what are the four, usually five
skills that are really critical for someone to
have in this job. And I think about them myself
and I think about the archetypes of what is the
ratio I want of these? But then I ask them, I say,
Hey, take out a piece of paper or take out your
laptop. I'm going to give you five skills and I
want you to stack-rank them for me. One to five.
So one being the one you're strongest at and five
being the one you're relatively weakest at.
So it's way better than saying give me your
strengths and weaknesses. It also forces them
to contextualize it against the skills that
you're looking for, but it also helps you have
a meaningful conversation around how they think
about themselves and their self-awareness and to
what extent they're ranking these skills based on
the context they're in versus their own ability.
Sometimes you rank something a five because
something you would just weak at because you
haven't had to do because there's a strong
function at that company. And so when
they stack-rank it and then people are
like ... I've asked this probably four or five
times on a recent role. I hire people like, Ooh,
this is really hard. But really good question.
I usually will dig into what is number two and
what's number four and number five, and why? And
it really helps me to one, calibrate am I looking
for the right person? And two, are their skills
actually a match for what we need at this time?
I love when I hear a question I've never
heard before. That is genius. Next question,
do you have a favorite product you've
recently discovered that you really like?
I think one that I enjoy quite a lot ...
Actually, it's really kind of ... It's
really simple, but amazing is this app called
Flighty. You heard of it? F-L-I-G-H-T-Y.
No.
It is a travel app and it manages all of
your flight itineraries and your friends'
itineraries. But the reason why I love it is it
goes two or three clicks deeper than the average
travel app or your airline app and it tells
you when your inbound plane is running late,
it helps you to understand where the gates on.
My wife was just in Madrid last week. And she
texted me saying, "Hey, I'm at the airport but
no gate is announced." I looked at Flighty,
I'm like, "Your gate is E67. It's actually been
assigned but it hasn't been announced." And this
happens a lot in Europe. You'll be there and they
won't tell you the gate until an hour beforehand.
So it gives you so much information right
before. It's actually publicly announced,
which is really helpful, especially if
you really need to be somewhere because
oftentimes I know if my plane's going to be late
and if I need to rebook before anyone else does,
which helps you, gives you a better chance
of getting somewhere. Or I will be able to
get to a gate, I get to SFO and it
might not be on the board at SFO,
but I know exactly where it gave you this. So
really a great app. Can't say enough about it.
I'm downloading it right now.
It's got a bazillion reviews,
five stars. Thank you for the
recommendation. Incredibly useful.
Of course.
I'm trying out a new question. You've
joined a bunch of different companies.
What's one thing that you've done in the first
90 days at the job that has made a big impact?
I go and I sit in team meetings and see how they
operate. I just listen. I talk to not only the PMs
but the content designer and everyone, and I try
to get to know them by both name and story. And
what I mean by that, it's like oftentimes
people, execs come in and they're like,
what are we doing? What are we prioritizing?
Why does it matter? And they don't really take
the time to actually learn who the people are,
what the story is, what they care about, what
they're passionate about, both professionally and
personally and really try to understand how the
team is working from that person's perspective.
And what I find is actually when I do that,
people are way more willing to hear ...
When it is time for me to share my thoughts,
they're way more invested because
they believe I'm invested in that.
I love that. Two more questions. Do you have
a favorite life motto that you really like
and find useful and often share with
friends or family in work or in life?
I'm not big on mottos. There's one that I've
actually been repeating. I don't remember. I
got it done ... It might have been like
Adam Grant or someone on Instagram,
but it was ... It's one, I said it to
a colleague of mine, he's like, "Wow,
that really hit differently." I think it goes
something like this. People and teams don't
really reach ... They don't actually reach their
goals. They fall to the level of their systems.
And that to me was really powerful because I
struggle a lot with just being balanced in life,
working out the way I want to and getting the
right rest and making sure that I'm spending
time in all the right places. And that's
really like ... It's a goal of mine. But
the problem is that I don't ... My system
for that specifically, I tend to ... I'm
not rigorous with it is when I need to be.
But on the other hand, at work, I'm very
rigorous in the systems and processes. So really
that saying to me really hits because it is both
applicable to your life and how you want to live
your life but also how you want to run your teams.
Final question. You mentioned that you were a dean
at a school, a boarding school. Is there something
that you take away from that experience that's
going to sticks with you? I know you mentioned
one thing about treat PM's skills are similar
to teacher skills. There anything else there?
Actually, so I was a dean of a boarding school in
Switzerland, which was actually one of the most
fun and interesting times of my life. It was
an American school in Switzerland just outside
of Lugano, Switzerland, the Italian-speaking
section. I learned a lot about myself during
the time. I learned a lot about just relationships
and people. I actually had a call with one of my
old students this morning. She's like in her
thirties now. This was like 20 years ago. So
I still keep in touch with them. And I think
that's the comment I made about knowing people
by name and story matters a lot. It says a
lot that 20 years later I'm still talking to
some of these students who are their own
adults running their own businesses. But
also I think the human challenges and human
connection, human problems, very universal.
This was a really interesting place when you
had kids coming from a variety of different
walks of life, some who lived in Azerbaijan or
Kosovo and felt like ... The families felt like
they couldn't be safe there, so they wanted to
send the kids somewhere else. So some kids whose
parents worked at the US Embassy and just were
kind of there for a little bit of time. And what
I found to be true is that just spending time
with people and understanding their own story
and family life really led to a lot of shared
interests and passions. And it helped really me
to see that the world can be very similar in so
many ways and it is very much reflected to me in
my day-to-day life in tech because as you know in
the Bay Area, there's so many people who come from
so many walks of life who end up in this journey
building these products and companies and just
help me to value so many different voices.
If you want to build world-class products,
if you want to build product that can scale
around the world, if you want to build product
that's be hypergrowth, you have to be inclusive
of so many voices. And so you have to build that
skill to be able to acknowledge and learn from
and to live in tension with different voices.
That is beautiful. I love that
we're ending there. Bangaly,
I feel like we've done a lot of understand work
and I think we've helped a lot of people with a
lot of things we talked about so much. Two
final questions. Where can folks find you
online if they want to follow what you're up
to, and how can listeners be useful to you?
For as much as I've worked at social
companies, I actually don't use my
social products that much. I'm on Instagram.
If you look @iambangaly, I-A-M-B-A-N-G-A-L-Y,
Google that. All of my socials handles all have
the same kind of link including LinkedIn. So
hit me up whenever. And then what can people do
useful for me? I don't know. I don't have a short
list. I would say I love to hear people's
stories. I love to give advice. Obviously,
my time is a little bit limited occasionally,
but I think if people can share with me things
that they're learning or things that they
see in the market, or if they have questions,
I always love to hear it. And so I think for
me, just hearing other people's stories and
learning what other people are doing
is probably the most rewarding for me.
Bangaly, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you. This is amazing. I
really appreciate you, Lenny.
Bye, everyone. Thank you so much for
listening. If you found this valuable,
you can subscribe to the show on Apple
Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You
can find all past episodes or learn more
about the show at lennyspodcast.
com. See you in the next episode.