The Sean Ellis test, such a seemingly simple idea
that has had such a profound
impact on the startup world.
The question is, how would you feel if
you could no longer use this product?
Once you got a high enough percentage of
users saying they'd be very disappointed,
most of those products did pretty well. If you
felt too low, those products tended to suffer.
Say someone is listening and
they're like, "Okay. Man,
I'm getting like 10%. I don't know what
to do." What do you find often works?
Just ignore the people who say they'd be
somewhat disappointed. They're telling
you it's a nice to have. If you start paying
attention to what your somewhat disappointed
users are telling you and then you start tweaking
onboarding and product based on their feedback,
maybe you're going to dilute
it for your must have users.
Moving retention often is really hard, but I guess
it sounds like there's often something you can do.
It's usually much more function of onboarding
to the right user experience than it is about
the kind of the tactical things that
people try to do to improve retention.
What are like three or four things that you think
people should definitely try
to help improve activation?
In my experience-
Today, my guest is Sean Ellis. Sean is one of
the earliest and most influential thinkers and
operators in the world of growth. He coined
the term growth hacking, invented the ICE
prioritization framework, was one of the earliest
people to use freemium as a growth strategy,
and maybe most famously developed the Sean Ellis
test to help you understand if you have product
market fit, which a large percentage of founders
use today and profoundly impacted the way startups
are built. Over the course of his career, Sean
was head of growth at Dropbox and Eventbrite,
helped companies like Microsoft and Newbank
refine their growth strategy, was on the
founding team of LogMeIn, which eventually sold
for over $4 billion, and he's the author of one
of the most popular growth books of all time
called Hacking Growth. In our conversation,
we dive deep into two topics. One, how to know
if you've got product market fit and what to do
if you don't, and two, how to figure out how
to grow once you've found product market fit.
If you're in the early stages of a new
product wrangling with product market fit
or trying to figure out how to jumpstart or
further accelerate growth for your product,
this episode is for you. If you enjoy
this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting
app or YouTube. It's the best way to avoid
missing feature episodes and it helps the podcast
tremendously. With that, I bring you Sean Ellis.
Sean, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Thanks, Lenny. I'm super
excited to be on with you.
There's so much that I want to talk about.
There's so many directions we can go,
but to keep it focused, I want to spend
time on two areas. I want to talk about
how to know if you have product market
fit and what to do once you have product
market fit in terms of figuring out how
to grow. I know these things are very
linked. I know you spent a lot of time
on these things. How does this feel?
Sounds perfect. Yeah, let's do it.
Okay. Okay, amazing. Let's talk about,
first of all, the Sean Ellis test,
slash something people call
sometimes the product fit test.
Such a seemingly simple idea that has had such a
profound impact on the startup world. I've never
actually seen you talk about the history of this
thing, how you came up with these questions, how
you came up 40%, the whole journey of this thing.
So let's talk about this. But first of all, can
you just tell people what is the Sean Ellis test
for folks that aren't exactly familiar with this?
It's a simple question that helps you figure out,
does anyone consider your product a must-have,
or ideally, who and how many people consider it,
but ultimately it's about trying to figure out is
your product a must-have, which could be equated
to having product market fit. And so the question
is, how would you feel if you could no longer
use this product? And I give them the choice,
very disappointed, somewhat disappointed,
or even not disappointed or not applicable,
I've already stopped using the product. And what
I'm trying to find are those people who say,
"I would be very disappointed if I could
no longer use this product," then that's a
really powerful vein to dig
into when you discover that
you actually have some people who would
give a crap if your product disappears.
This episode is brought to you by Gamma,
an entirely new way to present your ideas
powered by AI. If you hate designing slides and
dread that feeling of staring at a blank slide,
Gamma is here to help. Just upload your PRD
and turn it into a beautiful ready-to-present
presentation in seconds. Gamma works with
all types of formats from Google Docs,
PDFs, to PowerPoint. You can even drop in a
link to your favorite Lenny's newsletter post
and turn it into a presentation for your team.
Gamma has become one of the fastest growing AI
web products in the world, adding 20 million
new users just this past year and is setting
its sights on becoming the modern alternative to
PowerPoint. Whether you have design skills or not,
Gamma can save you hours of time synthesizing
your ideas and shaping your content. Visit
gamma.app and use promo code LENNY to get a
free month of Gamma Pro. That's G-A-M-M-A, .app.
Let me tell you about CommandBar. If you're
like me and most users I've built product for,
you probably find those little in-product
pop-ups really annoying. "Want to take a
tour? Check out this new feature." And these
pop-ups are becoming less and less effective
since most users don't read what they say. They
just want to close them as soon as possible. But
every product builder knows that users need help
to learn the ins and outs of your product. We
use so many products every day and we can't
possibly know the ins and outs of everyone.
CommandBar is an AI-powered toolkit for product,
growth, marketing and customer teams to help users
get the most out of your product without annoying
them. They use AI to get closer to user intent,
so they have search and chat products that
users describe what they're trying to do
in their own words and then see personalized
results like customer walkthroughs or actions.
And they do pop-ups too, but their nudges are
based on in-product like confusion or intent
classification, which makes them much less
annoying and much more impactful. This works
for web apps, mobile apps, and websites. And they
work with industry-leading companies like Gusto,
Freshworks, HashiCorp and LaunchDarkly. Over
15 million end-users have interacted with
CommandBar. To try out CommandBar, you can
sign up at commandbar.com/LENNY and you can
unlock an extra 1,000 AI responses per month
for any plan. That's commandbar.com/LENNY.
And the idea is that if you, 40% or more
of people, say they'd be very disappointed
if they can no longer use the product,
you essentially have product market fit.
I would say it's a leading indicator of product
market fit. The lightning indicator is, do they
actually keep using it? So probably retention
cohorts are more accurate, but the problem is,
like your time at Airbnb, how long do you have
to look at a retention cohort before you know
that you've actually long-term retained someone?
And so with this question, you can kind of find
out day one, you don't need a good analytics
system in place to be able to see if product
market fit exists. And so yeah, the 40% was not
something I originally had in there. Originally,
I was trying to have just a filter so that I was
not treating all feedback from customers the same,
but I was trying to find feedback from customers
who actually really cared about the product.
And then was over time, at the time I was
working for a couple of YC-backed companies,
and so those companies were all pretty connected,
and so I would share the question with a lot of
other startups in Silicon Valley. And so over
time, I started to see there was a pattern that
once you got a high enough percentage of
users saying they'd be very disappointed,
most of those very disappointed without
the product, most of those products did
pretty well. And then if you felt too
low, those products tended to suffer.
Okay, there's two things I want to
definitely follow up on here. The
first is such an important point that you made
at the beginning when I introduced this test
that you described it as a leading indicator
of product market fit and actually retention,
people actually using your product, the
product actually being used by the market
is the actual ultimate test. So the idea
here is this is a good way to get a sense of,
before you actually have data, are we headed
in a good direction? Could you speak more
about that, of like, when to use this and when
it's most useful in best [inaudible 00:08:34]?
Yeah. I mean, so for me in particular,
when I come into a company, my goal is
to help them grow. And so I don't want to put
myself in a situation where I'm going to fail
because no one actually cares about the
product. And so it can really be asked
at a company of any stage. It's helpful
to understand who your must have users
are. But essentially once you have even an
MVP, like a very first MVP on the product,
you can still get some useful feedback about
the product if it's resonating with anyone.
So I actually had a company where I had
committed to work with them. It was right
after I left Dropbox and I committed to work with
these guys for six months to help them grow. I
ran the question and it came back at only 7% of
users saying they'd be very disappointed without
the product. And so I'm like, "I have six months
to help them grow and they're only at 7% right
now. It might take six months to get the 40%. Am
I doing them a disservice by being in a growth
role and being on payroll during this period
of time?" But fortunately with the signal and
the information we got from the initial survey,
we were able to get them at 40% in two weeks.
Wow. What did you do there just as a case study?
Yeah. Yeah. So the company called
Lookout, it's a mobile security company,
and now most of the things in Lookout are built
into iPhones and Androids. But at that time,
the product had everything from backup my data to
find my lost phone to protecting your phone with
a firewall and antivirus. And so when we ran this
initial survey, I dug into the 7% who said they'd
be very disappointed without the product and found
that most of that 7% were focused on the antivirus
functionality. So they were like, they know they
need to protect their computer from viruses,
smartphones were becoming more like computers, so
it just made a lot of sense for them that they'd
need to protect their phone. And interesting,
at the time, I think there was only one kind of
phone virus that had ever even happened, but
it was a pretty easy mental leap for people.
And so now we knew, okay, it's antivirus that
people really valued. And so step one was just
reposition the product on antivirus. So that
kind of creates a filter. So anyone who now is
coming in to sign up for the product who doesn't
care about antivirus is not going to convert, and
those who are excited about antivirus are going to
convert. We already know from the initial survey
that people value that after they convert. So by
setting the right expectations around it up front,
you're going to bring people in with the right
expectations. But then the second thing that we
did was we streamlined onboarding so that the
first thing that they did after signing up for
the product was to set up the antivirus and then
get a message "you're now protected from viruses."
And so it's really the combination of those
two things. It's set the right expectations
and then speed to value. And so the next cohort
of people that we surveyed were at 40% saying
they'd be very disappointed without the product.
So that literally took two weeks to make those
changes. Six months later, it was 60% on the
score. And then I think they hit the billion
dollar valuation four or five years later on
ultimately being one of the early unicorns.
And interestingly, as all of those things were
built into mobile phones now, they've completely
changed the business, but they continue to do
really well, but they've continued to iterate
the business. I think that having that kind of
finger on the pulse early in the business was
important to build the muscle in the business
to be really responsive as the market changed.
Sean, this is already amazing. There's
just a fractal of topics I want to
explore from this very short conversation
already. So the first is just follow this
thread of basically you're sharing kind of a
growth strategy that I imagine you execute,
is look for the percentage of people that would
be very disappointed if your product went away,
see who they are, see what they're excited
about and lean into that both positioning-wise,
onboarding-wise, and probably also cut out stuff
from your product that they don't care about.
Yeah. And I was coming at it from a marketing
perspective initially. Over time, I position
myself more in a growth role with product
and marketing as areas I could influence.
But as a marketer, I probably didn't have a lot of
influence on a engineering founded company to say,
"Let's cut out stuff." So it made more sense
to say, "Let's just sequence the onboarding so
that we're highlighting this and onboarding
to this." That was a little easier to sell.
And just hearing that you can move this score
so quickly without even changing the product
substantially, I imagine what surprised a lot of
people when you think about moving retention often
is really hard. And maybe we talk about that, but
I guess it sounds like there's often something
you can do that's not very hard that might
significantly shift this product market fit test.
Right. And then that ultimately
moving retention is really hard,
but it's usually much more function of
onboarding to the right user experience
than it is about the tactical things that
people try to do to improve retention.
Okay. I want to put a pin on that and come back
to that because a really important topic. I'm
going to come back to, say someone
runs this survey and they get 40%,
what should they have in their mind of like,
"This is what this is telling me"? Because
I think a lot of people are like, "I got
product market fit. I got this. Let's go,
go, go." What's the best way to
think about what this tells you?
Yeah, I mean it tells you something really
important, which is, you haven't created
something that people don't care about. So
that's an important insight. But until you
deeply understand that product market fit, you
kind of don't have the tools to be able to grow
the business. So that's really the next step, is
to dig in and figure out who considers it a must
have, how are they using the product, what did
they use before, what problem are they solving.
One of my favorite questions is... So I tend to
have a lot of questions that I build off of that
I'm using that filter, trying to drill into the
users who say they'd be very disappointed without
the product, and one of my favorite questions
is, "What is the primary benefit that you get?"
And then I use that initially as an open-ended
question to kind of crowdsource different benefits
people are getting. But then I run another survey
where I turn it into a multiple choice question,
force them to pick one of four distinctive
benefit statements. And then the question
that follows on that next survey is,
"Why is that benefit important to you?"
And then I start to get really good context.
So I actually came up with this question when I
was working with an early YC company called Xobni,
which is inbox felt backwards. And when I ran that
question, basically the people who said they'd
be very disappointed without the product we're
focused on, "Xobni helps me find things faster in
my email." So it's great to know, okay, that's the
benefit. But when I asked, "Why is that benefit
important to you?" They said, "Oh, I'm drowning in
email." I kept seeing that statement as a written
statement. And so when I then was trying to figure
out how to acquire customers, when I tested
"drowning in email?", that set such a good hook.
That was the context that people were living in,
that they were really responsive to the message
of find things faster with Xobni and then a
description of what Xobni is. So I think when you
can really dig into the context of why that must
have benefit is important to people, you start
to get the ingredients to build that flywheel
that leads to long-term sustainable growth.
So what I'm hearing is whether you have
40%, whether you have 60% or even 7%,
the actual best use of this tool
is look at that percentage of
highly disappointed and see what they're
looking for, what they're excited about.
Start drilling in, start feeling back that onion-
Start drilling in.
... and just deeply understand them and make
sure that ultimately your product roadmap is
doubling down on the things that are important to
your must-have customers. Onboarding is bringing
new people to the right experience. Your
messaging is setting the right expectations,
your acquisition campaigns are targeting
people who actually have the need.
And so it's all about getting the right people
to the right experience. And then even your
engagement loop is about just reinforcing how to
get people to experience that benefit more often.
Awesome. And the 40% threshold, so
what you shared is you basically
emerged from just looking at tons of
startups doing the survey and finding
a pattern. How firm is that 40%? How
big of a deal? Is it 39 versus 41?
I don't think it's that firm. To me, I think the
real power is having some kind of target for the
team to be shooting for that basically says,
"We're not going to aggressively start to grow
until we hit this target." And I think that
as just a focusing piece is really important
because I think one of the biggest challenges
in an early stage startup is half the people
feel like we're years from having this product
ready to grow, and half the people are like,
"What are we waiting for?" Where if you can
actually get people on the same page of what does
product market fit look like for our business,
and it's at that point that we're going to.
Before I ever heard the term product market fit,
I remember the conversations back at LogMeIn in
the mid 2000s of kind of like, "When do we
step on the gas? What is the combination of
factors that need to be in place before we start
pouring fuel on the early fire?" And so yeah,
I think that kind of nail it then scale it.
It's probably been a term that's been around
for decades now, but it's all kind of pointing
to that same concept of product market fit.
How often have you seen false positives
with this test where someone gets 40% and
something is not right, they're actually far
from it? Or is it generally pretty accurate?
If you're having people say that they'd
be very disappointed without your product,
that's a really good sign. What I can tell
you is that not necessarily a false positive,
but what is driving people to say they'd be very
disappointed. One of my favorite books is Hooked
by Nir Eyal and he talks about in the kind of
engagement loop that your last step is investment.
And so I ran the survey on a business that I
thought was a fairly commoditized business.
Part of it I wanted to see, could I use the
same go-to-market approach on a later stage
company and use it to accelerate growth.
And so this was a business called webs.com.
They eventually got acquired by VistaPrint. But
they'd been pretty flat for the year before I went
in there. And then I started to use this approach
to try to dial in their growth engine. I ran the
survey thinking, "Yeah, you've had products like
Wix and Weebly that have come on to the market
since this more legacy website building product
has been around. I personally think they're a
little easier to use, they're a little better."
And so I didn't have high hopes when I ran the
survey, but it came back with one of the highest
scores I'd ever seen. And it was like 90% of the
people saying they'd be very disappointed
if they could no longer use the product.
Holy shit. I've never seen that.
And I was like, "How could that be possible?
This product is kind of a commoditized category.
I wouldn't even say it's one of the best."
And then when I want to dug into it again,
it comes back to that Nir Eyal Hooked model, is
that the investment people have made in building
that website, they put so much into that they know
exactly how to make the changes and the kind of
the CMS kind of side of things, they have spent
a lot of time just making it beautiful. And so
ultimately it was something that that was why
they were saying they'd be very disappointed.
But fast-forward when I initially went in,
still doing these things help the business
resume growth and have significant growth
over the next 12 months after we did these
things. So still the signal we got from why
people would be very disappointed without the
product was important and speed to value. All
the other things I think about in go-to-market
for an early stage product still were relevant,
but just I think they were a little stronger on
the percentage he'd be very disappointed.
Even Eventbrite when I was there when we
ran it was probably the second highest
I'd ever seen. But with event organizers,
if they've already set their event up on
that platform and they've sent it out to
their list and all those people are coming
in and they're managing their event, again,
they've invested a lot in the platform.
So sort of switching costs I think can
factor in there. So it's a function of both
switching costs and utility of the product.
So that's a question I wanted to ask is,
what's your guidance on when to ask this
question? What I'm hearing is, if you ask it
very far along the journey, when they're very
invested, you'll get a much higher score. Is
there any advice on the timing and the best
time to ask this question to your users?
What I recommend is a random sample of
people who've really used your product.
So they've gone in, they didn't just sign
up, but they went in and hopefully hit that
deviation moment. They've used it twice, two
plus times, and they've ideally used it, say,
within the last week or two weeks,
so they haven't churned yet. So if
it's a random sample of those people,
that's kind of the ideal time to ask it.
Got it. So basically it's people that
have activated whatever that means to
you and have been using it for a couple weeks?
Yeah.
Not people landing in your home page, not
people just signing up, not people months later.
Not people who've seen a demo of your product,
but it's people who actually have experienced the
product. But it's okay if you're hitting people
who've used it months later, but in that Lookout
example that I gave, if I'm testing people's
perception of the product after I made updates
to the onboarding, I'm going to only want to
survey people who went through the new onboarding.
Yep. In the experimental. Yeah. Okay.
So I asked people on Twitter what to
ask you. A lot of people had a lot
of awesome questions. I'm going to
sprinkle in a couple of these
questions throughout the chat.
Sure.
One came in from Shraaz Doshi,
a popular guest of the podcast.
One of the ones that I listened to recently.
Amazing. I think it's the second most
popular episode behind Brian Chesky.
Okay. So he had a question of just, "What
are the limitations of the score? When does
it break down? When should you not use it
if ever?" Is there anything of just like,
"Here's when it's not going to work for you"?
Yeah. I think one-off products would probably,
like, how would you feel if you could no
longer watch the movie you just watch? I
wouldn't care. Even when I run a workshop,
I don't run this as part of my survey after I do
a workshop because how would you feel if you could
no longer attend the workshop you just attended?
It doesn't make sense. So I'll ask an NPS question
as my filtering question so that I'm looking at
focusing in on feedback of people who love it,
also then through a separate lens, looking at
people maybe who would be my detractors. So I
think one-off products are probably not good
products to run the question on. There may
be other places as well that I'm not thinking
of right now, but that [inaudible 00:25:00].
It sounds like not many. What I'm hearing
is it's generally widely applicable.
Yeah, I think it is, at least from my perspective.
It's been really useful for me anyway.
Awesome. Okay. And then the follow-up question
from Shraaz is, and I kind of asked this,
but I'm curious if there's anything more
here, just, "Have you seen any instances of
startups over relying on the score prematurely
declaring product market fit when in reality
they haven't reached it yet? And just are there
any other caveats of like, 'Cool, I got 40%'?"
Is there anything else you should know, like,
" Okay. But maybe check this one thing"?
Yeah, I mean, I think to me it's kind
of like what really is the definition
of product market fit is the definition that
people who get through my crappy onboarding
and actually experience the product love
it. And if I'm able to retain those people,
that means I have product market fit.
Or, is fixing that crappy onboarding
part of getting to product market fit
as well? I think that's up for debate.
So to me, the hardest, I wouldn't obsess on
onboarding if I know those who kind of get
through the challenge of getting started with the
product still don't like the product then feels
like it's a core product issue or wrong people
using it in the wrong way issue. But once you
have that, then ultimately it doesn't mean that
you're ready to grow. When I focus on growth,
then customer acquisition is almost the last
step. Once I validate that it's a must have
for those early users, then I'm thinking about,
"Okay, how do I optimize speed to value? How do
I make sure that people have the right prompts to
come back and use the product at the right time so
that's kind of more of that engagement loop? How
do I get my existing users to bring in more users
if there's something that makes sense on that
end? Even how do I optimize my revenue model?"
Once all of those things are working well,
then I'll obsess on the customer acquisition
side. But customer acquisition is so hard that
if you're not really efficient at converting-
... customer acquisition is so hard that if
you're not really efficient at converting and
retaining and monetizing people, you're going to
really struggle on the customer acquisition side.
Yeah, cool. And we'll talk about
customer acquisition/growth.
Sure.
Another question I wanted to ask, and
a couple listeners asked, is the 40%.
I had Jag from Nubank on the podcast,
I think you may have worked with them,
and they use 50% as their threshold because
apparently Brazilians are very nice.
Yeah. Optimistic I think is what I said.
Yeah. I guess the question is
do you find instances where you
should increase that percentage? And
in B2B, is anything different? Do you
change the percentage in B2B? Any advice
there just when you adjust the threshold?
Yeah, I hadn't really thought too much on that.
Again, for me, generally I'm trying to just
figure out is this a product that can grow? So
if I got a 37%, am I going to be like, "Oh no,
this would be impossible?" Or if I had a 70%, does
that mean I'd say, "Oh yeah, I want to jump in and
work with this company?" It's more nuanced than
that. Obviously, if it's a 70%, but I have no idea
how I grow the business, I'm going to be stuck
there. But I do think he brought up a really good
point that, culturally, some people are going to
be more optimistic or pessimistic. Interestingly,
when I came up with the question, I used
to just use a normal satisfaction question.
When I was working at Xobni, I'm just an intensely
curious person anyway, so I'm just trying to dig
in and understand the customers, and so I've
always done lots of surveying. But at Xobni,
I was going to use my filter as a satisfaction
question, so how satisfied are you with this? I'm
very satisfied. I'm somewhat satisfied. And our
main customers were actually senior management,
and so I thought senior management's never
satisfied. I'm going to get always this super
lukewarm thing. How can I change this question to
give me a more real answer from these guys? Well,
if I flip it and say, "How would you feel if
you could no longer use this product?" I'll
probably get a more honest answer back
from them. And of course, they're very
disappointed if they can't get what they want.
And so initially it was just for the case of
Xobni, but then I went to Dropbox right after
Xobni and like, "Oh, I'll try the question again."
And the insights I got back were really useful.
And so each company I went to, I kept using the
question. I'm like, this works way better than
your typical satisfaction question. But initially,
it was more about thinking just senior management
to get a more honest answer out of them.
So that's the origin story right there?
Yeah.
Wow. That senior managers are just very
harsh and they don't need anything?
Yeah.
And you have to flip it. That is so
interesting. That question is such
a good reminder of how hard it is to
build anything people really would be
disappointed not to have. That's why
this works so well. People are like,
"I don't need this. Who cares?" That's
the core of this, is just that is hard.
Especially when I first moved to Silicon
Valley. The first 15 years of my career
were not in Silicon Valley, and so I was
in Eastern Europe and then New York and
then Boston. But you move to Silicon Valley
and you have people who get really excited
about technology for technology's sake.
And so just something being cool is like,
"Isn't it cool that we can actually do
this?" drives a lot of people. And so to me,
I'm very practical. If it's not something
that is really bringing value to people,
then the likelihood that that product's
successful long-term is going to be pretty low.
Even, interestingly, at Dropbox, through the six
months I was there, I'd ask one question multiple
times a month. I broke the early beta users
into a bunch of different lists. And I'd ask,
"Which best describes you? I like to be among
the first to try cool new technology, or,
I only try things that I think will be useful for
me?" And over the six months, it flipped from 90%
being people who try things that they want to
try cool new technology to six months later,
it was people who only are going to try something
that they feel like is useful. But what's cool is
just because what motivates you to try something
is you're an early adopter and you want to try
something cool, if you're going to keep using it,
it's because it's giving you some utility. And so
I can still use those early adopters to help me
figure out where's the value inside the product.
Awesome. So actually, two questions along those
lines. How durable do you find this percentage
being? Say you hit 40%, how often does that
fade and go away versus stay there or go higher?
Yeah, I haven't seen it really fade back down, but
I've seen companies fail despite having it. And I
think a lot of times then, it becomes an execution
challenge. Once you have product-market fit,
not everyone's going to be a good executor. But
before that, I think getting to product-market
fit, obviously there's a lot of methodology
for doing it today that might make it a bit
easier for people, but I still think it's fairly
random and pretty dang hard. And so ultimately,
the risk factor of creating something that people
care about is really difficult. So if you can get
to the point where you have 40% of the people who
are using it saying they'd be very disappointed,
and you have a reasonable sample size. Let's
say you've got 10 people and four of them said
they'd be very disappointed without it, you're
still going to get something useful from those
four. But I wouldn't say that's a sample size
that you can really go to market on, so yeah.
What's a good sample size
you look for of just, "Okay,
this is actually good data I want to rely on?"
It's really funny. So much of the stuff I
self-learned, but I basically at one point said
I need at least 30 responses, and I just thought
I randomly made up a number and then I had people
telling me, "Yeah, 30 is the minimum that you want
on stuff." Okay. And even when I first created
this survey, I remember showing it to the
co-founder of SlideShare and her PhD was in
survey-related stuff like cognitive psychology,
but she basically said it was really about
surveying. And she's like, "This methodology
is amazing. How did you come up with this?"
And so having some of that validation around
these things helped. But a lot of it was just,
again, driven by my own curiosity and also
just knowing that that failure is such a
likely outcome that trying to reverse engineer
that failure, and then the number one reason
for failure would be that people don't actually
care about the product. And so when I find that,
that's a really good sign that we're
now down to an execution challenge.
And there's this obvious element of you
may have product-market fit with people,
but that group might end up being very small
and the business you build around it could
actually be cool, but it's not going to be a
massive business. Is there anything there you
can share? It's hard to know the size opportunity
even though some people really, really like it.
Yeah, I talked about I go to a multiple choice
after I initially use open-ended questions to
crowdsource the different use cases. But
then I try to force people in a bucket,
and then I can run filters on each of
those buckets and I'll be like, "Oh,
people who use it this way are like 60% likely
to be very disappointed without the product,
but people who use it this way are
35% likely to be very disappointed,
but way more people use it the 35% way."
And so then, do you want that intensely
loyal group or the much broader group
that's maybe a bit less, but almost there?
I think that becomes a bit of a strategic
conversation of do we want to have a better
chance of surviving, going after a niche that
we know we can serve well? Or have we raised so
much money that we have to go after a really big
market, and one that's not going to be long-term?
But maybe then you're like, "Okay, once I have
traction in that market, I can start to try
to appeal to some other markets." But I think
that's where some strategic decisions come in.
Do you have a heuristic of
which you often recommend
or is it very dependent on the situation?
I prefer a more passionate customer base and
work from there, just because I think your
biggest competition when you're really innovating
is just being irrelevant. And so if you're deeply
relevant to anyone, I think that gives you
a much better chance of long-term success.
Awesome. That's a really good insight. Okay,
two more questions along this line and then
I want to talk about growth strategy. One very
tactical question. Is there a tool you recommend
for doing this sort of survey? Do you recommend
inline? In the product? An email? Something else?
I've used a lot of different tools. I actually had
a survey business that I sold to private equity
years ago. It is called Qualaroo. That's an inflow
survey tool. I think just using SurveyMonkey with
emailed surveys works fine. And for me, it's a lot
more of what's pleasant for the customer to fill
out and then what's going to give me something
where I can work really easily with the data? So
at Bounce, for example, they had already intercom
in place that had just introduced surveying,
but it was a really crappy customer experience,
at least at that time. That's been almost a year
now or actually a little over a year. And so
I'm really sensitive to is it a good survey
experience for the consumer itself? But yeah, I
don't think I'm stuck to any one platform there.
Such an important topic. Just, again, to
remind people why this is so important,
one of the most common questions founders ask
is, "Do I have product-market fit? Have I built
something people want?" That's just an endless
series of, "I don't know. How do I know? When do
I know?" And this is telling you in a really
interesting way. So your advice is this is a
leading indicator. You don't actually know until
people actually start using it and whether they
retain and continue using it. Is there just
advice on the shift you make from relying
on the survey to actually looking at retention
cohorts? Is it just once you have enough data,
once you have a couple of cohorts, then start
looking at that? Forget about the survey?
Yeah, but retention cohorts don't give you
any of the qualitative insights into the why,
so that's why we continue to do the survey. So
initially I would say if the survey comes back
and it shows whatever your target number is...
If you want to be Nubank, it'd be a 50%. Or
two of the companies I launched, we launched in
Hungary, and I would say it was the opposite end
of the spectrum of Brazil, maybe more pessimistic
than the average culture. And so maybe 30% is good
enough there, but that ultimately, whatever your
target is, that you have the signal that says,
"Okay, we have enough value here. Let's start
working on growing the business." But while
you're working on growing the business, I
would be paying attention to those retention
cohorts. And if you're churning out all the
customers who were saying that they'd be
very disappointed without the product,
then okay, let's retrench and rethink,
do we really have product-market fit here and
what do we need to do to get it if we don't?
Awesome. And speaking of Nubank, if anyone
wants to see how a company has actually
operationalized this in the way they operate,
that there's an episode that we'll link to in
the show notes where every new product at
Nubank they build, before they launch it,
they wait for 50% threshold. For people to
say 50% of people would be disappointed if
this product did not exist as they're developing
it. And only then do they launch it publicly.
Yeah, I think they even do
it down to the feature level.
Wow.
So if you think about it, how would you
feel if you can no longer use this feature
starts to give you, again, the signal, is that
feature a must-have feature? And if it's not,
maybe we shouldn't have it. And so yeah,
I was super excited when I saw how they
were using the survey and they were
doing it before I engaged with them.
Oh, wow. That's awesome.
But they were doing it, I think,
from pretty early on in the business.
The reason they can do this is they have a lot of
users. They have millions of millions of users,
so they can ask some small percentage
of people this question. Because people
hearing this might be like, "Oh my God,
how many times am I going to be asked
this question when I'm using this feature?"
But they have a lot of users, so it's easier.
Yeah. Yeah.
Okay. Last question, I promise, along these
lines. Say someone is listening and they're like,
"Okay. Man, I'm getting 10%, I'm getting
15%. I don't know what to do to increase
my product-market fit." You should have just
a strategy of just dig into the people that
are very disappointed and see what they
have to say. But any other advice/what
do you find often works in helping
people move from, say, 10% to 40%?
Yeah, so one of the things that's cool about
almost open-sourcing the survey approach is,
again, watching how Nubank has evolved their
usage. But one of the other companies that I think
used it in an interesting way is Superhuman. And
I would say that they basically ended up probably
putting a lot more momentum behind the question
than it had even before. They posted something
about how they did it on First Round Capital's
blog. And what I have always said, and again,
it's me coming at it from probably initially a
marketing background, which is I'm taking the
product as a fixed thing, and how do I actually
figure out how to market and grow this product?
And product changes are going to take a long
time, and so what are the variables that I can
control with a marketing background? So one of
the things I've always said is just ignore the
people who say they'd be somewhat disappointed.
They're telling you it's a nice to have. They're
as good as gone, so just ignore those guys.
I'll put one piece in the middle there before
I say what Superhuman did. The reason that
I say ignore those guys is that if you start
paying attention to what you somewhat disappointed
users are telling you, and then you start tweaking
onboarding and product based on their feedback,
maybe you're going to dilute it for your must-have
users. And ultimately, it becomes kind of good
for everyone but not great for anyone. And so
that was my fear of trying to read too much into
the users who say they'd be somewhat disappointed.
But the Superhuman guys actually found, I think,
a good way around that where they said, "Okay,
what is the benefit that my must-have users are
focused on? And then of the users who say they'd
be somewhat disappointed, so the nice-to-have
users, of those users who are also focused on
that benefit, what do they need in the product
for it then to become a must-have for them?"
And so they're staying true to that core
benefit, but they're trying to essentially
take those on-the-fence users and moving them
up. And so I think their way of approaching
that addressed what my concern was, which is are
we going to break it for the must-have users?
That's an awesome insight. By the way,
did Rahul and the team there just do this
on their own or were you involved
in any way in this at Superhuman?
No. That's the same thing. Like I
said, I wasn't initially involved
with Nubank. I wasn't involved with them.
We wrote about it in our book in 2017,
and so I think that I got it out there. But I
actually teamed up with the Kissmetrics team in
2012, and essentially published this survey on
survey.io where we just made it freely available
for people and a really easy template to prepare
and send out, and the how-to guide on it. It was
all just free. Kissmetrics is using it as
maybe lead gen. And for me, I just wanted
a way to put something out for the community.
And so it's been out there for a long time,
so it's not surprising that different companies
have found different unique ways to use it.
That's awesome. I think that post
is one of the most popular in First
Round. It really had an impact on a lot of people.
Yeah.
So just to repeat, the approach you recommend
for when you're digging into... I wrote this
down. When you were talking for how to
dig into what benefit people are finding,
your advice is it's basically a follow-up survey
to the extremely disappointed people asking them
what is the primary benefit you get? It's an open
text initially. Then once you get a collection,
you do it sounds like another survey as
multiple choice. Here's five benefits-
To a different group of people, to be clear.
Different group. Yeah. Got it.
Awesome. And then it's like,
which of these four or five benefits is
what you're getting out of this product?
And then the question is, why is
this benefit important to you?
Eventually the survey.io got closed down, but
essentially the template that I typically used
was then moved to PMFsurvey.com. And so you'll see
some other questions that I have on there as well,
like what would you use instead if this product
were no longer available? And that's one of the
interesting things is you start to see people
who say they'd be somewhat disappointed,
usually, they're focused on a commodity
use case and they know an easy alternative
to switch to. So to be a must-have, it
needs to be both valuable and unique.
Okay. Anything else on this
topic of the Sean Ellis task
product-market fit test before we
move on to growth strategy advice?
No, I think that's it.
I think we did almost an hour on that
one topic, which I love because I feel
like this is such a powerful tool that I
think people sort of know and have used,
but I think there's a lot of opportunity to
use it more effectively. And all the stuff
you pointed out about it's not just you have this
threshold goal, let's move, let's grow. It's like,
this is how you figure out how to make it better
and better and grow faster and faster. And it's
actually a good segue to talking about growth.
Even though you coined the term growth hacking,
you spend most of your time on the opposite,
essentially, which is helping companies figure
out sustainable growth strategies, not just
a bunch of hacks to grow for a little bit and
then disappear. And from what I've seen, it's
all rooted in this idea of product-market fit
and what helps you find product-market fit, and
I imagine many of the stuff we've talked about.
Yeah. Just one quick interjection there
is that when I coined growth hacking,
I did not think of it as a bunch of one-off hacks.
What I thought of it was what's more about what is
the way to ultimately drive sustainable
growth? But it's, over time, maybe more
interpreted the way you described
it, but just to jump in and say that.
That's a really good clarification, so how did
you actually initially frame it when you first-
Yeah, I just said it's about looking at every
single thing that you're doing and scrutinizing
its impact on growth in the business. And
particularly, I think most marketers, when I first
moved to Silicon Valley, most CEOs who were asking
me to help their companies, they were saying,
"We need help with awareness-building," and I'm
getting introductions from top VCs. And so, so
much of, I think, the way people were approaching
growth was marketing textbook how to approach it.
And startups just don't have the luxury to do all
of those things, and so you got to really focus on
how do I acquire customers to an experience that's
going to make them keep using this product? And
so maybe I picked the wrong term in calling it
growth hacking, but I think it at least opened
the conversation to getting more people thinking
about maybe we should be thinking about growth in
a different way than as it's traditionally
taught in marketing courses in school.
Is there another term you think you should
have used? Do you always think back,
I should have called it this? Is there
anything that you've had in your mind?
I don't. I think sometimes having something
that's a little divisive is almost better
because it's too easy to just go completely
unnoticed. But I was trying to put a name
on not just how I was approaching growth, but
seeing Facebook obviously had a very different
approach to growth than most companies.
LinkedIn, Twitter, there was a handful
of companies that were approaching it in the
same way I had previously been approaching it,
and I just thought this thing needs a name. And so
I sat down with a couple of friends, came up with
a name and it stuck. But yeah, obviously from day
one it was pretty divisive with different groups.
That's a fun story. Thanks for sharing that.
Okay, so talking about growth and helping
companies figure out how to grow. Say you go
to a company, they're getting 42% on the Sean
Ellis test, and they're like, "Okay, cool, let's
start thinking about growth." What's your first
piece of advice to them to start when they're
thinking about growth? And then just broadly,
how do you approach helping
them figure out how to grow?
Ultimately, it's about trying to get as many of
the right people to that same state that we just
talked about with the must-have users, so trying
to get as many people to experience the product
in a way where they'd be very disappointed
if they could no longer use the product.
And so that's not just acquisition, which is
how most companies think about... Initially,
it was awareness then maybe the more developed
way was, oh, let's at least focus on profitable
acquisition. But in my experience, the hardest
part really sits inside the product team, so how
do you shape that first user experience so they
actually use it in the right way and it's not so
difficult that they give up? And that ultimately,
we understand what makes it a must-have product.
And then what we're trying to do is build
a... Yeah, it sounds kind of theoretical here,
but I can go into the details on how, but
build a flywheel around that must-have value.
So step one would be understand it. Step two for
me is then figure out a metric that essentially
captures units of that value being delivered. And
so when I think about a north star metric, that's
what I'm thinking about is something that reflects
how many people are coming in and experiencing
that product-market fit experience, whatever
that is. And it's not just me telling them,
"Here's what your north star metric should be."
It's that ultimately the team needs to decide that
together. And then really just diagramming, what
are all of the different ways that we can grow
that north star metric? So that's where you start
to actually build, I call it a value delivery
engine, but it's what does our onboarding look
like? What's that aha moment? That activation?
What does the engagement loop look like? Is there
any referral? Try to capture it as it is today.
And then, from there, thinking about where are the
biggest opportunities for improvement, so those
high-leverage opportunities, and then ultimately
starting to run experiments against those
opportunities. Generally, I think I touched on it
a little bit earlier, but generally the sequence
that I like to do is start with activation because
that one's just so critical and it's easy to get
lost in between, especially for an early product.
The product team's so focused on the roadmap.
We're two features away from not even needing
marketing anymore. This thing's going to take off.
And then a marketing team so focused on bringing
new people in, but how do you get those new people
to a great first experience falls through the
cracks a lot of times. So a lot of focus on
activation and then engagement and referral
and getting the revenue model right. And then
once each of those pieces are working well, then
starting to really obsess on the channel side.
One thing that I'll say. When I go in
and directly am involved with a company
on the acquisition side, I am thinking about my
hypotheses on the acquisition pretty early on,
because if I go into it and I have no
idea how we'll acquire those customers,
I'm not real confident I'll figure it out when I'm
there. So I want to have two or three things that
seem pretty viable as ways to profitably acquire
customers, and knowing that once I get deep into
it, I'll probably come up with one or two more
and I've got five, one of them's likely to work.
But I don't want to just be under the pressure
of having to come up with that once I come in,
if I don't at least see an angle from that
before I get involved with the company.
What I'm hearing is when you come into
a company and they're asking, "Sean,
how do we figure out how to grow this thing?" you
actually focus first on activation onboarding,
and we're going to talk about all these things.
Then, after that, basically these are priority
order for you. Then it's flywheel engagement
referral stuff to see if there's a way to drive
that. Then revenue. How do we make money with
this and how do we make sure we're doing this
profitably? And only then do you start to
go big on acquisition top-of-funnel growth.
Yeah. I may need to do some acquisition stuff
before just to bring enough flow-through,
but I'm not obsessing on how scalable is this.
It's just like, yeah, let's get enough people
coming through that we can start to take the slack
out. Part of it comes down to that the acquisition
side is so competitive now that if you're not
really efficient at converting and retaining
and monetizing customers, you can't find scalable,
profitable customer acquisition channels.
This is fascinating because I think a
lot of people probably do the opposite.
Start driving a bunch of growth to a
product, then we'll fix onboarding,
then we'll figure out how we're making
money, and referrals comes along there.
So I think this is really important for people
to hear. So again, the reason you invest first
and focus a lot on onboarding/getting people
activated is because that is very correlated
to retention and this must-have customer,
this, "I'll be very disappointed," customer.
Yeah. And they're at highest risk
of losing them at that point. They-
They're at highest risk of losing them at that
point. They're probably a little skeptical about
a promise that you put out there, but they're
intrigued enough to want to use it. But until
you get them to that must-have experience, until
you kind of get them to that aha moment, they're
at their high risk of being lost. And so a lot of
people focus on, "Well, I better get their email
address or their phone number." But then you're
essentially having to reacquire them at that
point. So to me, if you can collapse that time
to value, I can give you a couple of incredible
examples of when we [inaudible 00:54:38]
So at LogMeIn, when we initially tried to
grow the business, I was stuck at being able to
spend... I couldn't spend more than $10,000 per
month profitably trying to grow the business. And
then I dug into the data and I saw that 95% of the
people signing up for LogMeIn. So LogMeIn, at the
time free remote access for your computer. And so
you install software and you can control it from
any other computer. So 95% of the people signing
up never once did a remote control session.
And so not surprisingly, then I had to get my
monetization off the 5% who did that was really
limiting my ability to find channels that worked.
Credit our CEO with this, that I shared the data
with him and he basically told the product team,
"We are putting a complete freeze on the product
development roadmap." So every single person from
product, engineering, design and then also said
to me, "Stop trying to find new channels." The
three of us on the marketing side are all going
to focus on improving the signup to usage rate.
And so in three months, we improve the signup to
usage rate by a thousand percent. So we went from
only 5% of people using the product to 50%.
I went back, tried the exact same channels
that previously only scaled to $10,000 a month.
Now they scaled to a million dollars a month with
a three-month payback on marketing dollars
invested. 80% of new users were coming in
through word of mouth. So there was this major
inflection point by just focusing on activation.
This episode is brought to you by Merge.
Product leaders, yes, like you, cringe
when they hear the word integration. They're not
fun for you to scope, build, launch or maintain,
and integrations probably aren't what led you to
product work in the first place. Lucky for you.
The folks at Merge are obsessed with integrations.
Their single API helps SaaS companies launch over
200 product integrations in weeks, not quarters.
Think of Merge like Plaid, but for everything B2B
SaaS. Organizations like Ramp, Dorada and Electric
use Merge to access their customer's accounting
data to reconcile bill payments, file storage data
to create searchable databases in their product or
HRIS data to auto-provision and de-provision
access for their customer's employees.
And yes, if you need AI-ready data for your
SaaS product, then Merge is the fastest way
to get it. So want to solve your organization's
integration dilemma once and for all? Book and
attend a meeting at merge.dev/lenny and
receive a $50 Amazon gift card. That's
merge.dev/lenny. What do you find often works
in helping increase activation? I know there's
a million things that people do, but I guess
what are three or four things that you think
people should definitely try to help improve
activation and their onboarding conversion?
One of my favorite quotes is a quote from a guy
Kettering, who was a hundred years ago at GM
running innovation. And he says, "A problem well
stated is a problem half solved." And so I think
a lot of it comes down to not the things you try,
but how you deeply understand the problem that's
preventing someone from using your product
effectively. And so I'll just give you one
example. We had one channel after we made a lot
of these changes and had already driven a ton of
improvement in the LogMeIn onboarding. We found
a demand generation channel that was really cheap
and the economics looked great, but at just
the download step we had a 90% drop off rate.
And so we A/B tested a bunch of different things
there to try to improve that conversion rate, and
then finally 10 plus tests, not able to improve
it. Finally, someone said, "When these people are
registering. Why don't we just ask them why they
signed up and didn't download the software?" And
so we didn't want to do it in too kind of a creepy
way. So we made it look like a note coming from
customer service. This channel was sending 200,000
people a day, so 20,000 people were converting to
registering. So we had essentially 20,000 people
we could email and then 18,000 of them who didn't
download. And so we just asked, "Hey, notice
you haven't had a chance to use the product yet.
It looked like it was coming from customer
support. What happened?" And the answer we
got back and not a formal survey was, "Oh, this
seemed too good to be true. I didn't believe this
was free." I mentioned to you we were one of the
first freemium SaaS products out there. And so
people were skeptical, especially in a demand
gen channel where they hadn't seen a radio or
a TV advertisement from our competitor who was
a premium only product. These were people who
were discovering the category for the first time
they were getting there. Once we articulated what
the problem was, our next test gave us a 300%
improvement in the download rate, which was...
We gave them a choice, download a trial of
the paid version or download the free version,
put a big graphical check mark next to the free
version. But when they saw we had a business
model and a trial of a paid version, the free
version was credible. And so that essentially
made that channel work for us. So I think again,
it's that combination of qualitative research,
looking at how others did it. We had this theory,
our previous company had been a game company that
didn't require a download. So initially we had
this theory that maybe just downloadable software
can't be in the millions of new customers a
month and so we're being unrealistic here.
But then we were like, "Are there any
counter examples to that"? And no,
the instant messengers are downloadable and
they have hundreds of millions of customers,
so let's study their download and install
process and see if we have any ideas that
we could borrow from that. So again, some
inspiration, tried some of those things,
it was a combination of just trying a bunch
of different stuff that ultimately led to,
I wouldn't say there was one big
gain, it was a bunch of small gains.
Awesome. So a few things for people to try
if they're like, "Hey, how do I improve my
activation rate? How do I improve my conversion
rate?" Just drill further into what is stopping
people from progressing. Ask them, "Why did you
bounce here? What did you think this was going
to be? Why didn't you end up using this?"
Look for inspiration from other products,
I think people probably already know that. You
talked about earlier this idea of the positioning,
having a big impact of just figuring out.
They want an antivirus software. Let's make
that very clear. "Hey we've got the best
antivirus software, that's what we're here
for." So there's probably just messaging
that you find works a lot of times, right?
I mean your two big levers on driving a
conversion are increase desire, reduce
friction. And so you definitely want to increase
the right desire. Sometimes it can also just be
reminding people along the way of what benefits
you're going to get. In the case of LogmeIn,
it was probably the most complicated funnel I've
ever seen because you couldn't even get to the
aha moment while you're sitting in front of the
computer. You had to actually go to a different
computer and to use the service to remote
control the computer you're in front of.
So it's not surprising that there was so many
steps where we could lose people, but we just
weren't that intentional about designing each
of those steps initially. And it wasn't until
we thought through why would we lose someone at
this step and studying the data, which steps were
we losing the most people at? Then deeply trying
to contextualize why are we losing them there,
coming up with a set of tests that we want to run
and then having a good way of deciding which one
to test first and ultimately focusing the tests
on the areas where we're losing the most people.
The other element of this is coming up
with an activation metric and aligning
on here's what we consider so activated. I
know this is very dependent on the product,
but any advice or heuristic for how to help
people decide this is our activated user.
I tend to start qualitatively. So just like when
do I think they've had a good enough experience
with the product to really know it? And so in
the case of LogMeIn, it was pretty easy. If they
didn't do a remote control session, they didn't
use the product. There was no value along the way
there. And then at least try to see if there's a
correlation to long-term retention of doing that.
Causation is you need to do some experimentation
to prove causation. At the very least, I want to
see that correlation, but if I start with two
or three ideas of what it might be and then
go and study the data, that can help you focus.
But again, I don't think there's necessarily one
exact right answer of what is that aha moment.
There might be two or three different things.
I think it's that intentionality about picking
something that's experience-based and saying,
"What is a likely experience that someone's going
to get a good enough taste of this product?" And
then I do see some companies that are like, "Well,
the activation moment should be, they've used it a
hundred times." That's going to correlate to
long-term retention, but it's just not very
actionable. It's so far down the user experience.
So ideally if there's a way that I could get them
there in the first session, in the first day,
that's great. And so it's sort of something
that's value that can be experienced super
early. To give you an example from the first
company I worked on was a game company, where
I actually flipped it and basically instead
of making a traditional funnel where they
could play our games after they signed up,
I made our games the advertisements. So basically
we syndicated our games to 40,000 websites.
They started gameplay experience on the other
website, then they would get a message that
they now have a qualifying score and if they
register, they'll be in the drawing for the
weekly cash prize and then we could pull them into
multiplayer games on the site. And so it's kind of
the strategy that YouTube used to grow, but it was
two years before YouTube introduced the approach.
It feels like you basically created Zynga, is what
I'm hearing there. So let's move further down the
funnel. So we've talked about activation,
onboarding. The next phase that you focus
on is basically some people call this growth
loops, growth engines, flywheels. Basically
it's the thing that helps your business grow
and something I am curious if this resonates.
I found there's basically four ways to grow and
usually one of these engines is responsible for
almost all of your growth. So what I've seen
is basically you're going to go through sales,
you're going to grow through SEO,
you're going to go through virality,
word of mouth or paid growth. Does
that resonate? Does that feel right?
And I wouldn't say it's necessarily one
or the other. I think Bounce is a really
interesting example where SEO is super important
for Bounce. So people who are essentially saying,
"Luggage storage, Paris. Luggage storage..."
Most people when they're trying to find a place
to store their luggage, they're starting with
Google, but at the same time, a huge percentage
of the people who use Bounce are dragging their
bag down a street over cobblestones in Paris.
And then they pass a sign that says, "Store
your bag here for $5 a day." And it's like,
"Oh, no-brainer." And so 10,000 partners around
the world means that there's a lot of people in
the right situation on the demand gen side.
One would be, I actually think of kind of...
I'm not sure how it would map to this, but
demand generation versus demand harvesting.
And so one of those examples would be a...
Demand generation example, when you see the
signs when you're passing, it's high context,
right place. And then obviously the demand
harvesting would be anyone who's Googling. And
so they do paid search and organic search there.
Interesting. I don't see that
sign approach work often,
but I definitely have seen it work. Like
Yelp I think grew in a lot of ways of just
little Yelp stickers in all the restaurant.
DoorDash I think probably grows through that.
I think every business could
be a little bit different,
but for Bounce it makes sense that that
would be a really good opportunity for them.
How do you help a business figure out which
area to bet on? Whether they should go paid,
whether they should go SEO, whether they should
hire sales. Sales is probably an easier one. B2B,
you're probably going to have to be a sales team,
I guess just to help them pick, "Here's
where you have a big opportunity."
Again, it kind of comes down as I'm going into
it, I'm thinking what are the realistic customer
acquisition angles for this business? And I want
to have ideally two or three that I'm coming
into it with, but it's going to... Obviously
Dropbox is a classic one of like, "Oh man,
this product..." User get user is going to be
just a classic. There's file share built into it,
folder collaboration. There's so many
pieces of it that cross from one user
to the next. But interestingly, it was
fairly similar to LogMeIn in some senses,
it's two businesses are solving similar problems
in different ways. Where LogMeIn, we grew almost
entirely off of paid search. And part of it
again is that for us, we had a competitor that
was spending tens of millions of dollars a month
creating the category with a premium only product
through radio and TV advertising. GoToMyPC,
they're creating all this latent demand. And
so it just made sense for us to disrupt them with
a freemium service and to insert ourselves in the
flow of someone... What was that thing that I
heard about on the TV commercial? And now they
go and they Google it and same thing, but free.
So we weren't really pushing for differentiation,
but just really trying to harvest that.
So I couldn't do that at Dropbox. No one
was looking for when I went there. And so we
tried a little bit with search to see can we
make it work on cloud storage or backup or kind
of going to some of these traditional categories.
Cloud storage wasn't even a traditional category
at that point, but backup was, and it was fairly
expensive and there was just not that much demand
there that way. And so it just made more sense to
focus on the user get user loops at Dropbox.
I think basically for each business it's just
thinking about what's unique for that business
that is going to open up channel opportunities and
everyone's going to be a little bit, I think jaded
from whatever the last thing that worked really
well. They're going to think they can apply it in
the next business. But after enough times myself,
I tend to get the most inspiration by just talking
to customers and finding out how did they find it,
how do they typically find something like that?
And that starts to give me some ideas as well.
I think that last point is really powerful
and I'm just writing it down. You said,
essentially one of your tactics is talking
to users, asking them how did you find this
product and how do you normally find products
like this? Is that the second question? I think
it's similar to your [inaudible 01:21:02] test.
It's such a simple question, but it's so powerful
because how else will people find your product?
They go to a place to find stuff like this, and
I searched Google for folder sharing. There's
so much there that you just skip over.
I think the reason that you don't actually
hear people taking the obvious route there
a lot of times is because, and I used to be in
the same thing, that people tend to be either
over indexed on qualitative or over indexed
on quantitative. So it's like analytics,
I'm going to get all my answers from testing
and analytics or I'm going to get all my answers
from traditional customer research. And I
was very much in that initial camp for the
first five years of my career. I'm just going
to measure everything and test the heck out
of things and find stuff that works. But I had a
VC who was our lead VC at LogMeIn who just said,
"When was the last time you talked to a customer?"
Just pushed me to survey and talk to customers all
the time. And at first I gave the smart-ass
answer, "I don't care what they say,
I care what they do." And he's like, "No, you
got to talk to him." Then just to appease him,
I would try to have a conversation every day
because he was in our office a lot and so I
could say, "Hey, yeah, I talked to a customer
today," when he would ask me. But I started
finding that my experiments were so much better
the more I talked to customers, and eventually I
became very much... The blend of qualitative and
quantitative research leads to much better tests.
That is another amazing story and
insight. It's so interesting that people
sometimes think of you as growth hacker guy
experiments data, when most of the advice we've
been sharing so far is very qualitative driven,
very survey driven, targeting customers driven.
And it is just really hard
to run good experiments when
you can't deeply contextualize what's going on.
I love this. By the way, I don't know if I knew
this. So you helped develop
the Dropbox referral program?
I was there at the time. Basically, even when I
first started talking with Drew. Before I came in,
I was like, "I think the way we're going to
grow this business is by leveraging the really
passionate customer base and that's what we
need to double down on." And we had tried a
similar kind of referral program at Zabni and a
friend who actually started Ring, Jamie Simonoff,
previously had a company called PhoneTag
way before Ring, and he had actually done
a lot of the testing on double-sided referral
programs and having incentive on both sides,
and he found that that worked the best.
And so between what we had tested at Zabni
and those conversations with him, I hadn't
actually seen PayPal yet at that point,
what they were doing. But that was kind of like...
It seems like a referral program where we have
incentives on both sides is the best way to go.
Interestingly, six months before I was at Dropbox,
I was at LogMeIn, and I really thought about
having incentivized referrals at LogMeIn,
but 80% of our new users were coming in through
word of mouth. And I had a hundred million devices
connected in on our system, and I was just so
afraid of breaking this growth engine by adding
an incentive that I didn't want to risk it.
But at Dropbox it was so early. I would still
say no experiment is one person. It happened to
be when I was there, I had some insights that I
brought in, but ultimately... The guy who built
it was actually an intern named Albert Knee and
he ended up dropping out, I think, out of
MIT to stay with Dropbox for a few years
after that. But he was kind of my right-hand
guy to collaborating on growth day to day.
Wow. I would say Dropbox is the referral
program, and the PayPal referral program,
as you mentioned, are the two most legendary,
studied, copied referral programs out there.
Unfortunately, I think that what they don't
realize is that before the referral program,
Dropbox had amazing referral rate. Companies
that are trying to copy it are like,
"Why isn't anyone talking about a product? Let's
add a referral program with incentives." To me,
I think it's a great accelerant
when it's already working,
but it can't fix it if people don't
want to talk about your product.
That's an awesome point and something I
was just going to ask about and just coming
back to this topic of growing engagement,
growing referrals as a growth mechanism,
what do you look for to tell you that there's
an opportunity there? And I'll just answer it,
partly I've seen exactly what you just
said, which is you need to already have
strong word of mouth growth because
referrals kind sits on that and gives
you a little more incentive to share. So maybe
do you agree with that, not agree to that? Any
other advice on helping figure out is there
some kind of loop here that we can build?
Well, one thing I will say is freemium
when we first started with it, as I said,
we were one of the first with it, so it took me a
while to figure out exactly how freemium worked,
but to me, freemium towards having a free
and a premium version of your product to
really work in any business, it needs to
be that your free product is so good that
people naturally have word of mouth around that
product. And then to be economically viable,
you have to have a premium product that's better
enough and differentiated enough that people are
going to upgrade to the premium product.
But I think a lot of times people are so
worried about the second part that they make
the free version not very good and then they're
surprised when word of mouth isn't very strong
there. So I think you have to essentially have
two distinct products that are great on
their own. So that would be the one piece,
but then obviously companies that have any kind
of collaborative layer to them are going to be
more likely to work well with referral. And
then I think on the engagement side, a lot of
it comes down to just the nature of the product.
Like Airbnb, you're not going to use it every day
unless you're like a vagrant or something and
then you wouldn't have money to pay for it. So
there's kind a natural usage cycle to products
and you want to be able to maximize against that
cycle. That's where I was saying, coming back
to the hooked model, I think is a really good
way to help to have a framework to think about
how do I improve engagement. One good counter
example to that though of the natural frequency
of using a product is Facebook when they change
their North Star Metric from monthly active
users to daily active users. I think, again,
just having what gets measured gets managed.
Once Facebook was on a daily active user goal,
the team suddenly had a lot more incentive
to think about, "How do I bring people back
every day and use this product?" Where when
it was monthly active users, they kind of
only got credit for that person for using once
in that month. And even if they used 10 times,
they didn't get 10 times the credit. It was
just like a, "Oh, that's cool too." But they
weren't sort of measured on that. And so I
think it was sort of a random decision for
Mark Zuckerberg to move from a monthly active
to a daily active because they hit 1 billion
monthly active users and they're like, "Okay,
let's go for 1 billion daily active users."
But it had a really big impact on making that
product way more addictive to the point where
obviously they ended up in Congress or get a lot
of pushback. I'm not sure they went to Congress
for that, but they got a lot of pushback for
having a product that's maybe too addictive.
And the same thing carrying into Instagram and
some of the other Meta products or basically
anything that is highly engaging. So I do think
the right incentives can actually help a team to
focus on it, but there's going to be sort of
a natural usage cycle to any product as well.
I'm glad you mentioned North Star Metrics.
I actually have a post I will link to in the
show notes where I collected the
North Star Metrics of 30 different
companies to give you some inspiration.
I know this is a deep topic of its own,
but just when someone is trying to pick their
own North Star Metrics, which I 1000% agree,
informs so much about how your company
operates. It basically focuses everyone's
incentives to let's drive this thing. And
that changes so much of what you're building.
Any just bullet point piece of advice for
helping you pick your North Star Metrics?
I start with the value that's uncovered through
the [inaudible 01:21:02] test. So with a company,
I'll say, "Okay, this is what the must have value
is according to our most passionate customers,
and we want to think about a metric that reflects
us delivering that value." And then I'll give them
kind of a framework of ways to think about
a North Star Metric. But I think it's really
important for it to be a time capped group
conversation. And if you give a team 30 days,
they'll take 30 days. If you give them
six months, they'll take six months.
But I think generally a team can come up with a
pretty good North Star Metric after 30 minutes
if they have the right raw ingredients and a
checklist of what's important in a North Star
Metric. Something that's not a ratio, it's
something that can be up onto the right over
time. So you can keep managing it and feeling
good. It should correlate to revenue growth,
but revenue shouldn't be the North Star Metric,
but as you grow value across your customer base,
you should be able to grow revenue
at the same rate. And so there's-
Revenue at the same rate. And
so there's some other things,
but I think that would be the most important,
is that it's something that could be up and to
the right over time and reflects value
that you're delivering to customers.
Awesome. And I was going to ask
about revenue in your opinion
there. And so your advice is don't
make revenue or North star metric?
No. Even Amazon, and again, this is just what I
know of Amazon's as being but monthly purchases,
but someone else might say Amazon, no Amazon's is
GMV or something. But I think monthly purchases
is great because it maps to value that people
are getting from Amazon. And so even if I spend
say $1000 on a TV set with Amazon versus
$3 on a or $10 on an electric toothbrush,
Amazon from the consumer's perspective
delivered the same value. I needed something,
Amazon helped me find that thing. And so units
of value from the customer perspective I think
is more important than overall revenue. But
clearly with Amazon focusing on driving more
monthly purchases, at least on their store side
of the business, that has helped them become one
of most valuable companies in the world. So I
think focusing on value is, revenue should be
a product of doing things. Right. It shouldn't
kind of guide your day-to-day actions.
To make this even more concrete for people,
are there some North star metric examples you
could share that you've seen that are good? Like
say for Eventbrite or Dropbox or any companies
you've worked with? And I'll share one real
quick as you're thinking about it. At Airbnb,
our North star metric was nights booked. And
so it's similar to Amazon. It's not like the
money Airbnb made from bookings, but it's like
nights booked and it was really, and basically
every experiment ran is like, is this increasing
night booked or is this decreasing night's book?
And so that's a really good marketplace
one. Uber obviously weekly rides. I'm
always surprised with the Airbnb, that
there's not a kind of time piece on it,
like the weekly rides that you have with
Uber, but maybe it's because it's such an
infrequent use case on travel that it
doesn't make sense to focus on. Yeah.
Yeah. Why is the timeframe important
to you? Why do you encourage that?
Just daily active users, you saw the
difference between monthly active users
and daily active users could change behavior a
lot at Facebook. It gives you a quantifiable way,
if you're just kind of taking an aggregate number
over time, it always looks like it's going up.
So it's an engagement element
of how often are they engaging.
Yeah. But,-
Any others? Any others real quick?
Yeah, I mean, I didn't really think about North
star metrics when I was at Dropbox and Eventbrite,
like the term itself, but I was thinking about
what is a valuable experience with Dropbox and
how do I get people to have that more time?
But I don't even know what they go with today,
but maybe files in Dropbox, files access might be
better than just files hosted. And then probably
for Eventbrite, again, I would say weekly tickets
or something like you could say weekly events,
but then you have events that don't sell
any tickets where weekly tickets would be
more likely to reflect, events are going to
be happy if they're selling tickets and yeah.
Okay. Sean, we've gone through so
much stuff. I'm trying to limit
how many more questions we get
through just so that we don't,-
We're going long.
We're going long, which is amazing. I think
there's so much value here that we're collecting
for folks. So let just ask maybe a couple more
quick questions. One is actually from Andrew
Chen who is currently partnered at a partner at
A16z. He wrote about growth for the longest time.
I think he helped popularize growth hacking
for better or worse with his article and it
being the future of VP of what is it? Growth
Hacking is the new VP of marketing, right,
Is the title. So he actually had a question for
you that he shared with me. His question is,
growth strategies have changed a
lot over the past decade. What is
the biggest difference now versus when
you first started working on growth?
When I first started just being data-driven on
customer acquisition was enough to win and being
test and data-driven on customer acquisition.
All the other companies were like CPM focused
and so we could do really well just with lots
of testing and some creativity in how it all
worked. But that over time as, now I would
say most online marketers are very data and
test drive. They know they need to do lots
of testing. And so to be competitive today,
you actually have to be able to be super
efficient at all parts of the business.
So again, like how you convert, retain, monetize,
and that's when it gets hard. Getting a marketing
team to be data and test-driven is pretty easy.
Once you start getting into activation and
referral and engagement and retention, now you're
talking about the overlap between marketing,
product if it's B2B, bringing sales in there,
customer success, and those teams are not used
to working together. And so it's really hard to
drive the collaboration that's needed to have an
effective testing program across the entire growth
engine. And that's pretty much any business that's
been successful with it, implemented it super
early in the business, and so very few later
stage companies have been able to make much
progress in replicating that type of approach.
It's just gotten harder basically.
Things are just getting harder.
It's gotten harder, but I think it's possible.
So it's what I obsess about all the time,
is how do you get cross-functional teams working
together on growth now? And it's still a
huge advantage when you can pull it off.
Okay. Totally unrelated question, going
in completely different direction as we
close out our chat. So you came up with ICE,
the very popular way of prioritizing work,
which is crazy. I did not know that until I
started prepping for this conversation. What's
your thoughts on RICE, the intercom version
of ICE, where R stands for reach, I believe.
Yeah.
Thoughts?
So I think it's an unnecessary addition, but maybe
I'm just being protective of my original idea,
that the I in ICE is impact and it's essentially
saying best case scenario, how much impact could
we get from this? And reach is a super important
part of impact. And so I think it's already
factored in the I in ICE. And so I think if
there's anything that I would be accused of,
it would be being over simplifying things and I'm
not saying them, but there's a lot of people who
approach things with, there's got to be a more
complex way to approach this and that's just
not me. And so yeah, more testing is better.
No, it doesn't just work like that. I mean,
better tests are better than bad tests, but
just if you have to hold yourself accountable
to anything, more testing would be better.
And so I think one just quick note on ICE is
that in order to be able to effectively
run a high velocity testing program,
you need to be able to source ideas from across
the company. And that's why I came up with ICE,
that if you're having people submit ideas and
you can't tell them why their idea was not
chosen, they're just going to get upset and
you're going to waste a lot of time. But if
you have a systematic way of being able
to compare ideas, it's more likely that
people will be able to get it and they'll
be able to come up with better ideas.
I love the way you think, Sean. I have a post on
prioritization where I basically just make the
same argument that there's all these complicated
ways to prioritize. In the end, it's just impact,
confidence, and effort and it really works
and rarely is more work. On the other hand,
I do also have a guest post called DRICE
by these two guys called Detailed RICE,
which actually I think is a really good point
where sometimes it's worth spending like 30
minutes per idea to just really estimate
how long will it take to avoid doing things
that are just going to not work and very
unlikely. So we're basically doing this
reach piece and spending the time too. Right.
And I think there's a lot of good value there.
Yeah. And what I thinks going to be
really interesting is that over time,
I think AI is going to actually change our
ability to model out potential outcomes on
experiments and start to, whether it's a more
informed way of doing ICE or replaces ICE,
that ultimately probability of outcomes is
something that AI will be pretty good at.
Well, amazing segue to the final question.
The actually final question is I wanted to
ask you about any ways you've been using AI
or ways you think AI will impact the work
you're doing or other folks are doing? And
maybe you just answered it, but you tell me.
No, I'll touch on a couple. One is
that probably the funnest way that
I'm using it today. Obviously I've done
it for coming up with experiment ideas,
but the funnest way I personally use it is
I get a lot of people asking me for advice,
and I don't have very much time to answer
with thoughtful answers to people. And so
almost every question that I get, I go to
ChatGPT say, how would Sean Ellis answer
this? And it gives me an initial draft to make
a couple of tweaks and definitely allows me to
answer a lot more. So it helps to have a book
that's indexed in there and lots of writing.
That is so funny, and that the question,
that's as simple as the prompt
is how would Sean Ellis answer,-
Yeah, because then a lot of times it'll
say, Sean Ellis, author of Hacking Growth
dah, dah, dah, believes that, and then it'll
obviously pull that part out in the answer.
Oh my God. So you're one step away
from a Chrome extension or something
that just automatically plugs that into your,-
Yeah, exactly. And I can even start
to have my personal assistant maybe
start to answer some of those questions as me,
but I'm a little bit afraid to send something
without reviewing it first because,-
Absolutely.
Sometimes there's stuff that's pretty different
from how I would answer it, but longer term,
I actually think, as I said, I think the
cross-functional challenge to growth is a thing
that holds a lot of companies back from being
able to implement this a bit later. Mostly product
teams don't want to get direction from marketing
teams. Marketing teams don't want to get direction
from product teams, and maybe a growth layer can
help to do these things, but I find that if AI
is essentially saying, you're underperforming
in this area of your business, you should drive
some experiments in this area. It's a lot harder
to kind of let ego get in the way when it's kind
of dispassionate recommendations from a system.
And so I actually think, I think the ability to
come up with great experiments is going to keep
growing with AI and identifying opportunities. And
then obviously the analytical AI side of things
is going to be really exciting in terms of being,
I do find with most companies, once we get a real
high velocity of experiments going, the bottleneck
ends up happening more on the analysis side. And
I think AI will help a lot with that as well.
Super cool. These are awesome examples.
Okay, Sean, is there anything else you
wanted to share or leave listeners with before
we get to our very exciting lightning round,
which we'll go through real fast? Because
we've gone very long and I want to let you go.
Yeah. As I've gone through and done a lot
of workshops and programs with companies,
I keep coming back to this advice that I heard
from guy Oleg Yakubenkov, which is it often comes
down to asking the right question at the right
time in how you figure things out. And he's a
former data scientist from Meta and so where he
basically boils data science down to learning how
to ask the right questions. And so I actually
have a course with him called Gopractice.io,
where that's really the big benefit of the
course, is to learn how to ask the right
questions and yeah, you learn how to query
them and amplitude, but more importantly,
being able to ask the right question. I think
it's kind of cool to hear that from a data
scientist from Meta, the importance of that.
But every time I'm going through exercises in
my workshops, it almost always comes down
to people who aren't able to come up with
the right or a good answer in a business.
It's because they're not asking the obvious
question. And as soon as they have, like why
aren't users downloading the software? Let's
just ask them that question. That would be
one example from my workshop. Who considers
the product a must have? That part of getting,
to figuring out the must have kind of benefit
that then allows you to hone in on product market
fit. And so yeah, right questions, right time I
think is a really important way to think about
growth and even getting to product market fit.
I love this advice because I think it gives us a
glimpse into how your brain has developed these
really seemingly simple ideas that end up being
really powerful. And it feels like the advice is
just think a lot about the question you need to
ask because that'll get you just something that
a lot of people just kind of under think or
don't. There's things, maybe it's too simple.
Yeah, or they just jump right into
the solution side of things where
they're not really trying to
understand what's going on.
Yeah. Yeah. Amazing. Okay, well with that, Sean,
we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
I am.
All right. Our first question is,
what are two or three books you've
recommended most to other people?
Increasingly, I'm recommending a book called
Presenting to Win that's been around forever, but
it really helped me with my presenting. And so of
course when I'm out traveling, I'm often sharing
the stage with other speakers and yeah, I like to
recommend that one to them. I've already talked
about Muriel's Hooked. I recommend that always,
and we'll just stick with two. That's good two.
Within Presenting to Win, is there one tip that
sticks with you of here's something
that helped me be a better presenter?
Ultimately, confidence in presenting comes
down to having very well organized information
that you're going to present. And
when you organize it correctly,
you are much more likely to deliver it
with confidence. And so he basically says,
if I had a presentation to do and I had an hour to
present, I'd spend 55 minutes creating the right
presentation and then five minutes practicing
it. But yeah, there's a lot more to it, but,-
Wow. Amazing. Okay. We'll link to
that book in the show notes. Do
you have a favorite recent movie
or TV show you've really enjoyed?
Yeah, so I've been binging
the Olympics. I love that,
just watching people who worked their ass
off for years and then maybe have 30 seconds
to do the thing that they worked hard for. So
Olympics have been awesome. And then the movie,
I actually just saw Blackberry,
I don't know if you've seen that.
Oh, the story of the Blackberry?
Yeah. I mean obviously we all kind of
know the story, but it was so really,
I mean, it's a classic example of
product market fit and then not.
Actually, it's probably even a counter example
to the dangers of the how would you feel if
we could no longer use this product? Pretty
sure most people would've said on Blackberry,
it's the keyboard, and until iPhone came along,
the keyboard was super important and then suddenly
it wasn't. But yeah, it's also interesting
on egos and other things that everybody's
getting friendly in the beginning and then egos
take over and things get a lot harder later on.
That was actually a really
good movie. There's also an
amazing movie called Tetris. For some
reason, I think of these two together,-
Okay.
About the story of Tetris, and it's a
similar parallels to those two movies.
Awesome. I'll have to see that one.
Next question, do you have a favorite product
you've recently discovered that you really love?
I forget the name of it, but I think or it's
called Pack Gear Hanging Suitcase, and I basically
like, I've done almost 100,000 miles in travel
this year, and I have another trip scheduled for
next week, and I love it because it basically has
all my clothes folded in this little insert that
goes into my suitcase, and then I just pull it out
and hang it up and just makes travel way easier.
It's called the Pack Gear Suitcase?
Pack Gear Hanging Suitcase Organizer.
So cool. Going to check that out.
Two more questions. Do you have a
favorite life motto that you often
come back to that you find useful
in work or in life? Maybe share
with friends and family sometimes.
Focus on reputation and learning over earnings
has served me super well that, and I'll give
you an example. I had two companies when I was
doing a lot of this early interim stuff yeah,
10 plus years ago, and I had two of them where
I talked to the founders afterwards and I could
tell they weren't that stoked on my contributions.
And I offered a full refund to both of them with a
thought that like I have this reputation that's,
like I randomly pulled the number and said, my
reputation worth $5 million. Why would I possibly
mortgage that reputation for $20,000? And so one
of them, I gave the check back to them and he was
happy to take it, but he had said, "Oh, you can
make it up to me. You don't have to give me the
check, just make it up to me by continuing to help
me for an unlimited amount of time going forward."
I was like, "Oh, take the check." And then the
other one said, "No, no, I'm actually really happy
with what you did. We're fine." But the two VCs
who had made those introductions were the first
two to give me term sheets when I went out to
raise money for my company. And the pre-money
ultimately ended up being valued at more than
double what I had put my personal reputation at.
So I, yeah, I think the, yeah, unfortunately the
company didn't do that well itself because of the
elusive product market fit challenges. But yeah,
the learning there of just focus on learning
and reputation. Reputation opened the door
to more and more learning. And as I got more
learning, the reputation grew. And so yeah.
There's a really good corollary there with
customer support. If someone just hates your
product and wants a refund, just give them a
refund and let them move on versus being upset.
Yeah, absolutely.
I love that. Final question. You mentioned
to me before we started recording that
you were maybe indirectly responsible for
TikTok's success. Maybe share that story.
Yeah, I mean, I don't want to overstate it, but
I yeah, my trip around the world that I did three
months ago, I think I wrapped it up. I met with
the original founding growth team at TikTok.
They're based in Singapore and they had, I can't
remember what the previous product was called,
but they started with the previous
product. And then when TikTok came,
they were in place to be the initial growth team
for TikTok, and they basically said all the early
stuff we did to grow TikTok was based on your
writing. So that was before the book came out.
So it's a lot of just blogging that I had done,
but it was really, really cool to get that
feedback that, yeah, I've always said I have some
really good wins, a lot of unicorns that I helped,
but none of the really, really big guys. And
then to hear that, it felt really good to know
that I played some kind of role in TikTok. Of
course, almost the same week they told me that
that was Congress having TikTok ban conversations.
So it was good. And at the same time, knowing that
maybe if they hadn't read my stuff, Congress
wouldn't be wasting their time on TikTok bans.
Oh man. Bittersweet. I hope they don't pull you
into some hearings. Sean, this was incredible.
This was everything I was hoping it'd be. I feel
like we collected so much wisdom here for folks to
them figure out product market fit, find product
market fit, iterate, grow their products. So
happy we did this. Two final questions. Where can
folks find stuff that you're up to if they want to
learn more and maybe work with you in various
ways? And how can listeners be useful to you?
Awesome. Yeah, so Seanellis.me is the website
where I kind of link to all the things that I'm
doing. And so that would be one place where, and
there's contact forms on there if anyone wants to
reach out. Obviously LinkedIn people can contact
me there. And then I did mention GoPractice. So
gopractice.io. Really cool way to learn growth
through a simulated environment of being able
to try to grow products. So check out GoPractice
and maybe go to Seanellis.me. When this comes out,
I'll put a special offer on there for
Lenny's listeners so you can save some money.
And there's also a LLM AI kind of,-
I wasn't directly involved on
that one, but there's yeah,
there's some other really cool stuff that
Oleg and the team are doing. Data-driven
product management, and the user growth
programs are the ones that I helped with.
Awesome. And then for folks, if they're
wondering, do you do advising? How do
you work with companies in case
they're like, hey, I need Sean.
Yeah, I mean, so the sweet spot for me on
companies that I go hands-on with are ideally
pretty early just after they get to product market
fit and now you know how to measure it. So if
you're kind of pre-scale, but you're seeing that
40%, or even if you're a bit earlier than that,
we can start talking earlier. But to me,
that's my favorite time to get in there,
build it right from the beginning. It's so
hard to retroactively do these things. And
I'll go in for three to six months and I'm all
in full-time, one of the team trying to really
help build traction in the business. I do one of
those every maybe year or maybe every year or two
because I purposely burn myself out and then have
fun doing more lecturing and workshops and stuff.
Awesome. Well, you might get a
flood of requests after this comes
out. Hope you're ready. Sean,
thank you so much for being here.
Awesome. Thank you, Lenny. I
really appreciate you having me on.
Bye everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
LennysPodcasts.com. See you in the next episode.