People tend to get into a public speaking
voice. We'll be in a class and they'll be
chatting normally and look super normal. And then
we'll say, "Okay, now just a timer, I'm just going
to give you a speech. Just speak for 60 seconds so
we get a baseline," and I click play, and suddenly
I say, "The important part about doing this," and
they enter into a different version of themselves,
a professional version, whatever that
would mean. It's so much more freeing,
powerful, connecting, and effective to speak
conversation. So the cue I often give people is-
Today my guest is Tristan de Montebello.
Tristan is the co-Creator of Ultraspeaking,
which is the best public speaking workshop I
have ever come across. In 2017, Tristan became
the fastest competitor to reach the finals of the
world championship of public speaking. And based
on that experience, built a very unique course
that helps you quickly build the skills to become
better and to become more comfortable speaking
in public, and especially speaking on the spot.
I'd like to spend time on this topic on this
podcast because becoming a better speaker is
such an accelerant of your professional life.
And in this episode, we delve into a bunch of
tactics and also misconceptions about how to
become a better speaker, and to make it even
more fun and interesting, we go through a
few of the exercises that Tristan and his
team have developed live on the podcast. He goes
through them, I go through them, it was a lot of
fun. I'm excited to hear what you think. If you
enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting app or
YouTube. It's the best way to avoid missing future
episodes and it helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you, Tristan de Montebello.
Tristan, thank you so much for
joining me and welcome to the podcast.
Thanks so much for having me.
So I took an abridged version of this speaking
course that you teach called Ultraspeaking,
and it immediately made me feel more comfortable
public speaking, which I've never felt doing any
other course. Public speaking is something it's
just is very scary to me as it is for a lot of
people, but it's just something I really dread.
Even doing these podcast episodes, every time I
get nervous before doing these things, as much
as it may not seem that way. So this is not my
natural habitat speaking, being in public. It
may not seem that way to people, but it's true.
And the way you approach this stuff is so
unique and worked for me. And because of that,
I thought it'd be awesome to just bring you on
this podcast and basically try to teach people
the stuff that you've learned about how to become
a better public speaker. I know we're not going
to do your course here, but just, what are some
very tactical things people can immediately start
to apply? And also, I want to make the super
interactive, so we're actually going to do some
of the exercises that you use in your class. So
that's what we're here for. How does that sound?
That sounds exciting. I'm in.
Great.
This episode is brought to you by Eppo.
Eppo is a next-generation, A/B testing and feature
management platform built by alums of Airbnb and
Snowflake for modern growth teams. Companies like
Twitch, Miro, ClickUp and DraftKings rely on Eppo
to power their experiments. Experimentation is
increasingly essential for driving growth and for
understanding the performance of new features. And
Eppo helps you increase experimentation velocity
while unlocking rigorous, deep analysis in
a way that no other commercial tool does.
When I was at Airbnb, one of the things that
I loved most was our experimentation platform,
where I could set up experiments easily,
troubleshoot issues, and analyze performance
all on my own. Eppo does all that and more
with advanced statistical methods that can
help you shave weeks off experiment time and
accessible UI for diving deeper into performance,
and out-of-the-box reporting that helps you
avoid annoying prolonged analytic cycles.
Eppo also makes it easy for you to share
experiment insights with your team,
sparking new ideas for the A/B testing flywheel.
Eppo powers experimentation across every use case,
including product, growth, machine learning,
monetization, and email marketing. Check
out Eppo at geteppo.com/lenny and 10X your
experiment velocity. That's geteppo.com/lenny.
Today's episode is brought to you by Command
AI. If you're like me and most users that
I've built product for, you're probably used
to chatbots at the bottom right of websites,
where you ask a question and it says something
like, " Check out these three helpful articles.
Did that answer your question?" And then you
click away and then a few seconds later you get
bombarded with some other useless pop-ups. For
those of us who work on software, no one wants
their product to feel like this. Command AI is an
AI power toolkit for support, product, growth and
marketing teams that embeds in your company's
product. The AI support agent can deflect
upwards of 80% of support questions, providing
actually useful answers, and it can magically
co-browse with your users to show them around
your interface. They do pop-ups too, but their
nudges are based on in-product behaviors like
confusion or intent classification, which makes
them much less annoying and much more impactful.
Command AI works with web apps, mobile apps and
websites, and they work with industry-leading
companies like Gusto, Freshworks, HashiCorp,
LaunchDarkly, and over 25 million end users
interact with Command AI interfaces. To try out
Command AI. You can sign up at command.ai/lenny
and experience a custom demo of how it
works in your app. That's command.ai/lenny.
Okay, so let me first ask just kind of a broad
question. What do most people get wrong about
public speaking? What are some of, what's maybe
the biggest misconception about how to become a
better public speaker and how to be good at it?
I actually think that the biggest
misconception with tackling your
speaking is that people grossly underestimate
just how transformative it could be to your
life. And the reason it's so transformative is
because speaking is not a specialized skill,
it's a meta skill. That means that the better
you get at speaking, the better your life gets.
So an example of a meta skill is fitness,
for example. If you were to start saying,
"Okay, I'm going to transform my fitness," and you
start lifting weights and you start going on runs,
obviously your muscles are going to get bigger,
you're going to get more in shape, and your
cardiovascular system is going to improve. But
that's actually only a sliver of the impact
it's going to have on your life because you're
going to start feeling more energy, and you're
going to start having these nice hormones, these
endorphins flowing through your body and you're
going to feel better about yourself. And when you
walk in front of the mirror, suddenly you're going
to have a boost in confidence. So naturally,
everything else in your life is going to start
to improve as a result of you focusing on your
fitness. And for speaking, it's the same thing.
This blew my mind when I went on my own speaking
journey, is when I started making breakthroughs in
speaking, other things started to feel different.
So as you get breakthroughs, how you feel at work
feels different. How you feel in your group
of friends feels different. How you feel in
a group of strangers, especially, how you feel
and your family can even be impacted. This seeps
into everything else in your life. But the thing
is, because there's so much self-consciousness
that goes with speaking, we often feel kind of
constraints under the layers of overthinking and
anxiety that come with speaking. So it can be
hard to realize that underneath these layers,
you actually have this extraordinary superpower,
because as humans we're evolved to speak,
this is what we are. So you don't need to
teach a baby how to speak, it will learn
by itself with no formal education. So what that
means is, we all have this incredible hardware.
The thing is, over the course of our life, because
of all these little situations that happen, we
start getting bugs in the software and we're not
really upgrading our software. The moment you get
the bugs and things start working, not working, we
start avoiding, and suddenly it's like we're not
upgrading our software anymore. So we're stuck on
old, buggy software. But the reality is, let's not
forget that we have incredible software that were
evolved for this. So all we need to do is some
debugging and some upgrading of the software and
suddenly your entire life can change. So that's
really one I want to impart on anybody listening.
You have it in, you already have what it takes.
Okay. So kind of building on what you just
talked about, some of this insight of,
your life can improve and how you kind of always
have to unlearn stuff. One of my favorite maybe
core insights and tenets of the way you approach
teaching people to speak, is you talk about how
if you don't enjoy speaking, you're doing it
wrong. And that really helped me because you
kind of encourage, you kind of remind people, try
to have fun as you're doing. Can you just talk
about that insight and why that's important
and how that helps people become better?
Well, I think that's very tied to what you
were saying. I see enjoyment as a barometer,
if I'm doing things right, I'm probably
enjoying myself. If I'm doing things wrong,
particularly with speaking, because again, this
is something we're naturally evolved to do. So
if we're naturally evolved to do it, it's not
something that we dislike doing. It has to be
something that rewards us. So as soon as things
start not feeling enjoyable, it's a sign, hey,
I'm probably doing this wrong, guy. There's
something here that I'm doing that is making
this unenjoyable that's probably not helping me.
And I think you mentioned that in those people
who can hold an audience who are really good
communicators in business, it looks like they
feel very comfortable, it looks like they feel
like themselves. And if you think about speaking,
when you're talking with your kids, or with
your partner, or with your best friend,
your childhood friend, your parents, ever, we
all have environments where we feel completely
like ourselves. And when we do, communication
is extraordinarily enjoyable. It's just a
means to connect with other people, a means to
share what we have on our mind and it's very,
very empowering and it feels very good.
Then I take the same person with the same
skill set and the same ability and I bring them in
a business setting, and suddenly I don't feel like
myself anymore. And because of the pressure, I
start trying to speak differently. So people start
having, I'm going to try to think really hard of
what I need to say and I want to control the words
that are going to come out of my mouth before
they come out of my mouth so I make sure I don't
make a mistake. And you basically loop in this
thing that is so counter what communication is,
which is just a natural subconscious scale.
So using speaking as a barometer of, hey,
if this is not feeling good, I'm probably
overthinking. I probably need to relax and try
to just feel a little bit more like myself.
But this also applies to practice,
where in your practice, because this is not an
overnight thing, you can't just snap your fingers,
read a book, and be a better speaker. Well,
your practice has to be enjoyable as well
because otherwise two weeks in, you're going to
quit just like a shitty fitness journey or diet.
Right? You have to find joy in it and it has to be
structured in a way where it rewards you as well,
so that you get more energy and you
get more enjoyment while you do it.
Awesome, and we're going to show people
how you do that. You do these games,
they're games that you play that help you
actually learn these skills. So before that,
and also I want to get into actual tactics that
we can just give people to become better public
speakers. But right before we get there, are
there any other core insights or principles
or lessons that are fundamental to the way
you found that it works to become a better
public speaker, that kind of inform a lot of
the stuff we're going to be talking about?
The day I understood that speaking was a
subconscious flow-oriented process and not
a conscious process, completely changed the
way I approached it. So instead of thinking
tactics and frameworks and adding more to the
outside of the things I need to think about,
when I realized when I speak best, I'm actually
not thinking about speaking. It's the last thing
I think about is the speaking part. I'm
completely in tune with whatever it is I'm
trying to convey to my audience or the person
in front of me. And the goal is to get into a
flow state and stay in that flow state all the
way through the finish line. That's what really,
really changed my mindset about speaking,
because then it changes all of the exercise,
the exercises you want to do. It changes
how you can think about speaking.
And one of the ways that changed
how I practiced was, instead of
focusing on the symptoms of speaking, I started to
try and figure out, well, what are the root causes
that create these symptoms, and can I address
those? So instead of counting my filler words, if
that's something that's annoying to me, I'm going
to go back and try to figure out, well, what's the
root cause of that? Well, the root cause of having
lots of filler words or racing in your speaking,
is that you probably struggle to feel comfortable
slowing down, relaxing, or even pausing when your
mind is racing and you feel pressure. Solve
that, and not only do the filler words take
care of themselves, but the racing takes care
of itself and you suddenly have more mind space.
And if you feel super constrained
in your speaking, very monotonous,
then maybe you feel boxed in and you're
struggling to allow yourself to feel to
be all of what you are under pressure because
there's probably a lack of certainty. A lack of
trust in, hey, if I let myself be more intense or
if I let some of these emotions pop out, or if I
take a time to gather my thoughts, is everything
going to unravel, or is that going to work for me?
And if you haven't proven that to yourself, then
you're just going to go for safety and so you're
going to be very monotonous and constrained, and
that's creates monotony. But if I can solve that,
suddenly I have freedom. So thinking through this
and understanding that the goal here is upgrading
the software and it's really layering, taking
all the bad habits away and putting in new habits
that I can just stay in this flow state without
getting pulled out, that really changes the game.
That is a really interesting insight,
and I love that you actually demoed that
in the way you answered this question,
where you took time to get into that state
and not just get, um... It's just like, pause.
Pause.
Yeah, that was a really
beautiful example of that. Okay,
let's get into a few tactics just
to give people something they can-
Sure.
... actually change about the way they
speak this week. What are two or three
things that you can recommend people
tweak in the way that they do public
speaking, in the way they speak in
meetings and presentations, whatever?
I actually thought about this because once
you think about speaking being much more
about the root causes, like play the games
that are going to change you at the root,
don't focus on the symptoms, then you find
yourself sharing much less purely tactical
advice and frameworks because we're trying to
get out of our brain into our subconscious.
So when I thought about it, I thought of three
things I wanted to share. One makes you sound
better or look better, one makes you sound better,
and one makes you feel better. So the first makes
you look better. Now this is super basic and very
crunchy, but it's a bad habit that a lot of people
have. That when I am trying to gather my thoughts
or think, people tend to look down. And if you're
looking down on Zoom, it's three times as bad
because it looks like you're looking at your phone
or looking at notes if you had any, but even when
you're in person, it doesn't look very confident.
And so you're suddenly giving off of that vibe of,
oh, this person feels a little bit uncertain here,
and maybe it's going to look like you stopped
speaking and you might get more interrupted.
If instead you switch that up and you start
thinking up. I think up into the right, but you
can think in any direction you want, but as long
as you're looking up, you actually look thoughtful
by default. So suddenly you're looking thoughtful.
That means you look more confident because anybody
who'd be willing to pause in their speaking
is somebody who's confident. And as a result,
you're much less likely to get interrupted. So
it's a small tweak but makes a real difference.
The only thing is if you're not used to
doing this, if this is not your habit,
then it's going to feel a little bit awkward the
first time you do it and you probably won't think
about doing it. So I recommend writing,
think up, on a post-it and putting it on
your computer so that it's there for you.
And then once you've done it a few times,
this will become the new normal and by
default, you'll look more confident.
I'm going to do this as we talk. I
have a poster right here. Think up.,
Oh, nice. Think up.
Okay, great. What else?
Look more confident. Now how to sound more
confident. This is a really important one,
and this concept is called end strong. And it's,
we had to bring this up because most people tend
to end weak. And why is that? They put freestyle
rappers in an fMRI, and what they found out is
freestyle rappers have to enter a deep flow state.
If you're freestyle rapping, you have a beat, you
don't have any lyrics, and you have to get into
the beat and invent the lyrics and the melody and
everything on the fly. So there's no choice but
being completely present. What happens is you can
see their brain and it's lit up in a very specific
place that shows that they're in flow, and when
they get to the very end, the brain just blows up.
Before they finish, they start getting pulled out
of flow. And this is the same feeling of you're
running at school and you see the finish line and
just a few yards before you start slowing down.
It's just, I don't know, we're built that way.
And in speaking, it's the same thing. People
tend to give a great answer and then either
they kind of taper off at the end, which
doesn't leave you with a good impression,
or they'll actively say the doubts that are
coming up in their mind of maybe they'll be
giving a great answer and then suddenly they
say, "I don't really know if that makes sense."
I do that all the time. That's very relatable.
Yeah, but what the thing is, what happens
when you do that? When you do that,
it's like you're forcing this lens on your
audience, where now even if they had the best of
experiences with your answer, now they're looking
at everything you said through the lens of, oh,
this person was kind of uncertain. So it's like
you had a very smooth flight across the Atlantic
and your landing was absolutely horrible. You were
bumpy when you were coming up, and then when you
hit the landing, you bounced three times and you
thought you were going to die. You're not going
to remember the smooth flight, you're going to
remember the ending. So a simple tactic here is,
anticipate that as you get to the end of anything
you're saying, you're going to naturally start
regaining consciousness and you're going to start
being a little bit more self-aware, and some of
those uncertainties are going to pop up. Know
that it's coming and make sure you land the plane.
So what that looks like is, either you just
make your ending sound like an ending and then
leave it at that, or you can prompt your
brain. You can use summary prompts, this
is incredibly powerful. It just means you say the
beginning of a sentence or the beginning of, yeah,
the beginning of a sentence, and your brain's
going to fill in the gap. It's going to. You're
prompting your brain and your brain will always
deliver. So you get to the end, you're like,
okay, I got to wrap up now. And so you'll say, "So
to wrap up..." And your brain's going to fill in
the gap. Or, "In summary, so my point here is, so
what I want you to remember," and you just place
those words and your brain's naturally going
to do the work of closing it for you. But make
sure you don't let go of the gas pedal at the
very last moment, you need to land that plane.
Awesome. I could definitely
get better at this, great tip.
Yeah, thanks.
I'm going to try to do that as we talk.
Yes.
And what else we got?
I'll be paying attention to that.
Okay, pressure.
Yeah. The third one is staying in character. And
these go hand in hand. And what's really powerful
is when you start doing these, there's a beautiful
feedback loop that happens that gives you a lot of
confidence. So staying in character I said is the
one that's going to make you feel more confident.
What's staying in character? So it's related to
end strong in some sense, in that people tend to
self-sabotage a lot. I'm speaking, and obviously
as I'm speaking, all of my senses are really,
really heightened. So I'm aware of everything,
if a word comes out a little bit weird or if
it's not the word that I was expecting to hear
come out of my mouth, I'm going to be very aware
of that because I was expecting something and
something different happens. But that happens
all the time when speaking. I'm starting to not
make as much sense or I feel like I'm rambling,
going a little bit too long. All of these
create insane noise in the back of my mind,
the insecurities. And you have a choice there,
because I can tell you right now, nobody can
tell. People cannot see what you feel, even
though it feels that way when you feel really,
really strongly, but people can't see it.
You're just looking like a normal speaker,
competent and confident. But internally,
it feels like everybody can see.
So you're feeling all this insecurity and it feels
like there's an elephant in the room. And so what
most people do is they start leaking and they
break character. And they'll say, "Oh, man,
I'm not making sense right now," or they'll laugh
nervously after saying a word that came out weird,
which is kind of saying like, "Oh, I also
noticed that this word came out weird and
it's okay." Right? Or they'll keep letting all of
the insecurities and doubts come out when people
didn't see it in the first place. So again, it's
like I'm forcing these filters onto my audience
and now they can only see me through that light.
And so one analogy I love for this is, again, a
flying analogy. You're on the plane, everything's
smooth, you're having a great time watching your
movie, and suddenly you're interrupted by the
pilot who picks up the intercom and says, "Oh,
ladies and gentlemen, so I just had a red
light start blinking here in the cockpit,
and I'm not sure what this is. It could be really
bad, honestly, but I don't know. So don't worry,
please, I'll get back to you soon." First thing
that's going to happen if you experience that
is you're going to think, I wasn't worrying in
the first place. But then you start thinking,
wait, something probably is going
wrong. And now the smallest noise,
the tiny little bit of turbulence, a creak
on the right, you're going to start thinking,
oh no, we're going to die, every time.
So you're going to make any little mistake,
any little imperfection, you're going to turn
that into something big. That's what happens
when you speak. If you start leaking
and letting the insecurities come out,
people are going to start thinking, this person
doesn't really know what they're talking about.
It's like a leader who isn't clear in their
direction. Suddenly I'm thinking, wait, I think
I have to second guess everything here because
I'm not sure about this guy or this person.
And the good news is, the solution is very,
very simple. The solution is that is just,
don't share your insecurities. Put your best
foot forward and stay in it the whole time.
Stay in character from beginning all the way
through past the ending, because you go all
the way through your speech, then you got to end
strong, which is a form of staying in character,
and then let it be. And that's so important, just
let it be and you're going to notice something
incredible. If you're the type of person who would
break character a lot, start staying in character,
and the cue use for myself is, stay in it. And
the worse it gets, the more I'll say, just stay
in it. And what happens is, you stay in it.
And you expect everybody at the end to say,
"Oh my God, you looked so uncomfortable, what
was happening?" But people can't see that,
that you look confident. So they're just going
to give you the reaction that a confident person
would get, and you're going to notice,
oh wow, I am coming off as confident,
and that's going to make you feel more confident.
And so it's a very reinforcing cycle. If you start
staying in character and ending strong, naturally,
you're going to be reinforced by this behavior
and you're going to realize, oh, I didn't need to
break character. I didn't need to hedge every time
I spoke, and that's going to give you much more
confident, and you're going to start realizing,
people just look confident by default. This is a
crazy thing. I want everybody to walk around the
world and look at people and think, most of the
people I'm looking at are actually nervous right
now. You're going to look at them and you're
like, I can't tell. Most people speaking up
in meetings are feeling a level of nervousness,
but you can't tell unless it's through the roof.
I love this, and it's something I'm
extremely guilty of. And I think the reason
I do this and the reason I
think a lot of people leak,
which I love that term of just I don't leak,
that you know, feel something's not going
right. The reason I do it is I feel like
me being upfront, I know this isn't great-
Exactly.
... makes it okay, but in reality,
that's hurting you because it's like
when I watch standup comedy. When
the comedian's like, "Oh, sorry,
that bombed," if he didn't say that or she
didn't say that, I'd just forget about it,
and we'd move on to the next thing. And it
brings all this attention to, oh, I see,
okay, it's not going great. Otherwise,
you're just like, all right, whatever,
I didn't like that joke. And so, yeah, I guess
any thoughts on just that, why people do this?
Well, I think that's exactly that. It's because
you're convinced that everybody can tell. And
so two things will happen. Either they could
tell because it was a big thing and everybody
could tell, but you shining light on it is
literally that. It's like, hey, everybody,
you're driving a train, everybody's in the
train, you're the driver as the speaker,
everybody's going with you. So if there's a crash
on the side of the road, you can keep going and
they'll not be looking at the crash a second later
and they'll be looking at the next landscape,
or you can stop the train and tell everybody,
"Hey, let's look at this crash here real quick.
I'm so sorry about it." When you keep going,
people will forget it in a second and they're
not going to pay attention to you. And with
the peak end rule, what we we're seeing, people
remember the end of experiences more than they
remember the beginning of experiences. So you're
going to be left with that feeling at the end.
The other piece is, because most people won't
notice it in the first place, they'll be
in their own minds. So when you share this,
you're popping their bubble. And so I see people
speaking all the time where I'm super in tune with
the feeling I'm getting when they're speaking.
I'm listening to the energy, I'm listening to
everything that's happening, so I can try to
understand, what state are they in right now? So
when I get woken up from that state of somebody
saying, "Oh man, can I go again right now? That
really sucked." It's even more visible for me.
And I'll often have to say, "Hey, man,
I was so into what you were saying," and I'll
poll the audience, "is anyone surprised?" And
everybody every time is like, "No, I thought that
you were doing great. I was completely with you."
So that's the case most of the time, but because
we're convinced that people can tell, we want to
break that fourth wall or because something
happened and we know people can tell, we want
to acknowledge it so it doesn't feel like I'm the
only one in the room who can't tell that something
went wrong here. But this habit of saying, "No,
I'm going to be confident, I'm leading, I'm going
to keep us going in a certain direction," is
extremely powerful and very self-reinforcing.
Okay, so let's actually show people what this
looks like by actually doing some live games.
I know one of your principles for Ultraspeaking is
you can't learn to speak by not speaking. You need
to practice speaking to get better at speaking,
and these games are a way to actually do that in
a really fun way. So maybe first of all, just why
games? When I did this course, I was just like,
huh, because it's a bunch of games. I thought
this was a public speaking course. So maybe talk
about just why you approach it through games,
everything you do is a game in this course.
Yeah. Well, the first piece of the
puzzle is what you were saying,
that you can't get better at speaking
without speaking. And it's, intuitively
you could think, everybody knows that if you want
to become a great cook, you can't just read 100-
Everybody knows that if you want to become a great
cook, you can't just read a hundred cookbooks. You
actually have to spend most of your time in the
kitchen refining your intuition, testing things,
experimenting, learning new recipes, and building
your timing and everything that goes with it.
But in speaking, we tend to do the opposite,
probably because it's a little bit scary and
because there aren't that many options out there
to practice the speaking itself. There aren't that
many environments where you can do it right now.
So we're kind of left with nothing, so, "Okay,
I'll just go read an article or watch a YouTube
short and hope that's going to make a difference."
But maybe the bad news is, you have to do it. You
have to ask yourself, "Am I going to be serious
about taking on speaking and making a difference
here?" And if you are, then you're going to have
to do the thing. You have to practice speaking.
But the good news is, it's only the outside
that's scary. As soon as you get started, you're
going to get rewarded. And then, the better you
get at it, the more enjoyable it becomes.
So why games then? Well, games number one,
are fun to play. And as I was saying earlier, if
your practice is not fun, you're going to stop. So
you need intrinsic reward with what you're doing.
But what all of the Ultraspeaking games have in
common is that it's short, deliberate practice,
short reps followed by feedback, followed by
another rep. So that was more important
than the idea that it was a game at first.
When we started coaching with Michael Gendler, my
co-founder, it was just him and me in my backyard
with somebody in front of us testing things out.
And we would say, we would give him a speech title
just to get a baseline. "Okay, what's the most
incredible invention in the world?" And we'd watch
this person go into their mind and start freaking
out. And they'd think, " The iPhone," and then,
"I don't know the iPhone. That's pretty recent.
So maybe it's fire. Is it fire though? Was there
a bigger maybe communication? I don't know.
Wait. Maybe we've evolved for communication."
And the longer they spent thinking,
the worse their answer tended to be,
and the more their confidence tended to go down
as they were speaking. So then we said, "Well,
we've got to get this person speaking right
away." So we'd say, "I'm going to ask you
another question, but just start speaking."
And so, I'd ask them another question and
they couldn't start speaking right away.
So we just tried to compress it more and
more and more to turn it into something where then
it was like, "I'm just going to say a word and you
have to say something about it, so horses."
"Horseback riding is fun because you can go
places." "Cats." "Cats are crazy because if they
were bigger, they would eat you." And I just,
almost like word association. Let's get words out.
Then we started developing different games for
everything. Every root cause we were
seeing, every symptom we were seeing,
we'd figure out the root cause and we'd
create some sort of a way to get the person
into it as quickly as possible. And it's just
one day, six months in that we realized, "Hey,
did we just create a game? This feels like a
board game." And then we created, I have this,
we created Speak Before You Think, the game
for people who think too much, and this is a
bunch of cards with all of our games. And then,
Covid hit and we turned it into online games.
Oh, I didn't know that.
Yeah. The magic of games is short reps,
immediate feedback, practice feedback,
practice feedback. And it's enjoyable, you
get rewarded, you get to adjust as you go.
And what's changing is your internal feeling
as you're going. So you're learning lessons,
but you're internalizing. All of the
practice is happening through speaking.
To reinforce what you just shared, I haven't
shared this with you, but after I took the
course, the mini course, I went to see my
family in L.A. We visited for a few days,
and I was talking about this course and just how
fun it was and interesting and how much I learned
from it. And I pulled up the games because I have
access to the things online. I was just like,
"Hey, you guys want to try this?" and we started
playing some of these games that we're about to
get into. And it was just, we spent like an
hour just doing this and everyone loved it.
Wow.
Everyone just felt so much better about
their public speaking. Afterwards,
my mom was like, "Hey, how do
I do that on my own later?"
Wow, that's cool.
My sister's like, "I want to start doing open mic
nights because that was really fun just to talk."
Nice.
So were you actually coaching them? How were
you walking them through the different games?
We just pulled them up and played them.
And then, I shared some of the tips that
I learned in the class that we took, just like,
"Try it this way" or "Try not to focus on being
correct. Just focus on confidence and not
leaking that you're not doing great." All
these things we're going to talk about. Yeah.
So it was a lot of fun. So let's get into some
of these games. So we're going to try two or
three. Which one do you want to start with?
Conductor maybe.
Sweet. I love Conductor. That
one was really insightful to me.
Okay, so I've got Conductor. The way this game
works is that when I click "start training,"
I'm going to have a random title that's going
to appear. And for those of you who are just
listening and not watching this, Lenny will say
the title out loud so you can hear. And then,
what you won't see or what you'll see if you're
watching is in front of me, all I'm going to see
are a series of random numbers. It's going to
start with five, and five is just my natural
rate of speaking like I'm speaking right now. But
then, I might see a number from one to 10, and
each one of these numbers represents an intensity
or a state that I have to tap into. So if I see a
seven, I automatically have to raise my voice and
get into that kind of an energy. And if I see a
10, you could only imagine what that is. But it's
also true for the lower ones. If suddenly I see a
three, I have to find a way to calm my energy and
match the three and go all the way down to one.
And then, there might be a slide that says
"breathe," which is just an indication to pause.
And when I see that slide "breathe," if I just go
silent, that's because I'm in front of the breathe
slide and I'm not allowed to speak. And in that
moment, my goal is just to relax myself and calm
myself and then see what happens where I'm at when
that slide moves on to the next one. And now we're
going to do this. This is going to be 70
seconds, so it's going to be super quick. Ready?
Yeah. So I'll read the
title as soon as it pops up.
Perfect.
"When I grow up."
When I grow up, I want to have taken on all of
my weaknesses or all of the emotional things
that are holding me back. Because kind of
annoying for me that I'm 40 years old and
there's still things that are holding me back
that man, I've had these when I was a kid.
I was like this when I was 10. And it drives
me crazy, because aren't I supposed to be an
adult? Aren't I supposed to be mature and have
my life together? I have two kids. I have this
incredible responsibility. And I have to
teach them, I have to show them the way.
So I've decided I'm going to hire a coach,
and I talked to him just a couple of days ago,
so this is perfect timing because I
want to unwrap, unravel, and untwine
every single one of these emotional blockers
so that when I grow up, I'm completely free.
That was so fun to watch. I'm seeing
the numbers. If you're on YouTube,
you can see what's going on there. If
you're not, basically there's different
numbers that give Tristan the different
energies to be at, and that was masterful.
I think we saw, what did we see? We
saw a six. It went up first, six,
seven, then it went down to three. Then we
saw, I think a two, a one, then a breathe,
and then it went back to a five. How
about you give it a go and then we chat.
Let's do it. What do you think?
Ladies and gentlemen, let's see this. Here
we go. The title is The Greatest Puzzle.
The greatest puzzle that I think that I've had
in my life, and I think just for most people,
is trying to figure out what to do with
their life. And I just had to spend so much
time thinking... Actually, no, let me change.
I'm changing direction. I actually have known
from very early on what I wanted to do with my
life. I've actually found it to be not much of a
puzzle. I knew from pretty early that I wanted
to be a software engineer. And interestingly,
I became a software. And as I think about
the puzzle that created around my life,
I ended up... So my life actually started
to look like a puzzle instead of what I'd
always thought I'd be. So I ended up having a
bunch of different careers. And I look back at
my life and it started with one piece, and each
piece led to all these other careers. Nailed it.
It's funny. At the end you were like, you
didn't even see there was a six that came
up and then when you looked up, it had
already gone away. That's a good warm-up.
Yeah, yeah. Let's do it.
It's funny, because what it
looked like to me is that, well,
you just didn't let yourself play the game.
You wanted to... You were more focused on,
"I want to make sure this works well, this
looks good, or I don't make a fool of myself"
than "Let me just play the game." So switch your
mindset from that. Back in the Creator Cohort,
you didn't really care, because if you failed,
it didn't matter. So you just played the game.
And this is the same idea. Just don't
try. Just let yourself play the game.
Okay.
The game will do good. But that was actually
really interesting. I feel kind of similar,
which is cool, except I didn't know where
it was going. But that feeling of all of
these puzzle pieces, and suddenly when
I hit Ultraspeaking, it's like, "Oh wow,
every single... There's no more. There are
no more gaps." That's really cool. Okay.
Here we go.
You ready?
Ready.
Here we go. "Integrating new cultures."
It's interesting having a kid. So we just had a
kid about a year ago, he is a year and a half.
And there's an interesting new experience
where there's my family and their culture,
there's my wife and her culture. And it was never
a big deal for us, these different backgrounds
that we have because we could do our own thing,
we have our families, they're doing their thing.
But now that we have a kid, I have to really
think about this. I have to constantly wonder,
"Is he getting both experiences? Is he being
pushed in one direction or another? Is he
going to get the full benefits of both of these
cultures?" And I find if I don't actually think
about it too deeply and just let him have fun
and hang out with our different family members,
he gets everything that I want him to get;
that he experiences my wife's family's culture,
my family's culture, and then the combination
of my wife and I's new kind of culture and
family that we're building. And so, I'm
really excited about the future for us all.
Yeah, that was awesome.
I'm practicing not leaking. All I think
about is how much better it could have been,
but now I'm leaking as I say that. See?
Yeah.
It's hard.
Yeah. You're hedging.
Hedging.
So the point of all of these games is to create
turbulence. This is going to be the theme of
this podcast. I'm going to share only flight
analogies. But if you think about a pilot, a
flight simulator, you can think about these games
as the flight simulator. You don't put a pilot in
a flight simulator and waste those precious hours
having them just cruise at 30,000 feet in clear
skies. You're going to say, "Okay, you're going
and now hey, you've lost your captain and you
have to do something" or "Hey, your motor just
broke" or "You're going into crazy turbulence."
So the gain here is always, every one
of these games have in common that we're
creating turbulence for you. So it's on purpose
that like, "Ooh, that's interesting how I tend
to want to leak, to want to break character.
Wow. It's interesting how at the end,
the ending strong is not just an automatic
habit that I've built for myself." So what
we want with the turbulence is that it
highlights areas that we want to work on.
And you can go again and see immediately because
you have that same pressure every time. There's
no way you can prepare for Conductor.
You can do just a ton of reps and get
to become the person who can just navigate
the turbulence really, really gracefully.
Which reminds me of a Kevin Kelly
quote that I love where he says,
"Pros are just amateurs who've learned to recover
gracefully from their mistakes." And this is what
we're trying to do here. If you know that you
can recover from any mistake gracefully, then
you're going to have confidence in any speaking
scenario. And most of the scenarios you're going
to be in are spontaneous, are ones you can't
prepare for. So it's that much more important.
So tell me, what do you remember from going
through Conductor and the Creator Cohort,
or specifically here, what was coming up and what
were some of the things that pop into your mind?
There's two things that I
really took away from it,
and it's different doing it now on
camera with this whole podcast thing.
Yeah.
But the things that I really took away that
have stuck with me from this exercise is one,
is that you have this kind of metaphor of these
file folders that you have kind of in your head
where every energy level, like a one when you
go low and a 10 or even a five, when you're at
that energy level, you access different insights
and memories and stories. So it's not just like,
"Now I'm going to say the same thing at a 10, or
I'm going to say the same thing at a one." It's
when you let your body just slow down and relax
to a one, new thoughts come up, because making
it up as you go along and you're just trying to
figure it out as you go. And that really happens
when you're forced to go from five to, "Okay," and
you let your body settle into a one. You're like,
"Oh, okay, here's a new thought that comes
to mind." So that was really powerful for
me because I never had realized that.
And then, the other is just this idea of
doing these really hard things with very low
stakes. It's higher stakes, so maybe that's
why it's different, how it feels different
doing it here where it's like, "Oh, this is-"
Yeah. Yeah, this is extremely high stakes for you.
Yeah, relatively. But yeah, there it's a couple
people and you're like, just don't worry about
failing so you don't even have to worry about
apologizing or fleaking. It's just like,
"Yeah, I did what I did." So those are
two really powerful ones. I just like
practicing this. And knowing you'll be okay
at low stakes builds confidence. I'm like,
"Okay." It's making up a minute of talk about the
most random thing on the spot, not something that
I would feel I'd want to do, but then you
realize, "Okay, it's fine. I can do that."
The common theme for me, and I've been on this
journey for seven years now, I still am blown
away every week by the lessons I've learned
over the course of the seven years, which all
come down to your brain, your subconscious is so
incredibly powerful. So your hardware is magical.
And because I've spent seven years kind of getting
rid of the bad habits, getting rid of the gunk and
trusting myself more, I allow myself to take many
more risks. So I'm jumping into these games still
with the same doubts in some sense, but they've
just, everything's tapered down way, way, way into
the background. So I get to be much more present.
And I talked about the summary prompts earlier in
the podcast, saying the beginning of a sentence
and trusting that your brain's going to fill in
the gap is something that's initially hard
to do. But when you've done it 1,000, 2,000,
10,000 times, you start believing, "Hey,
maybe my brain will deliver every single
time." So you can start saying the beginning of
sentences the direction you want to go into and
your brain fills in the gap, and we're
going to do a game on that in a second.
But the Conductor one is so beautiful because
the way we describe it, so that folder one when
it came into my mind was my favorite ever. But
the original one was when you tap into a certain
energy, that creates emotion. And if you
tap into that emotion, the words come as
a natural consequence. So it's energy leads,
emotions follow, and words fill in the gap.
And when you experience this for yourself, if
you go into Conductor and you play, you realize,
"Okay, if I want more conviction, I can raise my
energy or get into a state of conviction and the
words that are going to come out, the ideas, the
stories, the anecdotes, the examples, everything
is going to fit into that. If I feel frustrated,
I can dive into that state and stay in that state,
and naturally the content is going to follow. It's
a very, very powerful game. It's a very exciting
game, and it's a game that, especially when you're
playing with low stakes, you very quickly feel the
effect of, "Oh, I can see the potential of what it
could be if I could just be like this anywhere."
Maybe you taper out a little bit of the extremes.
But you can access this for free on Ultraspeaking
or the way we did this at first, you just
go to Google and type in a random series of
nine numbers and then just have a friend say each
number, one after the next, and you just match it.
I used to just put my hand out and go up and down.
So in essence, it's very, very simple to apply it.
And it's just like a lot of fun to just get an
excuse to just go wild and high and then just
get low. I love that part of it. And let's
get into the next theme. But just one other
insight I had that you shared with me when I did
it the first time is just people have a strength.
Yes.
They're either, correct me if I'm wrong,
they're strong at the highs and just very
uncomfortable at the lows or the opposite.
And for me, I thought I was going to, "Oh,
obviously I'll be more natural at the lows,
because like introvert world." And you're like,
"No, you're actually super
energized at this high end,
and then it's hard for you to access the low."
And I thought that was really insightful for me.
Yeah. You'll notice it pretty
quickly once you jump in,
especially with a friend. It's cool
because when you get to see, "Oh,
I'm much more comfortable going up than I am
going down or vice versa, or I'm stuck in the
middle and I am only comfortable when I'm not in
the extremes." It's just telling you something.
This is what we want. We want to a mirror
in front of us so I can know, "Okay,
what's happening here?" I'm not very much a fan
of actually watching yourself on camera on video,
because again, this is an inner game, not an
outer game. So when I watch myself on video,
I see the outside, which can be useful for
certain things, but the fundamentals are inside.
So getting a mirror of I play this game and I feel
a certain way, "Oh, interesting. It was easy to go
up." So I can muster energy pretty quickly,
and I'm willing to take risks of jumping into
a different energy stage, which might mean
changing the direction of where I'm going.
But slowing down means I need to be willing to
take up space. I need to be willing to just be
while everybody's looking at me and I'm using
up their time. But I'm going to take up space
and I'm going to take a moment to go inside
and be introspective and really ask myself,
"Okay, what do I want to say here?"
And so, that's a reflection of, "Well,
what does that mean if I struggle to do that?" And
that's why speaking such an interesting skill set.
All right, let's do another game.
This next game is called Triple Step. And Triple
step is a game for people who struggle to stay
on a single thought or get very easily put off
their game or distracted. If you're the type
of person where you're speaking and suddenly
somebody yawns and you just start freaking
out thinking, "I'm so boring and things
are horrible, I must be terrible." Not,
they probably have a baby and they didn't
sleep last night. A pen drops and you start
losing your ability to stay on track, this
is a game for you. Also, a very fun one.
The principle of the game is pretty simple.
Similarly to Conductor, we're going to start
with a random speech title. So I have no idea
what's going to show up. Then as I'm speaking,
in this setting here, I'm going to speak for a
minute. There will six random words or series
of words that are going to pop up as I'm going
through my speech. And my goal is to integrate
the words into the speech as seamlessly as I can,
as if they were part of the speech the whole time.
So in theory, if I do a perfect job, if you're
listening, you should struggle to pick out which
words were actually the words that were popped up.
The likelihood in one minute of me being able to
do that is low, but let's see if you can do it. So
if you're listening, you're not going to see the
words. We'll tell you afterwards what they were.
See if you can pick up on them. But otherwise,
my goal is just to choose a strong direction and
stay on that direction as naturally as I can.
Here we go. The title is, How Would Your Friends
Describe You? I've been described as a Labrador
by my friends. And I think the reason people
describe me as a Labrador is because I am so
easy to excite. It's like if you give me a box
of french fries, I'm going to go nuts and it's
going to be the best french fries I've ever tasted
in my life. But if the next day I get a massage,
I'll be completely in that experience and the
massage is going to be the best massage. And then,
I'm going to think, "I need to get a massage
every day." I'm going to start daydreaming
about massage as my natural day to day.
But the problem with being a Labrador is
that Labradors get kind of excited. So
I may be doing cartwheels one second,
and the next second I'm supposed to be working.
And so, I'll be on my computer, but then I hear
the microwave ding and I think, "Oh, maybe I
should go get some food next." And so, there's a
beautiful trait to being the Labrador that allows
me to explore all of what it's like to be human.
I always have access to the internet inside me,
but there are definitely some drawbacks as well.
Okay. So the words that you had to
integrate are french fries, getting a
massage, daydreaming, cartwheels,
a microwave, and the internet.
Yeah. And so, you might notice that some
of the words I'm integrating literally,
and some I might integrate more metaphorically
like the internet of my mind. It's like I have
access to the internet. So you can give yourself
as much leeway as possible. The whole point here
with Triple Step is you want to be that tree in
the storm that is not so rigid that if the wind
is too strong it's going to break in half, but not
so flexible that it's going to swing every which
direction as soon as there's a gust. So you want
that firm solid grounding, which is in choosing a
clear direction, that one thing off the bat, and
then you want to make the words work for you. So
stay focused on that one thing. And as the words
come in, the more focused you are on that groove
you've created for yourself, the easier it
will be to let the words work for you. Okay?
And again, the skill this builds
is to be more comfortable with
things not going perfectly and being distracted.
Yeah. I would say this one can be used for
two other things. Number one is resiliency,
right? Because this one will make your brain go
crazy. And if you can stay composed within it,
with all of these things happening, it
really builds this ability to say, "Well,
man, if I can do Triple Step on hard mode, I can
do anything. Why would anything else scary? Why
would an interview question scare me when I can
throw these kinds of things? I can always navigate
my way through." Right? We're trying to lower
the likelihood of a mistake really hurting you.
And then, the other piece is this is a game,
this one and a game called Rapid Fire Analogies,
are games that are really, really nice to use as
a way to warm your brain up. So you could use it
before a podcast. You could use it before a job
interview, before a meeting. When you want to
be on, do a few reps of this, and your brain's
just going to be completely lit up because it's
pulling on so many different parts of your
brain that are necessary for communication.
One last thought just before we dive into
it. I think it's just to zoom out again,
the reason that you've found this is a better
way to learn to become better at public speaking,
my sense is just if you were to just do the
standard thing of just give more talks, find
more opportunities to do presentations, it's too
broad of a brush to build these different skills,
and which you've identified is there's these very
specific skills that add up to a great presenter.
And these games pick a specific skill and help
you just focus on that again and again and again.
If you're already practicing, you're
already leagues ahead of everyone,
because most people aren't practicing. They're
you're trying to learn from a video or a YouTube
short or an article. You can only go so
far with that. But if you are practicing,
there are kind of two suboptimal ways that
might show up. One is what you're saying.
You're doing talks and you're speaking up more,
but you're not really practicing. It's kind of,
as you were saying, it's broad, broad strokes.
The other one is you are in a choreography,
so it's like learning how to dance,
but you only learn choreography.
Well, that's all you know how to do. So if I
ask you to do, I say, "Okay, now I'm going to
put music on. Just dance." You're kind of stuck
because you only know how to do the moves you were
doing. So we're trying to get people outside of,
"I have to be in my mind, or I have to do things
that I've memorized how to do" and come back to
trusting your natural ability to communicate.
So that's what we're doing here. You can feel
like when you don't speak, when you struggle with
speaking, you're stuck in this box, and everything
around you is tiny and you can feel the sides
of the box. And we're expanding the range. We're
playing around with all kinds of different things,
different tools. And all of them have specific
meaning, but even if they didn't that much, you
still would be able to, "Oh wow," you're pushing
back the sides of the box. And now suddenly, "Hey,
I can move around. I feel comfortable moving my
arms and moving my legs and going to the right
and the left and up and down." And just that
act of making you feel more comfortable and
more at ease is going to unlock your ability to
communicate, because you already know how to do a
lot of this. So we're tapping into these different
skill sets and we're doing both at the same time.
This episode is brought to you by Brave
Search. Brave Search is the private,
independent search engine that doesn't bias or
censor results. Brave Search and its answers with
AI feature are available for free to all users
on desktop and mobile devices. With Brave Search,
you get real answers faster, served from their
own independent index of the web. Their AI search
engine can give lightning fast, incredibly
accurate results for almost any question.
But Brave isn't just AI answers. It's also a
powerful traditional search engine with real
innovations versus big tech options. It fights
bias and SEO spam. It brings a cleaner results
page with fewer ads, Reddit threads in the search
engine results page, powerful local results,
and even community-driven ranking options. Tired
of big tech's same old list of links? It's time
to try Brave Search. Visit brave.com/Lenny
to get started. That's brave.com/Lenny.
All right, let's do this.
I'm energized. I'm pumped.
Let's do this.
No, I'm not going to... I was
going to say I'm going to nail it,
but no, let's just have fun. Let's have fun.
Yeah.
It goes how it goes.
Indeed. Here we go.
Okay. And I'll say the title. The best
thing about pain. So this is something
I recently shared in another talk is
just this quote that I always think of.
In another talk is just this quote that I always
think of, "The cave you fear contains the treasure
you seek," that the thing that is hardest often
points you in the direction you want to go. Like
I hate blue cheese, but sometimes I find that if
I eat the blue cheese and add it to a salad, it
ends up being the best salad I've had. Having kids
is another amazing example where just kids are...
There's so much pain, but it's also, there's
nothing that is more joyous than having a kid.
And sometimes even growing a beard. I grow this
beard and I have to maintain this beard for the
rest of my life. And I know people would
look at me without a beard and be like,
"What the hell? Well, you look so different
now and so young." Sometimes I think about
just having a sibling and the pain that
if I had a brother, if he just hit me,
the pain that would come from that, but just then
having the brother would be so much worth it,
even if he's hitting me all this time.
And there, I ran out of time, but that was solid.
Okay, I realize this is your first time playing
Triple Step. It's kind of mean of
me if you [inaudible 01:01:09]-
I have to go faster.
... Give you six words. So I'm
going to give you four words.
Okay. Okay.
But here's what I noticed. What I noticed is
you were letting the word... The word was the
beginning of a new thought. Right, so you say,
"Another thing is beers. Another thing is...".
So you're finishing your thought and then
you're moving on to the next one. Try to
hold onto one direction. The one direction
is approach your fears head on. And then,
so when you see a puzzle, it's like,
look, this doesn't have to be a hard
puzzle because now I know that if it's
scary, I do it. And it's like having kids,
which I thought was so scary, I just jumped in
and now I'm moving forward. And so it's like
I'm growing my beard without caring what other
people think just because it might be scary,
or maybe I cut my beard because that would be
something scary. So you're holding onto the line.
With four, it's going to be a little
bit easier to integrate them. Ready?
Let's do it.
Social-
Social distancing. It's interesting that social
distancing was such a thing that we all had to
do for so long. And then all of a sudden we look
back at that time we're like, "Was that actually
necessary? Did we actually have to stay far from
each other? Did that actually have any impact?".
There's all these things we have to learn,
like sometimes we look at the stock market
and we wonder, "Should I be paying attention
to the stock market? Should I be distancing
myself from it? Should I be investing more
often? Should I be reading every newspaper
that comes out every day to stay on top of
what's happening in the world? Should I get
closer to this information or should I distance
myself? What's better for me?". And sometimes
it feels like you're running this marathon where
sometimes you go back and forth. Sometimes it's,
"Let's all be together. Let's pay attention
to all the news. Let's hang out." And it
kind of feels like I just want to just
want to go to the toilet and peace out.
Amazing. That works. That's really good.
Okay.
That's really good. Well,
tell me what, because again,
the games are meant to put you in a state
of turbulence and find out what was easy,
what was hard, what am I noticing? And now
you know what you want to work on. If you
did a rep and you got it and it went perfectly,
then you're learning nothing. A really easy rep
is not worth much. The only reps that are worth
something are the ones where you feel an edge.
Yeah. And by the way, we should
say the words right, that I had.
Oh, yeah. The first one was the
stock market, then a newspaper,
which you brought in really, really well,
then running a marathon, and then toilet.
Yeah. Okay, great. Yeah, just the fact that I'm
okay doing this is a big milestone for me of
just like, ah, whatever. Because before
doing this thing I'm like, oh my God,
I never want to sit there and come up with a
talk for a minute on the most random subject,
and there's a lot of power in just feeling
comfortable just doing it, just like, sure,
let's do it. Whatever. Something will
come out that's interesting enough.
That's why taking on this journey of speaking
is so empowering because speaking is a high
performance skill. So taking on a high performance
skill, and starting to tackle it, and getting
kind of good at it is very addictive. It feels
really, really good. If you get good at tennis,
if you get good at golf, if you get
good at anything, product management,
it's a addicting, it's exciting. And as
soon as you get good, there's nuance to it,
and it's energizing in and of itself. And
because we have such awesome hardware as humans,
we've been speaking all of our life, a lot of us
have a pretty decent level to start out with. So
you really quickly, you're getting to like, "Oh,
I'm getting some results here. This actually feels
good." So there's something really energizing
about jumping into it. It's the thinking about
doing the exercise that's scary, but as soon as
you're in it, it's energizing and empowering.
And also just doing it, this is a very
hard exercise. Just giving a made up
talk for a minute with words you have to
integrate, and concepts. And I think just
doing that makes a regular talk so much easier
also, because you don't have to do that. So
there's something there about just doing it
on hard mode, learning things, and then, oh,
okay, I just have to talk about a thing that
I already know about, that I have planned,
much easier. Anything else around this game that
is worth sharing before we do our final game?
We have a whole series of games, and you
could probably even invent other games,
but some people will play Triple Step and will
say, "Wow, that's so hard." And then they'll
go and play Conductor and think, "Wow,
this is my game. This is so easy." But
other people will play Conductor and think
it's impossible, and then come play Triple
Step and they'll be like, "Man, this is my
jam. I can get this one very, very easy."
So again, it's just a mirror of where
you're at. And what's beautiful about this
is you start playing around with these games,
you're very, very quickly going to see, okay,
this is my edge. And where your edge is, as you
were saying with your quote, is often where the
gold lies. So if you can spend some time there
and learn what it is underneath the struggle,
what's actually holding you back. When you unlock
that, whatever's holding you back in Triple Step,
or in Conductor, in any other game, is holding you
back elsewhere in your life. So when you unlock it
there, it kind of unlocks the other things,
which is really nice, like a set of gears.
And it's interesting, as we were talking, where
my mind keeps going is I just want to say how
I didn't feel good about my performance, but
I'm internalizing the lesson of don't leak how
you feel. And that's a really powerful lesson.
It's really hard not to just to be like, "Oh,
that was not good." I really wanted to say that
after every time I tried this and I am making
myself not. And I imagine from your perspective
you're like, "No, it's fine. It's like whatever."
Yeah, absolutely. I was actually thinking, I bet
a lot of people watching you do that would think,
wow, I don't think I could do that.
That would be their first thought.
So absolutely. And again, and this is a habit.
And the noise doesn't completely disappear,
but it goes down to being almost imperceptible.
So what we're trying to do is we're trying to
internalize all of these habits to the point where
I don't need to consciously think about them.
So it's like a gymnast who's doing their
tumbling routine and jumps into the air. As
they're flipping, they're not consciously trying
to think of how to do a flip. They've done it a
thousand times. They know how to do a flip. The
only thing they have that they may be thinking of,
all of their attention is on being completely
present to what's happening, relying on your body
and your subconscious knowing what to do, is they
have kind of like listeners, like in programming,
keyboard listeners. You have something that's
there that is just listening for anything out
of the ordinary. And it's very, very fine-tuned.
So as I'm speaking, for example, I might think to
myself, "Oh, I may be rambling right now. Maybe
I'm going a little bit too long." And it's a
little listener that's going to just gently,
nicely, say, "Hey, warning, I don't know if
you're aware of this." And as I hear that, I might
say, "Oh, okay, let me wrap it up." Or maybe it's
saying, "I'm not sure if you're being clear," or,
"Can you be more precise here?". Whatever it is,
it's just a gentle listener in the background.
So as you get into the habit of staying in
character, and if you had an audience here,
we could have asked them right away, "Well,
how do you feel about this?". You probably
would've gotten really good feedback,
really positive, which would've
kind of jarred that feeling of, wow,
I didn't think I did it that good of a job. And
people are saying, "Hey, I thought that was pretty
good." So As you get that reinforcing pattern,
the voice starts going down more and more.
Awesome. I need that voice
to go down. That'd be great.
[inaudible 01:09:46].
Okay, let's do another game.
Always does.
Cool. Let's do
last game. Last one of these practical games. So
this is actually a game from one of our courses
that I'm pulling out. It's not a standalone game,
it's one that's inside of the courses. But again,
if you wanted to replicate this
yourself, you can very easily do it.
So what we're going to do here is we're
going to work on conviction prompts. So
this comes back to this idea of entering a state
or changing your energy to impact the words that
are coming out of your mouth. So what's going
to happen here, is similarly to Triple Step,
I'm also going to get a random topic that I
just have to start speaking about. But now,
instead of getting a word that I have to integrate
into my speech naturally, I'm going to get a
prompt. So it's going to be the beginning of
a sentence that I have to say out loud, and I
have to find a way for my brain to just complete
the sentence. And the sentences are specifically
chosen because they're going to put you in a state
of more conviction. So it's going to force me to
care more about what I'm saying basically.
And this is a game for executive presence.
If you think about somebody who you feel has
great gravitas or great executive presence,
they usually have, there's something about them
that's saying, this person really believes in
what they're saying. And what this game is
showing you is that, hey, there's a way to
fast track myself to that place. If I want to
have more executive presence, let me bring a
little bit more conviction to what I'm saying.
There's a caveat, small caveat. Maybe 10% of
people in the workforce need the opposite. They
need, "Hey, you need to maybe question what you're
saying here." But the reality is the vast majority
of people actually are not truly standing behind
their words and their ideas. And what that
does is that the people who speak a lot and
feel a lot of conviction, their ideas go through
more often than the others. And you'd want ideas
to stand for themselves, but that's just not
reality. So for most people listening to this,
if you can bring more conviction to your words,
then your ideas are going to have a better chance
of being seen equally to those who are already
doing that. So this is what this game's about.
Awesome. Okay.
Okay, here we go. The title is Saying No. I've
had to learn this the hard way as an entrepreneur,
that saying no is one of the most important
things I can do. But saying no is not saying
no to a meeting, because that can be easy.
And what I'm going to say now matters a ton.
This is saying no to doing all of the exciting
projects that I want to do. So as I said earlier,
I'm Labrador. I get excited about everything, and
I genuinely believe that every idea is awesome,
but that doesn't mean I can do
every idea. I need to choose a
very clear focus and stick to that focus.
And this is a game changer. When you start
reducing the amount of things you're doing
to a painful amount, a painful few amount,
then when you get there, suddenly everything else
changed. And it astonishes me when I do that,
just how much more I can get done,
even though I'm doing fewer things.
I love it. That was great. These words are tough.
They were, yeah. This was not an easy one. This
was not a... Good thing that I
get a tough one. Well deserved.
Let me read the phrases real quick, just so folks
know. So the phrases you had to integrate is,
"This matters a ton. I genuinely believe
that every idea is awesome. Game changer."
It was just, "I genuinely believe that." Yeah.
Oh, got it. Okay. "I generally
believe that." And then,
"game changer". And then, "It astonishes me when."
And I'm so eager for you to go through this, and
for anybody listening to try this for themselves,
even if you know what's coming. Like, if
you want to do this for yourself right now,
write the words, the prompts that Lenny
just shared, and choose any title,
and just speak for a minute, and see if
you can integrate those in. Because you're
going to notice how if you bring conviction,
these words naturally bring that out of you.
And it's so interesting to watch the content
change as a result of the state you get into
and what you say. So it's really powerful to
discover just how incredible your brain is.
So same intention for you I think, is choose
a strong direction from the beginning. This is
always, in speaking in general, the stronger
the direction you choose in the beginning,
the more ideas you're going to have. Everything
gets easier when you choose a strong direction.
Okay, let's try it.
But the goal here, is as it says, advocate for an
important idea related to the speech title. Ready?
Yeah, let's do it.
Here we go.
YOLO.
The title is Space Exploration.
I think it's hard to imagine anything more
important to the human race than space
exploration. I know there's a lot of talk about
people wasting time trying to get us to Mars,
or trying to not think about what is happening
on earth, but I feel like there's nothing more
powerful, and important, and inspiring. In
fact, the entire world needs to focus more on
the value of space exploration. There's so many
things we can discover, so many things that can
help us on earth, and we cannot forget how much
potential exists outside of our little earth,
that we think our whole existence and everything
that's ever existed on this one planet, when
really we're this tiny, pale blue dot. And it just
astonishes me when people don't think about this,
don't think it matters, don't think they
should spend any time getting us into space,
investing money in space. And just
hearing stories, if nothing else,
of people that have gone into space and
how life-changing that was for them,
should tell us that space exploration
is incredibly powerful and important.
Yes, that was awesome. That was so cool. So you
had, the title was Space Exploration, and the
words were, "in fact", "the entire world", then,
"We cannot forget that," then, "It astonishes
me when," and finally "life changing". So what
was that like? What did it feel like getting...
Yeah, there's a lot of...
It really helps, just like,
"Here's the thing you're going to believe."
And I don't know if I got lucky with stuff,
but it just felt like, okay, I have, something
comes up that I'm not going to leak. But anyway,
it was like, oh yeah, cool,
something interesting happens.
And that's one of my other actual, just going
on a little quick tangent, insights from the
lessons that you guys teach, is that as you are
forced to talk, you have new insights emerge.
And you almost figure out what you think and
know by being forced to get out of your head,
and these problems help you along that. But I
think that's really interesting, of just like,
this will help you develop things, and
insights, and take them out of your head.
Yeah. Well, hopefully we get to talk about
the Accordion Method, one of the most powerful
methods I have, which is very close to this.
But this is often a prompt I tell people when
they're speaking. I say, because people tend to
get into a public speaking voice, so we'll be
in a class, and they'll be chatting normally, and
look super normal. And then we'll say, "Okay, now
just a timer. I'm just going to give you a speech.
Just speak for 60 seconds so we get a baseline."
And I click play, and suddenly I say, "The
important part about doing this," and they enter
into a different version of themselves, a very
professional version, whatever that would mean.
It's so much more freeing, powerful, connecting,
and effective to speak conversationally.
And so the cue I often give people is don't think
about us, just think out loud. And that's really
what we're doing. We can, most people have a skill
set that's up here and a mindset that's down here.
And so if you can just change the mindset to match
the skill set, you've already made a giant leap.
And you do that by reducing the stakes in your
mind and by just speaking. And as you do that,
when you're thinking out loud, you have
these moments of connecting things in
your mind, and then naturally it pops out.
And if you're doing it well... And I love,
there's a really cool Naval Ravikant interview on
the Joe Rogan Podcast from many years ago that's
phenomenal. And at one point he talks about
communication, if I'm not mistaken. I think
it's on that podcast. But he says something along
the lines of, "One should discover the words they
are saying at the same time their audience is."
And this comes back to thinking out loud, like
if I'm really in my mind, I'm making connections,
and suddenly the words are the consequence of it.
So using prompts, poking your brain, giving
these cues naturally creates things that you
couldn't have anticipated otherwise. It's like
putting constraints on a creative project.
I love that. Before we segue to a couple of these
methods, the Accordion Method is one example,
I want to ask about, when people hear this,
they may feel like you're helping people more,
just like make shit up, and why, why would we want
that? Talk about just how this isn't just like,
you're not going to actually give talks like
this necessarily. This is... And I guess I'm
answering the question, but I'm curious
if that's how you think about it. This
is building a skill so that when you actually
want to give a real talk that you've prepared,
you are better at it. But yeah, just
thoughts on just that potential element.
Yeah, I think that's an important question,
and it's a question I hear a lot because we
all know a bullshitter, and that's the person
who masters the skill of communication but
doesn't have anything to show for it.
And so this thing happens, is that I see
bullshitter and I think to myself, I really,
really don't want to become that person. And
what happens is it becomes an immune response
or like an immune response where the desire not
to be that person and the feeling being around
that person gives you is so strong that now if
I take even the smallest step in that direction
of speaking freely, sharing my thoughts out loud,
bringing more conviction or confidence
to what I'm saying, not leaking,
then there's this immediate response like an
immune response in my body that's just too strong,
that's saying, "Uh oh, you're becoming the
bullshitter. Alarm bells. Alarm bells. Go
back to that safe little corner you were in."
But the reality is, if you're thinking that,
then you have no chance of becoming a
bullshitter. Because if that thought
is even popping into your mind, then you're
the type of person who has developed a very
acute skill set of noticing when people bullshit.
And you have that same skill set for yourself. So
it's just going to be, now it's just too loud.
So as we go through this practice,
we want to match, "Hey, I want to match
that bullshitter's level of communication,
except I'm going to have the ideas to back it
up. I'm going to really put effort into my craft,
but I'm going to be able to show them in the best
possible light." And what we want to be able to do
is notice, okay, if this is a big thing for
you, the bullshitting, and you're noticing a
big reaction, just even listening to us, not even
playing the games yourself, then you definitely
benefit from calming that voice down. So spending
time learning these skill sets, because you're
most likely atrophied because you're staying
away from it. And you're going to have this very
powerful listener in the back of your mind that's
going to ping you, and it's like, "Hey, you're
at the limit right now. Stay true to what you
know." And it's going to be a very good compass
for yourself. It's going to be there and you can
trust it because you developed this capacity.
Awesome. That's really helpful.
Okay. So, so far we've shared a
bunch of techniques, things that you could just
start doing today. We've done all these fun games
that you could play online. If nothing else,
just learning from the techniques these games
teach you I think is really helpful. You've
shared a bunch of principles of just like,
here's how you actually get better at public
speaking, and not this way, but that way.
I know you have a couple also methods just
like that people can implement that helps
them develop talks that I found really
helpful. So maybe just as a closing,
we talk about these two methods, the Accordion
Method, and I think it's the Bow and Arrow Method?
Uh-huh.
Awesome. Let's talk about the Accordion
Method. We did this in the class briefly,
and it was really helpful, and I've
been explaining it to people of just
like a really cool way of making your talk
better. So talk about how that works and
how people might be able to implement it
when they're trying to develop the talk.
Now, I'm biased when I'm going to say this, so
take this with a pinch of salt, but I think the
Accordion Method, the Accordion Method might be
one of the things I'm the most proud of in my
entire life because it's almost revolutionizing
the way I think we should prepare speaking.
So up until now, we've talked about spontaneous
speaking mostly, and that's going to be the vast
majority of your speaking. Probably 80% of your
speaking is stuff that you can't prepare for. But
there are going to be situations where you know
you have a deadline and you're going to have to
speak. And either you have to speak because it's
a job interview, or you're talking to your CEO,
or maybe you're presenting to your
whole team or an audience of a thousand.
The old way I think is shitty. I think
it's broken, and I haven't found anything
out there that is innovating on this. And it
drove us crazy with Michael, and that's what
gave birth to the Accordion Method. What's the
old way? The old way is I have a talk coming up,
so I'm going to dump all of my ideas on a piece
of paper or multiple pieces of paper. Then I'm
going to try rearranging those ideas. And as
I'm rearranging the ideas and trying to make
them in a talk, I have more inspiration. And I'm
thinking, oh, maybe I could say it this way, and
I don't want to lose that other thing that I said
in the beginning because maybe I would use it.
And you start just creating this alien stack of
paper with all of your ideas of what your talk
might be, and then you're left with 10, 15 pieces
of paper. And now as the deadline comes closer,
what do you have to do? Well, you have to go
through the excruciating pain of turning 10
pages into a script so that you don't forget
all of those brilliant lines that you spent
so many hours editing. And they're still
in writing mode. They're not in your mind.
So now that I've created that script
that I spent a lot of time editing,
now I have to memorize it. And memorization is
pretty. We're not good at memorization. Robots
are good at memorization, humans are not.
And memorization is like a chain where you
just have all of these links very linearly. And
everybody knows the feeling of going through,
reciting a poem as a kid, and suddenly
you miss one verse and you're lost,
and now you're a deer in the headlights.
So what we're doing with the Accordion Method
is instead of preparing our talk by writing,
we're going to prepare our talk by speaking, and
we're going to do so in a very specific way where
we're going down the accordion to create extreme
clarity, and to understand what the essence of our
talk is, and then back up the accordion to bring
back in intentionally just the right pieces.
So I was thinking of an analogy for this,
and one that I really like is imagine you're
redecorating your living room. The old way,
the writing 10 pages and memorizing it is I'm
going to look at my living room and I'm going to
rearrange things and put stuff in a corner that I
might need later. And then I'm going to bring some
new things that I thought could be really nice
and I'm going to struggle to make something work.
The Accordion Method is saying, and imagine
this were easy to do with furniture,
I'm going to take everything out of my living
room except the most essential pieces that
make my living room. So I might be left with
that one couch that I really love, a pillow,
a beautiful light that I bought three years ago,
and one or two other small things. And as I look
at that, I'm going to have clarity on the vision
I want for my living room. And then very slowly,
very intentionally, I'm going to go take certain
elements that were already there that I might
want to bring back in, and I'm going to bring new
elements that now I see make sense. And so by the
time you finish with your beautiful living room,
it's going to be this beautiful minimalistic room
that has a very clear design choice, and every
element there is there because you chose it.
It's there because you did it very intentionally.
So how does that work with the Accordion Method?
What we do is you can go through the first step.
If you want, you can write all of those ideas
on paper just to get them out of your head.
That's totally fine. But from this moment on,
there's no more script. And I'm just going to
give an example of times, but you can change
these time constraints slightly. We're going down
the accordion by using time constraints. So for
example, you would say, "I'm going to speak for
three minutes." So you're going to put a timer,
and you have two rules. I have to stay in
character the whole time and I have to end strong.
So you must make it to the end of the three
minutes, and it doesn't matter how bad it sounds,
how many mistakes you make. The only point here
is I'm trying to get my ideas out into spoken
word. So I'm starting to populate my mind with
everything and seeing where am I actually at.
Then after the three minutes, you think of, okay,
what did I like, what didn't I like? Then you go
to two minutes. And you put a timer and you do
two minutes again. And you're very strict with
those two minutes, because we're just trying
to learn something every time. It doesn't need
to be perfect. So at the two-minute mark, you
do the same thing, but now you had to shave a
whole minute out of that content. And as you do
that, well, that means getting rid of the noise,
getting rid of anything that doesn't feel right.
Then you go down to one minute. And you're going
to go down all way to 30 seconds. So you started
at a three-minute speech and you make your way
down to 30 seconds. By the time you make it to 30
seconds, you're going to have only the essential
pieces like that couch and that lamp in the
living room. When you have the essential pieces,
you're going to have a clear sense of what your
talk is about, and it might've changed as you-
Sense of what your talk is about and it might've
changed as you were going down the accordion. And
then from that place on, we're going to do another
30 second rep and then we're going to go back up
the accordion. So you do another 30 seconds and
then you do one minute, two minute, and all the
way back up to three minute. And every step of the
way you go from 30 seconds to a minute. Initially,
a minute felt hard. Now that's double the time
you just had. So you can bring in something that's
aligned with the talk you want to share, and then
two minutes, same. And then when you get to three
minutes, one of my clients once said that it
felt like he had a football field in his mind.
So much space. And now whatever talk you have
left there is a very clear, intentional talk.
And not only that, and this is why
this is such an incredible method,
your talk is now internalized. So you're
at the stage of I've written a script that
I've painfully edited in the old way that you
now still have to memorize and it's a written
speech that you're going to have to pretend to
give in a spoken way. In this case you're there,
but it's already completely internalized, not
even memorized. It's internalized. You have
these pillars, you know where you're going and by
the time you make it through the accordion method,
you're basically ready to go give it on stage.
But you could give it now in one minutes,
two minutes, three minutes, five minutes. It's
very plastic. You're going to be able to navigate
different time frames. It's not going to really
matter if you make a mistake because you're
going to have a deep sense of what your speech
is. It's not memorized, it's internalized. So
not only have you gotten clarity and built
out your speech in a very intentional way,
but by the time you get to the end of it, you also
actually know it and you're ready to perform it.
That example of the three minute when you come
back up the accordion, that's exactly how it
felt when I did this is just like, "Wow,
so much time now" because you essentially,
the way I think about it is you concentrate it
to the best, most important nuggets and then you
have time to build on those nuggets and you cut
out all the stuff that no one really cares about,
which is usually a long introduction, just like
now just get to the good stuff and then you
expand the good stuff. And it really worked for
me and it was a really illuminating experience.
For someone that wants to actually use
this. Say they have a speech coming up,
say they're doing an all
hands presentation in a week.
Do you do this a week ahead of time? Do you
do this a few days before? I guess where do
you fit this in the workflow so that you actually
remember what you want to say when it comes time?
I can't say do it exactly a week or two weeks
or it really depends how well familiar you
are with the content. If you have an all
hands, and this is something that you've
been hashing with your executive team over the
past two months, you probably know it really,
really well and you have a lot of clarity and
now it's just about organizing it nicely. So
in that case, maybe you want to do a
rough go through the accordion a week
ahead of time so you have a clear sense
of, "What is it that I want my audience
to remember and what are the pillars that I
know I like to hit that feel really good?"
So you can think about these as the foundational
pillars that support that one thing that you're
sharing or bookmarks that I know I have to hit and
then what I would like to do. And so that's what I
would write down. I wouldn't write a script. I'd
write those down. And then before the all hands,
maybe the day before, maybe even the
morning of, depending on how important
this is or how comfortable you feel, then you
might go through just one or two reps of it,
but now you already know it, so it should
come back very, very quickly in your mind.
And it sounds like it's okay to have some
bullet points at the end. It's hard for me to
imagine going on stage with a bunch of people
watching, not have any slide, bullet point,
speaker notes. Any problems just having a couple
of the bullet points of core points next to me?
Before a talk, I might have four
things written down. My one thing,
and we'll talk about this in the bow and
arrow, my one thing, the one thing I want
people to remember and then the three bookmarks
or pillars that I want to hit. And these are kind
of cues or reminders that are going to send me
into that part of the speech. So for example,
if I'm talking about the accordion method, like
what I just said, if I go back and I think through
the pillars of this one. Well, my one thing would
be the accordion method is more powerful than
memorizing and then doing it the old way.
And then my bookmarks might be number one,
describe the old way or the old way. Number
two, the new way or the accordion method. And
then number three might be internalize, don't
memorize, and that'll be kind of the takeaway.
And if I have that in my mind, if I have
30 seconds, I can say the old way sucks
because you have to work so hard and memorize
everything and you're memorizing written stuff,
the accordion method is much more powerful
because you are going to compress it and
go down and then open it up and then I'll
explain that in a second and then I'll say,
so you're internalized not memorized. What
I realized right now is actually, it's funny
enough though, those were the bookmarks there, so
that sent me down that path. But actually I would
say bookmark number two is probably the living
room analogy. So it would be the old way sucks,
the living room analogy, and then
describe the accordion method.
That's cool. That was an awesome example
of just the insights that appear by forcing
yourself through this exercise. And
it sounds like maybe the best use of
this method is if you have a talk all
of a sudden short term it's coming,
all of a sudden you have to give a talk
somewhere. There's a really powerful
method to come up with a great talk that's
maybe tomorrow, which you didn't expect.
When I say I love this, I use this for
myself, I use this with every single
client I work with regardless of if it's
a five-minute talk, a 20-minute keynote,
we're using the accordion method, and you can use
this at the macro level or at the micro level,
so you can use it for the whole talk, but you
can also say, "Hey, let's hone in on this part
one that you're struggling with or part two and
let's use the accordion to get clarity there."
So you can use the accordion as almost like a
brainstorming way. I just want to see where I end
up here and it takes maybe 15 minutes or something
to go through a full accordion. It depends the
time constraints you give yourself. Sometimes
I'll just do two minute, one minute 30 seconds,
that's even shorter, but I'll go through it for
one piece of the puzzle or it's like, "Hey, we're
almost there. Let's really internalize it. Let's
clarify this. Let's get it really, really tight."
And then I might say, "Okay, now let's do
the whole thing through the accordion. So
your 20-minute talk, I want to hear it in three
minutes." That gets really, really interesting.
Amazing. Okay. Anything else along
the accordion method before we talk
about the final technique before we wrap up?
We have a full self-paced course on ultra speaking
on the accordion. I think it costs like 30 bucks
or something like that to access all of the games
and all the platforms. A bunch of them are free,
but I think this one's behind the paywall. But
we also put together a resource where we go
all the way, we describe all of the accordion
method, the bow and arrow, staying character
ending strong on a free email course that we
put together. That's ultraspeaking.com/Lenny.
So this is shameless self-promotion,
but if you want it to go grab it there,
you can grab it there and then the bow and arrow
is going to tie into the accordion method as well.
Awesome. I'm glad you mentioned all
that and we'll point people to that
URL in the show notes. Okay, final topic
is the bow and arrow technique. Let's talk
about what that is and how folks
can use that to give better talks.
The bow and arrow starts with a, it's really a
mindset shift that most of us are in the weeds,
so we're very sensitive and familiar to all of the
content that we're working on. If you're in data,
then you have all of the data. If you're sharing
ideas, you still have all of the ideas. And the
mistake that most people do when they're preparing
a talk, a presentation, an all hands a meeting,
whatever it is we tend to focus more on what
we want to say than what we want our audience
to remember. So the mindset shift here is stop
focusing as much on what you want to say and focus
more on what you want your audience to remember.
What we found out is if you think about
your last all hands, the last big meeting,
the last talk you saw on YouTube or in person,
you probably don't remember much. In fact, I wager
you might only remember one thing from that talk.
And that's what this is all based on. We call it
the bow and arrow technique because we think you
can only remember one thing out of a talk and that
it's very powerful to go through that framework or
that kind of thinking when you're building a
talk. And the one thing is your arrow. And so
when you have that one thing to me I say it's
literally a single sentence that is the only
sentence people would remember if they left your
talk. Would you be satisfied with that sentence?
It takes some times to get to a good one, but
if you have a good one, it unlocks everything.
It's like you're having a north star or a
compass in your pocket. You can always pull
it out. You always know where you're going. It
gives you a lot of clarity. It's also giving
a lot of clarity to your audience obviously.
But you can't just throw an arrow at somebody's
face. You need to notch it in the bow and pull
the bow back. And so to pull the bow back, you
need to add in weight to that sentence. And that
often comes in the form of an interesting anecdote
or a data point that's going to support that or
a story that's going to add emotion or illustrate
it. So you want to find ways in which you can give
weight or pull back the bow so that your arrow has
that much more impact. So usually the process of
clarifying what your arrow is is a back and forth
between the bow and the arrows. So if you're going
down the accordion method after the first one you
might write or before the first one, you might
write a tentative arrow, "Here's my one thing",
and then the next one you say, "Okay, actually
my one thing might be a refined version of that."
And so you might rewrite it a little bit and
then you might tentatively put in what you
think the bow is. "I like the anecdote I used
here. I like this data point that I thought was
powerful and maybe I can end on this story or
this call to action." Then you'll put that in
and then you go back in and you give that a try
and that's starting to simplify in your mind.
And as you go, usually one informs the other. By
the time you finish the accordion for example,
you should have a very clear arrow and those
clear bookmarks, which is the bow. But really
the thing to remember with the bow and arrow, if
you can only remember one thing, is switch your
mindset from what I want to say to what I want
people to remember and limit whatever that is
you want them to remember as much as possible
and that's going to give you extreme clarity.
That is really helpful. I'm preparing my
talk for the summit, and so I'm going to
use both of these exercises and what I
take away from this last piece is as much
as you may want to say a lot of things,
really all someone's going to remember,
as you said is one thing, if anything, but
hopefully they remember that one thing.
So it's essentially what's the one thing you want
people to remember and then what are the pieces of
support that will convince them that that's right
and that's something that'll stick with them?
Exactly. And again, similar to the accordion
method, this works in the macro and the micro.
So if you have a talk where you're using
slides, use it for the whole talk. But
then for every single slide, ask yourself
what is my one thing? And you might have
some support there as well, but if you
don't have a one thing for each slide,
either the slide shouldn't exist
or it should be multiple slides.
The symptom of not having a one thing is
usually having a slide that says way too
many things. I don't know what data point I
want you to remember, so I'm going to put all
of it on that slide. I'm not sure which piece
of information is more important. So I'm going
to write down all of my thoughts and I'm going
to go through all of them or hope that you go
through all of them and extract what you think
is interesting. But the reality is people are
just going to zone out if you do that. So if
you do that slide by slide, you're going to
gain incredible clarity and again, you're going
to need less preparation and less memorization.
And to build on that, a pro-tip is to make that
title of that slide exactly that one thing you
want them to take away. Just put it there and
tell them exactly what you want them to learn.
Yes. I love that.
Sweet. Tristan, we've been on a journey. This
was a really unique experimental episode. I
had a good time even though I did some hard
things, you made me do hard things that are
good for me. Is there anything else you want
to share before we get to our very exciting
lightning round? Is there anything else you want
to leave listeners with or a nugget you want to?
I hope people found value. I mean, we did. This
was really a group effort and I really appreciate
you working on the agenda, really bringing in
the games and trying to make this as practical
as possible. I think the only thing I want to
leave people with is again, this idea of how
transformational tackling speaking can be, and the
more constrained you feel with your speaking, the
more transformational it will be to your life. So
I just want to give this encouragement. It's much,
much, much more enjoyable than you think it will
be. It can actually be exhilarating and energizing
and you feel like you can take over the world
once you're on this journey. It's beautiful.
And so I just encourage everybody, take the
first step and start practicing your speaking.
Awesome. And I definitely felt that after
doing the workshop of just I feel energized,
I want to just talk all time, but then
I'm like, I need more work. I need more
practice. Tristan, with that, we've reached our
very exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
Let's do this lightning round. Here we go.
Here we go. First question,
what are two or three books that you
have recommended most to other people?
I was given a book by my first coach, Nathan
Seward seven years ago called The Big Leap
by Gay Hendricks that I've recommended so many
times. And it's based on this idea that we tend
to self-sabotage ourselves when we experience
too much success or too much happiness. And
that that's linked to I think five things
that would happen to us when we're growing
up. One of them is the... What is it, the wild
poppy syndrome or something like that. Like the
tallest poppy is the one that's cut first.
So if you shine in a family of siblings,
then anytime you shine too much we're going
to say, "Hey, hey, hey, that's not cool for
the others." So that's going to be internalized
and hardwired in your body and as an adult, as
soon as you start shining a little bit too much,
you're going to do the same thing to yourself. So
the idea is going from having this point above
which you can't be happy to turning it into,
he calls it an upward-facing spiral with no upper
limit. It's a really exciting and empowering book.
Do you have a favorite recent movie
or TV show you really enjoyed?
I haven't watched much very recently, but I'll
say one of my favorite TV shows of all time is
the Peaky Blinders, English show with Cillian
Murphy. I'm absolutely obsessed with that movie
that show. I think it's a true masterpiece. And
I've recently rewatched, so I'll qualify this
as recent. I recently rewatched The Nice
Guys with Ryan Gosling and Russell Crowe,
and I think it's just a brilliant comedy.
Brilliant. Another masterpiece, I thought.
Do you have a favorite recent product that
you have discovered that you really love.
Could be an app, it could be something physical.
I have a physical product actually right in front
of me that was gifted to me by my business partner
Michael Gendler, co-founder of Ultraspeaking. This
is called an Ember Mug, and this keeps whatever
you have in it, warm and it's extraordinary,
whether you are a coffee drinker or a tea drinker,
you know the feeling of pouring this
and sipping it and by the fifth sip,
it's cold. This keeps it at whatever
temperature you want it to for however
long you want. And I absolutely love it.
I've been using it basically every day.
I have one of those. I find myself, you could
actually control it through the app. You can
control the temperature through an app,
which I love. I haven't been using mine,
but I love the idea. I know a lot of friends love
them. Two more questions. Do you have a favorite
life motto that you often come back to, share with
friends or family, find useful in work or in life?
I think we are too future focused as a species or
as a society and as a result, we're always looking
for the next thing. So the motto I share with my
friends and my business partners and my family the
most I think is these are the good old days. And
I remind myself, I'll tell you right now for you
and for whoever's listening. I mean think about
the podcast, it's never going to be this young,
it's never going to feel like it feels right now.
And it always feels like these things are eternal,
but truly one day you're going to look back
and you're think, "Man, those were really the
good old days." And so I say it right now,
enjoy because these are the good old days.
I love that. And it's so relevant with a
young kid, you're always going to think
about, "Oh, they're little." I love that.
Final question. You were the fastest person
to reach the finals of the world championship
of public speaking. I imagine that was quite a
journey. I'm curious if there's a story
from that experience that comes to mind
that's like a wild part of that journey
or something that might surprise people.
Well, the journey lasted almost seven months,
and it was the craziest journey of my life. I
went into that with no experience whatsoever
speaking, so really just a random amateur,
and I just climbed the ladder by outworking
everybody. The story that came to mind right
away was six days before the semifinals. So I'm
six days before the semifinals and I've qualified
for the semifinals two and a half months ago. So
I'm nobody, now I'm going to the semifinals of
the world championships of public speaking.
So my mind really is struggling to compute,
and I had finally unlocked a speech that I thought
was worthy of giving on the final stage. You have
to show up there for the semifinals with one
speech, and then the next day, if ever you win,
you're going to the finals and you have to
have a brand new speech, a completely different
speech that you're going to give on that stage.
So you need two speeches ready to go, and both of
those speeches have to be in theory, world-class.
I'm six days before. I was struggling at that,
really, really struggling to get that speech
together. I finally got something and Michael
managed to get me. I was flying I think
two days later to Vancouver for the semis,
and Michael managed to unlock this one opportunity
to speak in front of 50 people to give it a try.
And so I ran there. I give the speech, and as
usual, we film. I film every single speech.
I gave more than a hundred speeches over
seven months, and I filmed every single
speech. And we'd get home, we'd ask everybody
for feedback, and I get home and I'm thinking,
"Man, something is wrong. Something is wrong."
I was so pumped. I wept. I genuinely wept as I
wrote the speech because it was so moving.
It was all about my life. It was something
that I was so connected to. I don't know,
probably the emotion of the pressure as well,
but that's how much I believed in that speech.
We get home, we put the speech on the computer,
and as I get to the most important
part of the speech, I see two things
happen. So this is the moment where I'm
expecting people to pull out their tissues.
One person pulls up the agenda for the event
that they're at and is starting to look at
the agenda. Another person pulls out their phone,
another person starts going through their purse,
and I'm looking at this, and suddenly I realized,
"Oh, this speech, nobody cares about this. This is
not a good speech. This is terrible." And
then I go through all of these feedbacks.
I have 50 pieces of feedback, and all I'm getting
is, "Good luck for the semi-finals. It's going
to go great. I thought it was good", and I'm
like, "I'm going to humiliate myself. This is
terrible." So I had waves of anxiety. I threw my
speech away, and in five days from the ground up,
I rebuilt a completely new speech that was
basically the best of everything I'd explored,
everything I'd experimented with over the
course of the three months leading up to that,
the jokes that worked the best, like a stand-up
comic would. I built my special and I focused on
different areas like all of the transitions.
And right before the semi-finals, I gave the
speech to one person. I was in Vancouver trying
to internalize my speech and memorizing it in a
plaza where I delimited the size of the stage
and I'm just giving my speech out loud to get
over the nerves, so I'm ready for the pressure to
see if my brain will remember it and everything.
Anyways, I gave it in front of one person who
was our district director at Toastmasters,
and this is a speech meant for 500 to a
thousand people, not one person. So I was
scared it would flop. But in the middle of the
speech, which is a completely different one,
I saw a tear roll down her cheek, and then she
just hugged me and said, "You got it. You did it.
You did it." I walked out on that stage and I made
it, and I won the semi-finals with that speech.
I think to me, that was really the, it showed
me that everything I'd done was worth something,
that it actually worked. If I was able to
build a speech in five days, that could
get me a win at the semi-finals of the world
championships. That was kind of the ultimate,
"Wow, I won." So when I walked into the
finals, to me, I felt like I had already won.
Wow, that is a story. What an arc. Amazing. I'm
so happy you asked that question. Now I just
want to watch that speech and I want to learn more
about this whole championship of public speaking,
which I have no insight into. That
could be its own podcast interview.
But Tristan, thank you so much for being
here. This was incredible. One of the most
interesting episodes I've done. Two final
questions. Where can folks learn more about
Ultraspeaking? I know you built a page where
they could experiment with some of this stuff,
so share that. And then how
can listeners be useful to you?
If you go to ultraspeaking. com/Lenny, so
ultra like U-L-T-R-A ultraspeaking.com/Lenny,
we put together, you have five emails that go deep
into a bunch of the things that we've talked here.
You can also just go to Ultraspeaking.com where
you'll get access to a bunch of the games for
free, and you can check out everything else that
we do. If you want to follow me or hit me up or
ask me questions about this podcast, you can do
that on Twitter @Montebello, M-O-N-T-E-B-E-L-L-O.
And how can listeners be useful to me? Well,
first of all, if you made it to here, then I
really appreciate you. Thank you. Thank you for
being here with us, and what I would love for you
to do is to apply this. We said in the beginning,
you can't get better at speaking without speaking,
and another piece of that puzzle is you want to
do the thing that you're trying to get better
at. So if you're nervous speaking in front of
people, you want to speak in front of people
as part of your practice. So the way you could be
useful to me is introduce these games to somebody
else. Try them for yourself, practice them
with somebody else. Go through the accordion
method with a friend. Try conductor, and when you
succeed and when you have an awesome experience,
then you can tell the world that Ultraspeaking
helped you do that, and that would be huge.
Awesome. Tristan, thank
you so much for being here.
Thanks, Lenny. It was an honor.
It was my honor, Tristan. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If you
found this valuable, you can subscribe
to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also, please
consider giving us a rating or leaving a review,
as that really helps other listeners
find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
LennysPodcast.com. See you in the next episode.