Your name has come up more times than almost
any other product person when I ask people
for their favorite product leaders in Asia.
I created a career growth framework for product
managers, which comprises of three things.
What you produce, what you bring to the table,
and what's your operating model.
Your advice is early in your career,
focus on just getting stuff out and done.
Can you show me your last PRD? Can you show me
the last product note that you sent? Can you show
me the product strategy doc? You must have that
impact through the artifacts that you work on.
I'm curious what you found most impedes people's
career growth.
How you view change,
whether you are focusing on things you control,
and third is how you see yourself. The moment
you are able to correct those stories, you
may be back on the growth path again.
Today, my guest is Vikrama Dhiman. Vikrama
heads all things product at Gojek, including
product management, design, program management,
research and insights with teams across India,
Singapore and Indonesia. He has previously worked
at companies like Directi, Airtel, MakeMyTrip and
WizIQ and is among the most well-known product
leaders in Asia. When I asked people who their
favorite product leader is in Asia, Vikrama's
name has come up almost more than anyone
else's. We chat about how to move into product
management, how to be a great product manager,
how product managers often shoot themselves
in the foot, and so much more. With that,
I bring you Vikrama Dhiman after a short word
from our sponsors. And if you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's the
best way to avoid missing future episodes
and it helps the podcast tremendously.
This episode is brought to you by Uizard,
empowering product leaders to ideate and
iterate faster than ever before with the power
of AI. As a product manager, I often spend
hours taking screenshots and then annotating
them with feedback for my team. With Uizard,
I can simply upload my screenshot and Uizard's
AI will turn them into a fully editable UI design
that I can then take, make tweaks to, and then
share with my teams in minutes. And when I want
to get really creative and explore totally new
ways to improve our product experience, I can use
Uizard's AI to generate new design concepts from
simple text prompts and turn them into interactive
prototypes effortlessly. There's a reason that
over 2.6 million people have trusted Uizard to
accelerate every phase of their product life cycle
and speed up time to market. Developers can even
export UI components to React and CSS to speed up
their development. Uizard's drag and drop editor
is super easy to use and you can collaborate
in real time with your entire team. Even your
CEO and customer service teams can contribute.
Unlock all of Uizard's game-changing AI-powered
features and more with 25% off Uizard's Pro
annual plan. Visit U-I-Z-A-R-D.io/lenny and
use code Lenny to check out today. That's
U-I-Z-A-R-D.io/lenny. This episode is brought
to you by Webflow. We're all friends here,
so let's be real for a second. We all know
that your website shouldn't be a static asset,
it should be a dynamic part of your strategy
that drives conversions. That's business 101.
But here's a number for you. 54% of leaders
say web updates take too long, that's
over half of you listening right now.
That's where Webflow comes in. Their visual-first
platform allows you to build, launch, and optimize
web pages fast. That means you can set ambitious
business goals and your site can rise to the
challenge. Learn how teams like Dropbox, Ideo
and Orangetheory trust Webflow to achieve their
most ambitious goals today at webflow.com.
Vikrama, thank you so much for being here and
welcome to the podcast.
Thank you for inviting me,
Lenny. I'm very excited to be here.
So as you know and hopefully as listeners know,
I'm on this quest to meet the most insightful
product leaders from all over the world and
your name has come up more times than almost any
other product person when I ask people for their
favorite product leaders in Asia. And you're also
the third guest from Gojek, so there's definitely
something in the water over there and I want to
talk about that. To just dive right in, you have a
very strong reputation for building incredibly
strong product talent and also design talent,
and also helping people transition from other
roles into product management, which a lot of
people listening to this podcast dream to do. So
I'm going to ask a bunch of questions around this
area. How does that sound?
Sounds good.
Okay. First question is just when you
think back to the people that have done
best in the product management role
and have had a rapid career rise, what
are some of the most common traits or behaviors
or habits that you find in these people?
Over the last decade and a half, I've had
the opportunity to work with some really
strong product managers, learn from strong
product managers, and some of them have had
rapid career growth. When I was younger and I was
starting off, I used to think it's all about the
product. If you've got a really cool product
to work on, your growth's guaranteed. And if
you got really a product which no one cares
about or a stream which no one cares about,
then your growth is going to be slightly slower.
But as I started seeing more and more product
managers at their craft, I saw that working on a
cool product area is not the only thing. In fact,
sometimes some product managers would come
back and complain that despite their product
doing really well, they've not really grown.
And while some other product managers whose
product didn't have the impact really grew. And
as I started looking at it and as I started making
notes, as I started talking to other product
leaders, what I discovered was that the really
strong product managers who were also growing
in their careers did some things differently.
And based on that, I created a career growth
framework for product managers, which comprises
of three things, and I call it three W's. So
what you produce, what you bring to the table,
and what's your operating model? The really strong
product managers are good at usually two of the
three things. The ones who rise and when they
are rising, they are performing well on all the
three access. So if you would like, let's talk a
little bit more about each one of these W's.
Yeah, I would love to. I love that you put
the word what at the top and that makes it
the three W's, which is clever because I
find even if the acronym is not necessary,
it's really helpful to help people remember
so I totally respect what you did there. So
the three is what you produce, what you bring
to the table and what your operating model is.
Is that right?
Yes, absolute.
Okay, cool. Yeah, let's talk about these.
So what you produce, a lot of people index on the
impact while and they start thinking about goals,
they start thinking about direction and they start
thinking about strategy. While it is important to
know at what stage of the career you are and what
kind of a product that you are working on, the
very first thing that anyone, when you're starting
off, produces is outputs, okay? The output can
be launching a product, it can be analyzing
and running an experiment, and it could even be
just being a part of the team and contributing
to a go-to market strategy. So focus on that
output significantly. As you get comfortable
with output and you start getting comfortable
with working with different stakeholders,
you start controlling what outputs are necessary,
which is when you move to the outcomes. Outcomes
are product areas, goals that you can own and
or collaborate with other stakeholders on.
And when you start figuring out which outcomes are
necessary, that is when you move to the leadership
and directional areas. The mistake that I
see a lot of product managers make is they
start operating in either output or outcomes.
And when you are transitioning to outcomes,
it's very important that you continue to still
hone your craft on outputs. For instance,
do you just give up on the go-to-market strategy
or do you start making product nodes which are
then picked up by marketing people and are able
to be used to create that go-to-market strategy?
You always, always have to have the output
and outcome even when you're moving up the
so-called career management ladder. So that is
very, very critical that as you are producing,
even when you are at the senior most levels,
don't forget your IC roots, don't forget the
IC component. And sometimes it is necessary to
just pull up your sleeves and go back and keep
working on those things. That also gives you a
lot of creds with others in the team as well.
So highlighting one insight here is that a lot
of advice you hear about how to do well in your
career, which you pointed out at the beginning
here, is it's not just not immediately drive
impact. That's not necessarily what you need to
obsess over, which is actually what I recommend
to people is just find ways to have impact. So
this is really interesting. Your advice is early
in your career, focus on just getting stuff out
and done. Don't so obsess with the impact. Can you
talk more about just what, when you say output,
what are you describing there? Is it just ship
products and be helpful and produce something?
Absolutely. So outputs is shipping products,
but it also comes in smaller things. For instance,
if you are sourcing content for your homepage,
what are the different avenues that you can
source content from? What is the easiest to
source? What is the most difficult to source?
Just ranking it all in that order goes a long
way. And one of the product managers actually did
that yesterday and I went, wow, it just made my
life so much simpler. And not just my life but
so many other people's lives so much simpler,
and we were able to take that specific output
and use it as part of our overall strategy. If
that PM would have obsessed about the overall
content strategy, overall how we are going to
do it versus just how we are going to be sourcing
it, they would have indexed on something bigger
and maybe would have not even been able to make
that impact. But now, they were able to show
something which was a small part, which was an
output, but it fell into the overall outcome.
The way I think about what you're describing,
which I actually 100% agree with, is when you're
starting out in your careers, execution is where
you need to deliver. People just want you to get
stuff done when you're just starting out. It's
not like help us define our strategy and vision
for the next three years. We just have stuff we
need done. Can you help us get it done? Well,
yes. And then essentially the advice is as you get
more senior, you'll have more opportunity to think
about strategy and what to build versus just
how to build it and actually execute on it.
Absolutely. So focus on outputs at the
start of your careers and don't forget
outputs even when you grow in your career.
So along those lines, just to close the thread
on this idea, it's still helpful if you work on
something that does have impact that matters,
right? How important is that? And you said that
you've seen successful product managers work on
things that aren't as impactful and still do
really well, but I guess would your advice be
tried [inaudible 00:11:52] be in a place that
is going to drive more impact versus it's not
actually that important in the early career?
So I'll give you my example. In one of my
previous roles, there were two product areas
that were important for the organization. My
product area ended up being the center and focus
of the organization, yet the product manager who
was chosen to lead the area when it became big
wasn't me. It was someone else. At that time,
I really felt very bad that okay, why did that
happen? But now when I look back, I can see why
that happened because that product manager was
so much better at the overall craft of output,
yet when they were focusing on outcome, we're
not forgetting the output as well. So they were
just better at me on launching products, they were
better at me on working with design, in producing
design artwork, and they were definitely better
than me in running the experiments as well.
I love that. Yeah, basically when you're just
starting out, just execute well, execute smoothly,
ship things on time. I'm going to say a few
things, but I'm curious what else comes to
mind here of just what does good output look
like? Is it do things that are helpful to your
team and manager, ship things on time, bug-free,
have a clean road map, everyone's aligned behind,
[inaudible 00:13:11] deadlines, things like
that. I guess what else along those lines
should people be like, "Okay, here's what
I should be doing to have good outputs?"
Some of the things that I think are useful.
So first, what's output? Output is something
which is very tangibly defined, which
doesn't take too much of your time, effort,
and energy to visualize and think and strategize
over and you are able to quickly get moving on.
Go and ask your product leader, go and ask other
leaders on what are the areas they are blocked on.
Sometimes they will be blocked on, "Hey, I need
to prepare this brief for this particular summit",
"I need to prepare this particular slide for a
leadership review", "I need to prepare a review,
I need to prepare a review which has to be done
with the legal." You can volunteer and definitely
own and deliver the first drafts of those even
if the final draft is not something that you
own. That's a simple example of an output, which
I feel a lot of people miss because they want to
be focusing on the bigger strategic pieces.
It's basically be useful. That's the way I always
like to talk about this, just like your job as a
PM is be useful, make your team more effective,
help your company be more successful. Just find
ways to be useful to everyone around you.
Absolutely. And be useful in doing the small
things which make an impact and also contribute to
your learning versus being useful in areas which
you think the mini CEO should be working on.
Right. There's all this talk about
being an empowered product manager,
building empowered product teams. I think
there's an important nuance. When you're
just starting out, you haven't earned the right
to inform strategy and vision people. Why would
people follow you at this point? We just need
to get stuff done, so that comes over time.
Absolutely. And it's not just when you are
starting off or when you are young. Even with if
you are senior and you're starting off with a new
team, even if you're starting with a new company,
you need to have that mindset. And sometimes
you will not know the best. And we'll talk
more about how to, what is your operating model,
which is how you work with others. It's a very,
very important thing for you to know
that you are one part of the cog wheel,
you're not the entire wheel yourself. And a
lot of the folklore around product managers
can make you confused, especially when
you're starting off in your career.
I love it. Okay, let's keep going. Number two.
Number two is what you bring to the table. Now,
I think how I describe that is what is your impact
on impact? So the first access is impact, but you
also need to have an impact on impact. And this
is what I had missed a lot in my early career,
that you put the coolest product areas, your
product area is successful and that automatically
guarantees your growth. It doesn't. You have to
also show that yes, you were a useful contributor
to having that particular impact. The simplest
thing on this is that is your PRD quality good
enough? Are you writing that the draft notes
that go and circulate to the care teams, to
the marketing teams and so on? Are you making sure
that you are deriving from the strategy that has
been shaped or you're constantly just pushing back
on the strategy? Similarly, you also how you are
drafting the north stars, how you are working on
the experiments, how you're working on the data,
how you're working on the metrics.
All these things take time, effort,
and energy. And I know there is some literature
and there are some operating models where people
are working only at strategy levels while all of
these execution of these artifacts is being done
by some other people. I don't think, especially
when you are starting off, that's a very,
very good thing. Even when you are mid-senior, I
don't think that's a very, very good thing. You
have to have to be able to produce these artifacts
which are product artifacts. Even if there are
people in strategy creating their artifacts,
even if design is coming up with a design brief,
you need to have a cohesive product strategy
or product PRD and work backwards from PRD and
product knows yourself. These things are
important to show you are progressing on
four pillars, which is data and metrics, design
and research, technology skills, and strategy.
Product managers constantly are evaluated on
this when you interview, but you also have to
demonstrate these on the jobs. And the best way
to demonstrate these is through the artifacts,
through the notes that you are sending. So you
must have that impact to impact through the
artifacts that you work on. For a lot of product
managers, when I ask, "Hey, I was working on this
very impactful area. I'm not able to have the
impact on my career, what is missing?" And when
I go and ask, "Can you show me your last PRD? Can
you show me the last product note that you sent?
Can you show me the product strategy doc that you
have or collaborated on? Can you show me the brief
that you sent to the design team on the problems
and the ranking of those problems?" Usually,
you'll find something or the other missing.
In cases that those are bad, you will find that
the pre-iteration planning, pre-sprint plannings
are not running properly. You will find that the
Jira storyboards are very empty and there's just
a title in the subject and nothing gets described
and so on. So you'll miss all these pieces.
So these are the things which you bring to
the table and it's very, very important that
you work on these aspects as well. Finally,
we have what's your operating model, which
I feel is the most important thing which
you have to have to focus if you are going
from mid-senior to senior level. This is
essentially about communication, collaboration,
organizational skills and community skills.
And across product managers, again, because of the
folklore of mini CEO and others, I see that a lot
of people get carried away in the way they operate
as product managers with other stakeholders. There
are three tenets that I define in working well
as a product manager with others. Number one is
raise difficult issues without being difficult
to work with. Bring out important topics without
drawing importance to yourself. And finally,
you are in charge of getting the decisions
made and not making all the decisions yourself.
I think as long as you follow these three tenets,
you will have a successful relationship across
stakeholders. These three tenets are easy to say,
but they become very, very hard to embody and
display on a day-to-day basis. But this is
essentially going to be your struggle no matter at
what level of product management you are operating
at in your career or within your company.
First of all, can you just repeat them? Because
I think this is... Essentially,
it's like a mantra that PMs can
think back to of, "Am I doing these things?"
So the three things which are very important for
product managers to work with others and other
stakeholders are raise difficult issues without
being difficult to work with, bring out important
topics without drawing importance to yourself,
and be able to get decisions made without
having to make all the decisions yourself.
I like this list a lot. It reminds me,
there's this product leader I worked
with who their team got pushed to do a bunch
of stupid stuff. And he realized later that,
"Hey, it's actually my job to have pushed back on
doing this stuff." He was the head of product for
this business unit and he realized, "Oh, I see.
That's actually what I should be doing now that
I'm in this role." And you sometimes forget
that one, you have that influence. And two,
that's something you should be doing.
Absolutely, absolutely. It's always within
your control and it's always the things that are
within your control that you should be controlling
rather than focusing on the things that are not
within your control and obsessing about those.
I'm so aligned with the way you think about all
these things. Coming back to the second actually,
just to give people something they can do with
this trait. So the way I think about what you
described, and correct me if I'm misinterpreting
it, is there's a detail-oriented-ness,
high quality-ness to the way that you should
be crafting all the documents/artifacts you're
creating, your one-pagers/PRDs, your roadmaps,
your strategy docs, just like they should be
really high quality. So along those lines, if
you're an ICPM trying to get better at this stuff,
how have you found is the best way to level
up in these things? Is it working with your
manager and getting feedback? Is it peers?
What helps somebody get better at the quality
and yeah, the quality of these documents?
What you bring to the table is one of the most
misunderstood attributes and aspects of product
management. On one end, you could get around and
say, "Here is my PRD, here is my JIRA board, here
are my stories, here is my pre-sprint planning or
pre-iteration planning document" and go. It's not
just about the spread and the width of the things
that you're doing, but it's also about the depth
of those things as well. Some product managers,
what they bring to the table is arguments,
what they bring to the table are debates,
what they bring to the table are pushbacks, while
others are able to channelize the questions,
channelize the inputs, channelize the direction
and convert that into strategic choices which can
then shape discussions, which can then
shape direction. Be the latter and you
will rise faster in your career.
So you have these three buckets of
what you produce, what you bring to the
table, and what your operating model is,
the three W's. So let try to summarize and see
what I missed and then we'll move on. So one is
just focus on executing, getting things done
that are helpful to your team, your company,
your manager, and focus on just getting stuff out.
Not so much in necessarily in strategy. Even when
you're a manager and a leader and a VP, just like
you're still responsible for producing things, not
just telling people and being wise. Two, what you
bring to the table, my takeaway here is produce
high quality artifacts that raise the bar.
The way I think about this is as a PM,
you want to have this aura of I got this. People
put something on your plate, you want to feel like
Lenny's got this, I'm not going to have to worry.
It's going to be forgotten and I know it's going
to be done well. And then the third piece is this
idea of an operating model. Basically just make
sure decisions are being made. It's not about you
that you're pushing back on bad ideas. Is there
anything else I missed before we move on?
No. I think the art of pushback is another
important factor because if you're pushing back
a lot and the way you are pushing back matters a
lot as well. Just don't be someone who's seen as
an obstacle and a hindrance and as someone who's
just very difficult to work with, but rather
see as someone who's able to actually add value
to whatever your leader, your stakeholders,
your product area demands and you are able
to advance the product and the direction and
execution forward. Once you do that, I think
keeping that as the intent and ensuring that your
team is getting unblocked and not getting to do
work on anything which is stupid or is likely
to be changed, then you've really got it.
Do you have any advice for how to pushback
in a way, the way you describe it is not
to be difficult to work with or without seeking
importance? I guess is there words or phrases or
approaches you found are effective for pushing
back against ideas that you disagree with?
What I've seen that people who do pushback
very successfully and are still considered
not difficult to work with, they are also able
to bring the tempo of the conversation to a more
logical space from an emotional space. I think
that's such a useful skill and I sometimes am
guilty of operating on a slightly emotional note,
which is useful. Sometimes you need a war cry,
you need a high pitch, you need execution on war
footing. All that is fine, but it's only fine in
some cases. In other cases, it's always very
important that you're able to bring it down to
the logical space so that a logical and a little
more equal footing of the discussion can happen.
And a lot of this is something that leaders need
to ensure is happening, but product managers and
product leaders who are working with executives
who are able to bring this tempo down and bring
it to a little more logical space will also
do far better in their careers and they'll
also have a lot more rapid career growth.
So let's talk about the flip side of rapid
career growth, which is career growth that
stalls. And I'm curious what you've found
most impedes people's career growth. What do
PMs do that shoot themselves in the foot and
slow their career? Any pitfalls do you find
are important to try to watch out for?
I think part of it is on a lot of us in product
leadership space. We've not done a very good job
in defining rubrics, growth frameworks and so on.
But even in places where growth frameworks exist,
like three W's, what I've seen is that clean
mindset shifts and changes can enable faster
growth, but those mindset and changes also
can hinder your growth, right? So the first
thing is whether you are focusing on things you
control or whether you're focusing on things that
are beyond your control. Second, what's your
relationship with change? And third is how you
see yourself. The third is very, very powerful
and we'll talk about that as well. The first
is what you control. If you drew an access of
what you control and what you cannot control,
as you're starting your career, most of the work
that you're doing is in what you control, right?
You are very obsessed with feedback, you're very
obsessed with, "Okay, can I do this?" "Can I do
this?" "Okay, I'll probably not do this. I'll
probably do this", and so on. You're not worrying
about the overall corporate strategy, you're
not looking at what the competitors are doing,
what is their market cap and all those things.
You're focused a lot on your craft, you're focused
on a lot on your output and you're focused on how
you are growing. As you start becoming mid-senior,
I see the conversation shifts from what can I
do, how am I learning, how am I growing, to why
is the organization not doing this for me? Why
can that stakeholder not change this thing about
themselves? Why do I not get to work on projects
like this? Things which start going outside your
control. And it is very, very important that
you keep your focus no matter what stage of
career you get into what you can control.
And again, it's easy to say that everything in
universe should be in your control. It doesn't
happen like that, but a large number of things
that impact your career are within your control.
And go back to the three W's that we spoke about,
what you work on, what you produce or what do
you bring to the table, and what's your operating
model? And there is tons to do on data, tons to
do on technology, tons to do on communication,
collaboration, design and research, strategy
and community. And you can spend years and years
and years crafting those things. Focus on those
things, growth will happen at every single stage.
The second aspect of it is your relationship
with change. Again, when you are younger,
when you're starting off, rate of change is
crazy. You are growing almost every six months.
You are picking up skills and experimentation,
you're picking up skills in how to analyze.
You're picking up skills in how to work with
different kind of stakeholders. And since the
rate of change of your skills is high,
your rate of growth is also high. Again,
as you start becoming mid-senior, I start seeing
conversations on, "Okay, maybe I should not do
that. Maybe I should not take on this product. I
don't know what it means for my career. I don't
know what it means for my growth" and so on.
So your rate of change slows down. So it's very
important that as you get to mid-senior level,
you are constantly checking on what you can do
to keep increasing your rate of change. And
one of the simplest things that you can do is
if you think you are four on data, figure out who.
And you may be four on data out of five in data.
Within your organization, start benchmarking
yourself with the best in the industry.
You'll automatically see that your scale drops
and as your scale drops, you start seeing
what you need to improve and do. If you start
seeing that on communication and collaboration,
you're reaching four out of five within the PMR,
start mapping yourself to other stakeholders in
other functions. Again, your score will fall in
your eyes and you will start figuring out what are
the things that you can do as well. So keep your
focus on rate of change and rate of growth will
automatically take care of itself. Sometimes
it also involves changing your team or even
changing your company, but those should be the
last results. There are significant things that
you can do within that as well. One of the final
things that I see which limits you, especially as
you start growing in your career and you reach
mid-senior levels is how you see yourself.
I see a lot of product... And I've been guilty of
that. When I see that a lot of product managers,
that's included me at some stage, doing these
things, people will come back and say, "Oh,
I am a very high agency PM" or, "I'm a very
collaborative PM." Earlier on, I used to think
that okay, I need to give this kind of work to
these product managers. I need to fit them with
these kind of team, these kind of work areas,
these kind of opportunities. But then I started
understanding these things are not just signaling,
they are also anti-signaling. They are like, "Oh,
I'm high agency. So it's sometimes okay if
I'm little brash, if I cut corners somewhere,
if I sometimes come across as a little
rude to some people" and so on, right?
Similarly, if I'm seen as a hyper-collaborative
person, so it's okay if sometimes I'm not very
decisive, if I'm not moving fast and so on
because I'm this kind of a PM. So it's very
important that you check for what are the stories
that you're telling yourself because those stories
are defining you at a basic level, which is
then very hard to correct through frameworks
and structures. So figure out what is the story
that you are telling yourself. If you are not
able to figure that out, talk to the people you
trust so that they can tell you that as well,
and then correct those stories. And the
moment you are able to correct those stories,
you may be back on the growth path again.
Wow, there's so much meat and wisdom in what
you just shared. I want to go in so
many different directions. Maybe just
to follow on this last thread, did you go
through something like that yourself where
you have this sense of yourself that hindered
you? Okay, awesome. You're nodding your head,
if you're not on YouTube. Can you share that?
Yeah. So I'll give an example of when I joined
Gojek. The very first thing that I learned in my
career was SQL and Oracle. And I was very proud
of the fact that my data skills are awesome and I
know several frameworks and I know several tools
and so on. And when I joined Gojek and I saw one
of your guests, Crystal, and I saw the work that
she was doing and her team was doing and I just
immediately was like, "Yeah, no, this is not...
I'm nowhere near", right? And similarly, I also
thought that my communication skills are really
good and my product strategy skills are very good,
but then I worked with people like Dito and people
like Sidu who was so good at their craft that it
challenged me to see that okay, what is it that
I am missing? What is it that I am doing wrong?
And it auto-calibrated me in my eyes on where it
was, but that also created a hunger in me that
this is what I need to fix. And I immediately
corrected my assessment of myself that I'm
not the strongest product manager on data.
I'm not the one who knows all the strategy
pieces or even strategy frameworks or how
to bring everything to a strategy point of view
or communicate it from an effective perspective.
And then I started framing I'm still in a learning
phase. When I see that I'm not in that phase now,
I try and make myself humble by interacting
with people who are far smarter than me on
different scale or reading different books,
or watching podcasts like yourselves. And
that keeps you grounded on the fact that okay,
you are always learning. And I also found that
seeing yourself as someone who's a learner
is an enabling story to tell yourself, okay?
It may not be the most exciting story, it may
not be the most memorable story about yourself,
but it is definitely one of the enabling stories
as well. Similarly, I think one other thing that
I used to say about myself was more that I'm very
high agency PM. But as I started working more in
Southeast Asia, I learned that mindfulness
is also very, very important, that not every
team, not every culture will work with you in a
very hyper aggressive style. But you still need to
get the work done. And I'm still learning on that
and therefore, I've started using a word, I don't
want to be a high agency person, I want to be a
mindful agency person. And so these terms are very
important because these are the stories that you
keep telling yourself and these also then start
shaping your behavior. I do feel that I have a lot
to do, I have a lot to learn on these skills, but
these things definitely keep you grounded and you
keep coming back to the learning phase again.
It's interesting that when you saw Crystal being
incredibly good at working with data, you just
realized, "Hey, maybe I'm actually not very good
at this." And your reaction wasn't, "God damn it,
I'm really screwed and this is really depressing
me", it's, "No, instead I'm going to try to get
better at this." And that reminds me some
of the feedback I get with this podcast,
those people are like, "Man, these people are
so good, I'm never going to be this good. It
discourages me from thinking I will ever be
super successful in this career." Clearly,
you have a different approach. Do you have
advice or guidance to folks that are sometimes
discouraged seeing people being so incredible
and helping them actually continue to level up in
this rate of change you talked about versus just
like, "Nope, I'm never going to be that good?"
I think as product managers it becomes difficult
because a lot of your growth is being determined
because of feedback of others. And because product
management is so ambiguous and still not defined,
the stakeholders can also give feedback on
variety of dimensions. Some of them may not even
be important enough to give feedback on, but they
are important enough for them and so therefore,
they give you feedback. And therefore, you
have to shape that feedback in. But you also
have to consider that there are these eight
access that we spoke about, the data access,
the design and research access, the technology
access, the strategy access, communication access,
collaboration access, organizational skills
access, and the community access. You need
to channelize feedback into okay, is this an
area that you are targeting for growth or not?
And one of the most important things that I
learned was that when I joined Gojek or even
earlier, there would be so many different areas
that I needed to improve on and still need to
improve on. You can't improve on every single
area. That's what overwhelms you. You need
to pick which is the area which is the maximum
leverage for you and improve on that particular
aspect and then move on to the next area, then
move on to the next area and so on. Obviously,
if you are floundering in something, if you're
really negative in something, then you fix that
first because that will give you the highest
leverage. But if you are picking up data and
design and strategy and technology all at the
same time, that's when you'll overwhelm you.
So to summarize the advice there is one,
be actually very open to feedback you're
getting. It's easy to say that, it's hard
to actually listen to people criticizing
you and act on it. So I think that's an
important takeaway here is just actually,
feedback is a gift and actually understand that
and try to act on it. I have a great interview
with Jules Walter who's a PM at Google now, and he
has this awesome quote about how whenever people
give him hard feedback, it's like internally he's
just melting, but that's externally he's like,
"Thank you so much for that feedback, I
really appreciate it. It's very valuable."
And so that's a good way to get people to keep
giving feedback. Okay. And then the other piece
of advice you just shared there is pick a focus
area. Like say you're getting all this feedback,
your strategy isn't amazing, your PRDs aren't
great, just find one thing to focus on. And I
don't know, do you try to do somewhat
quarter? Somewhat year? Do you have a
heuristic of how long to spend on one thing?
So different skills take different time and how
you are progressing also depends a lot as
well. For skills which are softer in nature
like communication and collaboration and
community, those are skills that you will
work on all your life. You'll never achieve
anywhere near two or five on five on those
ever. There'll always be something that you
will miss, there will always be a new context,
there'll always be a new set of stakeholders,
new company cultures that you have to adapt to.
For others, you have to see that what gives you
the maximum leverage in your career. When you're
starting off, my recommendation is that you
pick between data and tech one, and definitely
one on design and research and strategy.
So usually, that's the combo that I recommend.
My advice is if you're coming from design and
research background, then you pick data or tech.
If you're coming from a data or tech background,
then you pick design and research, and that gives
you the maximum leverage because that's a skill
that you will necessarily not have developed over
the years. Once you've demonstrated on two of
these three, between data, tech and design and
research, then you start focusing on strategy.
We've had great success at Gojek in transitioning
a lot of product managers, especially in
Indonesia, using this framework. And it's
produced a lot of good product managers for us.
Well, let's actually follow that thread. That's
really interesting. And so the approach is you
have this access of skillsets and you pick,
for this person moving from say customer service
to product, here's the two things you need to
focus on. Can you talk more about that?
Yeah. For instance, we recently had two PMs,
one who came from a growth background. This is
actually [inaudible 00:42:24]'s team. And one
from a research background. And with both of them,
we use very different tactics. So we gave one of
finding driver redesign, which was very much a
very design-focused product, but we still had them
leverage their data skills because we were able
to create a PRD with incredible amount of data on
exactly what different segments of customers we're
doing. And that then we worked with designers on
what the designs and the framework for that will
be. And even now, Lenny, if you will come and see
our finding driver redesign next time you are
in Asia, it's a piece of art. And if you would
see that that was worked on by a product
manager who actually came from a growth and
data background, that makes it even more special.
Similarly, the PM who transitioned from research,
I kept giving feedback on technology and data
skills are the ones that we need to check. And
I need to hear from engineers that yes, they're
able to work with her very strongly. And once
she was able to do that, she's recently turned
a very heated question on one of the features
that we were doing into a full-blown solution
with designs, with trade-offs and everything,
and able to now convert it into a question for
leadership on how we should be approaching this
particular product and direction. So I think
that's proven successful as well. Similarly,
there's another person who took risk who
was originally from research and again,
worked a lot on our products, including our
enterprise product. And she's doing an amazing job
as well. Again, going through that path of okay,
these are the things that you need to leverage.
The only watch-out is that it doesn't work out
always. In some cases, some PMs will pick these
things up fast, and it also makes a big difference
if you are transitioning when you are slightly
younger in your career. If you are already senior
in a function and then you are transitioning,
sometimes it can take a lot of time in
transitioning and picking up those skills.
But it's definitely doable if you get a very
strong product leader working with you who's
able to shape those skills for you. So it's
sometimes okay to go a little slow when you're
transitioning so that you're able to go faster
later rather than getting faster somewhere and
then being stuck there for a while.
This episode is brought to you by Coda,
and I mean that literally. I use Coda every day
to help me plan each episode of this very podcast.
It's where I keep my content calendar, my guest
research, and also the questions that I plan to
ask each guest. Also, during the recording itself,
I have a Coda page up to remind myself what I
want to talk about. Coda is an all-in-one platform
that combines the best of documents, spreadsheets,
and apps to help you and your team get more done.
Now is the perfect time to get started with Coda,
especially its extensive planning capabilities.
With Coda, you can stay aligned and ship faster
by managing your planning cycles in one location.
You can set and measure OKRs with full visibility
across teams and stakeholders. You can map
dependencies, create progress visualizations,
and identify risk areas. Plus, you can access
hundreds of pressure-tested templates for
everything from roadmap strategy
to final decision-making to PRDs.
If you want a platform that empowers your team
to strategize, plan and track goals together,
you can get started with Coda today for free. And
if you want to see for yourself why product teams
at high-growth companies like Pinterest, Figma
and Qualtrics run on Coda, take advantage of the
special limited-time offer just for startups.
Head over to coda.io/lenny to sign up and get
$1,000 in credit. That's C-O-D-A.io/lenny to
sign up and get $1,000 in credit. Coda.io/lenny.
Something that you mentioned earlier that I wanted
to come back to is this confusion about what the
PM role is and how that trips people up in being
successful in the role and continuing to thrive
in the role. You mentioned this to me offline too,
that this is just something you deal with a lot,
just this frustration of what the hell is
this job? What am I actually responsible
for? What am I not? What do you find is helpful in
helping people work through that, get past that,
not make that a big blocker in their career,
not knowing exactly what the PM role is?
I think we've been in technology product for
several decades now, but we are still figuring out
what an exact definition of product management is.
And even the strongest definitions are slightly
principled and philosophical in nature, they're
not very concrete, and that also means that every
and different technology companies have gone
through different journeys and they've defined
the roles very, very differently. And even within
a very large company, you will see that different
teams, different divisions are approaching
the roles very, very differently as well.
And on top of that, what that does is that
not only internally the product managers
are figuring this out, their managers, their
leaders are figuring these things out for them,
but the other stakeholders who have to work with
these product managers are also confused and they
don't know what to expect. And the number
one question I get from stakeholders is,
is a product manager expected to do this? Because
they also don't know, okay, is this expected
from a product manager or not? And my general
answer to that is, if this is something which
is blocking the progress on the product, then
yes, the product manager should work on that.
Love that.
But that works if the product managers
have had some training and they have had some
training in working with different stakeholders
and they have had something on the job. What I've
figured out is that there are certain functions
and there are certain disciplines which you can't
define, but you can only become better at with
practice. For instance, what is an actor or what
is a dancer? Right? So these are things that you
will get better at as you become skilled at it.
And earlier, these things used to be looked at
as something which is very artistic, only the
people who are talented or only specific kind
of people can do it. But now, each one of those
has become [inaudible 00:48:57] and frameworks as
well. So there are courses on filmmaking,
there are courses on acting, there are
courses on dancing and so on. And similarly,
product management is that space as well.
So you have to understand there's an art to it
and there's a science to it, but you can use
the science to figure out the art. So that's the
philosophical side of it. The second side of it
is what we spoke about earlier that instead
of figuring out what is product management,
figure out what's your contribution, what's your
output and figure out are you contributing on
these access on data, on design, on technology and
on strategy. And one of my favorite things is that
if you created these four circles of strategy, of
technology, of design and of data, and you created
a product management circle which encircles each
one of these, so you are the only discipline,
which is the co-collaborator for all of these
disciplines and tying all these things out.
So it's not about you standing alone, it's you
always collaborating and pairing with someone
else. But you are the only one who's pairing
with everyone else and therefore, you have that
unique insight which no one else in the team will
have. That role can be played by someone else,
it doesn't necessarily need to be called a
product manager. But if you are being called a
product manager, you figure out the [inaudible
00:50:24] the time piece that you are. And
when you are added to the team, you must dream
the team's overall contribution, overall energy
and overall output up and not down.
I love that. Something I always tell
people is the PM doesn't necessarily have the
magical skills other team members don't have,
it's that they don't also have another job.
Engineers may do a great job at being the PM,
they just also have to build and code. And they
don't have time to do all the things that a PM
has to do, and a designer is in the same way,
a researcher or data person. And so oftentimes,
that's just like there's this person that has the
time to do all these glue, work things between
teams. And the great PMs also are very good
at these skills that help you do these things,
but it doesn't mean other people can't do them.
You see yourself as playing a role and not your
title and not your function, and
that just clarifies a lot of things
for people. And different people will play
different roles. And depending on the kind
of a PM you are, are you in a specific domain
or you are slightly generalist, the role that
you will be playing in different teams can be
different and the variety of roles that you
can play makes you a better product manager.
I love that. You've mentioned these four access
attributes of great product managers, overall
product managers. Let's just spend a little time
here. So you say basically the things you need
to be doing and good at, data, design/research
technology, strategy, and then you also mentioned
collaboration and communication. Maybe you're-
Yeah, organizational skills and community. I think
those are very, very important because one of the
things and one of the things which one of the
product managers works with me continues to say,
and I really plus on that a lot, is that product
manager is the all community enabler in the team,
in the organization. And that community is the
software aspect which ties everyone together
towards a common mission of delivering
an output. And that I think is a very,
very important goal in today's context, especially
for teams which are becoming more remote or
teams where people are not co-located or they're
distributed. That community aspect becomes a very,
very important part that product managers need
to focus on and bring and channelize as well.
So let's just quickly describe each of these
attributes. I imagine people might be thinking,
"Okay, what should I get better at as a PM?"
And this is an awesome list. Each company has
their own career ladders and attributes and
things like that, but not a lot of companies
don't. So I think for people that are trying
to figure out where do I need to get better,
I think this is a really cool list. Can you just
maybe just a sentence explanation of each of these
attributes and skillsets that a PM needs?
So each one of those skills, like the most
growth ladders, what they will do, is they will
have say for data, they will have level one,
exhibits these traits. Level two,
exhibits this trait. Level three,
exhibits this trait. Level four and level five and
so on. That's how they'll describe it. But five
is absolute ninja level data quality, like you
could probably do a data startup of your own.
Like Crystal basically?
Crystal. And level zero is someone who cannot
even basically define the basic metrics for this
particular product and won't be able to figure out
is this particular thing impacting orders or
users or revenue. And so you'll really not be
able to figure even that piece out. Similarly,
on design and research, for product managers,
we focus a lot more on problems and are you able
to identify problems from a user's perspective.
That's at level zero. And level five will be
somebody who's able to define the user problems
but is also able to tie them to business roles as
well. So that makes it the holistic. Similarly,
on technology, it's one of the skills which is
relatively easier to define where you don't have
any tech understanding. If somebody asked you
what is HTTP or API or internet and you'll be
like, "Okay, I don't know what it is."
And while on the other end, you are able
to have deep debates and could probably write
technology design documents yourself as well.
I think sometimes people get confused between
data science. And in different organizations,
I see data science bucketed either in data or
in technology. Either is fine as long as you are
clear on what your organization's framework is.
Similarly then, there is strategy. Strategy is I
think another area in product management which
gets very confusing because there is obviously
corporate strategy, there is business strategy,
there's pricing strategy, there's strategy
everywhere. Product strategy for me is where you
are able to define that while somebody defines
that this is the mountain that you're going to
climb, but okay, how are you going to climb that
mountain is basically the product strategy piece.
So you are not in charge of okay, are you focused
on growth? Are you focused on revenue? Are you
focused on profitability? That's someone's choice.
Are you going to pick this country? Are you going
to pick that country? But once that is picked,
what are the user segments that you're going
to focus on? What are the needs of those user
segments? How are we going to figure out what
the right product for them will be? What is
the order in which we are going to work on
that? That whole piece of product strategy
is with the product managers. And again, in
the first case, you are basically going to
rely on everyone to tell you, do this, do this,
do this. In second and in the level five cases,
you are able to articulate a very coherent
product strategy at a broad level as well.
Amazing, thanks for sharing that. I think for
people that are trying to craft career ladder
for product managers, this could help inform
the way they think about this. By the way,
when we mentioned Crystal, for folks that have
no idea who we're talking about, she was a early
head of growth at Gojek back in the day. She
was a previous guest on the podcast. I always
forget how to pronounce her last name exactly,
but I think it's Widjaja, Crystal Widjaja.
Widjaja.
Widjaja? Okay, okay. Great. Going
in a different direction, we're going to move to
contrarian corner. I'm curious if there's anything
that you believe that other people wouldn't
agree with or generally just don't believe?
I used to think intent is the most important
thing, right? And when I was starting off,
that used to be the advice that as long as your
intent is right, even if some of your words are
not landing, even if some of the comms are
not landing, that will work out. What I've
seen is that it's not enough. Your actions, your
behavior, and the way you communicate, the way
you collaborate, that also has to communicate
and show who you are as well. So intent is
not enough. And that's a thing which I think a
lot of people in my age group just don't get,
but people who are slightly starting off their
career, it resonates well with them. Second thing
I think where I feel that it's become, I don't
know, is it contrarian or it's become politically
incorrect, is that you still need to put in
the effort and our number of hours is effort.
And I think that's one thing which has become
very politically incorrect to say over the years
when I was younger, it was the norm that
yes, you will have to put in the effort,
you will have to put in the hours to grow
and improve your skills. And it's not even
about your growth in the company, it's just your
own growth. You have to spend the time, effort,
and energy into growing. I think a lot of that
is getting lost in the debates between complete
workaholism and just being not very serious about
your growth at all. So I think those are the two
that I find myself having to explain myself
again and again and why I feel this way.
I completely agree with that. I find a hugely
strong correlation between hours you put into the
work you do and success. And I think there's been
a return to okay, working hard is really important
and you shouldn't be afraid of promoting working
really hard. So we've actually gone through
everything that I wanted to ask you. Before we
get to our very exciting lightning round, is there
anything else you wanted to share or is there
anything you want to leave listeners with?
No, I think it has been great talking to. I hope
it was useful to people. I've tried to keep it
real, but also in takeaway format. And if there
are any questions that you have that I feel I
have not answered, I'm happy to answer them.
Okay, amazing. Well, we'll have people post in
the comments if there's anything else they would
love to ask you. With that, we've reached our very
exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
Yes.
First question, what are two or three books
that you've recommended most to other people?
The first book is a book which I feel is not
quoted enough in product management community,
is a book called Small Data by Martin Lindstrom.
This is a person who was an advertiser or
marketeer who would go and make campaigns for big
brands in different countries, and so would have
usually very short time to get the pulse of that
space and design a campaign around it. And how he
got insights very quickly from, and what are some
of the takeaways that are there for people working
in product space, not just product managers,
but designers, researchers, strategy people,
anyone really, I can't recommend that book more.
And I've cited that book a lot internally.
The second book that I recommend is Adam Grant's
Originals. I think it's a very important book.
It changed a lot of things. When I spoke about
that I was going through this crisis of, oh,
I'm behind so many things after joining Gojek,
Originals was one book that I read which really,
really helped me think about my growth and
how I see myself. And anyone who is stuck or
anyone who feels they are superstars, they are
the innovators of the century kind of a thing,
it's a book that gives you a very good reality
check. And the third book that I recommend
is definitely Daniel Kahneman's Thinking, Fast
and Slow. I think especially the thinking slow
part becomes very, very important piece as well.
And the reason why change is hard, the reason why
feedback is hard is because we are used
to thinking fast and we are not used to
thinking slow. While if you actually think slow,
you'll actually welcome change and growth.
Amazing. That book's come up a bunch actually
recently on the podcast and it is always sitting
under my laptop, holding up my laptop for these
interviews. So I fully agree. Next question,
do you have a favorite recent movie or
TV show that you've really enjoyed?
I haven't seen a lot of movies recently, I think.
But while I was on the flight back from Dubai,
I saw Miss Congeniality again and I really, really
enjoyed it. I thought it's a very fun movie,
but also had a pretty good message. I know
it's probably not the movie which anyone would
want to cited, but I think it's sometimes
good to just watch good entertainment.
That's quite the contrarian pick. Yeah, nobody
has cited this movie, Miss Congeniality. This is
a first, but I love it. It's way out there.
I would never would've expected this.
In terms of TV shows, I think the show that
I really go back to all the time is Schitt's
Creek. I think it's a show which operates at so
many different levels without taking itself that
seriously, and it just lands. And especially as
a product manager and as a leader who obsesses a
lot about diversity, I think it did a fantastic
job in showing different sides of motherhood,
of the LGBTQIA communities, and also
teenage girls figuring themselves out
as well. I think it did a fantastic job.
Do you have a favorite interview question that
you like to ask candidates when you're
hiring product managers especially?
So it's not really one question, but what I like
to do with them is to brainstorm choices on an
actual product. And I'll typically pick up a
product that they use most often and then I
will be like, "Okay, what if this product were to
do this? Then what do you think, it makes sense?
Don't think it makes sense? What about this?
Okay, how would it evolve in six months? What
would happen in 12 months and so on?" I think it
gives you a far better insight into how would it
be on working with them on a real case. And you
also keep... And what I like about it is that you
can keep going back deeper into it and develop
it together. So I typically try and pick product
that I will also not have very strong opinions on
so that it can become a two-way conversation.
What do you actually look for in an answer that
tells you, "Okay, this candidate is amazing"
versus flags that are like, "Hmm, maybe not?"
There are some obvious check marks that are they
able to first abstract out and figure out what
the overall goals for the product are, who the
users for that product are, what would they be
focusing on right now, whether this will align
with that or not. And then a reason backwards that
okay, maybe this may not work, but something on
these lines. Are you obsessed about this feature
or are you obsessed about okay, what this enables
you to do? So if this is what it enables you
to do, then are you okay with considering some
other options and so on? So I think that's the
direction which usually goes in the right way.
Is there a favorite product you've recently
discovered that you really love?
So the reason why I've not watched a lot of drama
or TV recently is because I've discovered these
short video apps through Instagram and all
of these apps, they dub Chinese TV serials
into English or there will be subtitles in English
and they are delivered in TikTok style two-minute
videos. And it's a masterstroke in how the
series are constructed. The first few episodes,
which is like 10 episodes which is about
10 to 15 minutes, sets up the story in
such a way that you have to unlock the next 10.
And these videos are quite expensive. They end up,
one series takes more than the entire cost of
monthly cost of Netflix to view. But it's just
amazing how the whole product has been put,
how all these products have been put together
on unlocking the lamification aspects of it, the
storytelling aspects of it, the content cutting
part of it, and even the selection of the stories
part of it. And what I'm told is that once I've
learned about it, I've also been reading about
it, they're actually companies which are able to
give you tools of where you can construct this
app yourself. And multiple people, two-people,
three-people companies are churning these out
and earning a lot of profit from it as well.
What is this called for people
that want to check this out?
So you can start with DramaBox, you can start
with [inaudible 01:07:47] Reels and so on.
And there are multiple of these. And those
of you who are very familiar with TikTok,
you would've seen that some of these show
you the first 10 episodes on TikTok and then
they take you to their app to view the rest.
Wow. I love so many unusual contrarian pieces of
advice here, I love it. Two more questions.
Do you have a favorite life motto that you
often come back to, share with friends
or family, either in work or in life?
For me, the most important thing has been that
I started my career very late in tech. I was
already 25. For the first several years, I worked
in a small [inaudible 01:08:32] town in India. I
came to Delhi only in 2013, and I joined Gojek
in 2018. I think I've done reasonably well for
myself. And it's never late to do or what do you
want to do and what do you want to be. I think
that's the thing that I really, really believe in
and I also advise in. Especially as the world is
aging and a lot of people are thinking about it,
I would say that it's not too late ever. You can
be and do what you want right now.
So good. It's not too late. I really,
really like that advice. My wife is an
illustrator designer. She has a book she
put out called Am I Overthinking This? It's in my
background somewhere there. And she has a chart
that communicates that exact message in a really
cute way, and we'll try to link to it in the show
notes. Final question. You live in Singapore,
I know you travel a lot. But if someone were to
come to Singapore, is there a food that you think
they need to try that's unique to Singapore?
Singapore? There are multiple. So Singapore is
a melting pot of different cultures. There are
four official languages. And the only thing I
will advise is depending on your taste buds,
whatever you want to do, you should go and visit
a Hawker Center. And it's an amazing experience in
itself. And those of you who've seen Crazy Rich
Asians, the first thing they do when they land
in Singapore is go to the Hawker Center. So it's
an experience of its kind. And if you are looking
for a specific recommendation, go to Lau Pa Sat.
If you are a fan of Indian, you'll get that. If
you're a fan of Malay cuisine, you'll get that.
If you're a fan of Singaporean Chinese, you'll
get that. So you pick what works for you.
I love that. Vikrama, I feel like we've produced
both a lot of output and we're going to have
really great outcomes from our conversation.
Thank you so much for being here. Two final
questions. Where can folks find you online if
they want to reach out and follow-up
on any of the stuff we talked about?
And how can listeners be useful to you?
Thank you, Lenny. It's been great talking to
you as well. Hopefully, this turns out well. You
can reach out to me either on LinkedIn, Vikrama
Dhiman, or you can reach out on Twitter. Twitter
works better. And the listeners can be useful to
me by, well, just sharing whatever they feel. And
I continuously follow a lot of people, a lot of
people who are not yet famous. Just tell me what
your story is, just tell me what you are working
on. And as long as you are passionate about it,
I will try and find time. Maybe I cannot talk to
everyone, but I'll definitely try and find to chat
with you and listen out and support or connect
you to someone who can help support you.
That's a very generous offer, I think a lot
of people are going to take you up on that.
Vikrama, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you so much, Lenny.
Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to the show
on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.