I love that you have very strong opinion
about this, which is just the state of
the product management career and
how most PMs are not that great.
Why is it that product management is still
such a relatively undeveloped discipline?
We're like 15 to 20 years into this, and
so there's something about the current
state of product management that isn't
getting at the truly important things,
the truly value-added things. If we were doctors,
you'd be like, "That's totally unacceptable."
What's the answer, Shaun?
How do we solve this problem?
In everything always talk from the customer's
perspective, from the market's perspective,
from the competitor's perspective, the
very small number of PMs do that. They
get dragged into internal politics, they
get dragged into scrum management or scrum
execution or product delivery,
and you just can't win that way.
You kind of have this hot
take that the way AI will
most impact product management is data management.
Well, you've got this synthesis machine, which
is this LLM thing that's going to help you do
synthesis, but if it hasn't got all that data to
do synthesis on top of, it's got nothing. And so
that means that LLMs can only be as good as the
data they are given and how recent that data is.
In the future, if you can easily clone a
B2B SaaS app like Salesforce or Atlassian,
what happens to these businesses long-term?
Do they just become, are they all in trouble?
People really underestimate
where the value is created in
these applications and they just
kind of get it completely wrong.
Today my guest is Shaun Clowes. Shaun is chief
product officer at Confluent. Previously he
was chief product officer at MuleSoft, which is a
billion-dollar business within Salesforce. Before
that, he was chief product officer of Metromile,
a public auto insurance technology company. And
prior to that he spent six years at Atlassian
where he ran the Jira agile and also built the
first ever B2B growth team. He also created two of
the most popular Reforge courses, one on retention
and engagement and one on data for product
managers. Shaun is awesome because he's both very
tactical in execution oriented, while also being
very philosophical and insightful about the craft
of product and growth. In our conversation,
Shaun shares why most PMs are not good,
what it takes to become a good or great product
manager, how he thinks about his career, like a
Bingo card and why he indexes towards finding very
different roles for every new job that he takes.
Why good data is the most important ingredient
in AI tools and for product managers working
with AI. Also, how to build a great B2B growth
team, what he's learned about doing B2B growth
and his really interesting take on how AI will
and won't disrupt SaaS tools out in the wild.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. It's the best way to
avoid missing feature episodes and it helps the
podcast tremendously. With that I bring you
Shaun Clowes. This episode is brought to you
by Enterpret. Enterpret unifies all your customer
interactions from Gong calls to Zendesk tickets,
to Twitter threads, to app store reviews and makes
it available for analysis. It's trusted by leading
product orgs like Canva, Notion, Loom, Linear,
Monday.com, and Strava to bring the voice of the
customer into the product development process,
helping you build best-in-class products faster.
What makes Enterpret special is its ability to
build and update customer-specific AI models
that provide the most granular and accurate
insights into your business, connect customer
insights to revenue and operational data in your
CRM or data warehouse, to map the business impact
of each customer need and prioritize confidently,
and empower your entire team to easily take action
on use cases like win-loss analysis, critical
bug detection, and identifying drivers of churn
with Enterpret's AI systems Wisdom. Looking to
automate your feedback loops and prioritize your
roadmap with confidence like Notion, Canva and
Linear, visit E-N-T-E-R-P-R-E-T.com/lenny to
connect with the team and to get two free months
when you sign up for an annual plan. This is a
limited-time offer. That's enterpret.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by BuildBetter.ai.
Back in 2020 when AI was just a toy, BuildBetter
bet that it could cut down on a product team's
operational BS. Fast-forward to today, 23,000
product teams use purpose-built AI in BuildBetter
every day. First, BuildBetter uses custom models
to turn unstructured data like product and sales
calls, support tickets, internal communications,
and surveys into structured insights. It's like
having a dedicated data science team. Second,
BuildBetter runs those structured insights into
workflows, like weekly reports about customer
issues, contacts to where PRDS, and user
research documents with citations, it even turns
stand-ups into action items that automatically get
assigned and shared into your tools. Plus,
with unlimited seat pricing on all plans,
BuildBetter ensures everyone at your company
has access to this knowledge, truly no data
silos. In a world of AI demos over-promising and
under-delivering, see why BuildBetter has a 93%
subscription retention. Get a personalized demo
and use code Lenny for $100 credit if you sign up
now at buildbetter.ai/lenny. Shaun, thank you so
much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you, Lenny. It's really awesome to be here.
I've had you on my radar for a long time
and I am really excited to finally have
you here and big bonus points for having a very
beautiful, sultry Australian accent that always
helps with the ratings, I think. I don't
know if it's causal, but it's correlative.
I'm glad to be a bit of a curiosity.
So I want to start with something I totally
believe and I love that you have very strong
opinion about this, which is just the
state of the product management career
and how most PMs are not that great
and how there's a big opportunity to
level up. You just talk about what you've
seen there and you're just thinking here.
Yeah, it's honestly a big conundrum for me. I
think it's actually part of... It's grandiose
to say so, a bit of my life's work. Why is
it that product management is still such a
relatively undeveloped discipline? We're 15 to
20 years into this thing. You would've thought
that it would be less random than it is. The
outcomes are random, the behaviors are random,
individual performance is random, seemingly. And
so there's something about the current state of
product management that isn't getting at the truly
important things, the truly value-added things,
the right way to think about problems,
the right way to think through problems,
the abstract reasoning that's needed, there's
something that isn't working about it. I spent
a long time trying to put my finger on it
and then be like, "How do you reproducibly
reproduce that?" Reproducibly produce people
who can really be really great product managers.
The thing is that if you think all the way back to
it, I spent a long time as an engineer and people
always talk about 10 times engineers and I wanted
to be a 10 times engineer. I'll leave it to others
to decide to tell you whether or not I was or I
wasn't, but certainly I wanted to be and I tried
to be a really great engineer. And it must be
true that if there's 10 times engineers, and I
would argue they definitely are, they must be 10
times product managers too. But at the same time,
those 10 times product managers, because product
management is ultimately about leverage, so it's
about helping other people have dramatically more
impact than they would if they were unorganized
that they didn't have somebody to organize
the goals and what we're trying to achieve,
then that means that a 10 times product manager
has 100 times return or more because they're 10
timesing the return on 10 times resources.
So the outcomes are so wild, like wildly
distributed and the benefits are so good that you
would've thought that it would've behooved us.
There would've been a way that this had evolved
and improved and really gotten way crisper than
it has, but here we are. I'm not saying that we
haven't gotten better, we 100% have, but I think
we could all say that we're not reliably producing
10 times product managers every day of the week.
I love this point and it's especially
painful that when someone works with
a PM that's not great. There's just this
meme of why do I need PMs? PMs are useless,
PMs suck, and it just creates that no one's
ever like, "Engineers are useless or designers
are useless." But there's so many people
are like, "I don't need product managers
on our team. Never hire a PM," and it
just sets the whole profession back.
When I first started out in PM somebody, it's
obviously a chestnut, but he pointed out that
realistically when you're a product manager, your
job is to say no to 90% of things that get brought
your way. And so that kind of makes you the bad
person pretty much from the start. And so you're
saying no to 90%, so you can say yes to 10% and
that kind of puts you behind the eight-ball right
at the very beginning, and so you have to very
quickly get runs on the board. You have to prove
to have the right insights, to have the right
data, to make the right decisions or you don't
get another go, you don't get another swing at
it. So it makes sense that product managers are
the easiest to single out and criticize, but
that is also what makes it the funnest thing.
If you think about why do we do this? Somebody
once asked me, "Would you retire? Why do people
do what they do?" Because certainly at some
point it isn't just about the money and at the
end of the day product management is so damn fun
because it's about trying to figure out an edge.
It's like trying to look at the world, find the
portion of the chessboard that isn't occupied,
but that is valuable and find a way to get into
it, invade it and destroy it. It's decisions
under uncertainty and that makes it unbelievably
fun. Really, really painful and very frustrating
and very hard to convince people, but very,
very fun. So in equal measures basically.
What's the answer, Shaun? How do we solve
this problem? I know you said it's your
life's work. What do you find actually helps most
in helping PMs level up and become say 10 X PMs?
I think the most important thing and the chestnut
that I repeat to everybody is that at the end of
the day, the time you spend looking inside
the building doesn't really benefit you very
much at all. And Steve Blanken, people used to
talk about you should be spending 80% of your
time thinking about things going on outside the
building. You might not be outside the building,
but you should spend 80% of your time thinking
outside the building. And I would say that very
small number of PMs do that. They get dragged
into internal politics, they get dragged into
scrum management or scrum execution or product
delivery, like elements of the delivery thing
and you just can't win that way. You just
can't win that way. You can never get an
A because you're fundamentally not solving the
job. The job is not about execution or anything,
it's about finding reliable, differentiated value
that you can uniquely deliver into the market.
So I would say if there's one thing, two things
I would say actually that I generally guide
product managers to do, one is to always start
from the point of view outside the building in
every document in everything, always talk from
the customer's perspective, from the market's
perspective, from the competitor's perspective,
and the people who listen to me on that I would
say get better almost immediately because
they're starting from a place that's easier to
understand and then secondarily be data informed.
They use all of that view of the world, but don't
just make up a bunch of statements, support that
statements with anecdotes and bits of data. It
doesn't have to be a treatise, but convince
everybody of what the world really looks like
and what the opportunities ahead of the company
looks like and good things happen to you. And all
of a sudden you go from a world where nobody wants
to help you get anything done to where everybody
wants you to win. They want you to win and they
may not give you everything you want, but they
certainly will try because they're like, "Well, of
all the bets we could make, this is a good one."
I imagine many people listening
to this are thinking, "Oh,
I am that person. I talk to customers
all the time. I'm always interacting,
looking at research, putting data together."
And what you're saying is you're probably not
doing that enough. Is there anything that
you could help someone recognize of, "No,
you're actually not doing this enough
and you think you are but you're not."
It's one thing to say you're spending a lot of
time looking outside the building. It's a whole
other thing to hear from the places you don't
normally hear from. So avoid availability or
confirmation bias. Most of the time people go talk
to the people they always talk to and they learn
nothing particularly new. They don't synthesize
the results that they got from that conversation.
They don't seek out the counterfactual, they don't
seek out the proof that they're wrong. They don't
analyze what their competitors are doing and
figure out what that must tell you about the
market. They don't bring back the data of how
their product is actually being used versus how
people say it's being used. It's like all data and
no analysis is not very useful. Everyone can bring
back an omnibus edition of random stuff I heard
on a Tuesday, but the competitive advantage is
extracted out of figuring out what other people
don't see, figuring out where we are wrong,
figuring out where a well-placed bet could
have dramatically outlandish returns.
And so I think firstly, people often say that
they do a lot of this stuff, but they actually
don't because they don't have any structured way
of doing it. So what they really mean is every
now and then I get in a customer call or every
now and then I get stuck into an escalation. And
so they're kind of conveniently bucketing it. So
firstly they don't do it in a very structured way,
then they don't bring back analysis, they get true
insights from that thing, so they don't really
gain very much at all. It's just more activity,
no outcomes. People do far too much activity with
not enough outcomes and there just isn't enough
time in the day to do that to be successful.
You as a product leader is at the Venn
diagram center of the sweet spot of where
this podcast has been going recently,
which is product and growth and how AI
helps you with all these things. And so to
follow a thread there with synthesizing and
understanding what people are saying, user
research and surveys and all these things,
have you found any tools that you and your team
have found really useful to help you do this more
efficiently versus traditionally just manually
going through all the stuff and finding patterns?
Yeah, so firstly, stepping back a little bit
just into the motherhood and apple pie portion
of qualitative research or whatever, I find that
most people don't even understand or don't start
with a rigorous foundation in what they're
going to need to do to get the answers that
they want. So for example, your listeners have
probably heard about the Nielsen number before,
but basically the idea is that once you interview
between 7 and 14 people, you stop learning new
things. Less than 7, you don't learn enough, more
than 14, you start learning anything new. And
so if you interviewed two people, you probably
don't have enough data. If you interviewed 22,
you probably had too much, so they don't even
right size their efforts. So that's a problem.
So they don't start that way. Then they go into
these conversations asking leading questions,
which really are designed to get the customer to
say what they already want to be true, which is
so they haven't done enough research or they've
done too much and then they've blown up all of
the results before they've even heard anything.
If you don't right size your research and you
don't set this up to learn, then you're going
to lose. No amounts of applying LLMs or any
type of kind of structured reasoning is going
to help you. Because you just basically you're
reading back what you want to hear or some
weird summarized version of what you want to
hear. But stepping back from all of that, what
I like to do specifically getting to LLMs is I
think that we live in just the most amazing
time for product managers right now in terms
of being able to analyze vast quantities of
information and see the common threads. And so
let me give you few examples of that. One might
be you can do a bunch of customer interviews,
you can put a bunch of customer interviews
into ChatGPT and you can say, "Hey, ChatGPT,
this is my strategy. Tell me where my strategy
does not fit what these customers talked about."
It's all about the not, not where it does,
where it does not. People spend far too much
time looking for what they're hoping to see,
not for what they're not looking to see. So
you can literally ask ChatGPT to help you find
where the customer is probing at the edges of
what you're trying to do, where it's wrong, where
what you're saying is not what they believe. And
you can ask it questions like that. You can ask
it what your customers are saying would better
fit what your competitors are saying. So you
can basically say, you can copy and paste one
of your competitor's positioning documents into
ChatGPT and say, "Is this a better fit for what
they have said than my thing?" Which is you can
summarize your own strategy, you can take your
competitors but public documents and you can ask
it to summarize what their strategy probably is.
And it's actually supposedly good at that because
mostly your public documents are actually a
summary or at least they're derivative of what
your strategy is. So it will give you crazy
insights into what other people's, literally
their product strategy at times creepy like,
"Oh, they will probably do this, they
will probably do that. It's more likely
they would do this than they would do that." And
so normally that type of insight was hard one,
it took a lot of sweat work. You basically get
to read a lot of stuff. You kind of had to use
your brain as this big summarization machine
and eventually you knew what you felt about
all the things you had read, but you couldn't
summarize why. LLMs let you get to that really,
really, really quickly in a very structured
way, but only if you push at the edges,
provoke the answers you don't want to hear,
provoke the problems, try and prove to yourself
that you are wrong, I think is the easiest way
to start trying to use some of these tools.
I love that. And it sounds like in your experience
you're just using straight-up OpenAI, ChatGPT,
Claude, not any specific tool for user
research for this specific use case.
No, mostly I find that the straight-up LLMs
themselves are good enough and we do have some
internal tooling that we built around, I don't
know if you've ever had Sachin Rekhi on the show,
you may have. He was a product leader
pretty well known in the gross community,
and he was a leader at LinkedIn for a long time
and he used to call this concept a Feedback River,
and he basically said that really smart
product managers are constantly swimming
at a Feedback River. They set out to
surround themselves by Feedback River
and I really deeply believe in that.
It's like, "Okay, how can I surround
myself with user interview data, with
direct customer feedback, with NPS data,
with competitor information?" Like I'm always
trying to wash myself over with information. And
where I'm going with this is that LLMs and tooling
based on it can be exceptionally good for this.
So for example, at Confluent we get a ton of
inbound customer requests, as you can imagine
coming from the field or directly from customers.
We use LLMs to take in those asks to summarize
what they're about, to find other asks that are
like that one, really in a compelling way, a real
way, like a semantic way, not other words, exactly
the same, are these the same concept? So that we
can look across all of the inbound demand on us
and say, "Well, the most popular idea is this
one and is getting more popular. The least popular
idea is this one. It is getting less popular." In
a really deep rich way, even across hundreds
or thousands of pieces of inbound feedback.
I think it's a really great time to be a product
manager if you can put these types of tools to
work, but they don't do the job for you, they
just help you do these things that are intricate
in that job of finding the gaps, finding the
opportunities, finding the common threads
without necessarily having to do all of it just
inside your wear-wear, just inside your brain.
I'm going to stay in this AI river that we're
in right now and ask a couple more AI-related
questions. And this may be what you just said,
but I'm curious if there's more here. You kind
of have this hot take that the way AI will most
impact product management is data management and
data versus models you're building or anything
else. Can you talk about what you've seen there?
Yeah, I mean, I think there's two implications
for people as they're building products based on
AI and as they're thinking about AI in their
workflow. So let's start with the first one,
because that's how product managers do product
management things. You just asked this question
of should it be specific tools built to make AI
easier for product managers to use? Or is it in
fact more general models being put to work?
At the end of the day, these models are very,
very, very smart, but they're also insanely dumb
and everyone knows that, insanely dumb. In other
words, they really only know what they were
trained on or what you bring to them right at
that moment. In that millisecond, and then they
will forget it immediately. And it's very easy
to convince yourself that isn't true, but it is
actually what really matters. And let me add one
extra piece that makes that really important.
At the end of the day, information has a decay
rate. So think about customer feedback, it
has a decay rate or what your competitors are
doing has a decay rate. So any new piece of data
decays in its value to your decision-making very,
very quickly, very, very quickly. You can
plot your own decay chart if you want to,
but the answer is very, very quickly. And so when
you think about the job which is synthesizing all
of this very complicated information to make
good decisions, what does that mean? Well,
you've got this synthesis machine, which is this
LLM thing that's going to help you do synthesis,
but if it hasn't got all that data to do
synthesis on top of, it's got nothing. And
so that means that LLMs can only be as good as the
data they are given and how recent that data is.
They're ultimately like information shredders.
They are limitless information eaters. You can
never have enough information to give to an LLM to
truly gain its value. The more things you give it,
the better it gets. Broadly speaking, that's
just not perfect, but that's close enough. And
so what that means is as an internal product
leader or putting LLMs to work, you need to
figure out how to bring as much information about
customers or their asks or your competitors,
all of it. How much can you find all of it and
bring it together and give it to the LLM either
in your tooling or even in just copying and
pasting or whatever your flow is going to be,
that's one thing. But then if you
take it beyond that and you go,
"Okay, well now I'm a product leader and I'm
building an app and I want to put AI in my app,
what will make my AI experience really great?"
It's definitely not going to be the models because
these models are mostly going to be somewhat
replaceable. And you could say, "Okay, well,
is it going to be the prompts?" Maybe, but
certainly good prompts are better than others,
and that's kind of an ongoing investment you'd
probably want to make to ask better questions to
get the LLM to deliver better answers. But it's
obvious that the real answer is the context,
all the context you're going to give it, all the
data you're going to copy and paste. And so if you
think about, let's say I'm building a, I have no
relationship to this, but let's say I was trying
to build a human capital like a HCM bot, like an
AI bot. Let's say I was working at Workday and I
was trying to bring an AI bot. It's pretty obvious
that the smarts of the bot would really be related
to all of the employee information, but not just
that, it would be the benefit's information,
it would be the legal situation in the country
where that person is currently working.
It would be the company's policies and procedures
that apply to it. So you get what I mean, by about
these kind of the jumps of logic and the jumps of
data and the way data is all linked together. If
you want to have a smart AI experience, you'll
convince yourself that all I really need to do
is get a model and wire it in and I'll build a
little pipeline that will suck some data in and it
will whack it into the LLM. And if you think that
way, you're going to be very sad, very, very sad
for a very long time because you are constantly
going to be wrestling with how do I get data to
this thing? How do I get good data to this thing?
How do we get timely data to this thing? How do I
get well-structured data to this thing?
And so it's a data management problem.
It's getting access to good data, getting
access to high quality data, getting access
to timely data and getting it to the LLM to
get the LLM to make a smart decision. That's
where 90% of the calories go. Maybe it's a bit
like Einstein's thing, "It's 10% inspiration,
90% perspiration." Nobody wants to hear it.
Everybody wants to just think about what these
really cool models and how smart they are, and
the next one will be even smarter. But really
it's just the hard work of getting really good
data to the LLMs to get them to do good things.
It sounds really obvious as you make this case.
It makes me think about at the Lenny and Friends
Summit, Mikey Krieger talked about how he had
the two types of PM groups within Anthropic.
One was focusing on user experience product and
the other was working on the model research side,
and they realized that all of the success
came from the model research work,
like making the model and the data they provided
the model was where all the value came from,
not just optimizing the user experience
and they're just putting more and more
of their product team on just that versus
tweaking UX and buttons and things like that.
Yeah, exactly right.
Something sort of related, I'm just going
to ask one more AI question. I don't want
every talk to end up being just all AI, but
something that's kind of been a meme recently,
and I know you have a perspective on this,
is that AI makes it really easy to build
products. So in the future, if you can easily
clone, say, a B2B SaaS app like Salesforce
or Atlassian or whatever your favorite B2B
SaaS app, what happens to these businesses
long-term? Do they just become, are they all in
trouble? Are there going to be 100 Salesforce
competitors? What's your sense and
prediction on what might happen there?
Yeah, I think it's really weird. I think people
really underestimate where the value is created
in these applications and they just kind of get
it completely wrong, and I'm not sure why that
is. So if you think you bet. So I spent a long
time at Atlassian, so I worked a lot on Jira,
which many people know, and I spent a long time
at Salesforce, so I spent a lot of time in the
CRM ecosystem, the marketing ecosystem and all the
rest of it. If you want it to be not charitable,
you'd step back and you'd look at all those
applications and you'd say, "They're all just
forms on databases." You'd say, "The Jira is a
form on a database, Workday is form on a database,
so Salesforce." They're all forms on databases,
all vertical SaaS or business SaaS is ultimately
forms on databases. And you're be like,
"Well, how hard can that be to replicate?"
And the answer is unbelievably hard, unbelievably
hard. And people just think, "You totally get
it wrong." Because it's not actually just
about the data model. So if you think about,
if it formed some databases, it's these beautiful
user experiences that sit on top of data models.
So whatever the object is, it might be a customer
object or a campaign object or an employee object,
you could say that, "Well, there's some elements
of lock-in in the object, the object itself,
like the fields of the object." I'm like, "Pretty
boring. That's not very interesting." But sure,
maybe. Certainly there's some value in being
the system of record like the default that
everybody uses. There's definitely some
value in the UX. Like, "Well, I want to
be the best HR-facing applications for working
employee data." Yeah, there's some value there,
but the real thing just staring at everybody in
the face is it's all about the business rules.
That is what drives the lock-in because why
do you buy Workday? You don't buy Workday
for its out-of-the-box configuration. You buy
Workday because you want to configure it to
be Lenny Inc's HR processes. It becomes Lenny
Inc's Workday. It's not Shaun Inc's Workday,
it's Lenny Inc's Workday. And actually the longer
you have the software, the more it becomes that,
the more it becomes less and less like Workday
and more and more like your specific company.
Which makes sense because it was built to be
configured to meet the needs of any specific
company, and every company is their own
precious snowflake. And as that happens,
those configuration pieces, the bit that makes the
application native and a fit for your organization
makes it a fit for nobody else's organization
and also makes it a black box to the point that
you don't even understand how it works anymore.
If you went to, for example, Salesforce and you
said, "Hey, could you define all of the processes
by which software was sold inside Salesforce?"
They couldn't tell you that without reading
the code of their Salesforce instance. That's
not a proprietary secret. That's obviously true
because over time, that's literally how sales
happened. There is no other way to do a sale
other than through their internal tooling. And
so what that means is that it's not the UI that
matters and it's not the data model that matters,
although those are both very useful. It's
the years and years and years of evolution
of the underlying workflows of the product to
support the customers, but also the customers
evolving those workflows to make them work
the way they do. And so how does that impact
AI companies? You could say, "It's easier than
ever to build forms on a database application."
And so I'm like, "Yeah, okay, that presumably
drives the incremental value of every new one of
those to zero, right?" So probably leads to more
power to the existing winning systems of record
because there'll just be a gazillion competitors
who would just more form some databases. So like,
"How would you ever choose between them?
You may as well just go with the winner.
Nobody ever gets fired for buying Salesforce or
whatever. You may as well start from the kind
of the premier vendor." That's one element.
You could go the other way and you could say,
"I've heard a few people mount this argument,"
which I think is really interesting that at
the end of the day, agents are going to take
away most of the use of that user interface.
So let's say for example, your Salesforce
with Service Cloud, I've heard people say,
"Well, a lot of those service agents might end
up being replaced with agentic workflows. That
will mean that there is no person operating
the UI. If the UI doesn't even exist anymore,
then why do you even need Salesforce? We may as
well just have raw database tables on who even
needs forms of databases, you can literally just
have databases." But that also doesn't make any
sense either because the agents have to operate
against the rules of the system and the rules are
defined by the business processes. So think about
Salesforce without a head. Imagine Salesforce had
no UI, it would still have those business rules
that I was talking about. And those business rules
are what define what the agent should do. They're
almost telling the agent what it should do and
how the world can operate, what is possible,
what is allowed. And so from my perspective,
this idea that this just completely
destroys the differentiation of these
kind of business process SaaS applications
just seems like a fantasy, a crazy fantasy.
The only way I could really believe it is if you
said, "Well, you could have a new startup that
introspected all of the rules that are configured
into a Salesforce to try and reverse engineer what
your actual business processes are and then kind
of operate on top of that." But the best place
people to do that would be Salesforce themselves
or Atlassian in Atlassian's case or Workday in
Workday's case. I just can't see a world in which
this... I think one of two things could happen.
All this moving to AI makes those applications
even better, even more unassailable, they
basically get stronger. It makes us stronger or it
could enable some new level of applications that
come from a more platform based thing, so less
a domain specific thing like you ACM or ERP or
engineering or less of the domain specific stuff.
It could enable a more platform like play where
you have more business objects and business
objects have rules. And you could imagine a
world in which there's kind of a whole evolution
of new more platform like SaaS applications that
do more than one business function worth of the
business rules and the way things move around in
the enterprise, but that doesn't exist today.
So you could say that that could exist and it
could say it could be way better than we've ever
thought of because of AI. Or you could say that
the rich are going to get richer. The most likely
outcome is that the currently dominant companies
are going to get more dominant, but I don't think
this idea that it would just cause a spring up of
a whole bunch of new apps that will more easily
challenge the incumbents makes any particularly,
it's not straightforward to me
how that would happen basically.
Wow, that was extremely fascinating and there's so
much there. I can go in so many directions. One is
I thought you would actually go in this direction,
which is distribution advantages become even more
important if it's easy to... Like today, I could
sit there and hire team clone. Salesforce might
take a while, but I could copy it, but by the
time I'm done, they've evolved, they're moving,
they're adding features, they're ahead, right?
You're skating to where the puck was. And so
if that's the case, one of the advantages,
one of the ways to get anywhere is to have
some kind of distribution advantage. It's one
thing to have Salesforce as a product clone,
another to get anyone to know about it, to adopt
it, to sell it, procurement, all that stuff. Do
you have a sense of distribution advantages
being even more valuable in that world?
Yeah, I mean, it certainly makes sense.
Ultimately, at the end of the day,
distribution is always an advantage because the
hardest problem is to even be in the consideration
set for any given problem. The world is full of
problems. It's just when people have that problem,
they firstly don't think they're going to solve
it at all. And when they do think of solving it,
they don't think of you. So distribution is
always an incredible advantage. But again,
in the world of AI, it seems like distribution
is more likely to get hard than easy. So if you
think about, for example, diminishing returns on
cold email because cold email is getting easier
and easier to send even worse spam, it sounds
better, but it's effectively causing everybody
to become desensitized to everything. I don't
know if you've noticed, half the LinkedIn charts
now are all basically clearly LLM generated spam.
I mean, to some degree it's actually worsening the
signal-to-noise ratio. And so I think that a lot
of the breakthrough distribution mechanisms that
startups often use seem to be getting more crowded
just in general and more expensive. That doesn't
bode well for, "I'm the not as good Salesforce,"
"I'm the not as good Salesforce, but I'm cheaper."
It has to be something different. There has
to be some angle upon which you are materially
better. And what I saw happening and what I've
been seeing happening, and I think it's been
really interesting is a lot of modern next-gen
applications bringing data as a first-class
citizen into the workflow. And I think that
that's pretty compelling. So if you look at the
next-generation of applicant management products
that deal with inbound job applicants, a lot of
them now like the latest core ones, they include
your time to fill data, they include outcome data
of who's got the best hiring outcomes, who over
what period of time has the worst attrition,
literally all the way back to the interviewers and
where the interviews were in the interview cycle.
So basically embeds data into the whole life
cycle. So I think that there are these ways in
which startups can bring these experience benefits
by just bringing a different approach to the world
that does enable them to capitalize on traditional
disruptive innovation. At the end of the day,
this is just disruptive innovation. It means that
most companies have overshot the utility like the
average utility, so you can win by meeting
the average utility and being different,
meet the bar and be different. Meet the
bar and be different is the way to cut
through. So that makes sense if that's a half
decent playbook. But even for those companies,
now they're going to have all these AI
competitors who are using AI to engineer
faster, to build a competitor just like them as
quickly as possible and start jamming it into the
channel. And it's going to be interesting to
see how this whole thing evolves. It kind of
got race to the bottom characteristics around
it. You're probably right, the distribution
is still the hardest part in software,
particularly when you're getting started.
So if you have some kind of clever and fair
advantage, it feels like that becomes even
more powerful. Say have a platform of
an audience or something like that. You
mentioned this ATS product they really
like. Is there one you want to give some
love to that you think is really cool that
you like or you want to keep it anonymous?
Yeah, it's Ashby. It's the one all the cool kids
are talking about now. And it's funny because
people literally talk about it in comparison to
all, even the last generation of modern SaaS ATSs
or whatever, and they talk about it in glowing
ways because of the way they put data inside
the actual workflow. So the actions and its
outcomes are directly tieable to each other
in the application you're doing the work in. I
think that's a pretty compelling user experience.
So just to maybe close this thread
before I move in a different direction,
this point you're making about how valuable
data is and how that's at the core of being
successful and differentiating in the future,
especially with AI tooling and products,
any advice you'd give to someone that wants
to do that? Is it just make sure you have a,
is it half proprietary data? Is it like
make it a first-class citizen? What's
the advice you'd give to founders who are
trying to do this, which you're suggesting?
Yeah, I, think at the end of the day, it's
kind of all of those things, isn't it? If you
have first-party data but you can't bring it
to bear, then it's not very much use. If you
have third-party data and you bring it to bear
in interesting ways, the problem with data is
we're all surrounded by data all the time. So
the data's everywhere. What really matters is
the right data at the right time in the right
place because we're all humans. And so to me,
there are obviously data advantages and there
are even data network effects if you can end
up in a situation where you have very valuable
first-party data. But in any case, it's still
about being able to bring the right data at the
right place, at the right time for those users,
for them to be able to get advantage from it.
A little kind of segue I guess on that one is I
know I spent a lot of my career, weirdly, actually
I've been a product person for a long time,
but weirdly I've ended up inheriting data
teams. So I've actually run data teams at a
lot of different companies, which is weird because
product managers don't normally own data teams. I
think I have just a really massive affinity
for data. I used to call myself data-driven,
it was kind of my jam. And in hindsight, I
look back and I think data is the opposite.
Data is more like a compass than a GPS. If you
look at data as a way of giving you the answer,
you're always wrong. You're always wrong or
you're slow. Wrong or slow or sometimes both,
because mostly data doesn't give you the answer.
It just tells you if what you just said is
ridiculous or there's potentially something there.
So it's more like about disproving whatever you
think and you end up being slow because if you
try and use data for everything, your brain is
ultimately a data sifter or whatever. So the
reason your intuition tells you something is
because you've seen a ton of data that tells you
that this is the most likely answer. And so being
data-driven, being data obsessed is it's something
you can easily overdo very, very easily overdo. So
it's about right-sizing data, having the right
data at your fingertips, having the right kind
of view on data rather than trying to expect data
to give you the answer or trying to use data as
a weapon or trying to use data as a way to force
people to believe you or to go in your direction.
But data is kind of at the center of everything
and about how to influence and be successful in
products you're building and arguments you're
mounting internally and everything else.
I love that you went there. I definitely wanted to
spend time on here. It's interesting you say that,
there used to be data-driven, [inaudible 00:38:44]
data-driven. You created the Reforge course,
data for product managers and also retention,
engagement course and Reforge. And by the way,
we'll link to these. You're still
helping with these courses. By the way,
they're still running. They're
awesome. People love them.
Yeah.
Great. So we'll point people to those. I
love that you're also saying you're like,
I think the way you described it to me before,
this is your reform data-driven PM. A lot of
people say this, they're like, "Don't just do
what data tells you to do. Use your intuition,
use it as a guide." It's hard on the ground to
operationalize that advice. Say to your PMs and
your teams when they have data telling them, "Hey,
this experiment is a huge success, or there's a
huge onboarding conversion opportunity here."
I guess just like what's your tactical advice
to folks that have data telling them one thing and
maybe something else telling them something else?
I think the first thing I always encourage people
to do is to look at a piece of data. If you're
looking at a piece of data and the result tells
you something that your intuition tells you is
insanely wrong, like they probably not right.
First, believe your intuition and go and prove
yourself right. Don't just take it at first glance
because most of the time it's like Occam's razor.
The most likely explanation for something that is
insanely not intuitive is that it's just wrong,
that there's a problem somewhere. Now,
occasionally, sometimes you actually will
be right. Now those will be paid dirt moments.
Those are the moments that make it all worth
it. There are times when you do find the negative
goal, you're like, you're staring at it and like,
"This is it. This was the problem. This was
the thing we were looking for this whole time."
But you have to be very diligent about following
it through, really understanding what you're
looking at. Is this data representative?
Is this data a good sample of the audience
we care about? Is it already subject to some
sort of selection bias? Oftentimes when I see
analysis from different product leaders or even
data teams, you can drive a truck through it,
literally drive a truck through it. And if you
present data with authority and that data is
ridiculous or the analysis is just full of holes,
you don't just not get benefit for that. You
lose a whole bunch of brownie points. It would be
better not to show up with an analysis that isn't
clear than it would be to show up with an analysis
that's dumb. And I see people self emulate on this
actually relatively regularly because they just
bring a knife to a gunfight or whatever, they did
bring in an analysis that is just not, it doesn't
hold water and they present it and then get shot
down live, which is nobody's idea of a good time.
So if I give you a little bit of additional
tactical things about that, it'd be okay if I'm
looking at a piece of data, what was upstream
of this piece of data and does that look normal?
So this thing happened or whatever, which you're
very, very excited about, what happened before
that? And does that match what you think should
have been right? So what happened before this
momentous situation? And then, okay, for that
thing that you're looking at, what happened after?
If you have an idea of what happened before and
after, that gives you some idea of whether or not
this thing, is it all worth interesting to talk
about? And then go one click above this data that
you're looking at. So it's like, these things,
let's say I'm looking at onboarding success.
Let's say I'm looking at onboarding success
to second week retention or something like that.
I'm like, "I have found this thing that totally
crushes it. This intervention crushes it."
If you go upstream and you find out that this
intervention only applies to 2% of the inbound
onboarding stream, it's meaningless. It's most
likely just a random aberration. But even if it
was not a random aberration, it's not a useful
tool. And so you've got to go up and then
you might go downstream and you might find,
yep, they last for two in the second week, but in
the third week they all churn. They're basically
pointless. Why are we even talking about this?
Or then you might step all the way back and go,
"Okay, yes, those people do get retained for
longer, but their average ASP is smaller."
Because what we really care about, we do care
about engagement and we care about more customers,
but we want to keep the customers at a
high ASP to reach a certain revenue goal.
The final goal is happy customers paying us money.
So that's what I mean about going a click up. If
you go a click to the left, a click to the right,
so before and after and then a click up and you
still see the thing that tells you the story that
you want to tell, then now you've got something
that's very compelling because people want to
hear about that. They want to hear, "Well, what
did happen before? What did happen after?
And why is that outcome happening?" But
you have to really do your homework and really be
rigorous about it to avoid fighting fool's gold.
I love that advice. ASP, what
does that stand for by the way?
Oh, average sale press, [inaudible
00:43:22] MRR or some other revenue metric.
Got it. This point you made about how a lot
of times experiments show positive and then
they end up not being anything, I had the
head of growth from Shopify on the podcast,
and they do this really cool thing where they keep
holdouts for years of cohorts and then it auto
emails them I think a year or two later, "Hey,
check this and see if these cohorts, this is still
higher or not." And 40% of the time, it turns out
neutral after a positive experiment long term.
Interesting. It's really funny because the last
time we did something similar, we had a global
holdout group actually that was held out of all
experiments. The experiment platform couldn't
target that group at all. So 10% of all people
never saw anything ever. So that's be really,
really helpful because you can always compare
them against whatever the experience was for
any of the same vintage of cohort. I agree with
you. But the other thing is I don't really love
some of that thinking process just in general.
It's like, "Hey, let's say an experiment does
show a temporary benefit. If an experiment shows
a temporary benefit, but that benefit does not
persist forever, does that mean the temporary
benefit was never worth it? Or does that just mean
the temporary benefit was an opportunity to reach
another level you just didn't capitalize on?" I
don't think there's a perfect answer, is what
I'm trying to say. I don't think that the fact
that a benefit doesn't last forever means that
you failed. But I agree with you that not trying
to understand, well, what has the net benefit
been, what has the net lift been is also really
important too. That's why growth is so hard.
Growth is part of product is so especially hard.
Marketers, I know that you love TLDRs, so
let me get right to the point. Wix Studio
gives you everything you need to cater to any
client at any scale, all in one place. Here's
how your workflow could look. Scale content with
dynamic pages and reusable assets effortlessly,
fast-track projects with built-in marketing
integrations like Meta, CPI, Zapier,
Google Ads and more, A/B test landing pages in
days, not weeks with intuitive design tools,
connected tracking and analytics tools like
Google Analytics and Semrush can capture key
business events without the hassle of manual
setup, manage all your client's social media
and communications from a unified dashboard,
then create, schedule and post content across
all their channels. If you're working on content
rich sites, Wix Studio with no code CMS lets you
build and manage without touching the
design. And when you're ready for more,
Wix Studio grows with you, add your own code,
create custom integrations with Wix made APIs
or leverage robust native business solutions.
Drive real client growth with Wix Studio. Go
to wixstudio.com. So you built the first B2B
growth team when you were Atlassian, correct?
Yes. Yeah, it makes me feel like an old
person, but yes, it was a very long time ago.
Slash maybe it's a new thing.
Yeah.
It's either a long time ago or
it's just recently figured out
this is a thing that you could
do in a B2B is focus on growth.
Yeah, it is. So that was around about 2012,
and at that time growth hacking was a thing.
People don't really use that term anymore,
but in B2C it was a very big deal because
people could see Facebook doing their 10
friends in seven days and they could see this
kind of thing that was working for people.
And they're like, "Man, that's amazing." And
at Atlassian we set out to go, "Okay, well,
do those techniques work in B2B?" And also,
it's kind of obvious now that a lot of them do and
that it's worth doing. But at the time it wasn't
that obvious because for a lot of B2B companies,
I mean, you summarized it earlier, Lenny,
distribution covers all faults. Almost all ills
can be filled in by really great distribution.
If you have a really good marketing, a really
good ground game, and you're kind of jamming
your product into the channel, you're jamming
your product in front of people and you're
papering over the ugly parts with customer success
people and services and consulting and whatever,
that people will buy almost any software or
you can certainly be successful with a lot of
different software. But back in 2012, it wasn't
clear of like, okay, which instead you went at
this differently and you've heard them in software
that sell itself, is the juice worth the squeeze?
And now I would say that it's pretty clear that
the juice is worth the squeeze to the point that
lots of think about this all the time, but it
was a bit of an interesting time at that time.
And that was essentially the beginnings of
product-led growth. Is that a
simple way to think about it?
Basically it's now called PLG, but yeah, at that
time we didn't even know what to call it exactly.
Just growth. So based on that experience, a
lot of B2B companies now have growth teams
through investing in growth, what makes
a great growth team in B2B? Any pitfalls
you often find folks fall into that
you think they should try to avoid?
Ultimately, a lot of these types of endeavors
are a matter of balance. So what I mean by
that is growth teams tend to go through a set
of phases. Their first phase is proving their
value at all. So call that the gold rush phase.
This thing's probably not worth even doing. Why
are we doing this, merry band of people out
there trying to prove that there's some growth
effect somewhere? So that's the proof of phase.
And so the advantage of that phase is life's
good because there's usually a lot of growths to
be found because nobody's gone looking before,
so life's good. But it's pretty random because
you're just literally searching across a random
search phase going, "Have we tried X? Have we
tried Y? Have we tried Z?" Then once you get
that model going, then it starts to be, "Okay,
how do we scale this thing? Is this just a flash
in the pan? Do we just find a little bit of low
hanging fruit and there's nothing else here,
there? Is this just a project we should
have done rather than an ongoing thing?"
So you have to make it a system. You
have to prove that it can be repeated,
and then you have to scale it. It has to become
a thing. It has to become part of your DNA. You
have to be taking a PLG lens to everything you do,
all the way from paid acquisition to activation,
retention, engagement, cross product expansion,
upsells, I mean, you name it, all the different
ways you can grow a product by revenue or
engagement. There's many different ways to go
about that. And so you end up having to scale out
and be able to do all of those different things.
And then you have to figure out how you fit in
with the rest of the organization because there's
other people who build products all day every day.
There's other people who sell that product all
day, all day. There's other people
who market that product all day,
all day. And so growth organizations are in this
interesting space, they're in between everybody
else. They're in everybody else's sandpit in a
little bit, in a little way, and they're kind
of at the edge of everybody's full-time job
and they are very valuable, but they can be
complicated because of all those relationships,
and because of the way they sit amongst all
of the other parts of the organization. So many
organizations fail because they don't really find
much the wins or when they do find wins, it just
seems totally random. Or they do find a lot of
wins, but they all can't understand them because
they seem like they're just a random walk through
a bunch of potential opportunities. There's
many different ways to fail to fit as you go
through your growth phase from trying the ideas
to success, to scaling, to operationalizing.
One of the biggest memes along these lines is
a lot of companies claim there's like just PLG
rarely ever works. You always, either you try it
and it just doesn't work or it eventually just
peters out, I guess. Any thoughts on just what
are signs that your product has a chance to work,
peel product-led growth versus just go straight to
sales immediately and don't even worry about this?
First let's examine the counterfactual, right?
So let's start with the opposite of your question
and say, "Hey, how would the world be sadder
if we all just gave up on PLG?" We just said,
"Hey, there's no point in doing it in B2B SaaS."
The problem is that there is not a natural force
that pulls companies towards thinking about the
end user's enjoyment and success early in their
journey. There is no natural force, there's no
natural kind of a link force. Why is that? I mean,
101, the buyer is the most important person. The
economic bar is the most economic person. Their
needs are the number one thing. They're usually
the person driving the RFP. They're usually the
person dealing with the sales organization. So the
needs of the person who you hear are usually all
feature-driven and they're not from the end users.
And so you're kind of sowing a seed of your own
demise if you don't think about that end user. But
it's one thing to say that you should think about
the end user, it's a whole other thing to have
a system by which you do that because people pay
lip service to all sorts of things. But I'm sure
you've heard this one before, but in economics,
people only do what their incentives told them
to do. Broadly speaking, that is what they do,
that is what happens. You get what you set out to
measure. You get what you give people incentives
to do. If there is nobody in the organization
whose true incentive is to measure their end
user success, their enjoyment, their happiness,
their retention, their engagement early on,
it will not happen. Or at best it will be a hobby.
And so then by extension, if I start from there,
then I say, "Okay, let's say it doesn't
exist, PLG doesn't exist and therefore
it's a hobby and therefore there will be a
bunch of hobby people who care about this."
Then you ask yourself, "Okay, will that mean
that there will be many products for which those
experiences really suck? And does that mean that
that will be an opportunity for competitors of
those products to be better at that? And is that
a differentiated competitive advantage?" Yeah,
I'd say it is. I'd say it is. And so
I just work my way backwards and I go,
"Okay, you can say that your PLG investment
might be too high." You could be like, "Well,
if I invest more, I won't get any more juice.
I can't spend my life just experimenting in
the onboarding. That's not the only thing that
matters." And that's very, very true, but it's
very hard to argue it should be turned to zero.
And so to me, therefore it's about the balance.
It's about, "Okay, how does PLG fit with the other
different ways that I grow in my business?" At
Confluent, for example, we have a PLG function.
We do grow with self-serve signups. People who
sign up, literally their credit card, lots of
them sign up and they're very successful, never
speak to us. We also have an enterprise sales
team that sells directly to very big companies,
some of the biggest banks in the world, the
people you would definitely know of. I don't
think it has to be one or the other. I think
that it's about a balance. It's about getting
the motions to work and for really sophisticated
companies, the people who really nail this,
it's about making both motions work together.
If you can get a PLG motion work to feed your
sales team and a sales team motion work to feed
your PLG funnel when the sales leads aren't ready
yet and you can get those motions into playing
with each other, you can make a lot of money.
It can be an extremely successful way to
go to build a very resilient business.
Why? Because you get a lot of customers and you
get a lot of revenue. You can't be that successful
as a company if you have a lot of revenue, but a
small number of customers because you're captive,
everyone knows that. You can't be that successful
as a company if you have a lot of customers,
but not enough revenue because you shouldn't
have enough money to sustain operations. So
the magic is in having both, a very large number
of customers and a very large amount of revenue,
it's very hard to knock over a company like
that. If I look back on my time at Atlassian,
and I think that they shared their most recent
numbers, I can't remember what it was, but it
was in the public data or whatever, something
80,000 or 100,000 customers, something like that.
That's a lot of customers. That's a lot of
customers. Let's say you're going up against
Jira and you're like, "Yeah, man, I'm going
to pick off 1,000 customers from Atlassian."
That's a lot, right? That's a lot. Obviously
1,000 customers is a lot. You only have 19,
sorry, it's going to be 89,000 to go or 79,000
to go, or however many it is to go. I can't
remember their exact number of customers, but
it's very hard to assail a company which has
a very large number of customers and a very
large amount of revenue. And so that's why I
think that PLG as a mechanism is incredibly
important for almost any type of company,
if you can make the motion work. Obviously there
are companies for whom the motion just isn't
relevant, but for those where it does matter,
it seems like the juice is worth the squeeze.
That was an awesome answer. I looked up
last year and they have 300,000 customers.
Oh man, I'm so far off. When I left
it must have been 80,000 customers.
They've done good work since then. Also,
you're talking about incentives and how
the power of incentives. Charlie Munger
has this great quote I looked up just
to make sure I get it right. "Show me the
incentive and I'll show you the outcome."
Yeah, exactly right. I've seen cases where a sales
team was people trying to get a sales team to do a
PLG motion, and you can beat them over the head as
much as you like, you can get into a meeting and
tell them that you really, really want them to do
this, but at the end of the day, they're not going
to do it. And the same is true for every other
kind of function. It's just the nature of things.
I have some newsletter posts around the stuff of
folks want to dig deeper. Also, Elena Verna had an
awesome podcast episode talking about product-led
sales and kind of the combination of these two
things that we'll point to.. Just a whole other
topic we can go deep, deep on, but we're not
going to do that in this episode. Maybe just one
more question. So you mentioned all the companies
you worked at, so you've been at Salesforce,
chief product officer, MuleSoft, specifically
within Salesforce, Metromile,
Atlassian, Confluent now,
a lot of really interesting and different
roles. How do you choose where to go work
and how do you choose which opportunities
to take? I imagine you have many options.
I have to think of my career. So in
hindsight, looking at it this way,
Lenny, so I don't know if forward-looking
was obvious to me this way. But looking back,
my career has been a little bit like a bingo card.
I've always been looking to fill in boxes I didn't
have filled because I felt like that would make
me a better professional. It's like if I didn't
know anything about that specific type of sales
model or that type of marketing or that type of
product management or that type of product or that
layer in the stack or that kind of thing is like,
well, if I learn about that thing, I will become
more versatile. So actually two things, it's fun,
it's fun to learn something new. It's fun to
prove to yourself that you can do those new things
and then it makes you more versatile because it
means that any given problem you go up against,
you've seen something that pattern matches to it.
It kind of feels like you end up bringing a gun to
a knife fight in a way because every problem you
look at, you're like, "Oh, I have seen this from
the other side. I've seen this from some other
angle, and so I know that this is likely to work
and this is unlikely to work." And so when I
joined early on in my career, I was working
for a big enterprise software company, sorry,
small enterprise software company that sold to
the Fortune 100. When I joined Atlassian, and
like I shared with you, we had no sales force
at all actually at all. Literally nobody to sell
the software. It sold itself or it didn't get sold
at all. And we grew to have 80,000 customers. It
was just pure product. They had growth and just
an incredible company. Then it was at Metromile,
which was a consumer company that got acquired,
made an insurance product for end consumers.
So they got nothing to do with technology
products, like literally a complicated Internet
of things device you installed in your car,
but ultimately it's an insurance product that
you'd sell to grandmothers in Florida as much as
you would ever millennials. And then at MuleSoft
to totally back end software that's used by IT
organizations and a consulate infrastructure
that's used by developers everywhere to build
really interesting data-driven applications, data
powered applications to do all sorts of things
in real-time. And you look at across all that and
you go, "It's all a bit random." But I didn't see
it that way because I learned, I actually was in
sales for a bit, so I ran a pre-sales engineering
group, went around the world selling software.
So when I joined Atlassian, I wanted to kind of
understand what it was to sell software at massive
scale with no sales team, can it even be done?
And so I learned a lot in my time at Atlassian.
When I went to Metromile, I'm like, "Well,
I've never built a consumer product before."
I can say that I've actually built a product
that's touched many millions of people because
Jira has, so I felt pretty good about that,
but I'd never built one that I could say, "Yep,
a consumer, your average consumer can use this
thing. It's so simple. Even my grandma can
use it." I'd never built a product like
that. So I got that experience at Metromile,
which is really fun. I'd never worked inside
an organization as big as Salesforce or an
organization with as good a sales motion. You
talked about distribution earlier. Salesforce
is an absolutely insane distribution machine,
just an incredible company with just an amazing
distribution network and a fantastic marketing
approach that it's like a PhD in marketing.
When you spend your time at Salesforce,
you're like, "This company is just one of
a kind. It's a one of kind, and it's so
outlandishly good at one specific thing." And
so looking back, all of these jobs have been,
when I say bingo card, I've just got an outlandish
education in these areas that are not obvious at
all. And once you've seen them, they're like
superpowers. They're superpowers to be able to
bring that same experience to bear on things.
And so one thing that I really I'm trying to
figure out is why often people don't do that. And
oftentimes people stay in a very specific domain.
They prefer to stay in a domain or they prefer to
stay in a specific kind of type of company or a
role that works in a certain way, like companies
that have the same operating model or they plan
the same way or they try to stay with things that
are pretty similar. But it seems obvious that the
most likely way to really grow is the opposite.
It's to constantly be choosing things that are
either outside that, not totally outside the
lines. Don't jump out of a plane if you've never
parachuted before. Obviously you want them to be
in some way and adjacency, that you want them to
have something in common with what you know, but
you want them to stretch you and change you. I
had a really transformative experience many, many
years ago when I was at Atlassian and a guy called
Tom Kennedy, he was our general counsel, so chief
legal officer basically, and a lifelong lawyer,
very smart guy. I liked him very, very much. But
just a lawyer. Just a lawyer, corporate lawyer,
corporate counsel, I'm sure you know what they're
like. And really great guy. And I remember,
so mostly in our meetings he didn't talk that much
except about legal things. But I remember in one
meeting we were having this vigorous debate about
a product strategy question about what we should
do. Should we go left or should we go right?
And as usual, he's there and he's mostly
just staying silent. And then eventually the
conversation's been going on for 15 minutes and
he is like, "Hey, everybody, a year ago we talked
about X, Y and Z," and he proceeds to lay out our
product strategy at that time, and he's like,
"Just recently we said the following things,
and that was a product strategy, whatever. Now
you are saying this. Isn't it obvious that isn't
this? What you guys are saying is not congruent
with that, and if you really meant what you said
back then we should be doing X." And again, the
room went silent, everybody kind of turned to him,
kind of nodded, and then everyone went,
"Yeah, okay, I guess we probably should
be doing it differently." And so the meeting
stopped when the GCE randomly mentioned that
he deeply understood our product strategy and he
knew enough to be able to contribute in that way.
And so the life-changing part for me about that
was just this realization that if I'm going to
be a really great professional, the type of
professional I want to be is that type of
person. The type of person who can contribute
to the whole company in all sorts of ways,
doesn't spend all of their time in everybody
else's business, but understands the business
and has the mental horsepower and the experience
to be dangerous in all sorts of, and I mean,
that in a compliment way. I don't mean that in a
negative way, but to be dangerous in all sorts of
situations. I think that when you have leaders
like that behind you and with you, then you're
just unstoppable. You're an unstoppable force
in business when you have that motion happening.
Wow, that was an awesome story and an awesome
perspective. It's similar to the advice I always
give PMs of people always wondering, "Should I
go deep on a specific subject? Should I just try
different things?" And I find just variety,
especially earlier in your career is really
powerful, not just to help you discover the thing
you like, but also to your point, just using
insights from all these different parts of the
product and internal tools and trust and safety
and platform and consumer product side and growth
and just core stuff. The more of that you have,
the stronger you get. And I feel like another
benefit of your approach is if you work at just
B2B SaaS companies, if you have too many of that
on your resume, it's very hard to get hired a
consumer company. And so just having it creates a
huge optionality for you if you do, which you did.
Yeah, it's interesting because people used to
talk about people who are T-shaped or whatever,
and I've never really loved the analogy because
it's more like people are scribble shaped. I mean,
there's the really best people you've worked with,
they're more like scribbles than they are T-shaped
because of course you want to be horizontally
capable, so you want to be broad and you do
want to be deep, but you actually want to be deep
in way more than one thing. Now obviously when I
say deep, I don't mean I'm not able to do the
job of our finance function all day every day,
but I'm 100% good enough to go three clicks
below the simple financial analysis. I can go
reasonably deep in our financials because I
want to and because it's partly it matters.
It's important to be able to do that. And
so maybe a different way to think about that
bingo card is I've rarely regretted going
deep in something that isn't quite my job.
I've rarely regretted it. The worst case scenario
is I've learned something new that I will never
use, which I guess at least that made my
brain slightly more agile. I don't know,
there must be some potential benefit of that.
But the very best case scenario is that when I
least suspect it at some point in the future it
will turn out to be the thing that matters. It
will be the tool that I need, but I'm facing
some important problem and I will be like,
"Oh my god, this was worth every cent." And
so if you think about it on an ROI basis,
doing things that aren't in your wheelhouse,
that aren't the things directly in front of you,
the ROI can really be outlandish.
It can be off the charts great,
but I guess it's speculative. Because you
don't know you're going to need it tomorrow.
You don't know if it's going to be something
that's going to be a regular tool you use.
What's interesting is the bingo
card is the analogy. Is there a
bingo moment at the end of
this? Is there retirement?
Oh, you mean you've got everything.
You've got the collectible Pokemon?
Yeah, you collect them all.
Yeah, I was working with somebody at Salesforce
and he'd been there a long time, very,
very, very successful person. Honestly didn't
need to work anymore. And he said something
that I found really useful. He's like, "Well,
now I'm at the point of my life where I want
to work at the intersection of things that I
am good at and things that will be valuable
to the company to do." So basically it
feels like the reward of completing your
Bingo card is actually to just get to spend
more time doing things that are leverage,
that you enjoy and that are high leverage.
And so that seems like a good outcome to me.
I don't think most people are going to work
and hopefully have some sort of great financial
outcome and then go, "Well, that's it. I'm picking
up stumps, I'm retiring." I think for most people,
achieving some sort of financial outcome or some
sort of independence or whatever is really just
another stage. At that point it will be, "Okay,
well now what do I do? What do I do with my life?"
And so that was why I said earlier that at the
end of the day, product management is at times
the worst job in the world and at times easily
the best. And it's both and it can be both. And
so it's hard for me to think about if I think
about the things that are the intersection of
what I'm good at and are valuable to the world,
product management is a pretty fun one to do
and it's different every day. So I think we're
pretty privileged. For those of you who listen,
I mean, obviously your podcast reaches a lot of
product people. I think we're pretty privileged
to be able to operate at that intersection, but
it's not easy because you got to show value. It's
a very complicated job to show value in and
to demonstrate value to the world, and it's
constantly being attacked, like you mentioned,
but it's still amazing when it all goes right.
When a product is very successful in the market,
it's hard to describe the joy you get from that.
Kind of along those lines to close out our
conversation before a very exciting lightning
round, I want to take us to failure corner.
People listen to these podcast episodes and
everyone's always just sharing all these wins,
everything's always going great. The CPO of this,
CPO of that, just moving on up and people
will want to hear times when things didn't
go right. Because those are stories
people don't share as often. Can you
share a story when something didn't go right,
when you maybe had a failure in the course of
your career? And if you learned something
from that experience, what you learned.
I mean, there's a lot of things that didn't
go exactly to plan, Lenny. Very early on in
my career, I was still a developer and
I accidentally deleted one of the core
systems of the company that I was working
at. So that's going to go down in infamy,
but luckily that one's far in
the rear-view mirror. That-
That wasn't Atlassian?
No, that was far pre-Atlassian, but very
bad. Yeah, the one I like to talk about,
I wasn't directly responsible for it, but I feel
responsible for it. I was at a company and we
launched a product. That was one of those products
that in hindsight should have been really obvious
it was going to fail, but for some reason we were
all blinded by the potential. It was a product
that was about, it was basically to measure the
environmental impact of your company and to help
you reduce the environmental impact of your
company by doing, think about it as a power
management, building power management, managing
the power drawer of computers, managing the power
drawer of AC and all of that stuff. That was
the vision basically. It's like a manage your
environmental impact of your business. The idea
was pretty cool at the time, and also it was the
right time for that, and it's still a thing.
It's still an area of active research and
investment or whatever, but it was one of those
things, talk about the wrong company, wrong place,
wrong time, wrong distribution. We had literally
no right to win, no right to play, just absolutely
no business in hindsight being in that business.
And I feel really bad because I, again, good idea,
wrong company. And at the end of the day, we
launched the product. We actually kept the product
in market for two years, and the final straw
was weird. The final straw was actually when a
customer finally wanted to pay for it. It had been
in market for two years, and we found ourselves
with a customer who wanted to pay millions of
dollars for it. They were ready to sign on the
dotted line, and that was actually the moment we
decided to kill the product because we were like,
"If this person signs this piece of paper, we are
stuck with this forever. This one customer will be
bound by contracts for however long or whatever."
So we actually ended up killing it. At the moment
after two years of failure when somebody wanted
to pay his money for it. And I look back on that
and I'm just like, "Man, that was a really
big..." I feel really bad because I'm like,
"It should have been obvious. It was obvious
and we should have been able to call a spade
a spade and I guess speak truth to power." But
instead it kind of got through to the keeper and
turned out to be a real accidental drain on
resources for years and just a big mistake.
So is the lesson there, just be real
with yourself? I like that you have this
forcing function of like, "Okay, this
is getting for real now." Is it like,
"I wish we had an earlier forcing
function to force us to make a decision?"
Yeah. I think if I could do it differently, I
might not have necessarily been able to 100%
change the decision, but I should have tried.
I mean, it was pretty obvious after six months,
this thing was a bit of a zombie product
walking, and the least I could have done is said,
"This thing is dead." We could have called it dead
way earlier, but instead we proceeded for another
year and a half investing in it. And so that's the
bit that makes me feel like real bummer about it.
It reminds me a recent episode with Raaz
who is the CMO at Wiz, and she joined
us the first PM and a few weeks into it with
doing tons of calls with customers she's like,
"I think I need a quick... Because I don't really
understand what we were building. I don't get it."
And everyone's like, "I don't either." And it
just, yeah, the founders just had a vague idea
what they're doing, but they didn't really have
an idea. And that just sparked a, "Okay, wait,
no one actually does. Let's actually get more
concrete." And it helped them pivot. And now,
I don't know if you know about Wiz, but they ended
up being the fastest growing startup in history.
Yes. Isn't that amazing, right? It
doesn't mean it's permanently fatal,
but asking that question and going through that
reckoning turns out that came out stronger.
Scary, but it turns out it's for the best often.
Before we get to very exciting lightning round,
is there anything else that you want to mention
or leave listeners with maybe a last nugget,
something that you think might
be helpful before we wrap?
Maybe a couple of different things that I think
are sometimes well understood, but just repeating
them I guess because they're very valuable to me.
One is that if you let your calendar rule you,
then nothing good will happen. I know people talk
about that a lot, but it's surprisingly common in
product management in particular that people end
up ruled by their calendar. And so it's related to
that whole look at spend 80% of your time thinking
about things going on outside the business. Easy
said, very hard to do, and if you don't do it, no
one's going to do it for you. And so it is really
hard to be successful unless you find a way to
force that to happen. So to repeat that, also,
somebody said this to me, I never looked up the
quote, but apparently Colin Powell said that if
you're making a decision with less than 30% of
the available data, you're making a big mistake.
If you're making a decision only after
you have 70%, either the 70% or 77%,
I can't remember the exact number, when you have
77% of all the available data, you have waited
far too long. And I've always found that very
insightful and it relates a little bit to what
we're talking about about data earlier, but at the
end of the day, we get paid in product management
to make decisions, good decisions, paid to make
good decisions that will deliver business benefit.
And a decision with too little data
is fatal. A decision that takes too
long and collects too much data is also
fatal. So everything, it's about trying
to find the balance of all of these different
things to try and deliver business advantage.
A great way to circle back to all the
things we've been talking about. With that,
we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
Yes. Let's do it.
Let's do it. What are two or three books that
you have recommended most to other people?
Yeah, they oldies but goodies, is probably going
to be The Lean Startup that I still find actually
really good. And the key lessons in there I still
think are very applicable to a lot of people,
particularly the cohort analysis bit, which
for some reason I still don't see people do
anywhere near enough cohort analysis. So there
you go, that's my little tip. And then INSPIRED:
How to build products that people love
by Marty Kagan and the Silicon Valley
product group. That's an oldie but
a goodie. I think it's got a lot of
the key lessons of product management in it,
even though it's been around for a long time.
Those are some classics. Very cool.
Do you have a favorite recent movie
or TV show you really enjoyed?
I'm watching a program. I don't
get to watch very much TV,
mostly at night. I like to watch things that
are extremely light, that just don't at all
inspire any element of stress and that are
very short. So basically short and funny is
basically my thing. And there's a new program
on Netflix, I think it's called Detroiters.
Oh, I've been watching that.
Yeah, it's really funny. I really like that. It's
so ridiculous, but very funny. So I like that.
The main guy, he's so funny. I forget his
name. Tim Sweeney or something like that. Yeah,
he's so good. Good one. I've been watching
that, I'm loving it. It's very quirky. I
think the New York Times quote on
there is "Very weird," the quote.
It's so weird. In the first episode
I'm like, "What is this show?" It's
not even clear what time it set in,
and it's very weird. It's really cool.
Yes. Well, good way to describe it. Next question,
do you have a favorite product you've
recently discovered that you really love?
Yeah, this one, some of your listeners
might be using it, but Glean, it's a
pretty well-known startup now. They recently
raised a ton of money. We've been using
Glean at Confluent for a long time and it's
just amazing. It's just amazing. I can't
describe how good it is. And I don't say this
lightly because I think search, like business
search is probably one of the hardest problems
in computing. Actually getting it right is one
of the hardest problems in computing. Amazing.
It's not often I use a product and I'm like,
"This thing is 10 times better than anything
that's come before it." It's one of those for me.
What's the simplest way to
understand what it does for you?
It searches all of our organization's knowledge.
So the thing you were just saying before,
you're like, "What does AST mean?" If I had
that in a meeting, I just open my new tab,
it'll automatically take over my new tab or
just like, "What does AST mean?" And it will
summarize back to me what AST means and it'll
give me a link to all the documents inside our
company that just grab what AST means and then
it will tell me who the expert in AST at our
company is. It's like having a second brain.
It's an insanely cool organization searching.
Great tip. Okay, two more questions.
Do you have a favorite life motto that
you come back to share with folks,
find useful and work during life?
I think about this one a lot. When I started
off in my career, I was an engineer's
engineer. I used to very much about technical
correctness and what computers were capable of,
and technical righteousness, the right
answer rather than there is only one right
answer and whatever. It's a long-winded way of
saying that I often think about this phrase,
which is people don't care what you know until
they know that you care. And so I've realized
that really being able to influence people,
it doesn't matter about whether or not you're
right or whether or not you're wrong. And at
the end of the day, it's first about trust and
about relationships and caring about what each
other's outcomes are, what their incentives are,
and all good things sit on top of that.
Once you have those kind of foundations,
then you can build really good partnerships
and that's where good progress comes from.
Wow, that is so good. It connects with Radical
Candor, similar in theory of just caring. People
need to feel like you care deeply about
them before they take your advice. And it
also connects with this parenting book I'm reading
called Listen, that a previous guest recommended,
which is all about how your kids have problems
when they feel like your connection to them is
weak. And so the solution is to build a
stronger connection for them to know that
you cared deeply about them. So this is really,
connected so much of what I've been reading.
Yeah, exactly.
Great one. Final question.
You were born in Sydney,
folks can maybe guess by your accent. If
someone were to visit Sydney, any tips,
anything you think they should
check out, favorite thing in Sydney?
Yeah, Sydney is a really beautiful city and it's
kind of famous for its beaches and it's basically
a metropolitan city. People probably be very
surprised when you visit it. It's a very big city,
very metropolitan, a little bit like New York,
but New York with really beautiful beaches,
if you want to think about it that way, it's kind
of crazy. But there's actually a ton of really
cool nature and beautiful things all around
Sydney. And so if you want to do something
like off the beaten path, you can actually go
to, there's an area called the Blue Mountains,
which is like an hour and a half drive from
Sydney, and you can abseil down a waterfall,
which is, well actually firstly you go
canyoning through a canyon full of water,
and then you abseil off a waterfall at the end.
And if you're looking for just a really beautiful,
fun kind of adventure like thing, an hour and a
bit away from a massive metropolitan city, that's
my sort of happy place. Really beautiful outdoors
stuff while also next to a beautiful city.
And you said you sail, what
sort of sail off a waterfall?
Abseil. You might think of it as
rappelling. Rappelling, I think. Yeah,
lowering yourself down on a rope or...
Got it. Because when I hear sail, I'm thinking
a boat just jumps through over the waterfall.
Oh, no, abseiling which is also, I think
in the States you guys call it rappelling.
Rappelling, yeah. Wow. Very cool. Shaun,
you're awesome. This was extremely cool.
Thank you so much for being here. Two final
questions. Where can folks find you online
if they want to reach out? Also point
folks to your Reforge courses that you
created. And final question, how
can listeners be useful to you?
Sure. Yeah, so my Reforge courses, you can check
them all out at reforge.com, as you mentioned,
the retention, engagement course and the data
for product managers course, so love to see
folks get some value from that. Lots of people
have been through those courses already and I
really get a lot of value from it because like
I said, one of my goals is to help all of us be
better product people. I think our leverage could
be massive. Where you can get in touch with me,
obviously on LinkedIn, but also ShaunMClowes on
X, if you want to get in touch. And in terms of
being useful to me, I mean, broadly speaking,
I'm always open to new ideas. If people have
ideas about how to do better B2B, PLG, better B2B
product-led sales, for example, better ways of
going about distribution and product-led sales and
product-led growth inside enterprise companies,
hey, I'm open to learn myself. We're all in
one big journey learning how to do this better.
So true. Shaun, thank you so much for being here.
Awesome, thank you very much, Lenny. It was great.
Bye, everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
LennysPodcast.com. See you in the next episode.