... Honored to be on a product
management podcast for a person
who doesn't believe product management is real.
We're already getting into the
hot takes. You launched tbh,
went viral, you end up selling it
to Facebook. What was the insight
that helped you come up with this
is a big idea that we should try?
I looked on the App Store and the
number one app in the United States
was an app called Surah, but
the entire app was in Arabic,
like the strongest signal that you could
ever have that people want something.
This is insane. I did not know this full story.
We launched this app, it immediately
took off, servers started crashing. I
looked at our numbers and I'm like, "We will be
number one in the United States in six days."
A tip that you're sharing
here is look for latent demand
Where people are trying to obtain a
particular value and going through a very
distortive process. If you can actually
crystallize what their motivation is,
you can have this kind of intense adoption.
I didn't know you're actually
a product manager at Facebook.
The thing I didn't realize as a product
manager in a large tech company is there
is very little product management that you
do. They're mainly just writing documents and
then being the team secretary and running around
getting approvals, but products live and die in
the pixels. You should be designing the hierarchy,
the pixels, the flows, everything. That's on you.
At some point you started tweeting like,
"Hey, I'm working on new app. Everyone
was going nuts." I saw a stat that you made
$11 million in sales, 10 million downloads.
The thing that is hard to really understand is
it is absolute chaos to keep the thing online. I
was sleeping three hours a day for three months.
Our team was also relentless though. They would
come over to my house, 9:00 AM, stay until
midnight and just do that seven days a week.
Is there anything else that's
just like this is something
that is probably going to help you with your app?
With certainty, if you're good at your job,
you can make an app grow and go viral. Over the
years of building all these apps, I've accrued all
these growth hacks that still nobody knows about.
Today, my guest is Nikita Bier. Nikita has
built, launched and helped get more apps to
the top of the app store than any human
I've ever come across. He sold his first
big hit tbh to Facebook for over $30 million.
He sold his second big app Gas to Discord for
many millions more. He did this all with a tiny
team and very little funding. He's also helped
dozens of founders and apps, and as an advisor or
investor to companies like Flow, Citizen, BeReal,
LOCKit and Wealthsimple and many more. Today,
he spends his time advising companies on viral
growth strategies, design feedback, structuring
their product development process and a lot more.
What I love about Nikita is that he has very
strong opinions about how to build successful
products that are rooted in him actually doing
the work over the past decade to see for himself
what works and what doesn't. Nikita has been the
single most requested guests on this podcast,
and you'll soon see why. This episode is
packed with tactics and stories and lessons
that I am sure will leave you wanting
more. If you want to work with Nikita
on your app, you can actually book his time at
intro.co/nikitabier. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in
your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's
the best way to avoid missing feature episodes
and helps the podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you Nikita Bier. Nikita, thank you so
much for being here. Welcome to the podcast.
Thanks for having me. I'm excited to
dive in. I feel honored to be on a
product management podcast for a person who
doesn't believe product management is real.
We're already getting into the hot takes.
We're definitely going to chat about... Wait,
and you said not real. Okay, I thought you were
going to say not useful. This is good. Let's put
a pin in that. I think we think this, I think
everyone already feels this. I think this is
going to be a very special conversation. I've been
looking forward to chatting you for a long time
and there's so much that I want to ask you. The
way that I'm thinking we frame this conversation
is we go through the story behind the apps that
you've built or helped build that have hit the top
of the app store, and basically here, the inside
story of what it took to build those apps and to
make them successful. Then through that, try to
extract as many lessons as we can about what it
takes to build a successful viral consumer
app these days. How does that sound to you?
Sounds amazing, and a lot of it
was luck, but a lot of it was very,
very tactical work that went into it all.
This episode is brought to you by
Webflow. We're all friends here,
so let's be real for a second. We all
know that your website shouldn't be a
static asset. It should be a dynamic part
of your strategy that drives conversions,
that's business 101. Here's a number for you.
54% of leaders say web updates take too long.
That's over half of you listening right
now. That's where Webflow comes in. Their
visual-first platform allows you to build, launch,
and optimize webpages fast. That means you can set
ambitious business goals and your site can rise
to the challenge. Learn how teams like Dropbox,
IDEO and Orange Theory trust Webflow to achieve
their most ambitious goals today at Webflow.com.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta.
When it comes to ensuring your company has
top-notch security practices, things get
complicated fast. Now you can assess risk,
secure the trust of your customers and automate
compliance for SOC 2, ISO 27001, HIPAA and more,
with a single platform, Vanta. Vanta's market
leading trust management platform helps you
continuously monitor compliance alongside
reporting and tracking risks. Plus, you can
save hours by completing security questionnaires
with Vanta AI. Join thousands of global companies
that use Vanta to automate evidence collection,
unify risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go to
vanta.com/lenny. That's vanta.com/lenny. First,
I want to start with something that I think
very few people know about you. The first thing
that you built, the first product that you built
was very different from what you do these days,
and it's a product called Politify, which
something I actually really want. It helps
you decide who to vote for based on how it would
impact your life. Can you just share a bit about
just that part of your life and why you decided
to pivot away from that into consumer apps?
When I was in college, I was really interested
in this kind of thing that American voters do,
which is they vote against their own financial
self-interest, like people in New York and San
Francisco vote for Democrats for higher taxes.
People in Kansas vote for Republicans for low
taxes and they make less money, and so fewer
government benefits. I wanted to build this tool
that would help communicate the financial impacts
of these policy proposals of presidents. I built
it in my last year of college and it was just a
web app that we put out and it would calculate
their tax proposals, the government benefits that
they were proposing, and you would enter in your
basic personal information, how many kids you
have, your age. Then it would just tell you in
dollars what the impact would be. It'd also
tell you, we simulated those policies also
against the tax returns of every zip code so
you could see how it impacts your community.
We went super viral. I think very few people
thought of politics that way and I think we got
4 million users on it during that season, during
that election. It was just like a project that
we raised some grant money for, but it ended
up feeding into this company that we spun up
and that was called Outline. Because we had a
bunch of governments reach out to us asking,
"Can you build this for our budget?" The governor
of Massachusetts actually reached out and I flew
out there to meet with them and that was going
to be our first customer. We raised some money,
we won a government contract and we
joined Techstars, the accelerator.
We got a contract in the pipeline with the Obama
administration and then we got this contract and
we started building it and the government
shutdown happened in the middle of like,
as we were building it and we had
one of our contracts canceled.
I realized I actually really don't like selling
software to governments and my core competency
all along was making things that go viral on the
internet. That was what we had built, not this
policy simulation tool. We went to our investors
and we said, "Look, this isn't actually what we're
excited about doing anymore." We offered to
give the money back and said, "We're going to
be building consumer apps and here's a few ideas
that we have." None of them took the money back.
Then we spent the next four or five years building
a variety of different kind of consumer apps. We
had a few mild successes during the course of
those four to five years. One of them was an
app called Five Labs that ingested your Facebook
posts and determine your personality based on the
language you use. It used this exact same model
that Cambridge Analytica used, and that was super
viral. I think we had tens of millions of profiles
in it and it went viral in like three days.
We raised some more money based off the success of
that and we started focusing a lot more on mobile
after that first app, Five Labs. We launched
basically every type of app you can imagine.
We launched mapping apps, chat apps, event meetup
apps. Basically, every consumer app on mobile that
you could think of. That actually helped us
build a muscle to understand what people want
and how to actually make things grow and how
to test them. Over time, we started focusing
more on teens. A lot of people ask why Silicon
Valley is so fixated on building apps for teens.
One of the reasons is their habits are pretty
malleable. As we get older, we get fixed into our
habits of using certain communication products
and we don't really adopt new things. Then the
other thing that we discovered was that adults
don't really invite people to new apps. We found
that as a user got older from age 13 to 18,
the number of people that they invite to an
app just declines almost exponentially.
Finally, and the most important thing is
they see each other every day, and that is so
critical. Consumer app developers sometimes
say smokers are great for targeting an audience
because they actually hang out serendipitously a
lot outside of buildings. Not to say social apps
are cigarettes, I don't really like that metaphor.
Just on the note of you talking about why teens
are important, I have this quote actually from you
that I love where building on the point you made
that for every social app I've ever built and the
number of invitations sent per user drops 20%
for every additional year of age from 13 to
18. If you build for adults, expect to acquire
every user with ads, and I love that you have
a very clear heuristic of per year, the amount
of people they invite to the app is 20% lower.
If your users aren't inviting people to your app,
you're going to have to find another way to
acquire them, and that most likely means ads.
If you're targeting older cohorts like adults,
you're going to have to raise a huge amount of
venture capital to finance that user acquisition
pipeline and it's going to be extraordinarily
expensive. As a seed stage up, it's going to
be basically impossible to grow that user base,
especially to get density if you need
actual network effects among users.
Basically, you're building this help
me decide who to vote for app that
turned into a real business with government
contracts coming to you trying to help you,
pushing you to build something that you
end up realizing I don't want to be doing
this. Why am I building this app selling
government contracts. What you did is you,
and this is a really interesting lesson to
take away, is you just realized, I don't want
to be doing this. Investors don't force me to be
working on this. I'm going to stop this. I'm going
to go work on some other stuff that I'm actually
excited about that I think has a bigger chance
of success. That's where you transition to this
startup studio where you're just trying a bunch
of apps and I think it was called Midnight
Labs, you said, something like that, right?
Yeah.
Awesome. Basically, I think that's a really
interesting insight of just like if you're working
on something you don't enjoy, you can change that,
you can pivot, you can tell your investors I want
to work on something else. Is there anything
there that you want to add along those lines?
It was really hard for us to pivot to mobile.
I think that was one of the most challenging
things for me personally because it was a
completely different paradigm. I actually
have been building web apps since I was 12 years
old. I built a full e-commerce business selling
pirated games on the web, and I knew everything
about growing a website. As we pivoted to mobile,
I had to recalibrate my whole brain on how to
do that. Mobile apps have such a low margin
for error when it comes to designing them.
Because I have this dogmatic view that every
tap on a mobile app is a miracle for you as
a product developer because users will turn
and bounce to their next app very quickly.
If you actually sit behind someone and watch
them use their phone, they actually switch between
apps at a pretty high frequency. Every tap that
you get, every single one is so scarce that you
should be optimizing everything. I had to change
my whole brain when we started pivoting
to mobile and building these mobile apps,
and it took a lot of failures. 14 of the apps
that we launched were basically duds, and then
we started fixating on teens and building apps for
them. Eventually, we figured out an interesting
heuristic for identifying consumer product
opportunities that ultimately led us to tbh.
You spent four or five years trying a bunch
of different ideas. I think people see this
headline and we'll get into tbh of just
like nine weeks after launch sells for
$30 million to Facebook and everyone's like,
"Oh, okay, that's amazing. I want that for
my life." Nobody knows there's this four or
five years of trying, you said 15 different
apps before you got there, learning the
things that actually work and don't work.
We built 15 apps over the course of that pivot to
consumer, and we built apps for every single app,
map apps, chat apps, to-do lists. We just
built every type of consumer app you could
possibly think of. Also, we built for every
audience too. We built for college students,
we built for post-college. It was always
very difficult to get the flywheel spinning
for anyone after like 22 years old.
That was the cutoff of when people
just give up on adopting new products. It took
us a few years to really internalize that,
a lot of failures to realize no one
needs another app after that age.
The thing that you found there, which is really
interesting because most people are building for
people older than 22, that's a profound insight
you had there. Every consumer app I see is trying
to build for adults, and your lesson there
is basically if you're trying to do that,
you're probably going to need to raise
money and spend a lot of money on paid ads.
Most likely, you'll never get network effects.
There's actually an interesting study many years
ago that some academics in Spain did, I think it
was in Spain, and they looked at how many people
you text per year of your life, and it goes up
very quickly from 14 to 18. It peaks around 21,
so it's growing. The number of people you text is
growing up until about 21, and then it just falls,
it collapses, and then it comes back up at end
of life. There's a few reasons all this happens,
but basically, once you exit college, you reduce
the number of contacts, your daily contacts.
Once you get married, it's even fewer. Then
as you get older and your kids start having
kids and you become a grandparent, you start
texting again more or you join a retirement
home. If you're building a product with network
effects that's a communication tool, you want
to be on that upward curve of adding connections
to your social graph because then the urgency to
connect is higher. If you really want to actually
innovate at the edges of communication products,
you really have to target that cohort that has the
highest urgency to communicate, and that's teens.
I love that you found these things out, not
through just research and not through just
thinking, it was through actual trying things over
and over and over and trying different audiences,
trying different experiences. A lot of
people see your advice and they're like,
"How does he know?" It's just you've done
all these things yourself. You've seen them,
you're sitting there watching teens use these
apps. I think very few people actually do that,
and they just come up with these theories
that aren't based in empirical evidence.
We got pretty good at building these apps. I
think our first mobile app took us about a year,
and then our last one took us about two weeks.
We also got very good at testing apps. The most
important thing that I often instruct teams to
do is to develop a reproducible testing process,
and that will actually influence the probability
of your success more than anything. It's so
unpredictable whether a consumer product idea will
work. If you actually focus more on your process
for taking many shots at bat, that's what actually
reduces the risk more than anything. We figured
out ways to seed apps into schools. We also,
during the course of that company, we figured out
how to seed it into affinity groups, hobbyists,
things like that. We were on app number 15, a lot
of failures during the course of this company, and
I remember a lot of our team members were like, "I
kind of want to leave. I think this is it for me."
One of our key team members actually put in their
two weeks' notice. The day before we launched our
final app, we were getting kind of low on money.
I was tired. I called our lawyer to ask, how do
you dissolve a company? I messaged a few mentors
saying like, one people that have been through it,
and I said, "What are the steps to do this?" Then
I had a conversation on the way out with that
team member that wanted to leave, and I said,
"I understand, but what if the app actually
starts charting on the App Store?" He said,
"What are the chances of that? You know that's
not going to happen." I said, "Sure, okay." We
launched this app and it was a polling app, tbh,
and it immediately took off in the school that
we seeded it into, in Georgia. We picked the
one school that had the earliest start date in
the United States because we needed to launch as
soon as possible, given the state of the company.
I think it spread to 40% of the school downloaded
it in the first 24 hours and it rapidly spread to
the neighboring schools. Suddenly, I was like,
"Oh, we might have something here." Servers
started crashing and watching it climb the charts.
I looked at our numbers and I'm like, "We will
be number one in the United States in six days."
Then I looked at our Amazon bill and it was like
120,000. I looked at our bank account, it
said 150,000. I'm like, "Okay, these two
numbers don't really..." I quickly had to put
together a funding round and I told my team,
"Can you guys just pause for two months
and just really focus on this? I think I
could probably sell this thing." It turned
into a pretty competitive bidding process,
actually. There was a really, really great moment
where there was one of the acquirers, or one of
the bidders was based in LA, had told me to fly
down, and they told me to fly down that day.
I got on a plane, went to the airport without a
ticket, showed up. When we were rolling out this
app, we were doing a state-by-state rollout
strategy where every state was geo-fenced. We
hadn't launched California until that morning.
I arrived at this company, this founders in LA's
house, and he said, "Show me the metrics. You guys
are like, what? Number four or something?" Since
we just launched California, it's a big state. I
said, "No, we're actually number one. We're the
number one app in the United States." He said,
"Show me the metrics." Our CTO, Erik Hazzard,
is a published author in mapping. He created
an amazing dashboard that could show real-time
installs on a map. It was around 4:00 PM and
school had just gotten out, so I zoomed in on the
block that we were having that meeting, and the
entire block was lit up with installs all around
us. Then that's what got the ball rolling on a...
It was a really, really like, cinematic moment of
showing something that you created that literally
just took over the entire neighborhood around you.
That's insane. That's going to
be in the movie of Nikita Bier
in the future. A couple of questions
here. One, you predicted the chart,
you would hit number one. What does it take
to hit number one? What is the number you're
looking at? Is it some number downloads
to get to number one in the App Store?
It fluctuates. It used to be like 80 to
100,000 installs, but now you have these
companies that are just spending extraordinary
amounts on ads and or injecting it into
one of their other apps. Between
Threads, Temu and all these other
apps that are spending on acquisition and
all that, some days it's up to 300,000.
That's per day?
Yeah.
Oh, man. Amazing.
At the peak of tbh, we were
getting 360,000 per day.
The other two things I want to spend a little
time on here before we move on to the next app is,
what was the insight that helped you come
up with this is a big idea that we should
try? Then what was the insight into how to spread
this so virally? I know that one is really close.
... to how to spread this so virally,
and I know that one is really clever.
After building all these apps, we had these
kind of lingering users that stuck around
and would share feedback with us on our
next app. And so there were a couple,
like there's a senior in high school that I
would send screenshots of our products. He
told me about this trend called TBH
that kids were playing on Snapchat,
where they would post an image of a
bunch of emojis and it would say like,
"I like you. Your smart. Your style is great."
And you would just reply to the story with the
emoji of what you felt. And I was like, "This is
kind of weird. You post this on your story and
then people send you feedback." And I'm like, "So
teens are looking for this vehicle for disclosure
essentially." And I'm like, "That's kind of cool.
I wonder if you could make that into an app." We
had sketched some things out. As we were
sketching things out, I looked on the app store,
and the number one app in the United States was an
app called Sarahah. It was for sending anonymous
messages by adding a link to your Snapchat story.
But the thing that was most interesting was the
entire app was in Arabic. The number one app in
the United States was in Arabic. And that was
one of the most strongest signal that you could
ever have that people want something. And so when
I meet with founders, I often tell them like, "The
way you should be searching for product ideas is
this concept of latent demand where people are
trying to obtain a particular value and going
through a very distortive process to obtain that
value." And if you can actually crystallize what
their motivation is and build a product around
and clear up what they're trying to actually do,
you can have this kind of intense adoption.
When we saw what people were doing with Sarahah,
I also looked at some of the tweets and comments
on it. A lot of people were receiving negative
messages. And so what I saw with the game
that kids were playing on Snapchat TBH and
then Sarahah, I realized just people want to
know good things about themselves and that they
don't want these bullying messages that they're
getting on these anonymous apps, and I was like,
"Well, what if instead of actually typing what you
wanted to say about somebody, you just answered
polls and we authored those polls so that we
ensured everything would always be positive?"
I mean, in the back of my head, I always knew
anonymous apps go viral, but they always lead
to these awful news stories of kids committing
suicide, self-harm and all that. And so I was
like, "I'll never build anything like that."
But when we came up with this new mechanic
where you could only say positive things through
polls, who has the best smile, who's most likely
to be president, and then you receive it
as anonymous, but your name is selected,
what we discovered a couple of things is it
made users feel a lot better. It actually
solved what they were trying to do and they
also sent a much higher volume of messages.
And so it was literally explosive adoption.
One school I was looking at, they sent 450,000
messages in the first seven days of adopting it.
And when you look at day one volume of messages
sent on a messaging app, you're lucky if
people send three or four or something,
but we were sending 60 and we couldn't even
handle it, so we had to geofence the app
because we needed to scale our servers, which is
actually a pretty controversial decision inside
of our company, because why would you turn
off something that's working? But at my core,
I knew if it's working at this many individual
schools, we could just relaunch it any time and
it'll go viral. So let's regroup and figure
out what's happening here and then relaunch.
So you keep talking about how went viral
and crazy, grew like crazy. I know that
there's a little trick that you came up with
to help it spread. Can you just briefly talk
about what you did there and to help
it spread so quickly within a school?
I think you're referring to, there's a
memo that was leaked to BuzzFeed while
I was at Facebook. The main thing we found
was like, to be convinced to download an app,
you need to see it. You need to see the
marketing message three times or so.
So you basically need to saturate an area with
every kind of marketing you can. So we ran ads
targeted at a particular school to when we
were seeding and testing these apps. And
we also followed people creating a dedicated
Instagram account that went to that school,
because we learned that high schoolers identify
their school in their bio, so it says RHS on
their bio. And so that was how we tried to get
the entire school to adopt synchronously. We'd
follow them and then accept the followbacks.
Big misunderstanding though, and I get this DM
a lot of people are like, "I'm trying to replicate
your strategy. We've just done it at 15 schools
and it's not working anymore." This is not the
way we grew the app. This is how we tested apps.
Really, it's a little bit nuanced there. That's
an important nuance because you need to get enough
intensity of adoption and density for a social
network to start to get the flywheel spinning,
but the app should grow by itself after that. And
people think we just went from school to school
following every kid on it. You can't, that's
totally unrealistic. But for the first 100 users,
yes, that's how we got them. And that allowed us
to know whether the product was working or not. We
could get enough people on it and then we could,
with conviction, say that whether the app had legs
and we wouldn't have this kind of uncertainty
like, "Oh, did they add enough friends? Did
we get enough people on it? Did they reach the
aha moment because you need friends to get on?"
So we wanted to eliminate that confounding
variable, and so we figured out a way to just
get a bunch of people to adopt at once. And that's
one thing I encourage a lot of founders to do,
is figure out a way to eliminate all those
potentially confounding variables so you can know
immediately whether something's working or not.
You never want to walk away from an experiment
or test and say, "Well, maybe the execution was
bad because it takes a lot of energy to mobilize
a team to test something," and you really want
to make sure your tests actually provide signal.
So your advice here is when
you're testing something,
test the best possible version of what
that could be, whether it takes manual
work or something that is never going to
scale, test the ideal. Because that'll
tell you, " Even if this could be the best
possible version, do people actually care?"
Yeah, we would try to get an entire school to
adopt, just to know if everyone had 10 friends,
would they actually derive value from
this app? We also did other things,
and I recommend all companies do this, is
put live chat customer support in your app
24 hours a day. It sounds insane. It's like
the whole point of tech is you don't need to
do that. That's the whole point of a software.
But then users get this white glove experience,
and that eliminates another confounding variable,
like did they think their problems were solved or
they were treated well? But most of all, one
of the reasons I actually recommend people
put live chat in their app is it's the best
vehicle for getting feedback and doing user
research because users will literally tell you
the problem they're having. So we had our person
that was running this. He's name is Michael
Gutierrez. He's done it for all my companies
actually. He's the community and customer
support rep. He would paste any interesting
feedback into Slack and then we would be
like, "Oh, this user has a great idea. We
should consider turning that into a feature."
So you really want your finger on the pulse
as you roll these things out so you can get a
sense for what's working, what isn't, and also
make users feel great and make sure at the end
they promote your app positively to their peers.
I love that piece of advice.
Okay, so to close out the TBH chapter,
is there anything else that you think is important
for people to know or any other lasting lessons
from that part of your journey that you bring
with you to new apps that you're building today?
I think the thing that is hard to really
understand for first-time founders that
hit breakout success with a consumer product is
how draining and how spread thin you get, because
everything breaks. Everything that you built
needs to be substituted almost every three days.
I can just give you an example. We were
just talking about this customer support
system that we had. The first system broke after
three days. The next one broke seven days later,
we had to replace it with a different one that
could scale even better. And if you think about
that on every dimension of the company, it is
absolute chaos to keep the thing online as it
scales up. And so you have to be ruthless with
prioritization as something scales up and put
out the largest fires first, because that was
something that I didn't really fully understand,
is how many things go wrong. And if we didn't
geofence the app, there would be no way we
would've been able to keep that thing online
because that gave us some slack to control growth.
This is a good example of when people ask
like, "Hey, does my app have product-market
fit?" I think this is an example of this
is what it looks like when things are
breaking every three days when you have
to geofence it to keep it from crashing.
A lot of people ask me like, "What's the benchmark
for product-market fit?" And this founder that I'm
friends with, his name's Roger Dickey, he told
me this one time, "If your product's working,
you'll know. And if there's any uncertainty,
it's not working." And it really is a binary
when it comes to consumer products. People are
going to be fighting to get into it and you'll
find new measures that you've never heard of
like, "Our metric was hourly actives per day."
Not daily active users, hourly active users. So
you'll start seeing that and it'll be abundantly
obvious what product-market fit is. You'll
know it when you see it is the bottom line.
Okay, so you launch TBH, it goes viral,
start getting offers from companies. Nine
weeks later after launch, you end up selling
it to Facebook. What was it like selling your
company and then what was it like working
at Facebook? Which you worked at for four
years. I was not expecting that when I
was looking at your LinkedIn. So yeah,
what was it like selling? What
was it like working at Facebook?
Selling your company is one of the most draining
processes you could ever go through as a founder.
When we met with Facebook, they told me they have
80 people assigned to this deal. And I'm like,
I have one person, it's just me.
They were like the SWAT team of M&A.
The funniest part was they wanted to meet the
team as well. And so they came out to our office
in Oakland, which is a dingy old office that I
got for $1,800 a month. That was our rent for the
office. They arrive and they walk in. There's two
engineers and one designer and me, and they're
just like, "This is the whole company? This is the
number one app in the United States?" I'm like,
"Yeah, this is it." And when we went there,
when we arrived, we joined the youth team,
which was about, I don't know, 150 people just
for this one division of Facebook. It was my first
job effectively that I've ever had.
When they told me my title, they said I
would be a product manager, I was like, "Okay,
I don't know exactly what that is, but yeah,
I guess that's what I do." I arrive and then I get
access to a workplace system where people post all
the things they're working on, and I realized it's
kind of like this almost academic environment for
social networks, like social network development.
It's like the Harvard of social networks. I was
reading all these studies that people were
doing on like, "Oh, if we change that,
this is the impact to retention and DAU." I was so
impressed, like, "There's a whole science here."
A lot of the stuff that we did
was learned from first principles,
but then we saw it actually turn into systems and
processes here. But the thing I didn't realize as
a product manager in a large tech company is
there is very little product management that
you do. You're actually not as involved in the
product as I had assumed. I thought, "Oh, you're
the person who gets in the pixels and designs
the flows." Absolutely not. You're completely
detached from the design process. There's a design
vertical org that does all that and they don't
really want you working on that. So that was very
difficult for me because when people ask me like,
"What do you think you're good at?" At the core,
I'm a designer. I don't consider myself a product
manager. I'm great at growing things, looking
at mixed panel and then designing the things
that make it grow. But there's a rift between
those two things inside of a large tech company.
And so I loved the academic approach to growing,
but it was really hard for me personally as
I became disconnected from the design process. I
think that a lot of my skills atrophied over those
four years. But I did stick around. I went through
multiple orgs. Favorite one at the end was new
product experimentation where I worked with other
founders, a bunch of legends in Silicon Valley,
building zero to one products, standalone
apps. I mean, I was building standalone apps
my entire time at Facebook. I think I built
probably eight apps while I was at Facebook.
Wow.
But it is much, much more difficult to build apps
at a large company. A lot of the insights that you
have are not things that you can necessarily
present or put in writing in a VP meeting,
like, " We're building an app for teens to
flirt." That probably is not what you would
present to a bunch of McKinsey consultants at.
So I think that makes it really difficult to be
completely intellectually honest about what you're
building. And when the team isn't honest about it,
then it's really hard to iterate toward the
right thing in that context. Having said that,
there's a lot of things you don't have to
deal with as a product... I don't have to
deal think about money, I don't have to think
about paying legal bills or doing finance and
accounting. So all that's abstracted away,
but there is regulatory stuff that you have
to deal with that I had zero exposure
to as a founder of a small company.
An insight you're sharing there potentially
is the reason a company like Facebook isn't
amazing at launching completely
new product, zero to one stuff,
is they might be a little too risk
averse and it's hard to talk about
stuff that people actually really, really
want deeply. Is that kind of the sense there?
It's hard to really verbalize some of the things
that motivate us as people. There's a tweet I put
out that's kind of dogmatic in terms of how I view
why people download apps and it's very simple.
It's like people download apps to make or save
money. Examples of that might be like WhatsApp,
where free texting. And then the other reason is
to find a mate, so maybe like Tinder or Snapchat,
find love. And the third is to unplug from reality
maybe like Netflix or Fortnite. There's a bunch
of other kind of subcategories that are very
utilitarian like movement, Uber or Airbnb, like
shelter. And so I think putting that in
a framing document and the particular
nuanced reason why people are going to adopt is
difficult when you're presenting that to people
that are seasoned professionals and care about
how something might reflect on them personally.
And so that's really difficult inside
of a large company. You'd certainly have
distribution advantages. If you want to just
inject your app into one of the parent apps
and get density within a community, you
could do that. But that part I think is
probably solvable for a startup if you just
want to pay for ads. Getting your app into
a dense friend graph is overall trivial. As
a founder, you should be able to pull it off
after enough tries. So that advantage that a
big company brings, I mean it makes it easier,
but it's not something that I think is something
that a founder can't solve for themselves.
So an interesting takeaway it sounds like is
many people feel like, "I'm going to build a
social app." They probably often hear, "Facebook's
going to do that. Instagram's going to copy you.
Snap's going to do that." And what I'm hearing
here is it's not as easy as many people think,
that it might be actually a lot
harder for them to try something.
It's not only harder for them to identify these
opportunities and to verbalize it internally and
align the company around it. It's also hard to
respond to signals in the market. A lot of people
think these incumbents are going to steal your
ideas. And for the most part, it takes a pretty
long time for them to respond to even the number
one app or charting in the app because it'll start
charting in the app store, a PM will make a post
about it. And then the market's strategy or market
research team might do a study to follow up on it.
It'll kind of float around for a few months. They
might put together a framing deck saying, "Hey,
we should go after this opportunity. Let's put
together this team. It'll go through VP reviews.
And then it'll start development. Development
might take six to 12 months." Realistically,
I think most companies, large companies
take 12 to 24 months to respond to
competitive threats in the market.
Do you think this is solvable? Is
there something a company can change
to get better at this? Are there companies
that are good at this in your experience,
or is this just as you grow,
this is just what happens?
The incentives within large companies make
this very difficult, because you don't want
to present something that you have a hunch about
being a good idea because if there's not market
signals already, then it's hard to defend. People
in companies are focused on getting their yearly
bonus or they're focused on their performance
reviews. It's hard to show up into a framing
meeting saying like... And a framing meeting is a
meeting where you are positioning the opportunity
and everything, "Here's what we should go after."
It's hard to just say, "Okay, by first principles,
this is a good idea and here's some
very vague market signals." In reality,
you need to walk in and say, "Here's the number
one app in the United States and we don't own
it." If you present something like that, that's
pretty defensible if you fail because there was
market evidence. But if you fail about something
that's more based on kind of vague abstract...
So you have to, generally, the only
path is to copy existing products
if you want to really get momentum
inside of a large organization. And for
completely new concepts, it's I think very
difficult to present a lot of those ideas,
either to verbalize them into a document or
to even get rally the organization around it.
That's a really interesting insight.
This episode is brought to you by Explo,
a game changer for customer facing analytics
and data reporting. Are your users craving more
dashboards, reports, and analytics within your
product? Are you tired of trying to build it
yourself? As a product leader, you probably have
these requests in your roadmap, but the struggle
to prioritize them is real. Building analytics
from scratch can be time-consuming, expensive,
and a really challenging process. Enter Explo.
Explo is a fully white-labeled embedded analytics
solution designed entirely with your user in
mind. Getting started is easy. Explo connects
to any relational database or warehouse, and
with its low-code functionality, you can build
and style dashboards in minutes. Once you're
ready, simply embed the dashboard or report
into your application with a tiny code snippet.
The best part? Your end users can use Explo's
AI features for their own report and dashboard
generation, eliminating customer data requests for
your support team. Build and embed a fully white
analytics experience in days. Try it for free at
explo.co/lenny. That's E-X-P-L-O, .C-O/Lenny.
Before we move on to the next chapter, I want
to come back to the very first thing you said
where product management is not real. Is there
anything else that you can say about your insight
there? Or is it basically what you described where
PMs aren't actually involved in design and
a company like Facebook in your experience?
The functional organization structure of big
tech has kind of separated product managers
from the product development process in many
ways. They're not looking at data because data
scientists are doing that. They're just
parsing some of the reports that they get
back. They're mainly just writing documents
and then kind of being the team secretary
and running around, getting approvals from
each cross-functional team, legal privacy,
everything like that. And yeah, you're actually
very much separated from the product itself. And
so I think what Snapchat has done, and
I think Apple too, to the same extent,
is that designers run the show. And I
think that's led to some very novel-
And I think that's led to some very novel products
coming out from both of those companies. But
I mean that is its own host of problems because
actually rolling out a product inside of a large
organization, it requires a sheer force of will
because it's a lot of work. I mean, there's a lot
of regulatory scrutiny, scaling it up. You do need
someone to project manage. And so I don't know if
it's the silver bullet as to give designers the
reign to run the show, but I also don't think the
current traditional like Google, Facebook style of
being team secretaries is also the best solution.
To defend product managers, I think many
product managers spend a lot of time in design,
spend a lot of time with data science. I think
probably what you saw is like the extreme big,
big, big tech version of product management.
I know even PMs at Facebook can if they want
to spend time with design. I think
it's just obviously very different
from a startup world where you're
just, that's all you're doing.
Yeah, it's certainly an exaggerated view, but it's
particularly relevant I think for all the zero
to one initiatives because if you're a product
manager on a standalone app inside of a large,
like you should be designing the hierarchy, the
pixels, the flows, everything. And then yeah,
it should be cleaned up prototype by a technical
designer, but that's your idea. And products live
and die in the pixels, like consumer products,
so that's on you. And that's where I think for
maybe larger growth initiatives, yes, you can
be a little more detached from the pixels.
I love that advice. Okay, before we move on to
the next phase of your journey of starting Gas,
I heard there's an interesting story
around where you were actually put
within the Facebook office physically, where
your team was put. Is there something there?
Yeah. When we joined the new
product experimentation group,
we were actually seated I think at basically
the same desk as Mark Zuckerberg. And that
was pretty cool to see how the machine
runs from Zuck's view. But we had a few
artifacts that we had kept with us from
our old office when we were running tbh,
and one of them was this kind of pop art
painting that I bought on the street when
I needed to get something on the walls for our
office. And it was this giant painting of Tim
Cook. We had been carrying it between our orgs
at Facebook just because it was a funny painting.
And I kind of got it because it was kind of
symbolic of who actually controls our destiny,
is Apple. And so when we relocated to the area
where Zuck was sitting, I put up the painting on
the wall and it was basically a giant painting of
Tim Cook was overlooking Zuck. And eventually one
of the EAs there said, "Actually, do you think
you could take that home?" And it kind of made
sense because you can't really have a painting
of another big tech executive overlooking us.
What does it look like? Do you happen to have it?
Yeah, I actually do. Let me go grab it.
Amazing. Oh, wow. That's artistic.
So that's Tim Cook. What is the idea
there that he's peeking through
this darkness staring at you?
Yeah, yeah. He's the real boss of all of us.
I could see why Zuck would
not want that staring at him
all day. That's amazing. And I like
that you still have that with you.
Yeah. One of the artifacts of
that chapter of life. So good.
Okay. So that was your Facebook journey, those
four years. That's wild. You left Facebook.
At some point, you started, I remember
this, you started tweeting like, "Hey,
I'm working on new app." Everyone was going nuts.
"What are you working on?" And at this point,
I think you probably in your mind thought, I am
this one-hit wonder, I haven't shown that I can do
this again and again. And so I think you probably
have this motivation. Maybe talk about that,
just like this drive of like, hey, I want to
do this again. Is that where your mind was at?
When that meme started, my intent was
to start a venture-backed company and
build something that would scale to be a big team
and this durable thing that lasted many years and
everything. And so I just made post that I was
leaving Facebook and looking for some teammates.
And I shared a couple of ideas with some people
privately and there were some really crazy ideas
that I shared. I'm not going to get into them,
but then people started posting, "Oh my God,
I just saw Nikita's app. It's crazy." And what
happened was others saw that and then they started
memeing it and it became this massive meme where
they're like, "Oh, I just tried Nikita's app,
it saved my marriage. Oh, I just quit drinking.
My kids returned home after all these like," and
it turned into this massive meme. And at the
time, I didn't even have an app or anything.
I wasn't even planning to launch it. It wasn't
even an app, some of the ideas I was looking at.
And so it just turned into this viral moment. I
wasn't even committed to starting another company
at that point. This was an exploration process.
But what happened was the market had crashed
shortly thereafter, there was kind of the end
of the Zerb era. The Fed started hiking rates. I
think my portfolio was down like 30% or something
and I was like, "Damn, this sucks. Maybe I should
think about how to make money today." That's the
reason we're in startups is to make money. And
so there was always in the back of my head this
question that I had, which was what if we had
monetized tbh? Because the number one support
message we received was can I pay to reveal
who sent me polls? It was the number one question.
And it was like, would it have made even more than
the acquisition if we just monetized it? And I'm
like, we could probably build this pretty fast,
like probably in a month, month or two. Ended up
being a lot longer, but we started rebuilding it.
It was a new team. It was one of the engineers
from a company called Paparazzi. His name's
Zay Turner, and he started building it in my
house and we had tested it to see would this
new version of tbh actually resonate with kids
five years later? That was actually the thing
I wanted to know most of all was like would an
anonymous polling app actually still be relevant
five years later? And so we dropped it into the
school just the same way I've always done it in-
Was it the Georgia School again?
Yes, actually. We launched at the exact same
school that we launched tbh on the exact same
day five years later, in fact. And people sent
a lot of messages, but it wasn't growing. So
let me pedal back here a bit. So tbh grew through
variety of things, people sharing their messages
to Snapchat and text invites, and that was 2017.
And the way you invited your friends on tbh was
that you tap their name, your contact name, and
there was a button that said Invite and then we
used Twilio to send them a text message. And the
regulatory environment actually had changed a lot
over those five years. You really can't send texts
from a server anymore. It has to be sent from the
user's device. And just the point of clarification
is a lot of people clone tbh over the years and
they think that when you voted on people in
the polls, it sent them a text. We never did
that. That's egregiously illegal to do and also
unethical at a user experience level to send texts
when people don't even know what's happening.
But anyway, we couldn't send texts over Twilio
anymore, and that led to people not sending
as many invites when we created Gas because
they had to pop the Compose window and hit Send.
They're going to just tap Invite on five names.
So we actually had to reinvent all the growth
systems and it took about I think like nine
launches including renaming the app, including
features that just never existed on tbh. So it was
actually just in many ways like yeah, the concept
on the surface was the same, but it was very much
a zero to one development cycle of figuring out
how to grow this thing again in this climate.
I know that point is really important
to you. I think a lot of people are like
Nikita just sold the same app twice. What
a guy. And the point you're making here is
not only was the infrastructure completely
different, the team was different,
you had to rethink the entire flywheel
of how it worked and how it grew.
Yeah. And there were so many layers of like we
validated one thing and then the next thing we
got stuck on. Like, okay, people send a lot of
messages. Cool, great. The next thing was will
it spread within a school? That took us a while
to get right. Will it hop schools? Each of those
was a very, very challenging problem in light of
the new climate that we were operating in. And
I always do things by the book when it comes to
operating legally within the compliance framework.
And that's something when I meet founders and
they tell me some growth thing that they're doing,
and I'm like, "You can't do that. That's
going to cause way more trouble down the line.
It's going to burn users too." And so we always
wanted to make it abundantly clear how our growth
system, how you are inviting friends and all
that. You can kind of go on a whole diatribe
on that because the thing that I see a lot of
founders do is they in the background use user
data in ways that it shouldn't be used. They
invite people on your behalf and all that.
And I have this kind of crazy view that the
internet is this living and breathing thing.
There's Wikipedia article called the Gaia
Hypothesis, which is about biology. And it's
basically like the earth is kind of living and
breathing and can respond to threats. Okay? And
when you enter the rainforest too deep, Ebola
virus will be released. Okay? So I think the
internet operates on a similar paradigm here
where if you do the wrong thing by users,
the internet will come back and get even and
defend itself. And so whenever I design products,
I try to do right by users because it'll
always come back much worse and I think
you should always operate above board with how
you design your growth systems. And with Gas,
we had to do things the right way and we
had to figure out at each particular moment
or problem that we solve, will it spread
within schools? Will it hop schools? Will
people pay for it? All of these things was
a whole reinvention of the original product.
I love that you shared that because I think
a lot of people see you from the outside and
they think you're doing all kinds of
these skeezy growth hacks and making
teens do things that aren't really mentally
healthy for them. But it's clear that that's
the opposite of how you think about it,
that you're trying to stay very positive,
like you only allow positive communication.
You do things that as you just said,
are going to be good long-term, the internet's
not going to come and try to shut you down.
The point you bring up here about wanting to
build a positive thing, some people, sometimes
I get criticism. It's not actually that often, but
they say, "Oh, you're building an app that makes
teens feeling insecure or anything." But with
Gas, I think we received a message every single
day from a user telling us that they reconsidered
suicide or other forms of self-harm. The app sent
you positive messages and affirmations. It made
teens feel really good. And I think that is lost
on a lot of people. Instagram can make you feel
jealousy and a lot of other social networks are
a mixed bag in terms of impact. But we were
entirely focused on making teens feel better.
And some people might say, "Oh, what if
someone doesn't get voted for something?"
We actually built a system to ensure everyone
got a vote. And what we did was we put your
name in polls at a higher frequency if you
weren't being voted on recently. So we wanted
to spread the love in every way possible, and
that's what really motivated me to grow this
thing was watching how it was impacting 10
million kids in such a short period of time.
I really appreciate you adding that. I didn't know
all those things about the way you thought about
these apps. Interestingly, I don't know how much
you can go into this, but there is a lot of stuff
going on with Gas around human trafficking and all
this stuff where people thought people were being
kidnapped through Gas, which is yeah, talk about
that whatever you can because that's pretty crazy.
We had this hoax started where people were
saying the app was used for human trafficking.
And I was like, "This is so strange." This is
a anonymous polling app without messaging and
the only thing you could do is send compliments
to your friends. And I researched into it and I
saw that this is actually plaguing a lot of
apps and any app that has gone viral in any
way has actually had this hoax started.
And part of the reason it happens is it
gets you attention if you say that about
an app. As a teenager, if you say, "Oh,
this app is dangerous," and then you get a bunch
of followers and who doesn't love followers?
So it's actually a really viral piece of
content if you put it out. And so we had
this hoax started and we were like, "This could
kill the company." And I talked to a bunch of
founders that it happened to them and they said,
"Yeah, we had to shut down because of that."
Wow.
And I was like, "Is this it? Is this the
end of the company?" And I remember it hit
number one when we started getting a few of these
reports in our support channels. And I was like,
"I'm just going to plant the flag on posts that
we hit number one in the App Store because this
thing's probably going to shut down soon."
So I make this announcement on Twitter,
"I just made the number one app and I thought it
would just be dead in a week." And then I just had
this sudden burst of energy and I was like,
"I'm going to win. I'm going to fight this.
This is not true. It makes no sense at all."
And so we fought it at every vector possible,
this completely made up hoax. We met with
journalists, reporters to make sure that
the number one match every time you search Gas
app human trafficking was Gas app is not for
human trafficking. And so that ended up being
The Washington Post headline. We insisted that
that be the headline if we do the interview. So
that was the first thing that showed up on Google
anytime someone searched it. There were schools
and even a police station that posted that this
app is used for human trafficking. I called those
superintendents, I called those police chiefs
and have got them to publicly retract it. And we
had some of the reviews on the App Store. We asked
Apple to remove them because we got review bombed.
But the thing that actually was the most impactful
was my girlfriend made a video, a TikTok video
explaining that it's not true. And anytime someone
deleted their account, they could watch this
video explaining it's not true. And at the peak,
we had 3% of users deleting their accounts per
day. So it was like a catastrophe for an app
and we got it down to 0.1% through relentless,
relentless effort. And it was really just an
unusual thing that happens when you grow really
fast is this human trafficking hoax that starts.
And you don't understand how crazy it is until
it happens to your company, but it was kind
of hilarious to think about. This app was the
most harmless benign thing you could think of.
This is insane. I did not know this full
story. And you were doing all this while
you were trying to scale the app and trying
to keep the servers up and try to grow it,
right? What was that like to try
to manage all these things at once?
I was sleeping three hours a day for three
months. It was extraordinarily difficult to
do it all. Our team was also relentless though.
They would come over to my house 9:00 a.m. stay
until midnight and just do that seven days a
week. So yeah, it was definitely one of the
most physically draining things ever, but we were
just so tactical. I remember investors were asking
to meet with us and I said, "If you can't get
a celebrity to post that this isn't true, then
we're not interested." But yeah, we went after
it on every vector and it ended up being okay.
I love how you took your brain to this
other completely different problem and
thought about all the levers you could use
to change the conversation around the app.
Yeah. I remember we had these TikTok videos
that were made that were saying it was true
and I networked my way all the way to the CEO
of TikTok and I said, "Can you delete these?"
And we got this information deleted. Yeah, so
it was really a whole new test of our team's
capacities was fighting. The key thing that
you have to know though when you have a hoax
spreading about your app is you really have
to make sure the hoax is less viral than your
app. And at a few points, the hoax was more
viral than our app and we had to take this-
The K-factor of the hoax.
Yeah.
That's absurd. Okay. So broadly, you built this
app. Again, a big success. I saw a stat that
you made $11 million in sales through the
app, 10 million downloads. Is that right?
Yeah. It was a blowout success in terms
of like it grew bigger than tbh. We
monetized it. We ran almost entirely on
startup credits, so it was basically-
Like Cloud Credits? Like AWS Credits?
Yeah. AWS Credits, Mixpanel. I remember when I
saw the early data, I'm like, "Okay, now it's
time for me to negotiate every bill down to the
last cent of margin for every vendor." And I got
credits everywhere, and so we really were tactical
with that. And so we ended up being all just pure
cashflow for the team. We had no investors. And it
was just so interesting though that the way that
I started posting about it on Twitter was it kind
of captured the zeitgeist of the internet. And we
didn't intend on selling it. We were just going to
let this thing run its course and just be this app
that kind of lives in the background of our lives.
But once it started capturing the zeitgeist of
Twitter, I was like, "Wait a minute, we could
probably sell this thing." And that's when we
started engaging with some of these, we ended
up getting three companies that wanted to buy
it. I won't be able to say them, but ultimately we
ended up selling to Discord and we joined Discord.
Awesome. So before we move on to the next part of
the journey and some of the other insights that I
want to get into, is there any lasting lessons
that you took away from Gas as a product that
you take with you to advising startups in terms of
building the product design? I know there's many,
but any that stand out most that you
think are really interesting to share?
I think I kind of touched on this before, which
was trying to validate things in a sequence
of like, will people use the core flow? Will
people spread it within their peer group?
Will it hop peer groups? And what I think the
most important thing that I learned is that's
actually a really great way to do zero to one
product development is execute at 100% for the
thing you're trying to validate at that specific
stage of the product development cycle. And then
you can kind of half-ass the rest just so
you can get 100% signal on that one part.
And so we made the polling experience
just perfect. The questions were great.
Push notifications, everything worked. And
then the next stage was getting sharing and
virality working. And so compartmentalizing
those things because ultimately you'll have
too much scope creep if you try to solve
everything at once and validate. And also
you're not going to get signal too, like you're
trying to test one thing at a time. So the way
that now I approach a lot of consumer
product development is if this is true,
then what next needs to be true for this thing
to work out? And these layers of conditional
statements. And the more layers you have, the
higher risk your product is, so you should try
to condense it to about like four things
that must be true for the thing to work.
And this comes back to your advice of
the thing you need to get good at is
testing and learning and making it really quick.
Yeah.
Okay. Maybe one last thing along this
thread. I'm just really curious how
this hoax came to be, like who's
behind it? How does this happen?
We got a original support message, which was
a screenshot of a story on Snapchat and it
said, "Do not download the Gas app. It's for human
trafficking." Okay? And it was a screenshot that
had like that mirror effect where you have
like 10 people that screenshotted it. More,
like 40 people because it had all the usernames.
So I was looking at this and I'm like, "How many
people have seen this?" And it looked like a viral
thing on Snapchat. And then I went to the App
Store page and I saw a review that said this app
is for human trafficking. And I went to my team
and I said, "This will probably kill the company.
This will kill the product. I've seen this before
with consumer apps and it's evident to me this is
going to be 10 times bigger tomorrow." And they
were like, "No. It's just one message. What do you
mean?" I'm like, "No, no, it's been screenshotted
40 times and now it's on the App Store page."
And we got another message four hours later.
And the next day, it was our entire App
Store page was just covered with reviews
saying that the app's for human trafficking.
And we actually had to rebrand the app. We
relaunched it once and we're like, "Let's just
call it something different. Just relaunch it on
the other side of the country." We did that,
started going viral again. And the craziest-
... again. And the craziest thing was it
re-emerged and what happened was one user was
friends with another person in another state and
they got an invitation. And that user told them,
"Oh, that was in my state. It's actually
for human trafficking." And then it just
completely started again and then it
was too late at that point to relaunch
again. We just realized, " We got to
fight this thing." And ultimately,
I don't think we'll ever know the true origin, but
it was definitely a living, breathing like hoax.
That is insane. The story just gets more
and more interesting. What were some of
the previous names, by the way?
Is that something you can share?
Yeah, we went through a bunch. One of them
was called Crush, one of them was called Melt,
and another was... The interesting thing
about Crush is we got a great domain. We
thought this would be the name. This was between
some of the re-brands. We tested it and we saw
that invitations dropped significantly
under the Crush name and we were like,
"What's going on here?" And we found that
actually when you invite someone to an app,
regardless of the app, you generally... Boys
invite boys, girls invite girls to apps. And
boys didn't want to invite their friends
to an app called Crush with a pink icon.
And then we looked at the data and
the app. I mean this was true TBH too,
which was the app indexed about 60 to 65% women.
So we were just like, "Let's make the app more
masculine and see what happens. We need balance
on this." So we made the icon black with a flame,
called it Gas and the invites rate jumped. And
you think a name doesn't matter, but right at
the moment of sending an invite... So that was one
of the interesting insights on the naming process.
Man, there's just endless stories that we could
keep getting into, but we've also gone very long,
so I'm going to try to move on to another
topic. So I ask people on Twitter what to
ask you? Just that question got a thousand
likes just me asking, "What should I ask
Nikita?" And the most common question, I'm sure
you get this a lot, is just people wondering,
do you ever want to build a durable consumer app?
Is it possible to build a durable consumer app?
Scott Belsky asked this, Robert at Figma asked
this, and Scott actually had a really nice way
of describing it about why are so many quick
sensation consumer apps proving to be more akin
to summer songs than enduring standalone products
and businesses? So there's kind of two questions
here. One is, do you aim to build a durable
consumer app? And two, how possible is it?
A lot of the fundamental tools for communicating
with our friends either messaging or broadcasting
one-to-many like on stories or the incumbents
have built pretty large motes in terms of
network effects and to provide true an
order of magnitude better experience is
non-trivial because they've been actually
improving these products so much over the
years and there's not that many entry points.
Not to say that it's not impossible. Snapchat
was showed that there was style of messaging that
people wanted that the incumbents weren't serving.
But I think there's these kind of edges that
you can go after with a much higher probability
of success and they might not actually be
something that's durable necessarily. And
I think finding durability for a communication
or social product, that's a black swan event.
Retention for consumer social is there's a
tremendous amount of randomness. There's one
every decade. If it was simple, I would
just be printing $1 trillion companies.
I be printing Facebook's every time I sat down.
But I think it's actually a lot of it is pure
randomness. On the other hand, growing a
product can be a science. With certainty,
if you're good at your job, you can make an
app grow and go viral. Now why haven't I tried
to take the viral part and build something
that has been durable or long-lasting? I'll
tell you a little bit about my motivations. My
favorite part about product development is you
make this thing through the night. You build
it and you watch it take over the internet.
That is the most thrilling drug I think you could
ever experience. And just watching it spread all
over the country is like you drop an app in the
deep south in Georgia and then you look on your
analytics dashboard and 40% of the high school
down your street in Los Angeles has downloaded
it one week later. That's a really profound
feeling. It's crazy to have that sort of impact
as a three-person team, and I live for that.
When I joined Facebook, here's an interesting
connection. So I joined Facebook and I saw
that many of my peers were looking up to VPs
and they're like, "That's what I want to make it
to one day. I want to run a large organization. I
want to have lots of reports." And then I met
with VPs and they were actually jealous of me
because my quality of life was actually pretty
cool. I got to build something high impact that
made many teens feel better about themselves,
made a decent amount of money. And then I wasn't
in charge of this becoming a people manager that
has to run this large organization for many years.
I think one day I will run maybe a venture scale
business, but I will say that I kind of like the
way that I've been doing things so far in terms
of quality of life and being fun. Financially,
it's been great. So I think that
part is what motivates me. And yeah,
I don't think running a large corporation
is necessarily what I described as fun.
That's amazing, man. I am really happy we
went here. So much of this resonates with
the way I think. And obviously, a big part of
this is also just it's very hard, as you said,
to build a consumer app that grows first
of all. Second, that actually lasts. But
that is interesting that you do hope to
one day build a venture funded business.
I mean TBH was venture backed, but I just
don't... I think I'm going to have to...
Do I want to sign up for 10 years?
And if you actually look at some of
the numbers on the actual proceeds that
some of these founders get after an IPO,
after seven rounds of dilution, a lot of
them are pretty comparable to what we get
from our apps for 90 days of work. So yeah,
the trade-offs there are pretty faithful.
Actually, just on that note, so what
would make you actually decide to
go venture funded? You talked about
how if you're going more mainstream,
non-teens folks after 22 years old,
is that why you would go that route?
I don't think that it's necessarily that part.
I think if I could keep the team lean and scale
up... I think there's some actual founders
that actually operate very lean teams and
have reached very large scale in terms of the
valuations of the company. Actually the most
iconic example is Elon Musk. His teams are
actually pretty thin overall and he's in the
weeds doing product development. And so I think,
yeah, if I was to ever do it, I would do it under
very specific set of operating principles
versus turning it into a big tech company.
Queue investor is emailing you right
now with term sheets. Okay. Nikita,
this has been amazing. There's one last segment
I want to spend a little time on, which is just
kind of a rapid fire of pieces of advice you've
shared that I think is incredibly insightful about
how to build a successful consumer app. And
so I'm thinking I'll just go through three to
five and see what you think and see what you
can add to the advice. How does that sound?
Sounds great.
Okay, cool. So the first is just
contact permissions in iOS 18
changes the game and how people can grow
apps basically makes it harder to invite
your friends. Thoughts on how people should
be thinking about this in their products.
When I first saw it, I was really concerned.
I saw your tweet about it. You're
like, "That's the end. Game over."
Just let me frame things up for
you. The contact permissions screen,
you average about 65% approval rate across all
apps. It's higher for teens, lower for adults,
but if you have a 65% consenting to contacts
access, then the next step on this new iOS
18 change is you select which contacts you
want to allow the app to access. And it's
an alphabetical list. And that alphabetical
list for me, I have 550 contacts or something.
The first 10 contacts are punctuation symbols
from whatever dirty entry I put when I was
driving or something. So you have to scroll
down and find that name. So I have to find
Lenny. I have to add you. And what if you're not
an app user? So I just added you or three others.
Assuming users are willing to even do that.
You and then the three others never sign up,
but maybe three of your friends do.
But I never get connected to them
because there's no over... So my expectation is
it's going to be very difficult to find friends
on apps going forward to invite friends on
apps going forward. And that founders will
need to rethink how they do it. And of the
companies, I'm working with on intro, we are
looking at ways to reinvent what contact sync is
or what purpose it served. It's not promising,
but we have some good leads and I think we'll have
a whole new set of apps emerging as a consequence.
But if you're betting on contact sync as a company
right now, you better start thinking about plan B.
So what I take away here is just it is now
much different and there's an opportunity
to think of something really clever that would
give you a huge advantage if you can crack it.
Yes, but most likely I think most apps will
not have social graphs going forward and this
will entrench incumbents even more. I don't
think Apple acknowledged that. I think the
person that designed the feature probably
has never built an app or done contact
sync before because the flow is egregiously
bad and it doesn't actually even, I think,
benefit the user's privacy because it just
completely eliminates the feature altogether.
Okay, next topic. So you helped this product
called Dupe succeed. It's doing incredibly
well from what I can see. And I saw you
tweet about one of the key things that
you helped them through, which is
to invert, I'm reading this quote,
"Inverting the time to value so that the user
experience is the aha moment in seconds." Talk
about that insight and how important that is
to building a successful consumer social app.
This kind of concept of getting users to the
aha moment is something I recurringly bring
up to every company I work with. And you have to
understand that in 2024, people's attention spans
are like three seconds. It's really sad, but we
are spread thin through so many notifications,
products, everything that if you can't
demonstrate value in the first three seconds,
it's over. And this also leads back to the
contact sync question that you talked about
was you have to sign up and then the first night
you have to see all of your friends on the app and
experience it, otherwise you'll churn.
So this idea of inverting the value,
when I was working with Dupe, they had this kind
of shopping app that had a bunch of different
features and there was one feature that I saw that
was interesting called Deal Hop and it allowed you
to just put in a product page and it would find
the cheapest version of it online. Something
I already do through a bunch of duct taped
methods of Google image search, Google Lens. And
I was like, "That should be a whole company.
But how are we going to teach users to do it
and how do we expose them to that aha moment
as fast as possible in a memorable iconic way?"
I had this product I built a while back where you
just type the domain in front of an existing URL.
So I told them, "You should try this. It's very
marketable, but you need to get a very short
domain that matches what you're doing." And so
he went out and bought Dupe.com for I don't know
how much, but when he bought that I was pretty
excited. I'm like, well, if this doesn't work,
I'm going to feel terrible, but if it does
work, it's going to be a blowout success.
So we put out a couple videos about it and then
it was iconic, went viral, the videos. Users
remembered to do it, to type dupe.com in front
of a URL. Now I think they're making millions
in ARR in a matter, and I think under 60 days of
launching. And that was a blowout success. And of
the companies I work with, I would say it happens
about 50% of the time we hit that much success,
but we hit success. I think 50% of the time it's
outright failure because consumer is so random.
And so what I'm hearing is a big
insight is just ideally get to
three seconds time to value. Is that the advice?
Yeah.
Sounds great. Easy peasy.
Yeah. You really have to craft
onboarding everything to ensure
that that's where the design part comes
in of being a great product person.
I imagine a big part of this is just cutting
things you think... Like killing your darlings,
cutting things you think people need and
just being really ruthless with that,.
Really ruthless, but also being extraordinarily
creative with how you use the tools available to
activate a user. I think extraordinary product
people are deeply aware of every possible API
and how it can be used in non-traditional ways.
Like this URL trick was something that I think
was non-traditional that people adopted very
quickly. I have a whole laundry list of iOS
mechanisms that people use for a certain
way today, but you could invert them.
Contact sync is a great example because you
sync your contacts and then it finds all the
friends and then ranks the people who are not
on the app yet but have a bunch of friends
on it. So there's a bunch of ways that you can
one tap, expose a ton of value to users that I
think founders often neglect. A lot of founders
will go and say, "Oh, they can just exchange
usernames and that's how they can add each other."
That is the most unrealistic thing ever because
that means you have to see the username, type it
into the app. You have to do that what 50 times to
get a 50-person friend list. So we're looking
at 10,000 taps versus one. So that's what I
mean by trying to get people to the activation
moment, the aha moment and get them to value.
I love that advice. So maybe as just a last
question along these lines. When you come to
a founder, a relationship that you're a startup,
you're trying to help, is there one more thing
that you find often ends up being really helpful
to them? Any common piece of advice that's like,
"Oh, this is probably what's going to help
you." You talked about this aha moment step,
the contact sharing stuff. I guess is
there anything else that's just like
this is something that's probably
going to help you with your app?
Right now, I think I advise around 35, 36
companies and all of them are at different
stages of challenges they're facing. Some of
them are pure at the product concept stage.
Some of them are venture backed billion-dollar
companies and each of them faces different
problems. The first thing I often do is I ask
them to show me the analytics. We look at how
people are distributing the app today, what is
the milestone that a user must hit to become
activated and what's getting in the way of that?
I also take a very deep look at every funnel
that users come through. And I think a lot of
founders separate marketing and product growth,
like top of funnel growth from the
actual products growth mechanisms, but
they're both the same. They both should be
treated as the same. If you're targeting a
community and you want them to all adopt
and get saturation, you need to build
marketing that shows imagery of that community
or whatever. And then when you get in the app,
you have to be able to join that community.
When you invite people from that app,
that community needs to be mentioned. You need
to actually cover everything from the ads to the
in-app experience. All of that needs to be aligned
for a user acquisition and flywheel to spin. A lot
of people really screw that up. That's my initial
rough approximation of what I do when I come in
and try to fix or try to help with some of
the challenges these companies are facing.
So this is actually a great segue to the final
thing I want to make sure people understand is
you help companies through this. Talk about how
you work with companies where they can find you,
what kind of companies you're looking
to work with and how all that works.
So I work across the gamut. Most of them are
consumer mobile companies and there certainly
are web ones too, but I work with companies
across stages. Typically, I recommend that
you don't book me unless you're venture backed
because it's a little expensive. But my main goal
when someone does seek my advice through intro
is I try to make them 10 times back their money
in the first 30 days. And so far I think I've
managed to do that with anyone who's met with
me. And that means get all the table stakes,
grow things out of the way, at the minimum.
Then identify two to three step function changes
that could change their growth trajectory. And
these are higher scope fundamental changes
to the product. So I try to couple both,
explain to them which direction I believe
they should go, and it's a conversation and
we talk about it. And then once they settle on
a direction, I tend to get in the pixels. I go
into Figma and we do a live session together and
clean things up. I identify, "Oh, that's going to
convert at this percent." And then I just manage
all that. But yeah, it's generally post-series A.
Some seed stage companies, and it's been really
fun. It's kept my mind sharp on where the market
is headed. I've also, over the years of building
all these apps, I've accrued all these growth
hacks that still nobody knows about. And so I
share those when it's relevant for the company
and it's been great. Dupe was one of them. I
was advising Saturn. I rebuilt their Friend
Finder. I think believe they're number one in the
productivity section above ChatGPT as of today.
But I think I've generally invested in about maybe
10% of the companies that seek out my advice.
Amazing. Well, I know it feels expensive to
some people, but if I were a company with cash,
it feels like the best deal I could find someone
like you to come in and actually help me think
through deeply in the pixels how to make my thing
work. So I think you're still undercharging and I
hope you keep raising your prices because
clearly there's a lot of demand. Nikita,
this was incredible. I feel like people see
you on Twitter and they're like, "Oh, this guy,
he's such a jerk sometimes." But meeting you
in person and talking to you, it's very clear.
You're really a kind dude, really thoughtful. All
your advice is based on real things you have done.
It's not just you sitting around pontificating
and I think that's incredibly valuable and I'm
excited. People are tapping that knowledge and
you're sharing it with people in a wider scale.
It's been a pleasure. Thanks
for having me. We covered a lot
and there's plenty more. I hope to
come back after the next viral hit.
Oh man. So I was going to ask you,
is there anything you're working on
now or stages, what can you share?
[inaudible 01:37:33]. Stay tuned.
Stay tuned.
Here we go. Amazing. I always ask
people how can listeners be useful
to you? So let me just ask you that as a final
question, how can listeners be useful to you?
Follow me on Twitter and enjoy my shit posts.
And I hope you have as much fun as me on Twitter.
I do, man. I love your tweets. Nikita, thank
you so much for doing this and for being here.
Yeah, thanks a lot.
Bye, everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.