Not only are you working at the
cutting edge of AI and LLMs,
you're actually building the cutting edge.
When I first came to Anthropic and I was like,
"Oh my God, I really love front-end engineering."
And then the reason why I switched to research is
because I realized, "Oh my God, Claude is getting
better at front-end. Claude is getting better
at coding. I think Claude can develop new apps."
What skills do you think will be most valuable
going forward for product teams, in particular?
Creative thinking and you kind of
want to generate a bunch of ideas
and filter through them and not just
build the best product experience. I
think it's actually really, really hard
to teach the model how to be aesthetic
or really good visual design or how to be
extremely creative in the way they write.
What do you think people most
misunderstand about how models are created?
When you taught the model, some of the
self-knowledge of you actually don't
have a physical body to operate in the physical
world, the model would get extremely confused.
Today my guest is Karina Nguyen. Karina is an
AI researcher at OpenAI where she helped build
Canvas, tasks, the o1 chain-of-thought model
and more. Prior to OpenAI, she was at Anthropic
where she led work on post-training and evaluation
for the Claude 3 models, built a document upload
feature with 100K context windows and so much
more. She was also an engineer at New York Times,
was a designer at Dropbox and at Square. It's very
rare to get a glimpse into how someone working on
the bleeding edge of AI and LLMs operates and
how they think about where things are heading.
In our conversation, we talk about how teams
that OpenAI operate and build products,
what skills she thinks you should be building
as AI gets smarter, how models are created,
why synthetic data will allow models to
keep getting smarter and why she moved
from engineering to research after realizing
how good LLMs are going to be at coding. If
you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. It's the best
way to avoid missing feature episodes
and it helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you Karina Nguyen.
This episode is brought to you by Enterpret.
Enterpret unifies all your customer interactions
from Gong calls to Zendesk tickets to Twitter
threads to app store reviews, and makes it
available for analysis. It's trusted by leading
product orgs like Canva, Notion, Loom, Linear,
monday.com, and Strava, to bring the voice of the
customer into the product development process,
helping you build best-in-class products faster.
What makes Enterpret special is its ability to
build and update customer-specific AI models that
provide the most granular and accurate insights
into your business, connect customer insights
to revenue and operational data in your CRM or
data warehouse to map the business impact of
each customer need and prioritize confidently,
and empower your entire team to easily take
action on use cases like win-loss analysis,
critical bug detection and identifying drivers
of churn with Enterpret's AI system, Wisdom.
Looking to automate your feedback loops and
prioritize your roadmap with confidence,
like Notion, Canva and Linear? Visit
E-N-T-E-R-P-R-E-T.com/Lenny to connect
with the team and to get two free months when you
sign up for an annual plan. This is a limited time
offer. That's Enterpret.com/Lenny. This episode is
brought to you by Vanta. And I am very excited to
have Christina Cacioppo, CEO and co-founder Vanta,
joining me for this very short conversation.
Great to be here. Big fan of
the podcast and the newsletter.
Vanta is a longtime sponsor of the show,
but for some of our newer listeners,
what does Vanta do and who is it for?
Sure. So we started Vanta in
2018. Focused on founders,
helping them start to build out their
security programs and get credit for
all of that hard security work with compliance
certifications like SOC 2 or ISO 27001 today,
we currently help over 9,000 companies, including
some startup household names like Atlassian,
Ramp and LangChain start and scale their
security programs and ultimately build trust
by automating compliance, centralizing
GRC, and accelerating security reviews.
That is awesome. I know from experience
that these things take a lot of time and
a lot of resources and nobody
wants to spend time doing this.
That is very much our experience,
but before the company and to some
extent during it. But the idea
is with automation, with AI,
with software, we are helping customers
build trust with prospects and customers
in an efficient way. And our joke, we started
this compliance company so you don't have to.
We appreciate you for doing that. And you
have a special discount for listeners,
they can get $1,000 off Vanta at Vanta.com/Lenny,
that's V-A-N-T-A.com/Lenny for $1,000
off Vanta. Thanks for that, Christina.
Thank you.
Karina, thank you so much for
being here. Welcome to the podcast.
Thank you so much, Lenny, for inviting me.
I'm very excited to have you here because not
only are you working at the cutting edge of AI and
LLMs, you're actually building the cutting edge of
AI and LLMs. You recently launched this feature,
which basically... the first agent feature
of OpenAI. I also just did this survey,
I don't know if you know about this. I did
a survey of my readers and asked them what
tools do you use every day in your work
and most use? And ChatGPT was number one,
above Gmail, above Slack, above anything else.
90% of people said they use ChatGPT regularly.
That's quite good.
It's absurd. It wasn't around two years ago.
Yeah.
Also, we're recording this the week that OpenAI
announced Stargate, which is this half trillion
dollar investment in AI infrastructure. So
there's just a lot happening constantly in
AI and you have a really unique glimpse into
how things are working, where things are going,
how work gets done. So I have a lot of questions
for you. I want to talk about how you operate and
how you work at OpenAI, where you think things
are going, what skills are going to matter
more and less in the future, and also just where
things are going broadly. So how does that sound?
Sounds great. Thank you so much.
Yeah, I was extremely lucky
to join early days Anthropic and learned
a lot of things there. And I joined OpenAI
around eight months ago. So, yeah,
I'm excited to dive more in into-
Okay, I'm going to definitely ask you about
the differences between those, but I want to
start more technical and just dive right in. I
want to talk about model training. People always
hear about models being trained, these big models,
how much data takes, how long it takes, how much
money toss it takes, how we're running out of
data, which I want to talk about. Let me just
ask you this question. What do you think people
most misunderstand about how models are created?
Model training is more an art than a science.
And in a lot of ways we, as model trainers,
think a lot about data quality. It's one of
the most important things in model training
is like how do you ensure the highest quality
data for certain interaction model behavior
that you want to create? But the way you debug
models is actually very similar the way you debug
software. So one of the things that I've learned
early days at Anthropic was we've discovered
especially this Claude 3 training, when you
taught the model some of the soft-knowledge of,
"Hey, you actually don't have a physical
body to operate in the physical world."
But then at the same time you had data that
taught the model some of the function calls,
which is like, "This is how you set the alarm."
And so the model would get extremely confused
about whether it can set an alarm, but it doesn't
have a body in the physical world. So it's like
the model gets confused and sometimes it'll over
accuse. So sometimes it says, "Look, I don't know.
Sorry, I cannot help you." And so there is always
a balance trade off between how do you make the
model to be more helpful for users, but also not
being harmful in other scenarios. And so it's
always about how do you make the model more robust
and operate across a variety of diverse scenarios.
That is so funny. I never thought about that.
Most of the data that it's trained on is kind
of assuming it's like a human describing
the world and how they operate. It assumes
there's a body and you could do things, and
the model is told you don't have a body.
Yeah.
Okay. I want to talk a little bit about
data while we're on this topic. I know you
have strong opinions here. There's this meme
that models are going to stop getting smarter
because they're running out of data. They're
trained in a large part on the internet and
there's only one internet and they've already
been trained on it, what more can you show
them about the world? And there's this trend
of synthetic data, this term synthetic data.
What is synthetic data? Why do you think it's
important? Do you think it's going to work?
I think there are two questions here. We can
unpack one at a time. But people say we are
hitting the data wall. I think people think more
in the terms of pre-trained large models that
are trained on the entire internet to predict
the next token. But what actually the model is
learning during that process is actually how do
you compress the compression algorithm here? The
model learns to compress a lot of knowledge
and it learns how to model the world. So the
next prediction of the word, like, "Teach me
how to drive," basically. And you only have
a few words that will match that, a car. So the
model actually learns about the world in itself.
So it's like it's modeling human behavior,
sometimes it's modeling... And when you talk
to pre-trained models which are very, very large,
they're actually extremely diverse and extremely
creative because you can talk to almost any
Reddit user through a pre-trained model.
But I think what's happening right now with
new paradigm of o1 series is that the scaling
in post-training itself is not hitting the wall.
And that's because basically we went from raw data
sets from pre-trained models to infinite amount
of tasks that you can teach the model in the
post-training world via reinforcement learning.
So any task, for example, how to search the web,
how to use the computer, how to write, wow,
all sorts of tasks that you trying to teach the
model all the different skills. And that's why
we're saying there's no data wall or whatever,
because there will be infinite amount of tasks
and that's how the model becomes extremely
super intelligent. And we are actually
getting saturated in all benchmarks.
So I think the bottleneck is actually in
evaluations that we don't have all the
frontier, like evals like, I don't know, GPQA,
which is a Google-proof question answering,
PhD level intelligence. The benchmark is
getting to, I don't know, more than 60,
70%, which is what PhD gets. So it's
literally hitting the wall in like evals.
I want to follow both those threads. So the
first is on this idea of synthetic data. Is
a simple way to understand it, that the models are
generating the data that future models are trained
on and you ask it to generate all these ways of
doing stuff, all these tasks as you described,
and then the newer models trained on this
data that the previous model generated?
Some tasks are synthetically curated. So this
is an active research area is how can you
synthetically construct new tasks with models
to learn. Sometimes when you develop products,
you get a lot of data from the product and user
feedback and you can use that data too in this
cross-training world. Sometimes you still want
to use human data because actually some of the
tasks can be really, really hard to teach. Experts
only know certain knowledge about some chemicals
or biological knowledge, so you actually need to
tap into the experts' knowledge a lot. So yeah,
I think to me synthetic data training is
more for product... It's a rapid model
iteration for similar product outcomes. And
we can dive more into it, but the way we made
Canvas and tasks and new product features for
ChatGPT was mostly done by synthetic training.
Let's actually get into that. That's really
interesting. I want to talk about evals,
but let's follow that thread. So talk
about how this helped you create Canvas.
So when I first came to OpenAI,
I really had this idea of, "Okay,
it would be really cool for ChatGPT to actually
change the visual interface but also change the
way it is with people." So going from being
a chatbot to more of a collaborative agent,
and the collaborator is a step towards more
genetic systems that become innovators ultimately.
And so the entire team of applied engineers,
designers, products, research got formed in
the air almost out of nothing. It's just like a
collection of people who just got together and
we rapidly started iterating with each other.
Actually Canvas is one of the... I would say
the first project at OpenAI, where researchers
and applying engineers started working together
from the very beginning of the product
development cycle. And I think there's
a lot of things that we have learned on the
way, but I definitely came with the mindset of,
"We need to do a really rapid model situation
such that it would be much easier for engineers
to work with the latest model possible, but also
learn from user feedback or early internal dog
food. How do we improve the model very rapidly?"
And it's really hard to kind of like figure out
how people... when you deploy a product, how
people would be able to use it. And so the way
you synthetically train the model is physically
figuring out what are the most core behaviors
that you wanted the product feature to do. And
for Canvas, for example, it came down to three
main behaviors. It was how do you trigger Canvas
for prompts like, "Write me a long essay," when
the user intention is mostly iterating over long
documents? Or, "Write me a piece of code," or when
to not trigger Canvas for prompts like, "Can you
tell me more about President..." I don't know,
some of the general questions. So you
don't want to trigger Canvas because the
user intention is mostly getting answer, not
necessarily iterate over the long document.
The second behavior is how do we teach the
model to update the document when the user
asks? So one of the behaviors that we taught
the model is actually have some agency and
autonomy to literally go to the document and
select specific sections and either delete it
or edit, so highlight it and rewrite certain
sections. Sometimes the user would just say,
"Change the second paragraph to be something
friendlier," and we would have to teach the
model to literally find the second paragraph
in the document and change it to a friendly
tone. So basically you teach both how to trigger
edit itself, but also how do you teach the model
to get higher quality edit for the document?
In case of coding, for example, there's also
the question of how good the model is
of completely rewriting the document,
versus having a very specific target edits.
So that's another layer of decision boundary
within edit itself is, "Let's select the entire
document and rewrite completely, or do you want
to have a very targeted custom behavior." And
when we first launched the model, we would bias
the model towards more rewrites because we saw the
quality of the rewrites were much higher. But over
time you are shifting based on user feedback and
what you're learning from iterative deployment.
Lastly, the third behavior that we taught
synthetically the model is how to make comments on
any document. So the way we used that is we would
use o1 model to seem a way of user conversation,
let's say like, "Write me a document
about XYZ." But then we used o1 to
produce the document and then we injected user
prompt to be like, "Oh, make some comments,
critique my piece of writing or critique this
piece of writing that you just made." And
then we taught the model to make comments on the
document on very specific [inaudible 00:17:45] So
it's also what kind of comments you want the
model to make. Do they make sense or not? How
do you teach the quality of that? And it all
came down to measuring progress via very robust
evals. But, yeah, this is how you used o1 and
a synthetic data generation for the training.
Okay, that's so interesting. So you talk about
this idea of teaching the model and you mentioned
how it's using synthetic data to teach the model
different behaviors is a simple way to think about
it. Basically that's where you do that by showing
it what success looks like using basically evals.
Is that the simple way to think about it? Like,
"Here's what you doing this successfully would
look like," and that teaches it, "Okay, I see this
is what I should be doing [inaudible 00:18:31]"
Yeah, great. Yeah, amazing. Yeah, you got it.
Okay, got it. I want to start unpacking
what your day-to-day looks like as you're
building these sort of things. Is
it like you sitting there talking
to some version of ChatGPT, crafting these evals?
Sometimes I do that. Sometimes I do sit with
ChatGPT. Actually, I think I learned this so
much from Anthropic, is people spend so much time
prompting models and where quality's a really bad
batch all the time, and you actually get a lot
of new ideas of how do you make the model better?
It's like, "This response is kind of weird.
Why's it doing this?" And you start debugging or
something, or you start figuring out new methods
of how do you teach the model to respond in the
different way, have better personality, let's say.
So it's the same thing of how personality is made
in the models with those. It's
very similar methods. But, yes,
I think my time at OpenAI have changed. I think
when I first came, I was mostly research IC
work so I was like building a lot of... I was
running code, training models, write evals,
working with PMs and designers to learn, teach
them how to even think about evaluation. I think
that was really cool experience and I think it
was just like an adoption of, "How do we do this
product management of AI feature for our AI
models?" Yeah, but now it's mostly management and
mentorship. I'm still doing IC research code up
to 4:00 PM, although. But I just kind of changed.
All right, don't talk too
much about being a manager.
Okay.
Because everyone's in firing their managers.
"Who needs managers anymore?" That's what I
hear now. Just kidding. It's interesting that so
much of your time was spent on teaching product
teams how evals integrate and how important
it is. And I've heard this a few times and I
haven't personally experienced it yet, so I
think it's an important thread to follow is
just how writing these evaluations is going
to become increasingly an important part of
the job of product teams, especially when
they're building AI features and working
with LLMs. So can you just talk a bit more
about what that looks like? Is it sitting there
with an Excel spreadsheet basically showing,
"Here's the input, here's the output, here's
how good the result was"? Talk about what
that actually looks like very practically.
It certainly depends on what you're developing,
but there are various types of evaluations.
Sometimes I do ask product managers, or there's
also new roles that we have, model designers,
to go through some of the user feedback maybe or
think of various user conversations that should
have triggered... Under these circumstances,
it should trigger Canvas. And then you have
this ground truth label of, "Okay with this
conversation it should look trigger Canvas, under
this conversation it should not trigger Canvas."
And you have this very deterministic kind of eval
that for decision-making behaviors is like this.
When we were launching tasks, for example,
how do you make correct schedules is actually
really hard for the model. But we built out
some of the deterministic evaluations that
is like, "Okay, if the user says 7:00 PM,
the model should say 7:00 PM." So if you can
have deterministic evals whether it's pass
or fail. And the way it works is all the...
Sometimes I ask product managers to just go
create a double sheet, have different
tabs and what's the current behavior,
what's the ideal behavior and why, and some notes.
And sometimes they usually use it with evals,
sometimes we use it for training. Because
if you give the spreadsheet to o1 model,
it can probably figure out how to teach itself
a good behavior. And I think there are second
type of evals that is more prevalent is human
evaluations. And you can have specific trainers
or you can have internal people to when you have
a conversation of the prompt and then you have
various completion of models, you choose the win
rate. Which model is the best? Which model produce
the highest quality comment or edit? And then you
can have continuous win rates. And as you develop
new models it should always win over the previous
models. So it depends on what you want to measure.
So interesting. Basically what I'm hearing,
and there's something I'm learning about as
I talk to people, is product development
might move from this, "Here's a spec PRD,
let's build it together and then cool, let's
review it. Are we happy with this?" From that to,
"Hey, AI, build this thing for me and
here's what correct looks like," and
I'm spending all my time on what does
correct look like on evals essentially.
You definitely want to measure progress
of your model and this is where evals is,
is because you can have prompted model as
a baseline already. And the most robust
evals is the one where prompted baselines get the
lowest score or something. And then because then
you know if you're trained a good model, then it
should just hill climb on that eval all the time,
while not also regressing on other intelligence
evals. That's what I'm saying, it's more of an
art than science. It's like, "Okay, if
you optimize the model for this behavior,
you don't want to brain damage in other areas
of intelligence or..." This is happening all
the time in every lab, in every research team.
I would say prompting is also a way to prototype
new product ideas. Early days at Anthropic
when I was working file uploads feature,
I remember I was just prompting the model to
just... I remember we were launching a hundred
key contexts. I was just prototyping this in their
local browser. I did the demo. People really,
really loved it. And they just wanted API for
file uploads or something. And then that's when
it clicked to me, and also one of the blog posts a
long time ago, it clicked on me prompting is a new
way of product development or prototyping
for designers and for product managers.
For example, one of the features that I
want to do is have a personalized starter
prompts. So whenever you come to Claude, it
should recommend you starter prompts based
on what your interests are. And so you
can literally do it prompting for that.
Mm-hmm. To experiment with that.
Another feature was generating titles
for the conversations. It's a very small
micro experience but I'm really
proud of. The way we did that was
we took five latest conversation
from the model, asked the model,
"What's the style of the user?" And then for
the next new conversation, the generated title
will be of the same style. It's just like
really little micro experiences like this.
That's so cool. Did you do
that at Anthropic or at OpenAI?
At Anthropic.
Okay, cool. I love the file upload
feature that Claude has by the way.
ChatGPT doesn't have that yet, is that right?
I think has the way.
[inaudible 00:26:23]
I think the way it's implement
is very different though.
Okay. Maybe it's the PDF feature, because
I use it all the time with Claude.
Yeah.
Okay.
That's cool.
Somebody needs to get on that. Main, it's wild
how many features you built that I use every
day and that many people use every day. This
prototyping point you made is really important.
It's something that comes up a ton on this
podcast also of how that... is maybe the way
that AI has most impacted the job of product
builders recently is just prototyping instead
of going from showing just like, "Here's a PRD,
here's a design." PMs are more and more just,
"Here's the prototype with the idea that I
have," and it's working. You can play with it.
Yeah.
Yeah. Okay, I want to spend a little more time
on how you operate. So you talked about you
built this in launch of this tasks feature,
is that the way to describe your tasks?
Yeah.
So talk about how that emerged and let's
better understand just how you collaborate
with product teams and how OpenAI works
in that way, whatever you can share there.
I think Canvas and tasks are going into the
bucket of projects where it's more short or
medium terms. And actually the way Canvas
and tasks came about to be was it started
with one person prototyping and creating
a spec. It's kind of like PRD. It's like
creating a spec of the behavior of the model.
I don't think tasks is extremely groundbreaking
feature necessarily. What makes it really cool
is because the models are so general... Model
can now search, they can write sci-fi
stories, they can search for stocks,
they can summarize the news every day. Because
the models are so general giving something
familiar to people that notifications is
very familiar, having reminders is very
familiar. So feeling like a form factor for the
people who are very familiar, same as Canvas,
Google Docs is very familiar, but then you add
magical AI moment and it becomes very powerful.
But the way it comes usually operationally...
Yeah, size is like a prototype, literally
prompted prototype of how you would want
the model to behave. For tasks, for example,
you need to design... Literally design thinking
is like okay, well, if the user says, "Remind
me to go to lunch at 8:00 AM tomorrow," what
information does the model need to extract from
that prompt in order to create a reminder? And so
this is how you design a spec for a new feature,
like a tool. Canvas and tasks are all tools.
So it's like how do you create the tool stack?
And then it's mostly like developing
JSON schema. It was like, "Okay,
from this problem maybe the model should extract
the time that the user requested." And then you
think about which format do you want the time to
be? And then how do you want the model to notify
you is basically the user should give instruction
to the model. And then this instruction would fire
off every day or something at that particular
time. So, for example, if you say, "Every day
I want to learn know about the latest AI news,"
the model should rewrite into, "Okay search for
the latest AI news and this task will get fired
at that particular type that the user requested."
And then your design is like tool spec. Actually,
I don't know. I feel like sometimes it's through
conversations I... Either people ask me to join
the [inaudible 00:30:15] team and they're like,
"Oh my god, we need researchers." Or like,
"We need some support. We need to train the
models," or sometimes. Canvas was mostly
like I just pitched the idea of... It got
staffed quite immediately during the break, so
it's dependent on the project. And then usually
with staffing is mostly a product manager,
model designer, actual product designer,
a couple of researchers and a bunch of applied
engineers. Depends on the complexity of a project.
And then for tasks it took, I don't know, like
two months or so to go from zero to one basically.
Oh wow.
For Canvas this was like four, five months,
I guess, to go from zero to one. And then
you teach product managers how to build evals and
maybe how do we not only ship the better feature,
but how do we think longer term? What kind of
cool features did you want tasks to have? I
think it would be nice for tasks to be a little
bit more personalized. It'd be nice to have
to create tasks via voice on a mobile,
right? This is how you get research
roadmap right here is thinking how the
feature will be developed in the future.
And then from there it's like you
start getting data sets. With evals,
you want to make sure that goes well. And then you
need to have a trade-off between what methods you
want to use. And the reason why I really love
relying purely on synthetic data instead of
collecting data from humans is because it's much
more scalable, it's cheap, less than half. You
literally sample from the model and you teach
the core behaviors of the models and that will
generalize to all sorts of diverse coverage.
And when you launch the beta feature,
you learn so much from the users that
you can... All your synthetic sets can be
shifted in the distribution and how the users
behave on the product behavior. And this is
how we improve. And this is what happened with
Canvass too when we launched from beta to GA.
Okay.
This episode
is brought to you by Loom. Loom lets you your
screen, your camera and your voice to share
video messages easily. Record a Loom and send
it out with just a link to gather feedback,
add context or share an update. So now you
can delete that novel link email that you
were writing. Instead, you can record your
screen and share your message faster. Loom
can help you have fewer meetings and make the
meetings that you do have much more productive.
Meetings start with everyone on the same page
and end early. Problem solved, time saved. We
know that everyone isn't a one-take wonder when it
comes to recording videos. So Loom comes with easy
editing and AI features to help you record once
and get back to the work that counts. Save time,
align your team, stay connected and get
more done with Loom. Now part of Atlassian,
the makers of Jira. Try Loom for free today
at Loom.com/Lenny. That's L-O-O-M.com/Lenny.
Something that I want to help people understand,
and I don't even 100% understand this,
is what's the simplest way to understand the job
of a researcher versus say a model designer and
other folks involved? What's the simplest way
to understand what researchers do at OpenAI?
So the project that I described are mostly
product-oriented. Research is mostly product
research. Another component of my team is actually
more longer term exploratory projects. And it's
more about developing new methods, understanding
those methods under a variety of circumstances. So
basically developing methods, you need to follow
very similar recipe of building evals but it's
much more sophisticated evals. You want to have
outer distribution or if you want to measure
generalization, you need to capture that.
But it is basically more sciencey in a way
where... If we talk about synthetic data, one of
the hardest things about synthetic data is how do
you make it more diverse? Diversity in synthetic
data is one of the most important questions right
now. And so it's like exploring ways to inject
diversity as a general method that will work for
all is one of the research explorations. Other
ones is more developing new capabilities. I feel
like it's always about you work on this new method
and you have signs of life that it's working,
either you think of how do you make it more
general or you think of how do you make it
very useful? And this is how the longer-term
projects become more medium, short-term project.
That makes sense. Essentially working on
developing ways to make the model smarter,
o4, o5, o6. New ways to... o1
was a big breakthrough, right?
Yeah.
The way it operates where it's not
just, "Here's your answer," it actually
thinks and takes time to think through the
process of coming up with an answer. Okay.
Yeah.
Very helpful. Speaking of that, of thinking
about the future, where things are going, I
want to spend some time on just this insight that
basically you are building the cutting edge of AI,
at the very bleeding edge of where AI is going
and where it is. And so I'm very curious to hear
just your take on how you think things are going
to change in the world and how people work based
on where you see things are going. And I know
it's a broad question, but let's say in the next
three years, how do you see the world changing?
How do you see people's way of working changing?
It's a very humbling experience to be in
both labs, I guess. To me when I first
came to Anthropic and I was like, "Oh no, I
really love front-end engineering." And then
the reason why I switched to research is because
I realized at that time it's like, "Oh my god,
Claude is getting better at front-end. Claude
is getting better at coding. I think Claude can
develop new apps or something and so it
can develop new features for the thing that
I'm working." So it was kind of like this meta
realization where it's like, "Oh my god, the world
is actually changing." And when we first launched
100K context at that time, obviously I'm thinking
about form factors that's like file uploads were
very natural, very familiar to people. But you
can imagine we could just make infinite chats
in the Claude.ai app, as if it's 100K context.
But because file uploads... It's like form
follows function. It's like the form factor,
the file uploads can enable people to just
literally upload anything, the books, any reports,
financial and ask any task to the model. And then
I remember it was either enterprise customers,
financial customers were really interested
in that. It's like, "Oh wow." It's actually
one of the very common tasks that people do
in that setting. It's kind of crazy to see
how some of the redundant tasks are getting
automated basically by these smart models.
And they're entering the era where, I actually
don't know for example sometimes if o1 gives me
the correct answer or not because I'm not
an expert in that field. And it's like,
"I don't even know how to verify the outputs
of the models." It's because all my experts
know they can verify this. So, yes, so
basically there are trends that are going
on. The first trend is the cost of reasoning
and intelligence is drastically going down.
I had a blog post about this. Maybe
I should update on latest benchmarks,
because at that time everybody was doing one
benchmark and they'd be... quickly saturated
the benchmarks. So I'm like, "Now we need to do
the same plot but with another frontier eval." But
the cost of intelligence is going down because
it becomes that much cheaper. Small models are
becoming even smarter than large models and
that's because of the distillation research.
This happened with Claude 3 Haiku. I was working
with the training on the Claude 3 Haiku and I
realized it was much smarter than Claude 2, which
was way bigger, lots [inaudible 00:39:08]. But the
power of small models become very intelligent
and fast and cheap. We are moving towards
that world. That has multiple implications,
but the news is that people will have more
access AI and that's really good. Builders and
developers will have much better access to AI,
but also it means all the work that has been
bottlenecked by intelligence will be unblocked.
I'm thinking about healthcare, right? Instead
of going to a doctor, I can ask ChatGPT or give
ChatGPT a list of symptoms and ask me, "Would
I have a cold, flu, something else?" I can
literally get the access to doctor almost. And
there's been some research studies around that.
There was a New York Times story about that
where they compared doctors to doctors using
ChatGPT to just ChatGPT and just ChatGPT was
the best of them. All doctors made it worse.
Yeah, that's crazy. Yeah. Yeah, that's crazy,
right? Education I think I would have dreamt
if I had the tool like ChatGPT when I was
young and would learn so much. But it's
like people can now learn almost anything from
these models. So they can learn new language,
they can learn how to build new look apps and
write anything they do want. It's humbling to
have... launch Canvas and bring that thing to
the people, enable them to do something else
that they couldn't have ever before. There's
something magical around this experience.
Education will have massive implications. I guess
like scientific research, I think it's the dream
of any AI research is to automate AI research.
It's kind of scary, I'd say, which makes me think
that people management will stay. It's one of
the hardest thing to... Emotional intelligence
with the models, creativity in itself is one of
the hardest things. So writers, I don't think
people should be worried as much. I think will
alleviate a lot of redundant tasks for people.
This is awesome. Okay, I want to follow this
thread for sure. And it's funny that what you
described as you were an engineer at Anthropic
and you're like, "Okay, Claude is going to be
very good at engineering. This isn't going to
be a potentially career long term, so I'm going
to move into research and AI is going to need me
for a long time to build it, to make it smarter."
I would say we still have... I think
Canvas team has still have really cool
front engineers that are really people
who really care about interaction,
design, interacting experience. I don't
think models are there yet I think if...
But we can get the models to this top
1% of front-ends and things for sure.
So what I want to move on to next along these
lines is just, and this is just speculation,
but what skills do you think will
be most valuable going forward for
product teams in particular? So folks
are listening and they're like, "Okay,
this is scary. What should I be building now
to help me stay ahead and not be in trouble
down the road?" What skills do you think are
going to be more and more important to build?
Yeah, I think creative thinking. You want to
generate a bunch of ideas and filter through them
and not just build the best product experience.
Listening. You want to build something that the
most general model will not replace you. And
oftentimes you build something and you make it
really, really good for specific set of users and
actually the mode is now in your user feedback.
The mode is more in whether you listen to them,
whether you can rapidly iterate. The mode is in
here. I don't think we are yet to... There are
so many ideas, I think there's an abundance of
ideas that you can work on. I wouldn't be
worried. I feel like in fact I just think
people in AI field are like... I wish they were a
little bit more creative and connecting the dots
across the print fields or something like
that to develop really cool new generation
and new paradigms of interactions with this AI.
I don't think we've cracked this problem at all.
A couple of years ago I was telling some people,
I was like, "You want to build for the future."
So it's like it doesn't necessarily matter
whether the model is good or not, good right now,
but you can build product ideas such that
by the time the models will be really good,
it'll work really well. I think it just happened
naturally. For example, at Anthropic the Claude
artifacts... And I feel early days of
Canvas was, back in 2022 before ChatGPT,
writing ideas was our knowledge [inaudible
00:44:36]. But I feel like Claude 1.3 model
itself was not there to have made really extreme
good high quality edits. For example, like coding.
And I feel like I see startups like Kaeser
was doing super well. And that's because
they iterate so fast. They invent new ways
of training models. They move really fast.
They listen to what users like, massive
distributions. Yeah, it's kind of cool.
That's really helpful actually. So what I'm
hearing is that soft skills essentially are
going to be more and more important, powerful.
You just talked about management, leading people,
being creative and coming up with innovative
insights, listening. There's a post I wrote
that I'll link to where I try to analyze
how AI will impact product management. And
we're actually very aligned, and my sense was the
same thing, that soft skills are going to become
more and more important. And the things that
are going to be replaced is the hard skills,
which is interesting because usually people
value the hard skills like coding, design,
writing really well. And it's interesting that
AI is actually really good at that because it's
taking a bunch of data, synthesizing it and
writing, creating a thing, versus all these
fuzzy things around of what influences, convinces
people to do things and aligning and listening,
like you said, creativity, anything
along those lines come up as I say that.
I think it's actually a really, really hard to
teach the model how to be aesthetic or do really
good visual design or how to be extremely creative
in the way they write. I still think ChatGPT kind
of sucks at writing and that's because it's
bottlenecked by this creative reasoning. I
think characterization is one of the most
important... I think for a manager, I feel like...
Actually, AI research progress is bottlenecked by
management, research management. It's because you
have constrained set of compute and you need to
allocate the compute to the research paths that
you feel the most convinced about. It was like
you need to have a really high conviction in the
research paths to put the compute, and it's more
return on investment kind of situation. It's like,
"Okay, I'm thinking a lot about across all my
projects, which projects are higher priority?"
Prioritization and also on the lower level,
"Which experiments are really important to run
right now and which are not?" and cut through
the line. So I was thinking prioritization,
communication, management. People skills like
empathy, understanding people, collaboration.
I think Canvas wouldn't be an amazing launch
if it wasn't about people and I think it's a
wonderful group of people. And I get a chance
to work with people like Lee Byron who's a
co-creator at GraphQL and some of the best Apple
designers. It's so cool to see... and how do you
create this collaboration between people. It's
just something that's still humane, I think.
Let me just follow through a little bit. I
imagine people listening are like, "Okay,
but once we have AGI or SGI it's like it'll
do all this." There's a world where like,
"Why isn't all this done?" I think it's
easy to just assume all that. I'm curious
this idea of creativity and listening,
why you think AI isn't good at it,
other than it's just very hard to train it to
do this well. Is there anything there of just
why this is especially difficult
for AI and LLMs to get good at?
I think currently it's difficult
for many reasons. I think it's still
an active research area and it's something that
I think my team is working on. It's like, "Okay,
how do we teach the models to be more creative
in the writing?" And so I'm thinking this new
paradigm of wise that the models think more
should actually lead to better writing in
itself. But when it comes down to idea generation
or discriminating of what is a good visual design
or not, I feel like it hasn't had learned
examples from people to discriminate it very
well. I do think it's because there are not that
many people who are actually really... It's not
accessible to models to learn from these people I
guess. So I definitely think that's why it sucks.
Yeah, that makes sense. Basically
there's not enough of you yet,
researchers teaching it to do these
things, slash people that have
incredible taste and creativity that can teach
these things. You could argue this will come.
Right.
But we don't need to keep going down that thread.
Let me ask you a specific question. In this post I
wrote, I made this argument that a lot of people
disagreed with that strategy is something that
AI tooling will become increasingly great at and
take over. There's the sense that that's the thing
that people will continue to be much better at and
you can't offload to AI basically developing your
strategy, telling you what to do to win. My case
is, "Isn't strategy, just take all the inputs,
all the data you have available, understand
the world around you and come up with a plan
to win?" It feels like AI and LLM would be
incredibly smart at this. What's your take?
I think so too. I think again, you teach the model
all sorts of tools and capabilities and reasoning
and it's like when it comes down to... For Canvas
right now, it would be very cool for the model
just aggregate all the feedback from users,
summarize me the top five most painful flows
on user experiences. And then the model itself
is very capable of thinking of knowing how it's
been made, figure out how to create a dataset for
itself to train on it. And I don't think that we
are far away from that self-improvement,
models becoming self-improved by...
That, and the part of development, is basically
self-improving. It's kind of like its own organism
or something. Again, like strategies, it's more
like data analysis and coming up with... I think
what models are really good at is connecting the
dots, I think. It's like if you have user feedback
from this source, but you also have an internal
dashboard with metrics and then you have other
feedback or input and then it can create a plan
for you, recommendations even. And I think this
is one of the most common use cases for ChatGPT
too, is coming up with these sort of things.
That makes sense essentially a human can only
comprehend so much information at once and look
at so much data at once to synthesize takeaways.
And as you said, these context windows are huge
now. Here's all the information, what's
the most important thing I should do?
Yeah, same as scientific research. Ideally
the model would be able to suggest ideas,
new ideas, or iterate on the experimental
given the empirical results of the previous
experiments like how do you come
up with new ideas or the methods?
Yeah. Oh, man. Okay, so just to close the loop on
this conversation, this part of the thread is the
skills you're suggesting people focus on building
and leaning into is soft skills like creativity,
managing influence, collaboration, looking for
patterns. Is that generally where your mind is at?
Yeah, I'm thinking a lot about how do we
make organizations more effectively and
I think this is mostly management, I guess.
It's like how do you organize research teams
or generally teams combined... Compose teams
such that they will be at their maximally
succeed or at the maximal performance of what
can possibly... We can literally create the
next generation of computers. It's just the
matter of conviction and the way you manage
through that. It's scaling organizations
or scaling product research, I guess.
Yeah, I think you're basically building
this thing and not efficiently doing it
is limiting the potential of
the human species right now.
Right.
It's mismanagement within the
research team in OpenAI and
Anthropic and some of these other models.
Yeah, it's kind of crazy to think about it.
Holy moly. Okay, so speaking of Anthropic
and OpenAI, you've worked at both. Very few
people have worked at both companies and have
seen how they operate. I'm curious just what
you've noticed about the differences
between these two, how they operate,
how they think, how they approach stuff.
What can you share along those lines?
It's more similar than different. Obviously there
was a lot of... There are some differences always
comes to nuances. I would say culture. I really
love Anthropic and I have a lot of friends there.
And I also love OpenAI and they still have a lot
of friends though. So it's not about enemies. I
feel like there's in AI, it's all like, "Yeah,
they're competitors. There's enemies." It's
actually like one big community of people doing
the same thing. I would say what I've learned from
Anthropic is this real care and craft towards
model behavior, model craft, model training.
And I've been thinking a lot about, "Okay,
what makes Claude Claude and what makes
ChatGPT ChatGPT?" And it's like I still have some
sense of operational processes that leads to the
outputs, to the model. It's the outputed model.
And it's like the reason why Claude has so much
more personality and is more like a librarian... I
don't know. I don't know. I am visualizing Claude
being like a librarian at some point, very nerdy
or something. ... is because I feel like it's the
reflection of the creators who are making this
model. And a lot of details around the character
and the personality and whether the model
should follow up on this question or not.
What's the correct ethical behavior for the
model in these scenarios? A lot of crafts
and curated datasets. This is where I learned
that part of art, I guess, at Anthropic.
I would say Anthropic is much smaller. When
I joined it was, what, like 70 people? When
I left it was tons of people. And obviously
the culture changed so much. I really enjoyed
being early days startup lives, and people knew
each other as a family. But the culture shifted.
I would say that I learned from Anthropic
that they're much better at focusing and
prioritization of... Very hardcore prioritization,
I guess. And they need to do it. But I think
OpenAI's much more innovative and much more
risk-takers in terms of product or research.
Actually, in way your full-time job can be
just teaching the model how to be creative
writers. And it's like there's some luxury in this
research freedom that comes with scale, maybe. I
don't know. I'd say I have much more creative
product freedom to do almost anything, I guess,
within OpenAI, evolve ChatGPT into the vision that
we want. It's more probably bottoms-up, I guess.
Yeah, that's how I was thinking about it.
It feels like OpenAI is more bottoms-up,
distributed, people bubble up ideas, try stuff.
And that leads to more products launching,
I imagine more things just kind of being
tried versus more of a, "Let's just make
sure everything we do is awesome and great and
craft and thinking deeply about every investment."
Right.
That's really interesting. I've never
heard it described this way. Karina,
we've covered so much ground. This is going
to help a lot of people with so many ways of
thinking about where the future's going. Before
we get to our very exciting lightning round,
I'm curious if there's anything else that you
think might be helpful to share or get into?
One of my regrets, I guess, when I was early days
at Anthropic was that... I think there was some
luxury of the time, because pre-ChatGPT,
to actually come in with a bunch of ideas
and prototype almost every day. And I think
that we did a lot of cool ideas like Claude,
and Slack was actually one of the first tool-usey
products. It's like Claude could operate in your
workplace now. It's kind of cool because you
can add Claude to summarize the thread. So
maybe you have an entire conversation with
someone and then you want a summary of what
happened you can ask Claude, "Summarize this."
Also, it was really fun to iterate on the model
itself. It's like when you just talk to the model
in Slack forever. It created some social element,
it was kind like [inaudible 00:58:19] and this
Discord, people learned so much about prompting
and how to work with Claude. Actually, one of
the features that was early tasks prototype
is every Monday Claude would just summarize
the entire channel. Or every Friday we'd just
summarize a bunch of channels and give the
news about the organization, or something.
And it's kind of like really cool form factor.
I think thinking about form factor's a really
important question in AI, especially we haven't
even figured out how do we create an awesome
product experience with o-series models. It's like
the paradigm between synchronous real time give an
answer paradigm into more asynchronous paradigm
of agents working on the background. But then now
the question is the agents should build trust
with you, right? And trust builds over time,
which is like with humans. And you start this
collaboration which is why this collaboration
model with you and the model is so important
because you build trust and the model learns
from your preferences so that it can become
more personalized and it will start predicting
the next action that you want to take on
the computer or something. And it's more
predictive, much more... We went from personal
computers to personal model basically here.
Why is it not a thing? That
seems like such an obvious
feature that every LLM should have as
a Slack bot version of them. Is that
a thing I can help you install?
Or is that not a thing right now?
I know that Claude and Slack was
sunset in 2023 or something. I think
it was after ChatGPT was mostly the focus on
customer use cases or enterprise use cases.
Mm-hmm. Bummer.
I think the form factor of Claude and
Slack was kind of constrained a little bit
when you want to talk about new features.
Bummer. I want that.
I know that ChatGPT had Slackbar tools. I
don't know, maybe it will come back sometime.
All right, I would pay for that. Any other
memories from that time of early days?
Because that's a really special place
to have been is early days Anthropic.
Any other memories or stories from that
time that might be interesting to share?
I think the very first launch when we felt...
When click from use, again, was 100K context
launch is when the models could input the
entire book and give you a summary of the
book or something. Or the financial... or
catalog multi files financial reports and
then give you an answer to the question, to very
specific questions. I think there was something
in there that was kind like, "Oh my god, this is a
really cool new capability." Not model capability,
but more like the capabilities that
came from the product form factor
itself rather than the model capability as much.
I think other prototypes that we were thinking
about... There's one part having a Claude
workspaces and it's kind of the same idea of
Claude and I would have this shared workspace
and that share workspace is like a document
and we can iterate on the document. And I feel
like sometimes the ideas, [inaudible 01:01:55]
and they're locked for two
years, just like in this case.
It's interesting, there's these milestones
that kind of open up our view of what
is happening and where things are going.
ChatGPT think was the first of just like,
"Wow, this is much better than I would've
thought." You talked about 100K context
windows where you could upload a book and
ask it questions and have it summarize. I
actually use that all the time. When I have
interview guests and they wrote a book,
I sometimes don't have time to read the whole
book. So I use it to help me understand what the
most interesting parts are. And then I actually
dive into the book, just to be clear. And then,
I don't know, maybe voice was another one where
you could talk to say ChatGPT. Is there any other
moments there that you're like, "Wow, this is
much better than I thought it was going to be?"
Yeah, I think the computer use agents,
like the model operating the desktop. And
you can essentially think of new kind of
experience where the model can learn the
way you browse. And from that preference it
can just browse as just like you. It's kind
of simulated persona. And it's actually
very similar to the idea of like, "Okay,
maybe Sam Altman doesn't have a lot of time. Maybe
I want to talk to his simulation and ask..." Or,
for example, I really appreciate some
of the technical mentorship. Yeah,
cool. But he doesn't have a lot of time
so it's like I really want to ask him this
questions. How do you respond with simulated
environments like this would be really cool.
That's a great place to plug Lennybot,
have one of those. It's trained on
all of my podcasts and newsletters.
Oh, cool.
It sits on many models. I don't
know which exactly they use,
but it's exactly that. And it's not even
me, it's all the guests that have been
on the podcast and on newsletter as
I wrote. And you could just ask it,
"How do I grow my product? How do I develop a
strategy?" And it's actually shockingly good.
Do you feel like it reflects who you are?
Yeah.
Or would it be... Okay.
The best part of it is you can talk
to it. There's an ElevenLabs voice
version that's trained on
my voice from this podcast,
and it's actually very good and people have
told me they sit there for hours talking to it.
Wow.
And somebody told it, "Interview
me like I am on Lenny's podcast,
ask me questions about my career." And he did
a half hour podcast episode with Lennybot.
Oh my god, that's so fun.
It's incredible. Future is wild.
Yeah. I think content transformation is... I would
imagine sometime when you generate a sci-fi story
in Canvas, you can transform this into audiobook
where you have very natural content transformation
of one media to another media. I think one of my
earliest inspiration is one of the last episodes
of Westworld where, I don't want to spoil, but
where Dolores comes to her work at that time and
she comes to this new workspace and she starts
writing a story. And then as she writes a story,
a 3D, virtual reality, starts creating on the fly.
So I kind of want to create that. Kind of cool.
Wow. Speaking of medium,
I guess I was wondering if I should go in
this direct or not, but real quick. Kevin
Weill/Kevin Weill, I don't know exactly how
to pronounce his last name, the CPO of OpenAI.
Kevin Weill, uh-huh.
Is it Weill or Weill?
I think Weill.
Weill. Okay. Okay. Let's just
say that. We'll go with that.
I hope, yeah.
He did a panel at the Lenny and Friends Summit
last year and he made this really fascinating
point that chat is a really interesting interface
for these tools because they're just getting
smarter and smarter and smarter and smarter
and smarter. And chat continues to work as a
paradigm to just interact with them, similar to
a human. You could talk to Albert Einstein. You
could talk to someone not very smart and it's
all conversation still. And so it's a really
flexible way to interact with increasingly good
intelligence. At some point it'll not be so great,
and you were talking about all these ways that
you're adding additional ways to interact. But
it's interesting chat proved to be a really
powerful layer on top of all this stuff.
Yeah, that's real cool. I feel like chat also has
social element which is very humane. It's like,
yeah, you sometimes want to get into group chat.
And having conversations with AI is kind of like
a group chat in itself, as messaging. Actually,
this idea of how do you build features like this?
I see tasks as this general feature that will
scale very nicely as the models would develop
new capabilities themselves. The models will be
able to do better searches and create new... come
up with more creative writing on render, react
apps and like HTML apps. And you can have everyday
new puzzle for you, every day continue the story
from the previous days. It scales very nicely.
You mentioned something as we were getting into
this extra section that we ended up going down
is this idea of the agents using a computer. I
know this is actually something you are going
to launch today, the day we're recording it,
which will be out by the time this comes out,
called Operator, can you talk about this very
cool feature that people will have access to?
Yeah, so I unfortunately did not work on
that, but I'm really, really excited about
this launch. It's basically an agent that can
complete the task in its own virtual computer,
in its own virtual environment. You can do any
literally task like order me a book on Amazon.
And then ideally the model will either
follow up with you which book do you want,
or know you so well that it start recommending,
"Oh, here is the five books that I might recommend
you to buy." And then you hit, "Yeah, help
me buy." And then the model goes off into
its own virtual little browser and complete the
task and buy the book on the Amazon. And then
if you give the model credentials, credit cards,
obviously it comes with a lot of trust and safety,
then it will just complete the thing
for you. It's a virtual assistant.
It's interesting how this just sounds
like obviously this should happen. Why
is this not yet a thing? Which is also
mind-blowing that we're just assuming
this should exist. Just some AI doing things
for you on a computer we just ask it to do.
Yeah.
It's absurd.
It's actually really hard. And I
think you're still cracking this,
but feel like... I don't know if you use
Tuple like a pair programming product.
No.
But at Anthropic we loved pair
programming, so if you used-
Oh yeah, Shopify uses this. I remember
it came up on a podcast episode.
Oh, nice. Yeah, so it is a very cool product
where you can just call anyone at any time and
then share screen and the other person
can have access to the screen or start
literally operating your computer. And it's
very realtime... The allegiance is very...
it's very high quality. And it's just like I
kind of want the same. I want to pair program
with my model and the model should even talk to
me. Draw very specific section in my code and
just go to tell me... Obviously teach me and
we can have different modes. It's like right,
this is a product right here for you. I
don't know. Some people should build that.
It sounds like a startup just got birthed-
Yes.
... from someone listening to this.
You mentioned that it's very hard to
do this agent controlling a computer
as you and helping out. What makes it
so hard for whatever, however
much you can explain briefly?
Much of it is because right now the model's
operating on pixels instead of language or
whatnot. Pixels is actually really, really
hard. The models [inaudible 01:10:25]
perception, or visual perception. I think
there's still a lot of multimodal research that's
going on, but I think language scaled so much
easier compared to multimodal because of that.
Another thing that I guess my team is working
that is how do you derive human intent very
correctly? It's like sometimes does the model
know enough information to ask a follow-up
question or to complete the task? You don't
want an agent to go off for 10 minutes and
then come back with an answer that you didn't
even want. That actually creates much more
worse user experience. And this comes with
teaching the model people skills. It's like,
"What do people like? Kind of like creating
the mental model of the user and care about
the user in order to ask certain questions.
Actually, that part is hard to do for the models.
That relates to what we talked about
earlier where this kind of the soft skill,
people skills piece is not where
these models are strong yet.
Yeah.
Okay. I'm going to skip the lightning round. I
want to ask just one question from
the lightning round, something fun.
Yeah.
Okay, so when AI replaces your job, Karina, I'm
curious what you're... And it gives you a stipend,
gives you a monthly stipend. Here's your
salary for the month. What would you want
to do? What do you want to spend your time on?
What will you be doing in this future world?
I've been thinking about this a lot times. I
feel like I have a lot of jobs options. I would
love to be a writer, I think. I think that would
be super cool. You should write short stories,
sci-fi stories, novels. I really like art
history, so you know those conservationists
in the museums who just try to preserve art
paintings, but just painting through a long day?
Mm-hmm.
I think that would be really cool to do. Yeah.
That sounds beautiful.
I don't know.
What I'm hearing is you need to Nerf these models
to not get very good at writing so that you can
continue... Although at that point you don't need
to do it from... You don't need people to buy it,
you're just doing it for fun, so it doesn't even
matter if they're incredibly good at writing or
art conservation. Oh man, what an episode of
our conversation. What a wild time we're living
in. Karina, thank you so much for being here.
Two final questions. Where can folks find you
online if they want to reach out and follow up on
anything? And how can listeners be useful to you?
You can find me, I'm on Twitter it's KarinaNguyen.
You can also shoot me an email on my website. And
my team is hiring and so I'm looking for
research engineers, research scientists,
as well as machine learning engineers, people
who come from product engineers who want to
learn model training. I'm actually hiring for my
team. My team is called Frontier Product Research,
and we train models, we develop new
methods but for product oriented outcomes.
What a place to work. Holy moly. What's the best
way for people to apply for
these very lucrative roles?
I think you can shoot me a DM on Twitter.
Okay.
Or I'm yet to create a job description for them.
Okay. This is the job description.
Or you can apply into post training team. Yeah.
Okay. You're going to get a flood of
DMs. I hope you're prepared. Karina,
thank you so much for being
here. This was incredible.
Thank you so much, Lenny.
Bye, everyone.
It was fun.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to the show
on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
LennysPodcasts.com. See you in the next episode.