I started noticing that there was a certain
mystique and aura about product strategy.
There was this perception that some people were
intrinsically really good at strategy and others
were not. It was almost as if there was a strategy
gene you needed to be born with to be good at it.
Say someone's sitting down, okay,
I'm going to start developing a
strategy for our product. Where do you
begin? What does this process look like?
In terms of what product strategy is? There
is a smallest flavor of it which focuses on
solving problems, they're called present forward,
and it typically operates in a two-year horizon.
We use a five-stage process to get there and
it takes about eight to 12 weeks. The reason
I think this process works is there is a ton
of alignment built in. It goes back to human
psychology of just something that comes from you,
feels a lot more familiar and easy to accept.
Let's talk about big S strategy. When
should you approach strategy this way?
There's this interesting
quote by Elon Musk, which is-
"Life's got to be about more
than just solving problems."
I think this is true of every sort of
company. There needs to be an aspirational
and cool component to strategy. What does the
product look like in five to 10 years? Why is
the world better in 10 years? And what is
the most exciting version of that view?
Today my guest is Chandra Janakiraman. Chandra
is chief product officer and executive vice
president at VRChat. He was a product leader
at Meta, chief product officer at Headspace,
a GM at Zynga, and a senior PM at Amazon. And
the way this podcast episode happened was an
avid podcast listener, Karthik Suresh, told
me about Chandra at a community meetup. And
when I connected with Chandra, it was clear
that I needed to get him on the podcast.
Chandra is a student of strategy and has spent
his career developing what he calls an operator's
guide to strategy, which essentially pulls
together the best ideas from Good Strategy,
Bad Strategy, Playing to Win, Michael
Porter and others to create a very clear,
reliable and easy-to-follow five-step process
to develop a great strategy and a set of next
steps for your product and company. After hearing
Chandra walk through this in our conversation,
I'm basically going to now point everyone who
wants to get better at strategy to this episode
and Chandra's method. Strategy is at the heart
of every great product and team and business,
and it's also the source of so much pain if you do
it badly. This episode is meant to help you avoid
that. A big thank you to Karthik for making
this connection. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in
your favorite podcasting app or YouTube.
It's the best way to avoid missing
feature episodes and it helps the
podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you Chandra Janakiraman.
This episode is brought to you by Eppo. Eppo is a
next-generation A-B testing and feature management
platform built by alums of Airbnb and Snowflake
for modern growth teams, companies like Twitch,
Miro, ClickUp and DraftKings rely on Eppo
to power their experiments. Experimentation
is increasingly essential for driving growth and
for understanding the performance of new features
and Eppo helps you increase experimentation
velocity while unlocking rigorous deep analysis
in a way that no other commercial tool does.
When I was at Airbnb, one of the things that I
loved most was our experimentation platform
where I could set up experiments, easily,
troubleshoot issues, and analyze performance
all on my own. Eppo does all that and more With
advanced statistical methods that can help you
shave weeks off experiment time and accessible
UI for diving deeper into performance and out of
the box reporting that helps you avoid annoying
prolonged analytic cycles. Eppo also makes it
easy for you to share experiment insights with
your team, sparking new ideas for the A-B testing
flywheel. Eppo powers experimentation across every
use case, including product growth, machine
learning, monetization, and email marketing.
Check out Eppo at geteppo.com/lenny and 10 x your
experiment velocity. That's geteppo.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Airtable
ProductCentral, the unified system that brings
your entire product org together in one place. No
more scattered tools, no more misaligned teams.
If you're like most product leaders, you're
tired of constant context switching between
tools. That's why Airtable built Product Central
after decades of working with world-class product
companies. Think of it as mission control for your
entire product organization. Unlike rigid point
solutions, product central powers everything from
resourcing to voice of customer to roadmapping
to launch execution. And because it's built on
Airtable's no-code platform, you can customize
every workflow to match exactly how your team
works. No limitations, no compromises. Ready to
see it in action, head to airtable.com/lenny
to book a demo. That's airtable.com/lenny.
Chandra, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Pleasure to be here, Lenny.
I want to share actually the context
and how this conversation happened.
I was at a meetup of my readership, of my
community and someone came up to me and they're
like, "Lenny, you need to get this guy Chandra
on your podcast. He's the most amazing playbook
for developing a strategy." He's gone through it
with you at a company he worked at with you once,
and he's just like, "People need to learn
this because it's so good." And to me,
if someone can get better at strategy, it feels
like it just makes so much of the way the company
operates and the way that people work better.
So we chatted, we met, I was like, "I completely
agree. We definitely need to get you on this
podcast to share your approach to the strategy."
So we made this happen, and so we're here. So
again, thank you for doing this and sharing.
Thank you. Thank you, Lenny.
First of all, I wanted to ask just you're very
passionate about strategy and developing a way
to consistently create great strategies.
What got you so interested in this stuff
in the first place? What kind of
sparked your interest in this area?
Yeah, yeah, it's a very interesting story. It goes
back all the way 10 years ago, but I remember it
vividly like it happened yesterday. And I was
a relatively new VP of product at Headspace,
and we had this amazing company vision and
mission that the founders had laid out,
and I had come in and established goals for the
team in terms of our key metrics, and we had a
very buttoned up roadmap in my mind that fed into
that company mission and vision. And I was feeling
pretty good about how things were shaping up.
And on a particular Monday, the founder,
CEO pulled me aside, and in his usual disarming
style, he sort of made a short but profound
statement. He said that, "Hey, CJ, I'm hearing
that a lot of people don't really understand
why we are working on what we are working on," and
that was it. That was really the extent of what he
shared. And it was a little bit of a bubble
bursting moment for me because we obviously
had spent a lot of time building the plan and
I was feeling relatively good about the plan.
And so I spoke to a few people. I sort of
wanted to understand it a little bit deeper,
like, "Hey, what's happening?" And he was
right. He was right. A lot of people didn't
really understand why we were working on the
things we were working on, and it led to some
soul-searching. And basically I was lucky because
there was actually a board member of Headspace
who had a product background, kind of knew what
good looked like, and I came to the conclusion,
"Hey, we needed a strategy for Headspace."
So with extensive work with her, with the
board person, we built the first written
product strategy for Headspace. And that,
and the subsequent actions on the product led
to a complete re-imagination of the product. And
basically we were able to create a new product,
we call it the Next Generation Headspace, which
on one hand it could support a comprehensive
library of content, not just meditation,
but non-meditation content as well. It had the
sort of home experience where everything was
incredibly personalized for the individuals,
and there were several motivational elements
built into the whole product experience.
And it was very transformational for the
company and the product because it changed the
product from being a meditation app to a broader
health and wellness service and really put the
company on a different trajectory. It led to
my promotion to the first CPO at Headspace.
And most interestingly, I had a chance to,
while going through it almost in a sort of out
of body way, observed the process of like, okay,
how did we put this thing together? And what
actually went into it? What really started as
almost a personal crisis moment of finding this
need to create a strategy for a product and a
company led to a bigger sort of quest for
me, which is I started noticing that there
was a certain mystique and aura about product
strategy, and there was this perception that
some people were intrinsically really good
at strategy and others were not. And it was
almost as if there was a strategy gene that
you needed to be born with to be good at it.
And that bothered me a lot, and I sort of wanted
to ask myself, is it possible to break that divide
between the haves and the have-nots and make
this capability widely accessible through a
procedural approach. And I have news for you.
The answer is yes, anybody can build product
strategy through a clear understanding of what it
is and through a friendly and repeatable playbook.
Amazing. That's exactly what I want to do here.
The point you made about the why, I think everyone
listening to this that's been in product for long
enough has heard that of just, "Your team doesn't
understand why we're doing this." I've heard
that a number of times, as much as you think
you're killing it, there's always that, you forget
sometimes to do that or you aren't doing it great.
And I love that basically the solution to that
is the strategy solves that problem of helping
people connect the dots and understand why
this is the roadmap, why this is the strategy.
Okay, so before we get into it, just one more
context question, what's just the best way to
think about what you're about to share and also
who's it for? Who needs to hear this briefly?
So the way to think about this, the substance
is that this is not a new framework or theory
that I'm going to be talking about. There are
plenty of excellent materials on strategy from
ancient texts like The Art of War from
Sun Tzu, all of Michael Porter's work,
Good Strategy Bad Strategy by Richard
Rumelt, who's been on your podcast,
Playing to Win Lafley and Roger Martin. So there's
a ton of extensively researched and well-founded
materials out there. So the way I would think
about this is, it's more of an operator's
interpretation of all the stuff that's out there
and are able to package it into something that's
friendly and repeatable, particularly for
product people who think they are weak at
strategy or perhaps have received such feedback.
And just in terms of the battle-tested nature of
it, I personally use this playbook about
five to six times tweaking and optimizing
it each time based on what I thought worked,
what people thought worked and didn't work,
including several times at Meta and
usually leading to strong results, both
for me achieving senior leadership alignment as
well as driving business results for the company.
Okay, I'm getting more and more excited.
Let's get into it, let's get into this
playbook. People hear this word strategy
a lot. They're told be more strategic,
build a better strategy. What's the simplest
way to understand what is a strategy?
Yeah, let's start with some basic definitions,
which is as you asked, what is product strategy?
And if you think back to the Headspace example,
this sort of comes to life as well. So product
strategy, strategy sits between the mission and
vision and the plan. It could be at the company
level or at the team level, but it's usually
sitting between the mission and vision and the
plan. And the plan, you can call the plan the
roadmap, which is basically an ordered list
of things that you want to get done and the
mission and vision is basically sort of the
purpose of existence, what does it look like when
you achieve your purpose of existence? So it sits
between the two and it forces choice to deploy
scarce resources to generate maximum impact.
And I want to borrow an analogy from the world of
physics. There is this concept called resonance,
and the concept of resonance is really
interesting, and it's actually very close to the
concept of strategy. So the concept of resonance
works as follows, when you apply a certain
frequency to an object and you get pretty close to
its natural frequency, you see a disproportionate
increase in the amplitude of how that object
vibrates. And so it's very interesting, if you
apply any other frequency, there's very little
effect on the object, but if you get close to its
natural frequency, there's this exponential
increase in the vibration of the product.
So this concept of resonance is interesting.
So the way to think about it in the context of
strategy is, it is selecting that frequency
to achieve resonance between the product and
the market. And so when you get close to that
frequency, you should see tremendous impact in
terms of the product landing well in the market.
And so that's how I would think about it. It sits
between mission, vision and the plan. It
forces choice to deploy scarce resources
to generate maximum impact, so using resonance
as a sort of an example, and it ideally includes
three components. The first is a handful of
areas to focus on and I call these strategic
pillars and then a whole bunch of areas that
are explicitly not the focus. And the third
component is why. So why are the focus areas,
A, B and C? Why are these whole bunch of areas
not the focus? And that's the three components.
That's really it in terms of product strategy.
I love it. And I love the things we
aren't doing as a core part of this,
that comes up a lot on this podcast of
being clear is what we're not going to
do. We know these could be things we could do,
but we're deciding we're not doing these things.
Okay, so let's just talk through how you go
about developing a strategy using this method.
Say someone's sitting down, "Okay, I'm going to
start developing a strategy for our product."
Where do you begin? What does this process
look like? Let's start talking through it.
So I sort of want to first explain
this concept called smallest strategy,
and I'll sort of talk about what that is and how
it's different from another kind. But the basic
sort of strategic process I would say takes about
eight to 12 weeks long. It's something that I
think people often underestimate how long it takes
and eventually end up taking a lot more time. But
when they start off, they think, "Oh, I could
probably stand this up in a couple of weeks,"
but usually through iteration it actually ends
up taking 8 to 12 weeks anyway. So it's good to
start with setting clear expectations that
it takes about eight to 12 weeks. And the
way to justify the ROI on that is typically a
strategy like this can be leveraged for about
a couple of years. So relative to that sort
of payback period, I think the investment
is relatively small. So it's pretty healthy
from that sense to manage expectations and
say that that's how long it's going to take.
So within that period, there are five phases.
There's the preparation phase, there's
a strategy sprint, the design sprint,
the document writing and the rollout. And those
are the five phases, which I'll explain how one
would go through. And basically each of them has a
certain sort of time recommendation. For example,
the preparation phase I would say is probably
about four weeks. The strategy sprint is up to
about one week. The design sprint is another one
week, document writing maybe one to two weeks, and
the rollout is maybe two to three weeks. So that's
how you get to that range of eight to 12 weeks.
Essentially it's like a quarter of work
to get to a final great strategy. And
of these five phases, the biggest bucket
is preparation, which to me sounds like
it's not like a full-time team thing. It's
starting to gather data and user research-
Totally.
As you talk through this, I'm curious just how
much of the team is involved in each of these
steps. But I think it's an important point,
if you want a really good winning strategy,
you need to give a time. You can't just say, "In
a month or a week, we need to develop a strategy,
go figure it out, write this document." Great.
Cool. So let's talk about step one preparation.
That's correct, Lenny. And I think you,
if I forget, remind me that sometimes there
is pressure. There's just business pressure,
like the CEO might still want a strategy in
two weeks, how do you respond to that? And
I think we can find some clever shortcuts
there, but I think to the extent possible,
the leader should push for [inaudible
00:18:39] to make something really great.
And I think part of it is that as a
leader, you can start on this before...
you know this is coming, so you should
get started before it's even asked for.
That's correct.
Yeah, awesome. Okay, let's get into it.
So I think you sort of touched on this in terms
of the preparation phase being the longest phase,
but also not being sort of like a full-time thing.
So that's absolutely right. So the preparation
phase is really... The way to start this, which is
a little different from other approaches I've seen
from people is to actually form a strategy working
group. This is an important concept. So the
strategy working group is sort of a small team. It
typically consists of engineering, product design
and data at a minimum. And in certain cases,
there's a luxury to have other functions like
product marketing, user research, that's also part
of the strategy working group. But the minimum
quorum, I would recommend is engineering, product
design and data because design in some ways
represents both sort of product design and user
research. So you do get the voice of the user from
that perspective. And typically the PM is driving
the strategy working group and the process,
but that working group is actually the team that's
going to collaboratively create the strategy doc.
And so in the preparation phase, there's usually
a kickoff meeting where the PM pulls the team
together, talks about the purpose of the process,
lays out the different phases, and gives everybody
a feel for what's going to happen in the next 8
to 12 weeks. And basically then creates a list of
very discrete action items and deliverables
for each of the stakeholders in the working
group. So specifically, there's an action item
around aggregating all the behavioral insights
that the team might have around the product.
And usually this is a combination of previous
analysis that the team has run on the data side
and potentially also feature launches and how they
have done. So all kind of analytical analysis.
The ask is really to create a meta analysis of
all of the analysis. So the data person on the
strategy working group has to scan the historical
archives at the company and sort of synthesize
and condense that into a very sort of digestible
macro themes and learnings about users. So
that's sort of one preparation phase item.
The second is UXR insight. So again, there's
probably a lot of soft hard signals about users,
not just based on research that's run by user
researchers, but also potentially from the
customer service team, social channels, and
basically a meta analysis of all of that into
one very actionable and synthesized deck on all
the insights on users. That's usually led by the
design person and with support from their research
team. And that's sort of the second action item.
The third action item is leadership interviews.
So I sort of have this fun story of the fruit
with leadership strategy reviews, which I want to
share. So imagine, this is sort of how sometimes
strategy reviews go, which is you bring a fruit
to the reviewer and say, "Hey, here's a mango,
what do you think?" And the reviewer says, "I
actually don't like mangoes." And you're like,
"Oh," you're sort of sad. You take it back, you
bring an apple and you show, "Hey, what do you
think of an apple?" And then the leader says, "I
actually stopped eating apples last year." And so
you're disappointed again. You go back, you bring
a banana. "I hated bananas since I was a kid." And
so it's a bit of a silly caricature of reviews,
but there's a bit of grain of truth there,
which is, imagine how frustrating that is for
both the reviewer and the person who's reviewing.
And so it could be made so much better if you just
engage with your leaders before you actually build
a strategy. It's amazing how few people actually
do that. And so the fruit story tells you, hey,
imagine if you just asked the reviewer, "Do
you even like fruits?" How much better the
experience would've been for both parties. And
so leadership interviews are a very important
part of a strategy formulation process. So you
can divide and conquer, there's several leaders,
like you assign different leaders to different
people on the strategy working group and each
of them sort talks to that leader. And there are
a few questions that I would recommend asking,
and it's basically, what does success feel like
for the leader? What does failure look like? What
is the measure of success? What are principles
to keep in mind while going through this process?
And these are centered around the
product that you're working on?
Exactly.
For Headspace, it'd be like, what
do you think success looks like for
Headspace or the specific feature
of Headspace? [inaudible 00:24:03].
Exactly.
Okay, cool.
That's right, yeah. And also I think ask
them for their favorite or better ideas. It's
actually what I've found through this process
is a lot of leaders have these better ideas,
they just feel shy to share it because they
don't want their teams to think of them as
micromanage-y. They want their teams to figure out
the answer themselves, but then when you ask them,
they actually have a pet idea always.
And so asking them just takes the mystery
out of it. And it also gives them a creative
avenue. So some people feel nervous about
engaging senior leaders in these conversations in
the sense that, hey, is it a waste of their time?
What I've found is the exact opposite, senior
leaders are, they welcome this because one,
it's actually a more fun conversation for
them than the other meetings that they have
in their day because they're getting a little bit
of their creative juices going, and they actually
feel happy that somebody actually asked them
what they're feeling and thinking about. And
so it's actually very, very positive energy
when you ask leaders just what they want. And
it's also not a sign of weakness. It's actually a
sign of strength and humility to ask your leaders
what you want. And so keeping that fruit story
in mind, I want to just say that this is a very,
very positive thing, a very powerful thing.
The next area is competitive analysis. So
if there is a product marketing person,
they can do it for you. If there isn't,
the PM should do it themselves. And basically
the idea is you try to understand who are the
comparables or the competitors in the space, and
you sort of build a little bit of a head-to-head
and sort a stack chart of where's everybody
going and what are of the angles of investment
for different people based on the explicit
signals, which is what are they releasing?
You don't really know what their strategies are,
but you can kind of tell when you look at the
features they're putting out that, oh, they seem
to be focusing on this particular area. And so
that's sort of competitive analysis. And bigger
companies, there's also another important input,
which is adjacent roadmaps. Are the teams adjacent
to you and what are they investing in? Because
oftentimes that can have a rub-off effect on
your team, and if you're not aligning with
other key teams, it's going to be important.
So adjacent roadmaps and a summary of that.
And last but not least, is what I call user
observation. So I like the strategy working
group to actually either interview a user or
watch a video and report key learnings. And
the idea is not to action those insights, it's
really to build empathy. When you get somebody
in the room with a user, it just changes their
mind, it softens them a little bit. It gets them
out of their own preconceived notions of what
to build, what the strategy should be and...
... their own preconceived notions of what
to build, what the strategy should be, and it
humanizes the whole process. That I think
is the purpose, but you still give them
the homework of writing down what they learned
because it's a little bit of a forcing function.
The output of all of this is what I call
the comprehensive preparation readout. It
is a single master deck where you sort of
have the behavioral insights meta analysis,
you have the UXR insights meta analysis, you
have a download of the leadership interviews,
you have the competitive stack charts, you have
the adjacent roadmaps, and you have a section
on user observations. It's a lot of work, but
to your point, it can be done in parallel with
your day jobs. You can multitask, and that's why
you take about four weeks to do that. That sort
of concludes the preparation phase. You get the
deck, and that rolls into the strategy sprint,
which is the next phase. I want to
pause and see if you have any questions.
Yeah, I have a million questions, but I'm
going to keep myself contained. Just to quickly
summarize. Basically you kick off, we're going
to start developing strategy for this product,
and you were going to touch on this, but it
may help just to talk about this right now.
I know you have big S Strategy,
small S strategy. This process,
what's an example of the level of product
scale that this process is for? Because I
know you have another approach for a larger
scale of a product, basically for a company.
What's the best way to think about small S
strategy, which is what we're going through?
Yeah, I think it's a good question, Lenny.
I would say that the process works well at
sort of a growth stage company or in
a vertical within sort of a larger
company. I think it scales pretty well.
The main difference between this small S
and big S is the time horizon aspect and the
aspirational component, which we'll get to.
Okay, so this is a process you can use for
entire company strategy of not a large company,
not a massively, and then also
just a product within a company?
Yeah.
Okay, perfect. Okay. Hey, we're kicking off
strategy for this thing. Let's say VR Chat
2.0. You have this kickoff meeting with your
working group. You assign action items and
there's six things you ask everyone to
do. Gather all the behavioral insights,
all the user research insights that you've had,
leadership interviews, interview people, ask
what they want and see what they're hoping for,
what success looks like, competitive analysis,
adjacent roadmaps across other teams and
user observations, just like watch users,
see what's happening. You assign each of these
tasks to different people in this working group.
You set a deadline. We have to present this in
say, four weeks. People go work on it. You meet
ongoing as it's coming together, and then the
output is a deck that you share. Do you share
this deck with just that working group, or who
do you share this deck with and read it out to?
Yeah. The deck is an output of the first
phase, and then it flows into the second
phase, which is a strategy sprint. You
don't share the deck with anybody yet.
Got it. This is our secret.
In the strategy sprint,
it's like a key thing. Yeah.
Awesome. Okay. I love how very concrete and
actionable this is with time boxes and action
items and the exact output you're looking
for. I love this. Okay, cool. Basically
what you're trying to do here is gather all
of the input that will inform the strategy.
That's correct.
It's giving yourself time to do
this, because if you think about it,
the output is determined by the
quality of your input. I love,
it feels like a core component of this method
is spend time creating, gathering all the input,
all the best input, actually spend time
there. Don't just make it a half-assed last
minute thing. Okay. Amazing. Okay, let's talk
about step two, which is the strategy sprint.
Yeah, so the strategy sprint is the heart of
the process. This is sort of where you make the
decision. If you recall, the definition
of strategy is it forces choice to deploy
resources into a few areas for maximum impact.
The core of strategy is really picking those
areas and the areas you're not going invest
in. That happens in the strategy sprint,
so really it's the heart of the process.
Typically, it's like a three to five day process.
The first day is the share out date. Everybody has
done some great work. They go in, they share what
they've collected, what they've sort of learned.
It brings everybody in the working group to the
same state of understanding, the same state
of consciousness on the state of the union.
That's a great process where what I encourage
people to do is write down things that you are,
as you're listening, write down things that you
find are problems for our users, things that
are coming in the way of our growth and things
that are sort of suboptimal for the business.
People take a lot of notes during that time
and the people who are presenting are sharing
everything they've learned. That's really day
one. It's just absorbing a ton of information and
writing down a ton of notes so people can kind of
understand where all the problems are. It's a very
problems focused process, and that's an important
point. I'll get back to it when we talk about big
S, which is different. Once people have
that common awareness, shared knowledge
of all the problems, day two is literally
the most important day in the entire 8 to
12 weeks because that's where you actually
make the choice. The way to flow through it,
it's actually really important to flow through it
correctly. The first step is really generating a
whole bunch of problems, because people
have been taking notes the previous day.
You start the day with, "Hey, let's collect
everybody's thoughts on what the problems
are that are holding us back." It's a free
flowing session. Everybody throws out their
observations on what's holding us back, and you
just capture all of that in a Google Sheets,
for example. Over even an hour, you start
to see these patterns emerging of like,
there's these clusters of problems that are really
holding us back. The next step is you do a joint
clustering of related problems and you create
these potentially, typically in my experience,
I've seen about 10 to 15 clusters form of
very related problems. The beauty of it is
each of those bigger cluster, you actually know
what the sub problems are within that cluster
because you sort of generated it very organically.
Then you have, let's say 10 to 15 clusters. What
you then do is you, because remember, because
it started as a problem generation exercise,
each of the clusters also has a name that
is a problem, and so the next step is to
flip it into an opportunity framing.
Let me give you a couple of examples.
Let's say there's a bunch of problems
around people don't really know where
to find different things in our product, and
they don't really know where to go, where to
find a certain feature or a certain experience.
There's let's say a lot of problems in that area,
so difficulty finding things becomes the
cluster, the problem cluster and discovery
becomes the opportunity sort of framing of it.
It's sort of the more positive framing of it.
Another example could be that people get a lot
of content that they don't like. They see a lot
of stuff that they don't like, and so they
disengage with the product. The opportunity
framing of that would be relevance. It's
basically stuff that really matters to me.
Maybe if it's a social product, then maybe
people are finding it difficult to find
friends and they are lonely because of that. The
opportunity framing would be social connection.
Flipping all of those problem clusters into
positive framing and opportunity framing is the
next step. Then you're in a great spot because now
all you have to do is you have to down select from
those 10 to 15 opportunity areas into ideally
three, maybe five, but I would recommend three
because it creates more clarity and focus. The
way to do that is really sort of ranking them on,
I would say four or five key dimensions or
criteria, and the first is expected impact.
Let's say you actually tackle that area. What
is the expected impact to whatever matters to
you as a company, as a business, as a product?
The second dimension is certainty of impact.
Certainty of impact is basically how concrete is
the evidence that this is a problem? Sometimes
you have really hard data, sometimes you have
more anecdotal evidence, and so the confidence
really depends on how big the problem's
sizing and frequency is. Expected impact,
certainty of impact. The third one is also
very important, which is clarity of levers.
Do you actually have an idea of how you
would solve it? If you don't, it's going
to be really difficult to move the needle on
it because you should kind of know that, okay,
I can imagine these solutions could actually
move the needle. I can actually launch this
sort of nudge system that can help people find
things. I can recommend people. I can recommend
friends so that people can form friends quicker
on the platform. You should have a sense of how
you would solve that particular space. Is there
clarity on levers? That's the third dimension.
The fourth dimension is super important, which
is are the levers unique and differentiated to
that particular team or company? Which is that
if another team or company could build it better
than this particular team or company, then
it's probably not that differentiated. It's
probably going to be pretty generic once you
launch it. It's a combination of sort of like,
is there a lot of impact here? How confident
are we of the problem? Do we have a sense of
the solutions? And basically, are we the team or
company that has the capabilities and the skills
to uniquely build it where other teams cannot?
Once you have that, and sometimes what happens is
you don't have too much data, and so it's okay to
have qualitative scores on this like high, medium,
low, T-shirt scores, whatever that is. The key
is you're doing it together as a strategy working
group, and you're debating the scores and you're
reasoning why it should be higher versus lower.
There's a ton of alignment and collision
that's happening when you're doing that,
which is very healthy for the eventual outcome.
Once you do that, basically you can do a simple
sort of addition of the scores and a sort, and
what you have is basically the top three and
you have the remaining 7 or 12 that are basically
not the focus. That's the core of the process, is
getting those opportunity areas and getting to a
shared sense of how do we prioritize them and why?
Okay, and this is all done in a week. I know
there's more to it. There's a couple more items
that help you move from what you just said to the
next step, but I love that this is the core of
the biggest element of the process, and you do it
in a week and you're only able to do it in a week
because of the work you did ahead of time. Again,
highlighting the importance of that prep step.
Just to share what you've shared so far, and
then we'll finish the strategy sprint step.
It's basically do the share out so everyone's
on the same page about all the information that,
all the inputs essentially. Enumerate all
the problems, like individual small problems
and then cluster them into 10 to 15 problem
clusters. Flip it from here's the problem to
here's an opportunity we have. Rank them based
on, basically there's these four attributes
you shared, which I'll actually, I wrote these
down. Impact potential, confidence that it will
have the impact, clarity of levers and are
they differentiated unique levers? Is there
something different from what other folks are
doing? Those are ways to rank these ideas and
problem clusters. You essentially come up with,
here's three bets basically we potentially should
take. Okay, and then I think that's
where you stopped. Is that right?
That's totally right, Lenny.
Okay, cool.
Those three that are at the top of that pile
are basically our strategic pillars. We've
sort of gotten our strategic pillars and
they basically hold up the strategy. That's
why they're called strategic pillars. The
idea is once you have the strategic pillars,
we basically translate that into a few how might
we's? Let's say it's a relevance thing. How might
we find the best content for a particular
user? How might we surface it in the right
place? There's a few how might we's, and the how
might we's are basically intended to help the next
phase of the process, which is the design sprint.
You generate these areas, these strategic pillars,
you generate the how might we's. How might we's
are typically pretty straightforward. Once you
have the strategic pillars, it takes probably an
hour to generate some how might we's for each of
them, maybe two or three for each strategic
pillar, and then you're done with that stage.
I just want to highlight real quick, this
phrasing is really important. I used exactly
the same phrasing. I had a PM that I worked with
and his name was Andrew Chen, but not the Andrew
Chen people know about, that's an investor,
who had this concept of fertile questions
that create ideas and spark ideas and solutions.
This phrase, "How might we", is actually really
powerful as a way to come up with ideas to
solve problems. It's just like, how might we
increase discoverability in our app? How might
we improve relevance? There's something magical
about that phrasing that it opens up your mind to,
how might we? Let's think about it. Versus like,
how do we improve discovery? That's a
different, your brain works differently
hearing this. That is a really powerful
phrasing. Just wanted to highlight that.
Yeah, that's awesome. It's also something
that designers are familiar with, Lenny,
so it flows really well into
sort of a design sprint.
Okay, so you have these how might we'd. You have
three pillars, maybe three or four or five how
might we's to solve these opportunities/problems,
and then what happens after that?
Exactly. Then the third day is it's good to
start fresh. The team's accomplished a lot.
This was all the first two days.
This is the first two days, yeah.
Wow. Okay. So much done in two days.
Yeah, exactly. The second day is particularly
intense on the team, so it's good to give them
a break, because it's a lot of really mental sort
of wrestling, and so give the team a bit of a
break. Then the third day is when people
are a little bit refreshed, we get to
winning aspiration. Winning aspiration is super
interesting because it's a very creative exercise.
You basically imagine in two years, because that's
the typical time horizon of a smaller strategy,
is like 18 months to 24 months. This is what
I tell the team. Imagine two years there's
a newspaper, there's a journalist that covers
this work, and there's a newspaper article that
comes out. I want you to imagine the progress
on all these strategic pillars and what the
headline of that newspaper article looks like.
It's called a newspaper headline approach.
Basically, everybody generates a newspaper
headline in parallel. It's interesting because
you often see there's these common themes that
sort of form when people generate these headlines.
The forcing function with the headline is also
that it has to be somewhat simple and plain speak.
It's not too technical. You have to get to a more
simple layperson's language and you have to get to
the key benefit that ultimately, the impact it has
on the world. Those kinds of themes come up often.
Then you do a little bit, you put them all into
a blender, you put all of those headlines from
the team into a blender, and you mash them
together and create the winning aspiration,
which is ultimately what does progress
on the strategy look like in a couple of
years time? That comes from the working
group, it's not like one person writing.
What's an example of an aspiration that you've
come up with on a project you
worked on, a winning aspiration?
We did this process for the privacy team when
I was at Meta. Really the strategic pillars
were around a lot of features that we would
build, but the winning aspiration was really like,
could we move consumer trust? The newspaper
headline is something like, "Facebook has moved
the needle on consumer trust by investing in these
areas." That's how you create the bigger impact.
That's a great example. Obviously this is
similar to the PR Amazon method and what I
love about your approach, as you said early on,
is you're just pulling together all of these
awesome ideas from all these different methods of
strategy work to a very methodical step-by-step
process. Taking all the best ideas into, and as
you described, an operator's playbook for doing
this. I love that. Okay. When you say blender,
by the way, I was thinking as you were talking,
put them into a blender, what I'm inferring
is you just take everyone's headlines and
you come up with one that kind of covers the
gamut of all three pillars being successful.
That's exactly right. More tactically
what I typically do is I put them all
on a slide and start, it's almost like a word
cloud, and then you start to see these common
words. Then you converge those words as
the key elements of the final winning
aspiration. Then you try to create a nice
statement out of that. It also symbolically,
everybody sees their own statement on the deck,
and that's how you get to the final model.
Awesome. I feel like AI could help with that now.
Exactly.
Just put in all your headline ideas and
it comes up with some suggestions. Okay,
cool. Is that the end of the sprint
or is there more to the sprint?
That's it for the sprint.
Okay. At the end of the sprint, what
do you have? What are the outputs?
Yeah, this is a great progress on strategy
because now we have the three strategic
pillars. We have the how might we associate it
with the strategic pillars. You also have the
why. Why did you get to those three strategic
pillars and what are you not focused on and
what are the reasons for it? You also
have the winning aspiration. It's great
progress. The team's done a great job. I think
now we sort of move on to the design sprint.
In your experience, how often are these
three the correct three that you end up
going with versus you learn something over the
course of the rest of the sprint and adjust?
It's a very good question. We'll speak about
an example that I had in Meta where typically
during the strategy sprint, you don't change
it once you go through the strategy sprint,
but eventually there are a lot of signals you get
through execution where you sort of have to course
correct. We'll talk about one very interesting
example of how that sort of changed things here.
Awesome. Okay. Basically, you've developed your
strategy at this point, and in your experience it
ends up being... Until you hit the market and
test, you don't really know what's going on.
Correct.
But there's kind of an implication that
in your experience doing this, I think you
said five or six times, it has been correct
and as good as doing it any other approach.
I would say it's not sort of an empirical study,
obviously because of the small sample size,
but I would say that it's really opened
people's eyes and it's led to really good
alignment and eventually good
results. Even when it has not,
it has led to good organizational buy-in
on why and how we are approaching things.
This reminds me of, Tomer Cohen was on
the podcast, he's CPO of LinkedIn and he
has this phrase that always says he says,
which is, "We may be wrong, but we're not
confused." I love that a core part of this
is everyone is completely on the same page,
not from the beginning, but once you start this
process of here's all the inputs, here's step by
step we are working together on narrowing down,
so at least everyone understands the why. Which
is what sparked your interest in this in the first
place, everyone understanding. I know there's a
whole rollout at the end too to solve that.
Okay, cool, so we have the sprint. We have
basically the three pillars that you're going to
invest in, this headline of what it might look
like if you're to launch and some solution
ideas with how might we's. What comes next?
Yeah. The next phase is the design sprint,
and the design sprint can be led by the
design person who's in the strategy working
group. If you remember, there's engineering,
product design and data, so the design person
can lead it and the PM can sort of take a bit
of a backseat during this process. The input to
the design sprint is sort of the three strategic
pillars and the how might we's associated with it.
The goal of the design sprint is not to sort of
come up with these are the features we
should build. That's not the purpose
of the design sprint. The design sprint is to
generate a lot of illustrative concepts that
bring the strategy to life because a picture is
worth a thousand words. Oftentimes, even though
you might have the right words in your strategy
doc, people might still scratch their head like,
"What do you exactly mean? What are you going
to build?" The illustrative concepts really sort
of give people something to latch onto, "Oh,
okay, I get it. This is what you're going to
build at the end of the day with this strategy."
The more generative, the better. Then there's the
ability to, sometimes if you do the Google
Ventures design sprint, you can even test
some of it with users and get a little bit of
sharpening of things. The goal here is not to
build feature-ready designs, it's more to generate
concepts. Once you have that, basically the design
sprint, and there's different flavors of design
sprints, which I won't go into. You can lean on
your design lead to decide what's the appropriate
way, but the input and the output is what needs
to be very emphasized. The input needs to be the
strategic pillars. The output needs to be a ton of
illustrative concepts to explain each strategic
pillar. You could almost have a section where
you talk about each strategic pillar and insert
those concepts in that section. That's the idea.
We're going to go through a couple examples to
make this very real. You mentioned the design
sprint method, which we had the authors on the
podcast. They actually didn't go through the
design sprint method. They have another book
called Make Time that's about productivity.
We also had their colleague from Google
Ventures that designed a bullseye sprint,
which is also an interesting sprint. It's
a new thing that helps you figure out your
ICP and who to focus your product on
and how that informs your product.
Oh, that's right. Interesting.
It's another type of sprint you could
use here. The input is here's the three
things we're going to invest in, say discovery,
relevance, privacy. The output is here's
concepts of what this could look like to
get people's minds going. Is it just a bunch
of mocks basically in a deck at this point?
That's correct. Yeah.
Okay, cool. Okay, amazing. That's a week. That's
another sprint. PM could maybe
take a little bit of a break.
Exactly.
And designers take the lead.
The engineers are kind of inputs and
thought partners in this, I imagine.
They're optional. Yeah.
Optional, but yeah, ideally they're involved
because you want all the best ideas in there.
Yep.
Okay, cool. What comes next?
Then the next step is the document writing.
This is sort of a solo activity that the PM
should take on, but the great news is the PM is
not starting from scratch. There's so much great
stuff to write. If you remember, there's a ton
of user insights, a ton of behavioral insights,
a ton of competitive analysis. There's the
three strategic pillars, how might we's,
winning aspiration. There's a whole
bunch of illustrative concepts.
Oftentimes, product leads have this sort of
creator's block. That is solved here completely
because you have a ton of great material. I have
to tell you, it doesn't make the job easier. You
still have to weave together a good story.
That's why I think it takes a week or two.
I think it's really about combining, connecting
and editing at this point and telling a cohesive
story from all those components, but I think the
building blocks are really solid and defensible.
Is there a template or kind of sections you
like to include in your strategy doc? As someone
sits down and is trying to write this out,
what do you want to see there as headings?
I think you could almost take the building blocks
as a little bit of a steer for the template. You
start with the broader context where you talk
about what the leaders kind of want from this
overall effort. Then you get into key insights
and analysis where you have user insights,
behavioral insights, competitive analysis. Then
you get into the strategic pillars and you explain
them. You also explain why. In the appendix, you
include the full table that you generated on day
two of your strategy sprint. You include the full
table in the appendix, including the criteria.
That's going to be really important because most
people are going to ask, "Why did you pick these?"
That's basically sort of the defensibility.
Then you have the winning aspiration that's very
bold. It's a big part of the heart of the deck,
and you sort of embed the illustrative concepts
into the actual each of the strategic pillars so
that it flows well. Then finally, you end with
some kind of alignment questions like, "Hey,
do these feel right? Are there things we are
missing?" So that it creates that framework
for alignment in the subsequent meetings.
I'm excited to chat with Christina
Gilbert, the founder of OneSchema,
one of our longtime podcast
sponsors. Hi, Christina.
Yes. Thank you for having me on, Lenny.
What is the latest with OneSchema? I know you
now work with some of my favorite companies,
like Ramp, Vanta, Scale and Watershed. I
heard that you just launched a new product.
... and to scale and watershed, I heard
that you just launched a new product to
help product teams import CSVs from
especially tricky systems like ERPs.
Yes, so we just launched one scheme of file feeds,
which allows you to build an integration
with any system in 15 minutes, as long as
you can export a CSV to an SFTP folder.
We see our customers all the time getting
stuck with hacks and workarounds, and the
product teams that we work with don't have
to turn down prospects because their
systems are too hard to integrate with.
We allow our customers to offer thousands of
without involving their engineering team at all.
I can tell you that if my team had
to build integrations like this,
how nice would it be to be able
to take this off my roadmap,
and instead use something like OneSchema, and not
just to build it, but also to maintain it forever?
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many
horror stories of multi-day outages from
even just a handful of bad records.
We are laser focused on integration
reliability to help teams end all of those
distractions that come up with integrations.
We have a built-in validation layer that
stops any bad data from entering your
system, and OneSchema will notify your team
immediately of any data that looks incorrect.
I know that importing incorrect data can cause
all kinds of pain for your customers and quickly
lose their trust. Christina, thank you for
joining us, and if you want to learn more,
head on over to oneschema.co. That's oneschema.co.
I pulled up Playing to Win, which I know you also
pull ideas from, and actually Roger Martin was on
the podcast talking about this stuff. And one way
I think about it as you're describing
a way to break up your strategy doc,
is he has these five questions that you ask.
The first is actually what's your winning
aspiration? So I love that you're pulling that
in. This is one approach your doc would be. What's
your winning aspiration? Where will you play? What
market are you going after? How will you win? What
capabilities must be in place for you to win?
And then what management systems are required?
We'll link to this framework just in case people
want that as a crutch in their thinking strategy,
but is there anything that we could link
folks to that describe how you like to think
about this doc? And if not, it'd be cool if
you make a template that folks could borrow.
I'm happy to share of the flowchart of
the process and the template as well.
Awesome. Okay. So this is how long of a
process, this writing of the document?
It's about one to two weeks, and I think
it's mostly solo work and hopefully by the
end of it there's a very tight doc,
and that's what we use to roll out.
And by solo work, I imagine you're looping
in this working team to get their feedback
as you're pulling it together, or is it
just you sit there in a room and then...
I would minimize pulling them in, because they've
all contributed so much to the process already.
So, I would say that at the end of it, obviously,
once you have a draft, it's good to share with
them, but I wouldn't tap their cycles too much at
this point, because they've given a lot already.
I see. Okay.
And how many pages do you see this doc
being, roughly? What's a heuristic?
It's not too long. I would
say probably three or four
pages and then an appendix has
a lot of additional... Like,
the table I spoke about and a lot of additional
maybe illustrative concepts. Maybe you can only
use a few illustrative concepts in the main
section so that there could be others there.
I think usually there's a desire from leaders to
say, "Okay, what are we building next?" And it's
important not to include a roadmap as part of
a strategy doc, because a strategy doc is meant
to be separate from the roadmap. It's meant
to be a companion to your roadmap. And even
though there's interest, maybe sometimes you can
include a illustrative roadmap in the appendix,
but I would try to keep it clean and try
to keep it focused on just the strategy.
So at this point you basically
developed your strategy, the next step,
I think you call rollout, where you
just start actually rolling this out,
so let's talk about that. But it's important
to note how many weeks in this is. This is like
six-ish weeks of work and you've got
a strategy for your company/product?
That's exactly right. So I think you're probably
in the last two to three weeks of the process,
and pretty important final step is the rollout,
and I would start with what I call gatekeepers.
And these are people who are absolutely...
You have to get their one-on-one alignment
and blessing on this before it moves
forward. And it's probably not too many,
probably two or three people. So I would
pre-flight it with them and get their alignment.
So these are one-on-one
meetings with these gatekeepers?
These are one-on-one meetings. Exactly.
And then there's a larger group of what
I call key stakeholders, people who are
impacted by it, different functional leaders,
et cetera. And that can be done either async or
through a group review. And then there's probably
a rolling of list of team roadshows. There's
different ways to do this, but the one that I
feel is most effective is the roadshow where you
have about eight to 10 people in each session,
so people feel more comfortable to ask
questions and it's more conversational.
So the purpose of this stage is to land it. It's
not to seek too much feedback, so it's a delicate
balance. At the same time, you don't want to
appear just being too inflexible. So it's a
very delicate balance. When people ask questions,
you can clarify it, and you can add clarifications
to the doc, but I wouldn't change... The most
important thing, three strategic pillars, I
wouldn't change that. I would defend it using the
framework, but if people are like, "there's really
good arguments about the criteria that led to your
ranking," then it's okay to reconsider it. I've
not seeing it happen in my five to six attempts,
but it's possible, theoretically possible.
The core of this approach it sounds like,
is you've done a lot of the pre-work where
you land in a generally correct place.
Okay, so this is the rollout. So what
I'm thinking as you talk, say you're like a
PM on a team, say you're working on privacy,
it's like an IC, your ICPM, working on strategy.
How do you think about including, say, your
manager because through this process, when do you
start to like, "Hey, here's what we're planning,
here's what we're thinking," making sure
they're on board? Because I could see this
working team off to the side working, working,
working. "Okay, we're ready to roll it out."
Oftentimes there's like, "No, wait. There's all
this other stuff happening at the company, we
don't have resources." Where do you loop them in?
How do you think about that kind of stakeholder?
The the more attuned PMs who
understand organizational dynamics,
probably keep the manager pretty in sync
through the process. I think, definitely,
the manager becomes a person who you interview
as part of the leadership interviews, so you know
what the manager's looking for from the effort.
And then once you get to the strategic pillars on
day two of the strategy sprint, you probably want
to just quickly pre-flight it with the manager and
say, "Hey, look, this is how it's trending,
and these are the things we are probably not
going to do" and any issues with that. And then
eventually you actually want your manager to
support you in some of these bigger meetings,
so you enlist their help. So I would say that
it's probably each individual style, but I
would keep them pretty aligned through the
process. But you don't have to be too heavy
[inaudible 01:01:23], just be super light.
Great. Makes a lot of sense
to me. There's like a...
We're not going to solve everyone's problems
with this one framework, maybe just quickly
touch on resourcing. As you think about this.
Like a part of a strategy includes like, oh,
we also need these resources. Just
any thoughts on how to include that?
And then I want to get into some examples
of how you've actually implemented this.
So I actually don't recommend thinking about
resources in the strategy phase, because what
you're saying is, "these are the areas of
focus" and the resourcing question becomes
more relevant from a road mapping standpoint.
Because then you say, "Okay, what percentage
of our engineering do we put on strategic pillar
A, versus B, versus C? And what are the specific
things we build?" So it becomes a road-mapping
question as opposed to a strategy question.
And so by the end of this, the rollout,
the part of the rollout is developing the
actual roadmap. We're not going to get
deep into that. That could be part two,
solve every PM's problems, teach
them all the steps of the process,
but we're going to cut it off at, here's you have
a strategy that is starting to be rolled out.
Exactly.
Cool.
Let's go through a couple
examples where you actually move into this
to make this even more real. I know there's
a couple companies you were thinking
about sharing, strategies you worked on.
I think there's just three quick notes to close
off this process and I'll
share two examples, Lenny.
Perfect.
So the reason I think this process works, the
first is because there is a ton of alignment
built in within team alignment and leadership
alignment built in. And it's not seen as,
"Oh, this PM went off and wrote this
strategy doc and I don't agree with
most of it." And part of this is actually very...
It goes back to human psychology of just something
that comes from you, feels a lot more familiar
and easy to accept. So this doc is actually not
from the PM, the PM is facilitating it, but it's
actually from the strategy working group. And the
strategy working group are the leads of the team.
And so it's actually... And the leadership inputs
have been baked in, so it's actually very team
representative. And so hopefully there isn't too
much misalignment when you roll it out. And
I have seen that, I've seen that work out.
The second is there's just better results. You
get to better problem articulation, you get a
better strategic pillar, because there's just more
minds on it than if it was just a product lead.
And the third thing is you have clearly
defensible criteria and outputs, and if
you want to change it, like I said, you have to go
back to the criteria and the scoring and then say,
"Okay, why do we believe this has to be
changed?" And even a change is easy to
justify once you do that. So it creates a lot
of benefits, but ultimately, and we'll get to
this a little bit more, it has to be tested with
execution, and that's the most important thing.
I think it's important to highlight, no framework
playbook [inaudible 01:04:26] method is going
to guarantee you have the correct strategy
that will win and your company will thrive.
It's always just the best effort at plan.
As the quote, "no good plan survives
first contact with the customer."
Exactly.
Cool. Let's talk through some examples.
so the first example I wanted to talk about is
at Zynga. I was at Zynga a very long time ago,
and this was the heyday of social gaming
on Facebook. The thing that I was extremely
impressed about Zynga was the strategic clarity
and strategic encoding at the company. And this
was not attributable to me, by the way, this was
already there when I got there as a entry-level
PM, but the kind of strategic clarity there was
really, really impressive and it was very evident
and observable from all the games.
So if you look at all the games,
there were three elements that were very common
across all the games. The first was viral game
loops. There's these game loops that just
required you to have a social and active
social network to be successful and play, and it
was very tightly and fictionally integrated into
the core of the gameplay. That was the first one.
The second one was there was this idea of paying
to complete things. So you're not paying to skip
a whole experience, what you're paying is just to
complete it. So what happens then is different
people, depending on how much time they have,
complete different percentages of a progression
task, or a part of the gameplay, and you only had
to pay the rest to get through the experience.
And it was this interesting experience where
people put a lot of investment into it, and
they didn't mind paying for the last 20% or 30%,
which was very interesting, because it created
this market for different elasticity of spend,
different times that people had in their lives.
And it was very, very clever. So that was again,
very common across all the games.
And then the third was network. So all
of Zynga games had this cross-promotional
component at the top of the game and they
would promote other games, and it's like the
Zynga network was the most important thing,
and not an individual game. And those were the
three in our parlance now strategic pillars,
and there were non-focus areas. It wasn't like...
The focus wasn't on high-fidelity graphics,
it wasn't on complex game mechanics, and this
was extremely clear and hard-coded into the
company culture and operations. And it was
perfectly tuned to the environment at the
time. Facebook platform afforded strong
support with social graph, and channels,
and basically the game studios contributed through
different games in a very network accretive way.
So for example, I was at Zynga San Diego, and
we took the company into net new game genres
like action strategy, match three puzzle games,
but we stayed true to the strategic pillars of
the company, and we had to invent new mechanics
so that the strategic pillars would work in the
new genres that we introduced to the company. And
what was fascinating is the company actually had
systems to reinforce these strategic pillars.
And, for example, the data infrastructure was
very incredible at the time, and really reinforced
these strategic pillars. There was this function
called Central Product Management, which basically
propagated best practices, made sure that games
were network accretive and all these things worked
in harmony to enhance those strategic pillars and
reinforce it, and it worked really well. The
company, if I remember right, got to a billion
dollars, it was the fastest to get to a billion
dollars in the history of companies at the time.
In revenue.
And it worked really
well until the environment changed and there was
a shift to mobile. And temporarily... Basically,
if you go back to that resonance concept,
that deep resonance between the product
and the market was temporarily lost
once that shift happened to mobile.
So there's a lot here. I think one
interesting note here is, as you said,
the strategy work you're doing, which sounds like
a lot of time, eight to 12 weeks potentially,
this lasted a long time for Zynga. And
so I think it's important to remember
the work you're doing here, even though...
On the one hand it feels like a long time,
on the other hand, it feels like very little time
to come up with the things that will most help
your business grow. In this case, these three
elements for Zynga. And by the way, these three
pillars, they didn't emerge from this method, but
it helped you see the power of being very clear...
Clear, exactly.
And having everything centered around, we all
agree, these are the three ways we win. Okay,
cool. And then I think the number three,
again, I just want to highlight the power
of just very few bets in investments. So
it's always three. I've always suggested
three as well. Some people are like, "three
to five," but I think it's... You just find,
in general, three is the right number as
much? Try very, very hard to make it three?
I agree.
Okay, cool.
And then I think there's also this element
of differentiation being really important.
So these three elements you shared for
Zynga are just like they're unique and
differentiated for Zynga. Network, powers of
apps driving other apps, paying to complete,
these are things Zynga has figured out, "this is
how we" win versus other products in the market.
Totally.
Sweet. Anything else along those lines with Zynga?
That was in hindsight reflection, Lenny, I was
pretty naive when I was there, and I realized
how... And this was, in fact, what led to my
blind spot when I joined Headspace from Zynga,
that you even need a strategy. That's
the story I said at the beginning.
The reason is because Zynga had it figured
out so well that I didn't actually have a
need to exercise that muscle at Zynga, and
we just had to come up with new games that
applied that strategy. And so it was a net new
muscle I had to develop when I got to Headspace.
It's like that parable of the fish swimming in the
water where the older fish swims by and he's like,
"How's the water?" And they're like, "Hmm?" And
then he leaves and he's like, "What's water?"
You just don't realize what you're in. You don't
realize what you're surrounded by until it's gone.
Exactly.
Maybe one other thing I just want to highlight
while we're on this topic is just the power of
focus. In the case of Zynga, just this focus
on everything we do needs to get these things,
these three things, everything we do, we need
to do in order to win. And I think that's a
recurring theme in what you're talking about, is
just focus. The steps of the process are focus on
this one part for now. So I think that's a really
interesting thread is just the power of focus.
Yeah.
Okay, cool.
And now you have another
example of your time at Meta.
At Meta there's this fascinating example, which I
think illustrates a different point, which is...
Basically I was standing up the product strategy
for a couple of product growth teams in Reality
Labs, Oculus, which was coming up with the Quest
II at the time. This is a standalone headset,
and then Portal, which was our video conferencing
product. And we stood up these teams to go after
product growth, which is basically driving
hardware sales through software features. And we
went through this process that I just described.
We stood up strategic pillars, and the strategic
pillars were fairly similar for both Portal, which
is our video conferencing product, and Oculus.
I love Portal by the way. I was a big
fan of... Sad that it's no longer around.
And that led to features that are known to
everybody, like the Oculus Referrals Program,
the Portal Memories Integration, where you see
one of your Facebook memories on the Portal,
sponsored ad in your Facebook feed. And also
we had this section on the Facebook app,
which is also from Facebook at the time,
and then eventually also from Meta,
which is these other products from the Facebook
ecosystem. And all those came out of that effort.
And about 18 months into it, they actually had
very different outcomes. So on one hand the
Oculus effort was incredibly successful, and
we graduated it into the VR division at Meta,
and till today it continues to be an
incredibly successful effort. The Portal
effort actually didn't move the needle as
much as we wanted to, and we sunset it,
and we basically redeployed that team to other
initiatives. And that's super interesting.
Basically it was like the same strategy process.
We got the nearly identical strategic pillars,
but eventually completely different outcomes.
And I think that that illustrates the most
important point about strategy, which is
intrinsically strategy has no business value.
It's basically a document with a few words. And I
think it starts accumulating value as you generate
business impact and results. And that happens
when you actually test strategy with execution.
And so ultimately any strategy is only as
good as the results it produces. And so
one has to have the intellectual honesty, and
the humility, and the courage to say when it's
working and when it's not. And sometimes what
happens is parts of your strategy might work,
parts might not, and you have to pivot away
from some and double down on some. But I do
think there's that evaluation that's really
critical and testing strategy with execution.
Such a great point. Just a strategy sitting there
in a doc is worthless, where the worth comes from,
is it actually having impact and being successful.
Makes me think about a product manager also,
just a PM is not worth anything
until they help you drive impact.
I think an important, to trickle down from
that point, is that you don't want to spend
too long just thinking about strategy, you want
to spend as little time as possible to get to a
strong hypothesis, basically to start learning
if this is the right path. And so I love that
your approach is like this middle ground
between give it real time, but don't spend
three, four or five months working on this one
document that just maybe one day you'll use.
Exactly.
And there is room for a six-month process,
which we'll get to in a moment. But for small S I
wouldn't recommend more than two or three months.
And again, small S strategy
is for a couple of years out,
not like Exactly. It's like
a timeframe. Okay, cool.
Okay. Anything else along those lines
of the examples of Meta or Zynga?
Those are pretty good lessons I would say.
Okay, sweet.
So, let's talk about big-S
strategy. When should you approach strategy
this way and what are just the steps of it?
So everything we've spoken about so far is what I
would call small S, and it's very problem focused.
It's basically what I call present forward.
It's like you have something, you have a product
out there, it has a bunch of problems. How do we
make it better for... What are the areas we tackle
for maximum impact? Typically led by product
managers. And there's this interesting quote
by Elon Musk, which is, "Life has to be about
more than just solving problems." And he says
it in the context of the aspiration to become
a multi-planetary species, but I think this is
true of every company, big or small. And there
needs to be an aspirational and cool component
to strategy. And I call this big-S strategy.
I'll run through this at a higher level because
I think this is a little bit more fluid in how
you build the big-S strategy. And it typically
takes longer, potentially up to about six months.
The approach is a bit different from small S. And
you start with the company mission and vision, and
there is a little bit of groundwork that is done
on long-term cultural trends, social trends,
competitive trends, technological trends,
and those are all the backdrop to trigger ideas.
And what you do with that backdrop is you, again,
do these leadership interviews, but with a
different goal of generating long-term futures.
And some of the questions you can ask during
these interviews are "What does a day in the
life of a user look like in five years? What does
the product look like in five to 10 years? Why
is the world better in 10 years? And what is
the most exciting version of that view?" And
basically take all of that input and cluster
it into I would say, three cohesive holes.
And what I mean by that is three, at least fairly
distinct, descriptions of the future. So to give
you almost a very simple example, imagine you
doing big S for the future of travel. You could
have a future that is talking all about fully
autonomous travel, where there's very little human
involvement in going from A to B. You could talk
about another future where there's extreme speed,
where you can get from A to B really fast across
the world that is really fast. You could talk
about a third where there is no travel, it's
virtual travel, and you still have the feeling
of travel, and you accomplish the same goals.
But those are different futures, they have
different properties, like different elements
to them. And once you generate those distinct
futures, you actually generate prototypes with
learning goals. And think of these prototypes as
concept cars. And the automobile industry uses
this notion of concept cars. Concept cars, the
interesting thing about concept cars is they're
never commercialized. They're often produced for
inspiration, and to potentially take some part
of them, like maybe a technology or a feature,
and that is brought into mainstream production.
So think of these prototypes as these concept cars
that really drive inspiration and potentially
give you some small nuggets that you can run
with. And then you start doing research with them
with potential users, you answer key questions,
and you uncover certain elements that
resonate with people. So you eliminate
a whole bunch of stuff, you combine a
whole bunch of stuff, and you establish
some winning components that are interesting.
And then what you do is you push stuff that
is winning into the product, live product,
testing. So this is actually something that
you actually want to start testing your
way into and understanding if it works
from a scalable standpoint. And this whole
thing is typically led not by the PM team,
but by design and UXR. And intentionally it's
a little bit more open-ended and green field.
And it actually is a very different mind space
that people have when they approach big. So the
roadmap is really built through a combination
of small-S and big-S work. And, for example,
at VRChat, we are doing both small-S and big-S
work, Lenny. And they are run as parallel work
streams. The product management team is
leading the charge of the small-S work,
and the design team is leading the charge on the
big-S work. And it's really exciting stuff. What's
coming out of both work streams is really exciting
and really different. And so we are building the
bridge from both sides and both work streams
ultimately flow into one roadmap. It's almost
like two tributaries that ultimately merge into
one river. That's how I would think about it.
There's so many things here that are so...
That's how I would think about it.
There's so many things here that are so
interesting. One is we've had this conversation
on the podcast a couple of times, this point that
people think and see the world differently. Some
people are very open-minded and creative, and
think big, blue sky people. Some people, me, just
like, "What are we doing next? How do we move this
metric? Let's talk about concrete things that we
can do?" For this big S approach, I think what
I'm hearing is make sure the people leading it
are very open-minded, creative, blue sky type
people. If you're the person that's like, "How
will this move our metric?" Maybe you shouldn't
be leading it and give someone else the reins.
Cool. And then with these timelines of
doing both at once, it's probably hard
to align them fully. So what I'm hearing is
it's like these are kind of ongoing sometimes.
Correct.
And they'll both inform what you're doing. You
don't need to have this perfect timeline of-
I agree to this. Yeah.
Sweet. And the big thinking I love,
because sometimes, you may experience this,
designers often are like, "Oh, we just work
on all this boring, incremental optimization
stuff. I want to think bigger." Which is
great, and this is a really good lever to
allow for that in a contained environment.
Cool. Let's just go crazy. Let's think about
what this could be in the future. Still, let's
make sure we're moving some metrics short-term,
but let's give us opportunity to think big. And
oftentimes the biggest ideas come out of that.
So I love it's giving space for both types of
thinking, thinking bigger and thinking long term.
Anything else about these two methods that
might be interesting to share? Otherwise,
I want to talk about AI a little bit, just how
that impacts things and a couple other things.
Yeah, yeah. I'll end on one short sort of
note on how this all feels when you do it,
and then we can segue into AI-
Great, great.
... Lenny. So I think that whether it's
big S or small S, these are incredibly
satisfying processes to go through in the end.
So once you get to the end, they're incredibly
deeply satisfying. But with anything in life
that is very deeply satisfying at the end,
they have a ton of challenge, frustration, and
dead ends while you go through it where you kind
of get a lot of self-doubt like, "Hey, will you
ever reach the end?" And I just want to sort of
normalize that. That's actually normal and I
want people to expect that as they go through
it. And I think that's what makes it even
more rewarding when you get to that sort of
point where you start to see things connecting.
The second thing is I would say that the person
who's leading the charge on these efforts has to
be really good at connecting diverse viewpoints
and keeping them all moving forward. And it's
not easy, it's very hard because sometimes you
have people who take you in different directions
and you have to keep it all hanging together.
So in terms of picking people who have
that skill, who are good integrators,
who are good connect the dots, I think it's
critical for these to be successful. And in
some ways low ego because it's not like... They do
get to introduce their own ideas, but truly, it's
about bringing the team together. So that's the
skill that you should look for for these leads.
And then the third piece is I would say that
I would just approach these with a little bit
of a lighter touch and more playful sort of
approach, because it's an intensive process,
it's a long process. And people can get tired,
they can find it grindy. So just having a little
bit of playfulness along the way goes a long
way in making it feel more tolerable for the
people going through it. So those are some
thoughts about either of these processes.
That was really important context, especially
this will be frustrating throughout. It sounds
really beautiful and great and smooth as
you describe it. In reality, there's a lot
of pain that goes into... Because you're making
hard decisions. A lot of people have opinions,
they have perspectives, there's data that's...
Rarely is there clear answer from the beginning,
so I think that's really important context.
I wanted to actually come back to your point
you made about how Elon made this
point about life shouldn't just be
about solving problems. I think part of
that quote is just like we should work
on things that are awesome and exciting and
inspiring, that aren't just immediately pain
solvers. And he's very good at that,
just inspiring people to what could be,
and we should be thinking much bigger than we are.
I was actually at an interview with Zuck where he
said the same thing. He's probably inspired
by Elon. He's like, "I've just gotten to a
point in my career where I want to work on awesome
stuff, stuff that is just awe inspiring, not just-
Exactly.
... another social feature." so I think that's a
really important point. And there's a lot of power
in that. People get really excited about holy
moly, I did not imagine this is what Headspace
could become, what VRChat could become, what
Meta could become. It's just really powerful,
getting people really inspired. And I love
this process they shared of how to do that.
And I didn't actually summarize it, so I have
it right here in front of me. I'll just share
the five steps of the biggest process. So it's
preparation, mission, you figure [inaudible
01:26:10] mission, vision, trends, interview
people about where they think things are going.
Then you come up with three distinct futures
of what the future might look like if you were
to do the things you're thinking. Then you build
prototypes of what might this look like? And then
you actually test these in your product, which
I love, to start de-risking these ideas. That
helps you converge to here's actual plan we want
to execute, and then you turn that into roadmap.
Yeah, yeah. And the first testing
of the prototypes is with UXR,
so it's more sort of concept testing
or prototype testing with a handful
of users. And then you use that as
synthesizing to a live product test.
Great. Basically, it's like big ideas and then
de-risking, validating them along the way-
Exactly.
... in various ways to like, "Okay, maybe this
could actually work. Let's try." Sweet. Okay,
so just two more things. One is I want to
talk about AI briefly, of how that impacts
this work. And then two, just maybe a recap of
the framework for people that are listening,
you're like, "Oh my god, I have so much.
I wrote all these notes." Let's give them
a summary so they could remember to use it.
Okay, cool. So let's talk about AI briefly. How
has AI tooling helped you evolve this process?
How can people use AI to make this easier?
So the first disclaimer is I'm not sort of an AI
futurist, but I read all the emerging stuff that's
coming out, most of the emerging stuff that's
coming out and use some of the tools. And it's
fascinating what's happening. And I think it will
definitely have an impact on strategy formulation.
So what I'll share is what resonates for me in
the context of strategy formulation with AI.
So right away, I think the basic idea is everybody
should be using assistance in the strategy
formulation process with the basic tools that we
have. And there are two ways to get AI to assist
you in the strategy formulation process. The first
is to support the preparation phase in terms of
research. And this could be competitive analysis
and, for example, you could do trend analysis from
a vast library of competitors' release notes. And
you can sort of say, "Okay, what are the themes of
investment of a competitor's release notes?" Or
you could do a reviews analysis of a competitor
product and sort of understand what's resonating
for users, what's not. And you could also ask a
tool like ChatGPT to do a head-to-head comparison
between a few players on a certain dimension
and really give you a heat map of how they all
stack up. And you could also ask an open-ended
question like, "Hey, why is this new product so
successful? Why is it getting so many users?"
And there's some good hypothesis that you usually
get. So really leverage in sort of the preparation
phase from a competitive analysis standpoint.
The second one is in this idea called generating
mock strategies. And I know Claire
Rowe at your summit spoke about this,
and I think this is absolutely right and should
be a critical input into the strategy process,
which is asking these tools for a mock strategy.
And I call this a mock strategy because it's kind
of almost the answer but not quite the answer.
So what I've found is that these mock strategies,
like let's say I support VRChat now and I ask it
like, "Hey, what should VRChat do? How should we
grow?" And it generates a mock strategy.
What I've found is that it's, one,
surprisingly good. It's incredibly well-informed
and well-articulated. I've also found that its
biggest strength is also somewhat its weakness,
which is these mock strategies tend to be pretty
comprehensive and extensive, and there's an
investment recommendation in a vast number of
areas. So basically, if you remember, the core of
strategy is really to be very targeted and to be
very focused. So these mock strategies become an
interesting input and the burden is still on the
team to down-select into the most important areas
for investment. So forcing that choice still,
I think, is a human element and needs that layer
of additional judgment, which is very context
specific to the company. So this is sort of
right away, I think people should be doing this.
I think more medium term and probably not too
distant future and likely sooner than we all
think, there's probably going to be, sort of
the model that resonates with me is sort of the
multi-agent model, which is you probably have
different components of the strategy workflow
automated. So you probably have a strategy agent,
you probably have a roadmap or feature agent,
you have maybe a engineering agent, and these can
communicate amongst each other to cycle through
results and iterate. And I think Armand Ruiz from
IBM has some good definitional frameworks on some
of the stuff. He shares it often on LinkedIn.
But let's take a simple example. I can easily
imagine something like this for a topic like
onboarding. So every company and product team
obsesses about their onboarding experience.
And today, there are advanced experimentation
frameworks. So imagine you're expecting a
large surge in traffic. There's these sort
of experimental frameworks like multi-armed
bandits that can really help you get to the
optimal sort of variation very quickly in
real time. And there are variations of that,
like contextual multi-armed bandits,
there's combinatorial bandits.
But the interesting thing is they still
rely on human design of the variations,
the different variations that you test. Even
though the experimentation framework is very
sophisticated, the variations are still human
generated. Now imagine if those variations could
actually be generated through generative AI and
could be plugged into the advanced experimentation
frameworks. The possibilities become infinite.
And really, you might be surprised by what
you find is the winning onboarding experience
that you couldn't even have humanly imagined.
And it might be different for every user,
different for every sort of territory, etc.
That is such a cool idea, I just want to say.
This agent that's just running, thinking about
ways to optimize your onboarding, coming up with
concepts that you probably review, like, "Cool,
let's try it." And then it does it, ships an
experiment to run it and just is constantly
optimizing your onboarding. Holy shit, that's an
awesome idea. I think everyone will have this.
And then what that makes me think
there's going to be some company
that's built the best onboarding agent.
That's what you're going to be paying for.
Totally. Totally.
Oh my god, that's so good.
Okay. Great. Great idea.
Yeah, yeah. So then the question becomes, hey,
what is our job? Our job becomes architecting
bigger and bigger pieces of the product to
take advantage of these agents. And there
will be a sequential increase in the complexity of
workloads that get automated over time. Onboarding
is probably relatively on the easier side in terms
of complexity of workload. And you get into deeper
experiences, eventually AI will get there.
So funnily enough, when that happens,
some of the manual processes I describe about
will seem archaic. But I think the fundamentals
will still have a long shelf life, and as you
think about these automated frameworks as well.
Man, this could be its own podcast. I have this
whole post about how AI, how PMs are the best
position, role in tech to thrive in a world
of AI, which I'll link to that makes people,
I find, feel better when they hear you talk about
how much might get done through agents in AI.
The other quick thought I had, and I want to
get to the wrap up, is I have this ongoing
debate with a friend about strategy in AI.
My feeling is in theory, an AI tool will be
incredibly good at coming up with your strategy
for you because it's just, here's all the data,
here's everything you need to know, how do we
win? And to me, that feels like the ultimate
way AI is good, is just here's data, here's what
I found as a path to a winning. But my friend's
also arguing that's the one thing that AI will be
least good at because that's where we need people
and context and discussion, all these things.
I don't know, it's like one or the other.
Either AI will be incredibly good at helping
you figure out your strategy or the worst.
Interesting.
I'm curious. I'm curious, I guess, do you have
any quick thoughts on that? Where do you side?
I think there is a crossover point where the human
judgment will be inferior to something that's able
to process multiple signals simultaneously.
There's an element of lateral thinking as well
here, and I'll sort of share a simple example.
For those who drive Tesla cars with the fully
self-driving capabilities, when you make a turn,
humans have this fairly narrow field of vision.
So you have to look both ways and you have to
make a decision combining both those signals,
right? Whereas the car has six cameras, which
is simultaneously processing and it can make a
decision not in sequence, but in parallel. And
it moves with confidence at turnings because
of that. So there is this crossover point
where some of these, the ability to hold
multiple signals in the head, it's going
to be more... It's going to be stronger.
That makes total sense. What
it makes me think about,
there's going to be a strategy agent just
sitting around always looking for ways to
improve your strategy and point you all
in a different direction. Oh my god,
future is wild, as I've said before.
Okay, let's do a quick wrap up of
the process for folks that are taking notes
and they're like, "Cool, here's the overview."
So let's just do that and then let's go
to get to the exciting lightning round.
I think the quick recap of everything
we've covered is that product strategy
definitionally sits between mission vision
at the top and plan at the bottom. So it
sits between those two either at the company
level or at the team level. What it does is it
forces choice to deploy scarce resources
towards maximum impact. And think about
the frequency selection and resonance as
an analogy, and it ideally includes three
components. A handful of areas to focus on, which
we call strategic pillars, and several areas that
are explicitly not the focus and why. That's
really it in terms of what product strategy is.
There is a smallest flavor of it which focuses
on solving problems. It's what I call present
forward, and it typically operates in a two-year
horizon. We use a five-stage process to get there,
and it takes about eight to 12 weeks. There
is a biggest process that focuses on an
aspirational future, is future backward and
typically has a three, five, 10-year horizon,
also a five-stage process, and can be
ongoing up to a six-month period to give
it enough space to generate something exciting.
And the roadmap for the company or the team is
built from a combination of smallest and biggest
work, which is like building a bridge from both
sides of a river. And ultimately, any strategy
is only as good as the results it can produce. So
test and iterate through execution and double down
on what's working and pivot away from what's not.
Incredible. I'm glad we did that.
Anything else that you want to share
or leave listeners with before we get
to our very exciting lightning round?
Just all the best with strategy work and
ultimately individual and business success.
Amazing. And when I asked you at the
beginning, before we started recording,
what your goal was for this conversation,
your answer was just to create a ripple of
success across companies and teams,
and I feel like we've done that.
Thank you.
Okay. With that, we've reached our very exciting
lightning ground. Chandra, are you ready?
Yes.
Let's do it. First question,
what are two or three books
that you've recommended most to other people?
Yeah, I love books on creativity and innovation,
Lenny, and some of my classic favorites
are Walt Disney's biography. And there's several
out there, but I think the one that I like the
most is the Triumph of the American Imagination.
And what's interesting is it talks about how Walt
Disney actually loved the theme parks more
than the movies. And the reason for that was
he could actually tinker with the theme parks.
He could make changes to where the rides were,
he could change rides in and out, and then
he could observe real sort of changes to
reactions of people flowing into the theme
parks, which he couldn't do with the movies
because once it was produced, it was done, it
was out of his control. And it was interesting,
he was basically A-B testing long before the
term was coined. And it's just a fascinating look
into how his brain worked, way ahead of its time.
The other classic is Ed Catmull's Creativity Inc,
and it talks about all the negative forces that
eat away at creativity in an organization. How do
you, as the leader, have to keep them at
bay and make sure the team can innovate?
And then there's this probably less popular
book, but really good one from Tom Kelly of IDEO,
which is The Ten Faces of Innovation. It talks
about different archetypes that you need on
the team that are essential for creating
something special. And you actually need,
I think there's the devil's advocate, you need the
researcher, you need the ethnographer, you need
the stage setter. There's all these interesting
personalities that you need to actually make
something successful. So I would say those are
some of the ones that I usually recommend, yeah.
That's a really cool... That third book is
really interesting, I haven't heard of that. And
Creativity Inc, something I want to highlight real
quick is to your point, that a lot of it is how to
avoid killing good ideas. And my favorite metaphor
from that book is the ugly baby metaphor where
every new idea is an ugly baby that people just
want to get rid of. Get rid of this ugly baby,
we don't want this around here. And just every
new idea is ugly when it starts, and you need
to protect the ugly baby, basically. Although I
don't know who's hurting ugly babies, that's not-
Yeah, yeah, it feels a bit... Yeah.
Feels aggressive.
Harsh.
Yeah, harsh. Yeah. But it's memorable
because I've never forgotten that.
Okay, next question. Is there a favorite
recent movie or TV show you really enjoyed?
Yeah, yeah. We watch a lot of
animated films with the kids.
But were a couple of good movies this
year. We really liked If, Imaginary Friend,
it's about growing up and forgetting
these memories of your younger days,
is was a really nice movie. And then of course,
we enjoyed Dune II as well. It was a fun watch.
But most of our time is dominated by the kids
sort of animated folks at home or the cinema.
There's a new Dune TV show, I don't know
if you've been watching it. It just started
recently on HBO. It's not the best thing in
the world, but it gets you a little Dune fix-
Interesting.
... in between movies. I think
there's a third movie coming out.
I see.
Third question, do you have a favorite product
you recently discovered that you really love?
Yeah, yeah. I've been playing this cute little
game for the last few days. It's called Capybara
Go! It's a tab-based strategy RPG game. It's got
really humorous writing and this cute capybara
that goes off on an adventure. It's very
well-paced and it's a very well-produced
game. It's one game I've been playing recently.
I've also been poking around Bluesky. Bluesky is
interesting. I haven't gotten into a habit yet,
but it's super interesting concept of empowering
the community with these community-generated
feeds. It's very different experience. But it's
also interesting, there's a trade-off with the
simplicity of the product and what you get with
the additional complexity. It'll be interesting
to see how it plays out, how it scales.
Do you have a favorite life motto that you often
come back to, find useful in work or in life?
So there was this 1995 interview of Steve Jobs
where he talks about this idea of there's a
tremendous amount of craftsmanship between a
great idea and a great product, and it sort of
stuck with me over the years. And the simple way
to think about that is it takes a lot of effort
to make something special. And conversely, if it's
easy, it's probably not that special or not that
great. And it's something that I sort of think
about when we build product, is there sufficient
pain here where it's sort of a proxy for, are
we creating something great, is interesting.
Wow. It makes me think about founder mode a
little bit. Like people talk about founder mode.
The reason founder mode I think is important is
the people that are most committed and passionate
and driven to go through that pain and continue
to make it... To take it from just an ugly baby
idea to an awesome winning product oftentimes
needs to be the founder. And that's why I think
it's kind of emerged as a trend is it's
important to have that drive, to just-
Surely. Yeah.
... continue to refine it and not just
like, "I had the idea, go build it now."
Okay, final question. You have an amazing
background behind you. [inaudible 01:44:31] if
people are on YouTube, it's just a beautiful
book background, a bunch of objects and books.
I'm curious if there's an object on there or a
book on there that might be fun to highlight that
you're especially into or proud of. And feel free
to turn around if you want to look around. Curious
if there's one thing that stands out, like,
"Oh, here's this thing, [inaudible 01:44:48]."
Oh, well, it's the picture of my kids right in the
center, which is without doubt the most important
and memorable thing there. It's also caught it
a unique time when they were incredibly... They
were sort of super embracing each other and
it's a phase where they've grown out of it.
Now there's a lot more, I think rivalry and then
sibling tussles. But that moment is my favorite.
I also have a bunch of fun stuff, like a big sort
of Snoopy fan, and so it is... Also a big Beetles
fan, so that picture is actually an interesting
blend between Snoopy walking, crossing the road
and then the Beetles crossing the other way. And
then a bunch of books that are more memorable over
the years. You'll see Creativity Inc there, you'll
see The Ten Phases of Innovation, all of that.
Amazing. Thank you for sharing... Your kids'
photo's blocked when you're in the center,
so it's like a little Easter egg. Thank
you for sharing that. Chandra, this was
incredible. It was everything I was
hoping it'd be. I think we're going
to create that ripple that you were hoping for.
Two final questions. Where can folks find you
online if they want to reach out? And
how can listeners be useful to you?
A reasonable choice would be LinkedIn to reach me,
and I really, like you and I discussed earlier,
I'd be really happy if this creates that kind of
ripple effect of successes, both for individuals
and for products. And I want everybody to think
of this, the stuff I shared as a bit of an open
source model. So test some of the concepts,
modify it, remix it, and share what worked or
did not. And ultimately, that's what makes it all
interesting is the community owns it ultimately,
and it doesn't belong to one individual.
That's what would make me super happy.
Amazing. Chandra, thank
you so much for being here.
Thank you so much for having me, Lenny, and
thanks for your service to the product community.
Same to you. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe
to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also, please
consider giving us a rating or leaving a review,
as that really helps other listeners
find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
LennysPodcast.com. See you in the next episode.