so it's the middle of the pandemic and I come across this very Grim but very interesting quote and it
basically said the greatest tragedy in life is not death the greatest tragedy in life is a life without purpose and I think about that purpose
and I thought about what I wanted to show up in the world and why I was here and put on this world and it hit me that
my why is I want to help people harness the power of Storytelling earlier this year I was
reading this book very dystopian sci-fi futuristic novel I'm not going to spoil it it's amazing go read it and it's set in the year 2020 before was written a
while back it's pretty accurate and it had this quote and I was like this this is why purpose is so important it unifies us it focuses our
dreams guides our plans strengthens our efforts purpose defines us shapes us and offers us greatness and we're all PMS I mean this is the thing that we're trying
to do in our product teams about a year ago um Lenny reached out to me to come talk I had the biggest imposter syndrome I'm like what the hell
am I going to talk about for 45 minutes it ended up being an hour and 30 minutes or more and really we were talking about this purpose and vision and since then
um he sort of forwards me emails that people send and the comments that are coming through and there's this kind of idea that it's this like very difficult thing and a lot of people sort of saying you know how do you bring this to life
and so we thought let's follow that podcast cast with a Playbook I joined YouTube right in the middle of the pandemic I just come from
Netflix and actually my boss was just my former boss was just on stage Unice and when I join any company I sort of say to
myself as any leader as any uh person of influence you don't have the answers in fact thinking you do is the biggest mistake so what I do is I go through this journey of conversations and that
leads to comprehension and then out of that comprehension will come my conviction and so one of the simple hacks that I used when we sort of got together and said we need to figure out
what the story is for our product which is YouTube Studio the way a lot of people tell stories all around the world there was a simple um hack we use
on the day one which is 10 Things I should know so invite lots of folks your marketing people your um Gap product counsel product managers uxr and one
after the other just tell me 10 things I should know and it forced people to sort of Stack rank what was important to them and so out of that sort of 10
Things I should know we locked ourselves in a room and came up with this vision and we called the purpose of that Vision expression meets connection which is how do you allow people all around the world
to tell their stories YouTube's mission is give everyone a voice I love waking up every day to that mission because giving everyone a voice is such a powerful thing and when you spend more
than a third of your life at work it's nice for that thing to be aligned with your purpose and so we said let's give everyone a voice through expression but
no one comes to shout into the void it's all about connection and so that Vision manifested as you know this product statement that we had and that product statement sort
of grounded in this notion of the product is a creative partner we brought that to life in themes Evergreen themes we said if we deliver these five things and keep those
in mind for our product as a creative partner then actually you know you will have an amazing product and then we brought the vision
to life with Sophia so Sophia is jenz um she is wearing a vegan leather jacket of course um in my day we called
it PVC and and um she doesn't think of herself as a Creator right no one really starts out saying I'm a Creator but the
fun fact is if you ask the average kid today Jen Alpha genen Z what do you want to be when you grow old they all say Creator and a couple of years ago it was
YouTuber so he said let's ground our story in Sophia and go through her journey and this sort of manifested as this document Google has short links so
it was like Go slash Studio 2026 and it was this 4-year journey of getting to how do we recognize her along the way how do we make sure that Community is key and it's not just a view or a
subscriber there's a human on the other side and we had three strategic pillars people think strategy is this very hard thing strategy is literally saying yet
no to a bunch of things that are great ideas it's never actually saying no to you know bad ideas like you already weed those out and it was we'll focus first on reaching everybody helping everyone
find their voice once we've done that we'll go into refining your voice how do you get closer to your story and then once you've got there and you succeeding as you found your voice how do we make
sure it's sustainable how do we make sure you don't burn out and that this literally that was our strategy there were four Marquee products it's a big deck it's like 42 slides but there were really these four
Marquee products and we said well if we bring these things to life will be the T Poes of making Sophia reach that Journey what was interesting was the
moment we put the deck out everybody was like oh my God it's Google insert Meme here um it's going to take forever it's never going to come to
life um the system will grind you down and I fundamentally believe in this quote which is if no one really ha no one hates it no one really loves it so actually I look and I provoke for the
people who dislike an opinion cuz actually that's a beacon of okay I've I've touched something and I'm very proud to say this year um I've given a lot of talks about Vision but it's the first time I'm a
actually able to talk about the vision that me and my team came up with at YouTube all four products are now live and they're on their journey to
realizing that sustain your voice for Sophia but sort of going from that I want to sort of level set when we talk about Vision I said earlier people think
it's this sort of ethereal thing so I believe there are four elements of a product Vision the first one is it's imaginative yet realistic it shouldn't
feel like it's completely unattainable but you feel like it's something that gets you you know super excited and inspired it gets the people going the movie Buffs know where that's from um
and then it's lofty and constraint free the moment you start to think about the Technologies of today or you start to sort of um Whitt it down to something very simple you've actually lost the
purpose of a lofty vision and then finally it's longterm and that means different things at different levels at my level I believe I should be thinking three four five years out and not just
for products for my own life as well and so the simple way to sort of think about this is if the purpose is this thing
that drives you and it's the why if you said for example I want to show that I'm capable of surmounting a very difficult challenge the why and so therefore I
will climb Mount Everest the mission and get there alive great Mission when you get there the vision at the top what you see as you describe it
the Himalayas the clouds that's the vision it's really that simple and so one of the first things I want to sort of demystify is go oh my God it takes forever and I was talking
to a PM recently and he was going on about my God you know we're doing all of the stuff and I'm not as excited um you know I wish we had a vision I said okay what stopped you from booking Out 3 days
and going out and creating a vision and he just stared at me you know dear in the headlights um fun fact we'll talk about him in a second he has actually delivered on that Vision you only need
three days and a bunch of passionate people and so I'm going to talk about 3 PMS because when I talk about Vision people think oh at this level you know I'm I get a lot of pings I'm in the org
I'm in ic how do I influence Vision so I want to talk about three L5 PMS these are like senior product managers so L8 at Google is like a GPM and L3 is straight out of University so that helps
you calibrate an Katrine Chris and lilon and elements from The Playbook that they use to bring the vision to life for their teams but a very important tenant
is you cannot and you should not do this alone humans are social beings we exist in community and actually we're stronger despite what people say or people think
we're so much stronger when we we do things together so I talk about these 3 PMS but behind those 3 PMS or with those 3 PMS are product teams with ux
designers uxr engineering leads who were hand inand with them bringing these Visions to life so the Playbook has
three parts empathize andv vision and evangelize and I sometimes joke that you spend almost half the time coming up with the empathize and envision as you
do evangelizing the most painful thing I've seen is to come up with this great idea and it's stuck in a document and so we'll go through each of these one by one the first being
empathize one of the playbooks um when I was at Uber I was converting from being general manager into a product manager and Yuki who was actually on stage um
did my conversion interview to being a product manager and I remember getting on a call with him and I said dude I'm trying to get these people to see this problem like they don't get it like how do I how do I get them to bet on this thing and he was like oh you have you
have to show them the Frankenstein and that's literally what um you know lilan did here and the Frankenstein is this sort of image that shows the Badness so
you've got this screen this is what YouTube Studio used to look like for Content it was very vaud we call it vaud even though vertical videos are also VA
but you would come on and it was just you know video and live and then we added podcasts and then we added playlists and then we added posts and
then we added all these things and lots more Badges and it just became very difficult for users to actually navigate um the experience also if you were a a
creator that used vertical video you would open that screen and it would be blank because it defaults to the vaud experience so she showed that Badness and then here you have an Katrine the
main app is the YouTube app you watch your videos on and what she did was she basically just showed this really messy IIA information architecture and you could you got it you're like okay we
need to fix this like it's all over the map the second thing in sort of empathizing is like grounding all of the the sort of work you've done understanding the problem into a single
Big Data headline and it's it's hard it's not going to be easy but if I bumped into you to you into in in the lift when I was at Uber I had a headline
which was 10% of uh rides or eats or experiences on Uber fail because of a payment issue when you're an80 billion company you're like oh wow and so what
is that one big data headline takes some time to find it but in an katrine's case she had this headline which was last year 42% of creators were in the main app they never downloaded YouTube Studio
this year 60% are in the main app and that number keeps growing and everyone got that so we set out on this goal to sort of meet creat is where they were and then the final
here is Chris he had this sort of what's out there one of my favorite interview questions is to ask tell me about a product that you recently discovered that you were super passionate about you
say I work for Google but it's an instant fail you say Google Maps or Gmail or Facebook it just tells me you're not curious and you don't you're not really keeping a pulse of what's going on out there and I I really love
going into product hunt and just seeing what's new and what's fresh and the reason is humans don't exist in a vacuum so what Chris did they spent like a massive chunk of their first day just
tearing down lots of apps apps that have nothing to do with YouTube Studio but had something interesting that they could draw from so you've got the empathized part
you now understand you know you brought this Vision the the the problem to life and you understand what the user problem is the next part is this Envision and making sure that you make it a little bit more
visceral so I love this quot quote cuz I go to the gym today was leg day I went to the gym and I've been sort of wobbling the whole day and I think about when you go to the gym and you sort of
like my my trainer will say the last three reps need to burn like it needs to feel like you can't do it anymore and by the way if your last three reps are not burning then you're doing it wrong you need to up the weights um and I and
that's that's how I think about it needs to be uncomfortable like I love ideas that sort of I'm dreaming about them problems where I'm like it it sort of consumes me but it also sort of scares
me like I'm excited about it but I'm a little bit scared of like making it come to life and that's really like don't be afraid of that that really has to has to happen the second nugget here is the
elevator pitch and you saw this earlier it really has six elements and you can put this in a Google sheet Koda whatever I print it out and I give everyone on
the team a piece of paper it's best when they're not on their screens and everybody fills it in and I've done this so many times and I I cannot tell you how many times a team is about to start
a project and they have a different answer to the user need they have a different answer to differentiator I kid you not I've had a different answer to the name of the
product so this is how it sort of comes to life um this is what an Katrine had for what we call Studio mini which is a version of studio in the main app and
you can see here how it's grounded in the user the need the key benefit and it's present so so you write this as though it exists already here is another
um uh example for a platform vision and you know the platform PMS need love too and so the mde what we call the MD is the metadata editor it's where you put your title your thumbnail your
description but again they wrote this statement of like how do we unlock the full potential of the content and then the final one is this
bringing the job to be done to life so I really hate user story stories like as a user tells me nothing about the context the emotions the feeling the goals of
the user I love jobs to be done because it tells me exactly what they're trying to do where they are what the goal is and you understand the context what they basically did was going through
grounding it actually in the overall team um strategy of Ana the surfer who goes through her journey of finding her voice and how the product is able to
meet her where she is give her highlights show the content mostly vertical videos at the beginning and then when she goes into refining her voice as she starts to reach a larger
number of subscribers she's looking at multiple formats she's trying longer videos she's looking at she's going through live and then you know that manifests in
this sort of experience where we're now helping them with creative a creative block with insights and what I particularly love about this and what lilan did here is the the the two products you see on the screen actually
had nothing to do with her she was redesigning this content uh page and actually Incorporated another team's idea and went to that team and said this is how I think this should come to life
and that's that really is true influence and then finally Ana goes to sustain her voice and at this point we're helping her dub her content and again that's another team and it's just this
beautiful um conversation starter with these different partner teams and then finally is the the concept car the concept car if you've ever looked at like a Mercedes concept
car or you if you're into cars or any of these sort of concept vehicles it's really the full car it's not just the steering wheel or the engine it's the full thing right even though you might
just be changing one element and so you know this example here is really the the team hooked up the entire app and it was this complete prototype with a short
link that PO teams could go play with and it was in all their newsletters and it just brought it to life you can use for research as well and it's a little bit different from a prototype so it's not just one screen that we're testing
it's the entire experience with notifications and an onboarding flow Etc so now you've got um your your you know you've got you've empathized you've got the vision and like I said the most
important part is actually evangelizing that uh Vision I was talking to a PM recently we were doing a retro I love Retros we're saying you know what's the learning from this experience and he
said something he was like I realized the real solution is always upstream and you heard this today in the talk with Yuki my ux partner put this together um on top of the Double Diamond
and it's really this notion of like solving the right problem and solving the problem right at Uber we had these five stages that I've carried with me because I'll sometimes go into review
and you heard this in the presentation earlier you'll find a team comes in they're showing a concept and I'm thinking oh God who's going to tell them this problem is not worth solving and so
it's so important that you carry your stakeholders along and just a really simple thing at the beginning of every slide when you come to present what we call uh product guidance or any of the
review meetings you put the color of where you are so are you at the stage where you're defining the problem are you at the stage where you're coming up with Concepts you at the stage where you're solutionizing etc etc and then I
can calibrate my feedback and then once you've got that and you've got the vision you can also Road Show and again there these three concentric circles you first tell the
team and get all the feedback from your team then you go to the stakeholders who are going to help you bring this thing to life and then you go to leadership and you have this sort of connected story and like I said people may not
love it that's okay because if nobody hates it that nobody truly loves it and once you've got all that one of the most important things is the moment you have
that green light to go forth and bring your vision to life the mistake I see people make is that the thing that they came up with they spend like nine months trying to get the first thing out the
door instead of breaking it into chunks right and so for example Lan she was going to design this content Hub she said I'm just going to fix the search component and make it multiformat and
that will show me the direction of where we're going and as soon as you start having those quick winds you start to build equity and Trust to finish the
vision as you go through all of this you just have to remember that the the vision might be this lofty thing and you can be very very stubborn about it but actually what comes to life will be a
lot of flexibility and details and I love this quote that really captures that a couple of years ago my team at Uber uh put together a vision and they
had this story using the bring the job to be job to be done to life where Dev had gone through his day woken up had his morning coffee and ordered um Uber
um through an Alexa we didn't there was no partnership with Amazon it was completely make believe the whole idea was would we have a payments experience
that would support that couple of years later last year actually I'm no longer at the company I saw this announcement and I thought holy cow wow it is so
powerful to imagine something in your head and to bring it to life and convince people and then put it in the hands hands of users and like I said we
had these four Marquee products they're now all live in the hands of customers it's a beginning of a journey and sometimes it's a long journey it took 13
months from the vision that Lenard for the content Hub to get the first version of the product out to life it took 18 months to because we had to hook up a bunch of things to get the idea of
moments and bringing that to life but this is a very one I'm very proud of it took Chris 71 days from the exec review to launching a gen product that gave
creators ideas and inspiration um for their next video and I'll leave you with this I have just talked about product Vision it takes a big chunk of your life but I
actually bring this into my life vision and I say to myself life is short but for every second that I'm on this planet I want to make sure that it was
completely aligned with my purpose and I did my absolute best to put a dent in the universe otherwise what's the point of being here and so I'm just I'm going to leave you with that I want you to go
back and think not just about your products but the vision for your life the why of why you are here because when we walk in our purpose Everything feels
aligned thank you