I have a cheesy Chrome extension.
Literally whenever I open a new tab,
it just says, how can you use AI to
do what you're going to do right now?
How do you see the future of
product development being different?
If you're not prototyping and building to see
what you want to build, I think you're doing
it wrong. It becomes even more important
to have that territorial and taste-making
at the heart of it because, otherwise,
you just have a Frankenstein product.
There's this acronym that you
taught me, NLX. What is that?
Natural language interface. NLX is the new
UX. Often I hear a product builders say, "Oh,
yeah. With AI, the model eats the products."
That doesn't mean it's not designed. You and
I are having a conversation. It's a podcast. I'll
have another conversation at Microsoft and that's
a meeting. Conversations also have grammars. They
have structures. They have UI elements. They're
invisible. What are the new principles, new
constructs in natural language as an interface?
I just saw that Cursor hit 300 million ARR in
two years. Interestingly, you guys were very
well positioned to do really well in this
AI coding tool space. You guys had Copilot,
the first tool in the world at this stuff.
So ahead of everyone, what happened?
I would say...
Today my guest is Aparna Chennapragada. Aparna
is chief product officer at Microsoft where
she oversees AI product strategy for their
productivity tools and their work on agents.
Previously, she was chief product officer
at Robinhood, vice president at Google,
where she worked on Google lens, search, shopping,
augmented reality, AI assistant, and a lot more.
She was also a long-time engineering leader at
Akamai, and on the board of eBay and Capital One.
In our conversation, we chat about how working
in B2B is like being Jean-Claude Van Damme doing
the splits across two moving trucks, how she's
operationalizing her team living in the future
so that they're building towards where things are
going, why people still need to learn to code,
why the PM role isn't going anywhere, why NLX is
the new UX, and so much more. If you enjoy this
podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow it
in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. Also,
if you become an annual subscriber of my
newsletter, you get a year free of a bunch
of products including Linear, Superhuman,
Notion, Perplexity, and Granola. Check it
out at lennysnewsletter.com and click bundle.
With that, I bring you Aparna Chennapragada.
This episode is brought to you by Eppo. Eppo is a
next-generation AB testing and feature management
platform built by alums of Airbnb and Snowflake
for modern growth teams. Companies like Twitch,
Miro, ClickUp, and DraftKings rely on Eppo
to power their experiments. Experimentation
is increasingly essential for driving growth and
for understanding the performance of new features,
and Eppo helps you increase experimentation
velocity while unlocking rigorous deep analysis
in a way that no other commercial tool does.
When I was at Airbnb, one of the things that
I left most was our experimentation platform,
break it, set up experiments, easily troubleshoot
issues, and analyze performance all on my
own. Eppo does all that and more with advanced
statistical methods that can help you shave
weeks off experiment time and accessible UI for
diving deeper into performance and out-of-the-box
reporting that helps you avoid annoying prolonged
analytic cycles. Eppo also makes it easy for
you to share experiment insights with your team,
sparking new ideas for the AB testing flywheel.
Eppo powers experimentation across every use case,
including product growth, machine learning,
monetization, and email marketing. Check out Eppo
at geteppo.com/Lenny and 10x your experiment
velocity. That's get E-P-P-O .com/Lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Pragmatic
Institute, the trusted leader in product
expertise. Pragmatic Institute helps product
professionals turn ideas into impact through
proven courses, workshops, and certifications
designed for real-world success. For over 30
years, they've trained more than 250,000 product
leaders at companies like Google, Microsoft,
and Salesforce equipping them with practical
strategies to build and scale market-winning
products. Pragmatic's full-time instructors
each bring over 25 years of hands-on leadership
experience, teaching strategies proven to
deliver real-world results. And it's not
just about what you learn, it's also about
who you learn it with. Completing a course
connects you to an active community of over
40,000 product professionals. You'll engage
in meaningful conversations, collaborate with
peers and mentors, and gain direct instructor
access to refine your strategies and stay ahead
of trends. Get 20% off with code LENNY20 at
PragmaticInstitute.com/Lenny. Aparna, thank you
so much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you, Lenny. Thanks for having me.
When I asked a lot of people that work with you,
what I should ask you about and what I should know
about you, something that came up again and again,
it's something that I think most people don't
know about you, which is that you're big into
stand-up comedy, and you take it semi-seriously.
Just how serious are you about this? How much of
your life is this and most importantly, how
does this help you build better products?
It's hard to say I'm serious
about a funny business, but
I do watch and do stand-up comedy. I
do open mics. I've done a few shows.
Wow.
I have one set brewing that is around AI,
unsurprisingly AI and tech and Silicon
Valley. It's really interesting for me. This was
an accidental discovery. I had always been an SNL
fan and Discovery fan, but I went to an open
mic because my son sings, and he went to the
open mic for singing and he is like, "Mom, you
should go do this." And I was like, "Oh, let me
go give it a try," and I found that I enjoyed it
and was good at it. To your question though, about
building better products, I'd say both have PMF,
I mean, product market fit, punchline market fit.
Actually, there are a couple of things that
I do find really powerful and useful because
in open mics or even when you're testing these
things, it's a very tight cycle of iteration,
and you get live... Open mics are the real
live experiments. You put something out there,
you get very clear micro feedback from users,
and then you get tough feedback sometimes.
And I think as product builders, that's
actually one of the great skills to have,
which is you sometimes launch stuff that have a
fantastic vision, but the first version is not
quite there. And Reid Hoffman says this, "Hey,
if you don't launch the first version and are
not embedded, you're doing it too slow." Just
that gap in closing that, it's good resilience.
Yeah. I never saw these corollaries between these
two things. I didn't realize you actually did
shows, and you're working on a set. I wasn't
going to ask you for a joke, but if you're
working on a whole thing about AI, is there
something that you can share from that set?
One joke I'd maybe share is people think about
these AI chat products as women because you don't
know what's going on. It's a black box, and
you don't know what they're thinking. There's
an entire set around that, but obviously on
the flip side too, that they're probably more
like men in the sense that they hallucinate
a lot. They kind of are not yet reliable.
I'm afraid to laugh with this
a little bit. This is great.
And even when they don't know the answer,
they make up stuff. They're very confident.
This is good. Where are we going
to be seeing the show by the way?
TBD.
Okay. This is great. Okay, let's get serious
again. So you worked at most of your career at
a lot of consumer internet companies. You worked
at Google, Robinhood, you're on the board of eBay,
you're on the board of Capital One. Now, you're at
Microsoft. I'm curious just what is most different
about working at a company like Microsoft and
building product at a company like Microsoft?
I think intellectually I knew that, hey,
enterprise, particularly the area that I look
at most at Microsoft is focused on enterprise and
productivity and transforming companies through
AI. And to me, I think two things really strike as
very different. One, in fact, I just posted about
this the other day saying, in consumer, you're
kind of like, "Oh, we have a playbook for make
the product work or make the feature work and make
it delightful," but I think in the enterprise,
you almost have... Every time you think
you have one use case, you have really two,
which is how do you make sure that the feature
works well and there's governance of the feature.
If you think about even something as simple as
sharing a link to a document, you want it to be
easy, frictionless, but at the same time, you want
that to be secure and safe and being able to have
auditability and all of those things. And often, I
find that when you go from a consumer enterprise,
you fall into a trap of either disregarding that
and say, "Oh, we'll just focus on one side of the
house," or overly crippling the user experience
side and leaning on the other side. So I think
there's an art and science and nuance and playbook
there too, so that's one big learning for me. The
other learning, and especially in the AI era
for me has been about this... I think there's
a famous trailer from the 2000s on Van Damme
on these two buses [inaudible 00:09:13] splits.
Like doing the splits.
Yeah, doing the splits, exactly. I feel like a lot
of the companies, including the tech companies,
but certainly the enterprises that I talk
to are in these two modes where one hand,
this is the most compressed tech cycle that
we've ever experienced. It's in the order of
weeks and months versus years and decades. If
you think about mobile and cloud and internet,
and there's just so much happening, the
intelligence overhang. On the other hand,
there's also humans and habits that...
Productivity habits change. It's hard
to change and change management through the
company is also hard. You don't want to be rash
on that. So it's like the future is unevenly
distributed but even within the companies.
On the second bucket of the bus that
Van Damme's riding on of governance
and adoption and changing behavior and stuff,
is there something you've learned about
how to get past that, help that along more?
The thing not to do is hold back folks who are
early adopters. I think that's the other one
learning. In fact, I think that's one of the
reasons why recently... I've been working with
folks to say, "Can we have both," which is the
longer-term change management, being able to do
it in a trusted way, at the same time do this
program we are calling Frontier program and
roll out cutting edge experimental features. We
just built this world's first deep research agent
made for work, post-trained for work. And of
course, it has all sorts of edges, rough edges,
but if there are only adopters in an enterprise or
outside, how can we put that in the hands of those
folks without insisting that all of the company
be completely developing different muscles?
This program Frontier you're talking about,
I wanted to spend a little time on
it. So what is the idea? The idea here
is people are working in this futuristic
environment. How does that actually work?
Yeah, I think the idea is exactly this,
which is I want to kind of institutionalize
and operationalize my personal model of
living one year in the future and say,
"What does this..." Imagine a company or a setup
like Frontier Consulting Group or Frontier Inc.,
right? And if you did live in that environment
where you had all the AI tools and really advanced
deep research intelligence on tap, what are the
kinds of questions you'd be asking? What's the
kind of work you'd be doing? How would you change
how you're going about your work day? So that's
the premise and you'd say, "Hey, how does it
change an individual?" But also down the lane,
we want to think about what does a Frontier
team look like. We talk a lot about Frontier
labs and models. I think models layer is
amazing and obviously that's what empowers
all these product building to happen, but I want
to push us to think about what does a Frontier
product look like? And more importantly,
how does a Frontier way of working like?
What does a team with three people and
tons of compute and AI tools look like?
So how exactly does this work? There's
a team within Microsoft that's like your
job is to use all of our latest tools and
build product using that. Does that work?
That is the setup. We are just
a few weeks into that setup,
but meanwhile what we have done is we've
actually set up a fake company and said,
"Hey, if you are somebody who wants to
come play with some of the cutting edge
science projects and deep research agents
and agents at work, come party here."
Wow. And it's only a few weeks
in. Okay, so TBD how it all goes.
Yeah. And again, these are micro... Let's
see. The meta point here also is that in the
traditional way, we've kind of always thought
about across the companies, across industries,
really thinking about roll-outs in these macro
ways. You build something and you kind of roll
it out, you have a general availability for,
and then you take the time. And that's really
important too because, again, we are talking
about pharma companies, legal companies relying
on this. So we do want to have that. But at the
same time, given the compressed cycles of AI,
how do we start to have people experience
what's the one year in the future?
Let's follow this thread in a few
different directions. There's how
product development changes, there's
how engineering changes. There's also
just agents. I know you're spending a lot
of time in agents, feels like you're not
an AI company these days if you're not
working on agents or building an agent.
Lenny, you're doing this wrong. You didn't use
the word agents so far into the conversation.
I try hard to push it out as far as I can.
It's like every conversation in San Francisco,
it's just like how long until I start talking
about AI? It's like three minutes. Average,
I bet. Oh, man. Okay, so with agents, I know that
you're leading a lot of this work at Microsoft
and a lot of people are wondering what the hell
does this mean? What is going to change? Give us
just a glimpse into how you see the world being
different in a world of agents being around more.
There's a short term and there's a long term,
right? There's a lot of hyperventilated, excited
talk about the eventual future and all of that.
I take a much more practical product building
lens on this, and I think about these. At the end
of the day, there are tools. Yes, underneath it,
there's stochastic models versus very
deterministic programming models. You can tell I'm
a computer scientist like the way that worldview
definitely shapes how I think about this. To me,
the short term is there's an evolution. We
had apps, and now I think we are firmly in
the assistance era where there's human driving
the... That's what we think of as co-pilot,
right? I think the human driving in the driver's
seat but having a lot of assistance from AI.
So I think of this as then you look at the
dimension of almost autonomy and delegation and
intelligence. As the intelligence, for example,
when deep reasoning unlock happened, of course,
then you can delegate more to the agent. So I
think, to me, there's one dimension where you say,
"Hey, agents are somewhat independent software
processes that can kind of run tasks," and
you're not just thinking about handholding
and fine motor stuff. You're saying, "Hey,
here's my goal. Go make this happen." I'll
give you an example. So we are working on
this researcher agent for work. And last night,
I said, "Hey, I have an important meeting coming
up with the leadership team. I really want to
present these frameworks here and this is the
roadmap here. Go back and look at all the people
that are in the meeting. What are their views
on this topic and come up with how I should I be
thinking about the right persuasion pitch here?"
And what's magical about this is not just that
it's saving time. Typically, we think about the,
so far, AI as summarizing a document or saving
time. This is like fighting synapses that I
didn't quite have and actually giving me
new insights and giving me, dare I say,
superpowers. So that's a natural evolution of
AI, I would say. So when I think about agents,
I think about three things. One is an increasing
level of autonomy and kind of independence that
you can delegate higher and higher order tasks.
Second thing I think of it is complexity. So it's
not just a one-shot, "Hey, create this image or
do this thing or summarize the document," it's
build me this prototype that expresses my idea
of, say, an augmented reality app. It's a complex
task. And then the third thing I would say is
asynchronous. It works when you are not working.
I think that's the other big thing about these
things that you don't have to sit in front of it.
This answers the question of
what is an agent essentially,
these three bullet points.
So what are the three again?
When I think about agents, I think
about these three things. So one, it's
autonomy like being... And it's a spectrum,
it's not a zero-one, it's how do I actually
delegate things that it can do. Second, I think
of as complexity. It's not a one-shot, "Hey,
summarize this document, generate this image,
but it's build me this prototype or help me
knock this meeting out of the park." And then the
third one I think of is it's a much more natural
interaction. That doesn't just mean chat,
but it may be actually jumping on a meeting
with the agent and being able to talk through
all of it or point it to things that I wanted
done differently. So I think all three things,
the autonomy, the complexity, and the natural
interaction are at least product principles
that will shape really good ones, good agents.
That is really helpful. Along this line of agents,
there's this acronym that you taught me as
we were chatting ahead of this podcast, NLX,
what is that and how does that relate to agents
and why are people not thinking about this enough?
Oh, that's one of my Roman empires these days.
The natural language interface. NLX is the new
UX. Here's the deal. To me, I think traditionally
we've thought very consciously about GUI because
the graphical interfaces are not something
natural, and so they have had to be explicitly
designed, but they're rigid interfaces. What we
have with conversational interface and natural
language is it's a much more elastic, right?
That doesn't mean it's not designed. Often,
I hear a product builders say, "Oh, yeah.
With AI, the model leads to the product. So
it's just you chat with it." You and I are having
a conversation, it's a podcast. I'll have another
conversation at Microsoft and that's a meeting.
So conversations also have grammars,
they have structures, they have
UI elements, they're invisible.
And so one of the things that I see and I'm really
excited about is what are the new principles,
new constructs in natural language as an
interface? I'll give you a few examples.
And actually a lot of startups as well as big
companies are really experimenting with this
stuff. One is if you think about it, prompt itself
is a new construct and that's a new UI element
just like a dropdown was or a menu was. But
others that are emerging, especially for agents,
I think are plans. So when you give a high
level goal, what we are seeing is that when
the agent comes back with a plan, preferably
an editable plan, that's a new construct.
The other one that I think about a lot is
showing the work, progress. You see this with
different products. You see with the Copilot, you
see with ChatGPT, DeepSeek, this idea of thinking
aloud and it's kind of showing the work, but how
much do you do it? If it's too verbose, it feels
like I'm running some cron job and scripts, but if
it's too terse, then I don't know if it's going in
the right path, and I don't have the confidence
yet. So there are all these new elements. So if
you are a product whittler, this is a fun new
space to be digging in for product design.
This is really interesting because I think
people chat with all these chat bots and it
just feels like this is just the way it is,
but you actually are designing every element
of the interaction, how much to share, but
how much you're thinking, here's my plan,
what do you think. So I think this will surprise
a lot of people, just realizing there's so much
that goes into just designing even these
what seemingly are simple conversations.
Yeah. Another good example is follow-ups, right?
You could say, "Look, you asked me a question,"
and then I could ask a follow-up set of things,
and that's explicitly should be designed for
success. So for example, if I said, "Hey, create
an image," and it created a black and white like a
clip art version of something. What are the next
obvious follow-ups that it should be suggesting
proactively? Now, too much and you are kind
of annoying me, but too little in some sense,
you've lost an opportunity to direct
me or guide me into a happy path here.
This resonates a lot with when we had Kevin Weil
on the podcast, he talked about this question of
just how much to show about what you're saying.
And it's interesting that DeepSeek went the
extreme of just showing everything and people
liked it too. I think that was interesting.
Yeah, and I think it's a point in time thing too,
Lenny, because in some sense right now these
things are such black boxes. They're almost
like peeking under the hood for anything.
Even if it's verbose feels like, "Oh,
I know what's happening," especially because
the compute inference time, it's taking long to
think. So it just feels like if you just went
silent, I'd be very uncomfortable, I think.
I know.
Exactly. So I do feel like there's that point in
time, but over time, I also feel like this is an
area ripe for personalization. For example, again
in human, my API would be very different from
somewhere. My interface is probably different
from others, and I might just want the direct,
"Hey, give me the TLDR," versus the, "Oh, so I
went here and then I went there," and I'm like...
Following the start a little bit. We're
talking about just how the future is going
to be different. There's designing for
these chat experiences, there's agents,
kind of zooming out to just product development
in general, it feels like you're at the forefront
of a lot of the tools that are going to change
the way we build products and also your teams
are working with a lot of these tools that no
one else has access to. So let me just ask,
how do you see the future of product
development being different from today most,
and what do you think product builders should be
preparing for doing to succeed in that future?
I'll start with one stark statement that I say
internally and externally, and I am trying to
live it is that in this day and age, if you're not
prototyping and building to see what you want to
build, I think you're doing it wrong. I call it
the prompt sets of the new PRDs. I really insist
on folks saying if you're building new projects,
new features of course come with prototypes and
prompt sets. And I think the notion is not to say,
"Hey, now everybody's just a biggest version of
a software engineer." It is to say you have the
fastest path to seeing and experiencing what's in
your mind to be able to communicate, right? It's
a much more high bandwidth way of communication.
I think about that as a really a loop accelerator
in terms of product building. That's number one.
When in doubt, as someone put it, demos before
memos, right? I think that's really number one.
I would say number two, this one is a little
bit tricky I'd say, is that what I'm seeing
is that the time to first demo is much
shorter, but the time to a full deployment
is going to take longer. So I think that there's
going to be an uneven cadence. So typically,
I think there was much more of a you've been
this thing, you take a few weeks and then you
can iterate and so on. But that inner loop of
prototyping and iterating and getting even user
research through AI conversations, all of that
gets shortened. But I think the bar for scale,
therefore becomes much high. In some sense, if you
look at it, there's going to be a supply of ideas,
a massive increase in supply of ideas in
prototypes which is great. It raises the floor,
but it raises the ceiling as well. In some
sense, how do you break out in these times that
you have to make sure that this is something
that rises above the noise? So I would say that
it's simultaneously thinking about not chasing
after every idea. I think is the second one.
I'd say the third thing is there's a lot
of conversation around full stack builders.
What does the team of the future look like? A
product building team. What I think about is
I think that is inevitable in terms of there
will be a few folks that are, especially at the
prototyping early idea discovery stage that the
lines of blurred, there'll be a few taste makers
at the same time. I think you can still have a
lot of people experimenting. It becomes even more
important to have that editorial and taste making
in a Frontier, one or a few at the heart of it
because otherwise you just have Frankenstein
product. That definitely doesn't change.
I have one other additional bonus thing, which
is a lot of folks think about, "Oh, don't bother
studying computer science or the coding is dead,"
and I just fundamentally disagree. If anything,
I think we've always had higher and higher layers
of abstraction in programming. We don't program in
assembly anymore. Most of us don't even program
in C, and then you're kind of higher and higher
layers of abstraction. So to me, they will be
ways that you will tell the computer what to do,
right? It'll just be at a much higher level of
abstraction, which is great. It democratizes.
There'll be an order of magnitude more software
operators. Instead of Cs, maybe we'll have SOs,
but that doesn't mean you don't understand
computer science and it's a way of thinking
and it's a mental model. So I strongly
disagree with the whole coding is dead.
That's awesome. I love that. And SO is a software
operator, what is that? What that stands for?
Yeah, I just made it up but yes.
Okay, cool. This idea of prototyping as being kind
of core to building these days, is there anything
you do within Microsoft to operationalize that
and make that just a thing everyone has to do?
Is it just culturally do it or is it like you
must show me a prototype before you show me it.
Again, the future is here, unevenly
distributed, even in Microsoft I would say,
but there is certainly a strong cultural
momentum and shift and desire to say,
"Hey, let's actually look at live demos, live
prototypes, and to even communicate the ideas.
And to me, I mean, it's not always possible
because obviously there are things that are
deeply... If you're trying to change something in
the bowels of Excel, you probably don't. There's
even enough depth in the product that what you
need to do, and you don't need to prototype
that. But if you're especially thinking about new
things and new products, new features, absolutely.
Okay, let's talk about product management.
There's this fear that emerged as soon as
all these AI coding tools came out of just like
PMs are dead, we don't need PMs. We could just
build things ourselves. What are these people
hanging around for? And what I found is it's
actually the opposite that now that coding
is easy. Now, the question is more and more,
what should we be building? Why should we
be building it? Is this right? Is this the
right solution? Then getting adoption for
it, which is what PMs are really good at.
I feel like it's the opposite. PMs are the
most important role. It'll change too, but
let me get your take. Just what do you think the
future of product management looks like? Do you
think it's dead? Do you think it's going to
thrive? Do you think it's going to change?
Yes. Look, if you are a TPS report, mostly
process person, and a lot of companies do
get confused about product management
and process and project management,
I think then you do have a question of, "Hey,
what is the value add here," especially if
AI can read and write 50,000 meeting notes
and track things and send emails and so on,
but what I do think on the flip side is the taste
making and the editing function becomes really,
really important. In a world where the supply
of ideas, supply of prototypes becomes even
more like an order of magnitude higher, you'd have
to think about what is the editing function here.
So that does mean that the bar is higher for
product folks, but I think there's an interesting
side effect I am observing in startups that I'm
advising, companies and even within the companies
that there used to be more gatekeeping I would
say, in terms of like, "Oh, we should ask the
product leader what they think." And again,
there is a role for that editing function,
but you have to earn it now. You just don't
get it because of this title, but there's
also just unlock of latent really good ideas
from smart engineers, smart user researchers,
smart designers who now have this expert in their
pocket to kind of round out all the other things
that they're not typically skilled at to bring
forward their ideas and that's amazing, I think.
And I think that expert, it's interesting,
I'm working with an engineer on some stuff
and he uses ChatGPT to even communicate
to me in a more effective ways like,
"Turn his pitch into something that will
convince Lenny, this is a good idea."
By the way, that is actually
one of my common use cases,
which is the WWXD I call it. What
would X do? I use it to say, "Hey,
what would Satya think about this particular set
of conversations or ideas that we are pitching
and so on." This is the power of, I think deep
reasoning plus relevant context, right? This
engineer you're talking about has that context
about you and so it's kind of very interesting.
If only everyone was as famous as Satya
and had so much information out there,
but I guess you can import all their
emails or whatever tools exist to just
understand from the conversations
you've had with that person.
Yeah. And I think this goes back to actually
what you were saying too, which is I think this
idea of what is the... There's like a coil spring.
There's an intelligence overhang that I just see
across the board. And I think the part of product
development has to almost rewire ourselves to,
I think, Tobi from Shopify calls it the reflexive
AI usage. And that's not as easy, and I've been
thinking about why. Basically, I mean, I have
a cheesy Chrome extension. Literally whenever I
open a new tab, it just says, "How can you use
AI to do what you're going to do right now?"
It's very cheesy, but it kind of helps to pause
and think, "Oh, what am I trying to do here?"
But the reason I find it hard, and when
I talk even people who are living and
breathing in this space, they find it hard
is that the updating of the priors is really
hard. The models couldn't do some things one
year ago. I mean, image generation was full
of spellings or reasoning. You just couldn't
have deeper and smarter answers. You couldn't
do data analysis. So my impression of it
from change, trying it a few months ago,
that prior needs to be updated. And it's hard to
do that, right? You have to do something almost
counterintuitive and against the grain
to say, "No, no, ignore what you learned
about what this can or cannot do." The baby
just grew up to be a 15-year-old in a month.
I think that last point is so important that we've
tried these tools over the years. And so far,
it hasn't been amazing and
then all of a sudden it is,
and you kind of don't know that and
you've given up almost and things change.
I think that's actually... If you are a
product builder listening to it, that's a
really interesting arbitrage thing for you. If
you can kind of cut against the grain and say,
"No, I won't have that scar tissue around."
This didn't work a few months ago and keep
setting high expectations and demand more of
the AI today, I think you can unlock more.
There's a lot of alpha in doing that.
That's right.
Today's episode is brought to you by Coda. I
personally use Coda every single day to manage
my podcast and also to manage my community. It's
where I put the questions that I plan to ask every
guest that's coming on the podcast, it's where I
put my community resources, it's how I manage my
workflows. Here's how Coda can help you imagine
starting a project at work and your vision is
clear, you know exactly who's doing what and where
to find the data that you need to do your part.
In fact, you don't have to waste time searching
for anything because everything your team needs
from project trackers and OKRs to documents
and spreadsheets lives in one tab all in Coda.
With Coda's collaborative all in one workspace,
you get the flexibility of docs, the structure of
spreadsheets, the power of applications, and the
intelligence of AI all in one easy to organize
tab. Like I mentioned earlier, I use Coda every
single day and more than 50,000 teams trust Coda
to keep them more aligned and focused. If you're
a startup team looking to increase alignment and
agility, Coda can help you move from planning to
execution in record time. To try it for yourself,
go to coda.io/Lenny today and get six months
free of the team plan for startups. That's
C-O-D-A .io/Lenny to get started for free and get
six months of the team plan, coda.io/Lenny. I'm
going to come back to this cheesy plugin, say more
about this. So this is a plugin that just lets
you put a custom message on every new tab, and
you have it say, how can you use AI to do this?
Yeah, it's as cheesy as that. And
it's interesting because it works.
In the last few weeks alone, I've
been doing this experiment to say,
"Hey, how much more AI pill can I get?"
Both at work and in personal life to say,
"When I'm trying to do anything manual,
should I be demanding the AI to do this?"
That's so cool. Do you know the name of this
Chrome extension by any chance otherwise?
No. No. I built it.
You built a Chrome extension. That's so
cool. Okay. Did you use AI to build it?
Of course.
Wow. Which tool did you use to do that?
Some kind of Microsoft tool I imagine.
Yes. No, actually, it was just like, I
mean, I live in GitHub and GitHub Copilot,
so I just was like, "Okay, let's
go build this Chrome extension."
Are you releasing this for the general public?
No, I mean, that's the amazing thing.
It took me like 10 minutes to do this.
Okay, let's link to it. Let's get it out there,
open source this thing. Okay. You mentioned Satya,
I have a question about this. So you're one of
the very few people that have worked very closely
with both Satya and Sundar at Google. Let me ask
you this. How do their leadership styles differ,
and is there just a fun story you
could share about each of them?
Yeah. I do feel lucky to have a window into
these two amazing leaders of this generation.
I would say, I mean, again, no surprise as you'd
expect from CEOs of multi-trillion dollar market
cap tech companies, they are 99.99 percentile in
almost every dimension you'd think of intellect,
empathy, leadership, product, strategy. There
are, of course, flavors of differences. I was
the technical advisor for Sundar for the first...
At Google and set up the office of the CEO there.
And they're, again, a matter of time and context
because there's a lot more consumer-oriented
focus there. So what I did find Sundar great
at it is being really calm and measured and
thoughtful in terms of making sure that things
have... Dealing with the complex ecosystems.
If you think about the phone ecosystem or even
the search and publisher and advertiser ecosystem,
it's a very complex ecosystem. He was a master at
that. He's a master at that. And I think on Satya,
I find it amazing the appetite he has for
learning and fine tuning his mental models
and just the zoom levels that he can operate at.
The macro, the strategy, what's the game? Also
the micro, "Hey, why are we not..." Here's
a specific insight that I saw on Twitter,
and you can count on the fact that he's ahead of
pretty much everybody else in terms of spotting
those early things too. So it's just been
learning from the firehose as they put it.
What a cool opportunity to work
with two incredible folks. Okay,
let's go in a whole different direction. Let
me just ask you this question that I've been
asking people more and more. What's the most
counterintuitive lesson that you've learned
about building products that goes against common
startup wisdom, common product building wisdom.
I don't know if it's as common as it should
be, and it's like a counterintuitive thing,
but I've repeatedly learned that when
you're doing something new, zero-to-one,
the temptation is to kind of think about...
It's like that South Park episode. Step one,
think about the problem. Step two, question-
Underpants. I think it's Underpants, step one.
Underpants. Exactly, right? So I do feel
like there's a temptation to rush and say
to go to scale before solve. So I've always said
to my teams solve before scale. So what that does
mean is there's a different posture and different
mode when you're trying to solve a problem versus
scaling something that's either post-product
market fit or even at least in roughly in the
ballpark. So to give you a couple of examples,
I think when you look at the solved stage, there
are wide lurches. You got to be very comfortable
with the fact that you're day one thinking about,
"Hey, a plant detection tool." And then day
15, you're like, "Oh, actually, the tech is
really good for translating foreign language." By
the way, this is not hypothetical. This is what
we kind of looked at in Google Lens back then and
said, "Okay, what is the intersection and so on?"
So from the outside, it looks like chaos,
but actually, in the... And you should be
very comfortable... Not only tolerant, I think you
should have an appetite for that because the last
thing you want is prematurely fix on one local
hill. And then you're climbing that in start-ups
and entire product areas and companies, big
companies make that mistake and three years later
you're like, "Oh, how do I get off this hill?"
So I'd say that's one big counterintuitive. When
you're trying to think about what mode you're
in, are you in the solved mode? Are you in the
scale mode? One example is kind of making sure
that you're comfortable with the chaos. I think
the other lesson I've learned is the danger of
metrics. And I think again, if you have worked
on Google Search or if you worked on Office
products, you really have a very fine-grained
sense of what are the metrics for this product?
You have the input metrics out, you have the whole
shebang, but when you're looking at something
zero-to-one. If you decide on a metric two
prematurely, that's false precision first of
all, right? I mean, CTR. When you have a thousand
people, it doesn't mean anything. Retention
also may not mean anything. So really being
very wary of this big guy, big girl of grownup
metrics as I call it, right? You are looking for
more qualitative, the sound of click, and what
is your... The other kind of the handler uses,
what is your set timer and play music? So if you
look at Alexa and Siri and Google Assistant and
all these things, they had a very promising
broad interface. You could say anything,
but I think there was one or two things that
it was really good at. You could set a timer,
you could play music, and you could play
trivia. And so you've got to nail those
things before you say, "Oh yeah, here you can do
anything with it," which is not a good recipe.
Not so funny. That's exactly
what I use my Google Home for,
so basic. I don't do the trivia thing
now maybe I got to give this shot.
Got to try that. Yeah.
There's something along these lines
that I've also seen you talk about,
which is how to go zero-to-one with
something, just a little framework for
helping you know if this is the right time
for this idea. How do you think about that?
Yeah. And when you think about the solved mode,
and this is again sticking with my whole living in
one year in the future, I gravitated towards the
zero-to-one and solved mode products completely
thinking about new category of products. And
what I've found, both the hard way I would say,
is that you do want to look for at least two
out of these three factors, inflection points
here if you want to make a really good product.
Number one is there a... Shift is a step function
in the tech. That's somewhat obvious I would say.
Deep learning was one for Google lens. Back then,
speech recognition was a step function for
conversational search. I would say for Robinhood,
the generational shift was very clearly, and
the fact that phones were a primary means for
you could actually have mobile app for finance
that you could use. So look for that inflection.
What is the tech inflection? And right now, of
course, like LLMs and reasoning models are that
step function, but that's not enough.
I would say the second factor that we
should look for is, what is the consumer
behavior shift? So to give you an example,
when we started working on Google Lens, what
we said is, "Look, people were taking mostly
pictures for sharing, selfies and sunsets and
so on. And suddenly, when storage became free,
mostly free, and everybody had phones everywhere
all the time, you took pictures of everything. And
then you had enough of pictures or you use the
camera as the keyboard for your world, for the
real world. And so how do you then say, "Oh, this
consumer shift is big, and so therefore, as you go
order of magnitude more photos, then you want more
to come out of them and you can apply AI to that."
And I'd say the third inflection point,
particularly I would say in enterprise but
also in consumer, is the business model shift.
Is there an inflection natural inflection point
in the business model? So any great products, if
you think about all the way from search, again,
the second price option and the fact that you had
CPCs, same thing with SaaS and the fact that you
could actually charge or monetize enterprise
products in a different way. And with AI,
of course the monetization is a whole different...
We've just barely scratched the surface of whether
you do seat monetization, usage like on
tap, and then of course outcome-based stuff,
outcome-based monetization. Hey, have you solved
the problem for me and then I will pay you some
fees. So all three to me are kind of like, great,
but at least two out of three for a good product.
So this essentially... When investors
look at startups, they're always asking,
why now? Why is this the time to start this
thing? And so your advice here is there's three
ways to look at it. Two of these three should
be true. There should be a shift in technology,
some new technology that has enabled this now
recently. There's a shift in consumer behavior,
and then there's maybe a new sort of...
Or you've invented a new business model,
any way to monetize something that it gives you
an advantage over folks trying to do it today.
Yep, absolutely.
Awesome. You did mention Robinhood,
I think in that example. That was
another good example of phones-
Yeah, I mean, talk about the business model
of, again, not having a zero fees. And again,
that combination of all of these things
is what can unlock it. You can't just say,
"Oh, we'll just have a much more better intuitive
interface and hope that people will switch to it."
Okay, so speaking of zero-to-one products,
I'm going to take us to a occasional segment
on this podcast that I call Hot Seat Corner.
And I have a question for you that is on my
mind and it's come up in a couple recent podcasts
actually. So there's these companies like Cursor,
VZero, Lovable, Bolt, Replit that are the
fastest growing company's history. I just
saw that Cursor hit 300 million ARR in two
years. Interestingly, you guys were very
well positioned to do really well in this space,
this AI coding tool space. You guys had Copilot,
the first tool in the world at this stuff,
so ahead of everyone. You build VS Code,
which is what all these companies are forking to
build on. You have incredible AI infrastructure,
incredible AI talent. So this could have been
your market. What happened? What happened, Aparna?
It's interesting, the framing... So I'm a dead
user of GitHub Copilot, and I would say, "Look,
if you unpack..." I think the beauty of this is
that code generation has become an amazing tool
that LLMs have unlocked. So it is actually
really good excitement and action that now
code generation has just opened up all of these
things that... We talked about the whole idea
of prototyping, goes from idea to marks and idea
to a clickable prototype in a few minutes. Those
are the kinds of things that, of course, we
should expect code generation to enable. The
way I think about how we are positioned and
what we do with GitHub is... So it's a system,
not just a product or a set of features.
If I think about GitHub, it's for folks who
have the repo there and you have... Of course,
you have the assistance in terms of autocomplete
and you can chat, but now we have the agent board.
It's one of the fastest loops that we are seeing,
really strong positive feedback. So in some
sense, when you have a system, what you are
looking for in terms of building and designing
it is not just a single product that can grow,
but what is the repository? What is your context?
What are the set of features that grow from your
expertise? If you're a really expert coder, you
want the assistance this product needs to scale
for that. If you're a wide coder, you should
still be able to do that and so on. So that
I think is the way that GitHub is positioned
to build on and growing honestly really well.
That's so interesting. So the core of
this is everyone ends up in GitHub anyway,
no matter what tool they
use and that's kind of the-
Yeah. The idea again is that code generation as
a tool will unlock lot more products. I mean,
they're not all competitors to the fact of...
They're not all kind of doing the same job.
I think when you are... At the end of the day,
you are building code for companies to run on,
you need to have a system. You need to have kind
of the ability, an entire Swiss Army toolkit, not
just the autocomplete, not just a chat, not just
like a software agent that runs and you kind of
hand hold. You need all of this to work together,
and that's what the GitHub product is going after.
All roads lead to GitHub. On
the flip side of this question,
there have been probably 5,000
startups that have tried to disrupt
Excel and you guys just keep winning, so
something there is working really well.
That is so interesting you say that. So when
I came to Microsoft, and I'm an Excel fan,
so I actually had a conversation with one of
the OG Excel product folks. I was like, "an,
what is it about this product?" And he said
a couple things that were really interesting
for me that just stuck with me. One is and I
said, "Hey, Excel is a proof that non-coders
also have to program." Programming is really
powerful and it's the tool that gives all of the
non-coders a really powerful programming ability,
and I thought that was just really striking.
And then the second thing that I found out
super cool, I don't know if you know this,
but I didn't know at least before two years ago
that there are these amazing Excel championships
like World Excel championships where you
see folks who can do just magic. And to me,
I think the insight here is also that
some tools are harder to learn. Perhaps
in the beginning there's friction in terms of
learning, but great to use. So it's a very good
case of, hey, the learning curve initially,
the one-time learning curve might be tricky,
but it is because there's so
much power and depth in the tool.
That's so interesting. I never thought of Excel
as a programming language, but it makes sense and
I feel like once you get used to it and this
is just the way things work, you're kind of
stuck there and everything else has to basically
copy that model, which is hard to be as good.
Yeah. And I think the depth then the
attention that the team has given,
and again, that's the compounding effect
over decades of working on deep, deep
signal from people who depend
on it day in and day out.
Okay. To kind of start to close out our
conversation, I want to ask this question
around your career. I find that most people
have one moment in their career that changes
the trajectory of their career. It could be
a manager they had, it could be a project
they worked on, it could be just the job they
landed. What would you say is the most pivotal
moment in your career that eventually led you
to becoming chief product officer at Microsoft?
Actually, there is one moment where it was a
turning point for me. I was in Google Search,
I was working on this idea that I thought
should just work and it didn't. I said, "Hey,
these phones are becoming a thing. Personalization
has to be important." So I probably banged my head
against the wall for a year or so trying to make
personalization work. And it turns out when you
have a query that you put into Google Search,
the personalization didn't matter as much.
And so we disbanded the team, but then I think I
started working on this product called Google Now,
which was a twist on that, which
said, "Hey, actually on the phone,
we should be able to push content. It's not about
searching with personalization." For example,
if you have a flight coming up, we should be
able to say, "Hey," connect the dots and say,
"you should leave now given the traffic and where
you need to go," and so on or if you're deeply
interested in stand-up comedy with deadpan
artists, you should check out Mitch Hedberg.
These are kind of these really moments that
the smartphone should be smarter. So I let that
product through the initial zero-to-one phase, and
that was a pivotal moment. It made me realize two
things. One, I really love seeing around the
corner and kind of seeing where things go and
building the product rise to the occasion way more
than the scaling and sustaining products. Second,
it's harsh, but being early is the same as
being wrong. This is pre-LLMs, pre-deep learning
a lot of the really amazing ideas in terms
of next token predictor, et cetera. We'd been
thinking of it but didn't have the horsepower to
go... The interface was great, the intelligence
wasn't there. And I'd say the third thing that
stuck with me is I got to work with some really
smart... They talk about talent density now,
and I think really smart people who have gone
on to do amazing things, and so it gave me a
taste of what a small group of people can do.
It's such a great story because it didn't
work out in the end. Google Now kind of
went away. And by the way, I super remember
that product. It was very cool. I remember
looking at it was very delightful
and happy. And so I also have this
segment on the podcast called Failure
Corner, where people share a story of
failure and how that helped them. And I
love this as a combination of those two.
Yeah. I mean, I'm not going to lie. I think it
was painful when you do that because you see
the vision of what can be and what is, and
sometimes it's hard limitations. Sometimes,
in this case, it takes five years or 10
years to really unlock the intelligence,
but sometimes it's one or two key
click stops away from the product
being great and part of figuring out is
knowing when you're in what situation.
How long was that period from starting out
until just moving on and it's not working?
Yeah, I would say in that case, one of the
good things is, again, it led the foundation
of... It was one of the foundations of the
Google Assistant. And of course, as the LLMs
step function happened now with Gemini, it kind
of works out. And I think it's the same thing
across the board, which is sometimes you want
to figure out the invariance that do work that
then go on to the next version of the product.
And other times, you just have to start over.
Is Google Now the first agent before
agents? That's what it feels like.
That was certainly the idea, but it is
fascinating to me that the interface,
that there, we had the opposite problem. Whether
you think about all the voice assistants, the
interface is like we overshot and
the intelligence wasn't there. Today,
I feel like there's an opposite problem. I
think these things have amazing intelligence
and the interface we have largely is
like the AOL Dial-Up Modem Chatbot.
We've covered a lot of ground. Is there anything
that you wanted to chat about or leave listeners
with, maybe a last nugget of wisdom before
we get to a very exciting lightning round?
I think I would say one thing that I'm really
excited about is this idea of figuring out how
we as people and agents collaborate together.
I think there's some great set of products and
experiences to be reimagined. That's my other
Roman empire, which is how do we actually have
this co-working space where you have the humans
and agents and how do you actually have an output
that's much, much more significant than what
any one of us or any few of us can produce?
Well, I need to hear more about this. When do you
imagine a co-working space of humans and agents?
What does this look like? Is this Microsoft teams
or is this a physical place with little robots?
Oh, I had a thought of the physical place,
but I am thinking a lot about... Right now,
all of these experiences are very
civil player, and I do think there's
an opportunity to think about how do we...
Again, I'm living one year in the future,
how do we actually have collaborate with
each other, but also with agents and really
figure out, for example, what tasks can we
delegate? What can we inspect? How do we
actually have information that flows between
people that agents can mediate, and so on.
All right, I'm curious to see what
you guys got cooking. With that,
we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
Let's do it.
Let's do it. First question, what
two or three books that you find
yourself recommending most to other people?
Oh, I have recency bias, but I've been
reading this book called The Brief History
of Intelligence, phenomenal book and like
lots of underlining from me. And I think it
kind of... The premises too, it looks at
the evolution of intelligence like human
intelligence and the brain development and
connects that to what we are seeing with AI.
Do you have a favorite recent movie
or TV show that you've really enjoyed?
Hacks. I've been watching this. It's about a
woman who's a great standup comedian of... I
think it's set in the fact that she grew up in the
'70s and '80s and really tried to break through in
an industry that hasn't traditionally been very
friendly to women, so really fun and quirky.
Do you have a favorite product that you've
recently discovered that you really love,
could be an app, could be some physical?
I do use a lot of Microsoft products,
GitHub Copilot being one of them,
but I think the one that maybe
I'll pick is Granola, I think,
is the name of the app. I found it really useful.
I just gave it a spin the other day and I'm like,
"Oh, this is really useful in terms of being
able to, again, without being intrusive, just
capture the thoughts, notes, and structure it, put
some..." It felt like one of those things where,
yep, the confidence of a few things like we
were talking about like the transcription,
real-time transcription tech has gotten
really good. Voice recognition is great,
and then enough of the LLM magic on top of
it to make it structured and contextual.
I am a huge fan of Granola. I'll give
a quick picture here. If you become an
annual subscriber of my newsletter, you get a
year free of Granola for your entire company.
Did not know that.
There we go, and then just check
that out, lennysnewsletter.com,
and you click the word bundle
and you'll see how to do that.
Very cool.
Very cool. Two more questions. Do you
have a favorite life motto that you
often come back to when you're
dealing with something maybe
you share with folks that they find
useful as well in work or in life?
I have one. In fact, actually, this is my email
signature for, I don't know, for the last 20
years or so. It says the best way to predict the
future is to invent it. I think it's a quote by
Alan Kay. I find it useful for two things. One is
no one knows anything. When you think about all
the folks who think about, "Hey, this is exactly
how everything's going to look and this is exactly
the sequence," and so on, I think there's
no substitute to experientially building it.
I think the second part is if you think there's
something that should exist, go build it.
I love that. Final question. We've talked
about standup comedy a bit. Is there a
favorite under the radar standup comedian
that you think people should go check out?
Oh, there's a couple of them. So one, I
think, there's an Indian American or I
think a British Indian standup comedian. Her
name is Sindhu Vee, super smart, mom comedy,
and I think the other one that... This
is definitely not under the radar,
but I just love his stick is
Nate Bargatze. He's just so good.
Aparna, this was amazing. Two final questions.
Where can folks find you online if they want to
reach out maybe and follow up on anything you
shared and how can listeners be useful to you?
You can find me on LinkedIn and Twitter.
Aparna CD is the handle. I do post stuff
a lot more on LinkedIn these days, so would love
to hear thoughts, comments, conversations there.
I'd say one thing that would be super interesting
is if any of this stuff spark conversations,
particularly around this, what can a
small team with a lot of AI tools do
or new products that folks are really excited
about, saying that they should exist, hit me up.
Amazing. Aparna, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you.
Bye, everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.