Everyone's always promoting dogfooding. It feels
though that you take this to a whole other level.
Either once or twice a month I will set aside
half a day and then I'll go out and I'll
drive and deliver. My team and I, we design
these amazing features. They look so good,
and then you get in the car and you
have a phone which is sitting three
feet away from you. You're driving at 45
miles per hour. The world just changes.
This thing that was looking so great in an
office setting, now maybe makes no sense.
When I was asking people about
you and what you're amazing at,
a motto came up again and
again. It was ship, ship, ship.
If you are going to go dog food and experience
this pain and you're going to document it,
what's next? You have to ship
this. You don't ship documents,
you don't ship brainstorming meetings.
What you ship is code in your product.
What are some of the most
impactful pieces of advice
that you share with early career product people?
What makes a great product manager is not five
amazing strategic ideas. It's the hows and micro
decisions that you made. Where should I put the
button? Should I put the screen there or not?
What should the copy say? Go to a job where you
can ship multiple products as fast as possible.
Today my guest is Sachin Kansal. Sachin is
chief product officer at Uber where he has
been for over eight years and where
he leads product management, design,
and product operations. Prior to Uber, Sachin
was chief product officer at Flywheel, a VP
of product at Lookout. He also spent the early
part of his career at Palm where he was director
of product management focused on Palm's mobile
operating system, webOS and their mobile apps.
In our conversation, we go deep into his passion
for dogfooding and now he makes this a big part
of the product culture at Uber. He's personally
done hundreds and hundreds of drives as an Uber
driver and also as an Uber Eats delivery person.
I've had a lot of people come on this podcast talk
about dogfooding. I've never met anyone that takes
it to the extreme that Sachin does. Much of what
the product team works on at Uber comes from what
he and his team discover from these experiences.
We also talk about why it's important to
always have a ship, ship, ship mentality,
PM career advice for early career PMs, how Uber is
planning for a future with increasingly autonomous
cars and what changes over time, what he's learned
from Uber's shift to efficiency and profitability.
Also, a bunch of really good tips for how to
avoid annoying your Uber driver and Uber Eats
delivery person. This episode is full of wisdom
for anyone who wants to build better products,
teams, and cultures. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. Also, if you
become an annual subscriber of my newsletter,
you get a year free of a bunch of world-class
products including Linear, Superhuman, Notion,
Perplexity, Granola, and more. Check it
out at lennysnewsletter.com and click
bundle. With that, I bring you Sachin Kansal.
Many of you're building AI products, which
is why I am very excited to chat with Brandon
Foo, founder and CEO of Paragon. Hey Brandon.
Hey Lenny. Thanks for having me.
So integrations have become a big
deal for AI products. Why is that?
Integrations are mission-critical
for AI for two reasons. First,
AI products need context from their customer's
business data such as Google Drive files,
Slack messages or CRM records. Second, for AI
products to automate work on behalf of users,
AI agents need to be able to take action
across these different third-party tools.
So where does Paragon fit into all of this?
Well, these integrations are a pain to
build and that's why Paragon provides
an embedded platform that enables engineers
to ship these product integrations in just
days instead of months across every use case
from RAG data ingestion to agentic actions.
And I know from firsthand experience
that maintenance is even harder than
just building it for the first time.
Exactly. We believe product teams should focus
engineering efforts and competitive advantages,
not integrations. That's why
companies like you.com, AI21 AI21
and hundreds of others use Paragon to
accelerate their integration strategy.
If you want to avoid wasting months of engineering
on integrations that your customers need,
check out Paragon at useparagon.com/lenny.
Last year, 1.3% of the global GDP flowed
through Stripe. That's over $1.4 trillion and
driving that huge number are the millions of
businesses growing more rapidly with Stripe. For
industry leaders like Forbes, Atlassian, OpenAI,
and Toyota, Stripe isn't just financial
software. It's a powerful partner that
simplifies how they move money, making it as
seamless and borderless as the internet itself.
For example, Hertz boosted its online payment
authorization rates by 4% after migrating to
Stripe, and imagine seeing a 23% lift in revenue
like Forbes did just six months after switching
to Stripe for subscription management.
Stripe has been leveraging AI for the
last decade to make its product better
at growing revenue for all businesses,
from smarter checkouts to fraud prevention
and beyond. Join the ranks of over half of
the Fortune 100 companies that trust Stripe
to drive change. Learn more at stripe.com.
Sachin, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
It is great to be here, Lenny,
thank you for having me.
When we were exploring what to chat
about and where to spend our time,
there's a bunch of themes that came up both in
our conversations and also when I was talking to
people that work with you at Uber and other
places. And the theme that came up over and
over is dogfooding. And dogfooding is something
that comes up a bunch on this podcast. Everyone's
always promoting dogfooding. It feels though
that you take this to a whole other level and
you do this better than anyone I've ever spoken
to. You're basically world-class at dogfooding.
There's a lot I want to talk about here, but
before we get into it, just give us a sense of
what dogfooding looks like in your world. What
is the scale that you go to, to dogfood Uber?
I mean call it dogfooding, call it just obsession
about the products that we ask our end users to
use and we should be using it ourselves. So in my
world, what it looks like. There are a few apps
in my world. There's the Rider app that everyone's
familiar with. There's the Uber Eats app and let's
not forget there's a driver and a courier app
as well. So dogfooding looks like the following
for me in general, on an average, I end up taking
maybe five to 10 trips or Uber rides every week,
which just happens because I'm an Uber rider.
Now, when I'm traveling, that's probably even
more. I end up placing maybe three orders, three
Uber Eats orders every week. Sometimes that's
too much. And again, when I'm traveling, that
could increase. If I'm traveling with family,
it can be a lot. It could be literally all our
meals. So those are probably more explainable,
more understandable. The volume goes up and down.
But then, how do you test the driver app? So I
actually go out either once or twice a month.
I will set aside half a day or a day and then
I'll go out and I'll drive and deliver here in
the Bay Area. So I've been doing that for many,
many years now. I will say that's probably one of
the best parts of my job. I really, really enjoy
it doing trips as well as doing deliveries, and
maybe every time I go out, I'll do about 10 to 12
rides and deliveries. So that's what dogfooding
looks like at the outset. That's the fun part.
The painful part then is, "Okay, what did I
learn?" Because it's very easy for me to do this
and then just completely forget about it,
not document it, use it anecdotally in some
conversation but not be able to go into a lot
of detail. So what I do after each of these
instances, whether it's using the Rider app or
whether it is driving, I take a lot of screenshots
and then I come back and I write documents or I
add to an existing document. So I have a driver
document, I have a Rider app document, I have
an Uber Eats document and I'll come back and
I'll just write everything that I learned that is
probably not ideal. I'll add a lot of screenshots
to that doc. I will tag people because I know
who works on what and then I'll just send people
my thoughts on what we think we can improve.
And after that, we have a process internally
which where we go through all of those issues, we
prioritize them, not everything that I thought is
a great idea is necessarily a great idea.
So we go through all of that and then we
fix issues. And I'm not the only one dogfooding
in the company, but I do follow through on the
things that I reported and make sure that things
that should be fixed get fixed and as quickly
as possible. So that's the the end-to-end
journey of dogfooding for me in my work.
How many trips have you taken? How
many rides have you driven? How many
food delivery trips have you done total? What
are the numbers here just over your time at Uber?
I think from a driving and delivering perspective,
in the seven to 800 range now and I don't know
as a passenger how many trips I have done. I
can't count that. Same for Uber Eats, but the
driving and delivering is many hundred trips.
Wow. Yeah, I think on riding on Uber and getting
food delivered, that's not so hard. To your point,
the real hard part is driving and delivering
people's foods and taking them places. Also
on the docs, I think you're also underselling
yourself when your colleagues or Ricky told me
that you write 40-page reports on what's broken
with screenshots and suggested fixes. And then
like you said, you follow up on all these fixes.
You don't just put them out there and then hope
people do something with it. You actually stay
on top of them and make people feel accountable.
Lenny, when I find those issues in our app, I
develop a bit of impatience because if I faced
it in my 10 trips that day, we have eight million
couriers and drivers in the world. So imagine the
number of times that thing may have happened to
our customers, which are drivers and couriers.
So I develop a bit of an impatience that we have
to fix it, we can't. Now, some things are small,
some things are big. I develop different
levels of impatience for different things
depending on the level of severity, and then if
I don't follow up or my team doesn't follow up,
and if you don't fix it, then it's a moot point.
Then I'm just doing it for fun, which is not bad.
It's great for me to be doing it for fun, but I
want to do it for impact and I also want to do it
for setting an example with my team as well.
Now again, I'm not the only one dogfooding.
We have hundreds to thousands of people at
Uber. We want it to be a part of the culture,
but we don't want the culture to be that every
individual product manager should be going out and
dogfooding their own feature. We want the culture
to be that every leader is doing that as well. And
that's why I don't want to be shy about or want
to shy away from writing these documents because
I want everyone to. And now there are many, many
documents written by many, many people at Uber
and honestly it's making our products better.
And I would say even more important than the
specific features that we fix or we add, it's the
culture of we are not just going to accept certain
problems in our products, we are actually going
to fix them. That's really, really important.
So let's talk about just why
this is so important to you.
I want to talk about how you operationalize this
in the culture of it at Uber, but just as a CPO,
I don't know of many that go draw people off
hundreds of times deliver food to people's
houses hundreds of times. I imagine you have many
things you got to do day to day. There's hiring,
there's drama, fires, all these things.
Why do you prioritize this so highly?
Here's my framework of how we think about
end users. Of course, end user feedback is
important. Everyone would agree with that. Every
product manager, every product leader would agree
with that. How do you get that end user feedback
I think falls on a spectrum. There's the extreme
quantitative end of the spectrum and there's the
extreme qualitative end of the spectrum. And I
like to believe that you need to be across that
spectrum. So on the extremely quantitative part,
we all love data. We all look at charts. And
in those charts, every user is an MAU or a DAU.
Every user is a number and collectively as those
numbers users are showing certain behaviors and we
learn a lot from that and that's a very valuable
exercise. You move a little bit to the left of
that spectrum and now you may go into things like
surveys where you're actually sending out surveys
to thousands of riders. You're quantitatively
understanding, do they like A, do they like B,
do they like C which is also very, very valuable.
Then you get into a little bit to the center,
maybe I have a room of 10 drivers and I'm asking
them, it's a focus group, it's a discussion,
and for an hour I learn a lot from them. It
becomes very interesting. We do this anytime
I go to a Brazil office, I go to our India
office, I go to a UK office, at a minimum I
do one or two roundtables with drivers. I also
do roundtables with riders. It's just extremely
valuable to hear from them directly. You move
one step further and now I may have a one-to-one
conversation with one of them. By the way, in the
rides that I take every single day, it's such an
amazing opportunity for me to do two things.
As a passenger, I'm talking to the driver for
30 minutes off my commute and I'm basically
one-on-one interviewing them and because the
driver app is placed in a certain way, I can
actually see how they use the driver app. So
that actually drives me a lot of learning and
every day there's an aha moment that, "Oh, this
is what he just did." A text message came in and
then he left the driver app and then he went and
addressed the text message and so on. So there's a
lot to [inaudible 00:13:54]. All of that is great.
However, until I get behind the wheel or
I'm a passenger or I'm using Uber Eats,
what I miss is the visceral reaction that you get
when something happens. So now, think about it. I
sit in my office, my team and I, we design these
amazing features. They look so good on my MacBook
or on a Zoom screen, and then you get in the car
and you have a phone which is sitting three feet
away from you. You're driving at 45 miles per
hour. The word just changes. This thing that
was looking so great in an office setting now
maybe makes no sense or there's a lot of stuff
that you have to change. So that's what you feel.
But then as you are trying to make money doing
that, every single little inefficiency, every
single flaw is costing me my earnings. And while I
don't do it for money, so I don't think I can get
to the extreme, extreme end of how drivers feel,
I think I can get close. And the only way
for me to feel that emotion is by doing it
myself. And I do think that that emotion is
very important. I'm a big believer in then
bringing that emotion to my work, whether it's
an emotion of joy, I have many, many moments
of joy and I bring that back and I celebrate
that and that's very motivating for my team
and I. But there are many emotions of outrage.
And I want to bring that to work as well and
make sure that we can use it as a motivator to do
better. So those are my reasons to be dogfooding.
What's an example of something that's super
outraged you that you experienced as a driver
especially and/or something that maybe is the
most surprising that you learned as a driver?
Let me start with the surprising and then I think
we'll get to the outrage part of it and there may
be things that you may not expect. The surprising
thing as I mentioned before was how the app just
feels different when it's actually in a moving
car at 40 to 60 to 70 miles per hour. That was a
surprise for me. The positive surprise is there's
a dopamine hit you get when you get an offer. I
get an offer, it's 20 bucks. I'm picking someone
up from point A, I'm dropping them off at point B.
There's a bit of an excitement angle and I don't
want to overplay it. Earners, drivers work really,
really hard to do their job, but I think
that part of our product, there's a bit of
an excitement to it. That was a surprise to me.
I will go into a few individual features,
but even at a more meta level, the thing
that surprised me the most is we obsess
about our app and our app is the center of our
universe, but when a passenger gets in the car,
the center of the driver's universe is that
interaction with the passenger. That human touch
between the driver and the passenger is something
that we don't talk about in the office enough.
And if you talk to the driver and when I'm a
driver, if the passenger is friendly, it lifts my
mood. If the passenger is grumpy, then I'm unsure
what to do. If the passenger is rude, which has
also happened, that can really be demotivating.
I want to share one anecdote with you. This was
way back almost eight years ago when I started
driving. This was probably my fifth or sixth trip,
so I was very, very early in my journey
of dogfooding. So it was early morning,
I think it was a Saturday morning maybe about
7:00 a.m. I was picking someone up, it was a lady,
I stopped my car on the curbside. She got in, she
was going to the airport, she was going to San
Jose airport and she had a suitcase, but she left
on the curb and she's inside the car and I'm like,
"What's going on?" And it suddenly dawned on me
that she's expecting me to get out of my car,
grab her suitcase, open the trunk,
and put the suitcase in the car,
but she didn't say anything. And then I suddenly
realized that there is an expectation of me as
the driver doing that part of the job as well.
And since I was very early in my journey, I had
not internalized that and the kind of emotions
that ran through me at that time just explained to
me, "Hey, what does a driver actually go through?"
That was a somber ride for me. That was a somber
day for me. And since that day, I have not
forgotten what it feels like to be a driver and
I carry that emotion with me and that has built
a level of empathy in my mind for drivers. And I
want to make sure that my team understands that's
their life and everything we build for them has to
have that level of empathy. And I would say that
was a big surprise for me. It's not just about the
app. Yes, there are many features in the app that
we can talk about which are also surprising, but
what does a driver feel day in and day out as they
interact with other human beings was a big one.
I love that. I want to talk about how you actually
disseminate this culture within the product team,
but out of curiosity, I always wonder what
pisses off a driver as a rider? For example,
do drivers like short rides or do they
like long rides? Does it not matter?
I think the short or long rides can be very
personal. There are some drivers and the great
thing about our driver base is there's a lot of
heterogeneity in terms of their preferences. Some
of them do like shot trips because it keeps them
closer to their home, they can make a decision
to go back whenever they want. Sometimes we have
incentives which if they do 20 trips, then they
get something more. They're able to do that. And
some of them just like a long trip because they
don't want to do multiple pickups and drop-offs.
So I think there's a lot of heterogeneity.
If you want a tip for what not to do to annoy
a driver, I'll give you a couple of tips. It's
totally okay for you to be on the phone. We have
to do that. Just ask them for permission to say,
"Are you okay if I'm on the phone?" They will
always say yes, but it will just annoy them a
lot less. So that's number one thing that I've
learned. The number two, on your way out do not
slam the door. It is their car. It is their final
moment of interaction with you. Close the door
and do it softly. That will ensure that you
actually get good ratings from the driver.
These are great tips. I know you can
check your actual rating now on the
Uber app as a passenger and so it's not
5.0 for most people including myself,
so this is good to know what might've caused
that. Oh, man. Okay. One other just that I want
to follow here is you spending so much time
on the experience implies that that is a huge
lever for growth and retention and long-term
success. A lot of people in growth and product
don't see it that way. They focus on what's
a metric we can drive, what's a conversion
opportunity here? They're not just like, how do
we just make this experience better? Can you just
talk about that insight of just why you believe
just making that experience better so important?
I think it's not an or, it's an and. I do
think that obsessing over your metrics,
especially when it's funnel metrics and
understanding all the points of friction,
numbers do tell the story. So I think you do need
to have the experience points whether they are
observed anecdotally or they come through some
other means as well as understanding the points
of friction because of drop off in your conversion
funnel, they're very important. But you can't just
have that. Because if... I mean, you're talking
about end users, if it becomes just a mathematical
exercise, I don't think that is enough, because
as I mentioned, what they're actually feeling
in the moment is something that numbers will
never show. And numbers will not bring the
level of intensity that emotions will bring.
Now the question is, do you have a culture
that allows coexistence of both? Does it allow
a coexistence of you bringing emotion as well
as the numbers? And that's what I am trying
to create every day. Our leadership team is
trying to create every day, the product team, the
engineering team is trying to create every day.
I think we have done a good job of having
a coexistence of those two in the company.
Okay. And then, so how do you operationalize
this and make this a part of the culture at
the company? Clearly, part of it is modeling it
and just doing a lot of it yourself. What else do
you do to help product people build this empathy
and dogfood as much as you do or just some extent?
I mean I do it. Tara does it. So there is
definitely just doing by example or teaching
by example. We also organize around it, because
I think creating a little bit of an organization
around it just helps. We are a large company
now and we try to assist with this by centrally
organizing. This means let's make sure that
everyone understands what it means to be an
Uber driver, how to sign up for an Uber driver.
Some people may be on visas and so on. So there
is a regulatory part of that. So we make sure that
everyone understands how to sign up. Then we also
organize, every year we organize, every quarter
we organize one week of driving and delivery.
And we have a little bit of a competition. So we
have hundreds of employees who go out and drive
and deliver and there's a competition of who can
do the most number of trips and who can bring in
the most amount of feedback in terms of things
to improve and we have prices and so on. And
that's just taken off over the last, I would say
especially the last maybe three years post-COVID
because during COVID I think it was a little
bit harder for us to gather everyone together.
And then the last thing I'll say is, what do you
do with all of that feedback? Because that's when
the "boring" part starts. Now you're gathering all
these documents, you're taking all those issues,
you're putting them in your Jira tracking
or whatever tracker you may be using and
you're fixing them. So what we have done
is you have set a six monthly OKR. So we
have set an OKR that we are going to fix
300 of these issues. Every team actually,
the driver team will fix 300 of these issues.
The rider team will fix 300 of these issues,
and same for the Uber Eats team. Now, I don't
really care whether it's 300 or 200 or 500.
The number actually doesn't matter, but the
fact that there is a number is what matters,
and we have been hitting those targets
every single half over the last two to
three years. So these are some of the things
that we do to operationalize it and make sure
that people understand that this behavior
is not just expected but it's also rewarded.
I imagine what's challenging about this is there's
also work to do that will clearly drive growth,
will clearly cut down support tickets, will
help with infrastructure costs. So these OKRs,
there's "Just fix these things that we know
suck. We don't know what good they'll do,
but we know they're not good." How do you
balance that in resource and prioritization
versus all these other things on the roadmap
that you know are going to drive a metric?
We have a pretty good balance set of OKRs. So
let's say one of our teams has six OKRs just
illustratively over the next six months. One of
them would be ... We call them fix-its, so we sign
up for 300 fix-its for the next six months. In
addition to that, we do sign up for a growth goal.
We sign up for a retention goal. We sign up for a
cost savings goal. And each of them have projects
behind them and the executional rigor is a pretty
big part of Uber. So for all of those projects,
we actually have, and I get engaged in that as
well, we have pretty serious executional rigor.
Now, OKRs are not meant to be hit hundred percent.
I think we celebrate if we hit about 75 to 80%
because you do want to set stretch targets,
and then every half we do planning. And we will
allocate resources between all of those OKRs. So
fix-its, for example, don't get all the resources,
but they also don't get zero resources, which
may have been the case if we had not set a
culture which celebrated this and allocated
resources towards this and rewarded this.
Awesome. Okay. Clearly, an important
ingredient here is the CO and C-suite
on down values of this as something we will
invest in and we'll trade off all focus on
growth for this because we believe this is
going to help us grow and win long term.
Absolutely, absolutely.
Some people hearing this just as a final
question along this area are going to feel like,
"Okay, Uber so easy to dogfood. Of course, I
order Uber Eats every day. I'll go and ride.
So good. This is what a dream. I'm dogfooding like
crazy." But a lot of people work at Oracle and
Snowflake and I don't know, Fivetran, all these
companies where it's much less, non-consumer
product essentially where it's more difficult
to dogfood. Just any advice for folks that want
to create a culture of dogfooding and up their
dogfood game at a product that isn't consumering.
So first of all, we thought the same when we
thought about the driver app as well because
it was a little bit distant for people. Now, I
would say while it is more difficult than just
ordering food and taking a ride, it is not as
difficult as perhaps some of the other products
that you mentioned. But I do think that you just
stretch that even further. We do have a product
we call Uber for Business where it's a business
admin using it. We do have our merchant product.
So Uber Eats is actually three sides of the
marketplace. The eater, the consumer, the courier
who's bringing your food and there's a restaurant.
Now, how do I dogfood the restaurant product, for
example. So these questions are very, very valid.
So my guidance would be, and what I try to do is
try to get as close to that customer as possible.
So in the case of a merchant, we go spend time at
restaurants. I'll give you a latest one. So we
have a cafe here at Uber on campus. We also have
a barista. So we enable the barista to be an Uber
Eats restaurant, and they have an Uber Eats tablet
and I can actually order from that barista. So
now you're dogfooding being an eater, you're
dogfooding being a courier and you can dogfood
being a merchant. So some of my product team,
they actually will go to the barista, they'll
stand behind the counter and they'll experience
what it feels like for these orders to come in.
We have very close relationships with our big
customers such as McDonald's or Domino's and
all of them. We also have a lot of small-medium
business restaurants and we have relationships
with them which allows us to go and spend days
with them so that we can observe what life is like
behind the counter for a restaurant worker, for a
kitchen worker, how does our product show up, and
we learn a lot of stuff, Lenny. And I would ask
everyone who's listening, irrespective of the
product that they're working on, go to the nth
degree of how much you can stretch. And if it's
really an IT admin at your customer who's using
your product, I would do two things. A, go to that
IT admin and sit next to them and observe them
using the product. B, set up what we call test
accounts and try to pretend to be an IT admin and
set up that account. I went through our merchant
setup flow, which I can just do by setting up a
test account and I learned so many things of all
the points of friction that we are putting in that
flow. So I think there is still a lot that you
can do even if you do not have a consumer product.
Awesome. So the advice there is just find a way,
get as close as you can. You may not be able to
ride an Uber, drive an Uber car, get an Uber
ride, but there's some way you can get really
close. You may not be exactly do the thing.
Awesome. Okay. I'm going to go in a different
direction and there's another theme that came
up again and again when I was asking people
about you and what you're amazing at. And a
motto came up again and again it was ship,
ship, ship. Talk about that. Why is this
motto, this way of working so important
to you? Why is it something you try to
encourage everyone to always think about?
I think it's actually a natural extension of
what we just talked about. If we are going to
go dogfood and experience this pain and you're
going to document it, what's next? You have to
ship this. I'm a big believer in you don't ship
documents, you don't ship brainstorming meetings,
you don't even ship designs in a Figma. What you
ship is code in your product. That is the only
thing that actually ultimately has impact
on the end user. So as I mentioned before,
I develop a sense of impatience. It's a
positive impatience if you will, that,
"Okay, I just observed a problem for our
riders or for our drivers. They have to
get a solution to that as soon as possible."
And for that, you have to ship, ship, ship.
Now, you could interpret ship, ship, ship to
be just mindlessly shipping. No, this is not
about mindlessly shipping, but once you know that
you're working on something that is important,
that is solving a problem, it could be a big
feature or a small feature, then you have to
cut down the cycle time. My biggest enemy is
the cycle time of we know it is a good thing
all the way to our users seeing it, you have to
minimize that time. So that's why ship, ship, ship
has become such a motto for me and we try to do a
lot of things internally operationally for us to
enable that. And I'll say we still are not there.
In my opinion, I think we can still be faster,
we can still cut a lot of that cycle time, but we
are on a constant quest to get as good as we can.
What does this look like in practice other
than just reminding people, "Ship, ship,
ship. Ship, ship, ship." Just repeating this
mantra. How do you help people ship faster,
to your point, not just
work all night and all day,
staying long hours, just what are some
ways to actually operationalize this?
I think it stems from the cutting down cycle time,
which is the time it takes to make decisions. I
realized that a lot of the time is not... I
mean, all the time that you spend documenting
the requirements or designing the product
or actually writing code is time really,
really well spent. All the time that is
spent in between those activities to align,
to discuss a decision, to not make up your
mind, then have a meeting the next week,
"Oh, let's regroup two weeks from now."
That happens in our companies a lot.
The question is, how do you cut that down? And for
that what we do is we have product reviews and as
much as possible we try to come out with decisions
in those product reviews. And you have to operate
in a one-way door versus two-way door concept.
If something is a two-way door, you have to
be able to make the call quickly and you want
to make a good call, but if you get it wrong,
it's okay, we can turn it back. If it is a
one-way door, if it's a massive launch, sure,
it's okay for it to take some deliberation.
Maybe it even goes through the C-suite and
we have a discussion, but my guidance to my
team is cut down the decision-making that has
to happen or to cut down the time required for
the decision-making between those various steps.
A few things I heard that you do that you didn't
mention that I think helped with this, one is that
there was a period where you ran daily stand-ups
with cross-functional teams during COVID just to
keep things moving. There's another story I heard
where you wrote a 15-page PRD over the weekend to
unblock a stall team. It feels like these are ...
look for opportunities to unblock essentially.
Well, I want that to be an exception rather
than the rule, but yes, I want to be able to
step in or I want all our leaders to be able
to step in when needed. I think you have to
be hands-on. You have to be hands-on when needed.
Those two examples, we were coming out of COVID,
we had a massive shortage of drivers on our
platform and we were talking about growth
earlier and we had clear goals on how we grow the
number of drivers on our platform all the way from
getting new drivers in and improving the funnel
as well as regaining existing drivers. And Lenny,
there was no shortage of the number of ideas, but
again, there was a problem with cycle time. So
I said, "Great, our cycle time is going to be 24
hours." And so I think there was a period of about
six months when we did do daily stand-ups and
they were extremely helpful to unblock the teams
on making certain decisions and we shipped a lot.
And I think it took us about nine to 12 months,
but we were able to come out the other
side having a great number of drivers.
And the great thing is that what we did in
our driver and courier funnel at that time is
still paying off because the number of drivers
and couriers continues to grow and now we are
worldwide at about an eight million number.
And we were probably close to half of that
when we were just out of COVID. So that's
an example of where daily standards help,
I try to minimize that. The PRD exam, yes,
I did write a PRD. It was a 15-page PRD. We
were working on a pretty big concept and it was a
risky concept. And it was driver facing and that's
always high stakes. And by this time, we have had
about 20 conversations and brainstorm meetings and
documents that had been written with the best
intentions, but thing that was not becoming
clear is, hey, what should we actually ship?
Because there were a lot of good ideas and not
so good ideas, but no one was actually putting it
all together to say, "This is what we're going to
ship." So it was one Sunday night and I literally,
it took me two hours and I just wrote down,
I'm like, "Guys, this is my stake in the ground.
We can completely change it, but this is the
product we will ship. Agree or disagree." Now, the
product that we eventually shipped was at least
50% different than what I had written down, but it
just catalyzed us getting to that endpoint. Now,
if I were to do that every single day or every
single week, then I would say there's a problem.
Yeah, you wouldn't have time
to deliver food and give rides.
That is exactly right. Or I would not
have time to do hiring or I would not
have time to do performance reviews and
so on. But once in a while, I think it's
totally fine for product leaders to step in,
especially if you're trying to remove ambiguity
and you're trying to just speed decisions
up. It's okay to step in and be hands-on.
Another tactic that I heard that I want
to ask you about, someone anonymously
said that you ask for live demos. And here's
the question, he always insist on doing live
demos that make everyone nervous when
they present. The question is, why?
So I think they may be talking about when we
do product announcements. So when we do product
announcements, externally, on stage, et cetera,
I do insist on actually live demoing the product.
Part of this comes from, I grew up as a product
manager back in the day in the 2000s at Palm.
Palm where the Palm Pilot. Palm was cut from the
Apple clock. There were a lot of ex-Apple people
there and we were in the consumer electronics
business. And every single year the way you would
announce your product is you would get up on stage
and you show the product working. And leading
up to that moment was a lot of massive amount of
work to make sure that it actually works on stage.
Now, I will say there's an internal
reason and an external reason to do this.
The external reason to do this is you have
to tell a story. One of my other beliefs is,
which I may not have shared before, is no one
actually really cares about the feature that
you want to talk about. People are way too
busy. You are obsessed about your products,
you, your products are your life, but for your
end users, your products are maybe 10 minutes of
their life once a week. So their life does not
center around your products. They don't care.
How do you make them care? You have to tell
a story and that story comes from actually
showing the product in action rather than a lot of
slideware and pictures. So that is my belief that
I don't want to have hubris about my own product.
I need to be able to tell a story about how an end
user will actually get value out of that. That's
my external reason for why I insist on live demos.
My internal reasons for why I insist on
a live demo is while it is a lot of work,
I think it creates a certain level of rigor ahead
of time before the product is ready to launch.
Because if it is going up on stage, it has to
work. And two, you may ask the same person who
asked you this. It creates such a sense of pride
amongst the product team and the engineering team
to actually see their product live on stage
and now it's on video and it'll stay forever,
to see the product that they put their
blood and tears into actually working.
I think that's a huge moment of pride and I
take it as personal responsibility to make
sure that I can help bring that moment. But
yes, leading up to that is a lot of work.
A lot of stress. Okay, that was a great answer.
Today's episode is brought to you by Coda. I
personally use Coda every single day to manage
my podcast and also to manage my community. It's
where I put the questions that I plan to ask every
guest that's coming on the podcast. It's where I
put my community resources, it's how I manage
my workflows. Here's how Coda can help you.
Imagine starting a project at work and your
vision is clear, you know exactly who's doing
what and where to find the data that you need to
do your part. In fact, you don't have to waste
time searching for anything because everything
your team needs from project trackers and OKRs
to documents and spreadsheets lives in one
tab all in Coda. With Coda's collaborative
all-in-one workspace, you get the flexibility
of docs, the structure of spreadsheets,
the power of applications, and the intelligence
of AI all in one easy to organize tab.
Like I mentioned earlier, I use Coda every single
day and more than 50,000 teams trust Coda to keep
them more aligned and focused. If you're a startup
team looking to increase alignment and agility,
Coda can help you move from planning to
execution in record time. To try it for yourself,
go to coda.io/lennytoday and get six months
free of the team plan for startups. That's
coda.io/lenny to get started for free and get
six months of the team plan. Coda.io/lenny.
I'm going to shift our conversation a bit to
general career advice. I've got a bunch of
questions. I actually asked the community, my
newsletter, Slack community, what to ask you,
and they had a few really good questions
that I want to run by you. So one is just,
what are some of the most impactful
and recurring pieces of advice that
you share with early career product
people that you find most helps them
get unstuck and most helps them move to
where they want to move in their career?
One is go to a job where you can ship multiple
products as fast as possible. Comes back to cycle
time where you can ... Let's say over a period
of two to three years, you can go through three
to five product cycles as fast as possible because
you want to put that under your belt. Don't worry
too much about how you show up in a room. Don't
try to spend too much time on being the smartest
guy in the room. Just define the product, work
with your engineering, with your design team,
with your data team and ship that product.
Rev that product, iterate on that product,
ship the next product. What you will find as
you do that over those two to three years,
three years later, you'll suddenly realize
that, "Wow, I've actually shipped a lot."
And the other thing that I strongly believe is
what makes a great product manager is not the
five amazing strategic ideas you had over those
three years. It's the thousand micro decisions
that you made, not the five macro decisions that
you made, but the thousand micro decisions that
you made. Where should I put the button? Should I
put the screen there or not? What should the copy
say? Do I launch this product in Atlanta or in New
Jersey? You go through these and what you want at
the end of that is you'll start developing
an innate sense of judgment. So you want to
increase your cycle time to be able to get to
judgment as fast as possible, because when you
make a similar decision the 10th time, you don't
even have to think about it. It just happens.
And we constantly talk about experimentation
versus gut or data versus gut. As you progress
in your career, you want to develop that gut
as fast as possible, because in my opinion,
that's what differentiates a good product
manager from a great product manager,
that they have developed some extra level
of gut and they're able to make the correct
decisions because of the experience
that they have had over that time.
Another way to label what you're describing
as product sense, which is something a lot of
people are always told they should be building
and are very unsure how to go about building it.
And what I love about your advice here
is this, is you find a place where you
could just ship over and over and over and
that keep that cycle time down. And there's
almost like implicit advice here is if
you're working at a company that takes
a long time to ship, this is probably not
a good place to be starting your career.
That's right. That's right.
Another question from the community, this
is from James Conway. He asked that. Okay,
so you've been in product for about 25 years,
something like that at this point, right?
That's right. 24 years. 24 years.
24, okay. Almost 25, almost there. Oh man,
that's a long time. Okay, so the question is,
what's remained constant throughout your
career in product and do you think that
constant will hold even as AI starts to change
the way that we build product and build teams?
I think there are many things AI is changing and
AI will change even if ... What did I work on
24 years ago or how did I do product management
24 years ago is different than product management
today. The way we write PRDs, the way you
do designs, the way you make decisions,
the fact that you have access to data today
didn't really exist 24 years ago. The only
data that you had was surveys and those surveys
took six months to run and for data to come back.
And now we have instrumentation and telemetry and
everything that we ship and we can analyze data.
So I would say things have definitely evolved.
With AI, things are just going to change even more
rapidly. I'm already seeing on a weekly basis we
are introducing a new way of doing things and if
you look at a typical product cycle all the way
from doing market research and user research to
writing the first draft of a PRD to doing the
first draft of Marks, doing user research and
even storytelling that we talked about, how do I
actually tell the story about my product? AI is
making all of that much, much easier. And I think
that transformation is going to happen very fast.
What has not changed in those 24 years
is you having to understand what your
end users want. And I know that's kind of
the cliché of product management. "Yes,
of course I have to understand what my end user
wants." I think it is harder than we think. I
think it takes more than we typically do to
actually really get your finger on the pulse
of what your end user feels. And I think that
that has stayed constant. I think that is the
holy grail, not just to understand one
archetype of an end user. At Uber here,
not only are we operational in 75 different
countries, even in a single country like the US,
we have different kinds of end users, whether it's
demographics, whether it is socioeconomic status,
and for us to internalize what do end users
want, AI will definitely speed it up, but for
a product manager, it is going to stay constant.
The one thing I do think product managers need to
be aware of is the importance of knowledge
is going to stay, it's going to continue,
but the importance of judgment and as you
mentioned product sense and the gut feel
that is going to become even more important in
the world of AI. As a result of that, we need to
increase that or reduce that cycle time even more
so we can develop that product sense and judgment.
Sort of along those lines, there's a question I
got from, I don't know if he's the CTO of Uber,
CTO of part of Uber, Praveen who
I believe you work with at Uber.
Yeah.
Okay. So the question here was,
ask him what he hates from engineers.
Does that ring any sort of bells?
I think Lenny, that's a trick question.
He wants to get me into trouble. I'm sure.
Let's get you into trouble. Let's do it.
I'll tell you, I actually know the answer to this
question. What I hate about engineers is when you
on a project and they say, "Hey, I can't do
anything because I do not have a PRD from a
product manager." Now, while I consider that to
be important for my job security and a PM's job
security, for a PRD to be required, I also think
that the best engineers are the ones who actually
don't need to start with a PRD. They can have a
whiteboarding session with a PM, with a designer,
they should have just an equal seat at the
table in terms of what we are going to build
and then they co-create. They should co-create
and they should write a document together and
they should just build. One of the things that
some people like about me and some people probably
hate about me is I'm very boundary-less
from an art perspective in how I operate.
So if someone has a product opinion, it doesn't
matter whether you're in the product org or the
ops team or customer support or engineering
or design. I think everyone's opinion matters
and is valid and I welcome that. I welcome
their participation. I don't care about org
boundaries. Now, at the same, time, I will have
an opinion about how we message our products.
I will have an opinion about maybe some
engineering architecture to the extent
that I understand that or I will have
an opinion about an ad campaign or how
we operationalize our product. So in
that spirit, what I hate is if we are
blocked because a certain document was not
written to the nth degree of specificity.
I love that you answered the question.
That's great. And I think what's also
interesting along those lines is it's a
lot easier now to write a good version of
a PRD/one pager with AI tooling where you
just like, "Here's what I want to build,
help me craft it into something very specific that
we can use as a product requirements document."
And you have so many tools now.
We do a lot of brainstorming,
we do whiteboarding. You could actually
convert summaries of those conversations
into the first draft of your PRD. So there
are many tools available now. So I don't
think PMs or engineers have any excuse
to be blocked because of lack of PRDs.
All right, amazing. I want to ask a few Uber
questions. I think there's a few that a lot
of people think about when they think of Uber
today. The first is, it feels like there's just
this big elephant in the room of what does Uber
become as self-driving emerges, we see all these
self-driving cars around Uber's historically
been drivers, people driving cars. What is
the vision of where Uber goes in a world where
self-driving becomes more and more of a thing?
Yeah, it's definitely a big
area of conversation internally,
externally. So absolutely agree with you on the
importance of it. If you rewind back the clock,
we actually had our own self-driving unit,
and during COVID, we decided to divest off it.
I remember.
And we decided that we're going to take a
partner-oriented approach and that is the approach
that we have taken since then. Over the last
year, we have signed about 15 partners. In fact,
we just announced another partner earlier
this afternoon called May Mobility. So we
have been announcing many, many partners when
it comes to AVs. Now, that's our strategy. Now,
what does that actually mean? What do these
partners do? What we are building is we are
building a hybrid network. The hybrid network
has a hybrid of human drivers and AVs on the
same network. And we work with partners. We have
a set of APIs that we have built. It's a very rich
set of APIs and we have partners who basically
integrate with those APIs and get access to this
hybrid network, this hybrid marketplace.
And let me explain why that is beneficial.
These cars are expensive. These are assets that
need to be utilized. And if let's say a city
has 500 Avs. When it is 10:30 a.m. on a Tuesday
mid-morning, we know that demand is going to be
really, really low and you may have a lot of these
vehicles actually sit underutilized. Whereas when
it is Friday evening at 6:00 p.m., you don't
have enough cars to fulfill the demand that
you will have at that point. So if any of these
partners try to operate that service themselves,
it can definitely work. But you're going
to leave either customers dissatisfied or
you're going to have underutilization. So our
hybrid network really allows them to equalize
that because when you don't have enough cars, we
are able to send drivers to fulfill that demand.
And then given that demand density that Uber
brings, we are also able to utilize all the
vehicles even if it is 10:30 a.m. on a Tuesday.
So that is the value proposition of our network.
We are big believers in autonomy. We think
autonomy is going to lead to more safety. It
is going to take some time. So as we project
out, we don't know if it is going to be five
years or 10 years until it sees a certain
kind of scale across the world, across many,
many cities. We are in about 75 countries today,
roughly about 15,000 cities. So there's a huge
geographical landscape for us to capture as
well. But that's our strategy. And so far,
we recently launched in Austin with
Waymo and that's been going really well.
And we of course have Phoenix with Waymo. We
are going to be launching Atlanta soon. We've
also launched internationally in Abu Dhabi with
our partner WeRide. And then there are many more
launches that are going to come down the road.
So very excited. And by the way, I talked about
mobility. Delivery has something similar. So we
have sidewalk robots with many partners who in a
downtown area for a short distance delivery are
actually doing thousands of deliveries today.
Oh wow. I've seen those robots. They're very cute.
I always wonder how they get to where they're
going, but clearly it's working. The Waymo thing,
I've totally noticed that Waymo basically in some
form has decided to move away from their own app
in many cities and Uber is how you get a Waymo,
which I don't think a lot of people understand.
So what I'm hearing is essentially the strategy
is just be the super app for getting around
and getting food and Uber drivers are a part
of that and part of that is autonomous
vehicles. And is the idea over time it
will stay that way? There will always a need
for humans to drive cars for a long time?
I will answer that in two ways actually. I
think for a long, long time there will be a
need for humans to drive cars. There are
pickup and drop-off spots that AVs can't
go to today. There are going to be regulatory
hurdles that we have to get across before AVs
are everywhere and so on and so forth. Second, we
have a mission to make sure that we can provide a
great earnings opportunity on the Uber platform.
Today, that is fulfilled by driving people and
delivering food or delivering groceries. But
that list is going to continue to expand,
and we want to make sure that we offer more and
more earnings opportunities on our platform.
Even me going back to dogfooding about,
I think about a year ago I also started
picking up groceries because now we have a pretty
large grocery business. And I have gone and I've
carried crates of water up a flight of stairs
and delivered that to the doorstep. And there
are more things that we will do as well. We
have a partnership with Walmart where we may
send a courier who may pick up 15 different
bags and deliver it to 15 different homes.
So the need for human drivers on our platform
or human earners I would say is just going to
continue to increase because we're going to have
multiple earning opportunities for them over time.
I love that visual of you carrying up big
jugs of water to some random person's house.
I think they tipped me well.
I think that was a good tip.
By the way, what do you do with the money you earn
from this? Does you just keep it
or it's like it goes somewhere?
So we have a policy that the money actually is not
kept by us. We refund it back to
the riders or to the eaters. Yeah.
What do they see when they get this
refund? They're just like enjoy.
Actually that's a good question.
I don't think that it says that
this is because it was delivered by an
Uber employee. It's a good question.
I should go back and see what it says.
But we do refund it back to them. Yes.
We're dogfooding right here.
Yeah.
Okay. Another question that I want to touch
on is Uber, it feels like Uber was one of the
first companies to take profitability really
seriously. I remember Dara meant tweeting or
sharing this insight during COVID I think of just
investors and public markets are now valuing cash
flow profitability. We need to change the way
we operate. You guys have clearly done that.
It must've been a pretty hard thing to
do for a company that was used to just,
famously all these companies raised
a bunch of money, scaled like crazy,
blitz... What is it? Blitz scaled as Reid Hoffman
called it and then making a big change like that.
I imagine it was very hard. What was that
experience like? Just switching cultures
from just raise money, go crazy
to profitable cash flow business?
I think it was awesome. I think it
was a great, great period, because
if you are taking inefficiency out of your
system and you're taking the dollars you
saved back into the business or back into the
end user's pockets or the driver's pockets,
that's just a great feeling. And as you said,
doing that is not easy. It's actually very,
very hard. But that's where real innovation
actually kicks in. Let me give you an example.
One of the ways that you would take cost out
of the system in the delivery world is to batch
trips together. So when a courier is delivering
from point A to point B, maybe they can deliver
two packages. They pick both of them up at point
A and they deliver them to point B and to point
C and point B and point C happened to be close
together and there we just delivered a lot of
efficiency with the courier's time. And now you
multiply that by a thousand different ideas that
we may have both in the mobility business as
well as the delivery business and it's a grind,
Lenny. There was a grind in terms of, how do we
take inefficiency out of something like that,
which is our core marketplace logic. How do we
take inefficiency out of how we do promotions? How
do we take inefficiencies out of support costs,
payment costs, background check costs? There
are many, many pockets and some of that required
building new paradigms and building new software.
And when you actually save that money and you're
able to put that back into the business and become
a profitable company so that you don't go under
and your stock price goes up, that's actually
feels very, very rewarding. I think that Dara has
done an excellent job driving that. I think the
company has done an excellent job responding to
that. I feel that that still goes on today. Yes,
we became profitable about two years ago and now
we are driving great margin quarter over quarter,
but the spirit of making sure that our core is
solid in terms of efficiency, it continues to
feed the system and continues to allow us to then
make more bets that may be outside of the core.
I imagine a lot of companies are going through
this same experience now, trying to cut costs,
try to be efficient, the government,
the US government's going through this,
it's very difficult to do well without cutting
things that are really dear to people, especially
at a product company, big bets that are going
to maybe pay off in the future. Big innovations,
things people are really excited about. For
people trying to do this at their company,
do you have any tips? I don't know, one or
two tips to do this well to keep morale up,
to not lose sight of big opportunities
in the future? Anything there?
Yeah, I think we divested out of two big
businesses, which were our self-driving unit as
well as what we call Uber Elevate and we divested
out of both of them during COVID. COVID was a very
special time for us, if I could use that term.
Our mobility business dropped by 80% overnight
and I think that Dara and the leadership
team actually showed tremendous leadership
during that time. And one of those was to make
those calls to divest out of those businesses.
Now, I think an important part to remember is you
could be on the quest to just drive profitability
and you may lose your sight on new growth bets
as we call them here and how do you do that. So
I have my framework on this, which is I think of
our portfolio as concentric circles. The center
of that concentric, the core is our core product.
We do 33 million trips every single day. And if
you think of a typical Uber trip or an Uber
delivery, there is a multi-point failure
possibility all the way from you opening the app
to a driver, accepting or you doing the pickup,
doing the drop-off and you getting a receipt. And
then similarly, there are a number of steps on
the Eat side. And we obsess over making sure that
that core is as flawless as possible. And also to
our point about profitability is as efficient
as possible as well. So imagine taking even 1
cent of efficiency out of 33 million trips every
day, the numbers just really start to add up. So
you have to make sure that you're paying a lot
of attention to that. As I go out and dogfood,
I'm dogfooding the core mostly and making
sure that it is flawless in my own little way.
And if you're spending enough attention on that,
then you get the license to expand out of that
core and start to think about other growth bets.
By the way, this is where Uber Eats came from
back in the day. This is where Uber Groceries come
from, which is now a very large business for us.
And on the right side, Uber Reserve, Uber for
Teens, which is something I launched a couple of
years ago, our focus on taxis and there are many
other growth bets that are now in the billions
of dollars in total. That's where it came from
because we are making sure that the core is being
paid attention to and it's giving us the license
to go out off that in that concentric circle.
There's another area of Uber that it feels like
is shifting a bit. So historically, I know a lot
of people that have worked at Uber over the
years, Uber has this reputation of being very
data-driven, very ruthless with prioritization. A
lot of what you've been talking about feels like
the opposite of just anecdotes and experiences,
empathy. So let me ask you this question. What's
something that you as a company, as a leadership
team chose to do that was not what the data was
telling you to do? Could be a feature, it could
be a whole big bet that ended up being successful.
I have a few and each of those could have gotten
me fired, Lenny. It was that sort of gut-based.
I'll give you a few of those examples.
When I joined I was working on safety,
and safety is a big issue on the Uber platform.
Was a very, very big issue back in 2017. We
had not built enough software to be able
to manage safety in the physical world.
So while safety in terms of incident reduction,
look at the number of incidents you're having
and then just like a growth hacking project,
you just drive that number down needing to do
whatever you can. I said in addition to that, we
also need to incorporate a lot of functionality
and features and UI in the product, both
on the rider side and the driver's side,
which is delivering a sentiment of
safety and making sure people feel safe.
99.9% of our trips are totally fine from a
safety perspective, but that doesn't mean
that people are not concerned. So in addition
to driving down the incidents, we also have to
develop a bunch of features so that they feel
safe. And that actually helped a lot because
we started hearing from our users that, oh, we
measure something called safety sentiment and
that safety sentiment has been going up a lot. So
I would say that was back in the day that I drove.
Another crazy one was I pushed the company
to work with taxis. If you look at my resume,
I worked at a company called Flywheel, which is
a taxi app company. And so I spent three years
there and that's what got me to transportation or
being interested in transportation and eventually
ended up at Uber. And Uber and taxis have always
had an issue with each other. We all know the
history. And I was saying, "No, we should actually
launch with taxis." Now, if you look at the data,
the data will tell you that the number of taxis is
going down, that the taxis are not very reliable,
the taxis have antiquated software in them,
the taxi drivers may not want to provide
the same level of service, so on and so forth.
And there's a little bit of a gut feel and I said,
"No, look, there are drivers who want to
make money who do not always have enough
demand. We have a lot of demand. If we put the
right incentives in place, we will be able to
create a structure where we can work together
productively." And today in the US I think we
operate taxis in about 10 to 15 different cities.
In New York City, by the way, every single yellow
cab is hailable through the Uber app and that
is generating a pretty large amount of revenue
for us and we have taxis all over the world as
well. So that was probably another one where the
data just didn't support my gut decision.
And the last one I would say is Uber for
Teenagers. There are so many reasons to not
do that, by the way. You go talk to parents,
they're like, "I am never putting my teen in
an Uber." And if you talk to the risk people
in the company, they're like, "We are not going
to put teenagers in our cars and there's a lot
of liability." I happen to be the father of
a 16-year-old and a 12-year-old. And I can
tell you that one of the biggest problems in our
household is kids' transportation. And I'm like,
"How can that not be a problem? And if anyone is
going to solve a transportation problem, shouldn't
that be Uber?" And so how can we build a product?
So I started with let's just build a product that
is going to solve every single one of these
problems that parents have in terms of safety.
So we launched that two years ago. It's been
growing really, really well. And in fact in
California for several reasons, we had to turn
the product off and I get emails every single
day from parents in California about why did we
have to turn that product off. So I would say a
lot of the growth bets that we actually make may
not have the best data supporting them, but as
long as we understand intrinsically what the end
user wants and the problems that we need to fix,
I think you have to go with your gut. And I
would say when it comes to transportation,
we still have not solved a lot of problems that
people have and so that's all headroom for us.
Very cool. On the taxi's point, I've always
thought taxis are great in so many ways. They
just know exactly how to get places. They're very
knowledgeable and they just get you done. It's not
the most pleasant experience, but they're very
good at what they do. And so I think it makes so
much sense to integrate. And it reminds me also,
my wife always jokes. There's always startups
that come in, disrupt the whole industry, like
Airbnb is another example and then they end up
just providing the same service. Oh, okay, cool.
Now we got taxis again. Here we go. Exactly.
They're very efficient. They know
the city like the back of their hand.
Yeah. Especially in the UK, their whole
knowledge thing. Okay. I'm going to take
us to a couple of recurring segments on
this podcast. The first is AI Corner.
Is there some way you've figured
out how to use AI in your work,
some AI tool to help you work better, to help
you work faster, to get better work done?
I would say the team is using a lot of
tools now. The team is using tools to
build initial prototypes, initial
mocks I should say. The team's using
that for user research to be able
to process information as well.
What are some of the tools, if you can name them?
We are using both ChatGPT as well as Gemini
quite heavily in the company. We have close
relationships with both the companies.
Specifically I end up using ChatGPT a
lot for summarization of documents. That's
one thing. All of us have too much to read
and we don't have enough time. I've not used
NotebookLM yet. I know a lot of people who
have started using it and that is the next thing
that I'm going to use just to be able to build an
audio podcast based on a bunch of information
that you can consume. I think that's awesome.
What I've been doing is I have been using
ChatGPT and Gemini to summarize long user
research documents. Some of these reports,
they're 50 to 100 pages long. I will never
have the time to read them. That's really making
me much, much better acquainted with, this is what
writers in South Africa feel and this is what's
happening in Brazil, this is what's happening
in Korea. So that has been a huge enabler.
The second thing that I've really, really
started liking is the deep research feature. The
deep research feature in, again, both Gemini as
well as ChatGPT, where you feed them a prompt, you
actually present a pretty hard ... The other day
we were thinking of a driver feature. It's a
driver feature that has been discussed a lot
in the past. We haven't done it. I just asked
ChatGPT deep research, here's the feature,
this is how it would work. Can you let me know
if drivers will like it or not like it? Is there
anything we can change about that feature for the
drivers to like it? And it presented me an answer,
which I would say it's an amazing research
assistant and it's absolutely a starting
point for a brainstorm with my team with some
really, really good ideas. So I think that that
is making us not just more productive. I think
it's actually going to make us better at our jobs.
That is an incredible use case. Essentially
it's a thought partner on strategy and
helping you find gaps in your thinking. And
I think for Uber, it's easier because these
crawlers can learn a lot about what Uber is.
For some products, they won't know as much, but
clearly, there's something you could do there,
whatever your product is. And by the way,
it's cool that you guys give access to ChatGPT. A
lot of companies don't. Look, a lot of companies
only have Gemini or something like that.
Okay, I'm going to take us to another corner
on the podcast. I call Fail Corner. And what Fail
Corner is about is people come on this podcast,
they share all these wins, cool taxis worked and
teens worked and safety worked. And look at this,
we got profitable, everything's just
going great all the time. But in reality,
that's not how it goes. Is there a story
you could share where something went wrong,
something didn't work out the way you expected
in your career and what you learned from that?
I still somehow, when I think about
it, I don't end up calling it a fail,
but absolutely you could call it a fail because
the product didn't work or the business didn't
work and so on. I was at Palm a long time ago.
Palm developed a Palm Pilot and then it went into
the phone business. Some of your listeners may
have used them, some of your listeners may be too
young to remember. And then there was a period of
time when it was really Blackberry and Palm or the
two smartphones on the market, especially here
in the US. And then Apple announced the iPhone
and then soon thereafter, Android was announced
by Google. And it took us a long time to respond
to that. It took us maybe three, four years to
respond to that. And in the end, HP bought Palm.
We did not have the level of scale or the level of
hardware quality that we needed to have to be able
to effectively compete with the likes of Apple.
When you are going through the motions, when you
are actually in the moment, you don't always
realize what's going to happen. You also think
that, "Oh, we will be able to recover and we will
be able to compete." But I think there are many,
many things that I learned from that and I always
keep that very close to my heart. In consumer
markets, if you are player number three or player
number four, it's a little hard, because the two
top players are going to compete with each other
so ferociously especially if they're scale players
like Apple and Google, it's difficult for number
three and number four to be able to keep up with
that unless you have a very, very unique angle.
And the way I use that now is I am, Lenny,
always paranoid about the number three or the
number four player or the number two player
who may have an innovative idea, who may try
a different strategy, who may try a different
go-to-market. I just never take the status quo
for granted. So that's sort of one learning. And I
think the second learning is speed and hustle and
resilience. After Palm, I spent time at a couple
of startups. I mentioned Flywheel, which was a
taxi company, which is also not able to scale. But
what I learned through that period is that hustle
and sense of urgency is extremely important.
So when I think of my portfolio of skill sets
right now, really, that's portfolio that I
have developed from a lot of failures over my
career. And those are, I would say sense of
urgency because you need to move fast because
status quo can never be taken for granted. And
second is resilience because times will be hard
and things will be difficult and you just have to
power through them and you have to keep building
for your end users through that and the times will
change. So I would say those are the things
that I've learned and those are my failures.
I can see where this motto of ship,
ship ship came from. It at all connects.
There's absolutely a causation there.
Sachin, is there anything
else that you want to share
or leave listeners with before we get
to our very exciting lightning round?
I can talk a little bit about how I think about,
I think I've talked a lot about end users,
but I cannot talk about end users enough.
So in terms of offering my unique take,
which may be completely flawed, but
that is my unique take, I'll offer this.
Intriguing.
Which is I don't think our relationship
with our end users is reciprocal,
which means when I wake up in the
morning, all I'm thinking about is,
"How can we make our products better for our end
users?" When end users wake up in the morning,
all they're thinking about is, "I have to do this
at my job. I have many complexities, many problems
in my life." And that's what occupies their mind
all the time. They're not thinking about you,
they're not thinking about your product.
As much as that may be a hit to your ego.
However, for those, and I'm talking about let's
say Uber Rides, for those 15 minutes in the day
when they do think about your product, that
is your opportunity to absolutely dazzle them,
give them an experience that they will
not forget or it'll be so seamless for
them that they don't have to think about. So
next day when they're again going to work,
they just open the Uber app just as muscle memory,
but do not expect their life to be centered around
your product. Their life is complex. All of
our lives are complex. You are just trying to
be a part of their lives. You're not trying
to take over their lives. You never will.
I love this advice. There's
a book that I loved that
is for writing and the title is
Nobody Wants to Read Your Shit.
Yes.
And that applies exactly to products. Marc
Andreessen has this quote where I think it's,
"Everyone's time is already allocated.
They don't have time for your product,
they have stuff to do in their day." And
to hit that bar is very high. And so I
think that's a really important reminder.
Thank you for sharing that. With that,
we've reached our very exciting lightning round.
I've got five questions for you. Are you ready?
I am.
Number one, what are two or three books that
you have recommended most to other people?
Maybe a boring answer, but these are the books I
believe in. I recommended the Steve Jobs book by
Walter Isaacson. I have recommended Elon Musk
book. I have read the Ashlee Vance one fully.
I'm in the middle of the Walter Isaacson one and
I have recommended Hard Thing About Hard Things by
Ben Horowitz. These are the three books. I think
that there was a period of time in Silicon Valley
maybe 10 years ago, and maybe this is still
true, but everyone wanted to be Steve Jobs and
they thought that they can just recreate being
Steve Jobs. There was this fever in the valley,
and the reason why you want to listen or read
that book is you need to understand the context
of what makes up the entire person.
Yes, the person part is important,
but how they apply their own context to the
products that they ship and they change the world
is important because not that I or anyone else
can recreate what they did or what they're doing,
but take the learnings from them and see how you
can apply the same principles to your context.
You're not going to behave the same way that
they did. You're not going to build products
the same way that they did, but you're going
to give it your absolute freaking best because
that's what your end users deserve and you're
not going to compromise on that. That's sort of
what my takeaway is, and I think that takeaway is
extremely strong in the books that I talk about.
And the Ben Horowitz book, it goes back to
my concept of resilience. Some people have
this really optimistic view of how life is in
the corporate world or in the product world
or in the CEO office. It's not so. These
are lonely jobs, these are hard things,
and how do you persist through that? I felt
that that book was amazing at teaching me that.
Amazing. Okay, next question. Do you
have a favorite recent movie or TV show?
My favorite recent TV show is Peaky
Blinders. Peaky Blinders is on Netflix.
It's based in the 1920s and now they're
in the 1930s. I'm on season six. It's
an Irish family that's in a town called Birmingham
and they go through all these years and they
do all sorts of bad things. But again, it's an
amazing story, so I highly recommend watching it.
I started watching it, but I didn't stay
with it, so maybe I got to revisit it. Do
you have a favorite product that you have
recently discovered that you really like?
It is the product that makes me or
evokes that emotion in me right now
is deep research from ChatGPT, because
I've never had a research assistant and
I keep going back to that research assistant
and I think it's an excellent product. I'm
sure it will improve further, but that
would be my favorite product recently.
Do you have a favorite life motto that
you often come back to in work or in life?
Yes, and my kids are sick and
tired of hearing this from me now,
which is just focus on the inputs. You have
input metrics in life and in work, and you
have output metrics. You can't really control the
output metrics. All you can control is inputs,
whether you're trying to lose weight, whether
you are trying to get good grades or become very
good at high school sports, or you're trying
to ship a great product or you're trying to
improve retention or churn or whatever, you can
only control the inputs or focus on the inputs.
I love that your kids are sick of that. I wonder
what context you use with your kids. But anyway,
final question. You shared a really good tip for
how to not annoy an Uber driver. What about as
a food delivery person, what can a customer of
Eats do to avoid pissing off a delivery courier?
If they're delivering food to your home
at night, turn the porch light on because
they've just driven in the dark. They don't
know your house. They're trying really,
really hard to find your house, and after that,
they turn the flashlight on, on their phone and
they're trying to find the door where they
can place the food. Just turn the light on.
I'm super guilty of forgetting that sometimes,
and they also don't want to be shot by someone
thinking they're sneaking around. Sachin,
this was incredible. Two final questions.
Where can folks find you online if they
want to reach out, follow up on anything,
and how can listeners be useful to you?
Send me a message on LinkedIn. I will say
that I've been guilty of not establishing
an online presence and writing.
Life and work have just taken over.
I need to do a better job. Maybe your blog will
or your podcast will really help you with that.
Here we go.
But yeah, hit me up on LinkedIn.
That's probably the best place.
And how can listeners be useful to you?
Well, back to my dogfooding theme. Send me
feedback. Send me feedback. Hopefully everyone is
an Uber user, whether it's Rides or whether it's
Eats. Send me feedback of how we can get better
as a product, and the more detailed your
feedback, the better it is. It's very easy
to say this doesn't work or that doesn't
work, but if you actually describe and say,
"Hey, this is what happened. I was doing
this and then this happened. This didn't
make sense. This is how you can change it."
I think that'll be extremely valuable to me.
Only 40-page reports accepted. Just kidding.
Sachin, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you, Lenny. Thank you for having me.
Bye everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.