The rate you're growing is absurd. You're
in this cohort of companies that are just
growing at rates that we've never
seen in the history of startups.
The company was on the verge of
going under when we launched Bolt,
and what ended up happening is, in the first
two months it went from zero to 20 million of
ARR. And we've already crossed 30 million
of ARR, with the current rate we're on,
our forecast for the year is we
want to get to 100 million of ARR.
This is just non-stop wild
shit. How is this possible?
What has allowed you to grow this much,
this fast, with such a small team?
Most importantly, it's been the people.
It's rare to find startups where you have
the core group of five, six, seven people
that have been there for five years plus.
You basically were building a tech first, and
then looking for a problem to solve later,
which is often what people tell you not to do.
I think that's the hard thing about being
an entrepreneur. There are periods of time
where you have to make judgment calls
that are not going to be the consensus
view. You got to have confidence in your
convictions on how to best play the hand.
A lot of people see these stats,
and they sometimes don't see that there was
also years and years of work before that.
It was kind of like, Bolt's this overnight
success, seven years in the making.
Today my guest is Eric Simons. Eric
is co-founder and CEO of StackBlitz,
which makes a product called Bolt, which
is currently neck and neck with Cursor for
being the fastest growing product in history.
They're currently the number one most popular
web AI code app with over three million registered
users. Two months after launching last October,
they hit 20 million ARR. At the time of this
recording, they're approaching 40 million ARR.
The story of Bolt is wild. They actually started
the company seven years ago, and were about to run
out of money and shut down. But they realized the
tech that they'd been building for the past seven
years, called WebContainer, was perfectly suited
for building AI products in a browser. So they
launched the product with a tweet, and as Eric
describes it, it was an overnight success seven
years in the making. If you'd like to better
understand the cutting edge of AI coding apps,
and where things are going with AI and product
building, this episode is a must listen.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. Also, if you
become a yearly subscriber of my newsletter,
you now get a year free of Perplexity Pro,
Notion, Linear Granola, and Superhuman.
Check it out at lennysnewsletter.com.
With that, I bring you Eric Simons.
This episode is brought to you by Eppo. Eppo is a
next generation A-B testing and feature management
platform built by alums of Airbnb and Snowflake
for modern growth teams. Companies like Twitch,
Miro, ClickUp, and DraftKings rely on Eppo
to power their experiments. Experimentation
is increasingly essential for driving growth, and
for understanding the performance of new features,
and Eppo helps you increase experimentation
velocity while unlocking rigorous deep analysis,
in a way that no other commercial tool does.
When I was at Airbnb, one of the things that I
loved most was our experimentation platform where
I could set up experiments, easily troubleshoot
issues, and analyze performance all on my own.
Eppo does all that and more, with advanced
statistical methods that can help you shave
weeks off experiment time, and accessible UI for
diving deeper into performance, and out-of-the-box
reporting that helps you avoid annoying, prolonged
analytics cycles. Eppo also makes it easy for
you to share experiment insights with your team,
sparking new ideas for the A-B testing flywheel.
Eppo powers experimentation across every use case,
including product, growth, machine learning,
monetization, and email marketing. Check out
Eppo at geteppo.com/lenny and 10x your experiment
velocity. That's get E-P-P-O, .com slash lenny.
This episode is brought to you by the
Fundrise Flagship fund. Full disclosure,
real estate investing is boring.
Prediction markets are exciting,
meme coins are a thrill ride, even the stock
market can swing wildly on a headline. Hello,
Deep Zeke. But with real estate investing, there's
no drama, or adrenaline, or excuses to refresh
your portfolio every few minutes. Just bland and
boring stuff like diversification and dividends,
so you won't be surprised to learn that the
Fundrise Flagship Real Estate Fund is a complete
snooze fest. The fund holds $1.1 billion worth
of institutional caliber real estate, managed by
team of pros focused on steadily growing your
net worth for decades to come. See? Boring.
That's the point. You can start investing
in minutes, and with as little as $10 by
visiting fundrise.com/lenny. Carefully
consider the investment objectives,
risks, charges, and expenses of the Fundrise
Flagship Fund before investing. Find this
information and more in the fund's prospectus
at fundrise.com/flagship. This is a paid ad.
Eric, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you for having me.
Yeah, I'm stoked to be here.
For folks that are not super
familiar with Bolt, what is Bolt?
It's really simple. You go there,
there's a text box, and you tell it
what you want to build. Whether it's a web or
a mobile app, and so, it's kind of one of these
text to app building tools that have become
pretty popular over the past few months
here. And it's not just building a static
site, or something like that, but you can
actually build full stack, real software
with databases, and hosting and et cetera,
just from prompting. And in a ridiculously
short period of time, it's not like you're
spending hours and hours or days, putting this
together. You can get results in like, a minute.
Let's just share some numbers about the
scale of what you're building. The rate
you're growing is absurd. You're kind in this
cohort of companies that are just growing at
rates that we've never seen in the history
of startups, and you guys are at the edge of
that. Share some numbers about how things went
when you launched, and where they're at today.
Yeah, when we launched, the company was on the
verge of going under when we launched Bolt,
our company StackBlitz. We'd been around for
seven years building web-based development,
environment stuff. And so when we launched
this we were like, "This would be amazing if
this added a 100K of ARR over the next couple
of months." And what ended up happening is,
in the first two months, we went from zero to 20
million of ARR. And I think we're on month four,
or four and a half or something like that at this
point, and we've already crossed 30 million of
ARR, and we're on the verge of crossing 40. By
the time this comes out, it appears that we're
going to be at 40 million ARR. So it's just, the
scale of the growth of the revenue has been nuts.
And of course, that correlates with insane
user growth, as well. We've added three million
registered users just in the past few months here,
and monthly active users is around a million,
I think at this point, per month. So it's
just been... I've never seen anything,
I've been doing startups for 15 years, I've never
seen anything like this. Everyone I've talked to,
our investors, or et cetera, there's not a lot of
corollaries to what's going on here. And it's kind
of extraordinary, because our company wasn't doing
AI stuff six months ago. We had no AI products,
and just out of nowhere we, from almost
death of the company to being the number
one buy traffic revenue, et cetera, like AI
Cogen app, that's totally web-based, in the
world. I think the only other startup ahead of us
is for Cogen, just in general, would be Cursor,
and the option revenue at this point.
And so anyways, it's been a heck of a
ride. And our team's like 15, 20 people, so
it's just dealing with, we're going to be
closing on 100,000 customers, and our support
team's like three people. So we're trying to
scale as fast as we can. So it's just kind of
mind-boggling, just the scale of the demand,
and how we've had to turn things around
to match the demand as best as we can.
Mind-boggling is an excellent way to describe what
you just shared. A million monthly active users,
you're at 40 million annual recurring revenue,
five months into the business. Is that right?
Yeah, single digit. Yeah, single
digit weeks. That's the current
track rate that we're seeing for the thing. Yeah.
I think, are you guys are the
fastest growing startup in history?
I mean, I think it depends on probably where you
peg the number. Because yeah, we're here to just
build great products, and just push the limits
of what's possible with the technology. And I
think that we do our jobs well, kind of crazy
things can happen, but I mean, the current track
rate we have, we're going to be exceeding the
forecast for Q1 with the current rate we're on,
and our forecast for the year is we want to get
to 100 million of ARR. And now, I think there's
been a couple, that would either be on par with
Cursor, or ahead of them, or something like that.
And I think there's going to be more things
like this, too. I don't think that... It just,
there's something really, I think a lot of people
are in disbelief about it too, where they're like,
"This is, okay." And this is from when we were
at, got to four million ARR, five million ARR in
the first month. I would talk with people and
they're like, "Okay, yeah, but that could go to
zero." And then it went to 20 the next, "Ah, it
could go to zero," but now we're closing on 40.
So from my view, I was also very skeptical, as
this. I've never seen anything grow like this,
right? And so part of me, for like a month
I was kind of waking up waiting for the day
where it just was like, "Okay, it's over." You
know what I mean? This crazy thing happened,
and now it's not. But that data just hasn't come.
And you see this happening with Cursor, you see
this with a lot of these other AI startups. And
the value proposition is real. The free market is
filled with rational actors. People are coming
to these tools because it is solving problems,
they're able to do way more for way less cost,
than it would otherwise. And that's why I said,
I think we're going to see more of this, whether
it's in coding or other verticals, or whatever.
In a sense, it's almost like maybe the new normal,
as AI just continues to get better. But, anyways.
Let's get to a demo of Bolt, so people can
actually see what this looks like in action.
And as you go through it, if you can even point
out stuff that is different from other products
in the space, say Lovable, VZERO, Replit, that
other folks have heard about, that'd be useful.
Awesome. Cool. Yeah, so this is Bolt, you just
go to bolt.new. Things that I think are really
interesting about Bolt. One is, it's just dead
simple. Whether you're logged in or logged out,
it's the same UI, it's extremely simple, it's
just a text box. And I think that the biggest
difference between Bolt and the other stuff
out there, it's actually subtle. It's not
like something you'd necessarily see in the UI,
but it's how fast it is, and how reliable it is.
And this is because of how we are actually doing
the compute, because what's going on here is
when you type into, whether it's Bolt or another
product, it has to spin up a dev environment to
actually make that application. So there needs to
be some operating system somewhere that's running
it. Everyone else runs those things on cloud
servers, which those can take minutes to boot up,
and they often will run into issues, and then you
can end up literally stuck and have to contact
support to get it done, and get it unstuck.
With Bolt, and for the past seven years,
what our company's been doing has been
building an operating system that runs
inside of your browser locally, using your CPU.
So we have a very permissive free tier, and it's
insanely fast, and it's insanely reliable.
So if I want to, just as a quick example
of this say, "Make a clone of Spotify," and just
hit enter. This thing's already getting to work,
and already, on the right here, this is a full dev
environment. This is an actual operating system,
running inside of my browser. And I can
run commands on it, et cetera. And really,
what you're seeing down here, this terminal and
kind of what's backing it, this is what took us
really five, six, seven years to build, and make
so reliable. There would not be a Bolt without
this technology called WebContainer, that allows
us to run an operating system in the browser.
Because what's going on here is, our AI agent
for Bolt has bidirectional communication with
this operating system. It's writing code,
it's running the dev server for this thing,
it's going to go ahead and spin this up. You
can see how fast this is, in a matter of 60
seconds I said, "Make me a Spotify clone," and
now we have one. And it looks pretty darn good.
That looks really good.
And that's one of the other aspects around Bolt
is, this technology we made for the operating
system side, the guys that have been working
with us for the past five-plus years on it,
before this they were actually doing machine
learning AI stuff. And so when it came time
to write the agent for Bolt, we had just
an incredible amount of in-house expertise
on how to actually merge these two different
technology sets, to have this really reliable
experience that produces really beautiful,
really functional stuff. So that's based on
what's really cool about the Bolt experience.
The other thing is, a lot of these products
it's like, you can make something, but often you
want to actually have a URL where you can share
this. Having, maybe even attach a domain
to it, or whatever have you. So with Bolt,
we actually have built-in integrations
with production grade hosting providers
like Netlify, and for databases with Supabase.
So if I go and just click the deploy button here,
this is actually going to run a production build
of this project we made here. And again, this is
doing this entirely inside of my browser, so it
doesn't cost us anything to do this. So again,
you can do this for free, and it has gone ahead
and deployed this on a real URL, on Netlify.
This is live, I can share this with anyone, and
if I want to buy the domain spotifyclone.com,
and point it at this, I can click this link here.
That will kick me into Netlify, I can attach this
to my account, buy a domain, point at that thing.
And then from there on out, whenever I'm prompting
Bolt to make changes to this application and
hit deploy, that goes live on my public website.
So this is the simplest way to build a web app
that's ever existed. That was one of the key
realizations I had, a couple of weeks into
the thing, I was seeing people use this for
personal use cases. Like medical donation sites,
or weddings, or whatever. And I was like, "Don't
these people know that Wix or Squarespace exists?
Should I tell them?" And then it hit me. Those
things are so complicated to use. I don't know
if you've ever seen just the UI of these things,
but they're crazy complicated, and that's just
for building a static website. There's no way
you could actually build a functional app. And
that's like, with Bolt, if we were to sit here for
another 30 minutes, we would have streaming. You'd
be able to make playlists of different MP3 files,
or whatever. You can just keep prompting
this thing to keep adding functionality.
So that's, I think, some of the cool
core experience of both here. I can
show you something cool that we just
launched, if that would be of interest.
Let's do it.
So this is like web apps, right? Web apps are
amazing, but often you want to have a native
app. And it's hard to build web apps, it's even
harder to build native apps, that can actually,
that you can then go put in the app store. And
so we partnered up with a company called Expo,
and their entire business is making, basically,
React Native tooling and this ecosystem that makes
it super easy to build beautiful apps,
and actually get them in the app store.
And so right here, I'll zoom in a little bit, we
have this little, "Build a mobile app with Expo."
So if you click that, we kind of instruct you on
how to just prompt mobile apps into existence. So
yeah, let's make another Spotify clone that's
an actual native mobile app. Let's say,
"Make a Spotify clone," go ahead and hit enter.
And what this thing's going to do is actually,
again, spin up a operating system here, where
it's going to boot up the Expo tool chain and
actually go and make a mobile app for us.
And what's cool about this is, we could
actually preview it just in the browser here,
but once this thing's done and it boots up,
it's going to show a QR code, we're going to
be able to scan it, and in real time actually
basically have a test flight of this native
application that we can try it on our phones,
and as we keep prompting you'll
see it making changes and stuff.
This is kind of the first time that, you don't
have to be technical to make production grade web,
full-stack web and mobile apps. At this
point I've done nothing that requires
developer knowledge to do any of this stuff.
And I think that's what a lot of people are
really excited about with this, and you
know, the majority of our audience are
people that are not developers, that are
using this. They're PMs, they're designers,
they're entrepreneurs. Because these are people
that have always been great at building products,
but previously, the only way that they
could get their ideas into coded software
was through a developer's fingertips. And now,
they can deal with their own, through prompting.
So you can see here, we've got this little QR
code. I'm going to go ahead and scan the thing.
I'm going to do it, too.
Cool.
By the way, I love that you had just enough
things to say until it finished. That was pro.
Just as I planned, you know? So on my screen
it's booting up, it's bundling the JavaScript
of this thing, and it's beta. We just
launched this last week, by the way. So
if you can kind of see on my screen here, I
actually have this Spotify looking app, right?
Wow.
That, you know.
That looks like, exactly like Spotify.
It looks exactly like Spotify, right?
It's good.
Yeah.
We're going to be sued right now,
so let's be... You're doing too good
a job with this. No, that's amazing.
Yeah. So it's pretty cool, right? And so what's
cool is that, and as you keep prompting on your
device, it'll just keep reloading.
Without you having to kill the app,
you can actually see the functionality
getting added. And so, in this use case
that you and I have right now, it's like
if you and I were building an app together,
we could be on other sides of the planet and you
could actually be not just seeing a screenshot
of the thing, but actually touching it and
feeling it, and putting it through its paces.
And so a lot of product teams, I mean, this is
just changing how people do product development.
It's faster to do this than design a whole
bunch of Figma frames, necessarily. Right? So.
We're going to spend a lot of time
on that. Okay, this is incredible,
this whole episode so far is you just blowing
my mind and I imagine listeners' minds,
just over and over and over. I don't even
know where to go with all this, sometimes.
You made a really important point, that you
worked on this for seven years before you
launched Bolt. A lot of people see these stats,
zero to 40 million ARR in five-ish months,
and they sometimes don't see that there was also
years and years of work before that. And the
reason that you guys have been so successful is
all the work you did that allowed, that built this
WebContainer technology, it sounds like. Is there
anything there that's worth sharing, you think,
of just that part of the journey? I know we'll go
through the origin that all, where Bolt came from,
but I guess just that WebContainer component
specifically. That feels like a huge deal.
A hundred percent it is, yeah. And I would say
this is, surprisingly to me, it's still one of the
contrarian viewpoints of our company. Because over
the years it was like, when we first... And that,
the WebContainer was the bet, that we made the
company on. Just to be clear. StackBlitz was a
browser-based, deep technology play on, "Can
we make a web assembly based operating system
that can boot in a browser, in like a
hundred milliseconds, and run full on
development tool chains?" That was really it.
And we'd gotten the idea for this, and the
insight that this might be possible, because back
when my co-founder and I came out to the Valley,
he and I grew up down the street from each
other in Chicago, we wrote code together at 13,
and been building stuff ever since. And we came
out to the Valley in 2012, and we just had the
good fortune of bumping into Dylan Field and
Evan Wallace when they were building Figma,
in the early days. And that was, I don't think
a lot of people know that Figma was also a
browser-based deep technology play. Their
first pitch for Figma, they didn't have a
design tool. Their first pitch was this 3D ball
dropping into water, inside of a browser town.
And the pitch basically was, "Browsers have this
new capability called WebGL," the predecessor
to WebAssembly, "and with these things, for the
first time, you could actually create a graphics
rendering engine, that you could then build a
design tool on top of. But you're going to have to
write that rendering engine from scratch, because
nothing exists that can just compile into WebGL,
or whatever. And if you want the performance
you need, et cetera, it's going to take us
years to do, but if we do it, we think
this will change everything for design."
And obviously, we know how that story has
panned out now. And back in 2017, 2016, 2017,
Albert, my co-founder and I, saw the same sort of
story begin to play out, but for web development
and development environments. And specifically
there was some stuff that landed in browsers
like WebAssembly, shared memory, service workers,
these different APIs. And we were like, "Oh, wow.
It should be possible, theoretically, to write
an operating system in WebAssembly that could
run Node.js, and NPM and all the tool chains on
top of it, that you need to do web development."
And that would be huge, because setting up
developer environments, it's a pain for beginners.
A lot of people churn out. The first thing you do
when you learn how to code is not even learning
how to code, it's how to set up your computer
to even start writing the code. If you go join
Netflix, or any of these other fan companies,
the first month or two is you being onboarded,
to run that stuff on your computer and set up
your environment. And we're like, "If we could
just have that be something, you click a link and
it just boots in your browser, that'd be huge."
It's also, if you look at the other productivity
apps that have really worked on the web,
they've all had this compute model, right?
Figma, when you open a Figma document,
there's not like some cloud VM that gets spun up
for you to render the documents. You're dragging
things around. It's using your CPU and your
memory to do the work. Same thing with Google
Docs. That's the only model that's ever scaled
to a billion users. And so, when you look at
Cloud IDEs, like Cloud 9 was the first one, back
in 2009 or so. The way these have always worked is
that your browser's basically doing nothing, when
you go to that. Every user that gets connected,
there has to be a cloud VM that gets spun up
for them, and then your browser's just taking
your keystrokes, sending it to the server, and
then sending back the results of it. And that's
how all these other AI code, text to app sort
of tools work. They're all using cloud VMs.
And the problem is, on a small scale it can
work, but as you scale it up, I mean there's
not even a 100 million VMs to rent, on the planet.
But there are a billion devices that you can run
this stuff on. Because that's kind of what we've
seen with Bolt where, if you want to build a
product that's going to be able to scale to that
size, you have to look at all factors and go,
"We have to build, make sure the technology
provides the best experience, zero latency,
transient cost." There's a permissive free tier,
because the other problem with the server is,
you end up, if you have a free tier, people are
mining Bitcoin on it, they're DDoSing people using
your servers. So inevitably, you have to nerf
these things and roll them back. But if it's
all done on the end device, it doesn't matter.
So anyways, WebContainer was the key piece,
and what we struggled with, it took us four or
five years or something, to build WebContainer.
What we struggled with for the years after
that was just how to build a product around it,
because developers loved it, but they weren't
using it in ways that they would pay money for.
And as much as the nerd side of me wished that
that would be enough, that it was like, building
cool technology was enough. It's like, "It's not.
We're here to build a venture scale company."
And so that was kind of why we were high at
the end of the journey, where it was like,
we're taking shots on goal. And at some
point, this got a connected bat, right?
There's a lot of really interesting
lessons from this journey,
that I think are counterintuitive. One is,
you basically were building a tech first,
and then looking for a problem to solve
later. Which is often what people tell you
not to do. And it worked out, in this case.
The other interesting takeaway here is,
it feels like it's a similar moment to when
AJAX came out and then everyone's just like,
"Wow, you can build new things here." So it
feels like there's a lesson here of just,
"If there's a new technology that has enabled,
something big that we think may, let's just work
there for a while, and see if something comes up."
And then I think the other lesson here is just,
as a founder, just survive as long as you can.
Because you may find something that works.
All great points, all great points. Because you're
dead right. And fortunately, my co-founder and I
had, we had built a lot of unsuccessful stars
before this. We spend most of the, or 20 times,
churning through ideas on things. So when we
had conviction, I was like, "This seems like a
technology that will be important." It seems like,
the web is the most ubiquitous... The pitch or the
theory in our head was like, "The web is the most
ubiquitous platform in the world, but yet it has
no, you can't use the web to build the web."
Every other platform, Mac has Xcode. Windows
has Visual Studio. The web had nothing. And we
were like, "At a minimum, Google should probably
buy this thing from us. It seems like it should
probably be part of Chrome," at a minimum. And
we thought, "Hey, this could be a huge
enabler." The vision of just making it
as easy to build full stack applications as
using Canva, it just seemed really compelling.
But when you do that sort of risky deep technology
play, you need to... And we were very good about
this, like the previous company Albert and I
did, we bootstrapped it all the way through
to acquisition, so we understood and we were
living hand-to-mouth, to bootstrap that thing.
So we understood out of it how to have a low
burn rate, and take a lot of shots on goal,
and make every dollar stretch beyond what anyone
would think is reasonable or possible. And that's
how we played our hands with StackBlitz. We
didn't raise money for the first two or three
years of the company's life. We were bootstrapping
it. When we did raise money, we barely spent it.
Largely because it was like, "We need to just take
a lot of smart bets, and it doesn't make sense."
And I would just say generally, until you see
pull, just people pulling the product out of your
hands, you don't want to be spending money. You
should be like, default, no. And when you go and
buy software, you should be going, "We're a tiny
startup. Can you sell it for half?" Everything you
buy, just keep the burn rate as low as possible,
because you need as many shots on goal as you can
possibly get. Because you have no idea. I think
just generally, for startups, that's the right way
in my view, to approach it. Unless you're seeing,
again, immediate demand and pull, or whatever.
But yeah, I think that'd be, maybe the extra
context I'd add on top is, I think that we
ended up doing a good job of being extremely
conservative. During a time in which, during 2020,
through 2020 and 2021, which were times where
exuberance and growing headcount was like,
KPIs of companies. And were things that were
being... With lot of emotional force of like,
"Hey, you guys ought to be doing this." And
I'm glad that we didn't heed the advice,
because if we had tripled the company and kicked
up the burn rate, there would be no Bolt. We
would've gone out of business a lot of time ago.
So I think that's the hard thing about being an
entrepreneur, I think is you kind of have to...
There are periods of time where you have to
make judgment calls that are not going to be the
consensus view. Maybe years later, it'll become
the consensus view, but you got to have confidence
in your convictions on how to best play the hand.
There's so many great lessons here, I think
just this idea of just staying alive. Dalton
came on the podcast, he's a partner at YC Ones,
and he just had this phrase, "Just don't die."
And that's exactly what you guys did, seven
years of just trying it until something worked,
and I love that you actually were planning to
shut down the company right before you launched
Bolt. And I know you launched it with just
a tweet, right? That was the launch moment?
Yep. Yeah.
Maybe talk about that moment of
just, after launch, signs that,
"Okay, this is working. Something's different."
Yeah, yeah. So day one it was like, there's great
reception to the tweet. We were like, "Wow, this
is one of the biggest things, launch day reception
we've ever seen." And I think on the first day,
I think we added 60K of ARR, or something. Which
was like, I mean, crazy. Again, we were at 600, so
we added 10% in a day. And I remember our dev ops
engineer, he was the one who would flag me. He was
like, "Guys, we got 60K today. This is crazy." And
I was like, "Yeah, yeah. But this is launch day."
There's the tech crunch, peak of
initiation, in the classic startup-
[Inaudible 00:30:17]-
... star, yeah. I was like, "Listen, guys."
I'm trying to temper enthusiasm for the team.
I'm like, "This is great. Got a lot of work
to do." And then the next day we added 80K,
or whatever it was, and it just kind of kept
going. And all the while, the product we put out,
we built a thing in 90 days. We built Bolt
in 90. So there's a lot of things that were
missing in the product. Like, basic stuff, basic
stuff. And which, again, we cut the right corners
on the thing to get it online, but we had this
just growing influx of people using it, going,
"How is there not a mobile responsive view? How
are chat messages not," we got to 20 million of
ARR without a mobile responsive view, by
the way. Just throwing that out there. It
was like the iPhone not having copy and paste
until iPhone 5, or whatever. That was that,
this was that for us, it was like, no mobile.
You looked at it on mobile, it was terrible.
But there was stuff like that, so we had to
just... And then, we're a small team and so,
we were completely unprepared for just the
growing traffic. And there was a whole bunch,
I mean, the list of problems that were happening
every single day was nuts. I mean, to start,
we had never had a plan on stackblitz.com for
more than $9.00. We had one price, nine bucks.
And so when we launched Bolt we were like, "Again,
we don't think, hopefully people like this, but
nine bucks doesn't get you a lot of inference."
And so people burn through nine bucks in 48 hours.
And they're like, "I want to buy more. How
do I buy more? Why won't you take my money?"
So it was like, within the week we rolled
out just completely new pricing plans,
where you could upgrade, which ended up, has kind
of now become the standard. All the other guys in
the space have copied this. Where prior to Bolt
going online, Copilot, all these previous AI
things, everyone wanted this Netflix model where
there's one price, it's like all you can eat,
or whatever. And the problem is, if you do that,
you want the inference cost to be kind of low,
because you're expecting people to use it
a lot. And so you can't do these agentic
experience things, it would be too expensive.
And what we ended up stumbling into is that,
"Okay, actually, people are willing to pay
more. People want to pay for more inference,
because we've crossed this threshold where
you can get a very tangible ROI." You know
that this is providing a tremendous amount of
value to you. So anyways, that was one thing,
and the servers were just melting. Anthropic
ran out of GPUs for us. Dario emailed me,
he was like, "Listen, we don't have anything more
to give you." At the times, where we're like,
"How do we deal with..." It was just
bananas, for weeks. It felt like in 300,
when they're surrounded by 10,000 people, and
our team is just doing everything. There's 15,
20 people, just doing everything.
My chief of staff and I were doing
customer support 95% of the day. Anyways.
So yeah, it was a crazy wild time. I mean,
it still is. We've had a little bit more time to
grow into this. And usually, I mean as a company,
to grow into even 20 million ARR, you get a
year at least or something, to kind of staff up.
Often, decades.
Yeah. So that was as hard, we'd go to
people and kind of be like, "What do
we do?" And the playbooks we get back are, take
six months, or a year, or something. It's like,
"This isn't going to work." Which is funny,
this is what it's all about. I mean this is,
at least for me, that level of intensity,
it's challenging. Fun challenges, you know?
Wow, okay. This is just nonstop wild, wild shit.
So you mentioned that your team was
about 20 people through all of this,
you guys are growing at this insane rate, 20
people. How was this possible? What has allowed
you to grow this much, this fast, with such a
small team? And this 300 visual is interesting,
I imagine having these Spartans is a big part
of it. Just what has allowed you to do this?
Yeah, I think a lot of it again, I mean if you
kind of look at where a lot of the other folks,
like the Cogen types of app space, have really
been struggling, a lot of it has been scaling
their servers with stuff. And it was kind of like
both this overnight success, seven years in the
making. All of this stuff, there's no way, if you
rewind to year two, there's no way we could have,
we would not be at the growth on DAUs, and
revenue, or whatever. There's just no way.
And so a lot of it is the technology we made,
and most importantly, it's been the people.
The people... It's rare to find startups
where you have the core group of five,
six, seven people, that have been there for
five years, plus. That's a pretty rare thing
to see in Silicon Valley. It is usually, folks
are at a startup for a year or two, they kind
of go to another one. You know what I mean? And
the problem with the turnover like that is that
you can't take really long bets like the one we
did. And so we've had, kind of from the get-go,
again, this comes back from bootstrapping the
previous company. Just having less people,
and more context per head. That's just been how
we do it, and we feel very strongly about it.
And the reason for that is, one, that you can
have high levels of trust with anyone you're
talking to, because you know that they have a lot
of context. It's not like this person's completely
in the dark, in some corner of the company that
doesn't... You know what I mean? The second thing,
everyone has agency to actually get stuff done,
front to back. And there's no political community
to get stuff approved by, there's no... So when
you look at what happened with Bolt, I mean,
we had engineers that were, front to back, were
on a call with someone running into an issue,
going and fixing it. Cooking up the UI
on the spot, and landing this thing.
Without involving anyone else on the team.
So I think it was the culmination of just
high trust, and people, we all just have enjoyed
working together in the past. Maybe that's why,
that's the only reason that anyone would ever stay
at a company for that long, or whatever. And so
those sorts of stressful situations, I think,
are make or break. Those are make or break for
any team. And so, I think that what's happened
is really, it is a direct reflection of the
strength and the bonds of the people that are
making this thing, and supporting the thing.
Yeah, I think that's such an important
point, that you guys have been working
together for many years. Most people won't
have that benefit. When you're hiring people,
when you hire this initial team, is there anything
you look for that you think maybe people aren't
looking for enough? Anything you prioritize when
you're hiring new folks? Is it this idea that
they can do a lot? They can do customer calls,
they can do design, they can do engineering?
Yeah, for us, and even if the folks were
hiring us, hiring people that don't care
about the titles, and they don't care
about... It's not like they're... People,
of course it's people have a career trajectory,
and that sort of thing, but they really are
motivated by just working on cool things, and are
chucking their ego at the door. And they're there
to collectively build something great, not just
kind of follow, and be the brilliant jerk. Most of
the people that we've hired have been in Europe.
We're a fully remote company. My co-founder and I
are in the Bay Area. It's funny, back in 2018, we
rented an office and stuff, and we were commuting
into it. Because we thought we'd hire people
here, and like a year into it we were like,
"What are we doing? You and I are coming
to an office for 10 people, we've hired,
the people working for us are in Europe, or across
the US." And we have one or two other people we've
hired that are in the Bay Area at this point.
But yeah, I think we kind of look for folks
that are intrinsically just trying to build
great stuff, and are interested. And then
the first people that we hired, the reason
that we found them is that they were users
of StackBlitz. A lot of people, the majority
of people we've hired at the company have been
people that actually came from our community,
basically. So when we want to hire people,
we put out a tweet and say, "Hey, we're hiring
an engineer," and then we get DMs or whatever.
But yeah, those are the general kind
of qualities we look for, though.
I'm excited to chat with Christina
Gilbert, the founder of OneSchema,
one of our long-time podcast
sponsors. Hi, Christina.
Yes. Thank you for having me on, Lenny.
What is the latest with OneSchema? I know you now
work with some of my favorite companies like Ramp,
Vanta, Scale and Watershed. I heard
that you just launched a new product
to help product teams import CSVs from
especially tricky systems like ERPs?
Yes, so we just launched OneSchema
FileFeeds, which allows you to build
an integration with any system in 15
minutes, as long as you can export a CSV
to an SFTP folder. We see our customers
all the time getting stuck with hacks,
and workarounds, and the product teams
that we work with don't have to turn down
prospects because their systems are too hard
to integrate with. We allow our customers to
offer thousands of integrations without
involving their engineering team at all.
I can tell you that if my team had
to build integrations like this,
how nice would it be to be able
to take this off my roadmap,
and instead use something like OneSchema. And not
just to build it, but also to maintain it forever.
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many
horror stories of multi-day outages,
from even just a handful of bad records. We are
laser focused on integration reliability to help
teams end all of those distractions that come up
with integrations. We have a built-in validation
layer that stops any bad data from
entering your system, and OneSchema
will notify your team immediately
of any data that looks incorrect.
I know that importing incorrect data can
cause all kinds of pain for your customers,
and quickly lose their trust. Christina, thank
you for joining us, and if you want to learn more
head on over to oneschema.co, that's oneschema.co.
I want to ask a couple more questions about Bolt,
and then I want to zoom out, and talk about
where things are heading in the future. Let's
talk about prioritization. I imagine you guys
are just barraged with, as you described, after
you launched, you're just barraged with requests.
Like you said, there's a million monthly active
users. I can't even imagine the feature requests
you guys are getting, plus all the stuff you know
want to build. Just how do you go about deciding
what to prioritize, and what to actually build?
There's a lot of things that you just
don't even know are possible to do,
and so, people aren't going to be necessarily
explicitly asking for them. And so there's been
kind of a couple of these, where we use our gut
instinct on like, "Hey, no one's asking for this,
in meaningful numbers at least. But we
think this is going to be a big deal."
Best example was last week with native
mobile app support. That's, by reception,
the biggest thing we've ever launched. And it was
something that, even internally at the company,
some folks were like, "This, I don't know. People
are yelling about these other things." And it is,
it's always this balance of how much
are we just triaging various things,
versus that new capabilities, but it was like,
"This strikes me as an important one," where we
put some chips into the middle of the table on.
And had it dead right. It's just this mind-blowing
experience, and now, there's just thousands of
mobile apps being created a day, that weren't
before. And how does that change things? I mean,
now there's small businesses that, they would've
never made an iPhone app before. It made no sense.
It's super expensive. Now, that's not the case.
So there's kind of these things where
it's like, "Hey, we should go and take
bets here." But there's kind of this,
I think the best analogy would be like,
it's kind of like working at a restaurant, being
like a chef. There's some amount of, there's
feedback from the customers of, "This thing
didn't taste good." And then there's like, "Hey,
we've been cooking something interesting, and this
tastes... I don't know. This, I think you're going
to like this. I think this is a killer dish."
And so you kind of have to balance those things.
And I think it's actually, largely, a function
of just years of experience doing it. I think
if you kind of rewound 10 years ago, I would have
had really no, I wouldn't have had just the years
of getting my butt kicked by the free market,
to have cultivated a sense of this stuff. You
kind of have to build your own gun and stick
for it, I guess is the best way of putting it.
To unpack this a little bit further, do you have
a cadence you guys work through to decide what
to build, and ship? Do you have a weekly meeting
every week? Because I know the answer is probably,
really, "It's just chaos constantly, and fires
we're putting out constantly." I know that's
a lot of it, but is there some kind of process
that you guys have for deciding what to build,
and how to share it, and just work with the team?
We all meet every day. Pretty much the entire team
gets on a call, and we just kind of front to back-
You meet, like a Zoom?
Yeah, every day at 8:00 AM Pacific,
we're on a Zoom for at least an hour-
Every day? The whole company?
Pretty much the entire company. Yeah.
Wow. For an hour. Okay.
Yeah. And we just go over everything and
I think we're going to probably start,
as the team's kind of growing, we're going to
start splintering off into different syncs,
or whatever. But the thing about just having
everyone in the same room every day is that,
a lot of people will complain that it's...
On Twitter, you'll see people say, "Oh,
it's the most expensive use of everyone's time,"
but it's like, "Yep. But there's 0% fidelity loss
in that. Everything, every day, is being audited
front to back, and being discussed front to back."
So when you're in these times of just
extreme growth, you want as close to 0% loss,
on communications. And so that's how we've been
doing it, especially since Bolt went online,
and I think it was the week after Bolt
went online we were like, "Every day,
until we're through this or whatever, we're all
getting on a phone call every day, and we're front
to back doing this." And again, another reason
why more context and less heads, every person
at the company is aware of everything else going
on at the company. So people can independently
be making decisions that are generally,
by default, more often correct than not.
That is so interesting. I've never heard
that before. Especially for company growing,
that is like yours. That is super
interesting, that that's what you do.
I don't think we're going to do that forever.
Yeah, yeah. Of course.
But, yeah.
No, but I think that's a really cool thing to
note, that that works. And has worked for you.
Where do you, so say you talk about stuff, then
where do you put stuff? Where do you put your
roadmap? Where do you plan? Just, what tools are
kind of in the stack of the company's toolset?
Yeah, on the engineering side, we use Linear
heavily. On kind of product roadmapping,
we're using Notion, and kind of making PRD type
stuff in Notion. And we use Figma for design. No,
actually, we use Bolt for a lot of design and
prototyping at this point, as you can imagine. But
yeah, I think that the tooling is nothing crazy.
There's nothing crazy sophisticated. I think we'll
be investing a lot more, and especially as you
start splintering people out of being on the
same call every day, so that's where this stuff
really starts to matter. Because you don't have
a time where you're able to dynamically catch
things that weren't going to be brought up.
I love that you guys use PRDs. I love that you
even used that term. There's a lot of talk of
just like, "Oh, we got Bolt now we got all these
tools, we don't need PRDs. We're just going to
create a prototype immediately, and that's it."
Talk about just why you still find that useful,
and just what you put into your
PRD, whatever that is for you.
Unless there's something that's very
sophisticated that we're working on,
we tend to keep them pretty light. I like to
just have the minimal amount of context possible,
that just ensures everyone's on the same page
and that the key outcomes for whatever feature
that we're working on, are going to be present
when we get there. Because the things that,
when these arguments get really beefy, you're
looking at it at, "God, there's so much stuff
to decipher." The problem is, a lot of people
are going to gloss over it when it gets kicked
to development, or design, or whatever. It's
just going to start snowballing into a lot of
stuff. It's just better to keep it as simple as
you possibly can. At least, that's our approach
to the thing. And often it's some of these
things are like, "Here's a link to a Bolt."
"And here's what it might look like."
Yeah. And not just look like, "Here's kind of
a working demo of what it will effectively feel
like." And then, be. Because that just,
if a picture is worth a thousand words,
a live actual demo is worth millions. You can
feel it. It's real. And that's what we're seeing,
a lot of the businesses that are adopting Bolt
now, that's the use case that they're using
this for. Is high fidelity prototyping, because
it's now faster to make real prototypes using
Bolt. Before, it was too expensive. The idea
of, "And let's prototype it, the engineers'
code a proto..." It's like, that, it would
take forever. It would be expensive. And now
it's faster to do this with Bolt, in code,
and have a real working software product,
than dragging around frames and Figma
to actually make a static version of it.
So let's actually talk about that. Just how far
have companies gotten with Bolt? Prototypes is
where everyone's kind of imagining these
tools are at. I know that the goal isn't
just to make prototypes, it's to build full
scale. I imagine, long-term, Salesforce,
Atlassian style companies, at scale. What
are some examples of products people have
built with Bolt that maybe would surprise
people, in just how far they've gotten?
Yeah, I mean, especially... When
you're starting greenfield stuff,
you can use Bolt to build... you
know. Like Salesforce, as an example.
One of the first people that signed up for Bolt
was this guy named Paul, and he's an entrepreneur,
and doesn't know how to code. Built a CRM in three
weeks, that has AI built into it and Stripe for
billing, et cetera. He had gotten a quote from
an agency for this, it was going to be 30 grand,
and take six months. He had done in three weeks,
and I think he spent 300 bucks on Bolt for the
thing. So it's like, this is... And he's making
money off of this. This is his start. Right?
Okay, so he built this, and he's
selling it. People are paying to use it.
Yeah. Yeah.
Wow.
And there's many such cases of this. If you're
looking at greenfield projects, 100%. Today with
this current state of frontier models, you could
absolutely build production grade software. You're
not going to get a zero shot, but you're going
to spend a couple of days, weeks, whatever. But
the cost reduction there, 30 grand versus $300.
It's 99% cheaper. Six months versus three weeks.
I mean, it's like order of magnitude sort of
fashioned delivery on the thing. And those numbers
have helped, for the people that we talk to,
that are building these full stack apps. People,
they go to Upwork, work, they get a quote for five
grand. They have it within 50 bucks. It's just
nuts, what you're able to do with this thing.
And so I think on the flip side, a lot of the
existing companies, there are very legitimate
use cases where things are greenfield, spun
up. A good example is public websites. Marketing
pages, landing pages, whatever have you. Folks are
adopting Bolt to just power those instead of using
Webflow, for example. Because it's like, this is
simpler to use than Webflow. And it integrates
with the existing design system of the company,
and et cetera. And the marketers can update
it without knowing how to code, whatever. But
then for product development teams, this is most
commonly for, again, existing software businesses.
They're using this to just accelerate the product
development process, and in a way where it's not
just like a Greenfield wholesale, "Hey, we're
building the entire thing in Bolt," or whatever.
Can Bolt integrate with your
existing code base, or not yet?
So yeah, we can actually open up repos in
Bolt. You can go and use Bolt on your code
base. It kind of depends on your setup. And we
do have companies, again, that have marketing
sites they're using this on, or their admin panel
or whatever. And I think it's going to be a use
case that we see a lot more people orienting
towards. These LLMs are not great, depending
on how big your application is, though. These
things are not quite there, where if you have
something that's a thousand files or something,
or more, where you're going to be able to have a
really reliable, super reliable experience per
se. Within a year, we'll chat a year from now,
I suspect the answer is going to be different.
So it kind of depends on the size of the app,
the scale of the app, and if it's too big,
you're looking at the prototyping, just pure
acceleration of product development. And if it's
not, then you can just do it entirely from Bolt.
So this is useful. So what would you say
are the major limitations of Bolt today,
where people should just know, "Okay, it's
not going to get you here yet. Maybe in
the future it will." So it sounds like, if
you have a really large existing code base,
probably not the best tool yet.
What else should people know?
I would say that's probably the main one, because
I think if you have a large existing code base,
you're going to need something like Cursor.
And you're going to need to be a developer,
meaningfully, to be editing that stuff.
I think outside of that, there's a,
just like using any other productivity tool,
like Photoshop or Figma, or like a DSLR or
whatever. There's some level of education, and
using the tool, and learning how to use it,
that's required to really unlock a lot
of the maximum capabilities of the thing.
And the people that we see that are most
successful with Bolt, outside of developers,
the people we see that are most successful are
people that are amazing PMs, for example. Because
these are people that understand enough
about how the technology works, typically,
and their job is to direct developers on how to
go and improve the product. And go and look into
how to actually spec this thing out in a way
that's executable, without lossiness in the
communication. And when you think about, "Okay,
how would you best interact with an AI developer
agent?" It's basically that. You really want
to be good at defining scope, and helping it
go and debug various things, or whatever have you.
There's a huge overlap of the skill set of being
a rock star PM, and being really good at using,
frankly, any of these text to apps or Cogen tools.
I love that you made that point. That's exactly
the point I've been trying to make, I have a
newsletter post about this. Because when all these
tools came out, there was so many people saying,
"Okay, PMs are dead. We don't need them anymore.
We can just build things so quickly and easily,
what's the point?" But I completely see the
world the way you see it. The hard part now is,
now it's easy to build the thing. Now it's,
"What the hell should we build? Can we clearly
articulate what it is we want to build?" And
then, "Can we just have the taste to know,
is this right, is this correct? Is
this good? Is this going to solve
the problem?" And then it's like, grow it,
which is something also PMs think about. So,
I completely agree. Basically it feels like PMs
are, and a lot of PMs listen to this, so they'll
love hearing this. To me, it feels like PMs are
the best positioned role to thrive in this world.
Zero question. I mean that was, as Bolt
was growing and we were like... Because
we were a developer product before this, and so
we expected the audience to be 100% developers
that were using this. And we just kept seeing more
and more and more people that were not developers
using it, to the point where it's like, 67% of
our users are not developers, at this point. And
when I started talking to these folks, at first I
was just weird, or whatever. It was like, "Well,
what's going on here?" But then it just kind
of clicked as like, "Oh, well, this is going
to change everything. The entire software
world order is going to get rewritten, here."
Because the way that companies are
organized to build software today,
totally going to change. The idea that again,
PMs are the people that really understand,
to the pixel level, what matters into making
a great product experience. And often they're
having... And listen, I'm a developer, myself.
They have to go and harangue the developers
to get things to be how they really ought to be,
to the smallest levels. And now, how this is going
to work, if you fast-forward one, two, five years,
whatever. PMs, they're going to be "writing code",
quote, unquote, instead of just writing a JIRA
ticket and waiting for a developer to do it.
The developers are going to be able to work on
intellectually challenging tasks that LLMs are
not well suited for, and still being augmented
by LLMs to do it. But PMs are going to be able
to go in and just make the changes themselves.
And what blew my mind is, it's not priced in,
to any of these companies out there. And it's not
reflected in the org charts of all the software
companies in the world right now. That is going
to completely change. The winners, at least,
their org charts are going to completely
change, and how they approach building
products and shipping products. Completely.
And it's starting, this is the beginning.
I want to follow that thread, but
first of all, I want to also add,
and correct me if you disagree with
this. I think when we talk about PMs,
that also applies to founders,
like product thinking founders-
One hundred percent.
... very similar. And then, I
think it's also important to note,
if you also have engineering skills and
design skills, you will be at an advantage.
That only helps you. But if you're looking at this
triangle of the triad of product, engineering, PM,
it feels like the PME skills are the ones that
will be most important and valuable. Although
it'd be great if you can also be in code,
and if you could also design really well.
Absolutely. And to me, it's the most
exciting mix. I think PMs, designers and
entrepreneurs that are non-technical,
that's the most exciting thing to me,
just because it's a brand new market that's
being unlocked here. For the first time ever,
these folks can directly code and build
the product, themselves. Their vision,
directly into the software itself. That's going
to change everything. That is changing everything.
So when you talk about how org charts are
going to change, what are you imagining
there? Is it just fewer engineers, mostly,
or what do the future org charts look like?
Good question. And I bet you there's going to be
some Gartner analysis someday, years from now or
whatever that's like, "Here's how the best," some
term is applied to how the best companies are
organizing. But yeah, I think that we're going
to see developers probably being pulled off of
a lot of the, generally speaking, pulled off of a
lot of user interface type work. I would imagine.
Except for the most complicated of those things.
And you're going to see designers and PMs really,
really leading the charge, and being responsible
for crafting those experiences. And perhaps having
a developer attached to be reviewing
the code and making sure the guiding,
the code that they're writing, reviewing those
pull requests and et cetera. And I think maybe
even the engineers are... Like you pointed out,
having engineering skills is not going to hurt
you. It's going to make you way more effective.
But I do think there's going to be, the leverage
that the front engineer is going to have is, it is
now insane, it's only going to get more so. And so
I could see there just being fewer front engineers
attached to, I'm seeing more product and design
folks, with one or two engineers or something.
And really having a larger matching of pods like
that. Something like that strikes me as probably
how this is going to start trending towards.
This touches on, we had a researcher from OpenAI
in the podcast. She actually started her career,
she worked at Anthropic first,
as a front-end engineer. And said
that once she saw what Clyde could do,
for front-end engineering, she's like,
"I need to move to a different function."
And so she moved into research, because she
saw that role disappearing, potentially.
And that's exactly what you're saying.
Yep.
So let me ask you this, I don't know if you
have a clear thesis on this yet, but say,
you just had a kid. Say your kid is, in the
future, starting school. Let's say your kid
was starting college soon. Do you have thoughts
on just what skills slash areas you think they
should go into, versus avoid, that maybe are
popular now and are going to be less popular?
Understanding how to leverage these AI
tools is key. I wouldn't necessarily,
I think maybe getting a basic understanding
of how programming works, et cetera, is great.
It's like technical foundations, just
understanding how systems work, how coding works.
Exactly. But it doesn't have to be,
because I think back to if Bolt existed,
like Albert and I say this to each other
all the time. Since the get-go, StackBlitz,
we've been building the thing that we
wish we had when we were 13. And heck,
for everything we built since then. And
especially with Bolt. I mean, I don't know
if I would've gone as deep as I did on learning
how to code, and being an engineer, if that had
been around then. The whole reason we got into
it is we had ideas for products, and businesses,
that we wanted to build. And coding was just
a necessary requirement in order to do that.
And that said, I think people need to follow
their intrinsic interests. If folks are really
interested in really getting in the
nitty-gritty of how computers work,
and program leaders, or spark and compilers,
or whatever, go for it. I think that stuff is
still going to be relevant. I don't know if
we're going to really have, we'll see, but to
the degree that there's AGI where it's like, we
don't have to think about anything ever again.
Yeah, that's always the answer
here. Do we sell anything?
Yeah, it's like if we're at that point, it's kind
of... I don't know, I'm not sure. But I think
from, at least what I feel like seems like the
next at least five years of what we're looking at,
I think people are still going to, there's
still going to be places to specialize,
and really go deep. But I think you want to go
into it with the idea, not like, "I'm going to
go and learn computer science because I'm
going to get a job for sure out of it."
I just think that's generally not a
good... This is like, my co-founder and I,
we didn't go to college. My co-founder dropped
out of college after a semester or something,
but I didn't go, because I was like, "We're
coding," we were doing contracting at the time,
making money. And it was like, "This is a
lot of," you know, it would've been like
a hundred grand of debt by the end of the thing,
just for four years of in-state tuition, at U of
I. 120 grand, I think, at that time.
And lo and behold, I mean there's a
huge issue with this. Where people are
kind of... There was a prevailing thought
by society that going to college in the early
2010s or late two 2000s, that you're going to
get a job on the other side. That's going to be
high paying. And that just has not been the case
for a lot of people. And I think that's just
going to continue to be the case. But again,
not to deter people from doing it, but you have to
go into it being like, "I for sure, this is what I
want, and I want to go and be the best that I can
possibly be at this thing." You know what I mean?
I like the transfer to your kid is going to be
like, "Don't even go to college," potentially.
Only if they want to. I think at 18, it's a
huge ask. I mean, it's a huge ask, not even
at 18. It's like at 17, because you could go apply
for colleges. It's just such a huge... Like, a six
figure debt commitment to someone who's making
$0, or negative dollars, and that young. Unless
you really have conviction, it costs nothing
to go and explore and learn for free, online.
I want to come back to the skills
that you think are going to be most
important, and let me try to mirror back a few
things you said, that I very much agree with.
So it feels like if you want to be successful
in the world where AI can build things for you,
more and more, what I'm hearing is get good
at figuring out what people need and want,
what problems they need solved. Get good at
articulating it really well to the AI tools.
And there's this talk, "You don't need to be a
great prompt engineer. You don't need to work
on prompting," but it feels like it's more and
more important, because you tell it something
and it goes off and builds a thing. If you're
clear about it, it'll save you a lot of time.
So it's be good at figuring out problems people
need solved, figure out how to articulate that
problem well, and ask for a clear solution.
Figure out how to grow the thing, feels like
that's still going to be a need, because Bolt's
not going to go and find every... I could see
that still running paid ads, and stuff like that.
But it feels like that's going to be ongoing need.
And then I feel like there's
this kind of unstuck step,
like helping AI get unstuck, and
it feels like that's where maybe
engineering skills will come in more
and more. Thoughts on just that skill?
Oh, totally. Yeah. So we actually, two weeks ago
I think, we announced this program called Bolt
Builders. And it's basically the genius
bar at the Apple Store, where as folks
are building on Bolt that are not developers,
they'll run into some nook or cranny where the
AI just cannot figure it out, or whatever.
And I think that's just going to continue
to be the case for the time to come. That's our
position, and that's why we spun up this program.
And these are humans, that help you out.
These are humans. And people
that we're certifying. And so,
in Bolt in the coming weeks or whatever, there's
going to be a button where you can just say,
"Hey, connect me with a certified expert." And
you can chat with them live, and they'll help
you get unstuck, and you pay I don't know,
50 bucks an hour. Whatever it is. And then
you get unjammed and you keep prompting. And
again, I just think this stuff is, it just all
seems like gravy to me. Engineers get to focus
on difficult challenges, not like cookie cutter,
"Let's make another CRUD app," stuff. They get to,
debugging is challenging, and fun. And going and
working on intellectually stimulating tasks,
and all this stuff that's just copy pasta,
over and over, all this, error app. It's just
like, let the AI do all that kind of crap.
This is a potentially new job, for now at least,
just unstuck the AI. Which I think over time,
it'll get better and better, and we
maybe won't need these people. But
I love that it's now AI first, and person
second. Versus person building the thing,
and then AI. Like when Copilot
launched, it was just like, "Cool,
here's a little suggestion for this function," and
now it's flipped. "Here's everything." And then,
"Oh, I don't know what to do here.
Help us here." And then, it's like a
human suggestion. Isn't that interesting?
It's like, human Copilot is flipping it.
Totally. Yeah. That's what's wild is, I
think Sonnet was really the first model
that flipped the equation, because
that was really us, and old Cursor,
and all these other things. The rapid growth
started the second Sonnet went online. We
actually tried building Bolt almost exactly
a year ago, with the frontier models at the
time. Spent a week or two building it. It just
didn't work. The output, the code output was
not reliable enough. It would constantly, it
would be a broken app, or it would look ugly,
or whatever. And then we got a sneak peek of the
Sonnet stuff in May and we were like, "Oh. Okay,
we should take that project back off the shelf
and green line it, because this might be it."
And lo and behold, that's exactly what has
happened. But yeah, that's the big deal that is,
kind of under the hood, this is... What's going on
here is, a very critical threshold has been passed
with LLM's ability to write production grade
code and apps that actually look beautiful,
and actually function well. It's not perfect,
but there's kind of this zero to one moment
that's happened where it's like, "Okay, so
now, yeah. Now the AI is the first thing,"
and then you're kind of popping a developer in
every now and then, versus the other way around.
I did not know that. I didn't realize
that so much of this was unlocked with,
like it's sitting on top of Anthropix work, and
specifically Sonnet. That was the first model,
you're saying, that could code well enough.
Yeah, zero question.
Wow.
Zero question. Absolutely.
That is fascinating. Just the amount of, I
don't know, revenue and business and ecommerce
that that one model has unlocked,
is insane. I did not realize that.
It is. And in retrospect, I'd mentioned,
we'd never done an AI product at StackBlitz,
and it's tempting. Like when of ChatGPT went
online, everyone started adding AI to their
products. We just didn't see a clear place for a
really added value. So I was not super bullish on,
you know, a lot of people were like, "AGI is going
to be here in 2023." You know what I mean? There's
all this stuff that was being said, and I was
like, "I just don't know if I necessarily buy
how fast people say that it's going to move." And
to a certain degree, that was the correct view.
What I didn't really think about though, is if
AI, if LLMs are going to get better at a specific
vertical, which are going to be the things that
it would be. And if you look at law, for example,
you want to make the best LLM for looking
at case law. The problem with that stuff is,
it's not deterministic. The judge's ruling is
dependent on society's view of things at the time,
political stuff going on, the jury. There's
a ton of things, that it's not deterministic.
And so you can't really create a lot of
training data that's going to be super reliable,
and produce really good results. And
you can't just make up cases and say,
"Theoretically, the judge would say this."
Because, I mean, it just doesn't work.
Software is deterministic. When you write
code and you hit run, it either runs or it
doesn't. And that's the key insight Anthropic
really had. They just went deep. And then,
this is what they're doing, is just reinforcement
learning on basically permutating every type of
app you could ever build, and just spinning up
tens of thousands of cores or whatever to do
that. Just building tons of training data, and
doing reinforcement learning, and making their
LLMs the best in the world at building beautiful,
reliable applications. I'm extremely bullish.
It makes technical sense why, of anything, LLMs
are going to get insanely better at writing code
than probably most other types of applications for
LLMs. Simply because it's something that can be
extremely deterministic, and permutated thousands
and thousands and thousands of times per second.
And so I think the broader trend here is... And
Sonnet has woken everyone up. Google, and Open AI,
all the... Everyone is now gunning for coding
because, how big is the market opportunity to
rewrite the software world order? It's trillions
of dollars, or something, right? The world runs on
software. So I think that just in a macro, the
highest macro view, and why we went and raised
money for Bolt. This seems like an extremely clear
shot, there's this, you can kind of separate the
hype of what people say and blah, blah, blah.
When you break it down technically, this makes
sense. It makes sense what's going to happen here.
And for us, we're like, we are so happy to be well
positioned to go and enable people to kind of ride
this wave of the innovation that is here in LLMs,
and is going to just keep coming, and therefore
enable more people to build even crazier amazing
software. So that's our world view, at
least, of what's going on here at the macro.
And when did Sonnet even come
out? It's been a while, right?
I think they officially, I think it was in
June, when they officially put it online.
So since June, this is the worst it will ever
be, the state of AI coding. And it's already
this good. And there hasn't been anything,
like they haven't launched their new model,
since last June. So this tells us just how
quickly things are going to start moving
once they launch their next model. And as
you said, everyone's gunning now for this,
because they realized "We're behind on the coding
piece." So, wow. This is going to get crazy.
I agree. Yeah, it's been, again, there was no blog
post that laid all of this out for
us. It's just been kind of this-
You just noticed the code
was really good, basically.
And from there, it's just, we've
been piecing together all this other
stuff. So it's been kind of the thrill of a
murder mystery of, "What is going on here?"
Oh, really.
Yeah. You know what I mean?
Just piecing together what you've
seen on Anthropic releasing,
is that what you mean? What have you
been noticing, murder mystery-wise?
Well, and then the impacts of Bolt, where we
have people that are not technical using this.
How are they using it? Why are they doing
this? And then, all the stuff we've talked
about in this podcast has been the result of nine
months of just R&D and seeing the results of it,
and then going, "What?" And then digging
in, doing another thing and then going,
"What," again. And then it just keeps happening,
because there's no charted course for this.
It's like an anthropology, if that's the
right term, of just watching. It's like
an emergent discovery, it sounds
like. Versus you had the strategy,
"Here, we're going to do this," where a
persona to launch this thing will happen?
Yeah, a hundred percent. Yeah. I think
that that's the best way to put it.
It's the best way to put it. It's exactly
that. And so it's very interesting to just-
To watch, and be a part of it, I imagine.
Yeah, yeah.
And I think as people say, "Okay, these
are just toys, they're prototypes,
it's not going to work with your existing code,
it's not going to scale." It's important to note
just what we talked about. This is a model
from last June that this is possible on,
and everybody's working on the next cutting
edge model that will make this even better,
and that's going to come real soon. Okay. Amazing.
I just have a few more questions to close out this
conversation. One is just, what is coming next
for Bolt? What are some of the cool new features
that'll be launching before this comes out? Maybe
right after this comes out, maybe in mid-March?
Yeah. Okay. So by the time,
and I'm going to go back and
tell our engineers, "I said this on this podcast-"
"I've committed. Sorry, guys."
This is, I found actually being a leaky
faucet on talking on podcasts and stuff,
my engineer is like, "How could you tell
them..." "You just have to ship it faster,
now. You got to make it real," right?
Or we'll get AI on it.
No, no. Yeah. But I think for us it's like, again,
we've seen a lot of PMs, designers, entrepreneurs,
et cetera, using Bolt. And so, we're really
looking at better fitting with the tools
that folks are using to do those things today.
Bolt's not going to replace them, or something.
And if you're working at a company, how do you
integrate this stuff with your existing business,
or your existing product and code base? Because
that's the question we often get from people is,
"How do I open my," like we're talking to one of
the fan companies the other day, and like, "How do
we open our production code base in this, that's
like 20 years old?" I'm like, "You don't. None
of this stuff. That's not what you do. This is
for rapid product development in your use case."
So the features that we're going to be shipping,
I'm pretty stoked about this one, so we've been
working on this for a while and we've partnered
up with a company called Anima to do this. But
basically, so on any Figma URL, when you're
looking at a design that you've made,
if you just put bolt.new in front of that URL
and hit enter, it's going to suck that design
into Bolt, and turn it into a full stack
app or mobile app, just out of the box.
That is genius.
Yeah. It's-
Amazing.
It's going to be nuts. Yeah, I mean, it's really
fun to use. Because whether you're a developer or
designer, or whatever, going and taking that and
turning it into an actual coded app. And the thing
is, once it's in Bolt, you can just keep prompting
from there. You're like, "Yeah, well, add another
page here." So you can have things that,
where you want pixel perfect design, you can
have it, and it'll translate one to one. And it's
splitting out the assets. Anima's been doing this
since 2017, Figma to code. They've got the best
agent in the world for, they're the number one
Figma plug-in, or whatever. And so in Bolt, it's
going to just work. It's just deeply integrated
So it's bolt.new slash, the
Figma URL, to the design.
Yep. That's all you got to do.
Amazing.
And in Bolt, we're going to also have a
little Figma icon in the chat thing. So
if you go to Bolt itself, you can click it
and then paste the URL, or whatever. But
yeah, but it's like that. It's from Figma
to full stack app in a click. Literally.
That's crazy. So that one's pretty cool.
And then the other one that we're working
on is an integration with Slack, because often
when you're talking about Figmas, like Figma
links or whatever, at a company, you're in Slack
or whatever. So you're having conversations about,
"Hey, we should really add a page to this that
does da-da-da." And so we're actually creating a
Bolt Slack bot whose job is to basically act
like a developer on your team. And so you can be,
in a thread, you can be like, "Hey, I think
we should a homepage." "Yeah, okay. @Bolt,
can you whip this up real quick?" And it'll go and
just suck down the entire conversation history so
far in your Slack, on the thread or whatever.
You'll be like, "Okay, cool. So you kind of
want me to take this Figma URL, which I can
convert automatically," thanks to the future
I just mentioned right before this. "I can just
go and convert that thing out of the box, and
then you want me to add a page to it, and then do
this thing. Got it. I'm going to go do that. Oh,
here's the URL where you can open it up and keep
prompting." You know what I mean? So it's like
having a developer or somebody to kind of
kick this thing out. And you're just like,
"Go make this thing real quick."
So those two things, I think it's,
again. You start think about how our company's
going to change how they're currently doing
product development. And even just like,
"Hey, we need to spin up a marketing site.
Here's the thing." We're like, "Can you do that,
Bolt?" "Yep. Let me go do that." You know what I
mean? And that's why I'm kind of excited about
those two, in particular, because I think it's
going to be well received, and folks are going
to be stoked about it. I hope. Knock on wood.
Those are awesome features. I love the Slack
piece, because when I think about agents,
there's always talk about agents. To me the
simplest way to understand it is just a Slack bot,
just that AI can talk to you like they're a
person in Slack. And I love that's exactly
what you're doing. And this is this gigantic
feature of just like, "Hey, you just have this
engineer now that can go build stuff for you."
Let me actually ask you a question along these
lines, that I was meaning to ask, but I forgot. Is
just, your engineering team, what are they using
to build Bolt? I imagine it's a lot of Cursor. How
much is Bolt, at this point, involved in building
Bolt? And is there any other tools that they found
useful, find useful, that are worth highlighting?
Yeah, good question. Yeah, we definitely use
Cursor. Our folks use Cursor a lot. We use Bolt
a lot for the product development process,
like a ton, we're using it. And we're doing
basically the flow that I described, where
if things that need to be Pixel perfect,
we're going to Figma for. And often we're
taking that and we're pulling that into Bolt,
because we've got access to the integration
today. So pull that into Bolt and we're saying,
"Hey, go add these things or
whatever." Or just saying, "Hey,
here's a screenshot of our UI, go do da-da-da."
Other AI tools that the developers are using.
I think those are the primary ones. I mean,
I think we've got a subscription to Claude,
and ChatGPT, and things like that. But I think
for development, Cursor is the main thing,
Yeah, it's cool how few tools, like there's so
many AI tools, and it's interesting how few people
actually end up using. It's like Cursor, Claude,
ChatGPT, and then maybe another tool. Like Bolt.
Yeah. Totally.
Okay. Final-ish question. Say somebody is opening
up Bolt for the first time. What's something that,
imagine you could sit next to every new
user that's just trying Bolt for the first
time, and you could whisper a tip in their ear to
be successful with Bolt. What would that tip be?
And this is like, because we have a
lot of different types of users. I
imagine you're talking about PMs
or designers, and that sort of-
Let's do PMs. That's a good one.
That's a lot of the audience here.
I would say, talk to this thing like you do a
Linear ticket, or a JIRA ticket. That would be
my advice. And talk to this like you would, like
you're talking to one of the developers on your
team. And what that means is, be specific
on things that matter. And on things where,
also, you can let it be creative.
You can go to and just say, "Hey,
make it prettier." And it does a good
job, it actually does a really good job,
when you give it just, vibes. So anyway, I think
for PMs it's like, you have the skillset. You know
how to do this. This is, just think of this
as your coworker, your developer coworker.
I love that. Because these tools are so easy,
you just go in and it's like tell it a thing,
and then, cool. You have a website. It's coded,
boom, done. And what I'm hearing here is, take a
little time to craft your ask. It may be tempting
to just start, "Cool. Build me a serum," and then
you're stuck with that first version. And then
you're like, "Oh, well, okay. I didn't mean that."
So it sounds like your advice is take some time to
craft the ask, and be clear about what you want.
Yeah, totally. Especially if you have a clear
vision of what you're trying to build. And
something reasonably sophisticated.
And what I recommend everyone to do,
if it's your first time trying Bolt and
you're like, "What should I have it do,
and I don't have an idea"? Tell it to build
you a personal website. There's something
like magic. You take your LinkedIn copy, and
paste your LinkedIn bio and work experience,
just like select text, copy, paste it.
"I need a website, my name is so-and-so,
here's my LinkedIn history. My favorite color is
blue, and I like dogs." And then hit paste, right?
"Make it prettier."
[inaudible 01:22:24] actor. Yeah. And then,
you know what I mean? And then you can hit
deploy. And if you don't have a .com yet, now
you can. Right? I mean, now you have a real,
personalized service. I think there's kind of a
moment around that where it's like, "Oh, okay,
wow. This," it's zero shot, zero shot 99.999%
of the time. You're getting a beautiful personal
website that you didn't have before, that would've
taken you an hour, on Wix. If not more. And that
gives you the taste of, "Oh, okay, cool. So if
I really take the time to think this through,
and make a PRD, and then put that in piece by
piece into this thing, the sky's the limit."
Eric, this has been just insane on so
many levels. I have so much to process,
I think a lot of listeners do too. Maybe as
an actual final question, I saw this story
about how when you were starting StackBlitz,
or maybe even before StackBlitz, you squatted
in the AOL office. Because you had some badge
that still worked. Maybe just tell that story.
Yeah, that was the thing I was most
known for. That happened like 2012,
and I was 19 years old, so it's been a very
long time. I think I'm 33, now or something.
The statutes of limitations are expended.
Yeah, yeah, exactly. But yeah, for a while I
was like, "I have to do something more notable
than living at AOL. This can't be what I'm known
for." But now people are like, "Oh, wait. You're
the StackBlitz guy, and you're the AOL guy?"
So when I first came out to Silicon Valley, we got
into a, I was building a K12 education startup at
the time, and this is back during the days where
Y Combinator, they only gave you like 20 grand,
and so there was this offshoot of Y Combinator
called Imagine K12, it was Jeff Ralston who, I
think he was CEO of YC a couple of years back.
And then Imagine K12 merged into Y Combinator
a couple of years after Rob went through it,
but anyways, they had an office space at AOL.
At the time, AOL was trying to reinvigorate the
company and they were like, "Hey, we should
get young startup blood in here, so let's
rent out office space to teenagers," basically.
So I was there, and we ended up running out of
money. 20 grand doesn't go very far in the Valley,
so three or four months in, we were like, "Oh God,
what do we do?" And I was going to the AOL office
multiple times a week, because we had access cards
to get in to get to the investors' offices. And I
realized, I was like, "You know, they have couches
here, and they have food. There's ramen that you
can microwave, and there's a gym where there's
a shower, and even you can do laundry." And then,
so I was like, "I don't know, maybe while I figure
this out, I'll just live out of here." And so
that's what I ended up doing for, I think, four or
five months. I was living out of this headquarters
over on Page Mill in El Camino, in Palo Alto.
And then, I got away with it for a while just
because the guards, the security guards, they
worked 12-hour shifts. And so the guys that, when
I was there at night... And I was coding, all day
every day, basically. So the guys at night just
were like, "Dang, this guy works really hard."
And then in the morning they'd be like, "Wow,
this guy is working really hard." And I became
friends with some of them, and then eventually,
I think there were also a whole bunch of Stanford
students that I think they put bunks in one of the
aisles. It was just started getting out control,
so I think they started cracking down. And
then one morning, at like 4:00 in the morning,
a guard came in and threw me out.
I'm from Chicago. I don't know anyone.
At that point I'm like, "I know no one in the
Bay Area." So I went to a Starbucks, which was
not open. I slept on the table outside of the
thing. And I think I hit up one of the other
entrepreneurs that was in the program. I was like,
"Do you have a couch? I think I kind of need it,
at this point." Yeah, the press got wind of it,
and it was this worldwide story. But I lived on
a dollar a day. That was the crazy thing. My
burn rate was a dollar a day, at that time.
What did you use that dollar for?
This is back when McDonald's had the
Dollar Menu. Literally. So it was like,
I occasionally would go and get a cheeseburger
or whatever. Yeah, it was ultimate scrappiness.
You're technically homeless. From homeless, to one
of the fastest growing startups in history. Eric,
what a journey. This is such an interesting
point in time of your life, and of just tech.
No matter what happens, I'm sure you'll
be extremely successful, but it's such an
interesting just point in that journey. And I'm
thankful that you made time to share it with us.
It's always good to just have the perspective of,
you should start companies to keep the
mindset that you're doing it to have fun. So,
stoked to see where this goes, one way or
the other. It's going to be interesting.
Eric, final questions. Where can folks
find online if they want to reach out,
maybe follow up on some stuff you shared,
and how can listeners be useful to you?
Yeah, totally. I mean, yeah, so bolt.new is the
website, over on Twitter, I'm @ericsimons40 on
Twitter, and I think our Twitter account is
@boltdotnew, not with a period. It's like,
B-O-L-T-D-O-T-N-E-W. And yeah, I'm curious to
hear what folks think. I mean, this is, again,
we are learning so much from the people that are
coming and trying this thing out and giving their
feedback. And within the first meeting of it
going online, we were not the experts on how
use the tool anymore, and it's been that way
ever since. And so, I love hearing from folks
on what they want to see next, and how this is
helping them. And where they run into problems,
like where we need to go and fix things. So my
email address is Eric@stackblitz.com. That's Eric
with a C. So I'd love to hear from anyone,
whether it's a DM on Twitter, or an email.
Amazing. Eric, thank you so much for being here.
Awesome. Thank you so much for
having me. This is a blast.
Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you can
subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also, please
consider giving us a rating or leaving a review,
as that really helps other listeners find the
podcast. You can find all past episodes or learn
more about the show at lennyspodcast.com.
See you in the next episode.