30% of PMs that leave Palantir start a company.
Just give us a picture of
what the people are like.
I feel like they screened really hard
for a few traits in particular. One
is like very independent-minded people who weren't
afraid to push back. Two is people
with broader intellectual interests.
What's the difference between, say, a
PM at Palantir versus a traditional PM?
They were extremely careful about only making
people PMs who had first proven themselves out
as forward deployed engineers. You basically
could not become a PM any other way. There's
two types of engineer at Palantir. So, there's
one that works on the core product and they're
a traditional software engineer. There was
a different type of engineer which you sent
into the field. You would spend maybe Monday
to Thursday and you would actually go into the
building where the customer worked and you would
work alongside them. You would literally get a
desk there and so, that engineer became
known as a forward deployed engineer.
What's something that you believe
that most other people don't?
I think this is a somewhat
contrarian view within tech.
Today, my guest is Nabeel Qureshi. Nabeel is a
founder, a writer, a researcher, and an engineer.
He was recently a visiting scholar researching
AI policy at the Mercatus Center alongside Tyler
Cowen. At one point, he worked with the National
Institute of Health and major clinical centers
to create the largest medical data set in the
world. He worked at the Bank of England for a
bit. He was founding member and VP of Business
Development at GoCardless, one of Europe's
biggest financial technology unicorns.
And most related to the topic of this
conversation, Nabeel spent almost eight years
at Palantir as a forward deployed engineer
working on public health projects with US federal
agencies, including public health services during
the COVID-19 response and applied AI in drug
discovery. Whether you are a fan of Palantir
or hate everything that they do, they are an
important and fast-growing company that is
pumping out incredible product leaders, as you'll
hear more than any other company in the world. So,
it is worth studying and understanding.
I've never heard an in-depth conversation
digging into how they operate, build product,
hire, and were able to scale from a primarily
services business to a software business.
So, I am very excited to bring you this
inside look. In our conversation, we go deep
into what the heck does Palantir even do,
why getting good at managing lots of data is
an underappreciated secret to their success, a
look at the unique forward deployed engineer role
that they innovated, and what other companies can
borrow from their insights here. Also, how they
hire and how they build amazing product leaders,
plus a ton of advice on talking to customers,
building products, and starting companies.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. Also, if you
become an annual subscriber of my newsletter,
you get a bunch of amazing products for free
for a year, including Superhuman, Notion,
Linear, Perplexity, Granola and more. Check it
out at lennysnewsletter.com and click Bundle.
With that, I bring you Nabeel Qureshi.
This episode is brought to you by WorkOS.
If you're building a SaaS app, at some point,
your customers will start asking for enterprise
features like SAML authentication and SCIM
provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in, making
it fast and painless to add enterprise features
to your app. Their APIs are easy to understand so
that you can ship quickly and get back to building
other features. Today, hundreds of companies are
already powered by WorkOS, including ones you
probably know like Vercel, Webflow and Loom.
WorkOS also recently acquired Warrant, the
fine-grained authorization service. Warrant's
product is based on a groundbreaking
authorization system called Zanzibar,
which was originally designed for Google to
power Google Docs and YouTube. This enables
fast authorization checks at enormous scale
while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases.
If you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features like
single sign-on, SCIM or user management, you
should consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in replacement
for auth zero and supports up to one million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
WorkOS.com to learn more. That's WorkOS.com.
This episode is brought to you by Attio, the AI
native CRM. Attio is built to scale with your
business from day one. Connect your email and
calendar and Attio instantly builds a CRM that
matches your business model with all of your
company's contacts and interactions enriched
with actionable insights. Sync in your product
usage, billing info, or any other data sources
and Attio's flexible data model will handle it
all without any rigid templates or workarounds.
With Attio, AI isn't just a feature, it's the
foundation. You can do things like instantly
prospect and route leads with research
agents, get real-time insights from AI
using customer conversations, and build powerful
AI automations for your most complex workflows.
Industry leaders like Flatfile, Replicate
and Modal are already experiencing what's
next for CRM. Go to attio.com/lenny to get 15%
off your first year. That's attio.com/lenny.
Nabeel, thank you so much for
being here. Welcome to the podcast.
Thanks, Lenny. Glad to be here.
In our chat today, I want to zero in on a post
that you recently wrote where you shared your
reflections on your time at Palantir. You spent
something, maybe just under eight years there.
The reason I'm really interested in Palantir
is I've been doing a bunch of research recently
looking into which companies hire the best product
managers and create the best product managers,
and Palantir just keeps coming up over
and over in the work that I'm doing.
So, I'll share a few stats real quick. I looked
at which companies produce the most founders,
especially out of their PM team, and Palantir
is, by far, number one. 30% of PMs that leave
Palantir start a company. And number two
is 18% and that's Intercom. So, that stat,
I looked at which companies PMs that leave get
immediately promoted in their next role, Palantir
is number one of all companies in the world.
I looked at which companies' PMs become the
first PM at another startup that they join,
Palantir is number two in the world. And then
I looked at which companies alumni PMs become
heads of Product down later in their career,
Palantir is number three in the world. Also, just
the company is doing extremely well. It's worth,
I think, something like $200 billion these
days. So, there's a lot to learn from Palantir.
I actually want to start a question that I imagine
every employee at Palantir constantly gets that,
and I still don't think people totally have an
answer in their head. What does Palantir do?
That's a great question. You started off
with an easy one, Lenny. So, Palantir is,
the way I describe it, is they achieve outcomes
for their customers very tactically. The way
they do that tends to be through a data platform.
So, they have what I consider to be the world's
best data platform, and I can go into what
that means in a second. And then there's a
couple of different versions of this. So, there's
one that's optimized for intelligence and defense
use cases that one is called Gotham. And then
there's one that's more optimized for commercial
use cases and that one's called Foundry.
And that's the classic explanation of what they
do. So, they sell a data platform. They typically
work with very large customers is the other thing.
So, it's going to be Fortune 50. It's going to
be governments around the world. It's going to be
those kinds of customers. So, that's the capsule
answer, but there's lots to unpack in there.
Awesome. Okay, and we're going to touch on a lot
of this stuff, including the data piece. I want to
start with talking about just the people and the
culture of Palantir. You shared a bunch of really
funny stories of what it's like to come to work
and even interview at Palantir. There's a story
you shared where because maybe the co-founder,
you're walking by and he's chewing ice,
and that's some benefits to cognition. Just
give us a picture of what the people are like,
especially early days Palantir and the
culture and how unique it might seem.
Yeah, it's definitely, it's an add-a-one
company. I don't know how else you would
start this company if you were not somebody like
Peter Thiel. And so far as, it seems like there
was a point at which they owned a silly fraction
of the office space in Palo Alto. So, you'd walk
around Palo Alto and there would just be Palantir
hoodies, Palantir buildings everywhere and so on.
And so, I feel like what happened at some point
is they raised a lot of money and they resorted
to all these really interesting ways of just
getting top talent out of places like Stanford
and other top schools and just people who knew
the founders who tended to be very interesting
intellectual people. And I feel like they screened
really hard for a few traits in particular. So,
I would say one is very independent-minded
people, people who weren't afraid to push back,
who questioned the frame of everything and
thought for themselves and had strong convictions.
Two is just people with broader intellectual
interests. Karp just released a new book and
he's quoting Habermas and all these European
intellectuals and just things you don't typically
see a tech CEO do. And so, I think there's that
intellectual strand in the company. And then yeah,
I think three is just people who are very
intensely competitive. There's a sort of win
at all costs mentality to the company. And so, I
think those were the set of traits that were this
gravity while in California at a certain time.
And so, you just had a lot of really fascinating
people joining the company at that time.
The way they screened for this was interesting
too. So, for the longest time, they had...
Everyone does this now, I think, but at the time,
it was a little bit rarer, is a founder had to
interview you in order for you to receive an
offer. And so, a founder, it could have been
Alex Karp, it could have been Stephen Cohen.
Earlier on, it might have been somebody like Joe
Lonsdale, but it was always one of these people.
And the interviews were pretty strange. With
Stephen, it would be, you'd be chatting about
philosophy for an hour and a half and it would
very much just be like he would pick a topic out
of thin air. It was impossible to prepare for,
and then he would just go very, very deep and
try and test the limits of your understanding.
But it would really just be a fun conversation
and then if you pass the vibe check, you'd be in.
And so, there was that strong selection mechanism.
There was also the question of, I think it might
have been Thiel who mentioned this, but he thinks
that a lot of the best recruiters in the world
or the companies that attract talent, they put
out this distinctive bad signal and it has to
turn some people off. That's the key of a good,
bad signal. So, I think in the present day, OpenAI
and Anthropic, they're both sucking up some of the
best talent that you and I know. And I think one
way they do do that, and they are sincere in this,
but they do really attract people who are almost
messianic about the potential of artificial super
intelligence and who really believe this
is the only thing that matters and it is
going to be the biggest thing in the world.
I think Palantir's version of that was that
they were quite focused on things like preserving
the West. There was a slogan of Save the Shire,
right? So, they were talking about military
and defense and intelligence and the importance
of that well before everybody else. And bear in
mind, this was during the era when it was social,
mobile, local apps. You had, social media was
on the rise. You had, the hot companies were
Facebook and Pinterest and things like that. And
so, this was, at the time, a very strange thing.
And so, I think to be drawn to that, you
had to look at the other options and say,
"Well, this is fine, but what am I really
doing in life?" Whereas you had this other
place that was like, "Hey, come solve the
hardest, messiest problems in the world
with us." And I think just at that time,
that really drew some really good people.
We're going to talk about the reasons people don't
necessarily like Palantir and the moral question
of what they do, but when people look at a company
that is like... I guess OpenAI, to your point,
is a good example where they're just so turned
off by maybe their approach. What you're missing
is that's potentially intentional because it
actually draws in the people they really want.
It makes me think about, I was involved in
creating the core values at Airbnb and something
that we learned at going through that process is,
when you define the values for your company, it's
really important to clarify who this is not for,
exactly as you described, which feels unnatural.
Like, "Oh, we want to be inclusive, we don't want
to make people feel like they don't belong." But
the whole idea is to be clear on here's who
will thrive here and here's who's aligned with
our mission. And what I'm hearing is Palantir
and these companies take it to the extreme.
A hundred percent, yeah. On my team at Palantir,
one process that we followed, I could talk about
this more if it's interesting, is when you started
a new project, you basically had to organize what
they called a murder board for it. I think this
is originally an army type. So, the idea is,
basically, you write up a two-page plan for
the project. You invite three or four smart
folks who don't know anything about the project
and their job is just to tear apart your plan.
And so, you have to write, here's the vision for
this, here are the goals, here are the tactics
over the next three months. And one section
was principles that you're following for this
project. And I remember giving this advice
a lot was just like when people joined,
they would write principles such as move fast
and I would always be, "Everyone likes to move
fast." It is not a good principle actually because
nobody can really disagree with this reasonably.
You need something that actually a lot of
people are going to go, "Why are you taking
this principle? This seems wrong to me." So, you
need something that people can disagree with.
I want to come back to the beginning of
what you described of what they look for,
what Palantir looks for in people. You talked
about independent-minded, a lot of interests,
broad interests, and competitive. First of
all, I think a lot of people hearing that,
especially the last part, be like, "I don't want
to work there." Why does this work? Because this
isn't naturally what you would think of as how
you build the most amazing, productive team.
I think it just draws people who want to win.
I think that's what was really important.
The other piece of it, I think, is that there's
actually, and this was much truer 10 years ago,
is there was a lot of talent that was a
little bit outside of the tech ecosystem
but could easily have been very successful
within it. So, people who got out of the
military or one of the intelligence agencies and
they were doing, let's say, an MBA somewhere to
transition into the corporate world. And I think,
typically, they would have taken a position at a
classic Fortune 500 corporation. And actually,
Palantir managed to get a bunch of that talent.
And at the time, that was very undervalued.
The people who succeed the most in the Marines
or the Special Forces or whatever it is, tend
to be pretty smart people. They tend to have
accomplished very difficult goals in very hostile
environments. And it turns out that when you're
starting a somewhat chaotic tech company, that's
actually a very useful skill to have. Again,
I think more companies are doing this now,
so Scale AI and et cetera. But at the time,
that was a very differentiated talent pool.
And so, I think having those values as opposed
to maybe the values that were more in fashion
then, so talking about how inclusive you are,
or the sushi that you serve at lunch, or whatever
it is, it just drew a very different crowd. And
I think the game that was being played there
was, one, it's mission alignment. You're doing
a defense company, that's the kind of person
you want to attract. But I think there's also,
two, which is just what is the talent that
maybe is a little bit undervalued now and how
do you actually draw those people to you?
And I think that game is always shifting.
This is definitely starting to explain why so
many Palantir alumni go on to start companies
and become leaders at other companies. These
are leaders that you're hiring. So, it feels
like a lot of it is just the talent you
hire are people that are naturally leaders.
I think you're right, and we can get more
into it, but I think there was also a very
concrete set of ways where that place
was a training ground for founders. I
even think it turned a lot of people who
might not have become founders into good
founders because of the way it works. So,
I think there was a selection effect there,
but there is also some training effect too,
but it's unique to the way the company works.
And is that along the lines of the forward
deployed engineer stuff or is that something else?
It is that, yes.
Okay, cool. We're going to get to that. I
love it. Okay, amazing. Before we do that,
one last thing is something I've seen is
that you guys at Palantir don't really
have titles. Everyone's the same level
and just generic titles for everyone.
Talk about that. Why do you think that
was important? Why was that useful?
I don't know this for sure, but I do know that
Thiel writes about this in Zero to One and his
take is just that as soon as we have these title,
you have a thing that people are competing for and
then you get these very unproductive conflicts.
You get people optimizing to game the system.
You get Goodhart's law everywhere. So,
it's like you have a metric and then
people basically manage to the metrics.
I don't want to pick on any one company,
but if you take Google, for example, there's
a lot of interesting posts by people who left
Google and they cite this as a reason
why they got a little bit disgruntled,
is that there's a way to get promoted. Rather
than, let's say, improving an existing product,
what you do is you start a completely new product
and that has your name attached to it. And then
when it comes to promotion season, you could
say, "Hey, I did this new thing." And then boom,
you have a new Google product, but
it's maybe confusing to the end user.
So, I think they wanted to avoid all these
kinds of dynamics. And so, the way that they
did that was they said, "Well, titles are not
going to be this memetic totem that everybody
competes for. Instead, everyone is just going
to have the same slightly meaningless title,
which is forward deployed engineer." And the
only people who did have titles were the CEO
and then there were six directors and that was it.
And now, I think it's a little bit more nuanced.
There are different teams. There are some people
with titles, but honestly, it was almost like...
We used to joke about it. It's like people would
leave the company and then you'd see them update
their LinkedIn and they would be like, "Oh yeah,
I was totally the SVP of XYZ." And it's like,
"No, you weren't. You're just..." But then it's
like I totally understand it too because when
you leave the company, you have to make your
experience legible to the next person. And so,
guess what? Things like SVP actually do matter.
And so, yeah, I think they wanted to avoid this
intel competition. There are downsides to
doing this. So, maybe the competition isn't
as explicit around a specific title, but
instead, what it becomes about is there's
a particular exact or something and you want to
gain that favor. And so, it becomes more about
who can get in the inner circle of this person
or whatever. And there were those dynamics too.
I actually am a big fan of this philosophy
though, the no titles one. I think what it
did do is that it basically said if you are in,
let's say you're in a role of you're leading
a very important project, which could happen,
what it said was... This is always fluid. So,
you are in this role because you're very good and
so, it's a meritocratic thing. But if you start
performing well, it's actually very easy to shift
that because there is no explicit " I am the GM
of this project title." And so, you always had to
earn your place in the company. You always had to
earn the right to work on what you were working
on, and I think that was a good side effect.
Let's start talking about forward deployed
engineers. What is a forward deployed engineer?
So, the way this originated was, basically,
you can think of it as there's two types of
engineer at Palantir. So, there's one
that works on the core products. So,
they don't necessarily leave the building
in Palo Alto or New York or the offices.
They're very much working on the core products
and they're a traditional software engineer.
Because of the way the company works where
you had these very large engagements with
these large entities, there was a different type
of engineer which you sent into the field. So,
what that meant was you would spend maybe
Monday to Thursday and you would actually
go into the building where the customer worked
and you would work alongside them. You would
literally get a desk there. And so, that engineer
became known as a forward deployed engineer.
So, within the company, that function is
known as business development or BD. And
then PD is product development. So, it's where
the product is made. And so, within BD, you had
forward deployed engineers. There are actually two
types. So, there is one that it's a more technical
software engineer. So, you have to pass a software
engineering interview and prove your chops there
and you would typically have a CS degree, but
there was actually a type of forward deployed
engineer that didn't have that. So, you would
still get a technical interview, but it would be
less about, do you know the specifics of this C++
algorithm? And it would be more about just like
can you reason about data? We didn't have that
division originally, but it turns out that there's
a lot of people who are technical adjacent,
shall we say, who you really need in the room
when you're working with these large organizations
or these large companies, because translating what
you're doing into language that would resonate
with an executive or being able to navigate
the social dynamics in a room, all these are very
valuable skills. And so, the hiring criteria there
were a little different. It was a bit more about,
are you savvy as a human? But all of that was
given the title of forward deployed engineer, and
it's just an engineer who works with customers.
Okay, so just to make this crystal clear for
people, a lot of people hear this idea of
Palantir having forward deployed engineers.
A few other companies have done this.
It's pretty radical. So, as you described,
you basically have a desk at a company. So,
you worked with Airbus and we'll talk about
that. So, let's just make it real. So,
you have a desk and a computer and login access
and all these things at Airbus. You go to their
office four times a week. You're sitting there
with their employees working side by side,
building a product for them, versus what
most people do where "they just talk to
customers," where they do an interview once
in a while, they do a Zoom, they share mocks,
things like that. This is like that on steroids.
Is that roughly the way to think about it?
It is, yeah. And so, we would really be there
a lot of the time. And so, the side effect of
that was, one, you learn to live and breathe the
customer's problems and you learn to speak their
language. And eventually, they saw you as one of
them and so, you develop these really close bonds
with the customers. So, at Airbus, I would be at
the factory where the planes were produced, or I'd
be sitting next to people diagnosing issues with
aircraft or whatever it was. Similarly, later on,
I worked with the NIH, which was part of the US
government, and I actually had a badge there and
I would work with civil servants and biologists
and clinicians and people who were working there.
And so, it's this pretty radical thing as you
suggest. I think the key thing there from a
business point of view is the average deal
that Palantir had was very large in the many,
many millions of dollars, which means that
you could pay for this as part of the thing
that the customer got. And then it was priced
according to the value that the customer got.
So, as a simple example, if you're Airbus and
let's say that you have an issue with one of
your planes and you need to fix it, and fixing
that is worth a $100 million or something to you,
that's how it would be priced. It would
not be priced as, "Hey, you're buying data
infrastructure and it's similar to Snowflake
or Databricks or one of these other providers.
It's much more anchored to, here is the outcome.
But then the job of the forward deployed engineer
is not just to deploy software. It is not just
to sell software. It is to actually solve the
problem. And so, you would have to be there.
You would have to meet the key stakeholders
who are actually in charge of reporting to the CEO
about the specific issue. You would have to become
their friend. You would have to gain their
trust. And you would have to, in some cases,
create new software such that it could actually
solve the novel problem that was in front of you.
So, I would have friends who worked with one
of our energy company customers and they would
have to learn the ins and outs of how oil wells
work. And then out of that, it turns out that
having streaming data is actually very valuable
for this use case. And so, boom, suddenly,
there's a product that can handle streaming data
that becomes part of the core platform. But that
would be the motion, is you learn about the
problem. You figure out what software would
best address it. You build that software. You use
it to accomplish the goal. And then eventually,
that gets folded into the broader product suite.
And so, you can start to see why this would be a
good forge for founders. And this was actually
part of my thesis going in and joining,
was I said, "Well, say, I got five reps of this,"
which I got more than that. But say, you got five
reps of doing this in five disparate contexts,
you actually become very good at this cycle of,
okay, go into the building, gain the trust
of the person, meet the people that are going
to become your users, talk to them about their
problems, make sure you're building something that
actually solves them, and it's just a boondoggle.
Get really fast feedback and iteration loops. So,
every week, you would have a cadence where it's
like Monday, you go in. You do your meetings.
Monday night, you build something. Tuesday,
you show it to somebody. Tuesday, you get the
feedback. Tuesday night, you iterate on it.
Wednesday, you show it to somebody. Wednesday
night, you iterate on it. So, you get four of
these, five of these cycles every single week.
It already got it. So you get four of these,
five of these cycles every single week,
and you're moving incredibly fast. So
6 weeks in, you've suddenly gotten to,
wow, this is really valuable, and somebody's
willing to pay you whatever, $20 million for it,
and boom. I think this is why you get so many
founders coming out of this same process.
It's becoming very clear why so many
founders emerged out of Ballinger. Okay. So
an important element of this as you described,
is that the idea here is build this as a one-
off solution to solve a real problem at say
Airbus or some government organization. And
then the idea as you create something out of that,
that then Ballinger can sell to other companies.
What's extra cool about that is they pay you
to solve this problem for them and then that is
funding this other product that Ballinger can
now sell to everyone. What a cool business.
However, early days Ballinger, everyone
thought it was just this services business
or just consultants building software for
companies like Airbus, there's no way they
can make this a platform that works for a lot
of people. Clearly, that's what's happening
and it worked out. This is like the holy grail.
Solve one customer's problem and then sell it
to everyone else. Every SaaS business basically
would love to do this. What do you think allowed
them to actually achieve this and be good at
this? What are some principles that worked?
Yeah. That's a great question and
it's true. I think that from when
I joined until maybe until IPO and a
little bit after, I was told, "Hey,
isn't this basically a sparkling extension? Isn't
it a consulting business lopping as a product
company?" And eventually it became undeniable.
One, because I always laugh when people are like,
"What does Palantir do?" It's like you can
go onto YouTube and just search Palantir
demo and you'll get plenty of demos of how the
software looks. Not many people know about this,
but you can go and sign up with a credit
card right now and start using it.
I can have a Palantir account?
You actually can. Yeah.
I did not know that. That's cool.
Yeah. I think it's called AIP now. So it's not
actually that mystical and there is a product,
and if you look at the margins, they
show that. So they have 80% plus margins,
which is not really what you would get if you
were actually a consulting company. It would
be closer to 20 or 30%. So then your question
was, well, how did they actually achieve this?
I think there was just incredible talent in the
product development organization, really top tier,
incredible talent. And it took some really, really
smart people to take the set of internal tools
that we were using at the time to create value
of customers and then go, what is the unified
version of this? Would this look like if this were
a product? And out of that process that I saw came
Foundry assume there was a similar process with
Gotham a while back. But basically it's like,
the motion was that you would go in and early on
you were basically armed with Jupyter Notebooks
and some data integration stuff, but it was very
primitive and you had to create value that way.
But we kept building tooling that was useful for
forward deployed engineers. So we were our own
first customers and at some point there was this
concept of, "Wait, what if we take our internal
tools and we let our customers use them?" And I
remember at the time, this is a really radical
idea. And then Shyam Sankar, I think he's the CTO,
maybe he's the president now, he just mandated
like, "Okay. Every customer deployment you have
to have a customer using this within three months
or whatever." So it was horrible at the time
because these had been built for these nerdy
Silicon Valley engineers, and so they weren't
particularly usable. They would crash all the
time. You'd have to debug spark errors or whatever
it was. But basically that process brought a lot
more rigor to our thinking about the product.
And out of that kind of, I would say three or
four year process came the Foundry product.
And then there was a lot of focus around
things like performance and reliability and
so on. That was all really painful. So yeah,
I think the answer was just talent. And then
there was this recognition that we do. We do
know things that most people do not know about how
data works in large organizations. That was the
other thing. We discovered a lot of "secrets" in
this process of living with customers for so long.
The basic one was just data integration
is massively painful inside organizations.
This is very hard to understand unless
you've worked in a large organization,
but it's actually impossible to even now to get
access to a lot of your own internal data that
you need to do your job. So you'll hear stories
of people being like, "I'm trying to calculate
our sales this quarter, and I had to wait six
weeks for some other analytics team to get me
this deliverable." So just knowing problems like
that and being able to focus our product efforts
around those problems, meant that we were
able to build something generalizable there.
Okay. There's a lot here. First
of all, you talk about Gotham and
Foundry. I know that we'll link to
videos of people checking these out,
but just what's the simplest way to
understand what these two products do?
So Gotham is optimized for military and defense
use cases and intel as well. I would say they both
have some things in common. So they both have,
I would describe this almost as a pyramid where
the bottom layer is data ingestion, the middle
layer is data mapping, and then the top layer is
anything that's user facing. So any UI component.
And then if you think of Foundry for a second,
there's different tools that allow you to
ingest data to it. There's different tools
that allow you to easily build data pipelines
and clean up data, which everybody has to do.
And then there's a bunch of tooling that
allows you to build compelling UIs on top,
do point and click analytics, do notebook style
workflows, however technical you are. So that's,
I mean, when it's a platform, it's a suite
of things that has a common data backing but
contains a bunch of different applications.So I
think that is somewhat true of Gotham as well. But
when you log in, you see this unified interface.
So what is the actual difference then? I would
say with Gotham, you're looking much more at
workflows like that involve maps, for example.
So when you're doing a military operation, a lot
of the time you are going to be looking at a map
and you are going to be monitoring the movement
of troops or tanks or whatever it is. Another big
difference is the idea of graph-based analysis. So
Gotham, one of the use cases was finding combing
through networks of terrorists and basically
finding the bad guys. So being able to do
queries that are graph-based was important. So
it's like, "Who is everybody that Lenny called
in the last week?" Imagine all the nodes fanning
out from there. And then it's like, "Okay. Well,
this one looks interesting. Let's zoom in
on that. What is this person's location?"
So it's this very graph-based way of thinking that
also applies to things like fraud. So Gotham has
been deployed against fraud, but if you look
at Foundry, it doesn't actually emphasize that
component so much because it turns out, let's
say you're a B2B SaaS company, you're probably
not doing that much graph-based analysis.
You're doing things that look a lot more like
classic SQL queries, tables, that kind of stuff.
So Foundry is a lot more traditional in that way.
That was an amazing explanation. For the first
time, I am starting to understand what these
products do. Basically, it's just sucks in a
bunch of data, cleans it up so you can actually
trust it and then helps you interact with it
in various use cases, maps, graphs, tables.
Yes.
Okay. Amazing. The example you gave
of what you worked on at Airbus,
you described it as basically a sauna
for making planes. Is that right?
Yes.
So how much of that does becomes a part of
this core product versus stays this one-off
thing? Is it elements, that's a cool innovation,
let's put that into Foundry. How does that work?
This was a really interesting story actually. So
the initial problem that we came into with Airbus
was that they had a new aircraft called
the A350 beautiful aircraft. By the way,
if you get to, I think if you fly New York
to Singapore, it's often in that A350. Really
nice. So it was a relatively new aircraft
at the time, and their mandate to us was,
"Okay. We need to ramp up production
of this really fast," much faster than
we've ever done it before. So it's like the
numbers are very approximate, but it's like,
"Okay. We're producing 4 this month, we need
to do 8 the next month, 16 the month after,
and so forth, and you are going to help us do
it." So this goes back to what I was saying
earlier is the mandate wasn't like, "Hey, we need
to upgrade our data infrastructure. We thought you
guys would be met the list of requirements."
It was much more just like, "Please help us
accomplish this mission. This is the big thing."
So we went in, scoped out the problem. There
were a bunch of different things that we
could build that helped accelerate this,
but one of the basic problems that we figured out
was that without getting too much into the weeds,
the way the factory would work, is that there's a
bunch of stations and you can think of the plane
as literally moving between each station and
then each station would do a certain set of
work on it. So initially, it's literally a big
fuselage and the fuselage is sitting there and
then people are doing a bunch of work orders
against it. They need parts in order to do
that work. And then at some point they say,
"Okay. This is ready to move to Station 31,
and the plane is physically moved to the next
station and then Station 31 does its next thing."
So in order for the next station to do its work
properly, they need to know, one, what work was
done at the previous station and what work is
remaining? Two is just like, if you think about
this problem, not all work is going to get done
on time. So things carry over to the next team,
and the next team then has to... So when I'm
describing this problem to you can start to
visualize, okay, maybe I need some Gantt chart to
this, and I need the ability to click in and say,
"Okay. What did Station 30 do and what work
orders remained undone?" And then it's like,
"Okay. For those work orders, what parts do
I need and where in the factory might they
be?" So this was very, very hard to do as it is.
A lot of it was just relying on people going and
having conversations with other people on the
factory floor, and coming from tech where it's
maybe not as complicated as building aircraft,
that is a phenomenally complicated process,
but it is easy to see, okay, you can
actually improve this problem with software.
All that data was stored in SAP and SAP is like
established software. It's good at what it does,
but it's not the most user-friendly necessarily,
especially if you're not an expert in how it
stores data. The table names are very hard to
understand and read. So one of the things we
figured out was just if you can pull in
these tables that may as well be written
in completely alien language, the table name
would just be like S3, F1_Z or something like
that. And you'd have to know, okay, this is the
table where the part ID is stored or something.
If you could pull in those tables and join them
in the right ways, and then just map them to human
concepts that humans can understand, so things
like a part a work order, an aircraft, et cetera,
and basically build a hierarchy or mapping between
them, then what you can do is, a user can just
log in and say, "Okay. Aircraft 79, where is
that? Okay. It's at Station 31. All right.
These are the work orders, et cetera." So you've
translated it into a more human-legible thing.
So the thing we built, I slightly flippantly
described it as Asana. It's a little different.
But basically that's what it did, was it gave
you a unified view of, okay, this is what's
going on inside the factory. This is the work
that needs to be done on this particular plane.
And then me today going to my job at Station 31,
what work orders do I need to fulfill and where
are the parts that I need to do that? So did this
directly become a part of Foundry? Not exactly,
because the way that other companies work is
not going to be using this same set of concepts,
but the overall idea of taking a bunch
of tables, and then mapping them to human
understandable concepts was a very powerful one.
So this actually resulted in a big piece of
Foundry now, which they call Ontology. You've
probably heard this term as you've seen... If you
see Palantir presentations, they always talk about
Ontology. This is what they actually mean by that,
is it is a set of concepts that is understandable
to you as a human and you are not having to go and
dig around and do. You're just able to say, "Where
is the aircraft now and where is it going next?"
So the ontology became a huge piece of Foundry.
It was directly informed by the learnings that we
had from building that application inside that
factory. And I would say it's still a very big
differentiator today. I don't think too many
other companies ship this kind of stuff yet.
Wow. I love how excited you still are about
this. I could see it being so fulfilling to
solve this big problem. I saw a stat that I think,
4X their productivity. What was the number there?
Yeah. I don't recall the exact
stat, but we did ramp up production,
I think at least 4X that 1
year, which I mean obviously,
they did this and we just helped with it. But
that CEO said that we played a critical part.
Also, you moved to France, I think for this. That
was how forward deployed you were.
You lived in France for how long?
Yeah. I lived in France for about a year and
a half. The way they built their planes is
they manufacture different components
around Europe. So they build the tail
in Spain and the fuselage in part of the UK
and Germany and so forth. So they basically
ship everything to France to be assembled
at the end, which you can imagine this is
a very messy process. So I was mostly in
France, but there would be weeks where I'd
have to fly between all these countries
just to figure out where things were.
In your post you wrote about how just
the life of forward deployed engineers
is pretty crazy. You just get a call
sometimes like, "Hey, you're flying to
this random country tomorrow. Get ready." Is
that just life as a forward deployed engineer?
It is. Yeah. The company had a very, I would say,
aggressive attitude towards travel in the sense
of when you join, you were basically told, "Look,
you have to be okay with travel. Are
you okay with that?" And the attitude,
which again I think is a very founder friendly
one is you need to be willing to just jump on
a plane that night if that's the best thing to
do for this customer and if it's going to get us
to where it needs to be to win. So there were
many times when it would be like, "I need to
take this cross continental flight tomorrow for
this particular thing because it will be useful."
So I think that's one of the takeaways for me
was just being in person is so valuable when you
are working with some external party, just going
there for a few days and spending time with them,
maybe going out for dinner. You build so much more
trust than if you're trying to close a customer
over Zoom or do an engagement over Zoom. It's
just the vibe is completely different. So yeah,
getting on a plane was a really cool part of
our job for a very long time. This obviously
changed around 2020 because COVID happened, the
company IPO, and so there needed to be a bit more
internal controls around this. But I would say
pre-2020, this was a very big part of the culture.
I'm excited to have Andrew Luo joining
us today. Andrew is CEO of OneSchema,
one of our longtime podcast
sponsors. Welcome, Andrew.
Thanks for having me, Lenny. Great to be here.
So what is new with OneSchema? I know that you
work with some of my favorite companies like Ramp
and Vanta and Watershed. I heard you guys launched
a new data intake product that automates the hours
of manual work that teams spent importing and
mapping and integrating CSV and Excel files?
Yes. So we just launched the 2.0 of OneSchema
FileFeeds. We have rebuilt it from the ground
up with AI. We saw so many customers coming
to us with teams of data engineers that
struggled with the manual work required
to clean messy spreadsheets. FileFeeds 2.0
allows non-technical teams to automate the process
of transforming CSV and Excel files with just a
simple prompt. We support all of the trickiest
file integrations, SFTP, S3, and even email.
I can tell you that if my team had to
build integrations like this, how nice
would it be to take this off our roadmap
and instead use something like OneSchema?
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many horror
stories of outages from even just a single
bad record in transactions, employee
files, purchase orders, you name it.
Debugging these issues is often finding
a needle in a haystack. OneSchema stops
any bad data from entering your system
and automatically validates your files,
generating error reports with the
exact issues in all bad files.
I know that importing incorrect data can cause
all kinds of pain for your customers and quickly
lose their trust. Andrew, thank you so much
for joining me. If you want to learn more,
head on over to oneschema.co. That's oneschema.co.
There's a lot of founders listening to this and
a question that I'm thinking and they're probably
thinking, and there's two questions here. One
is how hardcore to go potentially with their own
forward deployed operation. And then two is just
how and a company I know is actually doing this,
how far to go with one company's problem
and invest in just like we are going to
nail solving this one customer's problem
with the hope that this is something we
can abstract and sell as a big platform. So let
me start there. And you're building a company,
any I guess insights or advice on just how far to
go down this road of we'll solve customer one's
problem and we bet that this is going to be a
big opportunity for a lot of other companies?
So I would say on the forward deployed piece,
my friend Barry McCardel, the CEO of Hex,
the analytics company, he wrote a really good post
about this actually, and his take was just like,
"You probably don't need forward deployed
engineers." It's very specific. But I think
basically the thing there is you have to be
willing to be quite almost wasteful. You have
to be willing to invest a lot in finding the
thing. And for that you just need a certain
ticket size. So you need each customer's revenue
to be probably in the billions of dollars. If
it's below that, you're probably not looking
at a traditional forward deployed engineer
motion. It's something a little bit different.
So I think one thesis that a lot of people left
Palantir with and started companies around was
there's a lot of customers that Palantir won't
serve because maybe they're too small a ticket
size. So actually you could go and do something
like Palantir for those companies, but instead
of charging them $5 million, you're charging them
250K. So in a scenario like that, you might still
have forward deployed engineers, but they're not
going to France and spending five days a week in a
factory. It's more like you'll have one person and
they're looking after five different customer
accounts. It's more of that ratio in order to
make the numbers work. So I think a lot of the
principles can be abstracted from that experience,
but it is a really specific sales motion that
depends on a specific way of doing business.
I think to your other question, yeah, I think it's
obviously something that is very hard to give a
general answer to. My main thing here is just that
you can definitely tell when you are just doing
consulting and when you are closer to building a
product. And I think the error that people make
more often than not is they are actually too
stuck on their own product vision. That's the
mistake I've seen a little bit more actually than
the other way around. If you go to an enterprise
customer, and let's say you think you're doing
analytics software and it turns out they don't
actually care about internal analytics this much,
they actually have this other massive burning
problem and they don't have a good solution to
it yet. I think a lot of people are unwilling
to go and pivot to the big problem because they're
like, "Well, we're analytics software and so maybe
this customer is a fit for our thing," and maybe
that's the right call. In some scenarios, that is
the right call. You should go find a different
customer where your thing resonates more.
In other scenarios, it's actually the right
call to pivot and just put everything on that
big problem instead and then go and find
other customers for that thing. There's no
hard and fast rule. I remember reading a really
interesting post by, I think it was David Hsu
from Retool who had this exact thing. I think
he worked at Palantir for a while too. He said
that they had the Retool product and it wasn't
getting any traction at all. And then he tried
an outbound email campaign where he literally just
changed the subject line to build internal tools
easily. And then suddenly they started getting
all these replies from CTOs who were just like,
"Yeah. This is actually a huge pain point for me."
But the exact same solution, they were previously
framing it as, I think it was supercharged Excel
or something like that, and nobody was biting.
So they just changed the way they framed it and
found a different set of buyers and succeeded
that way. So yeah, no hard and fast rule, but I
think it's always you need to have this matrix of
options in your mind and be very deliberate
about which one you are going with and why.
I think your piece of advice is really important
there. Usually in your experience, you're saying
people index too far too? Like now, what they're
asking me to do is not what I think they need or
what customers will need. You're saying it's
actually more likely they're right, and that's
maybe where you should be focusing more versus
this abstract vision and original idea you had?
I think so, yeah. I think it's very hard to
not be anchored to your own experience and
your conceptions as a problem. And one thing
I've seen in really strong founders is they're
able to drop a bunch of those assumptions
and almost treat a new opportunity as a
completely blank slate. And then just
figure out how to reshape things so that
you're taking advantage of that, and that's
how you don't get stuck at a local maximum.
Your other piece of advice is also really
great. So people hear this and they're like,
"We don't afford an engineer to sit at one
customer prospects office and build stuff
for them." But your point is you can have
one for five different customers. They're
not there full time. They bounce around, but
they're... It's almost like sales engineering,
just like what you call it sparkling sales
where they help make it successful. I know
Looker is a famous example. They think they
called them forward deployed engineers. Do
you know any other companies by the way, that
some version of forward deployed engineers?
There's a lot. I mean, I know that the AR-Labs
are hiring forward deployed engineers now,
they're building forward deployed engineering
teams and they could make it work,
but I think there's going to be key
differences. I don't see Anthropic
going into an enterprise customer and building
some entirely from scratch solution for them.
It's going to be something that leverages
the Anthropic set of products. So there's
a lot of companies that have this label now,
but I think what's really confusing about,
it's just that it means a few different things.
There's another post by Ted Mabrey who's I think
the head of commercial at Palantir, and that's
a very good one too, to point with those too.
So say someone was, "I want to try this
sort of thing in my company," what would
be a few bullet points if things they should
get right? You're describing the spectrum of
what people describe as forward deployed
engineers, if they were to try to do this,
what do you think they need to most
do correctly for it to be successful?
The key things that made our model work well, one,
they were actually real engineers who could build
product themselves. That's a very big difference.
I think a lot of the time companies will say,
"This person's a forward deployed engineer," but
actually they're mostly there to be more of a
solutions architect, or they're not necessarily
building anything to know, but they're just
listening and trying to find a way of deploying
the existing product. They're not empowered to do
new product. So the really radical thing Palantir
said was, "No. Go in and if you need a completely
new product to do this, you can go ahead and build
it." And I think that's really the key difference.
The other stuff I've already mentioned, the value
of being in person, and I think building close
personal bonds with your customers. I do think
the better founders do this anyway. They're on
texting terms with their buyers, they become
friends with them outside of work, and they
see them as humans who they're trying to help. I
think this is very motivating, gaining a really
deep understanding of the business that your
customers are in and knowing how those dynamics
work. So a simple example might be, say hospitals
in America. It's very counterintuitive to think
of a hospital as a business. People think of it
as it's a place where you get healthcare, but
actually if you view it the way a COO or CMO views
it, it's going to look very, very different too.
As a very simple example, sorry, this is a little
bit dark, but how restaurants want to turn over
tables as fast as possible in order to maximize
for the day? Hospitals actually want to do the
same with patients. They would like to treat
you and then get you out of a bed so they can
free up the bed to get a new person in there. So
that's not super intuitive, unless you think hard
about how the revenue for that hospital works.
But then once you think about it, you're like,
"This has a bunch of problems associated with it."
And you start to go into really interesting...
... problems associated with it, and you
start to go in really interesting directions.
There's just like the words and memes, and take
you a long way working and understanding it.
Yes.
Okay, so essentially the things you want
to get right, make sure it's in person,
make sure the person is technical, make sure
they have a deep understanding of the business
and the problems they're having. The technical
piece is interesting with AI tools these days,
making everyone technical in some sense.
You could argue this is going to become
more common, people can just open up Cursor,
Windsurf and just start adding features.
I think this is a really interesting
thesis you've just hit on,
and I expect to see a lot more startups
that take advantage of that insight.
Basically it makes forward
deploying engineers cheaper.
Exactly.
What is the current state of forward deploying
engineers at Palantir? How much has it changed
over the past few years? If you join
now, is this still something you can do?
Yeah, of course. I should obviously emphasize
that one, I left the company in 2023, and so
this is just my personal view, I don't speak
for them. I think that if you think about it,
one of the metrics that the company had
to measure its own success was essentially
revenue per engineer, and so the more "product
leverage" you had, the higher that number was.
So if you had to throw a lot of people at every
marginal problem, then you weren't doing so well
at that because you're basically building a new
thing every single time, and you are in effect a
consulting business. If on the other hand, every
time you encounter a new customer, the product
turns out to be relevant to them, then great,
and so this product leverage metric was actually
a very unique thing and kind of a North Star
for the company for the whole time I was there.
If you reason that out, what that means
is that in the early stage of the company,
you will have a customer and then you might have
five to 10 engineers working at that customer. And
so over time you want that ratio to change. So you
want it to be each customer, because the product
is so powerful, maybe AI coding's gotten a lot
better, each customer you only need two people,
and then maybe you actually get to a point where
you can have one person looking after multiple
customers. And I think that's how the job has
changed, is now it's a little bit more about
you have multiple customers, maybe you're spending
less deep time with each individual one of them,
but it's a lot clearer what problem
you're solving across multiple customers
and you have more of a kind of defined offering.
And so I do think that has been a bit of a change,
but the company remains a very interesting and
dynamic place to be. In some sense the story's
only starting, because one lens through
which you can view this company is they
spent 20 years basically building the mother
of all data foundations for every important
institution in the world, and I guess what's
very valuable now that AI models are out is
proprietary data that isn't public. Suddenly
you have access to that and you are in a very
privileged position to help your customers
deploy AI in a way that makes them successful,
and that solves real business problems. That
is essentially the bull thesis for this company
and why it's probably going to 100X again. And so
it's still a really interesting time to join but
I do think the nature of the ratio of people to a
customer, for example, is one big difference now.
Not investment advice, but it might 100X.
I totally understand why that might happen.
So let's talk about the data piece, you said that
this was one of the secrets of Palantir's success,
this early insight into the power
of ingesting data, cleaning data,
being able to analyze and work with it. What a
marketing share there, just what they figured
out about why this is so valuable, why
it's so hard and how they achieved it?
I think it's just very obvious as soon as you
step into a corporation and spend a couple of days
there really, is you're like, all right, let's
suppose your job is to increase sales, so the
first thing you want to do is get a clear picture
of what's going on. All right, so let me go and
query the sales database. Oh wait, where's the
sales database? I can't get access to this. Okay,
I need to file an access ticket. All right, now I
have to wait one week. And so everywhere we went,
this was the big pain point, was we have to
wait six to eight weeks just to get data access,
and then when you do get data access, it's not
like the data's in an easily queryable format,
you actually really have to know what you're
doing in order to get the right metrics out,
and so on and so forth.
And so it turned out like,
okay, it's this iceberg analogy where the actual
analysis is actually just the tip of the iceberg,
it's kind of the last five or 10%, and the 95%
before that is, I am gaining access to the data,
I am cleaning the data, I'm joining the data,
I'm normalizing it, putting it all in the same
format. And so once we spotted that, then it's
like, okay, there's actually a lot of product to
be built there just to make that process easier.
People don't think of Palantir as this place where
innovative new product and UX ideas come out,
but I actually think it's been one of the most
generative companies for that specifically in the
last 20 years, it's just that most of that didn't
see the light of day and so people don't know.
But if you look at the product primitives that
they developed in order to make the things I just
mentioned a lot easier, they're actually really
valuable and interesting and could probably form
the basis of independent companies themselves.
And so, yeah, it just took every single
step of that process became much,
much easier once there was a software solution
around it. So if you talk about data ingestion,
there's essentially a universal data adapter
that's part of Foundry. It can read anything,
so JDBC, S3 buckets, whatever you want.
It allows us to look into the data,
maybe preview the first 20 rows, and then it
allows you when you're ready to set up a schedule
and just pull it in on some cadence. That process
alone for an engineer used to take a long time,
especially pre-Vibe coding, and managing all those
cron jobs and doing this analytics, VM somewhere
inside the customer's tenant was a huge pain.
And so you productize that piece, then it's like,
okay, once you have the data, it's like how do you
actually join it? What if you're non-technical? Is
there a way for a non-technical user to be able
to join tables and see what the result is? And
so there's all these very fascinating business
problems that, because I think the access was
very difficult to get, and people hadn't really
solved before, and so there was a lot of white
space to do some product innovation. So now I
would say Foundry's definitely the best data
platform in the world just because it has all
these different applications within it that solve
these discrete parts. And it came out of this,
years of painful experience, watching people have
to clean data and join it and figure out what
this table name meant and so on and so forth.
You shared in your post this kind of
evocative story of some people's jobs
is just to gate keep the data. They're there
to give you access to this very valuable data
within the organization, and how hard it
is to get. That was a lot of this work,
is just breaking through those political
battles of like, "Okay, we need this data
for the good of the company and took a lot of
work." I guess anything there you want to add?
It is, yeah. It's a huge pain, and there
are good reasons for it. It's not like
folks are malicious here. If you're IT
or if you're an InfoSec type person,
then your goal is to prevent data breaches and
to make sure that sensitive information doesn't
spread too wide. And so what's the easiest
way to do that? It's to lock the data down,
basically be a gatekeeper for access. I think
where it got a little bit more interesting was
where your skills are valuable and depend
on you being the gatekeeper. So what I mean
by that is let's say I'm the only guy who
understands the way the sales calculation
pipeline works and I write the SQL for it. All
the requests from business SMEs come to me,
I have a big queue of them, it takes me weeks
to get through this queue. I have a great job, I
have great job security, and people depend on me.
And so now along comes this company and they're
like, "Hey, actually we want to make sales data
available to everyone and we want to make it
point and click." Suddenly you're like, "Hey, hang
on, what am I going to do?" And so that's where I
think there was a lot of difficulty and I always
say people are like, what accounts as competitors?
I don't think it's the ones that you would think
of necessarily. Palantir's biggest competitor is
a company rolling its own solution, and so the
biggest difference would just be a CIO saying,
"I'm going to build my own data infrastructure,
I'm going to own it, it's going to be on top of
one of the hyperscalers, and we're all just
going to do our own analytics ourselves."
And what we came along with, which was quite
disruptive to this model, was saying, "No,
actually all your data is going to get ingested
into this one platform and everybody in your
company is going to use it." The trade-off
is it's going to be really, really easy for
everyone to do things. But as you can imagine,
some people weren't a huge fan of that model.
It feels like Glean is the biggest competitor
to Palantir after I hear this,
do you know about that company?
I do, yeah, Glean looks amazing from
the outside. So many differences there,
I can totally see why you would say this, but-
Clearly a different use case but it feels like
the reason they've been successful is they figured
out a lot of this data ingestion, permissions,
search stuff. I never thought of it that way.
Yeah.
Interesting. Okay, I want to talk about hiring,
you talked a bit about this. You're starting a
company again, what are some of the key lessons
you've learned from your time at Palantir when
you are hiring people for your company? I don't
know if you're actually hiring people
yet, maybe when you may start hiring.
Yeah, we have six people at the moment, so a
really reasonably small team. I think with hiring,
it's funny, man, there's so much hiring advice
online and you read it and you're like, "Yeah,
this is super obvious." And then when you live it,
you're suddenly like, "Aah, this is why people say
this." So a few simple examples are I think the
thing that is really hard to find is somebody who
really, really has a lot about doing the thing and
will go that kind of extra 20%. I think when you
hire out, especially not to pick on them, but I
think if you hired a [inaudible 01:00:17] right,
it's like people want a 400K a year job, they
would like to work a certain number of hours,
they would like to ship some code and then
go home, that's basically the model that
you get accustomed to even if you don't
intend to when you work at a big company.
And so if you hire out of that for a really small
startup, it can be really challenging because
a lot of your success as a startup depends
on each individual person being like, "No,
I'm really going to, I'm work this evening if
that's what it takes to get this thing working,
and I'm not just going to check my boxes, I'm
actually going to look towards what is the real
outcome that this business is trying to achieve."
And everything I'm saying feels kind of obvious,
but when you actually feel that difference
between somebody who's just checking the boxes
and somebody who's kind of an animal in this way,
they'll actually go and pursue and accomplish the
end outcome, that difference is very, very
big and it matters so much for your first 20
people. And there's no science to finding these
people. It's not like you can just put somebody
who cares about outcomes in your JD and then
suddenly you'll get all these people applying.
So then it's like, okay, well how do you
screen for that and how do you find those
types of people? And so that's where it gets
really interesting. I think that's where the
mission alignment comes in, and so you do have
to find people who, for what you are doing,
have this extra maybe private reason to care about
it a little bit more than the average person.
So I think for Palantir, they did hire a
lot of vets, for example, or maybe people
who were a little bit more patriotic or
pro-America than the average tech employee,
and those people had an extra reason to Palantir
and an extra reason to try that little bit harder.
And so what I'm doing is a little bit more in the
kind of medical and health space, and so I think
people who have themselves had experiences
with this system have maybe had relatives
go through difficult experiences with things
like cancer or whatever it is. They're just
that extra bit motivated to really care about
the thing you're trying to do and then work that
little bit harder, and so I think aggressively
filtering early on to things like mission fit,
how much have you cared about stuff
in the past, and what's an example.
You ask questions like, what's the hardest you've
ever worked to get something done and why? And
that does differentiate a lot of people, a lot of
people don't actually have a great answer to that.
So I would say that's been a really big learning,
is it's less about testing for the right skills,
yes, that's important, two it's much
more about just who has that extra 20%.
That is really interesting, everything you've
shared is essentially around motivation, and
drive, and passion, and kind of just commitment
to working on this intently, and it's almost like
a second thought of just like, oh, also they're
really smart and skilled at stuff. It feels like
that's just table stakes and this is actually
what makes the difference in your experience.
Yeah, I totally agree, and I think it's different
for every business. So I think if you're in a
space like B2B SaaS where maybe it's a little
harder to tell the story of like, oh, this is
so mission-critical, whatever, there are other
ways of getting at this thing. So for example, I
know a lot of people, again, it's a little played
out now, but I know a lot of people who for sales
teams, they will explicitly go for people who were
professional athletes or played sports in college,
and it's like, okay, what does that test for?
It's like you are very, very disciplined,
you're very, very goals and numbers oriented
and you're willing to just work really,
really hard. And so there's all these kind
of lateral ways of getting at these qualities
that I think you just have to be intentional
about as a founder. As a personal example,
I'm a runner and so I actually love meeting fellow
runners and I kind of joke like, "Oh, maybe I'll
go higher from run clubs or something like that."
But it's just same with I play a lot of chess,
I love meeting chess players. I'm not necessarily
saying that's the right kind of hire for me,
but I think having this thing of here
are some traits that seem uncorrelated,
but which actually give you good signal to this
person's personality, those are actually really
important. The last thing I'll say just as a
funny illustration of that concept is I think Max
Levchin tells the story of somebody interviewing
at PayPal early on and he passed all the skill
interviews and then it just got to the final round
and he said something about liking to shoot hoops,
like he liked to play basketball, and they
were like instant reject. The vibe here was
like if you're not a mega Linux nerd, hardcore
computer person, then we don't want you here,
even if you actually passed all the tests just
because you like to shoot hoops. Now whether that
was the right call or the wrong call, don't know,
but that's an example of what I'm talking about.
I think that's a great echo back. People hearing
this may be like, "What the hell? How dare they
do that?" But this is exactly what you said at
the beginning of our conversation, that like an
approach to building a generational business is
to be very clear about who this is not for, and
that's okay, it's your company, not everyone needs
to work there. And it's almost saving them time
because they might realize this isn't for me, this
isn't the people I want to be around necessarily.
So I think it's important to see that side of
it, is it's your business, it's important to
be clear about who is a good fit for the company
and who's not. Speaking of that, let's talk about
product management for a bit. I know Palantir
PMs are not traditional product managers. I
imagine people have the title, Product Manager at
Palantir, okay, so if so, as far as you understand
what's the difference between say a PM at Palantir
versus a traditional PM say at a FANG company?
Palantir was, as far as I remember, quite
anti-PM for a while and eventually we did
need them because we just got more
serious about product testing.
Classic story, classic story.
A classic story.
In many companies,
The big difference or one big difference I
noticed was that they were extremely careful
about only making people PMs who had first proven
themselves out as forward deploying engineers. You
basically could not become a PM any other way.
So as an example, when I mentioned earlier the
thing that we built for the plane factory,
the person who was managing that deployment,
she later became the PM for ontology, and it
was just because she'd kind of proven her method
in the field. And the reason for that's pretty
simple, it's going to be someone who understand
how customers work and has that customer empathy,
and it's going to be someone who has this drive
to get things done because that's what BD selected
for. I think the failure mode that they were very,
very averse to in traditional PMs was this
kind of Google Docs syndrome of like, okay,
I'm going to write my product requirement
documents, and I'm going to manage it in
this very sort of sane, rational way I think,
so the company was really rigorous about that.
And so basically PMs were almost always
internal promotions and they always came from
BD. I am not aware of a single case where we took
somebody who was a PM at a place like Google,
which produces many excellent PMs and hired
them successfully into Palantir, it's just
a very different vibe. So I think that was one
thing. This is maybe more of a classic PM trait,
but you just had to be either an engineer yourself
or extremely good at working with engineers, and
the ones I saw who succeeded the most were just
best friends with their engineering team. And the
team would always just be like one, it was called
the group pm and then it would be a lot of very,
very good engineers. And basically the success
or failure mode was just do the engineers and
trust you? I mentioned before Palantir how is
very almost disagreeable personalities, and so
if you didn't gain the trust of engineering
team pretty fast, you didn't last very long.
I think we've cracked the question of why are
Palantir PM's so successful? First of all,
the hiring bar is just basically hiring for
leaders in a lot of different ways, to this,
I don't know, forge for founders where they're
working with a company solving a real problem,
building a real product that makes money, and
then those are the people that become the PMs
at Palantir and then they go on to leave and
that's why 30% of them end up starting companies,
I'm surprised it's not higher, or become first
PMs at other companies or heads of product.
Yeah, absolutely, it's crazy. I was part
of a pretty small team within Palantir,
I think it was 20 to 25 people when I joined,
and I think at least six of them now are either
unicorn or just pre-unicorn founders from that
group of 25 people, which is actually a crazy
ratio. And then a bunch more have become
founders recently at an earlier stage,
so yeah, there's all these little pockets of
excellence and it's been really interesting to
see. I think the other thing that's driving that
a little bit is when you leave, it's just such
an interesting company to work at that I think
the retention numbers were actually very high
for that company. People would often stay a lot
longer than maybe the average Valley tenure. And
so when you left, it was really this decision of
just something very specific is pulling you and
you want to kind of play the next level of the
game, and so it was very unusual for someone to
leave and then join maybe a more traditional tech
company. It's sort of like you're either going to
go become a founder or why would you leave when
there's so many interesting different things to
work on? And I know that sounds a little
culty, but that's what everyone thinks.
I could totally see that. A lot of people
that left Airbnb have never found something
more meaningful, it's just hard, especially if
you're early. There's a stat that I didn't share
that I think is really interesting, and when you
look at YC founders and where they've come from,
I think you maybe shared in your post that
there's more YC ex-Palantir founders than
there are ex-Google founders in spite of Google
being something like 50 times bigger sample size.
Yeah, yeah.
Let's talk about the moral question of Palantir.
A lot of people probably seeing the title of
this episode, hearing this, will not be excited
about Palantir being highlighted and promoted,
a lot of people kind of disagree with
what Palantir's doing. Builds products
that kill people in some ways, they work
with governments they don't agree with. I
know you wrote a really insightful way
of how you approach this question when
you decided to work at Palantir and how
you see people tackle with this, can you
just talk about the framework that you landed
on and how you thought about this yourself?
Yeah, it's a really interesting topic, it's
definitely very nuanced. I think what I was
trying to say in that post was a couple of things.
One was that there was a lot of upside there. So
I worked on the US Covid response, I have friends
who worked on Operation Warp Speed, and these are
all things that I think saved a lot of lives, and
I was pretty focused while I was working at NIH on
cancer research. And so to me, these were just
obviously good things and you couldn't do them
anywhere else, and so that was alone a reason
to stay. The question I had in that post was,
well, okay, there are definitely going to
be other pieces of this that people object
to. So during the 2016 to 2020 era, it became a
pretty common thing to go into work in New York
and you'd have people protesting outside your
office or doing all kinds of things. And so
there was this question of, well, is this okay?
And I think the point I was trying to make was
it's rare that disengagement is the correct
answer, and I think it's more recognized now,
but especially then it went a bit too far.
So the famous example here is Google kind
of disengaging with a Pentagon AI project just
because some people felt that working with the
Pentagon was itself morally bad. I think that's
a way to sort of the left of what the median
American would say, I think the median American
would say it's fine to work on defense stuff
within reason and assuming you're doing largely
good things, and so there was just this kind of
almost arbitrage there at some point of just hang
on, it's not like working on defense is inherently
evil, it's actually a pretty interesting thing.
And then there's this question of, well, would
you rather be in the room and making this better
or not? And so I'm struggling with how much I can
share here, but as a simple example, if you're
doing even a workflow, which I think many people
would not be super comfortable with, let's say
you're targeting somebody for some kind of strike.
If you compare the way it's done now to maybe
the way it was done in 2010, it's going to be
a lot more targeted, it's going to be a lot more
accurate, and so you've actually improved that
process and reduced the chance of error. Maybe
you should feel good about that, right? Now, that
is a bullet many people are not willing to bite.
I didn't work on the defense side of the company
myself, but I think you have to be okay with
these kinds of grade zones and actually actively
thinking about what you are doing. And that
doesn't mean that it's always the right thing
to do to work in a defense company. Maybe we
go into a very dark future and we start being
the bad guys in some ways, and then it's probably
not a great idea to work at a defense company. So
it's a shifting landscape but I kind of felt
pretty strongly that a lot of people in tech
just didn't want to think about this at all.
So you have engineers now who are working on
optimizing short form videos for higher
engagement, and you sort of want to say
to them like, "Hey, are you thinking about what
this is doing to the brains of young children?"
Or "Have you seen an 11-year-old kind of scrolling
something for five hours and do you think this is
a good thing?" And I think people don't want to
think about this stuff too much. I'm not saying
I know the answer, but there was almost this
refusal to look at what tech was doing from a
political lens for a very long time. It was just
like, "Hey, let us play with our toys, let us sit
in our little park, and don't bother us, and we're
just going to build cool stuff and launch it."
And 2025, we're in a very, very different state
of the world, tech is involved in politics now,
and politics basically came to tech. There's this
famous image of Mark Zuckerberg, he's sitting in
Congress and he kind of looks very pale, and he's
like, "Why have they dragged me in here again?"
But I think tech went through this journey of,
oh, we're suddenly becoming important now, oh,
we're really, really important now, oh, we better
stop playing this game of politics. And so I think
what I'm saying now is a lot more consensus
than it was 10 years ago, but at the time,
the feeling was just like, "Look what we are doing
is political, so you better engage with that."
I think when this became really real for
a lot of people is with the Ukraine War,
the government's running out of certain vehicles
and ammunition, we're just not able to produce it,
and then we're like, "Oh, thank God for a company
like Anduril and all these other tech companies
that are actually ahead and keeping us ahead." I
think the only reason the US is ahead of that...
And keeping us ahead. I think the only reason
the US is ahead of China and the space race
is because SpaceX just is one company
that just has been doing this for a long
time. So I think a lot of people have kind of
realized, okay, maybe we need these things.
Right. And I would make this argument as well,
it's like people are like, well, how can you feel
good about working in defense? And it's like,
well, you're not going to feel great if China
invades Taiwan, actually, you're not going
to. I think you are probably also not going
to like that outcome. So we do just live in this
world where you do need to build up deterrents to
these things and they better be good. So to me,
it didn't feel that difficult of a question. I
think when you zoom into particular things, they
can be very difficult questions and there have
been a bunch of those in the last couple of years.
But yeah, again, disengagement isn't the answer.
Yeah. And again, it's not for everyone. I think
that's an important kind of theme through this
conversation is some companies ... like, to
build ... sometimes to build a generational,
really successful company, you need to turn
some people off because that's what brings
in the best talent oftentimes.
Okay. Just a few more questions.
Kind of like stepping back a little bit. You're
building a company again. What are a few core
pieces of advice that you're bringing to your
new startup that will inform how you build this
company, from your experience at Palantir? We
talked about a lot of stuff. Is there anything,
I don't know if there are three
things that you think are like,
"I'm definitely going to do these things this
way because it worked really well at Palantir."
One thing is probably just
really fast iteration cycles.
So placing a lot of bets and then being
really rigorous about just going through
that cycle very soon. I have this [inaudible
01:16:40]principles, and one of the things
on there is basically saying EOP successes
goes up the more bets you make, and it's sort
of a function of how many bets you make and the
probability of success of those individual bets,
right? And so one easy way to almost guarantee
that you'll hit something is just to make a lot
of bets and then just kind of cycle through them
very quickly. Now, obviously this is difficult,
often this question of, well, is this bet actually
failing or are we quitting too soon, kind of
thing. But that's kind of one principle I take,
is just test this thing very early. You know,
like the classic "why feed, why see" thing is just
when you take something to a customer, ask them to
pay you a lot of money and [inaudible 01:17:22]
then find a new problem. Don't wait three weeks,
which is what every founding team typically
does because you don't have that kind of time.
I do think the importance of just having a
really tight, distinctive internal culture and
building a strong feeling of trust within a
team is really important. And kind of like you
mentioned with Airbnb, and people definitely felt
this at Palantir, there was this feeling of like,
well, you worked here, you must be good. I
trust you, and all of that. And I think it's
so important to create that and you kind of know
that feeling. That's what ... like, people ask me,
should I go work at place X or should I just
go be a founder straightaway? I don't know
the answer for everyone, but I will say one of
the benefits of working at a place like that is
you just have all these internal benchmarks now
for, okay, this is what this should feel like,
and if it doesn't feel like that, we're off. And
I can't imagine not having those benchmarks and
just kind of having to figure it all out.
So yeah, I think that thing, too, is just
distinctive, internal, strong team culture.
And then I think for me, think three is just
working with a really messy part of the real
world. So I kind of joked when I left, like,
I am excited to just do pure software. I'm
excited to, I don't know, I want to build
an ID or something and just not have a support
email even and all of that. But it turned out,
look, my comparative advantage in a lot of ways
was the networks I'd built and the experience
I'd had in engaging with the messy parts of the
world. And they do need technology a lot, right?
There's this horrifying thought I have sometimes
of just like, maybe we'll get ATI in the next two
years and the healthcare sector will still
be broken and it will still be impossible to
afford rent in New York City and build houses
and all these things. And that may well become
true. And so I think it's important to engage with
those parts of the world too, even though they're
really, really challenging. And I think the really
nice thing about LLMs is that actually, there's so
many workflows now that are accessible to you as
a tech founder and people are somehow more open to
working with tech companies than they ever were
before. Selling into the sectors of the economy
in 2015, incredibly hard. I think now post the
ChatGPT moment, people are willing to give chances
to small startups that they weren't willing to do
previously. As you mentioned earlier, the cost of
doing things like forward-deployed engineering
has fallen by maybe five to 10 x now at least.
And so there's a lot of new possibilities
and I'm excited to engage with the best.
Wow, that is some alpha right there
that you're finding, that some of these
very large organizations are more open to
working with startups, because classically,
investors don't want to invest in companies
that are going after healthcare companies and
governments and things like that. So it
is really interesting actually to hear.
I'm going to mirror back the tips you just shared,
and there's actually a secondary tip that I think
is the more interesting piece. So the first
thing you're taking away is iterate quickly,
but I love your tip of ask for lots of
money quickly, early, to see if it's
an actual idea that people will pay lots of
money for. And if not, move on. I love that.
The other is build a very distinct culture, but
the piece you share there that I love even more is
this idea of knowing what a high bar looks like,
knowing what awesome A plus people look like,
and you need to work at a company like Palantir
to actually see that. So the advice there I
feel is just work at a company that is amazing,
first, with the best talent, to understand what
that should look like, plus you build a network of
those folks. So I think that's really interesting.
And then the other pieces of advice you're
pulling away is work on really hard,
messy problems because that's where the biggest
opportunities are, and it's sounding like this
is the easiest time to actually do that. Amazing.
Okay. I'm going to take us to a recurring theme on
this podcast called AI Corner. And what we do in
AI Corner is we share some way that .. and this
is you sharing ... some way that you've found
AI to be useful in your day- to-day, either in
life or in work. Is there any way you found some
tool ... some AI tool useful that you can share?
Oh my gosh, there are so many. I'll give you a
few examples. So I use Wispr Flow quite a bit.
So this is the talk to your keyboard and it
will transcribe for you app. Very good. It's
just great when you are iterating very quickly
with an LLM and sometimes you have to do these
paragraph-long prompts and it's just easier
to speak into them. So Wispr Flow, I like.
Just to double down on that, you
press a button and you start talking-
Yeah.
And it's writing out what you're saying. Cool. And
there have been these products for a long time,
Dragon Dictate and all these guys. Is
the difference now these are just very,
very good now at actually
transcribing what you're saying?
I think that's right. Yeah, they use
a really good model and so it rarely
makes mistakes even when I think
it's quite challenging. And then,
yeah, the UX I think they just
nailed. So that's really good one.
I love Claude Code for developing. Even
though I have my complaints about it,
there's something just very addictive about
just telling it what to do. And it's basically
something that you run within the terminal of
your computer, and so you just type Claude,
it opens up the Claude interface. It's very
cute, it's very beautifully designed, and you
just tell it what to do. And it actually operates
on the file system directly. So if you're like,
"Hey, create a bunch of these files," that'll
just do it and you don't need to go and muck
around inside Finder yourself. And then it'll do
these really complicated pull requests and it'll
basically execute them quite well. So to me, this
is a very exciting kind of preview of AI agents.
That's what I was going to ask.
So this is essentially an AI agent
engineer. I didn't know that's
what Claude Code did. Very cool.
Yeah. It's sort of a guided agent, but yeah,
it is really sweet. And then yeah, I'm just
enjoying ... you know, every week there's a new,
wonderful new thing to play with. Last seven days,
I've been testing Gemini Pro 2.5. Excellent
model. I don't love Google's UX sometimes,
but I was playing with that. And I use LLMs
every day for all kinds of things. The other
day I was doing taxes and I needed to classify
a bunch of transactions based on some metadata,
and so I just wrote a script up
really quickly and it did that. So.
I love just the smile on your face as you're
describing all these AI tools. I think a lot
of people are just like, holy shit, I'm just
overwhelmed with all the things I need to be
paying attention to. All these things I'm
hearing, all these tools I got to try.
And I love just this vibe of just like, this
is incredible and so fun. We need more of that.
Okay. I'm going to take us to
another recurring segment on the
podcast. You're going to get a double
whammy. Contrarian Corner. So here's
the question. What's something that you
believe that most other people don't?
I think going to college is great. I think
this is a somewhat contrarian view within tech,
maybe not in the broader economy, but I often see
people saying just like, oh, if you can just drop
out when you're 18 and just start working, why
would you go to college? And I think this is
completely wrong, but maybe it's good advice for
5% of the population who probably would've been to
your fellows anyway. But college is one of the few
times when you can just make really, really deep
friendships. You are in typically a nice campus.
If you're in North America, you get to spend all
of your time just thinking and writing papers and
reading books and hanging out with your friends.
And it's actually very precious and it's very
hard to find that kind of time after you turn
21 because you got to pay your rent, you've got
to work, you've got to do all this stuff. Let's
say you make a bunch of money, you take a career
break, it's still ... all your friends are working
and you always feel like there's a ticking
time or on top of your head or something.
So just taking those three or four years at the
very beginning and going really deep on lots
of different intellectual topics and being able
to try different things and discover more about
yourself. I'm a big college fan. I can't comment
on the ROI or whatever. I personally think the
ROI is great, even though the fees are kind of
high in the U.S., but that's probably my kind
of contrarian within tech view is don't drop out
of college unless you have a really good reason.
It's so funny that that is contrarian
and it does sound contrarian. I had a
great time in college here. Here. Okay. Is
there anything else, Nabeel, that you wanted
to share or leave listeners with before we
get to our very exciting lightning round?
No, I think it's a really exciting time in
the world. I think AI can be exhausting,
but it does really just open up the possibility
of building a better world in all these ways.
And so I think just reassess what you're doing
every couple of months and make sure that it's
aligned with where I think AI is going and make
sure that you are working on something that you
feel has very high potential if it succeeds.
And I think that's more important than ever now
just because the amount of leverage we have with
technology is at the highest point in history.
Let me double click on that real quick. So for
people that want to do what you're describing,
what helps you understand where AI is
heading and just kind of align with it,
are there places of information and news you find
useful? Is it just play with it kind
of thing? What would you recommend?
This is the big question. I use X a lot to keep
on top of AI, so I would just recommend finding
a good Twitter list and maybe following people off
of that. There's some good newsletters. I really
like Latent Space, I know his X handle, it's
Swyx, S-W-Y-X. I can't remember his actual name,
but that one is very good and it's pretty
technical. I would recommend trying to stick
to the more technical newsletters if possible. I
think there's a lot of philosophy about AI or AI
policy type stuff, and I think that's good if
that's your area, but it's an area where it's
very easy to have a lot of takes on it. You're
not necessarily learning a lot by reading those.
But I think it's just important to know what's
going on and make sure you are revisiting your
own workflows as often as possible. And just
making sure that the people who went here are
going to be the kind of hybrid cyborgs who fuse
with the AIs. This actually played out in chess,
if I can take a slight detour, is the chess
players who succeeded the most in the mid 2010s
especially were the ones who were really early
adopters of neural network based chess engines.
So when DeepMind did that thing, there was very
quickly an open source version of it called Leela,
and you find basically the very top
players like Magnus Carlson, Fabiano,
they were the ones who kind of mind melded the
most with Leela and learned how it played and
then kind of started copying its moves.
And so I think just becoming a cyborg to
the extent that you can. And then I
think there's this barbell thing of,
it's also important to just leave everything at
go touch grass just for your own mental sanity.
Excellent advice. And with that, Nabeel,
we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
Yes.
Here we go. What are two or three books that you
find yourself recommending most to other people?
The first one that comes to mind is Impro by
Keith Johnstone. This is actually ... I wrote
about it in that essay. It's one of the books
that [inaudible 01:28:36] used to send to people.
I just think it's a really interesting book. So
nominally speaking, it's about improvisational
theater, which I believe this guy was a pioneer
of. He was a British guy, Keith Johnstone,
active between the '60s and the 80s I think.
And Impro is just this really interesting book
about creativity and how social behavior works and
basically just what he taught his improv students.
It's a very weird book. It's full of these
unbelievably strange ideas. There's a lot of very
tactical things he tells you to do in the first
chapter, for example, just to break out of your
own mental frameworks, really just wild stuff.
He'll tell you to walk backwards while counting
down from a hundred and think about some problem
that you're struggling with and there's all these
kind of odd things. But the number of ideas per
page I've found on that book is extremely high.
The concepts about how social interaction works
and how things like status and so on play into
your social behavior are super important. And they
made every kind of fully deployed engineer read
that for the simple reason that I think it just
helps you kind of read people better and interact
with them better and become more conscious of
how you are coming across and just modulate that.
What is the title again?
Impro.
Impro. Okay, cool. We'll link
into it in the show notes.
Yeah, so Impro is number one. I think
just to go a little more highbrow,
maybe Shakespeare's history plays, there's a set
of them called the Henriad, so like Henry IV,
Henry V, Henry VI. I find most people don't
read these, so they'll read Hamlet or Macbeth
or whatever, but the Henry one is absolutely
incredible. You don't have to be interested
in British monarchy or British history in
order to enjoy them. They're actually some
of the most interesting and insightful books
I've read about power and how power works and
politics and what the sacrifices that you might
have to make if you want to be a successful
king in that case. But it transfers over.
I think it is worth thinking really hard about,
I think especially in a world where everything
is kind of organized around these prominent
figures and personalities now. When you
think about the current administration,
you think Trump, Elon, or when you think
about AI, you think of Sam Dario, right?
And so I think it's important to understand, how
do you think about these personalities and yeah,
the kind of game that they're playing.
And Henry is actually ... the Henriad is
an incredible kind of set of books around that.
They're also easy to read, which sounds hilarious
when I say it, but you can read a Shakespeare
play in a day. They're sort of ... I don't know,
they're like 50 pages long. It's not that
bad. You have to get used to the language.
Yes. But I would recommend that for sure.
I guess you asked for two to three. I love
High Output Management by Andy Grove. I just
think that's a great business book, and people
tend to read summaries of it on the internet more
than they actually read the book. But the actual
book has a lot of really interesting stories and
explanations about ... I think the most powerful
thing about that book is actually how Andy Grove
thinks, and less any of the specific tactics
there. And I think you don't get that unless
you read how he came up with all these things.
Your first two books were extremely out there
versus what other people have recommended,
and the third book was the most
recommended book on this podcast.
So I love that spectrum that we just
went on. Perfect. Okay, next question.
Do you have a favorite recent movie or
TV show that you've just really enjoyed?
The last movie I really loved was a Decision to
Leave. It's a Korean movie. It's by the Director
of Old Boy, which maybe some people have heard
of. It's a great movie. I think it was released
a couple years ago and the basic premise is,
there's a detective who is investigating a
woman who's accused of killing her husband,
and he gradually starts falling for her,
which starts to affect his judgment in all
these ways. Just a really fascinating kind of
psychological thriller with a sort of romantic
element to it. Visually, very beautiful. Yeah,
I think a lot of the most interesting movies
nowadays come from abroad actually. So East Asia,
South Asia, places like that. TV, I don't
watch so much yet. It's been a while.
Totally understandable for a founder.
Okay, next question. Do you have a
favorite product that you've recently
discovered that you just really love?
It could be an app, it could be something
physical, it could be a water bottle.
I don't have a good answer to that
one. I guess I don't buy enough stuff.
Fully acceptable. There's no wrong
answers in the lightning round. Moving on,
do you have a favorite life motto that
you often find useful in work or in
life that you come back to, that
you share with friends or family?
So there's this architect called Christopher
Alexander who wrote these beautiful books
that are about beauty and kind of more than
architecture. And he was a teacher at UC,
Berkeley, and he got really frustrated with
the students because he just felt like they
were always turning in kind of average work.
And so he would always tell them every week,
imagine there's a gothic cathedral in France
called Charge. And he would say, you have to
aim for Charge. You have to make something that
is better than that. That should be your goal,
not to just turn in something that's what you
feel is good enough. You actually have to try
and be better than the very, very best that ever
did it. And I find myself just repeating this a
lot to myself. It's just aim for that, really
try and do that. Otherwise, it's very easy
to anchor on something right in the middle.
And you do this unconsciously all the time.
So is that the motto, just aim for Charge?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I love that. Most people have no idea what that
would be, but with the context is quite powerful.
Final question, what's a classic novel that `you
think would be most valuable for product builders?
My favorite novel is Anna Karenina, and I
would recommend that everyone read Erica.
I'm reading that right now.
I've never read it before.
No way. And yeah, so it's by Leo Tolstoy. It's
this epic 19th century Russian novel that follows
a set of characters across society. And I think
it's just extraordinary because what's amazing
about him is he's just able to imagine himself
into the brain of anybody. And so even ... he
will briefly just go into the consciousness of,
I don't know, the servant who's bringing the meal
to the table or something like that. And he'll
just tell you a page of what they were thinking,
and then he'll just flip back into his
main character's head. And I think that
is the most impressive demonstration
of this kind of skill I've ever seen.
And I think, to connect it to your question,
this is what you have to do if you're going to
be really good at product, is you have to really
think yourself into the other person's head,
and you have to be really seeing it the way
that they do. And it's so hard, especially as
a founder or product person, not to just get
stuck on your own way of seeing the problem,
right? You wrote up this doc, you made these
marks. You're like, this is going to be great.
And then you take it to somebody, they don't
care that much. You really have to exercise
your empathy and understand why they see it
that way and what they actually care about.
What a beautiful way to bring it all together.
Let me also add, while I'm reading the book,
something ... a tip here is, people talk about
having Chat GPT voice mode, just kind of sitting
there next to you. I found that extremely helpful
with this book where I just ask what the hell does
this thing mean? There's all these Russian
dances and balls and etiquette. You just ask
and you're like, I'm reading Anna Karenina,
what does this mean? And it just tells you.
Yes.
So there's another cool tip for
AI. Okay. With that, Nabeel,
this was incredible. Two final questions
in case people want to look you up. Where
can they find you online and how
can listeners be useful to you?
Find me online, my website is nabeelqu.co and my
X handle is Nabeel QU, I'm probably most active on
that, but yeah, my website has
all the links and a bunch of
essays and interesting stuff. How can you
help me? I would say send me an email. My
email is on my website. Introduce yourself,
say hi. I love meeting people. I don't always
have time for coffees nowadays or things
like that, but I genuinely do get a lot
of energy from just receiving emails from
interesting people, so please do reach out.
Awesome. Definitely check out Nabeel's
Principles. Is that the name of that post?
Yeah.
Great. Okay. That's one to start with, and
then also there's the Palantir Post that we
just talked through. Okay. Nabeel,
thank you so much for being here.
Thank you. Appreciate it, Lenny.
Bye everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.