We would have a conversation with
founders, you're saying like, "Gosh,
I'm almost embarrassed to ask this question,
but who exactly is your target customer?" And
three co-founders have three different answers.
After these hundreds of
teams that we've worked with,
we've seen that there's one failure mode,
which is they don't know what that set
of basics are. Then there's this other
failure mode where they never test it.
Let's talk about the Foundation Sprint. Walk us
through the process. How does
it start? What are the steps?
The very beginning of your project, we
recommend this kind of crazy idea that
you clear your calendar. So the core team
come together for 10 hours roughly and go
through a sequence of activities so that we
can make all of the key decisions together.
I think a lot of people wonder as
they're hearing this is why don't
I just build something and launch it and learn?
One phenomenon we've seen when teams are building
things really quickly with AI is that the more
AI-generated or assisted they are, the more
generic they tend to turn out. Put yourself in
a situation where you can slow down and do some
hard thinking, some deep thinking about what's
actually going to make your product unique. Going
fast can actually slow you down in the long run.
Today my guests are Jake Knapp and John
Zeratsky. The framework that Jake and
John share in this conversation is basically
the missing manual for founders and product
teams trying to refine and test their startup or
product idea. It's called the Foundation Sprint,
and it emerged out of the famous Design
Sprint, which Jake and JZ co-created,
and also from working with over 300 teams,
building both new product at startups and
also with teams at larger companies like Google,
Microsoft, YouTube, Slack, Uber, and many more.
They published a book with this framework
at the beginning of this year called Click,
and the excerpt from that book that dives
into this framework is one of my most popular
posts of all time and is one of the rare
non-AI posts amongst the top post rankings.
In this conversation, make sure to get your
pencils out because we go through exactly how
to execute this two-day sprint, where at the end
of it you have a very clear hypothesis that your
entire team is aligned around that clarifies
what you're building, who you're building for,
how it differentiates from competitors, and how to
quickly test it with real potential customers. The
two days that you invest in a sprint might be the
highest ROI days in the history of your product,
and I highly encourage you to do this if
you're in the process of baking an idea.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. Also, if you become
an annual subscriber of my newsletter, you get
a year free of a bunch of amazing products
including Bolt, Linear, Superhuman, Notion,
Perplexity, Granola, and more. Check it out at
lennysnewsletter.com and click Bundle. With that,
I bring you Jake Knapp and John Zeratsky.
This episode is brought to you by Brex,
the financial stack used by one in every three US
venture-backed startups. Brex knows that nearly
40% of startups fail because they run out of cash,
so they built a banking experience that focuses
on helping founders get more from every dollar.
It's a stark difference from traditional banking
options that leave a startup's cash sitting
idle while chipping away at it with fees. To
help founders protect cash and extend runway,
Brex combined the best things about checking,
Treasury, and FDIC insurance in one powerhouse
account. You can send and receive money
worldwide at lightning speed, you can get 20x the
standard FDIC protection through program banks,
and you can earn industry-leading yield from
your first dollar while still being able to
access your funds anytime. To learn more,
check out Brex at brex.com/banking-solutions.
That's brex.com/banking-solutions.
Many of you're building AI products, which
is why I am very excited to chat with Brandon
Foo, founder and CEO of Paragon. Hey, Brandon.
Hey, Lenny. Thanks for having me.
So integrations have become a big
deal for AI products. Why is that?
Integrations are mission critical
for AI for two reasons. First,
AI products need contacts from their customers
business data, such as Google Drive files,
Slack messages, or CRM records. Second, for AI
products to automate work on behalf of users,
AI agents need to be able to take action
across these different third-party tools.
So where does Paragon fit into all of this?
Well, these integrations are a pain to
build, and that's why Paragon provides
an embedded platform that enables engineers
to ship these product integrations in just
days instead of months across every use case
from RAG data ingestion to agentic actions.
And I know from firsthand experience
that maintenance is even harder than
just building it for the first time.
Exactly. We believe product teams should focus
engineering efforts and competitive advantages,
not integrations. That's why
companies like You.com, AI21,
and hundreds of others use Paragon to
accelerate their integration strategy.
If you want to avoid wasting months
of engineering on integrations that
your customers need, check out
Paragon at useparagon.com/lenny.
Jake and JZ, thank you so much for
being here and welcome to the podcast.
Hey, Lenny. Thanks for having us.
Yeah, thanks so much for having us
on again. This is always a treat.
This is going to be a very tactical conversation.
We're going to be going through how to actually
execute a Foundation Sprint. And the reason
that I'm excited to do this is you guys shared
an excerpt from your book where you initially
shared this whole concept. It's called Click.
You shared this in my newsletter and I
was just looking at it, and that excerpt,
that post is amongst the top 10 most popular posts
of all time in my newsletter, which is especially
special because it's not an AI-oriented, it's one
of the few non-AI posts that are near the top 10,
which just tells me how valuable this is to
people. And consistently it has sat there, it
hasn't been usurped, it just continues to climb.
So I'm really excited to just have a conversation
where we share actually how to do this.
Let me just start with the beginning,
just a little backstory on how the Foundation
Sprint came to be. I know it emerged out of
the now very famous Design Sprint, which
you guys also developed. So just give us
a very brief overview of just how this came
to be, this idea of this Foundation Sprint.
Well, maybe I'll start by talking about the
Design Sprint part because it is essential
to understanding the Foundation Sprint.
And the Design Sprint first developed,
I had been working at the beginning of my career
at Microsoft for a few years. Went to Google,
which is like 2007, 2008, 2009, and was working on
the Gmail team, was working on some projects that
were just executing well, delivering, shipping.
But I had this other project, a side project that
had been going on for three years with a couple of
colleagues, was going nowhere, and it looked like
their office was going to get shut down after
the financial crisis. They were in Stockholm.
I went there for a week. We cleared our calendars
for the week, and we created a prototype of this,
this thing because we decided, look, we're
never going to get anywhere. We've tried
making the perfect pitch. We've tried to
make the ideal PRD, we've tried to show
the ideal design, and we can't. Perfection is
not working. We're not able to align people,
we're not able to get executive support for
this thing. We couldn't convince Larry and
Sergey and Eric that they should fund this thing.
In that week in Stockholm, we created a prototype
instead. We decided you know what? Forget it.
We're just going to build something and put it
in people's hands, put it in our fellow Googlers
hands. And that prototype was what became Google
Meet. It was this video conferencing tool
that you could use in the web browser.
No big deal.
Yeah, it was really cool. I mean, the outcome
of that, that's definitely probably the most
productive week I've ever had. But the thing that
struck me at the time and in hindsight was, wow,
it was so different to clear the calendar
for a week and have the entire focal point
of every person on the team be how do we create a
prototype that's so real, that works so well that
people will think it's real, that they'll react
like it's real, that they'll want it? And we were
in survival mode. We were trying to keep that
office from getting shut down. But the notion
that maybe you could repeat that and recreate
that is what led me to create the Design Sprint.
So for a couple of years at Google, I start
running these one-week programs with teams trying
to go at the beginning of a project from zero to a
prototype at the end that we can sort of evaluate,
test. And then I went to go work at Google
Ventures. So separate, one of the Alphabet
companies we're investing in startups. I meet John
Zeratsky and we start running these design sprints
with, well, it turned out to be over the course
of five years, I don't know, couple hundred teams
working in the early days with founders, in the
early days of their establishing the product for
the first time, trying to build it from zero
to one or launching a new marketing campaign,
a new ad campaign, some big high-risk endeavor.
We'd get to work alongside them for a week.
And we ended up refining this process into a
recipe. So across five days, it's map, sketch,
decide, prototype, and test, one big focal
point for each day. So at the end of the week,
you've got a tested prototype and you learn
are we on the right track or not? And that's
the Design Sprint. That's kind of the
prologue, the backstory to this thing.
And then after a few years at Google Ventures,
John and I left and eventually together with
our co-founder, Eli Blee-Goldman,
we started our own venture firm,
Character Capital. And that's kind where
the story of the Foundation Sprint comes in.
Okay, awesome. JZ, anything you wanted to add?
One of our goals, probably our biggest goal for
starting our own VC firm was that we wanted to be
able to focus on just the kinds of companies and
the stage of company-building that was the most
fun to us, but also was where we thought we
could have the biggest impact. And so for us,
with our background as designers, that is the
early days, the first couple of months or the
first year or two years of building a new
business. And at GV, sometimes we did that,
but sometimes we were working with companies that
were already well established. And when we'd come
into those companies, they kind of knew what they
were doing. They knew what they stood for. They
knew how they were different in the market and
how they were positioned. And so we could help
them answer these big questions and solve these
problems and test their prototypes with customers.
But when we started investing in truly
pre-seed, sometimes inception stage,
pre-product, pre-revenue, pre-everything
companies, there was this piece missing at
the beginning of that process. So we'd run
design sprints and they would be helpful,
but oftentimes it felt like there was
a foundational element of that project
that we didn't quite have our hands around.
And it was things like, what is the problem
you're solving and who's the ideal customer?
How are you different than what's in the
market today? Who are your actual competitors?
And there were these questions that just kept
coming up again and again that led us to say,
"Hey, we need to create a new sprint method,
something that is really targeted for the very
beginning of these big new projects." And so
that was what led us to create the Foundation
Sprint at Character Capital in 2021, 2022.
Okay. Yeah, I was wondering the timeline
on this. What I love about stuff like this,
episodes like this is you guys have done so much
work and done this so many times with
so many companies, so many founders,
and have learned what works and doesn't work. You
said hundreds of founders, hundreds of startups.
Yeah.
And you've just spent so many hours
studying this, refining it, crafting it,
and now you're just here to share all the
answers, save us so much time. Just the ROI
on this is incredible for us. So I appreciate you
guys doing this. Let's get into it. Let's talk
about the Foundation Sprint. Walk us through the
process. How does it start? What are the steps?
So specifically what we talk about with the
Foundation Sprint is it's at the very beginning
of your project. We recommend this kind of
crazy idea that you clear your schedule,
you clear your calendar. So the core team, this
is the co-founders if it's a startup, if it's a
product team inside a larger organization, it's
whoever's in charge of product, it's whoever's in
charge of engineering, it's whoever's in charge
of design, it whoever's in charge of marketing,
the core leadership team, they're going to come
together for, it's going to be 10 hours roughly,
give or take. And during those 10 hours, we're
going to go through a sequence of activities,
very highly scripted sequence of activities so
that we can make all of the key decisions together
and identify the basics of the project, what's
going to differentiate us in the marketplace,
and what's the best approach or implementation
path. All of those together form a hypothesis.
And then we recommend, so you finish now,
that's your Foundation Sprint, you've got
your founding hypothesis. Once you've got that
founding hypothesis, then you're going to go and
do design sprints, and we recommend you clear
the calendar for two to three weeks at least,
so you have the chance to be wrong about your
hypothesis. And we're going to run experiments.
And again, the Design Sprint, highly scripted,
calendar clear, emails off, Slack is off. We're
just focused on running through these sequence of
decisions, building prototypes, getting them in
front of customers, learning about a scorecard
that relates back to the founding hypothesis.
So at the big picture, it's going to be anywhere
from 10 hours to three to four weeks. You're going
to run this detailed script of activities with
your team with their calendars clear. And that's
crazy, and most people won't do it. But if you do
it, it confers upon you a huge advantage because
now you've got information, you know whether or
not your product clicks with customers. And we've
seen that be just such a tremendous signal
for is there going to be product market fit?
Okay. That was really helpful.
The 10 hours is that specifically,
that's the Foundation Sprint time box?
That's the Foundation Sprint time box, yeah.
And it's give or take, right? You might go fast
and be done in eight. And you might have a lot of
conversations and have a slightly larger team and
might take you 12. So we like to spread it out
over two days, do two four to six-hour blocks.
Okay. And then the three to four week-ish,
that's including the Design Sprint?
That's the design sprints, yeah.
Okay, awesome.
One week per sprint.
Okay. This is incredible ROI on 10
hours of work. Basically over two days,
you get to have a much stronger sense of
whether your idea is any good. Yeah. Is
that a simple way to describe it? You
just supercharge validating an idea?
Exactly. Yeah, it's a chance to... In the
10 hours, it's a chance to get clarity
about the core of your strategy, which is
something that teams will often go months
without really nailing down. And the
three to four weeks, that's a chance
to run experiments and get confidence
you're actually building the right thing.
Okay, let's talk about these two
days. How do you lay it out? How
do you approach it? What should someone do
if they want to actually try this at home?
So there are three phases to the Foundation
Sprint. First phase is the basics,
second phase is differentiation, and the third
phase is the approach to the project. So again,
all three of those are going to come
together to create the founding hypothesis.
So the first phase, the basics, as I mentioned,
that's identifying who's your customer,
what problem are you solving for the customer?
What's the competition for solving that problem?
How do they solve it today? And what are
the alternatives? How else do people solve
this? What are the workarounds? Those are
really almost embarrassingly simple things
to answer. But when we do this with a team
and everybody's answering, proposing their
answer to each question, we see everybody's got a
different perspective. And then when we lock in,
the decision-maker on the team says, "Okay, it's
going to be this one, it's going to be this one,
it's going to be this one." Now we have clarity
and confidence that that's the right way to go.
So we'll move forward from the basics into
differentiation and identify what are the things
that can set us apart from those competitors? And
we're going to use the advantages we have. We're
going to use our insight, we're going to use
our motivation, we're going to use our special
capabilities. These are things, again, people
are aware of these things, they're in tune to it,
but we want to get super, super specific, and
we'll go into an example in a second, and I think
that'll make it more clear exactly what we mean.
But going then from differentiation to saying,
"What are all of the different implementation
paths we could take here? Let's identify what
those are, put a little detail behind them."
And then we have a structured path for people
to take so they can weigh that decision, but
move through really quickly. Commit to one,
have a backup plan in case you end up feeling
like you need to pivot once you start sprinting
on it. And all of that together is going
to form this kind of Mad Libs sentence.
If we solve this problem for this customer with
this approach, we think they're going to choose
it over the competitors because of differentiator
one and differentiator two. And it's almost silly
how simple this thing is, but really powerful
for founders to have that clarity about,
okay, here it all is in one sentence. Now
let's go test and make sure this is true.
Amazing. Let's look at an example.
That's a really good idea. I know
you brought some examples. You're going
to do some screen sharing. You're going
to pull it up. If you're watching on
YouTube, you'll be able to see it. Also,
if you're watching on Spotify, you
can see the video. If you're on Apple
[inaudible 00:17:11]. But do your best to
describe what we're going to be looking at.
Yeah, so we're going to talk about this company
called Latchet first. This is the first company
we'll talk about. And Latchet is a startup
who was in our last group of Character Labs,
and we can go into Character Labs later on. But
essentially this is kind of an accelerator-like
program that we run at Character Capital where we
invest in a group of companies at the same time,
and we run them through that process that we were
just describing, where we start with a Foundation
Sprint, and then it's going to be a sequence
of three design sprints after that so that
they're testing and refining that hypothesis.
And so it's a great time for them. These are
founders who have just started their companies.
They're kind of that pre-seed, very beginning,
zero stage. And the progress you can see in those
three and a half, four weeks, it's phenomenal.
So let's talk about Latchet. So Latchet,
a couple co-founders, Chris and James,
who they had left Substack. They were engineers
leading up the growth team at Substack. And they
wanted to build a product for artisans. So if you
imagine you're a jewelry maker, you're a painter,
you're a woodworker, and you want to sell your
products outside of your immediate community,
the physical place where you are, your physical
location, well, you can build a site on Shopify,
but you still have to market it. If you do that,
you got to figure out how to reach those folks.
You can put your products on Etsy, but Etsy has
become quite commoditized. So you're going to be
up against everybody everywhere, and it's going to
be very hard for you to build an identity there,
to build a sense of who I am, what I'm all
about. And so what Chris and James thought
was maybe we could use some of the techniques
and methods we used at Substack to help people
find other newsletter writers through their
community, through recommendations they make
and help out artisans in that way. Wouldn't
that be cool? So they were at that stage,
they had a few different ideas about what form
that might take, what that might look like when
they joined Character Labs. And so that's kind of
the backdrop to this little quick story I'll tell.
And there's one really important thing
to emphasize about Chris and James that
Jake mentioned briefly, but I think is worth
repeating, which is that they're engineers,
they are builders. Their instinct is to write
code, it's to build software. And they actually
told us that they were excited but nervous
to come into Character Labs where we would
be encouraging them not to write code right away,
to take this time to clarify the differentiation,
the structure of what they're building, and to
validate that with customers before they went
all in on building a particular approach.
And I think you'll see in this example
how while they were a little hesitant to do
that upfront, eventually they saw how much
more valuable it was to work in this way versus
just diving right into building something.
That's actually really helpful
context. And speaking of the Substack,
Recommendations feature was one of the most
game-changing features for me with my newsletter
because it basically supercharged
my growth. So I get why they'd be
so excited about bringing this learning to
other ideas and to their own startups. So
thank you guys for doing that. And I'm even
more excited to see what they're building.
Well, let's take a look. So this
board here that we're looking at,
this is like their Miro board. So we've
got a big template. And whether you're
watching on YouTube or listening to this
episode, we'll talk about at the end how
you can get access to this template, which
will kind of guide you through the process.
But what happens in this first step in the
Foundation Sprint, in the basics, as we said
before, is that we're going through a sequence
of questions. Who's the most important customer,
for example, is the first question, the very
first question that a team needs to answer. And
as we do that, just as an important side note,
we're using this tactic that we call work alone
together. And specifically the note and vote
is this method where everyone's in silence,
in this case both Chris and James, but if you have
a team of seven, it's all seven people be working
in silence, writing down their own answers to this
question, who's the most important customer or
who are all the different kind of customers we
might consider? Writing down multiple answers.
And then once we've got those answers,
the team's going to vote on those. And
then one person who's designated as the decider,
usually it's going to be the CEO of the startup,
but it could be in some cases, maybe it's the
chief product officer, whatever, however they
decide to do it. But one person's going to say,
"Okay, this is our decision for now, and now we're
going to move on." And by doing this and using
silence and using structure and then having a
designated decision-making process, we can move
through a lot of conversations very quickly and
save some of that energy that it requires to make
the decisions that matter most. In this case,
what we're really worried about on day one of
our Foundation Sprint is differentiation. So we
don't want to spend too long on the basics.
Anyway, we motor through customer problem,
the capability, the insight, the motivation
that the team has, those are all advantages,
and who are the competition. And we get this sort
of one-page sheet, the basics, and it's going to
have the answers to all those questions. Who's our
customer? In this case, artisans who want to sell
online, but they sort of find tech and marketing
to be hard. The problem is sales growth. If we
jump down to the competition, their number one
competitor is Shopify, but Etsy is another way
people approach this, as we mentioned. But there's
also in-person sales and art fairs or other ways
that people try to get at this problem. And
realistically, if you're delivering a solution,
you need to stand out from all of those.
And then there are advantages. We talked
about this key one, they built Substack's
network growth features, so they know how
to do this thing. So now we've established the
basics. We're going to move on to differentiation.
Before you do that actually, let me ask you a
question here. Because I think people seeing
this could think, "Oh, this is like... I know
all this stuff, it's so obvious." It's like,
"Okay, I get it. I have an idea, I don't need
to do this." Where do you find people most are
often surprised by something that emerges out of
this? Is one of these buckets often, wow, this is
often not what you expected, or is it generally
a lot of surprises? What do you experience there?
I think the moment where you immediately
start to see value is when everyone on the
team is writing down their answers to these
questions. And then people put their heads
up and look at what everyone else has written
and they realize, "Oh, that's not what I said,"
or "I didn't think of that one." Or, "Gosh."
The actual concrete reality of going through
with the team and being very transparent
and clear about how we're making decisions
too about each of these things, when that basic
sheet comes together and you see the specifics,
the specifics are surprising, but it's also
familiar. We look at it and you say, "Yeah,
that all looks right, but I'm surprised by the
specifics. They're not what I would have written
if I had written it down. I might've gotten two
of those things, two of the six items on there."
And I think that's what's most surprising. And I
think it's also kind of a sense of relief that,
okay, well, that's very reassuring that we have
clarity about that and we've made it concrete.
These activities that we do during the basics
are impactful for different reasons. I think that
problem can be really interesting because
when teams sit down and think about it,
it is often less clear than they thought
what the actual problem is. Like, "Wait,
what problem do our customers really
have that we're solving for them?"
I think competition can be sort of an aha
moment when they start to think beyond
just what are the other startups in this
space? If this is an important problem,
your customer's probably already solving
it somehow. It may be a workaround,
it may be an alternative, it may not be a
direct competitor, but if it's worth solving,
they probably have some way of dealing with it
today. And what is that? And when you zoom out
and you look at that set of competitors,
it can be a little scary, but it is also
an important moment for teams.
And then I think that advantage
isn't necessarily immediately beneficial, but
it becomes really valuable when the teams are
looking at differentiation, because startups
can't compete with big companies on scale or
on having built-in distribution advantages or
having partnerships in place. So they really
have to dig deep and figure out what can we do
that nobody else is capable of doing? And...
... and figure out what can we do that nobody
else is capable of doing? And so by taking time
to sit down and do this almost unnatural act of
like, wait, why are we special? And when we're
able to encourage teams to really think about
that, it sets them up really nicely for the
next step, which is differentiation.
Ideally, based on those advantages.
What I'm hearing is a lot of
the value here is also just
everyone has the answers in their
head in some way, but just seeing
what everyone else is thinking and then
aligning on one is a lot of this value.
Yeah. It's like thinking deeply and quietly about
it yourself and then seeing what everybody else
comes up with when they are able to also think
deeply and quietly about it. Then ideally,
if they're working with us in character
labs, having somebody who's a bit external
to push them and say, try harder, dig deeper.
What really makes you special here? How are
you really going to beat OpenAI? How are
you really going to beat Google at this.
This whole idea of noting and voting and working
in silence. Such a recurring theme on this podcast
of not doing brainstorms in large groups with
a lot of people. It feels like that's just dead
in every way. I just had this naming expert
on the podcast who names some of the biggest
companies in the world, Pentium, Powerbook,
Sonos, Purcell, and that's their approach
is they used to do brainstorms. He's like, that
doesn't work. And now they just have small teams
sitting quietly in a room working together on
ideas and then thinking on their own. So that's
such an interesting trend and I feel like IDEO
just created this whole, we need to brainstorm
post-its, and then everyone's like, that's
not actually working. Let's stop doing that.
The other thing that I feel as you're talking
through this, what I'm feeling this is for
founders, there's not a manual for starting a
company. It feels like this dark art of like,
I guess I got to find product market fit.
And this idea, it feels like this is almost
a manual of everything you need to do to just
get the basics of is this even worth doing?
Yeah. And that's why we created it because
we still are investing in founders who are...
They're incredibly talented and they're
smart and they have a background that is
going to give them an advantage in building
some particular product. But you're right,
there's no manual and we were just kind of solving
our own problem and we believe in this so much
and we see the ROI as being so great that this is
the first thing we do when we make an investment.
We invest in a company and then we run a
foundation sprint with them right away. We
run more foundation sprints with startups than
we do design sprints at this point. And I don't
think we can ever encapsulate every single thing
that you need to know or that you need to do to
start a company, but this is our best take at
what you should do in the early days to set
yourself up for success and maximize the chances
that you're going to reach product market fit.
Amazing. Okay, let's keep it going. So
we've done the basics. What comes next?
Yeah, so we've done the basics and another
important thing that we've accomplished while
going through the sequence of activities and
the basics is to boot up the right context into
everyone's head so that we're ready for the main
event of this first day, which is differentiation.
And I still have very firmly in my mind, I grew up
with a Mac plus computer and you'd put in the disk
and the drive and you'd have to boot up the app
that you wanted to run. That's kind of the way our
brains work. We have limited working memory and
we've got to have the right stuff in there when
we're going to make a big decision, when we're
going to think hard about a certain problem or
question, it's important to have the right context
fresh at hand. So the basics is really the context
for thinking about differentiation.
And differentiation is the heart of
what we're doing in the foundation sprint
because it goes without saying perhaps,
but we like to say it. When you are making a new
product, people want to ignore it. People want to
not pay attention to it, and if they do have to
pay attention to it, if it gets in their face,
they want to not try it because we just
are all bombarded by so many things and
that's never been more true than it is now.
And so we have defenses up to save calories in our
brain. We don't want to engage. It's crucial then
that a product has a clear promise that it makes,
and that promise is radically differentiated
from the alternatives and that that promise is
strong enough that you'll try it and then that the
product delivers on that promise. And so when we
talk about differentiation, we're saying, look, we
want you to be really clear on your promise, not
the promise you're making to investors about this
technology and what's special about the technology
or what's special about the market opportunity,
but what the customer at the center. We've started
the basics by talking about the customer and the
problem they have and the way they see the world.
And we want to talk about what you're going
to offer to the customer and how it's going
to separate from the alternatives. And so in the
end of this next phase of the foundation sprint,
we're going to have a two-by-two diagram that's
going to look like a business school one-on-one
diagram. And in fact, we often refer back to this
Steve Jobs iPhone introduction slide where he
talks about the iPhone and he makes a joke about
it. This is a business school one-on-one diagram,
but it's really helpful to start developing
your product with this clarity about this
is the promise we'll make to customers at
the end, and we're going to deliver on that
promise because we can test and prove that
in design sprints. So anyway, we start off,
we talk about differentiators and we talk
about classic differentiators, fast to slow,
smart to not so smart to borrow from the iPhone
slide, easy to use to hard to use, and so on.
And we just start off and have the team, okay,
let's just score those up against the competition.
Put a sticky note on those continuums showing
where you think the product could be. And usually
you'll do this and maybe you'll start to see
there are a couple places where we can stand out
on these classics. That's great. These classics
are easily understandable by any customer. We're
all sort of familiar with these kinds of things.
So okay, that's great. Then we get into writing
custom differentiators. So we're going to write a
bunch of good things on one end, crummy opposite
on the other end, and then we're going to score
those. And so for the Latchet story, we'll pick
up with Chris and James here. They've written,
well, we could really differentiate on networked
versus siloed. Our approach is networked.
If you're using Shopify, you're siloed,
or maybe we can differentiate on painless business
growth versus labor-intensive business growth.
So that might be the specific way we describe
the promise of our product. So after evaluating
a bunch of these, writing a bunch of these, voting
on them quietly, and then the decider's going to
say, all right, I don't want to choose a couple
of these and we're going to try them out. The
teams are going to... If you're running
a foundation sprint, you're going to try
out a few differentiators. You're going to score
against your competitors. You're going to create
a scale and you're going to say, okay, let's
be honest. Let's be tough. Where do we really
think we could stack up against the competitors
on this differentiator we've chosen in great
detail plotting each company or product one at a
time. Okay, so you do that for one differentiator,
you do it for another, you do it until you
feel like we've got two that are really strong,
and then you make that business school one-on-one
diagram. And so here's this one for says Lyric,
they changed their name to Lachit,
so I'm going to edit that real time.
I love this. So just rebrand.
Yeah. So Lachit's up here in the
top-right corner and we say, okay,
look, this is a good differentiation chart because
you've got this quadrant here, this quadrant here,
this quadrant here, right? You've got the...
So you're in the top-right and you've-
You've got to be in the top-right,
you got to be in the top-right.
You always have to be in the top-right. And if
you see those other three quadrants, the top-left,
bottom-left, bottom-right, those form an L shape
and we call that Loserville. So we want to have a
way of looking at the world that puts all of the
competitors into Loserville. And then we want to
say, okay, if you can deliver on that and if that
promise is compelling to customers. So both those
things have to be true. Can you deliver on it and
do customers care and believe that that matters
to them? If both of those things are true, you
have a really compelling promise. You have the
possibility of a very successful product. So now
we've identified that and that becomes a core of
our hypothesis. Is that differentiation
true? So that's the differentiation step.
Before you move on to the next step, is that
where you were going next? Just so I could take a-
Yeah, yeah.
Okay. Follow a couple of threads. This is so
awesome. There's just so much value here. Also,
just this slide at the end here, folks
are watching YouTube. This is your deck
slide where you show your competitors
and how you're better than them all.
And actually I want to jump on that for a second
because we've all seen two by two. Hey Graham,
right? There's a ton of these. They're all
over the place. And if you're anything like me,
I just ignored these. I just thought these were
pretty much BS up until, well, whenever we started
putting these foundations friends three or four
years ago. And I think the reason why usually
these two by two diagrams feel like this is
just consultant baloney. This is just like
who... It's because maybe one person makes this
chart and they do it quickly because they needed
to slide for the slide deck and the audience
they're considering, maybe it's investors.
And so often these describe technology or they
describe the market opportunity, they don't talk
about the customer's perspective. And the other
thing is that they're not proven. There's no
evidence behind the fact that these are true.
So if they did happen to be about customer
perspective, it's unlikely that the whole team
would've weighed in on what those differentiators
are, and it's very unlikely that we would've
tested and proven that matters and that we can
deliver on it. And so if you do all of those
things and you do it at the beginning of the
project, we think this has the potential,
when we've seen it becomes this, well,
this guiding light, here's the North Star. We
need to deliver on this. This is what we have
to create. And that helps you make decisions all
the way through your product development cycle.
Just to point people to justification
for why differentiation is so important,
there's a couple of episodes that I did
that I'll point to in the show notes that
just give you more context of why you
need to differentiate. So I spoke of
David Plastic who is this naming expert
that we just had on the podcast. His
whole thing is when he's coming up with
a name for Sonos or Purcell or Windsor,
it has to differentiate. And he talks about this
in depth. So we'll point to that episode and this
is just like if you're not convinced, why are we
spending so much time in differentiation? Also,
April Dunford who's like, I don't know, the god
of positioning. She has differentiation is such
a core part of her approach to positioning. And
so there's just so much evidence to tell you
that differentiation is a really important
step and element of successful companies.
One of the things that I've noticed about these
topics that the basics we talked about already,
differentiation, this notion of you need
a foundation for your project. It's a bit
more under the radar for people. I think it's a
bit harder for people to immediately see like,
oh, we need this. We see the people who
react the strongest to this and have the
strongest immediate affinity to this
idea actually being start-up founders,
people who are really sophisticated in this
challenge. Product managers who are at... We were
invited in to speak at open AI and anthropic
about this, and we see the product people,
they're being like, oh my god, this is really
powerful. This is the kind of stuff we need.
I think for a lot of folks though, it can sound
like this is just elementary, differentiation.
Of course we need to differentiate. The problem
is that all of this stuff gets backgrounded. It's
something we've thought about a bit. We assume
we're on the same page, we assume we're going
to deliver something, but then business as usual
happens, we build a product, we get kind of more
interested in the technology and delivering that,
and we end up trying to sell it to customers at
the end. We end up putting a coat of paint
on it with a marketing page or sales deck.
We haven't actually built from the beginning the
thing that we know is going to matter to people.
One of the most useful steps here that I haven't
seen before is just a starting place for how
to even start thinking about differentiation.
Everyone's always probably thinking price and
speed maybe. You guys have a really cool
just starting list that you showed here.
Anything more you can add here for
helping people start to think about
ways to differentiate beyond the obvious price
and speed. And I don't know, a couple more.
So I'm just going to jump into another
startup here just so we can see what this
sheet looks like with scores on it. So
this is a startup called Mellow. Anyway,
the standard classic differentiators where
we start, they are fast to slow, smart to
not so smart, easy to use to hard to use, free to
expensive, focused to one size fits all, simple to
complicated and integrated to siloed. And so you
could probably argue there's these others that
should be included or some of those should be
taken off. But what we like about this is that
it's a small set. They're easy to understand.
We know customers can understand these and
they create a great starting place for your
team to think about differentiation because
you can quickly look at this list and start
scoring where you think your product could be
on these scales and you know that if you can
use one of these, people will understand it.
But it also starts to make the team comfortable
with this notion of differentiation. And again,
we want to make differentiation something
that all of the co-founders or core team can
participate in. It's not just the job of the
person writing the pitch deck. It's not just
the job of the marketer or the salesperson, but
we're getting everybody's perspective in on it
and this is a great warm up activity before we
start to write our own custom differentiators.
Awesome. And then again, this is just
inspiration for coming up with more ways
to differentiate. Something that is a common
question I think for founders is price as a
differentiator. Is there any insight you
guys have there? How often do you land on
price being a good differentiator
with the startups you work with?
I think price is rarely the
most important differentiator.
Part of what's interesting about going through
these classic differentiators, these standard
ones first and then jumping into the custom ones
is that the classic ones are sort of universal,
but it is going to be hard beat the competition
on very many of these. It's going to be hard to
build a product that's faster than what Google
can build or what OpenAI can build. It's going
to be harder to be cheaper than those competitors
because they just have so many more resources.
They can have lost leader products that are
underpriced. Where I think pricing has become a
really clear advantage for some companies is those
that are leveraging AI to solve problems that were
previously unsolvable with software. So we have
a company that we invested in called BindWell and
they use AI to design precision pesticides.
And we ran a foundation sprint with them right
after investing and five years ago you couldn't
design pesticides with AI. It wasn't possible.
Even if you had that idea, you wouldn't have been
able to build it and now you can. And so for them,
one of the big advantages is yeah, these
pesticides, they can be a lot cheaper because
it doesn't require this massive team of R&D
chemists to tinker and experiment with things
in the lab to try to create new pesticides.
We can design them with AI. So it is more
often true in AI companies like that, but it's
very difficult to compete on price in general.
And we think we find that it is not as durable
of an advantage as some of these other things.
That is such a good point because historically
price has been don't compete on price for
exactly what you said. It's hard to do
long term. It's kind right to the bottom,
especially if there's incumbents, they can
price a lot lower. But with AI, that is a
really often and strong differentiator. Now do
this thing like cursor basically is competing on.
You're saving engineering time and
it's worth so much money to you.
At the same time, the output of
the AI is probably not going to
be quite as good as a human process. So
it can be a little bit cheaper for now,
but it has to be a lot cheaper. It has to
be... I've heard people offer 10X cheaper
than the legacy sort of manual approach to
solving that problem as the rule of thumb.
That's awesome. Okay. I'll just quickly reference,
there's an episode that will come out before
this with Modobon about pricing strategy and
there's a lot of discussion actually on this.
Oh, great.
Especially with how to design your price with
customers as you're starting your company. Also,
the episode with the founder of Superhuman Rahul,
he actually spent, there's a lot of cool context
on how he differentiated Superhuman and
it was actually very much on speed. His
speed actually. Yeah, speed was where he
landed. And to your point, it was both...
It was the Venn diagram of what you said, can
we do this and do people value it? And that's
where his research pointed to is people really
value this and they were able to achieve it.
One of the things that's really interesting about
this example here that we're looking at Mellow is
that you can see that they were not the best on
all these scales. If teams are through and they're
being really realistic about how they stack up
against the competition, it's normal and natural
to find that you're not going to be the best on
all these differentiators. And that is really
helpful for creating clarity in your positioning
and in your marketing because you're not going to
show a feature checklist chart that says you're
better at everything than every competitor. But
if you can drive home one or two things that your
customers really care about and that you can be
radically better at, it's going to improve your
chances of winning and finding product market fit.
And we find that going through this process where
you're not just thinking about one differentiator
at a time or you're not trying to win on all
of them, but you're looking across this scale
of options and you're being just really honest
about where you stack up can both point you in
the right direction in terms of what you will win
on, but also can give you the comfort to say, hey,
it's okay if we're not better than every single
company on every single one of these things.
That's great context. That's going to make
people feel a lot better I think. Today's
episode is brought to you by Coda. I personally
use Coda every single day to manage my podcast
and also to manage my community. It's where
I put the questions that I plan to ask every
guest that's coming on the podcast. It's where I
put my community resources. It's how I manage my
workflows. Here's how Coda can help you. Imagine
starting a project at work and your vision is
clear exactly who's doing what and where to
find the data that you need to do your part.
In fact, you don't have to waste time
searching for anything because everything
your team needs from project trackers and
OKRs to documents and spreadsheets lives
in one tab all in Coda. With Coda's
collaborative all in one workspace,
you get the flexibility of docs, the structure
of spreadsheets, the power of applications,
and the intelligence of AI all
in one easy to organize tab.
Like I mentioned earlier, I use Coda every single
day. And more than 50,000 teams trust Coda to
keep them more aligned and focused. If you're a
startup team looking to increase alignment and
agility, Coda can help you move from planning to
execution in record time. To try it for yourself,
go to Coda.io/Lenny today and get six months
free of the team plan for startups. That's
Coda.io/Lenny to get started for free and get
six months of the team plan, Coda.io/Lenny.
Anything else on differentiation before we move
on to the third step of designing your approach?
I think it's worth taking a look at what it looks
like when you have a bunch of these custom crafted
differentiators, what that might look like.
Because in the case of Mellow, we've got,
I don't know, there must be 25 here. And so
they've written purposeful, magical, clear,
personal, provides direction, flexible, human
creative, beautiful, and on and on. What they're
trying to get at and what we want every team
to think about here is what is a new version
of reality, a new lens that you can offer to
your customers on the world. Because a lot of
times you're building a new product, you actually
have to change the way people think about what's
possible and what matters to them. Those classics
are often already well-trodden ground where other
people have differentiated, they've already
thought about it, but these new particular
things that are possible with your technology that
you know is possible with the customer problem,
the things that you believe might matter.
It's really interesting to try some very
fine-tuned list of sometimes just a slight
variation. We slightly change this wording
or the way we describe what's great about what
we do. And that is the thing we think is really
going to stand out. And again, you can see even
on this list that they've custom written, when we
see where they score it, they're not all the way
to the good end of the scale on all of them. When
they get honest and look through, they're like,
well actually, maybe we can't deliver on this,
but this one we really can. And this one
we also suspect will matter to customers.
Where did Mellow land on the differentiators
they picked and where did Latchit Land?
Yeah, let's take a look. For Mellow,
they trade out a bunch before they
decided here. So they actually scored
with the competitors on these scales.
And just for context, Mellow is a tool
that allows you to run very simple,
very targeted, very useful AI agents for common
everyday tasks like summarizing your email or
cleaning up your calendar or drafting responses
to messages. And one of their insights was that
there's been so many AI products that
have over-promised about being able to
replace all humans and do anything and 10X year
productivity, but so few of them have actually
delivered on those promises. And so they have
this insight that if they can be really focused
and really human and really high quality and
they can deliver on that promise of making your
life better by offloading tedious tasks that
that's going to really click with customers.
That's a great context. Thank you for adding that.
So Mellow lands on mobile first and
works out of the box if there are two
differentiators and they're trying to
differentiate from Gumloop and OpenAI is
sort of a generalized tool and Latchit
they're going to differentiate on...
We're pulling it up. If folks aren't watching,
he's pulling up the mirror board
to show us where they landed.
Latchit, they're going to differentiate on
helps you grow and cooperative. So when they
compare against Etsy, when they compare against
Shopify or setting up your table at an art fair,
they're going to differentiate on
helps you grow and cooperative. And
they think none of the competitors
does both of those things well.
That is cool. Thank you for sharing that. And
to your point, this is where they think it
will work. And then the next step is actually
test this in the market, which is where we go
from here. So let's move on to the next step in
which is the final step of the foundation sprint.
So closing off differentiation is a short step
that is just to create some project principles
that'll help you make decisions in line with that
differentiation. And you were just talking about
superhuman and differentiating on speed. And when
John and I worked at Google back in the 2000s,
there was this list called 10 Things We've Found
To Be True. And one of the things on that list
was fast is better than slow. And what was
interesting is this is a mantra that you
would actually hear people using in meetings to
help dictate decisions. Well, we're considering
this approach to this view or this approach,
this approach renders 12 milliseconds faster.
That's probably going to be the one we're going
to take. It's going to be a really compelling
reason for us to not go with just the one that
renders faster or the one that gets the user
to their benefit with one less click.
And this notion that you can have a
decision-making guide, we think we've seen it
be so useful for us in those contexts. We think,
hey, this is an easy moment. You've got your
differentiators kind of loaded up in your mind.
Let's take a second here and just think, what's a
principle? How can we turn that into a principle?
So if we take a look at Latchit, they've got
help sellers help each other. So if they're
trying to make a decision between two approaches,
well, which one of these helps sellers help each
other or do the thing that makes sellers more
money? If we're choosing between two things,
let's do the one that helps make them more
money. And so then we've kind of moved on.
We've got a mini manifesto we call it, which is
that differentiation chart and these principles.
And the notion is this page, the basics page was
just kind of the core simple stuff you need to
know about this project. The mini manifesto
in one page is your decision-making guide.
This is so cool and this looks like it
would take a lot of work, but again,
this is just a day or two of sitting
around working through this framework.
Yeah, you'll get to this in four-ish hours.
By the end of the first day, you'll have a mini
manifesto that describes how you win
essentially as a company and a startup.
Or how you believe it's
going to work. And of course,
we're going to test it. Now, the
next phase of the foundation is-
Believe it's going to work, and of course we're
going to test it. Now the next phase of the
foundation Sprint is locking in on the approach
we're going to start with. So we'll continue the
story of Latch It here, it's easier to use an
example than to describe this in the abstract.
So coming into Character Labs, Latch
It had sort of four approaches in mind,
but they weren't sure which one to take. So
they might build an app, that's one approach
they could take. They might build a sort
of newsletter platform. That's something
obviously they knew how to do. They might build
a Shopify plugin, that's a simple way to kind
of piggyback on something people are already
doing. Their number one competitor is Shopify.
Or they might have to build the full stack. And I
think a big question for them was, which of these
and how much do we have to build before there's
enough value for customers that they're actually
going to adopt it and we're actually going to
get some traction and get this thing going?
And it's important to call out here that all
four of these approaches solve the same problem
for the same customer. And they're all likely
to differentiate from the competition in the
same ways based on the unique advantages
that the founders Chris and James bring to
this company. So these are not wildly different
product ideas or company ideas. These are just
different approaches. You have the same
destination in mind, but you say, "Hey,
which path could we take?" It's like pulling up
directions on Google Maps. This one's a little
faster, this one uses less fuel, this one avoids
tolls. What's the right approach for us to take?
And I love the work you did on that first
day eliminates a lot of ideas you probably
had that you would've probably spent
time building and then realizing, "Okay,
this doesn't make any sense. It's
just like what everyone else has."
Totally, totally, yeah. And we usually see
teams starting projects in one of two states.
And one state is the state that Latch It
finds themselves in where, gosh, there's
a few different ways we could do this. How do we
decide? We can discuss and discuss and discuss,
but that could go on forever. So that's state
one. We know there are some options. And state
two is we're pretty locked in on one approach
already. We think we've got this figured out.
In either of those cases, we think it's worth
taking, again, about four hours-ish to be really
careful to lay out the options. If you think
there's only one option to sort of force yourself
to think, well, what if this doesn't work?
What's another alternative? Or is there another
alternative that we have previously considered
and dismissed that we should maybe reconsider just
to make sure? And end with a situation where
you've made a decision clearly about, okay,
we've considered alternatives. This is our first
choice. And you've also identified this is our
backup plan. So that failure doesn't seem quite so
scary when we start to run experiments. And we're
really able to pivot fast should that happen.
So what we're going to do on the second day of
the foundation sprint through this sort of
third phase, which is the approach. Is to
identify those different paths, so for Latch
It here, they've got a B, C and D options.
We're going to color code those and then
we're going to plot them on these charts. So
we've got these different lenses. We call this
activity magic lenses. And the notion is, if
we had a discussion about it, and we could ... as
investors, if we could imagine like waving a magic
wand and putting the perfect team of advisors in
place to counsel the founders on this decision,
we would love for them to have a customer
expert, somebody who's just brilliant vision
for the product and the customer experience. And
they're hammering their fist on the table saying,
"The customer, the customer, the customer, make
the decision that's best for the customer."
And so we'll plot those options on these axes
of easy to use versus hard to use and perfect
solution to the customer problem versus this is
just an okay solution to the customer problem.
And then similarly, we want an advisor who's
going to pound their fist on the table for
building something cheap and fast, getting
it out into the market, being pragmatic,
get it out there as fast as possible. That's the
pragmatic lens. We want somebody who's going to
advocate for growth. What's the way to reach
the most customers? Get it in people's hands
as fast as possible, easy to adopt. We want
somebody who's going to advocate for money,
for the financial health of a business. So
what's going to create long-term value for
the customers? Where's the biggest audience of
these folks? We want to look at differentiation.
Which we spent the first half of the Foundation
Sprint establishing. Well, we want consider
these approaches through that lens, as well.
And so what the teams will do is to plot these
options on these lenses. They'll almost
always create some lenses of their own,
some custom lenses that matter to them. They might
have one about their conviction. I think there's
sort of a humorous one for Mellow where it's
like, which founder is like, "F yeah, that's
exactly what I want to build." And on the other
end of the spectrum it's like, nah, just kind
of the sort of heat of excitement that you feel.
That might be a really important decision point.
That feels really important. That feels like that
should be one of your ... you
call these the magic lenses?
Yeah, yeah. It probably should be. It
probably should be [inaudible 00:57:11]-
Yeah, I feel like ... just like how excited
are you to build this? It feels
like a really important piece.
Yeah, we saw that one in ... this is our
cohort of labs that's going on right now,
and I'll bring that one up for context.
If we add it, we can call it the Lenny lens.
The Lenny lens. Yeah. Oh, that's a good idea.
In honor of.
Yeah, so here it is. And you can see that Marie
is more likely to swear than Ben apparently. But
it's crucial, right? And many founders, they'll
have different ... one of the challenges is that
for each founder, I think, each set of founders,
there's maybe a different way that they phrase
what that means. What conviction means to
them. And maybe it's as simple as this,
I just feel it, I just know. And sometimes it's
a little bit more like, well, it's conviction,
but it's also, what's the data that we have behind
it? And that's what forms my intuition about it.
Awesome. I love that lens.
I love that you asterisk
out so it's not a little bit [inaudible 00:58:08].
A little bit. A little ...
just slightly concealed.
Slightly.
Yeah, if you zoom in, it's actually not censored.
So the cool thing about this lens's thing is at
the end, you've done all that, you've plotted
it all out. And if you're having a conversation
like that, you just have to sort of maintain in
memory, what did that person say? What did that
other person say? What's that conversation I
had a week ago? Whatever. Here it's all laid
out and sometimes you zoom out and it's
honestly as simple as like, "Oh, hey,
look, the blue one is in the top right quadrant of
almost every single lens. What is that one? What's
going on? That might just be an easy decision."
Sometimes you zoom out and you say, "Oh,
clearly like nothing wins in every lens."
And that's actually really reassuring because
then you know there is no perfect decision.
There's nothing that checks all of the boxes.
And that's going to help us decide. Because
now we decide which is the most important lens,
which is the most important viewpoint to take.
And you can actually move forward in either way,
either situation you get in where there's
sort of consistency across all the lenses
or there's not. You either pick a lens
or you just pick the consensus winner.
I love that this step answers a question that's
been the back of my mind that I think a lot of
people wonder is they're hearing this is just,
why don't I just build something and launch it
and learn? And why am I spending all this time
sitting in a room? And this to me is a big part
of the answer is just spending an hour or two
thinking through, here's the ideas we have.
How do they compare on ... how do they look
on these magical lenses? Which makes so much
sense. How do they just filter on what customers
will love most, will help us grow the fastest,
we'll drive the most money? Things like that.
It's such a simple, quick exercise that will
save you so much time building and launching and
having to spend time learning. That is weeks,
days, months of work versus a couple hours.
It could save you so much over that time.
And it's also the case that you start
building something. It's exciting,
you can move fast. It's easier and easier to
see progress now with AI tools. And that act
of building and starting to create something has
a momentum of its own that can be hard to stop.
And if you're headed in the wrong direction,
you can spend a lot of time building and making
progress. But it's just, if it's not progress in
the right direction, it's actually hurting you.
And that's why we want people to pause and
take this. It's really, as you said earlier,
the ROI is high. But it feels very unnatural to
pause when you're so excited at the beginning
and ready to go. To pause and say, "Okay, let's
make sure we're taking the right path." But just
imagine you're Gandalf, you're Frodo, you're
starting off, you're trying to get to Mordor,
it's a long trip. You don't want
to take the wrong path. You want
to take the ... think before you start
marching through the swamps or whatever.
One phenomenon we've seen when teams are
building things really quickly with AI is
that the more AI-generated or assisted
they are, the more generic they tend to
turn out. Which makes sense if you think
about how LLMs were developed, they're all
basically pre-trained on the same data. And so
in this excitement, in this rush to say, "Wow,
look at how fast we can build it." You actually
end up with something that is less differentiated
than what already exists in the world. And then
let's say you launch it, and that takes longer
than building sort of a clickable prototype.
But you launch it because you're moving so fast.
And then you get data from the people who managed
to find that thing about what they did with it.
But you don't get any data about what they didn't
do with it. And you certainly don't get any data
about the people who never found it, who never
tried it. Maybe they landed on your website and
they're like, blah, another generic AI-generated
thing, that's not worth my time. And so
we think it's really helpful to basically put
yourself in a situation where you can slow down
a little bit and do some hard thinking, some deep
thinking about what's actually going to make your
product unique. And then you can switch into this
mode of like, okay, great. Now let's go as fast
as possible and get that out into customer's
hands. But if you don't take this step first,
it's actually kind of counterintuitive that going
fast can actually slow you down in the long run.
Yeah, to build on that, I had
this guest recently, Bob Baxley.
Yeah, we know Bob.
Okay. So he has this really interesting insight.
He calls it ... I think he calls it the Primal
Mark. Essentially his feedback is, wait
as long as possible to start any sort of
sketch or prototype, because as soon as
you start drawing what you're building,
now everything you do will be a response to
that. And so the more time you can spend before
starting to concept out the solution, the more
likely you are to land on something that works.
That is super interesting and it is-
Counterintuitive [inaudible 01:03:18].
And I find myself challenged to think about it
in the context of the sprints that we run with
founders. But I think one way to interpret that
in the work that we do is that we used to just
run design sprints with every team, that was
our hammer and everything looked like a nail.
And part of what we found so valuable about
doing the Foundation Sprint is that it keeps
you away from ideation for just a little bit
longer. And it forces you to think about why
you're unique and the market that you're going
into before you get to that moment of creating
something that looks realistic and then maybe
being a little bit locked into that approach.
That's such a ... like I love that this emerged
out of that. Like you guys were so design sprint
oriented, and it's just like, cool, let's just
make prototypes, let's design, let's make it real,
let's show people. And that's, I think, where
a lot of people's minds are at more and more.
And maybe as a result, and this is almost like,
okay, maybe that wasn't the right approach to
start. Maybe it's actually better to think
a little bit of what we want to design and
build before. And so just the fact that you guys
spent so much of your life and time on that. And
then realize this is actually potentially
even more important to do, it says a lot.
And ideas always get distilled down to one thing
that people grab onto and they focus on. And I
think with the design sprint, it got distilled
down to just build a prototype. Just quit messing
around and build something. But the reality is
when you run a design sprint, it's five days and
you don't build the prototype until the fourth
day. So you do a bunch of work to figure out
how does our customer learn about this thing? What
are the different ideas that we're bringing to
what our solution could look like? Which of those
are the most likely to work? And only then at the
end of the week are you building a prototype.
But I do think that as that method has become
really widely known, people just think
about let's build something. And then
once you multiply that times the power of AI,
it definitely creates this narrative that the
only way to build something new is to just
create the product as quickly as possible.
And that doesn't really match our experience,
that doesn't really fit the pattern of what
we've seen working best across the few
hundred companies that we've worked with.
I think this validates in some ways the role of
a product manager where the PM's job is to help
the team figure out what should we be building and
are we all aligned on what we're building before
we start designing and building? This process is
almost like the product requirements document of
a company. Which I think a lot of product people
listening to this will feel really good about.
Yeah, we see this as a great tool for product
people. It's a way to give you a structure for
leading your team through those decisions.
And a way to give all the folks on a team,
including the person who's the product leader.
But the person who's the engineering leader,
the person who's the marketing leader, sales
leader, the design leaders, the exact right
opportunity to contribute and participate in
forming the strategy. The exact right opportunity
as we get into design sprints, following the
foundation sprints, to then make it real. And
turn that idea, that hypothesis about what might
work into hopefully evidence that it does work.
I feel like it's actually more helpful
to engineers, like non-product people,
because I think a PM my brain
would be like, I want to do this
intuitively. Whether they do it right or not. I
think it's other functions almost they're like,
no, let's just jump straight to
design, straight to prototyping.
Let me ask you ... while we're on this tangent,
we're on this wild tangent out of this process,
but want to ... this question has been in my mind.
Because I recently had a founder on the podcast,
Maor, who built this company called Base44.
He built it, it sold in six months for $80
million. And this journey of that is he just
had a problem he wanted to solve for himself,
for his girlfriend, for a scouts program. He
built it, people started using it, and he kind
of evolved it from there. And obviously he didn't
go through a process like this. Thoughts on just
like, is it okay to just do that? When should
someone think about, "Okay, I should actually
set aside time to do a Foundation Sprint."
Versus, I'm just motivated to solve a problem
for my friends. I'm just going to build it, evolve
it, iterate with them, and kind of go from there.
One of the observations from our hundreds of
experiences working alongside founders in the
early days of their projects and watching
them make decisions and watching them try
things and succeed or fail, is that there are
so many founders who are incredibly bright,
incredibly capable. They have great insights
about the market, about an opportunity. And yet,
their startup does not work out. And there's
a problem with selection bias that we hear
from the folks who they were brilliant, they
checked all those boxes I just described. They
saw a great opportunity, they were smart, they
executed well, they had courage and conviction,
and they did it and it worked out,
and it was a tremendous success.
And I think that the danger in thinking
like, "Well, they didn't follow a process,
so I don't need to." And that may be true and
maybe you don't need it. But what we believe is
you have a better ... this just increases your
odds. This is a chance to get more clear on,
is this a good opportunity? To get more clear
on, will the thing I build click with customers?
And if you've already figured out that no, this
thing's ... my product has taken off, my product
is working. We've actually had founders in labs
who they started off character labs and they said,
"I started selling this thing and it's already
taking off. I want to stop running experiments."
And we're like, "Yeah, stop running experiments."
You don't need to do this if you've got product
market fit, if you've got evidence that this
thing is clicking and you have conviction,
run with it. But if you're not there,
this is a great path to get you going.
And if you're not sure if the thing you're
going to build is going to turn into that
$80 million exit in six months, we believe
this is a good chance to improve your odds.
People hearing this might feel like, I haven't
heard of any company doing this that has become
a trillion dollar IPO success. What would make
me believe that this is the process I should
follow versus just, I'm just going to do what I
hear on YC, just build it, launch it, iterate,
that kind of thing. What can you share to give
people confidence this is the approach to take?
Well, the first thing I'd say is give us some
time where we're pretty new to this. We started
Character Labs about three years ago. We created
the Foundation Sprint about three years ago.
But more seriously, when we were creating this
method, one of the things that we did was look
back across all the projects we've been involved
in and the ones that were really successful,
and we looked for patterns. And while those
teams didn't have the Foundation Sprint,
they ended up having really clear differentiation
and a really clear view of what made them unique
that they were able to build on. And as we
ran design sprints with them, we were able to
test and validate against that differentiation. So
we believe that this is sort of a key to success,
even if those teams didn't have
access to this exact same methodology.
So what I'm hearing is this
is essentially like Alpha in
starting a company. This is a new process
that companies are just starting to use.
You guys are working closely with founders,
and it's rooted in the success of many, many,
many companies that you guys were involved
in early on and continue to be involved in.
Yeah, it's based off of this thing we've
seen again and again in the most successful
projects. When we're inside the room in the early
days and we're seeing people make decisions,
this is what drives those decisions.
It's differentiation. And so if we look
back across all of the sprints that
we've been a part of over the years,
and John and I have been inside lots of
these rooms, lots of these conversations.
And if you're not watching on YouTube, by the
way, there's a cool visual that Jake is showing.
Yeah, it spans across Google, Google Ventures,
Character Capital, and if you're watching
on YouTube, you'll see all these little white
circles. And each one sort of represents a company
that we've seen inside of during these design
sprints. And there are a lot of really great
success stories in there. We've had the chance to
... I mentioned the story of Google Meet and being
there and figuring out what is it that's going to
make this thing stand out? That was what made the
project finally start to take off. And to this day
is still sort of what animates it. Being inside
of the early days of what became Google Photos or
Google Trips and some of the early design sprints,
and there are a lot of others on here.
But honestly, of course, we've also seen
inside a lot that it didn't work out. If we looked
inside the greatest hits though, the real smash
successes, we looked inside all of those. We
realized there is a common element, and that
common element in all of them is differentiation.
That there was clarity around this is what we're
trying to prove to customers, this is the promise
we're making. And so we've been on those teams,
or we've worked alongside those founders
who have this clear idea of differentiation.
And sometimes they're not right. They run the
experiments and they change it. But the thing is,
they're keyed into differentiation as being
crucial. They're not just thinking about the
product and trying to get the right shape of the
product or trying to make it usable or whatever.
They're really keyed in on differentiation and how
do we find the right promise and deliver on that
promise and express that promise to customers.
So to explain a little bit quickly of what I mean
by differentiation and how this has manifested in
products we've seen, if you go back to the early
days of Gmail in the 2000s, if you had email,
you were probably using Hotmail or Yahoo and it
worked fine and you didn't have to think about it.
And this new product comes along and you're like,
"God, I'm not going to want to switch my email
address. What a hassle. Who wants to do that? No
one." Gmail's promise was, hey, massive storage,
great search. And as we were building the product
out and marketing and explaining it to people and
making decisions inside the project, we had to
continue to deliver on great search. Great search,
great search, that was key to standing out.
You fast forward to 2014, and we're working with
this tiny company who's now competing with Gmail,
who's now sort of the market leader people are
used to using in their teams. And here's this
new messaging software called Slack, and they're
trying to reach new customers. And gosh, switching
to Slack is an even bigger hassle than switching
to your email address because everybody on the
team has to switch. Well, Slack says, "Hey, if you
believe that having fun and boosting teamwork is
important, it's going to be clear to you. This is
a new way of looking at the world." And when they
were making their decisions in their first big
ad campaign, their first big marketing campaign,
this was what they were trying to convey to
customers. So we kind of see that from the inside.
Another one, we didn't see this one from
the inside, but in one that we're all
sort of familiar with is what happened
with ChatGPT. It goes from this trusted,
I don't have to think about it, I'm going to
run a Google search. To, oh, wow. It's a new
way of looking at the world. There's zero clicks,
just tells you the answer. This thing's great.
This is also something that we've seen in
some of the early success stories from our
own portfolio. So 2019, this company called
Reclaim going after calendar management. And
most of us manage our own calendars, most
of us don't have administrators helping us
out with that. And it's free, we're in control.
Reclaim's argument was, hey, we can automatically,
we can use AI to help you focus and to
automatically prioritize your calendar. And
that animated enough people to take the plunge
and switch and try it out, that they were able
to build up an audience of tens of thousands
of users, and Dropbox acquired them last year.
A great answer to my question, you
guys well-prepared for those skeptics.
Part of our motivation, our selfish motivation
with this Foundation Sprint is that now that we
are investing our own money into companies
and we're working with all these founders,
we want them to have that same clarity on
differentiation. We saw how important that
was to Gmail and to Slack and to all these
other companies. And we want to bring that,
we want to give them that same advantage
and help them avoid the pitfalls that all
the other unsuccessful teams and companies
that we've seen have fallen into. So that's
kind of what we're trying to do here,
is bring the lessons from these really
successful teams into any team that
reads the book and runs this process.
And the special sauce that John and I bring
is that we're obsessed with the sequence of
decisions that you make and how you work together
with your team to make good decisions quickly.
And that specificity about the method is something
that we do have a lot of evidence behind it
working well because of what's happened with the
design sprint and with how many successful teams
have run that at those companies who are trillion
dollar or whatever kind of giant ... all kinds of
teams run design sprints. This is that same
methodology around how we work together at
high velocity and high quality. And it's just
brought to a different part of the process.
Excellent answer. Speaking of the method,
we went on the world's most epic tangent. I
want to bring us back. We haven't finished
actually going through the process. I think
we're towards the tail end of it. So let's
just finish that. What else do you do? So
you have this ... I guess, catch us up.
Let's catch up with Latch It. So as a refresher
for you who forgot. Latch It are building this
tool for artisans, they want to help them
sell with the community networking features
like you might find on Substack. And
they've identified their differentiation,
they've identified their approach now
using magic lenses. And all of this is
going to come together to create a founding
hypothesis. So if we help Artisans solve
online sales growth with a social sales app,
and then they've also got their backup plan.
Or we could-
A social sales app. Then, they've also got their
backup plan, or we could build the full stack
solution if that doesn't work. We believe
they're going to choose it over Shopify and
Etsy because our solution is cooperative
and easy to use. In this single sentence,
we've laid bare their strategy, and now they're
going to try to find out does that work?
That is so cool. The output of the
sprint is the founding hypothesis.
I love that the term hypothesis
is a part of this because it's
not telling you this will work. It's
this is the thing you will now test.
Absolutely. Every project has at its core ...
Every new product has at its core a hypothesis.
There is a founding hypothesis. It's just
usually not explicit. It's usually hidden,
and different people on the team may
have different ideas about what it is.
Because it's not explicit, it's
very hard to interrogate it and
test it and find out if the different
variables in it are the right variables.
I'm curious what's in that photo to the
right as you're showing the YouTube.
Oh, yeah, if you're on YouTube. We did this
spread together in person. On Lachit's board,
you're going to see that here's where they wrote
it out and took a photo of it and dropped it in,
and then later filled it out on the Miro board.
Beautiful. It has their old name there there.
That's right. Yeah. Yeah.
Every brand that.
Lyric, which it turns out is not the easiest for
SEO. There's a lot of lot of Lyrics out there.
There is a lot of Lyrics. I know
some Lyrics. Just so I understand,
is the next step, the design sprint, and
that's where you actually start testing?
Exactly. If we zoom out now we see now they're
going to head into a sequence of design sprints
running one after another. Each of those design
sprints starts with the founding hypothesis.
Then, the team is going to say, "Okay,
what are the biggest risks that ... That
hypothesis not being true? What
do we need to assess right now?"
Going to make a map of how customers discover the
product, what that core experience looks like,
and then figure out using that map, where's
the key moment for assessing that risk?
For them, the biggest risk is do people even ...
Will these artisans even want this thing? Are
they actually going to want to have a community
sharing sales platform? They decide the key moment
for us to test that, it's actually on the landing
page. They figure we can prototype landing pages
that describe the product and learn a lot for
our first experiment, just with landing pages.
They're going to sketch solutions. This
will be familiar to anyone who's heard
about design sprints. Each person sketching
their own proposal for how that key moment
should work. Choose the strongest of those.
In this case, they choose ... They're going
to actually prototype three things. They test
three things head-to-head against each other,
fake brands for each one. They
look like three different products.
Then, this is a really key part. At the end of
the design sprint, we've got a scorecard. This
is actually a new innovation. This
is not in the [inaudible 01:20:54].
Oh, shit. Here we go. Hot off the
presses, design sprint improvement.
This scorecard is going to break down the founding
hypothesis. Hey, as we talk to each customer,
was this the right person? Is the right kind of
customer for us? Do they have the problem that we
think they have? Was this the right approach for
them? Did they choose it over the competition?
They're going to test these prototypes
head-to-head, and also show people like,
okay, here's Etsy, here's Shopify. Now, out of
all these five options, think about, out loud,
about how do you compare these? Do we believe
they'd actually choose it? Did the differentiation
actually work? Are those differentiators
valuable and motivating to them? Does it click?
Our new book is called Click. The idea there is
you can see when a product clicks with one person,
and that's a helpful signal. Now, granted, these
interviews are kind of a simulation. It's not like
the real world, but they're a helpful signal that
we're on track for product market fit. If we see,
gosh, this product just seems to be clicking
with customer after customer, that's a really
strong signal. That's when people start to
get the confidence that it's time to build.
That's a really good term, by the
way. I feel that's such a good way
to describe what it feels like.
It doesn't just click with them.
Just kind of clicks. Yeah. If you
look across Latchet's first scorecard,
there's a ton of red. It's a
lot of things that didn't work.
[inaudible 01:22:17].
The conclusion at the end ... In this
last column, there's a conclusion, hey,
we interviewed ... In this case, they interviewed
four customers. Well, it looks like this is the
right customer. It looks like they have this
problem, but everything else kind of didn't work
about the hypothesis. Approach wasn't working,
differentiation wasn't working. There's some
mini hypotheses about the prototype itself. Just
lots of red on here, so they sprint again and-
Just zooming out for a second, this is a team
who just started working on this new company.
Sometimes it can feel slow. We talked about
it feeling slow to go through all these steps,
but they're only a week in. They've already
built three prototypes, and they've tested
those three prototypes with four real customers.
They have this super detailed scorecard of here's
what's working, here's what's not working. That's
after a week. It's interesting how what can feel
slow in the hour to hour actually can really
speed you up in the weeks and months timescale.
That was such good context, because I
was feeling that. To your point, most
founders do not do this much testing, iterating,
learning in the first few weeks of their startup.
Yeah. They might spend a few weeks just talking
to customers without showing a prototype,
and then they might spend a few months building an
MVP, and then they might ... Maybe they're going
to spend some more time talking to customers
while showing them the MVP. Maybe they'll do
manual onboarding, something like that.
Yeah, that plays out over months. It fits
with what founders tell us. Of course it's a
subjective measure, but founders who go through
this process with us, they say that they're able
to accelerate three to four months of work into
the three or four weeks back-to-back sprints
that we're doing together in Character Labs.
Excellent context. Thanks
for throwing that in there.
These conversations with customers are so much
more fruitful and pointed when you've got the
context of I know exactly what my hypothesis
is and you have prototypes to show them.
We have a founder in our group of startups and
Character Labs at the moment. I'm thinking of
Maruthi John who comes from doing sales at
Rippling, who had been talking to tons of
customers while starting off the ... His company.
He said, "I've had 50 conversations over the past
month, but I learned so much more from even the
first conversation when I had a hypothesis and I
had a prototype, or a couple prototypes,
to show them. It's like night and day."
That is a great example. This all
makes sense. As you guys describe it,
you're actually testing something very
concrete that your entire team is aligned
behind and actual prototypes, and you've
thought about different directions. You're
testing something very specific versus just
generally testing at your general concept.
As we go into the second design sprint
for Latchet, they're making some edits
to their founding hypothesis. Now, they're
revising a few things, making new sketches,
new proposals for what this solution might look
like. They've learned a lot in that first sprint,
a new prototype. They've got a prototype that
has more detail now. They are engineers. They're
starting to actually write some code and put some
more detail behind the product. It's more robust.
Again, they're trying to fix that positioning.
Here's their scorecard. If you're watching on
YouTube, you'll be able to see it. Again,
there's a lot of red here. At first blush,
the scorecard is bleeding, but there are
some promising signs. There's like maybe a
few little sunbreaks, there's some spots where
some of the red has started to flip to yellow.
If we look at the conclusion on the far
right, they're starting to believe their
differentiation is dialed in, and they're
starting to believe that this could be the
right approach. They may be able to get
people to choose it to the competition,
even though they haven't done it yet. Those are
starting to become yellow lights on the scorecard.
Now they'll take what they've learned, and
now we're into the third consecutive week of
design sprints. Again, they're going to sort
of review that founding hypothesis. They're
going to sketch. They're recruiting a new slate of
customers, as they do each week. A new prototype,
again, more code in the prototype.
It's becoming more and more robust,
more realistic as they're also adjusting the
marketing and the positioning at the same time.
All of these things kind of go in concert.
The product itself and the marketing are
sort of one as they're moving along,
and this is an extreme example of-
What? [inaudible 01:26:48]. Everything is green.
Everything's green.
[inaudible 01:26:50].
If you can't see it, every single one is green.
Oh my god.
This is extreme, but it is
a pattern that we've seen.
This is real.
Again and again. This is a real example.
Wow. How do I invest to get us
in this round? This is great.
Yes, this is pretty great.
This is great. Nice job.
We see this again and again. I can share a
couple of other boards of ones that are in
progress. We're also constantly adjusting
the template so you can get to see a
little bit more how people will edit their
founding hypothesis from sprint to sprint.
Mellow, who we were talking about, here's
their first prototype, and here's their first
scorecard. Lots of yellow for them. Maybe they're
a little bit more likely to use yellow than red.
Then, here's the edits to their founding
hypothesis after the first sprint. You can
kind of see in red, they're slightly changing
the definition of their target customer from
the first week, slightly changing the problem that
they're solving, slightly changing the approach,
slightly changing the competition.
They've dialed in, they've gotten
more crisp on who are we up against.
They've gotten a little bit more crisp,
just a tiny tweak, on what ... How do we
explain this to people to get them excited
about it? What's the differentiation? They
sprint again, they prototype again. If we
just jump down, and just looking at hypotheses,
they learn a bunch. Now there's another slight
tweak to that founding hypothesis. Week
after week you're learning, but you're
also really able to track exactly what is it that
we learned and how does that affect our strategy.
Okay, guys, this was incredible. I think we've
covered the entire process. I love that you
also covered the design sprint pieces, which
isn't part of this book, but is such a core.
Clearly these things are very connected and meant
to work together. You go from here's the thing we
should be building to how to actually test it.
Let me ask you before we wrap up, is there
anything else that you think is really important
for people to know before they start trying this
process at home? Is there anything you can
point them to actually try this at home?
One thing we didn't talk about, we used
an example of a company who's not building
an AI-first product. Latchet's building this
network community sales platform for artisans.
It'd probably be interesting to look at how
people use this when they are building a very
technical product, when they're vibe coding
prototypes. That's a question we're getting
all the time. What's the influence on this of
the speed with which you can build something?
That's an awesome idea. Let's definitely do that.
Yeah. Okay. Let's jump in here and take a look
at a company again, in our current group of labs
teams, Axion Orbital it's called. The founder,
[inaudible 01:29:30], is actually running this
whole process solo, which is pretty cool too.
He's a remarkable guy. We have a couple of solo
founders right now who are able to generate ...
You can see, just to give a sneak peek,
he's generating, when we talk about customers,
all these sticky notes himself and making the
decisions himself about which is the right one.
To ground us in this story, his founding
hypothesis is he wants to help geospatial
devs solve these sort of complex workflows
with a browser-based no-code development
environment. We'll take a look just really
quickly at what his prototypes look like.
In the first week ... I can show you
this prototype right here, and it's a
marketing page. On this marketing page,
there's a link to a video. If I click find out
more, I'm going to see this video. This video
is going to kind of hear [inaudible 01:30:27]
talking over it. It's going to kind of walk
through a screen share of a very rudimentary
version of what this product might look like.
Now, if you're watching on YouTube and you
see this prototype, you might think, "Boy,
that marketing page and the demo itself, pretty
bare bones. Not the most polished-looking. This
doesn't look super compelling."
He was focusing in that first sprint
on the messaging, on finding those people who
actually have that role, testing it with them,
and he learned a lot. If we sort of go
back to his scorecard, we'll see, okay,
that was a pretty good one. Actually, a lot
of green on his first scorecard, but he also
felt like what he tested was pretty incomplete.
Now, one thing that's cool here, we saw the big
leap with Latchet from one week to another in
terms of their learnings and the scorecards.
One of the things that's interesting here
is to go from [inaudible 01:31:19]'s first
prototype here to his second prototype.
It's obvious he's been able to just build
a ton in the next week. He's using AI-based
tools. He's doing a lot of work. He's also
just a terrific engineer. Here we've got a much
more real-looking marketing page, very detailed.
An important thing that he's done here with
this is he's built out a lot and created a
video of something so that the product, while
not fully functional, you can see exactly how
it works. If we sort of play this video, he's
created this demonstration of what it looks
like when you type in a query into the engine
and exactly the kinds of results you get. By
doing a combination of vibe coding, real coding,
all of which is based off of pencil sketches,
we can go back and see the sketches he's doing
on paper to define this is what I think needs to
be in there to make this compelling to deliver on
my differentiation, and then he's using a product
video so that the entire thing doesn't have to
work fully freeform. That's what it can look
like when a team is building something that's more
AI-centric, when it's a more sophisticated tool,
when people are going to be curious
about sort of the ins and outs of it.
Along those lines, where do
you find people are leveraging
AI most in helping them through these
sprints, through either the foundation
sprint or the design sprint? Is it
mostly just vibe coding prototypes?
That's definitely the first and biggest use of
AI in sprints so far is in making prototypes
that look more realistic faster. It's kind
of like having an entire prototyping team
on standby so that you don't have to just make
it yourself and sort of piece things together,
but you can have a ton of people ready to
jump in, make something look really realistic.
It's also really critical we found that while
you're outsourcing that prototyping work,
you don't outsource the thinking. You don't kind
of skip over the part where you think about,
"Well, what is the actual copy on the website?
How do I actually describe what the product is,
how it's differentiated?" It's
one of the reasons why doing the
foundation sprint first and then doing
a design sprint can really help you,
because it allows you to spend time
working on that harder part of what
it means to design and build a product.
Then, once you have a clear view of that,
then you can use AI tools to go really
fast. In this example that Jake is showing
of Axion Orbital, people get really clever
about which parts of this need to be real,
which parts of this can be vibe coded, which
parts of this can just be a static Figma mockup.
It's all about kind of creating a simulation,
something that looks realistic, that you can
put in front of real customers to
help you answer the key questions.
That's a really good point that you're
making. Again, it's just a reminder,
you'll move faster if you slow down a little
bit at the beginning, that because prototyping
is so easy now and just things that look
... It's so easy to make something that
looks really nice and kind of it's doing what
you want, but spending a little time making
sure you understand what you're testing
and what you want becomes more important.
We had a couple of teams in this current group of
Character Labs where they jumped to vibe coding
prototypes right away at the very beginning.
When you generate something using an LLM,
using an AI tool, it looks pretty real. It looks
believable. I think there's a temptation to say,
"Okay, this is good to go. It looks close enough
that I'm just going to show that to customers."
Then what they found was, actually, it was
super generic. It didn't really describe
what the product was. It didn't really describe
how it was different because it was generated
by a model that is trained on existing products.
In that second sprint, that was when they really
took a step back and said, "Okay, let's think
through this and then shift into prototyping
mode." It's definitely helping people speed up,
but we also think there's an important lesson here
that while you're outsourcing prototyping,
don't outsource the thinking as well.
I see you pulling something
up, Jake, that might be ...
Yeah.
I imagine you want to show.
Yeah, I think it's kind of interesting to see the
sketches that went into [inaudible 01:35:40]'s
prototype, the Axion Orbital prototype that we
just looked at, because they are super detailed.
This is ... Doing this level of thought where
you're pausing, you're being really intentional
about what does the customer need to know,
what needs to happen for them to find a
solution to their problem and within the product,
that's a way of doing your prompt engineering.
If you end up vibe coding this prototype, but
you start off with a very clear plan about this
is what the thing needs to look like, rather
than going immediately into a conversational
mode where you're co-designing with the LLM
and going back and forth via chat conversation,
this is much likelier to yield an opinionated
product that makes sense, that's very clearly
defined around the problem that you're trying
to solve, the tasks that need to happen to
solve that problem, and the right messaging,
the right wording. It's really crisply aligned
with what you know about your customers,
what you know about what they care about.
That's such a good point. Again, just the
concept of the primal mark is ringing in my
head as you talk about this. Just as soon as you
make that prototype, everything from that point
is a response to that first idea, versus have
I actually thought through what this should be.
Guys, we did it. This is incredible. I think
this is going to help a lot of people think
through and actually save a lot of time. Is
there anything else that you want to share,
leave listeners with? Maybe a last
nugget or something you want to,
I don't know, just double down on to
leave folks with before we wrap up.
Well, one quick thing is that we've shared a lot
of examples in this conversation. We actually have
a template, a Miro template, that folks can use
if they want to run their own foundation sprint.
It's the template that we use
when we're working with founders,
taking them through these sprints. We do our
work in Miro. Even if we're in person with them,
we're usually working in Miro, or maybe working
on paper and then capturing it in Miro because
it's just such a great canvas to work on.
We'll make that template available so anybody
who's listening or watching can grab that and
use it to run their own foundation sprint.
That's amazing. You answered the question I asked
that I forgot to come back to. Can we give people
a URL? Put it in the show notes, but is it at
your ... Yeah, I guess where can folks find it?
You should find it at character.vc. You can go
there and we'll have a page for you to ... Yeah.
Amazing. So easy. That is awesome. That's
awesome that you guys are doing that.
Obviously you could also read the book.
That goes through a lot of this process,
but I think the template is just like a
plug and play. Let's just do this at home.
Obviously, if they want to go deeper, they
can work with you guys to have you ... It's
such a win. They take money. You give them
money and you help them figure out what
the heck to build. What a deal. That's also
character.vc if they want to explore that.
Yeah. Yep.
Amazing. Okay. Is there anything else, Jake,
that you wanted to share before we close up?
No, just if you made it this far, hopefully
your mind and heart is open to this idea,
but we know it's a lot to ask, to clear the
calendar and follow these steps. If John and
I weren't so convinced that beginnings are
essential to getting your best efforts in
the hands of people and to achieving the things
you want for your customers, we wouldn't be doing
this. We wouldn't be going to all the trouble.
There are simpler things we could be going after.
The kind of cool thing we've found
about working in this way, though,
we've focused a lot on finding product market
fit and building your business, getting started,
getting momentum, getting alignment, all these
things that tactically are important, that
business-wise are important, but another part of
it that's a nice side benefit, that actually maybe
is the most important thing of all, is how close
it brings you to your customers, to the people who
you're building for. Because you're interacting
with them, you're focusing on them as you plan
and you're interacting with them on a weekly basis
when you work in this way, and how close it brings
teammates together in a very authentic way.
We're working together on the most important
things. We don't have to navigate the usual social
dynamics of conversations where one person has an
idea and they're pitching it. We don't have
to navigate the constant context switches
of the calendar that dominates our days.
We're just working on the most important
thing. The structure takes care of a lot
of the difficulty of the process of what
we should do. We just find people come out of
it with renewed motivation, renewed energy,
and renewed enthusiasm around the fact that they
get to work on what actually matters to them.
Yeah. It just feels like really fun. Just this
part of the process is so fun, and then not having
to decide how to approach it, having someone
just give you here's a framework to follow.
It's like a yoga class, right? It's like,
I don't know how to do yoga, but ...
Just tell me.
Explain to me step by step.
Yoga for startups.
Yeah.
That'll be the title for this episode.
[inaudible 01:40:39].
Guys, this was awesome. I'm going to skip the
lightning round just because we've gone long.
Cool.
I guess just where can folks find you
online? How can listeners be useful to you?
You can find me on LinkedIn. John [inaudible
01:40:51] find you on LinkedIn, too.
Yeah.
[inaudible 01:40:54].
We'd love for people to apply to
Character Labs, or if a founder,
apply to Character Labs. Get
in touch with us, character.vc.
There we go. All right, guys, thank you
so much for being here and for sharing.
Yeah, thanks, Lenny.
Thanks, Lenny.
Bye, everyone. Thank you so much for
listening. If you found this valuable,
you can subscribe to the show on Apple
Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us
a rating or leaving a review,
as that really helps other listeners
find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
Lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.