In six months, he went from zero,
basically nothing to selling this company
for 80 million plus dollars to Wix.
The funny thing is that Base44 for the
first time in my life was not trying
to build the biggest thing ever. Me and my
girlfriend, we were on a plane. I told her,
"Hey, you know what? If we get to
1.5 million until the end of 2025,
we're going to buy a nice car,"
and we got there in four weeks.
I feel like the journey that
you've been on over the last
six months is like the dream for a lot of
founders. How long were you actually solo?
The first person started a month and a half
before the acquisition, so I think it's a
different ballgame because even if you're solo,
you are literally managing teams of AI's writing
code. I don't think I've written a single line
of HTML or JavaScript in the past three months.
You're competing against
very well-funded companies,
Lovable, Bolt, Replit, Vercel,
and you get your first 10 users.
I started with three users, really close friends.
I got them to sit down with me every other day
around the table and they would use that,
the tool. They'll try to build something,
it'll break. I'll take a look and then just
build it for them. I'm not going to try and
scale anything before I know that users
enjoy it and the best metric to seeing
them enjoying it is that they're
starting to share it with someone.
Today, my guest is Maor Shlomo. This is a unique
episode because I almost never have conversations
with early stage founders. I made an exception
because Maor's journey is in many ways the dream
for a lot of founders. Maor started a company
called Base44, which is essentially a more
advanced vibe coding tool. Six months later,
just a few weeks ago, he sold the company for
$80 million to Wix. He's a sole founder. It was
just him for most of those six months. He never
raised any money. He bootstrapped it and built it
purely off profits. When he launched it on Product
Hunt, it got so much love that the Product Hunt
algorithm thought that it was bots when it was
really just people from all over the world wanting
to support the product. In our conversation, Maor
shares exactly how he grew the product from zero
to 10 to 100 to hundreds of thousands of users.
His tech stack that allowed him to move so fast,
tools that he uses to be super productive as a
sole founder with severe ADHD. Also, the super
important insight that everyone needs to hear
about how he came up with the idea and then
refine the idea. Also, just a bunch of common
growth tactics that he tried that didn't work
for him and some key advice for anyone looking
to start their own bootstrapped company. A
big thank you to Noam Segal and Amir Klein
for suggesting topics for this conversation. If
you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting app
or YouTube. With that, I bring you Maor Shlomo.
This episode is brought to you by Sauce. The way
teams turn feedback into product impact is stuck
in the past, vague reports, static taxonomies,
unactionable insights that don't move business
metrics. The result, churn, lost deals, missed
growth. Sauce is the AI product co-pilot that
helps CPOs and product teams uncover business
impact and act faster. It listens to your sales
calls, support tickets, churn reasons, and lost
deals, surfacing the biggest product issues,
opportunities in real time. It then routes them
to the right teams to turn signals into PRDs,
prototypes, and even code that drives revenue
retention and adoption. That's why Whatnot,
Linktree, Incident.io and Zip use Sauce. One
enterprise uncovered a product gap that unlocked
$16 million ARR. Another caught a spiking
issue and prevented millions in churn.
You can too at sauce.app/lenny. Sauce, built
for AI product teams. Don't get left behind.
This episode is brought to you by Dscout.
Design Teams today are expected to move fast,
but also to get it right. That's where Dscout
comes in. Dscout is the all-in-one research
platform built for modern product and design
teams. Whether you're running usability tests,
interviews, surveys, or in the wild field work,
Dscout makes it easy to connect with real users
and get real insights fast. You can even test your
Figma prototypes directly inside the platform. No
juggling tools, no chasing ghost participants,
and with the industry's most trusted panel plus
AI-powered analysis, your team gets clarity and
confidence to build better without slowing down.
So if you're ready to streamline your research,
speed of decisions and design with impact, head to
dscout.com to learn more. That's D-S-C-O-U-T.
The answers you need to move confidently.
Maor, thank you so much for being
here. Welcome to the podcast.
I'm so excited to do that.
Thank you for having me, Lenny.
It's my pleasure. I don't actually do
conversations like this often with early stage
founders, but I'm really excited to be doing this
because I feel like the journey that you've been
on over the last six months is kind of like the
dream for a lot of founders, especially founders
that don't want to build massive teams, that
don't want to raise a ton of money. Basically the
journey you've been on is build a product. People
loved it. It grew like crazy. You didn't raise
any money. You sold it for $80 million, we'll talk
about this six months in. And I know it's not all
rainbows and butterflies and this amazing happy
moment to moment all day, but I know it's a lot of
hard work, but this is just what a lot of people
want to achieve when they start a company and
you're just in the thick of it right now. You've
just announced your acquisition. So I feel like
this is a really unique point in time to extract
as much wisdom out of your head as possible.
Really the right time to reflect back.
Yeah, I think there's going to
be many more times. This is a
really unique time. Let's start with a
couple of basics just what is Base44 for
folks that aren't super familiar
with the product that you built?
Base44 is an AI app building platform, meaning
that you are able to use natural language to
describe what you want to build, an app, a game,
a website or something like that, and then have AI
code it for you. We're not the first ones doing
that. I think it's a very crowded category, but
I think Base44 takes a very different approach,
a very opinionated one for and one that users
or users like to call it a batteries included
approach, which means that for every app that
you build in Base44, you already have built-in
included database, integrations, user management,
analytics without connecting third party services
or bringing your API keys and so on. And I think
it helps a lot when you're trying to scale a
vibe coded application to be very complex and
very functional. So yeah, I think for most of the
category nowadays they're doing a fantastic job.
One with building React web apps like
front-end web apps and then when a user needs
some backend stuff, they have a great integration
with Supabase. Supabase I think is the most
common thing that most competitors use. And
honestly, all of them are doing a great job
with the integration, but as the nature of an
integration, I think it's potentially slightly
less strong than building everything full
stack. And once we did that, and actually
I engineered the endpoints and the SDKs and
whatever to work well with LLMs, I think
Base44 does a really good job with building very
complex and functional real world applications.
I want to talk about the origin story of just how
you even realized that there was an opportunity
here. Clearly it worked out. But before we
get there, let me just share a couple stats
about this journey to give people a sense of just
how crazy this is and add anything I'm missing.
So in six months you went from zero, basically
nothing to selling this company for 80 million
plus dollars to Wix, took you three weeks to
hit a million dollars ARR, you bootstrapped
this business. I think you put in a few tens
of thousands of shekels, not even US dollars.
You have something like 400,000 users right
now. You're still a founder. There are two
different wars involved in the journey. You're
based in Israel, so you have to deal with that
and we're going to talk about some of the
stories. Any other stats that are worth
sharing? Anything else that's important high
level before we get into the origin story?
No, I don't think so. I think looking back,
it sounds insane, but mostly this is it.
I love that perspective.
Okay, so how did this start?
There were two things I think that drove me to
it. One, my girlfriend needed a website to capture
leads. She has a small business, she's an artist.
And I tried building that with one of the tools
out there for website building, not an AI powered
one. And it was such a pain trying to do that one,
designing with the drag and drop and everything
and then things get messed up in mobile and you
try again. It's like and then how do you manage
your data and so on. And in my previous company,
we dealt a lot with LLMs. While I was
doing that, I was like, "It doesn't any
sense." I know models can write the code to
do exactly what I'm trying to do right now.
Build a website for my girlfriend or builds
slightly more complicated than a website was
actually a web app. I know models can do that.
They don't have the right infrastructure to do
that. So if I set up an infrastructure for like,
"Hey, here the leads go to the database like okay,
you can write React code and it'll solve it and
it'll be great from an SEO perspective and so on,"
then I'll notice like it's going to be super
easy and she could do it on her own. And the
other trigger, I was volunteering to help with the
Scouts organization here in Israel with everything
that has to do with system and software and back
office systems that they needed. And back then,
it's a huge organization by the way, really huge
tens of thousands of people and they have many as
any other organization in the world that we're
constantly living at has many software needs.
And so every time they needed to build something,
they didn't have any internal devs, any software
engineers. So they reach out to other agencies and
agencies usually would quote them like a million
bucks just to build something that they knew
people could build. I was, and still by the way,
a huge fan of tools like Retool for the previous
wave of no-code tools, but then those tools were
really more of low code tools. You still needed
to know some JavaScript, something to make them
work to have the interruption. And again, also
back then I was like, I know for the software and
systems that they want to build, I know it could
be done. It's just LLMs can write that and we can
really empower the organization to build all the
different tools that they want, just give it the
right setting, the right infrastructure so that
LLM has access to a database, maybe to another
LLM to be the app on top of AI, to have some user
management to have all those kind of things that
it needs, but it can translate the user needs to
actual code. So those two were triggers back then.
I started a company seven years ago called
Explorium, very different than Base44, very
much like enterprise top-down sales in the data
space, very capital heavy. We raised $130 million.
I was a CEO for seven years. Then when the October
7th wall broke out, I went to reserves for almost
a year. And then when I came out, I went to
travel the world a bit just to take some time
off and wanted to do what I was liked the most and
I haven't had a chance because Explorium grew and
grew and haven't had a chance for a while to do,
which is coding. I wanted to get back to building
and get my hands dirty. And so I had given those
experiences both with my partner, my girlfriend,
and also with the scouts. I was like, "Let's
take a shot at it and start the product that
I know is going to be very fun to build."
And I think when you are approaching it
this way and not the usual way of let's raise
a ton of money and try to own the category,
and I knew I'm always getting into a very crowded
category. I also knew that I have some different
angle and some different take on the category,
but when you're approaching it this way,
there's not a lot to lose and I think it gives
a lot of energy and that's how Base44 started.
I definitely didn't think it's going to take off
so fast. But yeah, that's pretty much about it.
Okay, I like that you don't take it for the
work you did to help it take off so fast. I'm
excited to talk through that. Just first a few
maybe takeaways from what you just shared of how
this idea emerged for folks that are looking for
ideas. One is clearly we're solving somebody's
real problem, your own problem, helping your
girlfriend build this website for her and then
working with the scouts program in Israel,
basically building them software. So I think
that's a really important takeaway. You weren't
just like, "Hey, maybe this will be useful to
someone." It's a real problem and I want to
solve it and nothing out there is good enough
so I'm going to build it myself. The other is you
said that you're having fun feels like that's an
important element, just like you should enjoy it.
You shouldn't feel like it's some kind of drag.
You know what? I feel like when I was a first
timer, when I first started my first company,
Explorium, it sounds like many smart people
told me those two very important truths. It's
build something that you would want to use or
that you'll actually use and make sure that
throughout time you keep doing something that
you really like. And so when you first timer,
or at least for myself when I hear
those kind of things, I was like, "Yeah,
those are cliches businesses is always important.
Let's increase revenue, let's close more deals."
And I feel like even though it sounds like
a cliche, it's so much easier one building
something that you'll actually use. So I actually
tried solving both problems like I was building
the product and at the same time developing those
two products for my girlfriend, for the scout,
and later on also for friends and Family.
And we'll get to that. That's how I got my
first couple of users. But super important to
build something that you'll use, you'll move
forward so much faster, but also doing something
that you love. I think I was the CEO of exploring
for seven years. It was such a fantastic
experience. It had so many highs and lows,
but at some point it grew and it took me too
much time to realize that what I really like
doing is just building products and scaling
products and not necessarily being a CEO,
managing sales, managing HR, managing, all
those kind of things. And I think that gives
a lot of power. It's easier to work very hard
when you're doing something you really like.
Let's follow that thread and talk about being a
solo founder. I think this is something a lot of
founders like it's hard to find a co-founder
that out of the blue when you have an idea,
YC famously doesn't like solo founders. So I
think there's a lot of power in what you've
achieved. Let me just ask you first of all, any
I guess lessons about being a solo founder that
you think would be helpful for other people
considering starting a company on their own?
And also just how do you stay productive? How do
you get stuff done as a solo founder using AI?
One solo founder and specifically bootstrapping,
I don't think it's suitable for every use case.
If you're building a B2B company, especially
if you're doing a B to enterprise company,
you'll need to hire a salesperson or sales team.
You need to spend your money on marketing. It's
going to be very hard to try to sell to your
company when you are on your own and nobody knows
if the product's going to stay there tomorrow.
So I don't think it's the right setting for
every company. I feel like if you're building
something that has the potential to be viral
or to target the masses, and so it doesn't really
matter if you're funded or not, you just build a
great product that people will share. If you're
able to do that and you're able to get out of the
escape velocity of getting to product market fit,
then everything is better doing a solo bootstrap
than the other way around. One else, even from
a pure cold angle of the financial outcome.
Obviously if you're able to
bootstrap your business and again,
get out of the [inaudible 00:16:32] velocity and
be profitable to some degree, then you'll likely
generate a financial outcome. That's I think
for most cases, way better than any other thing.
Second is not specifically the solo, but the
bootstrapping thing less stressful. You wake up
in the morning as you feel profitable, and I think
there's this term default alive. It's so much
easier. I've done both and the weight of raising
so much fund, even if your investors are great,
my investors were awesome and they were always
supportive and so on. But even so, I feel like
being bootstrap, like no other money except of
yours in the business and the business is going
and profitable, I feel I can keep the energies up.
And I think one thing that I've learned from my
previous company is energies are super important.
Usually it's a marathon. For me, it was a sprint.
I thought it's going to be a marathon, but
you want to do something that you like for
years and years. And if you're able to show up
every day, your chances goes up immediately.
But then there's a lot of downside and a
lot of stressful moments during that. One,
just keeping the self go up, keeping the
servers up. When you're solo, you don't
have a DevOps team, you don't have on-call, you
don't have anything I think is really tough.
I had a few accidents that really, I'm joking
about that, but I was saying it to my friends,
shorten my life a bit with just the stress. I had
one funny, now I look at it as a funny moment,
where I was at my brother's wedding and we were
doing the photo shoots and I was actually the one
actually was supposed to also do the ceremony and
then doing the photo shoots. I have a friend from
MIT calls me up and he's like, " Hey, somebody
hacked into Base44 and it's like a crypto scam
and you've got to take care of that because
people are building apps on top of Base44
and they're putting the data inside and so on."
And I remember hanging up the phone, I was like,
"Okay, I'll take a look at it immediately."
I remember hanging up the phone and saying,
"It's karma. I know for a fact it's true. Somebody
probably hacked into that because what are the
chances that on the only night that I'm not able
to open up a laptop and handle that, this is what
happens." And so I threw out there some excuse and
I have to go and practice towards the ceremony or
something like that, open up a laptop, spend two
hours, two very scary hours of my life. It ended
up being just the LLM tried using a package called
cryptography, which is a Node.js like a JavaScript
package, has nothing to do with crypto, but
obviously the user, not a technical user,
saw this error of like, "Hey, something
cryptography or something like that was sure,
someone like a crypto scam hacked into the app."
And so you have a lot of those moments that
the whole thing is like you are not able to
share it with anyone. Share the burden even
or the stress or put anyone on top of it and
say, "Hey, you know what? I'm out for today.
You handle that." In my previous company, my
two co-founders, we were really good friends,
great friends. And even if one of us would mess
up, then still would have someone to share it
with and run jokes around and just be there
with someone. So when you're solo, it's hard.
And then brutal prioritization, which is
something you have to do because you have
to keep up the pace of the product. And obviously
nowadays with AI and everyone can build software,
you have to go extremely fast on one side and
on the other side figure out marketing along
the way and how to do that. And every time, I
remember that every time I had this ceremony
where I'd start a day and try look inside and ask
myself, "What do I need to work on today and what
do I want to work on today?" So what I want
to work on today, it was always like I want a
code. That's what I like to do. Let's improve the
product. I know there's a bug that makes a noise,
some of the users, I noticed the feature that's in
my head that I'm saying, "Oh, competitions haven't
thought about that. I have to build it. I have to
put it out there to be in front of everything."
And then it's like what do have to do today? So
at many different stages on Base44's journey,
it was I know I can improve the product a lot, but
I need to do some more marketing. I know this is
not the bottleneck. I know people are converting
well, they're growing, retention is looking good,
and it's all about just increasing the audience,
even though I really want to work on the product.
And so I think it is like this contact switching
is hard. And the last piece obviously is I was
spending a lot of my time on making sure that my
setup, like how I code, how I write content and so
on is optimized and everything is automated.
And so I spent a lot of time thinking and
agonizing about how to structure the code
repository, for example, so that I can use
[inaudible 00:22:14] for backend and Base44 for
front-end to write light code really fast. And
this was really important for me to keep trying to
find out new ways of how to automate and increase
the pace of building solo. Because if you're able
to correct that, I feel like smaller teams with a
lot of context nowadays can move faster.
And the same goes also for marketing and
for other tools where you want to automate as
much as you can, especially when you're solo,
because time is going to be the thing that kills
your business if you're not managing it right.
Okay, let me follow that thread.
That's a really interesting topic.
So what is in your stack of productivity for
yourself that allowed you to build Base44?
... for yourself and then that allowed you to
build Base44, just like the tech stack of Base44.
So you said Cursor, Base44. What else did you
use day-to-day that helped you be more efficient?
So I have severe ADHD, and so it can also be like
a superpower. But then you have to like, first,
the first thing you want to do is make sure that
your workday looks that you can be focused and
that you get a lot of like deep work and so. I use
a product called RescueTime, which I really like,
but I think there's a bunch of other products
like shuts down every access to Twitter and
LinkedIn and so on. This was really hard because
I was starting to do this build in public, which
turned out to work pretty well for Base44. And so
every time you want to take a look at your post
or see how many likes and impressions and so on,
but then you can't work on anything else. And so
I had this first setup that really
allowed me a certain set of software
tools that I can use to manage kind of deep work.
[inaudible 00:24:12] has been awesome. Base44,
not only did the work for the front end side, but
also a lot of the business apps that I used, well,
on top of Base44, so where I'd manage users
and give credits and where write content.
And then I had this app where I, kind of at the
start of the week, would write some high-level
content ideas. And then the Base44 app will take
it and break it down just to kind of something
that sounds more like me for a LinkedIn post,
and then I'd approve that and then it would break
it down to like a Twitter post. And so I wrote
things that were really customized to my process
and what I wanted to do, which really helped.
But I think you can do that not only with Base44,
where just you can vibe code your way into
like productivity tools that really fits
what you want to do and what the process for
you looks like. So again, for example for my
social posts and so on, there's like a
process that I would follow and maybe no
one else would follow that. And so vibe code,
the custom apps for that, was really helpful.
Let me actually ask about
that. That is super cool.
So you built basically internal tools for
yourself using Base44. People can use other
tools potentially. So you built one that's
like, "Help me craft a tweet." Well, how
does that actually look? Like what is the
input? That sounds really interesting.
So the way that I like to work is like I would
have those moments where I would have inspiration
for like a piece of content, right? So the way
I grew Base44, and probably different topic,
but was a lot around building in public and
growing an audience and speaking to my audience,
which were fellow builders. So it was
really easy. So a lot of that was like
around sharing on the Base44 journey. And
then I'll have a process that I follow,
is like I'll write down before that on a piece of
paper, like some ideas that I had for like post
for throughout the week because you want to keep
consistency and keep putting the things out there.
And then my process before the
app was like I'd go to ChatGPT,
I'll write like a very vague kind of structure
or skeleton of a post and tell it like, "Hey,
fix my writing, improve my writing a
bit." And then ChatGPT will spit out
something that was like too far off, like too
salesy, not my tone, and then I'll say, "No,
keep closer to the original." And we'll fight
about that, and then like remove the emojis,
the hyphens look weird and so on.
So okay, I'll have now my LinkedIn post,
and I'll need to generate an image for that.
So I'll go to a different tool. And then I'll
take this LinkedIn post and now, okay, I need to
put it out also in my Twitter account. So okay,
let's break it down to a Twitter thread. Now
you need to shorten there, like you need to
make some adjustments to the content.
And so I've taken this entire process,
which I think was what was working for me and just
vibe coded it up around it to help me speed it up,
and then made sure that the LLM inside the app
was using my own tone of voice and was saving
the previous posts to understand how it looks
like, like what are the posts that I really
liked that I've written beforehand, so that
in the next post it will speak just like me.
This might be a good plug for Base44. So say
someone were to go to Base44.com and try this
out. What would be a prompt you'd suggest, like
how to get started building a tool like this?
Usually what I'll do is I'll write down... I think
LLMs nowadays do a very good job with like start
vague. It's going to build the skeleton for what
you need, and Base44 does a good job with this,
like understanding at least the big pieces. Okay,
there's going to be an LLM writing the content is
going to be this and that, and so you don't have
to write the entire spec. It's just like something
like, "Hey, I want to build my own content
generation AI-powered tool. Here's my process
currently and my process is doing this. And
then LinkedIn and then Twitter, write something
to support that and then form their iterate."
And also something that I really like with the
entire category, again, not only Base44, I feel
like there's tons of tools doing a great job,
but something I really like in Base44 is that
because it's really easy to change the software,
it's like you get this adaptive software, is
like as you improve your processes or maybe
your processes change, it's like you adapt it.
So Base44 got acquired by Wix two weeks ago,
and so now the process of putting content out
there looks a bit different. And so with just
two prompts, you change it to support
your new process, which is really fun.
That's a cool phrase, adaptive software.
I heard malleable software is
another way to describe this.
I want to talk about growth, but a couple more
things real quick. This idea of bootstrapping,
I'm curious. So essentially you're competing
against very well-funded companies, Lovable,
Bolt, Replit, v0, Vercel, Cursor raised, I don't
know, bazillion dollars at this point. I know
you're not competing with Cursor directly.
If you weren't going to be acquired by Wix,
did you plan on raising money? Do
you think you had a chance staying
bootstrapped, competing against the folks that
everyone's, the more popular products today?
Base44 was very profitable, much more than what
I thought. So even if I wasn't getting acquired,
I felt like I can make good money out
of it. It ended up like, I remember I
had like a very failed ProductHunt launch at
mid-January and then started writing some,
like started building in public at around start
of February and that's where it took off. And then
started, I think, first dollar or like the first
10 or 100 bucks towards March. And then in May,
I already did close to 200K in profit.
And so I think either way, there was like
a room to compete, and even though it was small,
I was seeing that the users that come to me stick,
that come to Base44, stick with Base44, even
though they're very familiar with the rest of
the competition, the challenge was obviously
making as much noise as data folks. So you
can see like data vibe coding tools doing
like a million dollars hackathons and so on,
and doing awesome job on growth, really.
But I didn't have the resources,
so I tried finding ways to fight the fight. I
think we had a very successful hackathon 4Good,
which found out to be a great growth engine and
also did good in the world, which we had 3000
teams just building some great do-good apps.
But also, to be very honest, I think part of
the reason to get acquired is because
this market has been moving so fast,
faster than anything I've seen, faster than
what I've thought it's going to move. And at
some point, I figured it's going to be, like
you see Base44 grows and you start thinking,
"Hey, this can really help people with their
lives." This is like one of those software
categories that, I'm saying that, I'm very not
objective, but I feel like can really move the
needle for a lot of people. I've been seeing
people build like fantastic, awesome things.
And so I was like, "Let's go for the big one.
Let's try and actually build some global scale,
maybe lead the category and maybe win it." And
I felt like the best chances to do that is to
partner up with Wix. There's plenty of
reasons to that. We can touch on that
later. But it's like same DNA, same customer
base. They know what they're doing, they're
seeing and obviously like very good connection
with the entire management team over there.
And so I feel like the acquisition, again
being very honest, I felt like it's going
to be a financial success either way, but the
acquisition is like taking a stance and saying,
"You know what? Let's play in the big league
and let's punch down, not only punch up when
fighting in this very crowded space." And
that's part of the reason why to get acquired.
That was really insightful. So part
of what, part of I'm hearing is you
could've stayed independent and made a really
good income and built a really good business,
at least for a while. Who knows
what would happen longterm?
But if as a solopreneur, as someone that's
never raised money, you can make significant
income doing something like this in a crowded
space if you have something that people love,
that enough people loved. So I think that's a
really interesting insight. Like it's okay if
there's a bazillion dollars in funding going
to competitors. There's a big market here.
Yeah, I think it's a bit different ballgame right
now. I was scared many times. Like I thought,
"How am I going to go into this
fight?" Those companies are, one,
some of the fastest-growing companies
ever, again, they're great teams and very
well-funded and a lot of money being poured into.
But then, throughout time I saw that I'm able to
keep the pace, if not even have like a faster
pace and have like a different angle and it's
not changing over time so nobody is like... And
so I think it's a different ballgame because even
if you're a very small team or even if you're
solo, you're, literally, managing teams of AIs,
like writing code. I don't think I've written
a single line of like HTML or JavaScript in
the past three months, but still the Base44
front end changes a lot because AI writes that.
So yeah, if you have an interesting angle and
you're able to move fast, I feel like money and
funding is not necessarily the factor to win a
category, and that's going to change even more
drastically in the future. As LLMs get better,
it's like people, like 10X engineers would
have way more impact. They're going to be 100X
engineers because they're able to manage LLMs.
And it's not necessarily the team size, nor the
funding, that will be able to win you a category.
What you just shared is amazing
that you haven't written any,
you said JavaScript, HTML in three months,
which is half the lifetime of this company,
which sold for $80 million and more potentially.
It feels like now the big things you got to get
right is kind of at the beginning, of
figuring out what problems to solve and
being really good at understanding where
the gaps are. And then it's distribution,
marketing, getting people to be aware
that you exist and give you a shot.
Yeah. And even distribution, I'm still
learning that. Even distribution nowadays
it's very different and also in favor
of the solo, not necessarily the solo,
but it's like not necessarily that you're going
to pull a lot of money on paid campaigns like
a Base44 goal with close to zero marketing
budget. I spent like $2,000 on an influencer
post that didn't really bring anything, and then
tried paid for a couple of thousands of bucks,
didn't really work. And so everything
was organically and built in public,
and so even distribution is
very different, but yeah,
if you have an interesting take on end domain.
Base44's first user was one of my best friends,
like we grew up together, and up to few
months ago, he was a restaurant manager.
And then he left and started like a SaaS company
for managing invoices for restaurants. And so this
is a guy that has both distribution, obviously
this is very local like software and company,
but has distributions, like has those connections,
but has a very deep domain knowledge. And now that
the technical, he has no... like human coding
are very different in very different places.
And so I think if like domain knowledge
become or domain expertise and some, again,
interesting take on a domain or a product
or a category becomes like a key thing,
and then distribution, yeah, that's a hard one
to get, but also all that's changing a lot.
Yeah, and I love that you did it with no funding.
The other thought here, as you're talking,
is it feels like you could have kept doing
this and made money and lived a great life,
but there's this question of how ambitious
do you want to be? I've gone through this
myself where I was like, "Oh, this
newsletter is I'm making a living
off this writing one email a week. I
could live really well just doing this."
But then I'm like, "Oh, why not do a podcast?
Why not do another podcast? Why not do some other
stuff?" And the reason I do that is it just like
it's boring to do something the same way forever,
and there's this opportunity that's out
there. I'm like, "I should do that."
And I feel like some people are, "I just don't
need that. I'm good. I'm going to live in,
I don't know, Fiji and just code it, make
100, 300, 500K a year from this thing."
But I feel like folks like you, there's
more ambition, and one way is raise a bunch
of money and then they sell to a company
that has a platform that you can build on.
Yeah, I empathize with this a lot,
but the funny thing is that Base44,
for the first time in my life, was not
trying to build the biggest thing ever.
So I remember when I started Explorium, my
previous company, I was so hung up on like,
"Let's raise the most amount of money in the least
amount of time." I remember that I showed like,
now I looked, kept looking like, "Hey, Explorium
raised $100 million before Snowflake. This is
insane. This is amazing," and so on.
And I did that for seven years,
and I think Base44 is the first time, it's like
I stopped and said, "You know what? I just want
to go back to do what I really love, which is
just building a product." I don't care like if
it wins the category or not. I don't care
if it's going to become really big or not.
I remember when me and my girlfriend got back from
like the trip to Asia, and we were on the plane,
I told her, "Hey, you know what? If we get
to 1.5 million," I don't remember why I said
exactly this number, like, "If we get to
$1.5 million in ARR till the end of 2025,
we're going to buy a nice car." And we got
there in like four weeks. And so it was the
first time of like saying, "Let's not try
and build the biggest thing. Let's just do
something I really like, and let's just build
a product that I'm going to enjoy building."
But then at some point, it got to be very, very
successful, and I think it comes with like once
you're seeing success and you're seeing like true
positive impact on people, then you're saying,
"Okay, you know what? Let's go for the, like,
let's play the big league, and try to scale it."
That so aligns with my journey. Similarly,
I'm just going to do a newsletter,
life's going to be great, I'm not going
to build, I'm not..." I called it my
anti-empire. I don't want to build anything big.
I'm just going to keep it chill, project chill,
project avoid getting a real job. That's what
I called it. And I think that is a really big
insight. Some of the best stuff comes from
not putting a bunch of pressure on yourself,
trying to build something huge, and just following
a pull, following your interest, following just
that insight you have ends up being some of the
best ideas come out of that and the biggest ideas.
I love it. I agree with that, yeah.
This episode is brought to you by Content
Square, the analytics platform that helps
companies build better digital experiences.
Ever wonder why customers drop off before
converting, or why some pages perform better than
others? Content Square takes the guesswork out of
digital experiences, giving you real-time insights
into how users interact with your site or app.
With AI-powered analytics, automatic
frustration detection and clear visualizations,
you'll know exactly what's working and
what's holding your customers back.
Whether you're optimizing an e-commerce
checkout, refining a B2B lead flow or
improving a mobile app experience, Content Square
pinpoints exactly what needs fixing and why.
Content square powers better customer
journeys across 1.3 million websites
and apps. Discover the insights you've
been missing at contentsquare.com/lenny.
Let's talk about growth. So here's
what I want to do. I want to talk
through just how you got the first users
of Base44. So I'm thinking maybe how'd
you get like the first 10 users? How'd
you get the first 100 users? How'd you
get the first 1000 users? What are the
levers used there? What are the tactics?
So let's start with 10. How'd
you get your first 10 users?
Just begging people close to me that I feel
like that they have really good connections with
to use it. I feel like there's no other way.
And maybe there are other ways, but,
again, I was very new to like B2C,
like to consumerish-type of product.
And so I grabbed, well, I started with even
three users, like really close friends. Two
of them back at the time, I caught them
in a part of their life where they were
unemployed. So I was like, "Hey, why don't
you try build a SaaS business or something
like that?" So three really close friends.
Well, somehow I got them to sit down with me
every other day around the table, and they would
use the tool. They will try to build something,
it will break. I'll take a look, I'll take a
look at the logs, I'll go back to my computer,
try to change it, push into production,
and then just build it for them.
I feel like plenty of people are lucky to find
maybe a method that consistently works for your
like 10, 100, 1000 users, and then from there.
But I try to look at it as like milestones.
And so, first, I was like, "I'm not going
to try and scale anything before I know that
users enjoy it." And the best metric to seeing
them enjoying it, or at least making value
out of it, even if they're not enjoying because
there are plenty of bugs and slowness and so on,
is that they're starting to share it with
someone. So I haven't invested anything in
marketing before I felt like, "Okay, for the first
three or five or 10 friends." At some point, they
started sharing it with their friends. They're
like you'd see, okay, there's one new users
today and then two new users today and so on.
So once it started happening, even on very low
percentages because Base44 turned out later in
its journey to be very viral, but back then,
it was like an okay product. People loved it and
all liked it and started sharing it with that.
And so once I started seeing that this works,
and we got to like 10 users where all my friends,
and then the 11th user or something like this
started seeing people that don't really know me,
that's why I knew, okay, now it's time to
invest in marketing or try to launch this
thing or try to get more people to use it.
Because if you try to do it beforehand,
I feel like you're going to waste a lot
of time and resources on just having a
very revolving door. Like you get users in and
users out, you not be able to. And unless you
have a lot of money to invest in paid so
that it makes sense, then it's very hard.
I knew that I'm not going to do that. It's like
a product that I'm building. I want it to be
profitable from the get-go and not feeling bad for
investing too much money into paid and so on. And
so I knew that it has to be viral. At some point,
I saw it's starting to look like it's viral.
Then I did a very failed, very bad ProductHunt
launch, but also now looking back and saying,
"This is completely fine." I feel like
people sometimes treat their launches,
like product launches as like make it or
break it for the company. This wasn't the
case for me. I was like, "This is a tool
for me to get to my next 30 users, my next
50 users." And that's exactly what happened.
And so first ProductHunt launch, we got like 50,
I got like 15 new users. By the way, the second
one broke ProductHunt. They thought that there's
like plenty of bots. We won the first product
of the day and the first product of the month,
of the week, but it's a different story.
And so we got like 50 users, and we got the
first user to pay. This was an insane feeling
because I'm an entrepreneur coming from like
the enterprise space. I was thinking that this
is insane. Why would anyone pay for my product
without meeting me, without looking me dead in
the eyes or trying to get a discount and so on?
Obviously, this user churned in like a few hours,
the product wasn't good back then. But from there,
I started seeing some very slow growth.
So I got my first 50, and then 20 left,
and then the other 30 started sharing it
with like other users that were really good.
And then I tried a bunch of
marketing things, didn't work,
influencer post or paid or something like that.
And then one of my friends was also a founder,
in a different space, told me, "Hey, you know
what? I think it's really cool that you're
building it on your own and that you're trying
to like take a very different approach than the
usual VC-funded way. Why don't you share
content about that? At the end of the day,
it's like you're going to have the
same, like your audience or builders,
they're trying to build their own
products or maybe even businesses,
and it will likely resonate with them."
And so I started sharing the journey on
LinkedIn, and I remember seeing posts like, "Okay,
there's this nice concept of build in public,
and people get really interested." And I think
here in Base44, we had this really nice synergy
between the build in public and also my audience
was like builders, right? If I was building,
I don't know, a product to attorneys, and
probably this wouldn't have made a lot of sense.
Once I started sharing what I'm building
in public and then getting more users and
improving their product tremendously,
I was so lucky. The community around
Base44 is nothing like I've ever seen. It's so
supportive. There's so much feedback and so-
[inaudible 00:46:00] is so supportive,
there's so much feedback. And so from
the loop of improving the product, this is
exactly how people say it should feel like
is like people asking for features before you
can actually build them. They're getting so
excited about your product. They're writing the
nicest things. People have started writing like,
"Hey, you changed my life. I wanted to build.
I had those ideas throughout my life. I didn't
have an ability to do that or resources or
money to pay for developers." And then the
other thing that I did, it worked really
well, is I've noticed that people really
like sharing what they're building on
top of Base44. They would write posts.
I remember at some point a friend of mine
reached out and he was like, "Dude, how much
are you paying those people to write posts about
Base44?" I was like, "I'm not paying anymore,
honestly." So what I did is actually I did
this program inside Base44 saying, "Hey,
if you share just about the process of building
the app or the app itself, it doesn't even have
to be about Base44, if you share it in social,
you'll get extra credits to build." So those two,
build in public and giving out credits worked
extremely well and that's how we got growth going.
Okay, let's pause there. That was awesome. How
many users do you have at this
point of the journey roughly?
I think there was two weeks between... no, a
week between being on a pace of 20 users a day
to seeing 4,000 users come into your product,
like new users a day, break the product. It
was hard scaling it. Also, just some things
I needed to learn while moving. It's like,
yeah, I wasn't a DevOps engineer. I don't
know how to scale databases. I didn't know
that the virtual CPU would really come back at
me when trying to scale and so on. And again,
trying to be profitable and so you try to use
every free tier that you can, but then once you
start scaling it [inaudible 00:48:04]. So, yeah,
I think once I started sharing in public it grew
to a few thousands a day and then [inaudible
00:48:14] the credit thing did the rest.
Okay, so this is kind of the whole journey. I know
there's a few other elements I want to touch on,
but let me point out a few things that stood out
to me that I think might be helpful to folks. The
first is right at the beginning, coming back to
a lesson you shared at the beginning, which is
build for specific people. So initially it was
build for yourself, build for your girlfriend,
build for the Scouts program, and then
it was built for these three friends,
just building it, sitting with them,
building the things they need to use it,
which is really interesting because a lot of
times the advice you get is look for pull,
look for people with problems to solve.
You almost went the opposite. You're like,
"Use my product. I need you as a favor.
Use my product and help me make it better."
Absolutely. Also, I don't know though. I think
maybe paradigms are changing, but there are some
things that I don't believe in is MVPs, first and
foremost, is like if you're building something
that people will not be able to use or is not
good enough, especially these days where it's
so much easier to build software, so the attention
span for people to actually try out new software
products is getting shorter and shorter, so,
yeah, pick a bunch of people that, I don't know,
owe you something or have any reason to use your
product when it's bad, build for them, be there
physically. I remember that even when we passed
20K users, 50K users and 100K users, it was still
very tough to get the right feedback. So I would
bring 20, 30 people to a room together, almost
like a focus group or a small hackathon. I'll
do that every other week, just to get feedback,
and it was so much easier than any other thing.
It was the same thing that I tried developing
when we were just three users and five users.
So, yeah, build it for them. They can come from
different backgrounds. Again, something else that
I don't really empathize with or agree with is you
have to have a certain ICP. It's not necessarily
about the profile of a person. More of what
they're trying to do is way more important.
So you can have different types of people,
but they're all trying to do the same
thing. They're trying to build a tool.
I think some of those people should
remember the tool you're building
is a specific kind of tool that helps
you build things and so these lessons
don't necessarily apply. In a lot of cases
you want to be really specific with ICP,
because there's one thing you accomplish with
this thing versus this very horizontal product.
I agree.
But I think that's still very good to know.
Because maybe for your product you hear all
this advice, you need a very narrow focus,
you got to have a very specific role and
company size and all these things,
and you're like, "Okay, maybe not.
Maybe [inaudible 00:50:49] is something that
a lot of people can use for a lot of different
reasons. Don't worry about that too much."
Okay, so step one, shared it with friends,
a few friends, forced them to use it. "Please
use this. I'm going to watch you." Your point
about being there physically, I think, is
really interesting. Like, don't just send
it to them over email and ask them how it went.
It's like sit next to them and watch them use it
and then keep making it better. Then you tried
this product at launch. Another great lesson.
You may fail on product end. That's okay. I
don't know. It sounds like you tripled your-
Yeah.
... quadrupled your user base from 10
to 30-ish in a failed product at launch.
Yeah.
You also said you've tried paid, which didn't
work. You tried influencer marketing, didn't work.
So, basically, all the paid stuff didn't work.
But that's great lesson. I think people generally
don't want to be doing that kind of stuff. The
point you made about starting to share it in
public, I think, is really interesting. A lot of
people post stuff on LinkedIn and it's cringey.
There's a lot of people building in public. Who
cares? What are you building? I don't know. I
don't care about what you're building. What is it
you think stood out about the way you approached
it that is it this tool you built that tells you
how to post really viral stuff? What do you think
you did that made people care? Is it the small
community you're already a part of in Israel and
the tech scene? Is that a big part of why you
think it worked? Is there anything else that
might be helpful to folks that are thinking about
building in public and being successful there?
So first a disclaimer. I feel like
I had some very small, not audience,
but I had plenty of LinkedIn connections before.
So everything started from LinkedIn, right?
It was LinkedIn, okay.
'Til this day.
Great.
Yeah, so now that the acquisition story is
getting crazy all over the world, so getting
a lot of followers from a bunch of different
social media platforms. But it started with
LinkedIn. I think the fact that I was the CEO of
this company previously had some people around me
in my connection. So, again, you have to have, if
you're writing to something that it's [inaudible
00:52:44] a few weeks ago, building public is
great. Other channels can really work, but at
some point you have to take a bet on one channel
that you see it's working. So if you're writing
posts week over week and you get five likes, it's
likely not going to change drastically. Again,
I tried a bunch of things. Influencer didn't
work. Okay, just put it aside for a second.
Let's see if I can find a channel that works.
For the build in public, I was trying to be
as honest as I could and just write the
good, the bad. I think also the fact that
I wasn't a VC-funded company, I didn't try
looking the best or show, "Hey, look at my
amazing metrics," or make everything looks really
[inaudible 00:53:37] and really great and I'm the
fastest going whatever bootstrap company in the
world, I think just writing really about the good,
the bad and the ugly and just being very realistic
and sharing the learnings along the way. Again,
this is specifically for my audience. My audience
were builders and so I'm not sure that it works to
any other product category. But, yeah, just being
very realistic and doing posts from the deepest
technical tech stack and how I optimize the LLMs
to just sharing some feelings or growth. People
like to see numbers, people like to see charts.
Also, even there, even in the building public,
I would ask my friends beforehand that
they knew that they were the target,
like, "What do you think of this post? Is
it interesting? Is it not? Do you see value
out of that?" It's almost like a product that
you're releasing out there. It's the same thing.
Okay, this is really interesting. So being honest,
really effective. It feels like there's this
underdog element of being a sole founder, not
VC-funded adds to it. Also, just sharing really
interesting learnings, things you've learned
yourself that innately people find interesting,
because you didn't know this stuff. Also, just fun
stats and [inaudible 00:54:52] charts and things
like that, building a tool on Base44 that can
help you make these tweets better. Also, I think
it's important to note you had a network ahead of
this. You had people, you had followers, you had
connections. It wasn't starting from zero. What's
a rough sense of just, I don't know how large your
network was, what's a way to think about that so
folks are like, "Oh, wow, I'm nowhere near that"?
I don't think it was very big. I think it was
maybe a few thousand connections. Nowadays,
it's a few tens of thousands. But you start seeing
some engagement and once you do that, especially
when like you're saying, "Okay, this is the
channel that I'm going to put all my weight on."
Okay, that's a really important point
too. It wasn't like cross post to Twitter
and Instagram, all these things.
It's pick one and just nail that.
Yeah, 'til this day I think that
for me posting on Twitter was a
waste of time. At some point I saw
LinkedIn succeed and I was like,
"Okay, let's do the same thing on Twitter."
Now I have a better following on Twitter,
but it didn't really work. So I was spending
a lot of time where from LinkedIn I saw the
highest ROI. And it could be very different
for different founders for different products.
It could be Reddit, it could be opening up a
Substack. It could be very different things.
For me that's what worked. Once you see something
work, just double, triple down on that. Keep on.
Don't try just pray and pray. It doesn't work at
this stage. At least for me [inaudible 00:56:20].
That is really great advice. It aligns
with what I often see with traditional
growth engines. There's like SEO, there's pay,
there's sales, there's reality, word of mouth,
and usually a company grows mostly
through one, and LinkedIn interestingly
was your vector of growth. Also, just this
incentives piece is really interesting,
a really cool tactic. So the tactic here is
incentivizing people to share what they built
on Base44 and they get credit to build more.
I've never heard of that before. How do you
actually do that? Do they send screenshots
or something? How do they get credit for-
Literally early on they sent me emails and I would
take them, again, with an app and an LLM. Support
is a whole different topic that we can speak
about for hours, like, how do you run support
when you're solo, which is a huge topic. But they
would send... I would say, "Hey, write a post,
paste the link back, send me an email with the
link and I'll give you credits." So at some point
I automated that because I couldn't really manage
the whole thing. But, yeah, because you couldn't
really connect to the social APIs and so on. It
was hard. So i was like, " Just send me the post."
I know exactly what you mean with the
support challenges of being a solo
person. With a newsletter of a million people,
I get endless little things just come up. I am
really curious to hear you solve... Let's
not get into it. In terms of being solo,
actually, I haven't asked this yet,
how long were you actually solo? When
did you actually hire your first second
person into the journey of the six months?
The first person started two months ago, so a
month-and-a-half before the acquisition. So I was
running mostly solo, I think. But when he started
I already knew that it's headed there then.
To acquisition?
Yeah. Also, at some point, once I started,
the chances of this happening might grow,
so I hired the best people I know because I knew
that I have now these few years, if not more,
that I have to build this to be really big and I
need the right people around me. It's not anymore
about let's try and be as profitable and as fun
as possible. It was like let's literally take
a bigger bet. That's where I started bringing in
the best people that I knew to help me build that.
Also, the way the deal is structured, not
that I can share a lot of details around this,
like, okay, there's the 80 mil that got
published, that's the initial payment,
and then there's this [inaudible 00:58:57]
piece, which is really interesting,
because I think that Wix structured
the deal in a really win-win situation,
but then a lot of my compensation and a lot of the
upside is actually based on that other than the
80 mil. So I have both the financial interest,
also the personal interest in building this to
be as big as possible. So the month before the
acquisition I had the team starting to scale.
But also Base44 became more profitable that I
could afford myself to bring in more people.
The first hire, was that an
engineer? What'd they do?
Actually, a product person.
Whoa. Like a product manager?
Yeah. Well, it's someone who I've been working
with a lot and he is like a jack of all trades. He
can go into LLM logs and look at mistakes and fix
the points. He can write Python scripts to analyze
things that we do. He can start implementing
analytics into the product. A very technical
product person that could wear many hats,
that's what you want when you're starting
out. His name is Joav. At some point, I was
telling him, "Hey, Joav, you take growth
now." And he was like, "I haven't done growth
anywhere. Right?" "No, you take growth now.
Try and let's try a new challenge. Let's
try those kind of things." So you want to
bring in someone that at least the [inaudible
01:00:21] that can do many different things.
Okay, that's really interesting. Let's finish
talking about growth and let me share stuff
you've shared already about what worked and
then there's a few more things I read that
you did that I'm curious how big of a deal they
were. First, you just grabbed a bunch of friends,
used this product, used that to learn
what to build, you tried Product Hunt,
sort of effective early stages. It ended
up being really effective. Then you had
another launch that was, like you said,
broke with the Product Hunt Algorithm.
How many users did that drive? Was that a huge
inflection, that second Product Hunt launch?
The thing is things happened so fast that I didn't
really implement any data for stuff like this.
I don't really know how many users it's bought,
but I remember first the community around Base44,
again, is one of the most incredible communities
that I've seen. It's a very strong one. And
the whole entire [inaudible 01:01:14]. So they
all were very excited about the Product Hunt
launch and I was like, "Let's skyrocket Base44."
And then I wake up and I see the weirdest things,
like Base44 is not even in the top 10. And
I was like, "I know for a fact there's a
thousand people already voted by the time it
was noon." And noon in Israel, very early on,
was like I see people write, I see more posts
on LinkedIn saying people should vote to Base44
vote then they actually see upvotes. So 'til
this day I don't really know what happened.
One of the community reached out to the
support team for Product Hunt and saying,
"You guys should check out your algorithm
because something is not right." Just even
look at LinkedIn, search Base44 Product
Hunt, you'll see this many posts. Like,
you know what? You're right. We fixed it.
And then we jumped to the first place. We
were like 500 for upvotes. The delta was
500 up uploads from the second place.
My god. I've never seen that.
Yeah, so it was fun also seeing
the community really for this.
Speaking of community, was that all in
WhatsApp? Where do you manage this community?
WhatsApp is a surprisingly really good tool
to get feedback from the community. Obviously,
it's not a great tool for the... The community
is going so fast. It blew past 1,000 or 2,000
or 5,000. I don't even remember what's
the limit on WhatsApp. But 'til this day,
the WhatsApp community, which was very early
on is such a great place to get feedback,
it's also even only enough, when it first
started out, it was my best place to find
out if the product is up, if there's slowness,
if there's bugs because people write really fast
and I can see that. But, obviously, at some
point we turn to more scalable solutions,
like Discord, Reddit, those things, and then
just keep on sending product updates via email.
Okay. There's another couple levers I've
read about and then I'm going to move on
to a different topic. One is this hackathon
you mentioned that helped you grow and become
more aware. The other is you did a bunch
of partnerships, which is really rare for
a company of your size. So just talk about
those and what that did to the business.
At one point, one of the things I really
liked about building Base44 is that I
saw people building apps that were really
incredibly positive and doing really good
in the world. I think something really
interesting right now in vibe coding in
general is once you actually scale software,
you can also scale the impact the software
does. So you can have nonprofits build
themselves tools, you can have people that
build apps for education and neglected domains
that didn't really have budget because there was
no business [inaudible 01:04:18]. And once
you opened this up and make it super cheap
to create software, then it's becoming. And
this was early on. We were at the 5,000- ish,
10,000-ish users. And so I said, "Okay, well
you know what? Let's do a hackathon where we
open up for everybody to build apps that do
good in the world." I had no budget back then,
so I was like, "Okay, this is going to be a
5K hackathon. The price is going to be 5K."
And it was your own money
you were going to give away?.
Yeah, it was the profits that [inaudible 01:04:55]
Base44 did at the same at that time. And then a
lot of people started registering and a lot
of teams. It ended up being 3,000 teams. So
really big. I think it's the largest 4good
hackathon so far. And then started getting
sponsor requests because it went all over social,
and all of a sudden I found myself with a very
nice, back then, smaller business partnering
up with Amazon, with Google, with MongoDB,
with Deloitte, with really great companies, that
one after another stood behind this hackathon,
which was so fun. Those are awesome teams. The
ones that we partnered up with, they opened up
their offices across of the globe to have teams
be there. And the prices went obviously very high.
I think this will likely be one of the
top moments in my career. It was very,
very empowering, but people built a lot
of interesting things. I remember this
person building a tool for her grandma
with Alzheimer, she has Alzheimer's,
and building an app, which is essentially a game
to help the grandmother to memorize her family
members with photos and names, and so many
interesting and great and impactful applications.
I love that there's benefits to the hackathon
route which other vibe coding tools are taking,
not just growth but also just good
feelings and just building community
and seeing what people are doing, like
meeting people excited about what you're
building. So many side benefits.
Okay, before we move on from growth,
is there anything else that's worth
mentioning that worked really well or
just that people think will work and just didn't
work for you that you didn't already mention?
The last piece, but people talk about that a
lot, is that velocity eventually is a growth
engine. Part of building in public is you
want to put content out there that people
really like to see. So we joked about it,
but it's really true. People like to see
charts and they like to see numbers. It gets them
attached to this project if they are saying, "Oh,
I wonder what's going to be profit next week,"
or "I wonder how much money is it losing and how
can you optimize," and like they get attached to
that. I think, also, velocity is to some degree
the same thing, because if your product evolves
really fast and you're putting features out there
every other day, people get attached to that .
I remember people commenting on my posts saying,
"You know what? It's moving so
fast, I have to try it now."
So this is part of this velocity solves
for so many things. Most of my thoughts,
and still are, when running Base44 is how do we
increase velocity? How do we increase velocity?
It's going to solve every product problem we have
or most of them. It's going to solve some of your
marketing challenges if you're smart about it
and you're putting the content out there and
you're making everything like a mini launch. So
I feel like that was also a great growth tool.
That is a really good point. Clearly everyone
in the space understands this as well. I want
to talk about the acquisition piece, but a couple
of quick questions that have been on my mind. One
is just what is the tech stack that you built
on? Because I think a lot of founders are like,
What the hell do I build on? What will
help me move fast?" So get as geeky as
you want. Just what are the tools and
infrastructure used to build Base44?
Render.com, oh, my God. Honestly, they're
not paying me anything. I wish I would've
invested or anything. I don't think I ever
spoke to someone senior there. Holy. This
was so much fun to work with and still is.
I mean, my previous company, we had large
teams of DevOps building processes for us to
push to production. So render.com is like-
... DevOps building processes for us to
push the production. So Render.com is like,
how is it called? Just it's a cloud. I was like,
yeah, it's like a very build on top of AWS. You
have a bunch of easy to manage processes and easy
to start up web apps and scale them and so on.
And it's just Render. It's not a fancy
version of Render, it's the word Render.com?
Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I just looked it up. Okay, cool.
Yeah. So this is everything that has to do with
infrastructure and manage both the website,
the platform, and the applications itself.
Because Base44 is a complex ecosystem. You
have that user applications that have to
be isolated and separated from the platform
that has to be isolated and separated
from the website. It's a whole thing.
MongoDB is really good when you're vibe
coding, especially when you're building a
vibe coding platform because schemas change a
lot and it's not necessarily users. LLMs don't
always understand what the user is trying to
send, so they keep changing the data schema.
And I feel like this has been the right choice.
Obviously Kelso, but again, I was spending 20,
30% of my time just optimizing for making the
whole repository LLM suitable. By the way, those
are concepts that I also implemented in Base44,
but one thing that I kept doing is I tried making
the LLM write as least code as possible. When
you're trying to implement a feature that try to
get to a place where it can implement the feature
entirely without you writing code, but that the
LLM would write as least codes as possible.
Because then, when the AI tries to implement the
entire feature from scratch, there are more places
where you can make mistakes or get confused.
There are more things that it needs to save in
the context when you ask it for a follow- up
prompt or something like that. And so I built a
very high level, very opinionated infrastructure
like code infrastructure. It takes care of the
entire thing. When you build a new feature,
it takes off the entire, the CRUD, the
authentication, the database, everything that has
to do with that so that when you ask the LLM to
implement a new thing, it writes very little code.
And by the way, this is also true for Base44 is
provide LLM with a really good infrastructure and
SDK. And have the LLM... The LLM still has
the flexibility to write the entire feature
because it's code, but make it so that it doesn't
need to spit out too many tokens. And obviously,
everything that has to do with rule set does one.
Controversial take for me working with LLMs is
don't use TypeScript, use plain JavaScript,
use JSX. It's easier for models to write
code this way. So the front end for Base44
for the platform, I mean is built in JSX,
not TypeScript. And I feel like this has been
working well. Part of the reason why I haven't
written a single line of HTML or JavaScript
in the past, just it does this really well.
And another thing that works really well
working with AI is try to push as much as
possible in the same repository itself. Like
separating the front end and the backend,
it's easier to give the context to the AI of both
what's in the backend, what's in the front end.
Besides that, so my stack is the back end is in
Python. I feel like people can be very judgmental
about that. In terms of performance, I
haven't gotten into performance issues.
And there's a lot of traffic to Base44. And
every now and then people try to DDoS Base44
and still the server holds. And so I feel
like if you're building it the right way,
Python is just a very great language to do that.
And another maybe interesting take is
because there's many of the new apps and products
that are being built to some degree around LLMs.
So one of the things that I use is for the LLM
that actually writes code in Base44, I use a
mix of different models for different tasks. So
Cloud Four, for example, does a really nice job
with first the initial prompt, writing the app
from scratch. Then everything that has to do with
UI is just fantastic. Design is great. But then
for example, Gemini is really good when you get a
very complex problem or we need to figure out
an algorithm or Cloud Four got stuck in some bug
loop, which happens a lot when you write code. And
so I have this pipeline that tries to figure out
the user prompt and then route it to the right LLM
which I feel like has been working pretty well.
Wow, that was extremely interesting. In
this routing, is this what you do within
Cursor or you do this within Base44
based on what the person's working on?
Base44. Yeah.
Oh wow, okay.
I don't think Cursor has this. I wish they...
I think there's maybe an auto option for it,
but in Base44 it's like when users ask-
Wow. That's awesome.
... I just try to analyze what they're asking
and then figure out what's the right LLM to use.
That is so cool. So it's just Claude and
Gemini, those are the two they use for Base44?
Yeah. Well, all of those tools, Base44, Kelso,
all the right coding tools, I use the same
paradigm or I don't know if you call it or
method, which is you have the heavy guns,
which is usually either Cloud Four or Gemini.
And then Cloud Four and Gemini usually
create a high-level solution or high-level what
changes do you want to make to the file? So not
writing all of the file from scratch every
time. Kelso does that, Base44. So writing
only the chunk of code that needs to be
implemented and high-level, then you get smaller,
faster models like Flash, or o4-mini from OpenAI
to implement to patch the code inside this file.
Okay. One very tactical question in
a completely different direction,
product question. Activation, getting people
to an aha moment feels like something that
is core to retention. Something that comes up
a lot on this podcast. Is there anything you
learned about getting that right? Anything you
did that was really successful in getting people
to see the value of Base44 really quickly?
And in that, start sharing it, using it?
Here's one interesting thing
that I learned that I think
was counterintuitive to me because
you always want to build the best
product out there for your users,
but sometimes it contradicts the aha
moment or how fast can you get users to do that.
So, first when a few months ago or more than that,
when Base44 started before actually implementing
your app, so you would say something like, "Hey,
create a task management app." And before
implementing that, because a lot of times
you get this not super clear request from the
user, I'd show the user like the LLM would first,
before even writing code, it would first
generate user flows. Almost like a PRD,
but something that's more digestible to
folks who are not coming from the space.
So it will generate user flows, it'll show it
to you like, "Hey, you want to create a task?"
And then you could say, "Hey, yeah, so maybe I
want to add some files and stuff like that." So
it will show you what it's going to generate to
make sure that it understands you. And then you
click okay and then it will generate the app.
This was actually something I ditched because
too many users, even though it was good for them
and it was the right product decision to do that
because you'll create better apps doing it this
way, but the conversions to get to the aha moment
were not super high. And also not super... I
think one of the key to the aha moment in the
vibe coding world, or at least in Base44, is
like, "Holy shit, it actually understood me."
And they see the app. And if you have a stage in
the middle, it makes it slightly less surprising.
So I think I ditched that and that was a nice
lesson that, I don't know actually how to define
the right way, but it's like get your users as
fast as possible to the aha moment. Sometimes
there was a price to that, make sure it's not
too big. But sometimes there are a price to
that because at least when you're building B2C,
and it's all new to me because I'm not coming
from the space, but at least when you're building
BTC, the attention span is so low, really. So you
want to get there in a minute or two or three.
And then from there, okay, later on, ramp up the
features that you want to actually put there so
that it can be the right product for your users.
That was an awesome insight. Thank you for sharing
that. That's actually something that I think will
help a lot of people. Okay, final topic. I want to
talk about the acquisition process. Founders often
look at this as the dream. "Oh my god, I can sell
my company millions of dollars," but I know it's
always stressful and hectic and wild and the work
only begins. You are not like a moth. You have
to keep building this thing. So first of all,
just how'd the acquisition conversation start?
Wix reached out. I think back then there was a lot
of folks from the community were posting saying,
"Hey, Wix should definitely buy Base44 before
it gets too big," or something like that, even
though we're not playing or competing in the same
category, but it was clearly it's going to be-
Why were they recommending Wix?
What was just the connection there?
First because of the Israeli ecosystem.
Got it.
But also folks were building websites
with Base44 and so it's the same thing.
Got it. Okay. Makes sense.
Yeah. Obviously Wix is an incredible product for
building websites, but a different approach from
LLMs. It's now definitely getting there.
And so I got there. The management team,
Wix's management team is so friendly and such
great guys. And I remember sitting there and
I think the first sentence, the first thing that
Avishai the CEO told me is like, "Hey, everybody's
been saying that we should buy you. Maybe it's
least worth the talk and we're here to help."
And I think early on we explored, at least in
my mind it's like, "Yeah, it seems like that's
a great team to work with. They're definitely in
the same space. There's a lot I can benefit from
partnering up together." So it wasn't clearly an
acquisition on the acquisition path. And Avishai,
the CEO is a very seasoned, very experienced and
helped a lot of entrepreneurs in the B2C space
and specifically in Israel to go and succeed.
And so I remember meeting him for a few nights
of just eating some steaks and just chatting about
how to grow Base44 and just literally just getting
there to get an advice. And so at some point we
saw first that we have great chemistry both with
him and with the rest of the team, which I think
is really, really crucial, especially if they're
buying a solo... This is a very unique case,
but especially if they're buying a small team,
I think it's crucial for the buyer to make
sure or to feel like they're going to have
really good connection and chemistry with
the founders, with the key people because
eventually it's like I remember one of the key
reasons where we were debating together whether
I should join Wix or not. One of the key things
that we've put on the table is, "Oh, yeah, and
it's going to be a lot of fun working together."
And I think also being a person that's going to be
fun to work with is a key, especially if you are
not a 500 people company that someone's buying.
They feel like a big company and it doesn't
really matter. You're buying the operations,
you're buying the product. If you're a small
company, they're just starting out and getting
some great momentum, you have to be a person
that people would love to... Want to work with
for the next few years. And so this was critical.
I think the best place, and this is not easy to
get to, to this position, but the best position
to negotiate such a deal or even to get there is
to be also very fine with the other path of not
getting acquired. In some ways it's weird, but
it's like in dating. When you're in the first
couple of dates, you don't want to show too much
interest because then it's... I think also I was
in a position that I was saying, "Hey, if it works
out, it's going to be amazing. And if not, it's
going to be amazing. It's going to be either way
fun." Obviously I wanted it to work out.
Yeah. And the last thing they think is,
I don't know if it's suitable for everyone, but
I'm very happy with the structure of the deal
with the Airnote piece because I feel like it's
still, I show up every day to work and it's been
only two weeks, but feel like it's going to be
like that for years. And like I have a personal
investment in the business and its success.
So it's really, I feel like it's better than
just selling the business and just spending
the next few years and wanting to disappear.
I love that part of the deal. You could be a
billionaire if it does well enough. I don't
know the deals, but in theory. Let me ask,
so I know a part of the story also is that
when you were signing the deal, the war with
Iran basically broke out. Tell that story.
So I was trying to not... I wasn't nervous
throughout the process, but this is a huge deal
for me. It's going to change my life, probably
will change my kid's life. And when we kicked
off the process, we wanted it to be fast. Also,
it's not like Base 44 was a very old company with
a lot of baggage. There's no legal, it was very
easy. The due diligence process was very fast.
And I remember us saying to the lawyers and
to our great institutions that we work with,
it was, "Until Thursday night, that's it. We're
signing Thursday night. No matter what we do,
let's do it. Let's wrap it up and make sure that
we're aligning to sign Thursday night." And we
get till Thursday night, it's 2:00 AM. We stopped
fighting over small details and the lawyers have
agreed to everything. I was like, "Okay, just send
it out for signatures. We said Thursday night."
And then lawyers were saying, "Yeah, we agreed
on everything but we still need to change the
wording and so on." And we were very tired. I was
like, "We're not going to do it the right way.
Let's wake up tomorrow morning and do that." And
I remember us, I remember going to sleep and then
4:00 AM was this announcement like, "Hey, a war
broke out between Iran and Israel." I was like,
again, this is so classic. I'm sure that
the dealer... I wasn't sure, I was like,
"Holy... I can't believe this is happening.
It's such an insane turn of events." But
everything went fine from there. We woke up
the next morning and signed the papers. Yeah,
as I said before, it was definitely the
least boring month that I had in my life.
I was just thinking back to exactly that phrase
that you shared. Oh, man. There's just so many
parts of the story that are so interesting. It's
a hero's journey story in so many ways. Maor,
is there anything else that you want to leave
listeners with? Anything that we didn't touch on?
Maybe just last piece of a negative
advice for founders that are trying to
start on this journey or on this journey
that you think might be helpful to them?
First, before getting to the negative advice,
the only thing that I would say really, if
there's anyone from the Base44's community that's
actually listening to this, I am so grateful. This
community has been so supportive. And many times
I'm saying, "Okay, maybe I did this right and that
right," but it's hard for me to think about what
I did so many things right to get this community
behind the product. And so I'm so grateful
for the community. So if everyone's listening,
really, I'm hoping to serve everyone better.
What not to do? Yeah, there's plenty. Just
make sure that at least 50% of your time you work
on the parts of you that you really like and that
you're really good at. There's plenty of ways
of saying that and different diagrams that they
show you as what you're good at, what you want
to do, what's fun for you, what's energizing,
what's not. I think 50% of it should be in this
sweet spot of you are doing the thing that you
are genius at, your genius zone or whatever they
call it. And they're also fun because that's what
keeps you up, showing up every day.
And it's unbelievably different
than being a very talented person and a very
skilled person, but doing things that you
either don't like. And it's fine. Everybody does
things that they don't like. And in every job
there's those places, but keep yourself in the
zone of genius. I think that's really crucial.
And I feel like in the last few months I've also
met plenty of really great and friendly CEOs,
even from the Israeli ecosystem for public
companies, like Wix and Mindy.com and Ito and so
on. Obviously, they have to do a lot of different
things and being CEOs of public companies,
you have to manage a lot of things, a lot
of logistics and I don't know, bureaucracy,
but they all have a major, or to some degree
major part of their job is doing something
that they really like and they're really
good at. It's whether it's product design,
whether it's building a marketing machine or
something like that, or I think that's critical.
Yeah, that's the biggest thing. And also it's
like, and you probably hear this nowadays on
every podcast, but it's the best time to
build. And it can be really life-changing,
just starting out something that you really like.
Well, I feel like we're at the start of an age is
going to be bigger than the revolution that the
internet did obviously. I think now it's becoming
clearer to anyone. And so just building what
you want is becoming so much easier. Just do
it. Do something that you like. I think it's
going to be from a lot of chance, it's going
to be life-changing. And if not, at least
you'll have very little regret in the future.
Maor, I'm going to skip the lighting
round, but I'm going to give you...
Because approaching midnight your
time, I want to make sure he gets some
sleep. I'm going to ask you one question.
There's something I meant to ask earlier,
but I didn't. Base44, what is that
about? Why did you call it Base44?
This is the most really the stupidest probably
reason that you hear for a name behind a product.
So again, Base44 was not intended to be a very
large scale, the global phenomena that it's
becoming right now. I wanted to have base in
the name because I felt like that's going to
be the base of where people's going to start
build software or solve their pains and so on.
And obviously back then Base.com wasn't
available and I didn't have money to buy a
very fancy domain. So I started seeing, I think
it was Cloudflare, I don't remember even what
domain provider was that. It started showing me
some numbers. My date of birth is February 2nd,
and so Base22 available and say, "Okay,
let's double it." And then Base44 was like,
"I like the sound of it. It's almost like
Base64." And for the nerd in me it was like,
"Okay, Base64 is one way to encode data
from one type to another." And it's like
Base44 is going to do the same. It's like encode
natural language into software. And I was like,
"Okay," to Wix, "Let's go with
it." It's good that it's memorable,
the number in the name, but there's no
real very sophisticated reason behind it.
That is an amazing story. I love that you were
like, "Base64 was cool, but I guess there's a
reason 44 could be cool." And it's not even
Base42. There's always numbers around there
that people know and it's like, "No, 44, double
my birthday. Sort of like 64." That's amazing.
It worked. I guess. I don't know, maybe it
shows you the power of how a name doesn't
necessarily make a huge deal. Interestingly, a
recent podcast episode is about how a name can
make a big deal so there's both sides to it.
Maor, this was incredible. Thank you so much
for doing this. Congratulations on the outcome.
I know this is just the beginning. I know the
product is only going to get better. What
a fun place to be. Hope you get some sleep.
Two final questions. Where can folks
check out what you're building? Is
it just Base44.com? Anything else they should
know? And how can listeners be useful to you?
Just try it out. I think we're at a place where
people really love the product. And for every
user that we get, it turns out to be two or
four later on because they're sharing it. So
just try it out, base44.com, and build something
that you like. And if you have a bit more time,
just leave feedback so that we can make it better.
Amazing. Maor, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you, Lenny.
Bye, everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.