Let's talk about crisis. I think it might be
helpful to do a quick taxonomy of
the types of crisis founders face.
So two, abstractly, two types of crisis. One is
I would call that a cash crisis. All of a sudden,
your cash program or plan is being
jeopardized, losing a customer,
disappearing investor. And the other
one is lose of product market fit.
When product market fit disappear, you
actually need to go back to square one.
Then you basically say everything that
I know so far is irrelevant anymore.
You also talk along these lines of never give
up in a crisis and throughout your journey.
Always keep on looking for ways to
make it work. Never give up is the
most important behavior of successful CEOs
of startup. The second one, by the way,
is making decisions with conviction. If you don't
make them with conviction, then the team is not
going to follow. If the team is not going to
follow, then you are not going to be successful.
The core part of your advice on crisis,
it's always the founders fault
if things don't work out.
At the end of the day, you cannot rely on
someone else, you have only one company,
you need to make sure that this company is
successful. When you assume responsibility,
you're basically saying, "You know
what, I control my own destiny."
Any advice for how to avoid
falling into a crisis as a founder?
Number one answer is no, don't
worry, you will face crisis.
Today, my guest is Uri Levine. Uri is the
co-founder of Waze, along with nine other
companies. He's sold two companies for over
a billion dollars, he's been on 20 different
startup boards, has been an advisor to over 50
different startups. And even more impressively,
this is his second time on the podcast.
In our first conversation, we walked through
the biggest lessons that he's learned over the
course of working with all of these different
startups that he chronicled in his beloved book,
Fall in Love with the Problem, Not the Solution.
In this conversation, we go deep on one very
specific topic, crisis. As Uri shares in his book,
building a startup is a journey from one crisis
to the next. And my goal with this conversation
is to give you tools to handle the next crisis and
the next crisis and the next crisis that you face
as a founder. This topic is so important that Uri
decided to update and re-release his book with a
whole new chapter dedicated to managing crisis.
And this new edition is actually going to launch
right around the time this episode launches.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube, it's the best
way to avoid missing future episodes and it
helps the podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you Uri Levine.
This episode is brought to
you by WorkOS. If you're building a SaaS app, at
some point your customers will start asking for
enterprise features like SAML authentication and
SCIM provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in,
making it fast and painless to add enterprise
features to your app. Their APIs are easy to
understand so that you can ship quickly
and get back to building other features.
Today, hundreds of companies are already powered
by WorkOS, including ones you probably know like
Vercel, Webflow and Loom. WorkOS also recently
acquired Warrant, the fine-grained authorization
service. Warrant's product is based on a
groundbreaking authorization system called
Zanzibar, which was originally designed for
Google to power Google Docs and YouTube. This
enables fast authorization checks at enormous
scale while maintaining a flexible model that
can be adapted to even the most complex use cases.
If you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features like
single sign-on, SCIM or user management, you
should consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in replacement
for Auth0 and supports up to one million monthly
active users for free. Check it out at
workos.com to learn more. That's workos.com.
This episode is brought to you by Rippling, a
single platform to build and scale your startup
on. Rippling handles all the can't get it
wrong admin work of payroll and benefits,
giving you back hours every week. But it
does a lot more than that. Rippling is a
game changer for the entire company with tools
for HR, IT and spend all built from the ground
up and designed to work together seamlessly.
Just hired someone, Rippling makes onboarding
easy whether your new hire is sitting next to you
or halfway across the world. In just a few clicks,
Rippling automatically generates an offer
letter, ships a laptop with the necessary
apps and permissions and even delivers
a corporate card. An employee needs to
update their benefits contribution, when they
do it in Rippling, the change automatically
syncs to payroll. CTO forgot her laptop in
an Uber, lock it remotely with Rippling.
Many startups I've invested in like Sprig,
Ellamy and ClassDojo use Rippling because
it's a force multiplier for lean teams,
helping them eliminate major headaches
and operate their business more efficiently.
For a limited time, Rippling is giving Lenny's
listeners three months off. To redeem, visit
rippling.com/lenny. That's rippling.com/lenny.
Uri, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you. I'm really happy to be here.
I should have said welcome back to the
podcast, this is your second time here,
which is a pretty rare feat. And the reason
that you're back is, the first time we chatted
in depth about your amazing book. I have it
right here, Fall in Love with the Problem,
Not the Solution. And you decided to re-release
the book recently with a new chapter about
something that every single founder is going
to go through. You actually have this quote
I'll read that I think is a good summary of
why this is so important. "That building a
startup is a journey from one crisis to the
next." Let me just start with this question
of why did you decide to add this chapter,
why is it so important to update your book?
End of the day, recent years have demonstrated
major significant crisises throughout the world,
from Covid to interest rate, to inflation, to
wars. And then I realized that wait a minute,
this is something that I haven't spoke
about during my first book and it's time
to write a new edition to that or a new
chapter that will be added into the new
release. And so this is about crisis. And
in addition, my publisher told me that,
"Oh, you should have a paperback, it's going
to sell more and more people are going to
read it because it's easier to read."
So I do have the new edition already.
There is?
It will be published in about a month and it
does include a new chapter. And it's a paperback.
I love that you're solving the jobs
to be done, make it easier to read,
we'll make it paperback. I also, as you described
it, it made me realize the reason your book is
so great is it's basically a step-by-step
guide of all the things you need to know
about building a successful company. And
what it feels like is you just realize,
oh, I forgot this step that every
founder goes through, which is crisis.
Multiple crisis.
Multiple crisis, we'll get into that. Also,
I love that you can actually update a book.
Usually people are like, "Oh, books,
done." You move on. I love that you
have the opportunity actually to
update a book. That's inspiring.
I'm already thinking of the next one.
The next book or the next update to the book?
Not sure yet, not sure. Look, at the end of the
day, there is a reason for me to write the book.
I wrote the book in order to make a bigger impact.
I'm an entrepreneur and everyone knows that,
so I built Waze and Moovit and dozens of
other startups, but I'm also a teacher. So
I feel equally rewarded when I build something
myself or I guide someone to build it. And the
book is fulfilling my destiny as a teacher,
sharing my know-how with entrepreneurs,
with business people, with pretty much everyone
to help them to become more successful.
So the realization that what I really want is
people to take out of the book is something
that will increase their likelihood of
being successful. And the next book is
going to be pretty much the same, with
the same philosophy of wait a minute,
if I can make a bigger impact, I
would like to make a bigger impact.
It's a beautiful mission. I think we're going
to do that. Let's talk about crisis. Maybe to
make this very real and visceral for people
to get a sense of, you hear the word crisis,
you're like, oh yeah, sure. Can you
maybe share a story of a crisis that
you experienced that might be illustrative of
the types of crisis that founders face across
the many companies you've started
and advised, what comes to mind?
Covid was an excellent example. And one of
my startups back then, called Order.chat,
and actually it was the first AI chat back
in 2020. And that was meant to help people
to make reservations to restaurants. As simple
as, "Oh, I would like to make a reservations for
six people for tomorrow night at XYZ restaurant."
And that chat was actually very, very successful
in Israel. And the reason is that we actually
built an engine that had facing the user with
a chat but also facing the restaurant with a
chat. So we did not require any integration,
we could go online anywhere and actually
cover all the restaurants in no time. And
that turned out to be pretty successful and then
Covid hit. And guess what? All the restaurants
were shut down for hosting guests and there
were no more reservations for restaurants.
Now we were really good at that, but we
did not have enough funding to actually
pivot into something completely different. And
the result is that we had to shut it down. And
still people still ask me what happened
to that? What happened to that was Covid.
I feel like Covid happened to a lot of companies.
And it feels like that's kind of an impetus to
this chapter. I think you even said that, it
created so many crisis across so many companies
you were involved with, helped you realize a lot
of companies and founders are just not prepared.
So by and large I would say end of the day, we
look at the global crisises and we say, "Oh,
this is going to impact an industry." But as an
entrepreneur, you don't care about the industry,
you care about your own startup, that's it. And
if the rest of the world is suffering from the
same problem, doesn't help you, not even a single
bit. So your problem is your problem, that's it.
And then you need to abstract that and basically
realize, okay, wait a minute, I will define a
crisis as something that you already had that is
significant, disappears. So let's say that you
already have millions of dollars in revenues and
all of a sudden your biggest customer decide not
to continue and you lose half of your revenues.
All of a sudden you basically say, "Wait a minute,
I have to adapt, something significant happened."
And that something significant is that your
revenues disappear or maybe your funding
disappeared or maybe ... So in general, the
first type of crisis will be around cash. All of a
sudden your cash is not the same as you expected,
something happened, maybe funding, maybe revenues,
maybe projection, maybe you lost a big customers,
a cash crisis. And then you need to adapt.
The second one, which is even more significant,
is that you lost product market fit. And
that might happen, it might happen because
of regulations, because of competition, because
of something dramatic happened that there is no
more value into your product. And we are
going back to basic, product market fit is
very simple. That means that you create value
to your customers, this is what it is. And you
never heard of a company that did not figure out
product market fit. They simply died, that's it.
And by the way, product market fit in general have
only one metric, only one metric, retention. Look,
it's really simple, if you create value, they will
come back, that's it. If they are not coming back,
that means that you are not creating value. And
so in your startup journey, this is going to be
the first phase, and it's going to require a lot
of iterations and it's a journey of failures. So
we're going to try something and it doesn't work,
we're going to try something else. And we keep on
trying until we find one thing that does work.
But once you figure that out, you're ready to
move to the next part of your journey. But what
if it's all disappeared? What if all of a sudden
someone changed their regulation? Someone you
rely on, a very unique data, that you were able
to build and all of a sudden someone create a
way to access this data for everyone. What if
there is a competitor that makes you irrelevant?
I'm using iPhone, obviously a lot of people using
iPhone and I'm using that for a long while. iPhone
is born in 2007. Before that we used to have
different phones with keypads. And when iPhone
was introduced, Microsoft basically say this will
never work. They were in a position of a market
leader, they own Windows mobile operating system
that was running on pretty much all the phones
in the world. All the smartphones in the world,
from Nokia to Motorola, to Samsung, to pretty
much everything. And they look at it and say
this will never work. They haven't realized
how impactful it is. So this is a competition
coming out to the market with something
that is completely different. And not only
disrupt the market but actually create
crisis for pretty much everyone else.
And the result is that today Microsoft is not a
player in the mobile operating system and Nokia
disappeared or pretty much disappeared
and Motorola disappeared and pretty much
everyone that was really significant in
this industry, they were not adapted fast
enough to the change. And the change was that
their product market fit disappeared. Now it's
not that their product all of a sudden become
irrelevant, people simply wanted something else.
So when product market fit disappeared, you
actually need to go back to square one. And
the faster that you realize and you basically say
everything that I know so far, everything that I
knew so far is irrelevant anymore. Can I restart?
Can I go back to square one and restart? Because
if you cannot, you will die. You're following your
own solution and you believe that this solution is
going to be marketed better than what the market
wants. And what the market wants is different.
It can be also a matter of regulation change. One
of my startups called Fibo died because of change
in regulation. So Fibo was doing tax returns,
something that everyone hates, but we have to do
that. And when we started we basically say wait
a minute, when I speak with people and ask them
how is tax returns being done in your country,
what I heard was pretty consistent, it's either
complex or expensive or both, that's it. And I
said wait a minute, what if I can simplify that?
What if we can make it really, really simple?
And we define simplification by filing in less
than five minutes. Whatever you do, if you can
do that in less than five minutes, it's simple
enough. And we ended up with building a platform
in Israel that people were able to file in less
than three minutes. And that was actually pretty
amazing. Now the result was that in about ... In
Israel filing is not mandatory. So we actually
enable people that were not filing up until now
to file because it's simple. And we increased
the size of the market by 25% over one year.
Of people filing taxes?
Yep. Because it was simple. So you go into the
platform, you realize that wait a minute, I
actually entitled to get a return, so let me file.
If I'm not entitled to get a return, then I'm not
going to file because it's not mandatory. And
the result is that we increased the load of the
taxation system. And all of a sudden the Israeli
tax authority didn't like us anymore and they
basically shut us down. So changing the regulation
and we lost product market fit overnight. They
basically say, "Oh, we are going to shut you
down and that's tomorrow." And that's it.
Now we did not have enough run rate to actually
... because the company was about break even,
so we did not have enough funding to go
and try to find something else. And we
tried to fight the regulator, but fighting
regulator requires a long period of time and
a lot of funding and we did not have that.
So regulation might be a reason why you lose
product market fit. And you need to go back to
square one. And what we decided is that, okay,
what I decided on a personal level is that I'm
not going deal with the regulation anymore. I
don't want to rely on a regulator to allow
me or not allow me to do what I want to do.
By the way, with Waze, in the early days we
thought that the business model is going to be
selling data to authorities, to municipalities,
to maybe public transportation systems and so
forth. And we basically say wait a minute, we
have the best traffic information in the world,
I can go to a municipality and tell them
how long does it take to make a left turn
in each and every traffic light in the city
every day of the week, every hour of the day.
And therefore they can recalibrate the traffic
control system and enable better utilization of
the entire road system. And it turns out that
this is really, really, really slow business
development process. They didn't really care. And
that was frustrating. Even if you offer that for
free they still don't care. And the result is
that we changed the business model and we ended
up with advertisement. But the reality is that I
don't like to work with regulators, that is all.
Okay. There's so much here I want to dig into.
One is this example, this story about losing
product market fit, it reminds me of, I had Drew
Houston on the podcast, the founder of Dropbox,
and he described a moment where when
Apple launched Apple Photos or iCloud,
I think it was iCloud, he's like, "It's as
if there's this mushroom cloud exploding
far in the distance that you don't hear for
a long time and we didn't necessarily see
exactly how much this will have impacted our
business." And I think that's what happens
a lot of cases. You see something happen
and you're like, "No, this is no problem,
we're going to win anyway." Like Blackberry
I think did the same thing with iPhone.
We had the same thing with Waze, because when we
started Waze was free and it was the only one that
was offering turn-by-turn navigation free. And
the reason is that we created our own maps. And
then one day in 2010, Google announced their free
turn-by-turn navigation. Turns out that they were
working for the last two years in building maps
of the US. And they enabled that on Google Maps,
turn-by-turn navigation with audio guidance
to turn right, turn left and so forth.
And two companies were actually
shocked, the entire industry,
but two companies were impacted. The first one
is actually TomTom. TomTom was the provider
of the maps for Google to do navigation. And
they basically say, "No, we have our own maps,
we are going to terminate the contract." And
TomTom said, "Wait a minute, you are paying us $18
million a year and we have five years contract."
And Google say, "Yeah, we will keep on paying you
that amount of money that we are committed, but
we are not going to use your product anymore."
And that one was Waze because basically everyone
in the industry told us that we are doomed. Our
own investors told us that, "Look, if we can
sell the company for $20 or $30 million today,
do it because you are not going to be successful."
Now obviously we turned the corner and turned out
to be very successful. And to that level that
eventually Google acquired us. And the reason
is that the use case was different. Waze
was focusing on the daily commuters. So
we wanted people to use our application twice
a day, when you go to the office and when you
come back home. And Google Maps is something
that you are being used not that frequent,
you are in general I would say if I ask a hundred
people how often they use Waze, they will tell me
every day. If I ask them how often they use Google
Maps, they will tell me, "When I need it." So
a different use case and obviously different
product that is built for the specificity of
the use case. So Waze is way simpler and the
map looks almost abstractive, they're not,
but looks like abstractive and way less details.
And the result is the ability to create something
that is simpler and people are using every day.
But when Google announced turn-by-turn navigation,
all the investors in the world turn their back
on us. And that was 2010. We were looking for
new funding. I remember that night, because
we were just about to go and meet with all
partners meeting at Khosla Ventures. And we had
multiple meetings beforehand and that was like,
okay, this is the final seal.
And the evening before we had
dinner with the partners that was promoting
us at Khosla Ventures and he told us, "Look,
I have a lot of relationship in the industry,
and I spoke with my friends at Google and they
told me that they are at least two years away
from building their own maps." And the next
morning they simply announced this turn-by-turn
navigation. Going to that meeting was a waste of
time already. And we had very, very hard
time to raise capital because of that.
But eventually we were lucky in the
sense that once Google announced their
turn-by-turn navigation, turns out
that the rest of the industry were
took by surprise. And Microsoft decided that
wait a minute, we don't have our own maps,
so let's invest in Waze. So we ended up getting
investment from someone that we did not expect.
Okay. So first of all, you've
shared all these types of crisis,
I think it might be helpful to do a quick
taxonomy of the types of crisis founders
face. You shared regulation changes, competitors
coming at you, investors not wanting to invest.
So two types of, abstractly, two types of crisis.
One is that I would call that a cash crisis. So
all of a sudden your cash program or plan is being
jeopardized, for losing a customer, disappearing
investor, not meeting your expectation, dramatic
price change in the market and so forth. And the
other one is lose of product market fit. So all of
a sudden whatever you have is irrelevant anymore
and you actually need to go back to square one.
For the first type of crisis, if this is a cash
crisis, then what you really need to
ask yourself, and in any type crisis,
first of all is what is actually being impacted?
Is that my run rate, is that my product, is that
my revenue stream? If I'm still relevant?
With Order.chat, we were irrelevant,
that's it. And so the first thing that you
need to do is what is really being impacted?
And then the second thing is how long it's
going to last? Is that a temporary thing?
Is that forever? Is that the new future? And
then you ask yourself, okay, so how much run
rate do I have? And you re-plan accordingly.
And I'll give you some examples, and this is
really important, because let's say that you're
a company that we have $5 million of revenues a
year, say 400,000 per month, and your burn rate,
your net burn rate is 200,000. So you actually at
the end of the year, in order to run for a year,
you need about two and a half million dollars to
run. If you lose half of the revenues, and
you only had two and a half million in the
bank, you now have six month to run.
So obviously you need to re-adapt.
Now, one of the things that you might say to
yourself, "I'm going to remain on the same
course and I'm going to deal with the crisis in
five month from now." Or you can basically say,
"No, I'm going to change my expense to adjust
to the current revenue stream that I have and
still have 12 month of run rate."
Whatever you are going to decide,
you are going to decide, you need to decide today,
right now. And the reason is very simple, if you
want to reduce the burn, the expenses in order to
extend the run rate, if you wait two more month,
then it's going to become nearly impossible to
do. If you wait six more month, then obviously
this is impossible to do. So the longer that
you wait, you actually lose options. The only
ability to choose is today. This is one of the
most challenging part of a crisis. You actually
need to make a decision rapidly, like today.
There are few reasons to that. Number one is
that if you don't then you might lose options.
Number two, and this is about communicating
within the organization that decision. Look, if
there is a crisis everyone knows, everyone knows,
and you don't do anything about it, this is not
a good practice. Now you might want to decide,
no, we're going to keep on running full steam
ahead until we hit the wall because by that
we increase the likelihood that we will have
enough velocity to bypass the wall. But you
need to communicate that with your team because
the one that is really suffer is not just you,
it's the entire team. They know that there is a
crisis and they want to know that someone that
holds the steering wheel is making the decisions.
And if you don't, then guess what? You are then a
sinking ship. And what's going to happen is that
the top performing people, they would leave.
Let me do a quick summary of what you've shared
to give people a landscape and then let's keep
going down this route. So there's basically
two types of crisis. And there's small crisis,
I imagine someone's pissed off at something.
These are how you describe major crisis,
like existential crisis for your startup.
Is that the way to think about it?
Right. Because if an A-player leaves,
I hate it, but it's not a crisis.
Yeah. Okay, cool. So there's two, cash crisis,
which is either a bunch of revenue disappears
or investors bail or don't want to keep
supporting you. Those are the two major
buckets. And then there's product market
fit crisis, could be a competitor launches,
could be the market changes, things like that.
And within the cash crisis, so say you realize
we don't have as much cash as we planned or
need, the three steps you just described,
what is really being impacted? Just be
really real with what is the impact to
our business with this change. How long
do we think this cash crisis will last?
And how long do we have before
we run out of cash essentially?
Yep. And then you need to decide, and then you
need to decide on your action and your new plan
and maybe it's a new strategy. If all of a sudden
I would say if this is about product market fit
disappeared, then this is a new strategy.
And maybe it's about deciding on extending
the run rate or keep on trying or whatever. And
this is something that is really interesting.
And we go back to Covid and I look at two of
my startups that were in the travel space,
one of them is WeSki, and it's essentially the
booking.com of ski vacations. And guess what?
Covid started. And there was no more ski trips
to Europe. Europe were shut down completely.
And all the ski areas were shut down. And you
know that I'm an avid skier? For me that was a
disaster on a personal level. And eventually
by the way, what happened is that I was back
in Tel Aviv and I was unable to travel to Europe,
and it was only somewhere in 2022 that I was able
to travel to the US after vaccination and so
forth. And in March, 2022, I actually moved
myself to Utah to Salt Lake City and I basically
say, "No, I'm going to ski every day that I'm not
busy." And I skied until the end of the season.
So what happened is that Covid started and we
realized that we have major problem. And the
problem was actually, the first thing that you
face is cancellation because all of a sudden out
of very few cancellations per day, you ended up
with hundreds of cancellations per day because
this is it. And after you dealt with that, then
the next question that we ask ourselves, okay,
so how bad is it, how long it's going to last?
Now that was supposed to be the first year
that we were profitable. So we did not have a
lot of cash in the bank because we expected to
become profitable this year. And we basically
told our ourself, okay, this season is over, next
season is not going to happen. We don't know,
but we need to plan for something that is
going to last longer than that. And then we
basically say, okay, how can we deal with it?
Now, because of WeSki had a lot of strategic
investors from the travel industry, in the travel
industry, they didn't really care about WeSki,
they care about their own product. If you are
a hotel chain, then guess what? You have no
travelers. If you're an airline, guess what?
You have no flyers. So anyone in the travel
industry suffered from the same problem.
And the last thing on earth that they care
about is a startup that they invested at. And we
realized that, okay, wait a minute, we don't have
enough cash to survive for two seasons without
revenues, we need to raise additional capital.
Now, no one, no new investor is going to
speak with us, because there's no ski, so
what are you talking about? And we approached the
existing investor, and by the way I'm one of them,
and we basically say, "Okay, you know what?
We need your help." And everyone told us,
"Oh, we are busy. We have other problems
to deal with. We have our own problems.
I don't see how is that going to become
a good investment and so forth." And then
we basically decided that, okay, wait a
minute, we're going to do a pay to play.
The pay to play is actually sort of
forcing new investors at the expense
of the existing one. So for example, doing
a major down round is sort of pay to play,
because if you're not participate your position
in the company is going to be diluted severely.
And this is what we decided to do. And that was
way more complex, I describe that in the book,
way more complex than that because we also had
safe instruments that we need to convert before
we can actually do something like that. And that
was really complex. But we ended up doing that.
And today the company is actually very successful.
After Covid, we used the time of Covid to actually
improve the product, and as soon as Covid
was over then we started to grow rapidly.
And the company is profitable, is growing rapidly,
is actually providing very, very good service to
its customers. To a certain extent I would say we
ended up getting out of this crisis successfully.
But if you are in the middle of it and you ask
yourself, so what are the chances that we will
end up being successful? It looks way smaller.
Way smaller. So what happened here is that you
realize that, okay, this is not forever, so ski
is going to come back but we don't know how long
and therefore we assume that it's going to be for
two seasons until it's coming back, until 2022.
And for that we need to adapt. And so we resized
the company to be very, very lean and small and
we raise just enough capital to survive those
two years. And it ended up to be working very
well. But in that sense now, if you would ask me
how much luck was in there, luck is always good.
I think that I heard ... maybe the most
significant real estate developers in New York is
Silverstein, and he built the World Trade Center
and pretty much everything on the Hudson. And
he was asked how he becomes such a successful
developer and he said, "Tell you the truth,
this is 85% luck and 15% skills and know-how
and so forth." And then he was asked if he
can change one thing, what exactly it's going
to be, and he said, "You know what? I'm going
to replace the 15% skills with additional
15% luck." So luck is good. For me luck,
I will define luck as opportunity meets readiness.
Readiness is up to you; opportunity, not always.
Beautifully said. I also agree with luck
being so core to most people's success,
most company's success. But I feel like
you're not giving people enough credit
for the hard work that's also involved
in the skills and timing and stuff.
On the readiness.
That's the readiness.
Of being ready to take advantage of opportunity.
That makes sense. Okay, there's a bunch
of stuff I want to dig into here. So one
is, and this is something, it's kind of a
tangent, but I think it's a core part of
your advice on crisis, which is that it's always
the founder's fault if things don't work out,
even if they're completely out of your
control, even if the whole world is changing,
it's still your responsibility and
your fault if things don't work out.
I wouldn't say fault, I would say responsibility.
Responsibility.
It might not end up beautiful, in some cases
you will die. But at the end of the day you
cannot rely on someone else. The fact that
the interest rate is going up and the result
is that it's becoming very, very hard to raise
capital, the fact that this is industry-wide,
so what? You have only one company, you need to
make sure that this company is successful. And
later on if you fail, then you can rely to then
basically say, "This is my excuse, it was not
just me." Not just me is not going to help you to
become successful. Just me is going to help you to
become successful. When you assume responsibility,
then you are able to ... you're basically saying,
"You know what? I control my own destiny. I'm
going to make the decisions and I control my
own destiny." When this happens, you increase
the likelihood of being successful regardless
what happen to the rest of the
market, and you don't really care.
You also talk along these lines, you have this in
your chapter, the section of never give up in a
crisis and throughout your journey, this is by far
the most important behavior of a startup CEO. Can
you just talk about that. Because a lot of times
it's like maybe just stop, maybe just give up.
You shared one example where it's like I don't
want to deal with regulation, other companies,
I'm just going to stop. Any advice there, just
like, okay, maybe it does make sense just to stop
and try to give the investor's money back versus,
yeah, it's just part of your job not to give up.
I heard of cases that you basically say our
underlining assumptions didn't work out and
our thesis is wrong and therefore we would
like to return the investors their money. But
entrepreneurs never give up. And this is the most
successful behavior of startup CEO, never give up,
always keep on looking for ways to make it work.
And so it is going to be a journey of failures,
and in particular during crisis, but you still
need to keep on trying to make it work even though
it's way harder. So never give up is the most
important behavior of successful CEO of startup.
The second one, by the way, is making decisions
with conviction. This is true for all CEOs or for
all companies, not just startups. Now startups,
those decisions are probably more frequent and
there are a lot of them. But during crisis, all
CEOs in the world need to make hard decisions.
And you need to make them with conviction
because if you don't make them with conviction,
then what will happen is that the team is not
going to follow. If the team is not going to
follow, then you are not going to be successful.
But never give up. You ask entrepreneurs what will
happen and they will basically tell you, "No,
we keep on fighting." One of my other startups
in the travel industry called Oversee, back then
they called FairFly. And the CEO told me that a
cat might have nine souls. We are a cat in that
sense, we have nine souls. And the reason that
I know that is that we already died nine times or
almost died nine times. And so the reality is that
you don't give up, you keep on as long as ...
And for a second I would say, look, there are
only two reasons that you would like to give up.
One is that your mission is wrong. So the problem
disappears. And if the problem disappears, your
mission is no longer relevant or no longer valid,
and you might want to consider to give up.
The other one is that if the team is not right
and you are unable to change it. So you brought
toxic investors into the board and they started
to control the company and obviously in many
cases they create more damage than help. And
you're unable to change that anymore,
then this is a good reason to give up.
Other than that, never give up. Crisis, not
crisis, hardship, no money to pay, no ... anything
that might happen, anything that you might
want to think that might happen will happen.
I'm excited to chat with Christina
Gilbert, the founder of OneSchema,
one of our longtime podcast
sponsors. Hi Christina.
Yes, thank you for having me on, Lenny.
What is the latest with OneSchema? I know you now
work with some of my favorite companies like Ramp,
Vanta, Scale and Watershed. I heard
that you just launched a new product
to help product teams import CSVs from
especially tricky systems like ERPs.
Yes, so we just launched OneSchema FileFeeds,
which allows you to build an integration with
any system in 15 minutes as long as you can export
a CSV to an SFTP folder. We see our customers all
the time getting stuck with hacks and workarounds.
And the product teams that we work with don't have
to turn down prospects because their systems
are too hard to integrate with. We allow our
customers to offer thousands of integrations
without involving their engineering team at all.
I can tell you that if my team had
to build integrations like this,
how nice would it be to be able to
take this off my roadmap and instead
use something like OneSchema. And not just
to build it but also to maintain it forever.
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many horror
stories of multi-day outages from even just
a handful of ad records. We are laser
focused on integration reliability to
help teams end all of those distractions
that come up with integrations. We have a
built-in validation layer that stops any bad
data from entering your system and OneSchema
will notify your team immediately
of any data that looks incorrect.
I know that importing incorrect data can cause
all kinds of pain for your customers and quickly
lose their trust. Christina, thank you for
joining us. And if you want to learn more,
head on over to oneschema.co. That's oneschema.co.
This idea of never give up, it's very similar to
Dalton Caldwell was on the podcast, he's
a partner at YC, and his whole ... he has
a famous talk, I guess, at YC, and this
was the title of this podcast episode,
is just don't die. That's his main
advice to a startup, just don't die.
Never give up.
You might die by the way, you
might die, you'll never give up.
Then be reborn. And to be clear, the way
a startup dies is they run out of money,
is that the simplest way to think about that?
That's the only way that they die. By
the way, all the companies in the world,
they are unable to pay their
bills and therefore they die.
And many of the tactics you share is just ways
to not run out of money. Oftentimes it involves
down rounds, creating strange cap structures
just to keep it alive, losing equity percentage
just to keep it going, that's part of the job
basically, and that's what you have to deal with.
In many cases, we had to engage the employees,
"No, we don't have cash." So what we did is that
we diluted all shareholders in order to give
employees way more equity. So five times more
equity than they had before. And we told them,
we need you to trust us and believe in the cause
and believe in our ability to recover. And if
we don't, then everyone loses. But if we do,
then everyone wins big time. And so this will
be a way to actually reengage employees if you
are unable to pay them their regular
pay. And that was the case in most of
the startups that almost run out of cash.
Occasionally you can do, if you will tell
me that you're going to run out of cash next
month and therefore you need to shut down,
I would like to imagine that you have at least
six more month of run rate. You don't know that,
but this is through leadership. So you
basically tell your people, "Stay with me,
you believed in the cause, you believed in
my leadership, I still believe in the cause
and I still believe in you. And maybe
we are going to have some hard time,
maybe we are going to have some month that unable
to pay, but eventually we will get out of that."
And in many cases, most people will stay.
Now, leadership, you don't build leadership
during crisis, you might, but in particular
you build leadership through transparency,
through recognitions of your team,
through actually putting your team
as the top priority. At the end of the day,
you are going to be successful if your team
delivers. And in order for the team to deliver,
then they need you to trust them to deliver.
This is really powerful advice and I
want to spend a little more time here,
which is keeping people on board and engaged
and motivated through a crisis. So this kind of
almost script you just shared is really great. Is
there anything else that you found useful or any
advice you could share for helping a founder
keep the team on board, keep people excited,
driven? These words you shared I think is a
really good example, is there anything else?
So during crisis, people will appreciate more
than anything else transparency. And if you hide
information from them, then they would leave, they
don't trust you anymore. But if there is a crisis,
and look, if there is a crisis then
everyone knows that there is a crisis,
it's not surprising for anyone. And this
is where they expect your leadership the
most. This is where they expect you to be
there for them. And tell them that this is
what we're going to do. And if ABC happens,
then we will be successful. And if it's not,
then we will die. And I want you to
believe that we can deliver A, B and C,
and I want you to stay here for that part of the
journey. And this is really, really dramatic,
this is perhaps the most important part. Look,
during crisis, the team is the one that is going
to take you out of the crisis, and you need them
more than ever. And guess what? They need you.
When you talk about being transparent and
open about everything, what's an example
of just how far you recommend people
go? Because you could just be like,
here's all of our data and metrics and
numbers, here's what our investors are
emailing me. How real do you recommend
people get? I know it's hard to just
summarize in a couple sentences, but
what's a good way to illustrate that?
So number one, don't sugarcoat. So you basically
you don't need to share all the feedbacks from all
the investors. You can tell them, "Look, I met
dozens of investors in the last couple of weeks
and they're all saying no." Or we had a signed
term sheet and the investor disappeared. Okay,
that's fine. It is what it is.
Look, the fact that it's ugly,
if you don't tell that it's ugly, it's still ugly.
And so I would share the essence. And if we have
metrics, then what I would like to do is believe
that everyone is aware of the metrics, of the key
metrics of the company. This is something that
in general I would say, "Oh, in the lobby of the
office, we should have the key metrics displayed
for everyone to understand this is what we stand
for, this is how well we are executing anyhow."
And so when they will see the numbers drop,
they know that the numbers drop. And this is
something that I will in general I would say,
look, key metrics, they should be shared
anyhow. And so in particular during crisis,
we should keep on sharing them. Definitely
not hiding information. So if you have a
major customer leave or investor disappear or we
are unable to sign a term sheet. And so this is
the highlight, this is the major issue. And
the details themselves, it's less critical.
Now if people ask, then answer. If someone ask,
"Okay, so how many investors have you met?" I'd
say no, then start counting, 37, be specific.
That's a great answer. I want to come back to
something you said that I think is so important
but so hard, which is to act fast. If I was
a founder, something changes in the market,
it's easy to say, "Okay, you need to
cut burn, you need go raise money,
down round." It's so hard to do, to lay people
off, to do all these challenging things for
your company. Can you again just help people
understand why it's so important to act fast?
You talked about optionality goes away. Just
like what actually happens there if you don't?
So I'll give you an example. So let's
say that you are almost run out of cash
and you believe that you're going to
raise capital in the next two month.
And if not, then you run out of cash. One of
the things that you might want to do is extend
the run rate. One other thing that you might want
to do is actually tell the people that we will be
running out of cash in two month. And number one,
I want you to help me even if we run out of cash
because there are good chances that we eventually
will be able to raise capital and recover that.
And number two, in order to get your support and
belief in the company I am going to offer you more
equity. So, the more equity is something that I
will do twice, once today, once you realize that
this is going to be challenging, and then again
if we need to ask people to reduce their salary
or do something dramatic around that.
And the first one is actually preventive
action. So you share the know-how, you share the
challenges that we are going to face. And you
demonstrate generosity not out of you have
to, but you demonstrate that. And then you
essentially dramatically increase their loyalty
and their commitment. And when you will need them,
they will be there. So this is one example.
The other example is about calculating end of
cash. And this is really, really important. So
let's say that you have run rate of X month, six
month. If you reduce burn by 50% today, then you
simply increase your run rate to a year. If you
don't do it today and you wait three more month,
then you only can do that for the ... so the first
three month you burn the same way that you did
up until now, and now you reduce that to half,
so you have six more month, total of nine month.
If you decided today that you need 12 month, and
you don't act today, you will never have 12 month.
Now, is that the only way to do that? No,
it's not the only way, but it's one of the
ways that by the way most companies will do.
So they will reduce burn rate today in order to
extend the run rate. Is that going to be more
helpful? Don't know. Really depending on the case.
If you had asked me if you reduce the burn rate,
increase the run rate, so now you have 12
month to raise new capital, is that going
to have higher likelihood of remaining with
the current plan and growth and raise capital
within six month? I don't know that. But this
is exactly the decision that you need to make.
That's a really great way of putting it.
Just the math means the leverage you have
now to extend runway is so much higher the
sooner you make the decision. And the key,
just going back to your algorithm of deciding
if we need to act in this way quickly,
is first think about what's being impacted,
then how long is this impact going to last,
and then how long do I have before you
run out of money. And those questions
is your advice for deciding, do we let
people go now, do we raise money now.
There is always, by the way, there is always
alternative for let people go. In general,
I would say letting people go is probably better
than reducing salary for everyone. But let's say
that you need cost reduction of 30%. One of the
options is let 30% of the people go. Another
option is actually reduce salary by 30% for
everyone. And it's going to have the same impact.
Not exactly, the same impact on the balance
sheet and on the P&L, but not necessarily on
the organization. If the organization feels that
they are committed to each other, they will prefer
the second way. If this is more of individuals,
then obviously they will prefer the first way.
Is there a different way? What about if management
gives up on their salary? That might make the
same impact. And definitely demonstration
of leadership. And by the way, increasing
the commitment of the rest of the organization.
So in that sense, I would say there are multiple
ways of reducing the cost. But in general, this
is always about impacting people. If you look at
the startup and you look at the budget, 70% of
the budget is people, maybe 75% of the budget is
people. Everything else is nickels and dimes. If
you're going to tell me, "Oh no, we are going to
start the supply of coffee to the office and this
is how we are going to reduce cost." No, this is
how you create dissatisfaction with the team and
you would reduce costs because some people would
leave because of that, not because of lack of
coffee, but because of inability to determine
and to make hard decisions. So end of the day,
if you need to reduce costs that means people.
That was really good advice and really good set
of options to consider versus laying people off.
So most of what we've been talking about right
now has been the cash crisis route. We've spent
a little time on the product market fit crisis
route. But I want to spend a little more time
there. So for the cash crisis route, you have
these kind of three questions and then it's like,
cool, this will tell you how quickly to
act and how severely to make cuts. In the
product market fit route, is it essentially if
you've lost product market fit, it's to pivot,
is that basically the question? And then it's
a question of where to pivot and what to do?
So the first question is, am I still relevant?
And probably the answer is no. And then the next
question that you basically say, "Okay, do
I want to pivot?" And for that I will say,
"If I would start today, is this is what I'm going
to do?" And if the answer is yes, then do it.
Now in many cases you say, "Oh, wait a minute, I
already have the organization and I already have
money in the bank and this is what I'm going to do
instead." I wouldn't necessarily do that. The way
that I would look at it is different. Because
the other alternative is basically say, "Wait
a minute, all of my underlining assumptions have
gone, they are wrong." I lost product market fit.
The value proposition that I had is wrong or is no
longer valid or no longer relevant. And therefore
I need to start from scratch. Do I really have
the assets to become successful on the new path?
And the assets could be technology that you
already developed, could be the team that
you already built, could be the know-how that
you have in that specific market that gives
you a significant advantage. And if any
of those is really, really significant,
then it's possible that you want to
pivot. Pivot basically say major fuck up,
all of our underlining assumptions have gone.
And because everything else, if it's not,
then that's part of the journey of failure. If
you'll tell me, "Oh, we tried this product or
we tried this feature and didn't work," then this
journey of fail. This is going to be your journey.
But once you figure out product market fit,
if it disappears, then pivot is one option,
shutting down is another option. And for shutting
down, there are two things that you need to ask
yourself. Do I have the energy to keep on going?
Maybe you basically say, "I spent the last seven
years trying to do that and now it's gone
and you know what? I need some time off."
And the other one is that do I really have the
assets to become dramatically successful? Pontera
is one of my startups that I started back in 2012.
And back then we called that FeeX. And we were
dealing with financial fees in Israel and we were
actually pretty successful. And then we decided,
okay, wait a minute, Israel is a small market,
let's move to the US. And we moved to the US.
And one day the CEO came to me and said,
"Look, we need to focus, I cannot do both,
so we need to pivot." And we stopped the
Israeli operation completely in order to
focus all of our effort on the US operation. And
then we realized that the nature of the beast is
different and therefore we need to re-look for
product market fit. And eventually we found that
with the regulations of the Obama administration,
and that was our product back in 2016 or 17.
And then the administration have changed
and now it's going to change again. And
they changed the regulation. And overnight we
figured out that ... And we were actually on
being a successful path. And we had to reinvent
ourself. Now, what we basically said is, "Look,
we have the energy to keep on going, we have
something, a thesis that we believe might be
relevant for us. We have the technology that
can serve the thesis and we have enough cash
to try it out." And we went back to the board
and we offered them two options. Number one,
we give you your money back. And number
two, this is what we're going to try.
And the interesting part is that investors
don't want their money back. They did not
invest in order to have their money back, they
invest in order to make a significant impact.
And obviously they don't want to go back to
their investors and tell them, guess what?
And so we had all the support to keep trying
something else. And since 2018, we are actually
being pretty successful on this path. And all of
a sudden, company is 12 years old, and we pivoted
twice. And now we are end of the day helping
Americans to retire richer. Helping financial
advisors to support you on your 401k plans,
on retirement saving plans. And the result is
pretty significant. So this company is on a path
of being successful, but we almost died twice.
And look, all the CEOs in the world, if you would
ask them, have you nearly died already? And they
will tell you yes. And then the next question
would be how many times? And they will tell you
multiple times. And if they're not, that means
that they're simply too early on their journey.
That's such an important point. It came up,
I just had Toby from Shopify on the podcast,
and he said exactly the same thing. That just
like the number of times Shopify almost died,
people have no idea. It's important
to know, that's very common.
Yeah. And I'm a good friend with Harley
Finkelstein, the president of Shopify,
and he told ... we exchanged horror stories
about nearly dying. And we are still here.
Just never give up. To double down on this
pivot point real quick. So the things you
should look at to help you decide if a pivot is
a good idea, you shared, you have some tech that
might be helpful in this new direction, you
have a team that's really well suited to this
new idea or you have some knowledge. Is there
anything else, just like what's that list of
things you should look at to see, to come up with
ideas/decide this is a good idea for us to pursue?
So going back to basic, but now you are already
running, so you probably have already validated
the problem or the value proposition. About
pivoting, so when you start you think that,
okay, I have this brilliant idea. And what
I really encourage people is first of all,
go and validate the problem, speak with
people, understand their perception of
the problem. And only then start to think about
the solution. Now, this is still not the case in
most startups. And this is fall in love with
the problem, not the solution. And for a few
reasons, and maybe number one reason is, look,
entrepreneurship journey is about creating value.
Simplest way to create value, seel a product,
that's it, simplest way. And I like simple.
But then in addition, when you focus on the
problem, then the problem is going to serve
as the north star of your journey. And when
you have a north star, you're going to make
less deviation from the course and increase the
likelihood of being successful. But by and large,
your story is going to be way more compelling.
If we will be here in 2007, and I will tell you
that I'm going to build an AI crowdsourced based
navigation system, you're going to say, "Oh yeah,
very interesting," But you don't care. If
I will tell you I'm going to help you to
avoid traffic jams, then you do care. When your
customer care, they want you to be successful.
And when they want you to be successful, they
are going to help you to become successful.
And so this is going back into pivoting the same
way, first of all, validate what's your value
proposition, what's the problem you're going to
solve. Now, in most cases you already validated
that because you in the market for some years
and you had dialogues with customers and you
already realized that. And maybe you already told
yourself, you know what? In my next startup this
is what I'm going to do. And so it's possible
that you already validated. And if you haven't,
then this is exactly the time to
revalidate the value proposition.
So this is the first thing that you need to do.
And then the second thing that you want to do is
ask yourself, do I really have a significant
advantage here? Do I really have the team,
the technology, the know-how to make a
leap from here and really lead the market?
And then the other part of it is, okay, do I
have the energy and the passion to go and do
it all over again? Because this is going back to
square one, trying to figure out product market
fit and then figuring out business model and then
figuring out growth and so forth. So the entire
journey from scratch. And if you answer yes to
all of those, so you have the very significant
value proposition and you think that you
have something that is going to accelerate
you dramatically because of the know-how, the
technology, the team, then the next thing that
you're going to do is validate it with the team.
In your underlining assumptions the team is going
to continue. Maybe, maybe not. This is
exactly the time that you would like to
validate that. And the way that you're going
to validate that is you basically say to them,
"Guess what? We are fucked. Our underlining
assumptions are no longer valid. And this is
our new opportunity and we can go this path or
we can die." And let's see what people, if they
believe in the new path, then this is a good idea.
In many cases, by the way, it's possible that
the new path will come from them. They're
the one that are closer to the customers,
they're the one that are closer to the technology.
They're the one that are probably know better than
you if this new path is actually valid or not.
And if this is the case, then you go and do it.
The last one that you want to ... Look, even
if you don't have the money for it, let's say
that you don't have plenty of cash in the bank, go
back to the investors and go back to raise capital
because now you actually have a very significant
advantage. You already have a technology,
you already have a team, you already have the
know-how, you are already second time entrepreneur
because pivot is like restarting from scratch
or you are already multiple times entrepreneur,
so you are way more attractive today than
when you were a few years back. And so go
back to existing investors and new investors
and raise more capital for this new journey.
I like this algorithm. I was writing it down as
you're talking. So basically when you're deciding
to pivot, looking for opportunities
to pivot, step one is find a problem,
validate there's a problem that exists.
Step two is figure out if you have the tech,
team or know-how that gives you an advantage to
win at solving this problem. Then ask yourself,
do you have the passion and energy to be
spending your life and the many number of
years attacking this problem? Then validate your
team, wants to also go after this problem. And
then check with your investors and try to get
money to fund you going after this problem.
Yep.
Awesome.
And I like this order now.
Some people will tell you,
"Oh, my order is different." And I'm not saying
if this is the right thing or the wrong thing,
but I think that ... One of the reason that I say
this is the order is, look, when you validate the
problem and the value proposition, even if you
don't have the passion, if it's been validated,
your passion will be built up. Because then you
speak with potential customers and you tell them,
"This is what I'm thinking of doing and this
is how it's going to help you." They will say,
"Yes, I need that. Can you do it tomorrow?"
Then all of a sudden you get excited about it.
And usually when I speak about consumers
then I tell people, look, when you go and
speak about the problem, if the answer that you
are going to get is, "Oh, I know someone that
had this problem," don't follow this path.
If they will tell you, "No, no, no, no, no,
this is not the problem, the problem is," and
they will give you their version of the problem,
this is where you want to follow that. To a
certain point, if you speak with enough people,
you would have the sense that you are being sent
on a mission. And this is where your passion is
going to go through the roof. And so don't start
with the passion, let the passion be built.
I totally feel that. I have friends who started
this company Zip, which is a procurement,
a really good procurement platform.
And I don't know if they were growing
up wanting to be building a business
that helps procurement experiences be
better. And they pivoted six times before
they picked this idea. But through that,
I think found how big of a deal this was and
how much happier people can be in their day
to day with a better product and got excited
about it. And now that's what they're building.
The best thing happen when you try
to validate a problem is that you
speak with someone and they will tell
you in a very strong emotional word,
"I hate that," or something like that. Yeah,
this is exactly what you're looking for,
you're looking for something that people will
engage emotionally and with strong emotions.
Someone once described it as you
want to look for their pupils to
dilate when you tell them, when
you talk about this problem.
Yep.
There was a quote I wrote down as you were talking
earlier that I think is really great. It's kind
of a framework for ... the way you used it is to
help you pick which direction to go. But I think
it's a useful framework in general for companies
and founders is ask yourself, if I were to start
today, what would I have done and what would I
do if I were to start this company again today?
I think that's such a powerful thing to always
think about even when everything's going great.
I agree. Today is the first day of the
rest of your life. And this is pretty
much everything in your life. So ask
yourself, knowing what I know today,
would I do something different? Now, if the
answer is yes, then do something different
today. Don't wait until next life or next company
or next relationship or next something. If you
basically know today that you should be
doing something different, then change.
I think that's extra important because
somebody will do that probably and compete
with you and put you out of business,
and it's better that you do that first.
But this is true for everything in your life.
Look, if you are working in a place and you
are not happy and you suffer there, then
I would say ... The guidance that I give
to my children is very simple. If you're not
happy at your working place, then ask yourself,
is there something that I can do to change
that? Then try to change that for the next
three month. If you're unable to change that,
then leave. You don't deserve to be unhappy. And
you need to control your own destiny. For me,
quitting your job, do you know what it means?
You fire your own job boss, that's what it
means. You fire your boss by quitting, that's it.
That's empowering, I like that. Okay, just, okay,
two more questions. One is I want to close the
loop on the Waze story. So you talked about
how Google launched, a competitor basically,
free turn-by-turn directions, that was
the business you were building and you
essentially had to change direction. What did you
actually do, how did you decide and realize this?
We didn't change. Back in 2010, we were simply
not good enough, we were still in the product
market fit iterations and iterations and
iterations, and we were not good enough.
And we kept on building and we kept on iterating
and iterating and iterating. But we almost ran
out of cash. And then we had this lucky day that
Microsoft decided to invest, and so did Qualcomm.
The funny part is that I had this dialogue with
Qualcomm Ventures and they told me that they're
not sure why is that important for them. And
I read someplace that they did not invest at
Twitter at $55 million. And this is exactly
what I told them, "May I remind you that
you did not invest in Twitter at $55 million
valuation. This is where Waze is today." And
obviously different story, but that was the fear
of missing out, the FOMO was [inaudible 01:14:58]
Yeah, I was going to say, good FOMO.
But the result was that we had enough cash
to keep on trying and keep on iterating and
iterating and iterating. And eventually we ended
up to be very successful. So that was not about
pivoting or changing directions or doing
anything dramatic. We basically say, okay,
we will need to reduce costs dramatically.
We decided that we are not ... By the way,
what we did is we reduced the salary of the
management only. And to a certain extent I would
say people didn't even know. We decided in the
management meeting that this is what we're going
to do. And if push come to shovel, then we will do
the next step and the next step and the next step.
But we were eventually able to raise capital.
So in that sense, the nearly die was a matter of
state of mind, but we did not run out of
cash, we raised capital just before that.
The story is actually really illustrative of
a point I was thinking as you were talking,
which is that product market fit crisis often
also leads to a cash crisis from
investors not wanting to invest.
In many cases, yes, in many cases.
You get a double whammy.
But to a certain extent I would say no.
Product market fit basically means that
you go back to square one. The other alternative
that you have, and by the way it's also valid,
is if you are unable to convince your existing
investors to reinvest in the company in order
to build the new part of the journey, the
new journey, then you know what? Shut down
the company and restart a new company that is
doing exactly that. And that's a bigger threat
for investors because they are not part of the
new journey. Now, they might want to say, "Oh,
the company owns the IP." The know-how is the
people, owned by the people, not the company.
How do you avoid the crisis? A lot
this advice is here, you have a crisis,
here's how to deal with it. Any advice for how
to avoid falling into a crisis as a founder?
Number one answer is no. Don't worry,
you will face crisis. And if you worry,
you're still going to face crisis. Number
two is that, look, it's way easier to deal
with a crisis if you have plenty of cash
in the bank. So if you can raise capital
and maintain higher level of cash in the bank,
it will help you to go through the next crisis,
but it's not going to avoid it. So always be
funded is a good advice. But in general, look,
you do not prepare for the next crisis because
you don't know what kind of crisis it's going
to be next. And you can assume that there will
be the next crisis. Trust me, there will be the
next crisis. And then the most important part
is that you analyze that fast and then you act
fast. But you cannot prepare for it because
you don't know where it's going to come from.
And this is really, really important. The best
preparation is that if you have plenty of cash.
In general I would say if you have plenty of cash,
then this is going to help you for many things.
When you say plenty of cash, do you have
any advice, kind of common advice of have
18 months of runway, is there anything
there you'd recommend for founders?
And this is really depending on the CEOs and
their risk attitude. Some of my CEOs prefer
to have two to three years of run rate. They
basically say, "This is my comfort zone. I know
that I can restart if I need to. I know that I can
suffer major crisis. I know that I can go into new
direction if I want to. I know that I can expand
and try something completely different if I want
to." And this is not necessarily as a result of
a crisis. So maybe you basically say here is an
opportunity and I have the cash to do that.
My general rule will be around 18 month.
Are you okay with 12 month? Yeah, if you risk
taker, bigger risk taker then you can survive
with 12 month. But the challenge is that,
look, if you have shorter period of time,
then you don't have enough time to execute, you
need to focus on fundraising all the time. And
you want to focus on creating value and
not just bringing cash into the company.
Yeah. Obviously the downside of raising more
runway is you're giving away more of your company,
but it's always this trade off, how much
to sell, how money to get. Being a founder,
what a tough gig. And I'm going to come back to
this quote you had that I shared at the beginning
of the podcast, which is building a startup
is a journey from one crisis to the next.
Yeah. It goes back into how ... the
other three dimensions of a startup,
it's a roller coaster journey with ups and downs
and ups and downs, and it's a journey of failures
because we are trying to build something new
that no one did before so we tried multiple
things. For that, Albert Einstein used to say
that if you haven't failed that because you
haven't tried new things before. And it's a long
journey, it's a very long journey. In particular,
the longest part is until you figure
out product market fit. And now I add
the fourth dimension of that, that this is
a journey from one crisis to the next one.
How many companies have you
started, 10 last time I saw?
Yeah, about, a little bit more than that, yeah.
A little bit more than that.
Not all of them are going to be
successful, but most of them are.
In some form. And you just keep doing it. You're
a glutton for crisis is what I'm hearing here.
I'm not here for the crisis, I'm
there for the value creation.
Uri, is there anything else that
you wanted to share that you think
might be helpful to get into before we wrap up?
I really like this podcast, I really like it.
Me too.
And hopefully, in my mind, this is my mindset of
a teacher, my destiny is about value creation,
and if this podcast or this book, this one,
can help people to become more successful,
then I fulfill my destiny.
Uri, I'm so delighted to be helping you fulfill
your destiny. Two final questions. Where can
folks find the book? When is it for sale? And
then just how can listeners be useful to you?
The book is going to be published
in about a month from now. And it
is already available for pre-orders on Amazon,
but later on it will be on bookstores
throughout the US and Canada and so forth.
What's the date it'll be published
because we're recording this ... Maybe
it's coming out around the time we
publish this. So what's the date?
I think it's February 15th.
Okay, great. I think this is coming out
right around there, so perfect timing.
So perfect timing. And you can follow me
on LinkedIn or you can go to my website,
urilevine.com. And I want you to read the
book. End of the day, you asked me at the
beginning what do I want to accomplish? Do I
want people to buy the book or read the book?
And I told you, "Look, everything that I'm
trying to do in my life is about doing good
and doing well." So buying the book is
the doing well part of it and reading
the book is the doing good part of
it. And I want you to read the book.
That's so good. Uri, thank
you so much for being here.
Thank you, appreciate it.
Bye everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.