... the CEO of the company you work at
now, Mercury, tweeted a few years ago,
where he basically was very proud of not
having any product managers. Clearly,
you have product managers today. You're
a product manager at Mercury. What was
the sign to Immad and the leadership team
that it was time to hire product managers?
The bottlenecks started popping up. To take
things from soup to nuts on every single project,
it requires design and eng then to
take on a lot more responsibility,
which means somebody's doing the PM
duties even if you don't have a PM.
What is it that you think people most miss
about the value that a PM brings to your org?
There's just so many different flavors of
what a product manager is. We use this idea
of like a pioneer, a town settler, and a city
planner. So the pioneer is a PM that's really
good at zero to one. Settler PM is in that growth
stage of maturity of a product. You're in a town,
there might be a bank, there might be a post
office, but nothing more than that. And then
a city planner is a PM that's really good
at mature products. They have the city.
Let's talk about the final big
topic, going multi-product.
The organizational structure is really important.
One thing we learned was having new product areas,
new seedlings being too close within the
true org structure to the core banking
or payments or mature products made it
hard for that new product to even grow.
Today, my guest is Rohini Pandhi. Rohini
is currently a product leader at Mercury
where she leads the product expansion team,
which incubates and scales new product lines
within Mercury. Previously, she spent over
seven years at Square, also known as Block,
leading product work on Square Payments, invoicing
and the Bitkey hardware Bitcoin wallet. She's also
the co-founder of the startup bootcamp,
Transparent Collective, and a very active
angel investor. In our conversation, we talk
about why founders are often so resistant to
hiring product managers and Mercury's journey
on deciding to hire their first PM and then
scale their product management team. Also, we get
into what attracts great product managers to join
your company. She makes an argument for why it's
important to invest in quality and user experience
versus just working on things that move metrics
and how that could differentiate your business.
We also do a deep dive into how she successfully
launched a half dozen new product lines at Mercury
just this past year, which is extremely rare
and very hard to do, and also something that
every single startup hopes to do and tries to
do and often fails. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's the best
way to avoid missing future episodes,
and it helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you Rohini Pandhi.
This episode is brought to you by Cloudinary,
the foundational technology for all images
and video on the internet. Trusted by over
2 million developers and many of the world's
leading brands, Cloudinary is the API-first
image and video management platform built for
product leaders who rely on visual storytelling
to express their unique product value, who are
building engaging web and app experiences and
who understand that harnessing the power of AI to
automate is the only way forward. Gil Grossman,
engineering team lead at Fiverr, says that
our users share billions of images, video,
and audio files. Cloudinary's ability to automate
our post-production work at scale amounts to a
savings of up to 92,000 work days per month. Think
bold, build big, ship fast. Let Cloudinary handle
your media needs. Start your free plan today at
cloudinary.com/lenny. I'm excited to chat with
Christina Gilbert, the founder of OneSchema, one
of our longtime podcast sponsors. Hi, Christina.
Yes, thank you for having me on, Lenny.
What is the latest with OneSchema? I know you now
work with some of my favorite companies like Ramp,
Vanta, Scale, and Watershed. I heard
that you just launched a new product
to help product teams import CSVs from
especially tricky systems like ERPs.
Yes, so we just launched OneSchema FileFeeds,
which allows you to build an integration with
any system in 15 minutes as long as you can export
a CSV to an SFTP folder. We see our customers all
the time getting stuck with hacks and workarounds.
And the product teams that we work with don't have
to turn down prospects because their systems
are too hard to integrate with. We allow our
customers to offer thousands of integrations
without involving their engineering team at all.
I can tell you that if my team had
to build integrations like this,
how nice would it be to be able to
take this off my roadmap and instead
use something like OneSchema and not just to
build it, but also to maintain it forever.
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many
horror stories of multi-day outages from
even just a handful of ad records. We are
laser-focused on integration reliability to
help teams end all of those distractions
that come up with integrations. We have
a built-in validation layer that stops
any bad data from entering your system,
and OneSchema will notify your team
immediately of any data that looks incorrect.
I know that importing incorrect data can cause
all kinds of pain for your customers and quickly
lose their trust. Christina, thank you for
joining us. And if you want to learn more,
head on over to oneschema.co. That's oneschema.co.
Rohini, thank you so much for
being here. Welcome to the podcast.
Thank you, Lenny. I'm excited to be here.
I'm very excited to have you here. I want
to start with this tweet that the CEO of the
company you work at now, Mercury, tweeted a few
years ago, where he basically was very proud of
not having any product managers, of this idea
that engineers are going to do the PM work,
designers, basically everyone's doing PM duties.
And clearly, you have product managers today,
you're a product manager at Mercury. And
the reason I want to chat about this and
spend some time here is a lot of
founders, there's this meme of,
"We don't need product managers. Who needs
PMs? What a waste. They slow everything down,
they disempower people on the team." And
then eventually they realize, "Oh, okay,
I see the value of PMs." So I want to spend some
time on this topic. How does that sound broadly?
Perfect. Let's go into it. Okay.
So first of all, how many engineers/employees that
Mercury have by the time they
ended up hiring the first PM?
Prior to two years ago, there were no PMs
at the company, and I think at that time,
there was probably close to 400 employees
across Mercury. I'd say at least half of
them were in some level of the R&D roles, so
engineering, design, those types of core roles.
Wow, so 200 engineers, 400 employees?
Probably. Probably.
That's pretty far. Okay, great. So
this is going to be really good.
Okay. And then how many PMs are there now roughly?
Now, we have about 30 PMs across the company,
and I think it's split between junior and more
experienced PMs, but it's about more than half are
senior PMs with managers baked in there somewhere.
Okay, and then where do you fit in the timeline
of no product managers to the PM team is built?
So yeah, so two years ago, no PMs at Mercury
or no one with that official title. There are
still people doing the PM duties and having those
responsibilities. And then I joined about a year
ago, so I think they were in their, what was the
first set of learnings from that first year of
having PMs and then me joining and doing a bit of
revamping of the product discipline internally.
Okay, cool. So there's a few threads that are
going to be really interesting here. One is
clearly, Mercury has done well and has thrived
without PMs for a long time. So I think there's
that thing. And then there's also just how
they built this team to be successful. So I
want to start with that first kind of thread
of just a lot of founders start off feeling
I don't need product managers. Who needs
them? Everyone's going to do PM duties.
They're so annoying.
Yeah, so annoying. Just slow [inaudible
00:07:37] down. What do they even do all day?
They're a bottleneck. Yep.
Yeah, exactly. But I think it's rare to actually
work out really well. A lot of companies just
become chaotic without PMs and I think Mercury did
something right in order to be successful without
PMs for a long time. So here's the question,
just what do you think Mercury had in place
or needed to have in place to be successful for
as long as they were without product managers?
I think the crux of it comes down to the
founders. And the founders are your original PMs,
and I think whenever I talk to any small seed
stage company who's asking, "Should I hire a
PM?" I'm like, "Absolutely not. Until you cannot
do the job anymore, you yourself should be the
PM." The co-founders, the founders, they need
to be that. And I think this was true even at
Square. I guess I got lucky with some of my past
experiences being at places that took product
seriously or the work that product does and
the intentionality of making product decisions.
It doesn't matter that there wasn't a PM title
necessarily at the company, but you need to be
as close to the customers as you possibly can. You
need to be as close to the solution that's getting
built. And in those early days, the founder needs
to be that PM, they need to take on those duties.
I think you talked about what was the magic piece
of it? I do think it's hiring amazing engineers,
hiring amazing designers, because as you scale,
those are the people, the disciplines that you
really need to build your solution in the software
product world. And so having those types of folks
that have that product obsession, have that
product mind already there, makes me excited
to join companies that hated PMs or had a negative
reaction to this idea of a PM because they already
do the product role, they already have that
implicitly as part of the way that they operate.
They have these autonomous teams that are able
to make local decisions in their product surface
areas, and so they know they have this intuition
and they're already close to the customer,
they're already close to how to build it. And I
think that's what made Mercury successful at the
start of not having any PMs. I think early
Square days, it was the same exact story.
Following this thread, what was the
sign to Immad and the leadership
team that it was time to hire product managers?
There's one element, that's scale. It's just
there's so much going on, and a single PM,
a single CEO couldn't handle that kind of scale.
We have three co-founders, but even at some point,
that scale becomes too broad for three PMs to
handle. And I think there was one, the bottlenecks
started popping up. So if every decision kind
of depends on these co-founders to make every
single call, things just slow down or even halt
until they're available again. The other piece
was complexity. We were starting to not only scale
but just grow in complexity. And when you think of
fintechs, you have a lot that you need to work...
You have a lot of partnerships, cross-functional
collaboration you need to do. We need to work
with compliance, we need to work with legal,
we need to work with risk, we need to do all of
these checks before a product even gets launched.
And so to take things from soup to nuts on every
single project that's kind of going out the door,
it requires design and eng then to take
on a lot more responsibility, which means
that somebody's doing the PM duties even
if you don't have a PM, but then that means
they're not doing their engineering or design
responsibilities. And so I think for Mercury, that
kind of started breaking way before the 200 or 400
employee marker. That probably broke under the 100
marker. And so what they had was generalists.
They hired these "business lead" titles,
and those business leads started doing those
cross-functional collaboration meetings, making
sure everything was kind of like the Is were
dotted, Ts were crossed type project management
pieces of the PM duties. And they started
becoming the product managers, so to speak,
within the company. And then they officially
changed titles about two years ago, I think.
So a bunch of those business leads became PMs. The
problem with that became they weren't PMs, they
didn't have experience in the PM role, and so the
core, maybe the basics of what product management
needed internally were missed. Strategic planning
wasn't exactly right or road mapping was really
hard for some of these folks. Prioritization,
doing any sort of goal settings, doing deep
customer research wasn't necessarily part of what
they've been trained for or had gotten experience
with. And so they kind of struggled with a bit
of that. And I think in hindsight, we should
probably have done the official transition to the
PM role a lot sooner, but hence, it's always 2020.
This is so interesting. So one, it feels like
the team was like, "No product managers." And
then they're just like, "Okay, you guys do this
thing that's quite sort of product management,
but we're not going to call you product
managers. You're something else." And
then eventually it's like, "Oh, I see. There's
people that are very good at all these things
that we need help with and maybe we should
just admit that and that's okay. We need PMs."
I think so. And one, it's good to
just have that recognition of, okay,
here's what these folks are really good at, and
when you hire a really good PM, they can make
the product velocity, the quality just 10X better.
Yeah, that's what I always say. A lot of people
are like, "Oh, PMs suck. They make everything
worse on our teams." And I'm like, "You just
haven't worked with a great PM." Because great
PMs make your life easier. You have more joy.
You could do the thing you want to do more.
Yes, yes, 100%.
Okay. Let's talk through the journey of
building the product team at Mercury.
So it went from zero, we don't need
PMs, to 200 engineers, potentially,
you could argue it was 100 because they had sort
of PMs that were doing the PM job to the PM team
now. So a lot of founders are trying to figure
out what does the beginning of my product team
look like? Who do I hire? What does that look
like and how does it scale over time? And you
were in that journey. Can you just talk
through the journey of Mercury building
out their product team and any lessons along the
way for folks that are trying to do this today?
I think the first step for us was just defining
what the discipline is and what the expectations
of a product manager are internally. When
I started, a lot of the questions that came
from the PM groups are like, "Am I doing this
right? What should I be doing? How should I be
doing it?" And so step one was almost just putting
that on paper and making sure we were all aligned,
from leadership, down to an individual PM, on
what those expectations of the role were. So
one of the first things that we put together
was a career ladder. It was just literally
a matrix of the role at different levels and
expectations, and we kind of put in what was
really important to us. So we have a career ladder
for Mercury overall just for everybody at Mercury
that hits some of our core values. And that was
set the foundation of it, like humility, low ego,
those types of things are really important to us.
But then what was it that added on in order to be
a PM at Mercury and what were those expectations?
So we kind of took a step back and we said, all
right, what we want is for Mercury PMs to strive
towards building a product, building products that
our customers just genuinely love. And that was
really important to us. So that was one vector of
the career matrix. And then the other was the work
that you do needs to have a positive impact on the
business in whatever way that is. It doesn't have
to be a revenue goal or anything like that, but
it needs to be some sort of outcome-based impact.
And then there was also work around can you build
the long-term vision? Can you communicate that?
Can you... Again, we're in a regulated space,
can you work with cross-functional leaders?
And so we started building out these
necessarily skills across the different roles,
putting that on paper. Then that led to, okay,
we know what our current PMs need to
be able to do. As we bring in new PMs,
we need to update our hiring process and interview
process to fit these same sort of criteria that
we're looking for. So what skills do we want to
figure out? Where's the signal in the interview
process to say that these are the skills that we
really value at Mercury and this person has them?
So we test for things like product sense, customer
and quality obsession is really important to us.
Analytical skills, strategic or system-wide
thinking skills are really important to us.
We pretty much took what we had in that career
ladder and applied it to the interview process.
One thing that I would love to have in the future
is a written element of our interview process.
We don't have that yet, but I really do think
quality and writing demonstrates this ability to
go in depth with something and to really put your
thoughts on paper. And so there's something in
there that I really want to try to do in the next
few months or quarters and just experiment with,
but we'll see how that goes. But aside from
that, I think we're getting to a really good
place with some of our hiring and interview
process to get the right folks in the door.
That's actually really interesting. I've
never heard of a PM interview process
with a essay component and it makes so much
sense because so much [inaudible 00:16:49].
It's something about being able to edit, being
able to put thoughtful content in there and have
a two-pager that gets everyone aligned on
what you're trying to communicate. It's a
really important skill, especially at the senior
levels, especially at a scaling, growing company.
Yeah. So what I love about what you talked
about is something that basically every
company has to reinvent from scratch.
What is a product manager? What are
their responsibilities? What is the career
path? What does success look like? What
does interviewing look like? What helped you
develop this? I imagine you borrowed a bunch
from Block and places you worked. Is there
anything else for folks that are trying to
do this themselves versus just copying exactly
what you did to help you develop these things?
I think it was a mix of yes, taking work
that others had already done. One of my old
professors used to say, well-stolen is half
done. And I think that's very true. And so-
Well-stolen is half done.
That's right. Well, it has to be well-stolen.
And then you're only halfway done once you
get to that point, but it does help. And I
think taking some of those cues from Block,
but then also just talking to senior product leads
across companies and saying, "What do you guys
test for? How do you do this? What are some key
learnings that you've had?" was really helpful.
And then we kind of went and worked with our
exec team. What were the values that you really
think are important? There's some skillsets
that are just table stakes for a PM to have,
but then there's superpowers that you want to
flex into at different companies or at different
roles. And so really just kind of baking that
in. You want to stay a little weird, you want
to stay your personality as part of this process.
A good example is we still go through... We have
this Mercury presentation in our interviews, and
the prompt is very, very generic. It's just talk
about something that you're interested in and
talk in depth to a panel about it. And what we're
really testing for there is attention to detail,
the craft and care, the desire to go deep into a
specific area and show your passion for that area.
One of the PMs, we talked about his presentation
internally a lot was he went through... I think
it was an Airbus or a Boeing plane, and truly
just from soup to nuts, what was the reason for
this type of plane structure, all the way to what
kind of bolts do they use for this plane and why
are those important? And just going into... Yeah.
[inaudible 00:19:10] how that turned
out to be very prescient and important.
I know. We had a lot [inaudible 00:19:15]
of questions after. Yeah. But yeah,
it's just something that shows off your
personality, shows that you care about
a topic in depth and you're able to go
into the details of something like that.
So to reflect what you shared of here's what to
build a product org, to start hiring PMs, you need
to have in place a career ladder with basically
the skills that you're looking for from the PMs so
that it's clear what you're looking for, there's
values of the PM org. I imagine there's a job
description, just describe the responsibilities
of the role and then the interview process.
Yeah.
Okay, cool. Something I should have highlighted
that you spoke about earlier that I
think is a really important lesson of
a sign that it's time to hire PMs is essentially
what you highlighted as bottlenecks. Your team
is starting to get bottlenecked more and
more. Just coming back to that real quick,
do you have a sense of just, it sounds like
there was already bottlenecks, things are not
going amazing all the time. And okay, where does
it flip to like, "Okay, shit, we really need PMs
now."? Do you have any insight there of just like,
okay, now is the time versus wait a little longer?
The one piece of advice I always have is don't
hire PMs too early. It's not worth it. There's
not a need for it. And I think when founders
are asking themselves that way too early,
it feels like they're giving over the reins to
somebody else to handle everything from customer
conversations, the product development, the
personality of what this company needs to be.
And so you want to be as close to it as possible,
but I think you do start bringing PMs in when,
one, work just isn't getting done without
you, you are that bottleneck as a founder.
Or when people other than you are doing the
core PM work at scale. So design and eng are
starting to do more of that and not doing some
of the core stuff that they need to be doing.
And similarly, I guess, when you can't
scale yourself in the decision-making
or wearing multiple hats or doing the
cross-functional collaboration with folks,
getting things from start to finish, that's
another sign that you probably need to just
hire some PMs or project managers in that
space. And then truly when it's like, okay,
you need a product person here is when you
start moving into adjacent surface areas
or different product areas with different
target segments of customers, because now,
you have to learn what that customer is, what they
need and what you should be building for them.
I love that you mentioned that. We're going to
spend a bunch of time on that. I know that's
what you spend a lot of time on at Mercury. And
I actually have a post on what is a sign you need
product managers now, and you touched on
all the points that I made in this post,
which is bottlenecks or you want to go deep on
a specific subject and hire someone to take it.
Snapchat actually is a good example of that,
where they brought in their first PM when they
wanted to go deep on ads and they brought
in someone just like, that's your thing.
That's perfect. Yes.
Okay, cool. We'll link to
that in the show notes. Also,
something I'll link in the show notes
that will be very helpful to people,
I have the career ladders of something like 20
to 30 companies, the attributes they look for
and links to their actual ladders. And so for
folks that are developing this, we'll give you-
Love that.
[inaudible 00:22:21].
Yes, I think I saw that. I probably referenced it
at some point and just went into my subconscious.
So as a final question along this topic of
building out PMs, hiring PMs for the first time,
for someone that's still like, "I don't know, I
don't really want product managers at my company
and they're just so annoying.", what is it that
you think people most miss about the value that
a PM brings to your org that may be a sign?
"Oh, okay, I see. Maybe we do need this."
All right, so I think there's different kinds
of PMs and different flavors of PMs. One thing
that I really, I feel like sometimes gets lost in
when we talk about, oh, I've met one PM and they
kind of didn't do what I wanted them to do or they
didn't work in the way that I wanted them to work,
so therefore, all PMs suck. There's a problem
with that because there's just so many different
flavors of what a product manager is, and
it depends on the company, it depends on the
industry, it depends on the role within a company.
And so a framework that I really like using to
determine, okay, what kind of PM do you need
and then hire for that is something that I
learned at Square. We use this idea of a pioneer,
a town settler, and a city planner. And that idea
is like, okay, so the pioneer is a PM that's
really good at zero to one, they can create
something from nothing. You're pioneering into
this uncharted territory. There's nothing there
for you. There's not any sort of infrastructure.
You're building it from scratch. You're kind of
taking natural resources and seeing how you
can reapply them into building what you need
in order to survive and then hopefully grow.
The town settler PM is in that growth stage of
maturity of a product. They're really working
on, again, to use the same metaphor, I guess,
you're in a town, there might be a bank, there
might be a post office, there might be a school,
and there might be some gravel roads, but nothing
more than that. And so you have some level of
infrastructure, but what you're trying to do
is further grow the town that you're building
out and put in some foundational elements but
also try to do some experiments. Maybe things
don't work out exactly the way you want, but
then you also want to build for the future.
And then a city planner is a PM that's really
good at mature products, really good at driving
efficiencies at scale. They have the city.
Everything that they do touches hundreds,
thousands, millions of customers immediately. And
so the type of PM that you need for something like
that is going to be very different than a zero to
one PM. And so when people, especially founders
say, "I don't want a PM.", I think it's because
they're thinking of a mature city planner when
they could find a former entrepreneur, a former
founder, a good pioneer to build out the next
set of products, or they really need somebody
who's great at growth and starting to put some
of the process in but not build it to the point
of I'm a big mature enterprise company anymore.
I love this metaphor. And is the advice that
as the smaller you are, the earlier in the
spectrum you want to be hiring? More pioneers
and a few town settlers as you build your team?
Probably. I think it just really depends on
what you're hiring for. Even for Mercury,
we had our banking, core banking services, we're
still a mature product in our spectrum. Everything
that we do there, we have to truly not even
measure it twice, measure it three times,
cut once, be really sure about what we're doing.
And that scale and the ability to have a PM that
can think about all of that scale is really
important. And so you really want to test
out have they done it before? Do they know what
they're talking about? And then in which case,
were you willing to take riskier bets versus
being really conservative about what you're
doing and then determine what kind of PM you need
for it. Because otherwise, you see the resumes,
you see what they say they've done.
But when you've talked to somebody,
when you're interviewing someone, really try to
drill into what kind of experience they are good
at, what they want in their next role, because
otherwise, the resume without the receipt is just
a piece of paper and you want to get the receipts.
What's the work that they've actually done?
Following this thread, I asked a bunch of people
that work with you at Mercury and Block what to
ask you. And one of the questions that I loved
came from the COO of Mercury, Jason Zhang. And
his question was, what do you think attracts
great product managers and great talents to
a company? What makes them hungry to join your
company? How do they hire a Rohini, basically?
Okay, there's a few answers to this. Maybe just
starting off, let's take away some of the table
stakes. Let's assume that candidates know that the
company's viable, it's doing well, paying market
rates, all of that. The candidate and the product
have good... There's a resonance with that. The
culture has good vibe checks. So taking away kind
of the table stakes of hiring, I think there's a
couple things from the company side and then the
candidate side. I think from the company side,
it really boils down to do you understand the
candidates that are coming through the door,
especially when you're hiring for seniority and
experience, you kind of have to take it like a
product manager would think about this problem
and say, "All right, if this is my customer,
what's their goal? What's their jobs to be
done?" kind of an idea and consider where the
PMs would be that you're hiring for on this...
Actually, a mentor of mine had this great
framework. He said that every career follows
this S-curve. And if you think about the Y
axis being kind of level of ambiguity, X axis
being level of scale, you start off in this S,
kind of near the origin, and you're usually
trying, especially when you're just starting
off in the discipline or your career, you have one
project, low ambiguity, and you're just saying,
"Can I do this one thing? Can I fix onboarding?"
There's only so many different ways to cut that
up and do it. And you know the goal, it's
a defined goal. You're just kind of driving
towards being able to make these improvements or
make it better, make it better designed, whatever
you need to be doing. It's like this one project.
And then you kind move around along that S at the
bottom and you're doing multiple projects with
low ambiguity still, but can you handle multiple
things and juggle them all at the same time?
At some point, you get into this inflection
point and you have this one really ambiguous
problem set at some point in your career it's like
10X revenue in 12 months. There's a lot of
different ways you could probably do that, but
there's a lot of wrong ways to probably do that.
And there's a few right ways and you got to figure
out which way is up and there's just so much
ambiguity and you just don't know how to maybe
do that immediately. But that's the challenge for
that part of your S-curve. And then at another
scale, it's like towards the top of that S,
you're pretty much just doing all ambiguous
projects or problems at scale. That's all that
hits you. So you think of a VP of product CPO
kind of level. All it is is strategic questions
that you don't know the answers to and have to
figure that out across 10 or 12 different topics.
And so I think going back to how to attract these
types of talent, know where on the S-curve they
are and what's their next step in that S-curve
because then you can say, "All right, I can then
give you a fun challenge for what you need next in
your career." I think senior folks want to know,
is a problem area big enough? Is it meaty enough
where I wake up every day and I get to be working
on this scope and working to serve these types of
customers? Will it challenge me? Will it make me
a better PM? Those are the considerations that
they're making. And then the second consideration
is who do I get to work with? So we actually kind
of talked about this in a recent post that we
wrote for your newsletter of the functional types
of organizational structures. And I think when
you have a functional structure within your org,
it's really nice because then, you can say, "oh,
I get to work with these types of PMs because
there's a product lead, there's a product group."
And I play tennis. You want to play tennis,
you want to challenge yourself with people that
are a little bit better than you and bounce that
ball back and forth and it's fun. And the same
thing goes for the functional leads within design
and eng because those are going to be your peer
groups. You want to make sure that you're working
with folks that are excited and are fulfilled
by doing this kind of work. And so for me, it
honestly comes down to those pieces, understanding
that the candidate where they are and then
communicating things to them in a way that breeds
transparency, honesty, trust overall. I tell them
when I have conversations with candidates, the
good, the bad, the ugly. I want to be as upfront
as possible and where the challenges are for us
right now and where the opportunities are. What
I see as you don't want to over promise, but you
do want to sell the dream of why you're excited.
So that was awesome. There's so much here. So
I'm going to reflect back a few of the things
you said. So when you're trying to hire the
best people, a few things here that are really
helpful is one, this S-curve, I drew it as you
were talking of ambiguity versus scale. And it
almost sounds like there's two things people
would want potentially. One is more ambiguity,
just something really meaty and complicated,
which is like they're accelerating up that
S-curve. The other is more scope. They're
already really good at, they've done a
bunch of really complex ambiguous stuff and they
just want something bigger and more impactful.
Yeah, that's a great way to... Probably
a third dimension on all of that.
And I love that it's not just
up into the right linear line,
it's an S-curve where it's like,
okay, now you're on something
really complicated. You're just going
[inaudible 00:31:38] this ambiguity Y-axis.
Exactly. And you can kind of trace
back our own careers into this idea
or even engineers and designers. It
doesn't have to be a product S-curve,
but it is really interesting to
kind see it from like, oh, yeah,
this is how you get good at the functional skills.
This is how you get good at the strategic skills.
What was that project for you, the one
that shot you up the S-curve on ambiguity?
I think it was probably at Square. The first
products that I worked on there was invoicing,
and it was one of those projects that was like, it
was a hack week project that just did really well
and we got a team on it. There was, I think at
the time that I started, it was three engineers,
a designer and myself. And it was like, "Okay,
just go make this work." And a lot of the first
sets of work was like, "Oh, we just need to make
this less hacky." Just make this a real product
that you're not embarrassed to be serving up
to customers that are using Square Invoices.
And then very soon, you started seeing the next
levels of work that needed to happen. And for me,
that was the first time that I got to
really just drive this strategic plan.
So Square Invoices first step one was like
just get it to a place that was functional.
It was the first rev of this product was almost
people wouldn't use it, but they would have to
spend so much time in order to figure out how
to use it. That's honestly when I knew we had
product market fit, but we just needed to make
it better. And then the next insight was, oh,
the people that are using our Square mobile app,
no idea that Square Invoices existed because it
only existed on desktop, on dashboard web. And
we're like, "Okay, get into mobile." That was
truly another step of growth that we just saw. And
then it was a huge step function there. And then
the next one was we wanted to draw out people. So
instead of going after existing Square customers,
we want it to be a front door product.
And that drove another step change of
growth for us because it was like, oh, when
you're looking for invoices, you don't think
of Square immediately, you're just looking for
invoicing solutions. And so the app store and
those types of places were much more interesting
for us to go after and do SEO and SEM on and
find net new customers. So there were some
really interesting challenges of saying,
"Okay, how do I increase the top of funnel? How do
I then also decrease risk loss at the loss level?"
And just being able to play around with all those
different levers was my huge ambiguity experience.
Yeah. Speaking of levers, I was going to
highlight just I love the way you described
this as such a good example of a great product
manager skill of just breaking the problem down
into these step-by-step steps versus like, oh,
shit, we have to scale this massive business
of invoicing. It's just make it less hacky, make
it easy to discover, bring in new customers. And
so I think that's a really good skill to learn
as you're ramping up this curve of ambiguity.
Absolutely. Yep.
Awesome. Okay. And then coming back to the other
tip you shared of how to hire amazing people,
just to close that thread, it's make it clear
how awesome the other people at the company
are that you're going to work with. Because
like you said, you're going to learn the most
from playing tennis with awesome people, and these
awesome people want to work with awesome people.
Exactly. And I think the other thing to add onto
that is the candidates are testing you as much as
you're testing them. And so that's why we had to
do the interview revamps because I would judge a
company based on the interview questions that they
would ask me. As a senior [inaudible 00:35:19], I
want to know that they understand what they're
even asking me for and they understand how to
change those prompts around for the right type
of candidate. And so a lot of what we did was
revamp things based on just my experience of
the Mercury interview [inaudible 00:35:34].
I love that. [inaudible 00:35:37] dogfooding it.
Exactly.
Okay, so I want to talk about quality
and I want to talk about multi-product,
going multi-product. Let's start with quality. So
classically, a lot of PMs are just not the person
that advocates for high quality user experience,
investing in things that aren't moving metrics.
And I know you're kind of on the opposite of
that. You actually have a really interesting
approach to advocating for quality and helping
people understand why it's worth investing in.
And in particular, you've worked on, in quotes,
"boring products", banking, finance stuff,
but have helped make them awesome and great
experiences. What can you share with folks
about how to advocate for investing in quality
when it's not something you can really measure?
This is something I've learned a lot from the
Mercury folks over the last year. Even the
OGs back at Square in the early days,
there was a lot with on the surface,
I think Immad even says this, on the surface,
it's completely irrational to invest in quality,
especially for a KPI-driven company or KPI-driven
company or organization, there's often this false
dichotomy that creeps up that's like you either
have to be this [inaudible 00:36:48] heavy of
experimentation, move fast type of company, or
you can be this design-heavy focus on artistry
but doesn't really drive any customer value. And
I feel like those two ends of the spectrum are
just completely insane. You need to be somewhere
in between. And I think what I've learned from
the companies that I've most recently been at is
the details done right really matter, especially
when you're in a boring industry like FinTech,
meaning it's just unsexy, there's not a lot of...
It's not like this consumer exciting app,
but you need the details to be precise,
to be intentional in order to breed that trust
and confidence that the customer base needs in
order to save its money with you in order to
move its money with you. One of the examples we
had recently is we launched a product called Bill
Pay. And in that, you can upload an invoice, you
can just drag and drop your invoice from a vendor
and we will OCR it, we'll read all the details,
and we'll pre-populate some fields for you. And
as you kind go through those fields and check that
we got everything right, the right-hand screen
zooms into the right part of the invoice. And
that little detail, that little additional, hey,
we just helped you with this and highlighted where
you need it to be, won't move a completion rate,
won't move a singular metric really. But it is the
thing that everyone who uses this product, every
customer that comes to me, they're like, "That
was fantastic. I loved using a product to pay my
bills." Which is not something you hear every day.
And I think one of the Mercury values that I've
really tried to internalize is have that intention
behind every detail in order to take that product
to that next level of care and craft. And when you
consider the compounding effect of all those
little intentional, incremental improvements,
altogether, it starts becoming a moat. It
becomes this competitive advantage for you. And
so I think there is a strong argument to really
think about quality craftsmanship, how you're
building something that can be evergreen and
beautiful, confidence-inducing, and trustworthy.
And then on the other side of it, I just think
it's building great products should be fun and
fulfilling for all of us. And so you want to
spend your life on something that people love
and enjoy using. I think that's something that
Jason's really taught me. And so by doing this,
by investing in quality, by thinking about
quality, you're also having the second-order
effect of attracting great talent who want to
be there and be proud of what they're building.
And then it also has this effect of endearing
customers to you because they know that you're
focusing on what matters and how to make their
lives a little bit easier and better and simple.
And so it's this circular effect that I do
think has compounding interest rates on it.
There's a couple of things here that I think about
as you talk about this. One is if there's a PM at
some bank that's like, "Oh, great, we're going
to do this. I love it. We're going to invest in
quality, we're going to make beautiful product."
It's hard to do in reality if the founder is not
on board and if it's not core to the principles
and values of the company. And so I think
you almost need that kind of top down. And the
other thought is I feel like there's kind of
like strategically, we will differentiate by
blank. And one of the blank can be quality.
Linear is a great example, Mercury is a good
example. A lot of competitors in the space,
we believe we can win by quality and experience.
And I don't think that exists in every market,
but thoughts on just that is like if
you decide this is our differentiator,
then that's a huge opportunity
to invest in quality in UX.
Yeah, I completely agree with both... One, it's
a cultural value, it has to come from the top,
it has to come from the beginning. And I think
the second piece of it is there was this trend of,
I don't know, B2B products that became, I think
maybe a decade ago, a big push was simplify it,
make it feel like a B2C product, make it simple,
make it easy to use. And there was this push
of just, I don't know, rounding corners and
making the fonts better or something like that,
using some white space. Just
very simplistic ideas of it.
But now, I think the next generation of all
of these products is not just make it simple,
make it still powerful and make it easy to use.
So now, you have both concepts coming together.
And so quality is truly just this idea of how
do you build these products that fit within a
small mobile screen and still have the full power
and capacity of an enterprise level product line,
but are still easy to use on the go. And
being able to do a bunch of banking that
wasn't even close to this level of ease
and customizations in two decades ago.
It's something that we really think is
the basis of why quality is embedded into
everything that we talk about and do. It's an
obsession within the company, quite honestly.
Interesting. So yeah, I feel like there's
a big rise and we will just make beautiful,
incredible high craft products probably because
there's so much competition and so many options
that that's one of the few remaining ways to
differentiate and stand out, especially in a
boring industry as... Like another example, this
company that I'm an investor in is called Zip,
which is procurement. And there's all these boring
ass companies that are billions of dollars and
just so ugly and it's like, cool, here's how we
can compete. We'll build an incredible experience.
Nobody wants to be at the other, the audience
end of this or the user end of this. And so
you don't want something that like, oh, it's for
procurement, so therefore they don't care. No,
everyone wants to have a nice experience in
dealing with the work that they have to do
day in and day out. And so I really do love
unsexy products that can just be done right.
And that's a cool opportunity for
PMs to just find a company that
is struggling in a market that's big
and just maybe this is how we went,
just make it incredible versus more features.
And I feel like I should write a post about
this. What are the ways to differentiate?
There's experience, there's probably price,
there's maybe features, just like we have the most
features like Jira. There's probably a few others.
Probably the customer segments
and who you're going after. Yeah,
I love this thread. I think we could
talk about that for another hour.
This could be a whole other... That'll
be your second visit to the podcast.
This episode is brought to you by Airtable
ProductCentral, the unified system that brings
your entire product org together in one place.
No more scatter tools, no more misaligned teams.
If you're like most product leaders, you're
tired of constant context switching between
tools. That's why Airtable built ProductCentral
after decades of working with world-class product
companies. Think of it as mission control for your
entire product organization. Unlike rigid point
solutions, ProductCentral powers everything from
resourcing, to voice of customer, to roadmapping,
to launch execution. And because it's built on
Airtable's no-code platform, you can customize
every workflow to match exactly how your team
works. No limitations, no compromises. Ready to
see it in action? Head to airtable.com/lenny
to book a demo. That's airtable.com/lenny.
Okay, so let's talk about the final big
topic that I know you're passionate about,
and this is what you work on at Mercury, which is
super cool, which is going multi-product, going
from one product that is doing well, to layering
on additional products. This is the holy grail for
a lot of founders, a lot of teams, expanding
TAM, finding more ways to generate revenue,
expanding into your customers, building
new products. You've done this at Mercury,
Block is really successful at this. So I want
to learn everything I can from you about how
to do this well. A lot of companies try this and
fail and waste a lot of time. So let's just talk
through this. What are maybe just lessons from
your experience building products, multi-products,
additional products at a company like Mercury?
Maybe just share some of the new products that
Mercury has just because to give folks a sense,
because I think people think of Mercury as a bank.
Everyone still does. And so we're in the early
days. So yeah, I'll take this opportunity to make
sure that we talk about which products first, and
then I can go through our lessons learned. But we
shipped a lot this year. There was just a ton of
activity this year, which was really exciting.
2024 marked the first foray into consumer for us.
We launched Mercury Personal Banking in April,
which has been a wild success and we have a lot
more coming up with personal banking as well. And
then we launched a suite of software that sits on
top of our business banking, our core offering.
And that suite allows our customers to do things
like the accounts payable work that they need to
do as they grow, accounts receivable, accounting
workflows, those types of things. And so in the
last, let's say, six, seven months, we launched
what I talked about before was Bill Pay in May,
we launched Invoicing, something near and dear to
my heart in August, we had updated spend controls
and spend management tools and employee
reimbursements that launched in October.
And each of these, one of my favorite learnings
from all this, or the favorite stats is each
subsequent launch that we just described took less
time than the previous from concept to launch. So
we're getting really good at understanding what
that product philosophy is, how we build products,
and then how we launch and find the right
product market fit within these systems.
And so a lot of exciting stuff. We're still in
the early days of building out the SaaS model,
building out personal banking, but lots more to
come. So excited for where Mercury is set up for
in the next few quarters. Going into some of maybe
the biggest lessons learned about going from one
product to multi-product, probably two general
categories. One, the organizational structure
is really important and probably as important as
just the product decisions, and the organizational
culture is also important. So one thing we learned
was having new product areas, new seedlings being
too close within the true org structure to the
core banking or payments or mature products, made
it hard for that new product to even grow because
they were always being pulled in, sucked in.
The gravitational force of a more mature
product always had prioritization work,
maintenance work, things that were more impactful
to be done. And so their roadmaps would always get
trumped by any of that. So it didn't afford
any space for seedlings to grow. And yeah,
this idea of when you have this small little fire,
you want to give it air in order for it to truly
blossom to a flame. And so the organizational
structure really gives these teams that space.
We actually created completely different orgs.
This is why my team exists as an expansion org
because it is completely separate from
some of the more mature product teams.
And when you say separate
dedicated resources on this project
for some number of... What's the
timeframe you give new seedlings?
We're thinking of these as small seed stage
companies and every quarter, every half year,
we look at them as like, do we want to keep
investing? And so there's no end time for
them to ever move back into the mature products
until they become, I don't know, series C company
in and of themselves. So we're not really
looking at an end time. We're just saying,
"You have this dedicated team. We'll continue
investing and providing headcount and whatever
you need as this product, this business
line shows the path towards success."
And I think that point is really important.
So it's basically every quarter/two quarters,
you check in, how's this going? Do you agree to,
here's a milestone that we're
looking for in the next quarter,
six months? Do you make it super concrete? Is it
pretty qualitative? How do you think about that?
We have goals and we also allow these teams...
They're so early that the learnings are really
important. It's just like an angel investment.
There's going to be pivots, we realize that.
We're not saying that we're going to kill it if
it doesn't hit X. But we do have goals in mind,
we have financial projections in mind, and we say,
"If you don't hit that, what's the
key learning that we've made that
we think we can still hit something in that
general direction in the next six months?".
And what does a seed team look like generally?
What are the resources you put into it?
I mean, it's the full cross-functional
squads of eng, design, product, data science,
everyone that you probably need. And then we
have cross-functional overlaps with our core
teams across the company. So sometimes
we will have dedicated... If we need a
dedicated CS or dedicated risk or dedicated
ops folks on these teams. But usually,
it's just leverage the central teams that
already exist for some of those functions.
And how many engineers do you usually
try to put on a seed investment?
It kind of depends. Our personal banking
product has a lot more engineers,
probably 3X than maybe our invoicing product line.
Even at the beginning?
Well, so I think seeding that, it just required...
We were going after a completely different market.
We were going after a different base, and having
another banking solution, while we still had one,
we took a lot of the learnings and efforts
that the business banking side did,
but we had to build a bunch of that.
And so the initial investment just was
a different request. Whereas in invoicing,
we're building the software on top of the
banking and it requires a different level
in order to get to minimal lovable product.
And so we're giving the teams just
enough, but we want them to stretch.
And I feel like there's also a connection to how
big this opportunity is invoicing versus becoming
the new personal bank of the world. So it makes
sense. Let's put a few more resources on this one.
Right. Absolutely. I would say I think the PMs on
those teams both want world domination. So yeah.
Let's not hit on invoicing.
Yeah.
Okay. I understand. Okay, so specifically, they
hired you to create this carve out almost for
new product investments. I think that's
a really cool lesson. Just hire a leader
that is overseeing all of these new seed
bets versus just a team off to the side.
Yes. I think that kind of hits that culture that
needed to be instilled into this organization too,
because we're going to be a zero to one team and
we're going to have to work in a little bit of a
different way. Our counterparts on the core
mature products will use monthly development
cycles. They'll figure out their roadmap for the
month and then just start executing on it. I could
not find a way in which... I wouldn't know what
was changing in a month. And so we had to move
towards two-week sprints and then weekly check-ins
with a bunch of our work just to stay as nimble as
possible. We wanted to be able to learn, iterate,
repeat, and we also have a really heavy-handed
culture of customer calls, customer research
that the PMs needed to do. There's just much more
kind of touch point, pulse check with who these
customers are. We're going after adjacent areas,
and so make sure that as a team, you know what
your customer needs and why it's important.
Can you share more about this
customer call culture for folks
that maybe want to learn from how you do it?
It's kind of like, I don't know, just the
heartbeat of how we operate. So it almost feels so
natural that I'm not sure if I can impart any new
learnings on it, but it's like I kind of expect a
customer conversation at least one a week from the
team. That seems like such a low bar to me that
I think the teams do close to... Some teams, when
they're really into discovery mode, are doing 20,
25 calls with people. It's wild. Or even just
going through surveys and understanding what
qualitative info that they're getting from the
surveys, quantitative info that they're getting
from it. I think all of that really counts.
We're customer obsessed at Mercury and so
you'll even see it like Immad will
talk to folks on Twitter or on X
directly. We'll get pings from different folks
across the company. We'll look at why people off
boarded with us and we get those messages in a
Slack channel and it just kind of hits whenever
it happens in real time. And so all of those
pieces are customer touch points in my mind,
and so it's like get on a call with CS, get on
a call with RMs, drive those calls yourself,
but just learn as much as you can from what
our customers need and what they're doing.
I'm going to follow us through
a little bit more because one,
a lot of companies say, "We're customer
obsessed, our teams are customer obsessed,
we talk to customers all the time." But
they still build bad stuff. What do you
think they often miss that maybe you're doing
that companies you've seen actually that really
are obsessed and do this well, that often is
missed when people think they're doing this?
I think there's a little bit of what a customer
says versus what they want are going to be two
different things. I think there's just so
many inputs to all of this, but if you take
just a conversation, people are really nice,
especially when they're talking on the phone,
they'll be really nice. They'll say nice things
about your product. They'll tell you that they
messed up and the UX is great, you built it the
right way and they were doing something wrong, and
they try to take some of that pressure off of you.
And what you don't want is to go into a
conversation with a bias. You want to be a
researcher, you want to be this third party
non-judgmental, kind of like being brought into
the jungle and just watching what's happening.
You're an observer, you're being a documentarian.
It's not about getting your biases checked or
validated or invalidated, but it's like just
understand what it is that the customer's
trying to do, what context they were trying to
do it in, and get to a truth that seems to find
a pattern or you hear about multiple times and
then validate that truth and see if that still
sticks. Have a prototype, do the betas, see if
the numbers actually work out in your favor.
I think the other thing is the
customer obsession needs to also be
anchored back into does it work for your business?
Just because a customer wants it, I mean,
they probably want free products that doesn't
work for what we're going to be able to serve
them with and still be a viable business and still
survive. And so I think I actually used a lot of,
when we were doing pricing, I used a lot of
insights from your podcast with Madhavan. That
was a great, I mean, if I can promo a different
podcast episode on this one, that was great.
I think I listened to it twice just to hear it
a few times, and I think there was an example
of a water at a fountain is free, a water at a
hotel is like five bucks, a water on the plane
is... The context and the price of what you're
offering somebody changes the value perception
of what they're getting delivered. And so
I think that customer obsession needs to
be just anchored back into the business and the
business needs and what you can actually offer.
And so it all needs to be triangulated and
balanced out. And so it's not just customer
obsession for the sense of customer obsession,
but where does that artistry meet the business?
Awesome. That was a great example. We'll link to
the Madhavan episode, folks that want to check it
out. And then one very tactical question, how
do your teams find customers to talk to and
organize that? Is there anything operationally
that folks can learn about how you do that?
We do have a UXR team, which is great. We
have a research team, and so they help us
make sure that we can... Honestly, the scheduling
Tetris that has to happen is probably the hardest
part in a PM schedule because you're going from
meetings to meetings. So sometimes we'll just have
dedicated research weeks where we know there's
a question that we need answered and we need
to go through that discovery, and so we'll clear
off our calendars and just book customer calls.
When it's regular sessions that are happening
every week, then we try to leverage a central
team to help us manage those calendar and meeting
invites and getting people booked. We'll also just
get in the sidecar of an RM call or a
sales call or a CS call whenever we can,
anybody who's doing any sort of research or
voice of the customer calls, anything like that,
we're in and we want to hear about it. And
then we're also looking and just responding
on X or on email or... We want to hear from
people. So find us any which way you can.
Okay, cool. And then what
does RM stand for by the way?
Oh, sorry, sorry. Relationship
managers, our sales team.
Okay, cool. So like account managers?
Yes.
Awesome. Okay. I'm going to come back to where we
were. I pushed us off track. I'm going to bring
us back on track. So we're talking about things
you've learned about building multi-products,
additional products at a company. The
first kind of theme was the org and
creating barriers almost to pulling resources
away from these seedling teams into your core.
Yeah, I think the other decisions that we had
to make that might be helpful to folks was like,
what are the next products? And so we really
looked at like, okay, we need to find solutions
that tie closer to the existing spaces we're in.
It needs to be an adjacency that's just beyond
the core. It's not about just building a new
feature. You are building a new product line,
so what is that adjacent customer segment
that would be interested in a deeper,
more fuller product experience? A good example
is invoicing. We de-risked that when we were
thinking about, okay, what's the next set of
products that we could look at? We looked at
a bunch of different areas and we're really
thoughtful around who is our target segment
or ICP and then who do we want to serve?
And we saw some work that was interesting.
Because we had this concept of this product called
Payment Requests where you could send somebody a
URL, they could go to that URL and send the money
that they owe you directly to your bank account.
That had traction and so that was something that
we used as a competitive advantage because we're
like, "Oh, we can talk to people that were
already doing something that was invoicing,
which is a request for payment over the web."
And so we talked to a bunch of those customers.
We also knew that we had a distribution advantage
because if we already had people that were using
this, we could probably get more folks that
were on Mercury already. We didn't have to
go find them outside. We didn't have to do a
full go-to-market effort. We could just kind
of test out if they had a fuller invoicing
solution, would they want to use that?
And so we used that adjacency to our advantage
and our distribution to our advantage and said,
"Okay, let's build out these next products that
are kind of in that same ecosystem or universe
and see what works and see what sticks." We
also kind of used that current UX to drive
that attached to these new products. So on the
opposite side, like the accounts payable side,
when you're sending a payment, we highlight Bill
Pay if you need more complex vendor payments. And
so it's a really easy way to just fit into the
natural flow of what a customer is doing anyways
and say, "Hey, do you actually need something more
robust? We have something for you. Try it out."
So some attributes you look for is have you
de-risk that... Basically, you're already
seeing there's a need here from a baby feature of
that product. And then do you have a distribution
advantage essentially? Can you find a way to
get in front of people in your existing product?
Exactly. That's it.
And then there's probably just like,
"Damn, is this a big opportunity?" And
then just thinking about what are
the biggest opportunities we have.
Right. Yeah, we did all of that kind of like
pre-work as just is it even viable? And then do
we have an advantage around that? And I think the
place that we hit are like, yeah, we already have
an advantage. This would be... There's a little
bit less friction in order to get to the escape
velocity that we need. And then right now, I think
once you've launched, that's one step, that's one
big hurdle. Then there's the next hurdle, which is
really trying to find that product market fit and
that's where we're at now and I think that's
a really important lesson of don't go from
launch to try to revenue optimize or find that
efficiency immediately. I think what we really
want is to give away the second product, the
third product for free, encourage as much usage
and engagement and retention to show that there's
something there, and allow customers to feel good
about how they would use us in their workflows.
And then once they get to a place where they're
needing more complexity or needing some areas
where they could save time and drive some just
ease of use, then yes, they'd actually be willing
to pay for it. But it's not like you put this
paywall in and then automatically just launch
a product and say, "Now you have to pay us."
We want to encourage this idea of what worked for
a core product. We were always free to customers,
now we had to go to a paid offering. And so
we want to make sure that people feel good
about it. We're not overcharging customers that
are too small and don't want to pay, and we're
really focusing on the customers that need that
extra, the heft that comes with these products.
It's interesting because if I reflect back to
the Madhavan pricing episode, he's actually like,
"Don't ever discount. Charge exactly what
you want to charge at the beginning because
that's actually a test of product market
fit." How do you think about that balance?
Yeah, I think I really love this idea of... What
he talked about was know what your product value
is and you have to put a price on it in order to
know that. And I think we do see that. We just
don't... Our target customer for these products
is someone at the other end of the complexity
scale. It's not everyone that we serve right now
with our banking solution, and so we have to be
really tight about who that ICP was. And then yes,
we do put that price in front of them and say,
"Tell us that it is worth X dollars or Y
dollars." And we did a whole willingness
to pay process as part of the homework for that.
But I think there's this customer journey with
these products, especially accounts payable,
accounts receivable. You don't need that
immediately when you start a business.
You do need a bank account immediately,
and so you need somewhere to save your money. You
need somewhere where you can move money around,
but that might be 6 months, 12 months, 18 months
until you need something that's more complex to
pay your vendors or to receive payments and things
like that. And so at that point, that's when we
want to have the pricing conversation with you and
say, "We have this product already available. It
works seamlessly. It's beautiful with your bank
account. You don't have to do anything more."
Got it. So essentially, it's just a part
of the journey of finding product market
fit and figuring out what to build.
Let's just see if anyone even wants
this at all for free and then it's
okay, here's [inaudible 01:03:27].
Yeah, and there's some basic functionality that
we think should still be free. Our core banking,
core money movements should always still be free.
So when invoicing asks for a different kind of
metadata on top of that money movement, that
should still be free. But when you need anything
more complex and you really are offering your
services or consulting fees or products or goods,
and you do need an invoice solution that
works really well with your accounting and
then your CPA knows how to track all
of that, then that's a paid product.
Awesome. Is there anything else along
these lines of building a new product,
layering on additional products, that you
think might be helpful to people? I'm also
curious if there's any missteps you've
had along the way either at Block or
Mercury of building something and just
failed, which I [inaudible 01:04:09]?
Well, one other learning that I've had from
the Block and Mercury world is one thing that
[inaudible 01:04:15] always said and something
that he said he learned from Jack actually
was something that I feel like is very true
with the Mercury co-founders as well. They're
never hyper-focused on the revenue. They're never
focused on a number that they're trying to drive.
They really want to build... They keep telling
the teams to build the products that people
love and the revenue will just be a byproduct of
that. And so if you can get this one step done,
the second step is almost a... You will get
there. And so I think that's one learning.
I think a few missteps that we have made
were trying too many things at once. It's
the classical example of like, "Oh, we have so
many ideas. Let's go build all of these things."
And then there is an element of you're going
to understaff these new efforts. There's not
going to be enough folks to, again, take
that seedling, put it into the ground,
put enriched soil on it, water it, take
care of it. And so trying too many things,
understaffing them. And then there's just a
lot of missteps, learnings around pricing I
think we've talked about a bit. But there was
a lot of internal discussions on pricing model,
bundling versus a la carte, how we
would price it, how much work we
would do on understanding that willingness
to pay. All of those pieces were exciting.
Is there a product that you launched that
just did not work out, fail in spite of doing
all these things? Or have generally things been
successful on your journey of adding new products?
I think we're still early, and so I don't
want to say that there isn't a failing yet
or anything like that, but I do think everything's
showing really strong positive signal. But yeah,
fingers crossed, we'll see how things
go and it's always an iterative process.
Awesome. Okay. Last thing I want
to touch on is something that I
know you're passionate about. This is kind
of outside the core of our conversation,
but I'd love to spend a little time on
it. You started this organization called
the Transparent Collective. Former guest
IOs told me I need to ask you about this.
Oh, that's awesome.
Yeah, so tell me what the
Transparent Collective is,
the impact you've had with it, and what folks
should know if they want to check it out.
Oh, gladly. That'd be great. So
Transparent Collective is a 501(c)(3)
nonprofit organization. We help underrepresented
founders get access to resources, connections,
whatever they need to build successful
tech companies. We started this, gosh,
I think it's been about nine years now, eight
or nine years ago, and it really was born out
of just this organic conversation that happened.
My co-founder and I met up for drinks one night.
We both knew each other from Michigan
back in the day, went to school together,
and we were talking about how we both went on
this entrepreneurial journey. And trying to
raise money in the Midwest was very different
than raising money in New York, which is very
different than trying to raise money and sell
this dream in the West Coast. And so where we
had to learn a lot of the tribal knowledge that
just existed on our own, we wanted to create this
collective that transparently shared information
with one another in order where we started step
one, we would have the next generation
started step two and then pay it forward.
And so our programming really focuses on
preparing founders to fundraise, being able
to connect investors to high caliber founders
that we have in our Rolodex, and then also the
entrepreneurs to the right investors for them, and
then just ultimately contributing to an ecosystem
that can really allow these types of founders
to flourish. So we host a bunch of programming,
webinars, workshops, that kind of thing. But our
kind of spotlight event is we fly founders in
from all over the US once, maybe twice a year
to participate in our seed programming. And so
we have 200, 250 applications that come through.
We bring about 8 to 10 founders in to join us for
a week in SF where we pay for everything and
we have sessions for mentoring, small group
workshops. We even do hands-on training. We'll
ask our investor friends to come in and do mock
investor meetings and get the butterflies out for
these founders that are coming in from all over.
They're not coastal founders, they're folks that
come in from Detroit or Baltimore or Atlanta and
they have amazing companies. And so we kind
of just connect the dots and help them along
the way. So far, I think we've had 90 plus alums
across our 11 batches, and I think 65% or 70% of
them have raised venture funding now because of
our programming. I think we have a total of like
125 million in seed or early stage fundraising
across all of them, and I think we've now done it
for so long that about 10% are already acquired
and exited companies too in our alumni group.
So cool. Such a thing that obviously
should exist and I love how well it's
going. For folks that either...
And it's a 501(3)(c) you said?
Yes.
So for people that either want to donate and
support this work or people that want to apply,
how do they do that? What's
the best way to learn more?
Transparentcollective.com, we have both a donate
button there and an application button. So yes, we
would love to... I think we're starting to figure
out the next batch. And so great applicants,
please come and drop your information.
And then we do operate on donations and
so we would love to find folks that would be
interested in helping us achieve our mission.
I love that. It feels like in a perfect
world, there would be no need for this,
but we are not in that world and I love that this
exists to help folks. Rohini, we've covered so
much stuff. You're awesome. With that, we reached
our very exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
Ready.
All right, here we go. First question,
what are two or three books that you find
yourself recommending most to other people?
I got this book recently called Vectors: Aphorisms
& Ten-Second Essays. It is so much fun to just
pick out a couple of these ten-second essays at
night and just read a couple of these and go to
bed. I'm going to recommend it to other folks.
A friend gave it to me and I'm going to pay it
forward. And then I guess the other one that I
really just enjoy is this book called The Inner
Game of Tennis. I've already mentioned that I'm a
tennis fan. But it talks about the state of flow
that you need when you're playing in this idea
of relaxed concentration. I just love that idea
of how do you get into that state of flow in
your day to day. Other books that I think that
I've read recently have all been fiction, so
Pachinko, Cutting for Stone, Song of Achilles,
all great ones that I've read recently when
I've had some beach time. So highly recommend.
People love fiction recommendations on our
podcast, so I'm glad you threw those out. The
Inner Game of Tennis, I know I read I think half
of it and then I for some reason stopped, but it's
important to note, it's like tennis is kind of
this metaphor and it's lessons from this coach
that he taught people how to be amazing tennis
players, which apply to all kinds of greatness.
Exactly. And I will say I love stopping a
book in the middle sometimes when you just
can't finish it. I don't know why I waited
for someone to give me permission on that,
and I think it's really helped me. Like,
oh, I got through a few starts of books.
Yeah, I think Naval was
one of the few that's like,
"You don't need to finish books, just
stop as soon as you want. It's fine."
Exactly. It's fine.
It's funny that we need permission
[inaudible 01:11:44]. Because then,
it makes you feel more comfortable
starting a book and trying books.
Right, right. It's easy.
All right, there you go. If you
haven't heard Naval's advice on this,
just don't worry about finishing a book. Don't
feel bad. It still council's reading it basically.
Next question, do you have a favorite recent
movie or TV show you've really enjoyed?
I got to admit Apple TV's got some
bangers and they don't talk about it.
I don't know why they don't market these
things better, but I'm behind on these,
second season, but Shrinking or Bad Sisters,
Slow Horses was great, Severance, I'm waiting-
It's come up a bunch.
Yeah.
Yeah. Slow Horses has been coming up a bunch.
Sorry, you said something else after that.
Oh, I think Severance is
coming up in its new season.
Severance.
Yeah, there's some good ones on Apple TV.
Also Presumed Innocent. Have you seen that?
Oh, I haven't.
So good. Apple TV. Watch it. It's only six
episodes. It'll pull you in immediately.
Can't wait.
Yeah, it's a good one. Okay,
next question. Do you have some
favorite product or a favorite product you
recently discovered that you really like?
I don't think it's a recent
discovery, but I still love
the Waymo experience. As a product....
You've experienced these rides, right?
Yeah, it's mind-blowing and
it's mind-blowing how quickly
it becomes just like you forget
that you're in a self-driving car.
Yes. I actually asked one of the product leads
of Waymo this at a happy hour and I was like,
"Is it kind of like when you kind of remember this
old elevator, there's always an elevator guy still
there, even when it was all automated and you were
just pressing buttons, but you wanted somebody
there to make it feel like I'm not in death cage?"
And I was like, "Do you still need a fake driver
to just make you feel comfortable?" And he was
like, "You'll feel comfortable in less than
five minutes." He was right. I felt comfortable
in 30 seconds. It's wild. I love Waymo. Yeah.
Me too. I love seeing many
Waymos in a row on the road
in the Bay Area because it's like it's
coming. The future is coming so fast.
So true. And I started seeing it in LA
now too. It's going to be fun. Yeah.
[inaudible 01:13:37]. I can't wait for
them. I live north of San Francisco and
so I can't wait for them to be able to get
on the freeway and cross the bridge. Oh,
man. Yeah, I love Waymo. It's so amazing and
it's just... It's like you hear about it,
but then you actually experience
it, it's a whole other level.
It's great.
Two more questions. Do you have a
favorite life motto that you often
repeat to yourself, share with folks, find useful?
I write a lot of quotes down and
I think there's... I don't know,
I just really like reminding myself of some
of these kind of quotes. So I use a bunch.
I think I use a Bruce Lee quote pretty
often, or I used one Jesuit's line in
one of my job reqs. And there's certain ones
that I do repeat, but I actually found this
and I forgot about it, but I really love
it and so I'm going to read this one out.
Please.
This is from Adam Robinson I think, and he
wrote, "My three guiding rules of life. First,
whenever possible, connect with others. Second,
with enthusiasm, strive always to create fun and
delight for others. And third, lean into
each moment and every encounter expecting
magic or miracles." Isn't that great?
So I think that's going to be my life,
or at least something that I remind myself
about as much as I can moving forward.
I love that it includes both creating
moments of happiness and joy for yourself,
but also for other people. It's a nice
balance of this too. It makes me think
about Cyan Banister was just on the Tim Ferriss
podcast. I don't know if you heard that one.
No.
And there's a lot of this and that.
Worth listening to. She's fascinating.
That's great.
Awesome. Thanks for sharing that. Final
question. You're a very active angel
investor. I know that it's hard to pick your
favorites, pick your favorite baby, but do you
have a favorite angel investment, one that you're
most proud of or most just [inaudible 01:15:26]?
That one's really tough.
What's one that like, "Oh, that was a good one."?
I think. Okay. What I'll say is, yeah, I
really don't want to pick a favorite there.
"Rohini, why didn't you mention us?"
Yeah, I'm going to get founder texts. But I
will say I tend to gravitate towards people
that are producty minded. And when I hear some
of the work that they're doing or their pitch,
even if they're not PMs, I tend to gravitate
towards those and I really love their approach
to how they think about the problems. And so you
know what? Maybe I will call out one because they
just got acquired. Bobby Matson, he was the
CEO and co-founder or founder of Payitoff of
student loans and working on making student loan
repayment easier for people, finding them ways
in which maybe they didn't have to repay...
Doing a lot of this again, unsexy work. And
when we talked the first time, he was telling me
that he had a new kid, he was still up at 3:00
AM reading regulations and what's happening
with the student loan process and the federal
government, and I was like, somebody that cares
that deeply, that really strives to try to make
someone else's life better because they're
just finding what actually needs to happen,
what doesn't need to happen, and it deals with
real money that these folks are coming out with,
a real debt they're having to deal with,
there was an emotional tug. And I love
when founders have the drive, that passion, and
the detail orientedness of finding a solution.
For folks that want to raise money
and maybe have Rohini as an investor,
here's your lesson of what she looks for.
[inaudible 01:17:07] share that. Two final
questions. Where can folks find you online if
they want to learn more? I know Mercury is hiring,
so share anything you want to share there. And
also, just how can listeners be useful to you?
I'm on X, AKA Twitter, @rohinip. Would love to
connect with folks there. I'm also on LinkedIn,
not really on anything else. So hopefully you
find me in one of those. And we are hiring,
mercury.com/jobs if folks are interested or if
you know great people that we should be talking
to. I think other than that, listeners can be
really helpful to us in continuing to send us
product feedback. Please keep it coming. We
really do love it and we have a lot of Slack
channels just focused on those pieces of like,
"Oh, I've heard from this founder." Or I'll get a
text and I will post in our Slack, internal Slack.
And so whether you're a business banking account
holder, personal banking account holder,
we just want to hear what's going well,
what's not, what we can do to improve your
lives. One thing on the personal banking,
we're going to be giving away... So if anybody
hasn't tried Mercury Personal Banking, we want to
give folks that are listening to this podcast the
opportunity to skip our wait list. And so we'll
send you the link, Lenny, and hopefully can add it
to the show notes. But we're giving a small subset
of skip the wait list opportunities for folks that
are interested in trying out a new personal bank.
How cool is that? I'm going to use this link.
[inaudible 01:18:32]. Did you
say how many you're giving away?
Well, I think we'll have 25 available.
25. Okay. There's going to be 24 now.
You'll get one. Don't worry, Lenny.
Okay, okay. It'll be 25 again. Okay. And
if you're listening to this way beyond,
it may be all out at this point, but if you're
listening to this recently, it'll be available.
Yes.
Awesome. We're definitely going
to include that in the show notes.
Thank you.
Rohini, thank you so much-
... for joining me.
This was great.
So great. Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much for
listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.