I see introversion and extroversion in general
as just two different kinds of strengths. The
problem in our culture is just that we emphasize
one type of strength, the extroverted strength,
usually more than we do the introverted
strength, but that they're equally valuable.
It's probably not this binary thing, you're
introvert, extrovert. It's the spectrum of
introvertedness, extrovertedness.
Do people move along the spectrum
often? I feel like I've definitely
become more extroverted over time.
I've had the exact same trajectory you
just described. I used to be terrified
of public speaking, now I do it all
the time. I used to be quite shy,
but that's not really describing, I don't
believe, becoming more extroverted, that's
more describing acquiring skills. As we grow and
gain experience, we acquire all kinds of skills.
What people most want is just like, how do
I become potentially more extroverted/less
allow introvertedness to hurt me in my career?
This is a paradox that I have observed that
the more introverts become deeply comfortable
in their own skin, that's when they start to
show up at the job interview or on the stage
in a more powerful way, because you're
now there as your own true being,
as opposed to there always being a voice in your
head saying, I'm not really supposed to be me.
How can you help people believe this is
actually true, that you can be just as
successful being very true to yourself
versus learning to be an extrovert?
One of the most important things you can do.
Today my guest is Susan Cain. Susan is the author
of the number one New York Times bestseller,
Quiet, The Power of Introverts in a World That
Can't Stop Talking. Her books have been translated
into 40 languages. Her TED Talks have been viewed
over 50 million times, and she basically made me
and every other introvert in the world feel okay
about being an introvert, and showed that actually
embracing that about yourself can unlock a
ton of opportunity and success in your life.
In her conversation, Susan shares a ton of very
tangible advice for how to be more successful in
business as an introvert, including what skills
you should actually be building that don't come
naturally to you. Also, what actually is
an introvert? How to raise kids who might
be introverted, and so much more. This was
such a wonderful conversation, and so much
of it resonated with me. This episode is for
anyone who considers themselves an introvert,
or if you work with people who are introverts
and you want to learn how to help them thrive.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. It's the best
way to avoid missing future episodes,
and it helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you Susan Cain.
This episode is brought to you by Enterpret.
Enterpret, unifies all your customer interactions.
From Gong calls to Zendesk tickets, to Twitter
threads, to app store reviews, and makes it
available for analysis. It's trusted by leading
product orgs like Canva, Notion, Loom, Linear,
Monday.com, and Strava. To bring the voice of the
customer into the product development process,
helping you build best in class products faster.
What makes Enterpret special is its ability to
build and update customer-specific AI models that
provide the most granular and accurate insights
into your business, connect customer insights
to revenue and operational data in your CRM or
data warehouse, to map the business impact of
each customer need and prioritize confidently,
and empower your entire team to easily take
action on use cases like win-loss analysis,
critical bug detection, and identifying drivers
of churn with Enterpret's AI assistant, Wisdom.
Looking to automate your feedback
loops and prioritize your roadmap
with confidence like Notion, Canva and Linear?
Visit E-N-T-E-R-P-R-E-T.com/lenny to connect with
the team, and to get two free months when you
sign up for an annual plan. This is a limited
time offer. That's Enterpret.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta,
and I'm very excited to have Christina Cacioppo,
CEO, and co-founder Vanta, joining
me for this very short conversation.
Great to be here. Big fan of
the podcast in the newsletter.
Vanta is a long time sponsor of the show,
but for some of our newer listeners,
what does Vanta do, and who is it for?
Sure. So we started Vanta in 2018, focused
on founders helping them start to build out
their security programs and get credit
for all of that hard security work with
compliance certifications like SOC
2, or ISO 2701. Today, we currently
help over 9,000 companies, including some
startup household names like Atlassian,
Ramp, and LangChain start and scale their
security programs and ultimately build trust
by automating compliance, centralizing
GRC, and accelerating security reviews.
That is awesome. I know from experience
that these things take a lot of time,
and a lot of resources, and nobody
wants to spend time doing this.
That is very much our experience,
but before the company,
and some extent during it. But the
idea is with automation, with AI,
with software, we are helping customers
build trust with prospects and customers
in an efficient way. And our joke, we started
this compliance company so you don't have to.
We appreciate you for doing that, and you
have a special discount for listeners,
they can get a thousand dollars off
Vanta at vanta.com/lenny. That's
V-A-N-T-A.com/lenny for $1,000 off
Vanta. Thanks for that, Christina.
Thank you.
Susan, thank you so much for being
here. Welcome to the podcast.
Thank you so much, Lenny.
It's so exciting to be here.
I just want to start with just from one
introvert to another, and from someone that
would rather be sitting in a corner writing
versus being on camera talking, performing a
little bit. I appreciate you extra for doing
this, and flexing your extroverted energy.
Oh my gosh, absolutely. Thank you. And I know
you haven't even asked a single question yet,
but in response to what you just said, because
you just identified yourself as an introvert,
that was actually a question I wanted to ask
you, because when I look at the work that you
do in the world and the way that you do it,
and I had never seen you on video before,
I said to myself, "I'm sure Lenny's an
introvert." And the reason I thought that
is because there's something about the
intensity with which you do your work,
and you're so passionate about your subject,
and your means of success is by going super
deep into your passion, and that's such an
introvert thing. So I was like 95% sure.
That is so funny. I love that, I appreciate
that. Okay, so let me set a little foundation
for folks. We kind of dove into stuff, but
I think this will be helpful. We're talking
about introvertedness. What is, what
are the clearest sign you an introvert?
Two questions you could ask yourself if you're not
really sure how you identify. So one of them is,
how do you feel... Imagine that you are
going to a party, or networking event
that you are truly enjoying with company
you truly enjoy. If you're an extrovert,
you probably find this incredibly energizing.
And so after two hours or so, you're looking
for more because you're now hyper energized.
And if you're an introvert, no matter how much
you love all those people you were just talking
to, your battery is probably way drained. And so
after two hours you're looking for the escape
route. So that's kind of one question to ask.
And then another one would be, if you imagine
a weekend, let's say, where you are totally
free of social and professional obligations,
how would you choose to spend your time? And
how many people would be in the picture, and
how well would you know those people? Would
you be allocating your social time to just
one or two close friends or family members,
or would you be excited about a party full
of people you don't know that well? Those
kinds of questions tell you a lot about what
your true preferences are. And I stress that
phrase true preferences because for introverts
in an extroverted culture, we spend so much time
kind of unconsciously adapting to what we think
our preferences are supposed to be, that I hear
from many people that they kind of have lost touch
with how they actually prefer to spend their time.
First of all, I love the two-hour heuristic as
a, think I could just pay attention to after two
hours. Because as you were describing
initially, no, that'd be really cool,
just like meet with a bunch of interesting people
for... If I'm an extrovert, if I enjoy that,
I'll maybe am extrovert. But then it's like,
okay, at two hours. Okay. And so clearly to
me be like, yes, I'll be exhausted
and want to go do something else.
Yeah, and don't you have the feeling of you wish
you could just push a button and be
instantly home when you hit that wall?
Yeah, I would love that. What I find is I just run
out of steam, I just can't talk, and just like my
voice is like I'm pushing it out. That's really
interesting. Okay, so another thought I had as
you were talking is, I know it's probably not this
binary thing, you're introvert, extrovert, it's
the spectrum of introvertedness, extrovertedness.
Is there anything along those lines that's useful
for people to hear, just like how to think
about the spectrum of introvertedness?
Oh yeah, absolutely. So first of all, there
is a term that psychologists have termed that
have coined for people who really are kind of
neither here nor there, they're in the middle
of the spectrum. So that term is ambivert.
And I think that does describe a fair amount
of people. But then what's also important to know
is that even for people who are quite extroverted
or quite introverted like me, we still have our
moments when we're acting kind of out of type,
because humans are incredibly complex beings.
So I feel like it's really important when
talking about this topic, it's like two
opposite things are true. On the one hand,
I really do believe that this question of
how introverted or extroverted we are shapes
so much about the way that we work, and
think, and make decisions, and love,
and interact, and all the rest of it. It's
hugely important. Psychologists have called
it the north and south of human temperament,
so that's 0.1. But then on the opposite side,
humans are gloriously complex, and there's
always a danger in talking about subject like
this of reducing ourselves and each other to
a label, and then expecting ourselves and each
other to behave according to that label in all
circumstances. And that's, of course a mistake.
Do people move along the spectrum often?
And I ask this because I feel like I've
definitely become more extroverted over
time. I used to be super shy and very,
very afraid of public speaking and big social
things, and I've just learned to not be as much,
and I still definitely am. So is it common
for people to move along the spectrum,
and did they move in both directions, or
is it usually from introvert to extrovert?
Okay, so first of all, I've had the exact
same trajectory you just described. I used
to be terrified of public speaking, now I do
it all the time. I used to be quite shy. I
would say I am still a shy person, but it's
not as much a top of mind, every day type of
reality. Now that's not really describing,
I don't believe, becoming more extroverted,
that's more describing acquiring skills
and also managing fears. And even managing
learning to manage a fear is a type of skill.
So what happens is as we grow and gain experience,
we acquire all kinds of skills of the kind you
were just talking about. But I still come back
to that question I asked at the beginning
of like, how would you spend your time when
you have no obligations? Because on that score,
most of us actually become more introverted with
time. And I don't know if you would describe
yourself this way, but I remember for me,
even though I was a shy person in high school,
I would come home from school and spend my
whole evening talking to all my friends on
the phone. And I would never do that now.
And psychologists have studied this, so people
tend to mellow out over time. So if you are,
let's say the third most extroverted person in
your high school, and then you go to your high
school reunion 40 years later, you'll probably
still be one of the most extroverted people in
your class, but all of you will have chilled
out and calmed down quite a bit. And that's a
separate dimension from that dimension of learning
to be a public speaker and all that kind of stuff.
That is so interesting. I never thought
of it this way. I've always thought I'm
getting more extroverted because I'm
doing more of this sort of thing,
and enjoying things like this more.
It's so interesting to reframe it into,
I've just learned how to cope and be successful
in these situations, but I'm still the same.
And it's funny that you say that because I can't
tell you how often people have said to me, well,
they'll either say, "Oh, you do public
speaking, so you never were an introvert.
You're actually an extrovert." Or they'll
say, "Oh, you've gotten more extroverted
with time." And I would say neither of
those things is true. It's just a skill.
Okay, this is something I definitely wanted to
ask you about. So people hearing you right now,
hearing you be very confident, clear,
just not coming across as an introvert,
also watching your Ted Talks, probably seeing some
of your other talks, it's not... You don't seem
like an introvert. I'm curious just what your
experience of being an introvert is that might
give people a glimpse into, okay, I didn't
realize this about people. Because I think
it's common to a lot of people. You see a lot of
people that are actually super introverted, but
they don't seem that way. So just to give people
an example of the stuff you've gone through, the
stuff you deal with as an introvert that people
may not see. What are some examples of that?
Oh, yeah. And to your point, I can't even
tell you how many people there are out there
presenting as quite extroverted. And then because
I have this funny role in society as the world's
confessor of introverts, they all come up to
me at conferences and things and tell me what
they're really feeling, and who they really are,
and it's often the people you would never suspect.
But yeah, okay. I mean if you look at the way I
just spent my day before recording this with you,
and it's now my time, 4:24 PM, so it's quite
late in the day. I have not really spoken to
many people today. I drove my son to and from
school, my husband's out of town, so I didn't
talk to him yet. And then I've been working on
my laptop and walking my dog, and that's been
a really happy day for me. So in general, I'm
really, really happy lavishing a lot of social
time on my family or close friends, but I don't
do that much social, technically social stuff.
And in terms of, I'm not sure if you used the
word overcome, but it was some kind of word
like that in your question. So for things
like this, like super public-facing stuff,
that I really did have to learn how to get
comfortable with over time. And I used to be
absolutely terrified of public speaking, like lose
five pounds before every speech kind of terrified.
And I want to say this, for anybody out there
who's listening who has this fear, because it's a
lot, a lot of people that the miraculous thing is
that this kind of fear, as with any type of fear,
is actually overcomeable because there's this
miracle kind of phenomenon that psychologists
call desensitization. That basically if you have
any kind of fear, you can expose yourself in very
small and manageable doses to the thing that
you fear, and that's the way to neutralize it.
So I signed up... Before my book Quiet came out,
and I knew I was going to have to really be out
there in the spotlight, I signed up for classes
for people with public speaking anxiety. And in
these classes you just had to, you'd start out by
standing up and saying your name and then sitting
down again, and that would be the whole exercise
for the class. And then you'd come back a week
later and do a little bit more, and that's the
way to get over it. So I always encourage people
sign up for Toastmasters or something like that
where you can practice speaking in supportive
environments where the stakes are really low
until you can retrain your brain that the stage
is not actually a saber-toothed tiger, which
is what your brain currently believes it to be.
Okay, so let me come back to this, because I
think this what people most want is just like,
how do I become potentially more
extroverted/less allow introvertedness
to hurt me in my career? But let me just
ask you this question, this kind of like-
Can I actually stop you right there?
Yes.
I would just say I totally get it that
that's what people feel that they want.
But what we think we want is not always
actually the way to the ultimate goal we
want. Because I think what we really want
is to learn to be completely comfortable
as ourselves. And I will... I know that
sounds like a bland or woo woo thing to say,
but this is a paradox that I have observed
through all the years that I've been doing this,
that the more introverts or anybody else
become deeply comfortable in their own skin,
that's when they start to show up at
the job interview, or on the stage,
or whatever the venue is in a more powerful way,
because you're now there as your own true being,
as opposed to there always being a voice in your
head saying, "I'm not really supposed to be me,
so I'm going to pretend to be somebody else." And
people can pick that up, and you can pick it up.
I think people hear this idea that you teach in
your book that you can be very successful as an
introvert, and I bet it's intellectually
difficult to actually believe you can be
as successful as an introvert versus being an
extrovert. Because you see all these founders,
they're very charismatic, extroverted, you see
people at meetings, all the loud voices in the
room always seem to get what they want. How can
you help people believe this is actually true,
that you can be just as successful being very true
to yourself versus learning to be an extrovert?
One of the most important things you can do for
whoever's listening in whatever field that you
happen to be operating in, is to look for people
in your field who have your way of being who are
introverted, and who are powerful. And there
are so many of them in every field. So just
to go back to the public speaking example for a
second, but then I'm going to go out from there.
When I was getting started as a public speaker,
for me, my talisman person was Malcolm Gladwell.
Because he's an incredibly captivating
speaker, he's a self-described introvert,
and the power of his speaking is not
being the super energized showman,
but rather he's a pretty cerebral person with a
lot of interesting stuff to say. And I thought,
okay, not that my personality is exactly like his,
but it's like, okay, that's kind of a way that I
could be on stage. I can have interesting things
to say that I'm very impassioned about saying.
And this is true, you can look at so many
different fields. So for example, in finance,
somebody like Warren Buffet, he's a shy introvert,
he has talked about this. And a lot of the engine
of his success is that he figured out how to draw
on his own introverted strengths. So for example,
he's known for spending hours pouring over
financial documents, and he's known for saying
that what gets people to be a really good investor
is not so much IQ, as having the temperament to
control yourself and take prudent bets, which is
something that introverts are known for. There's
all kinds of studies documenting this and showing
introverted traders being especially successful,
and so on. He's also known for selecting managers
very wisely and carefully, and then really
delegating and relying on those people, which
again is a hallmark of introverted leadership
that we see in various studies and examples.
Now, Warren Buffet was also somebody who started
out as a shy public speaker, and he signed
up for one of those Dale Carnegie training
classes when he was like 21. And so he
learned how to be this kind of folksy
guy out in public. And so there's nothing,
I'm saying that's against the idea of, yes,
acquire the skills that you need to acquire to
be successful in your given field. And yes, that
might require stepping outside your comfort zone
to acquire those skills, but there's a difference
between acquiring skills and trying to be someone
who you're not. Those are really different things.
So yes, acquire the skills, but then learn how
to be you. And whether you are a public speaker,
or a salesperson, or a negotiator,
or a marketer, or whatever it is,
there's a way to do that in a kind of more
thoughtful, more deliberative, more analytical,
more listening-oriented style that can be
incredibly powerful. The bottom line of everything
I just said is look for your role models, because
they're going to show you that you can do it.
That's such a powerful point. Just instead
of kind of assuming what you see in the media
of just here's all the successful people
and just assuming they're all extroverts,
actually find folks that are in your orbit that
are successful, that are also introverts to
show you and give you evidence you can be really
successful, and not have to become someone else.
Oh yeah. And if you're talking about the
realm of founders and startup people,
there's just so many of them, especially
in the world of Silicon Valley,
Who comes to mind, those examples?
Oh gosh. I mean, dating all the way back to Bill
Gates and that era, there have just been so many.
This point of becoming more of who you are
is connected to something that comes up a
lot on this podcast of the power of leaning
into your strengths, and not trying to focus
on your weaknesses, of just becoming more of...
Leaning into the things you're good at and doing
the things you want to accomplish through that.
For example, in my experience, I'm just like...
I'm not an amazing speaker, I'm not an
amazing person to run meetings, but I'm
really good at like after the meeting, here's
the doc of the meeting, here's the next step,
here's kind of like a-sync followups and
stuff like that. And I found the writing let
me accomplish all the same things without feeling
like, oh, I need to become this amazing presenter.
Absolutely. And I would say in addition to that,
I don't think that that means that you need
to be limited only to writing. Because I mean,
even just talking to you for 15 minutes
or so, I get a feeling of like, okay,
I'm talking to somebody who's extremely authentic,
extremely intelligent, extremely knowledgeable,
and those are all incredibly powerful traits
that modest introverts tend to discount.
That's a good pushback and good
reminder, but I hear you. Okay,
good, good. I want to go back to the tactics
you started to share of how to be successful
in business as an introvert, because a lot of
times companies aren't set up for introverts
to thrive. And so I'm curious what either
you have done, or what you've seen people
do as introverts to set themselves up
for more success in a business career.
Gosh, there's a lot we could talk about. I'll
give you a few ideas. I mean, one is to find ways
to make sure that other people know how much you
know, and how much you're contributing. Because
I can't tell you how often company leaders
will tell me that they lose valuable people
because those people aren't good at
self-promotion, and then their contributions
are undervalued or they feel undervalued, so
they end up leaving. And that is not good for
anybody. Okay, so what can you do to do this?
If you are somebody who is comfortable writing,
the way you are, you could start a company
blog or some other way of disseminating your
expertise through writing that will thereby
gain attention. Another thing that you can do,
if you're either comfortable already with
public speaking, or are planning to acquire
that particular skill, there's something in our
culture where people who put themselves forward on
a stage gain disproportionate respect. So if you
can put yourself forward to do, it could be like
two minutes, it could be five minutes. Maybe you
start a lecture series at your company where you
bring in speakers and you're the one who's always
introducing them. So you're just on stage for the
two minutes that you're introducing them, but
you're the one who put the whole thing together.
That's the kind of thing that can bring you a lot
of prominence with disproportionate bang for the
buck. And that kind of thing is also a great way
of just practicing these skills and getting more
comfortable with them. Okay, so that's one.
A second one is to, I'm thinking of a woman
named Kathy Fish who until not long ago, was the
head of R&D at Procter and Gamble. And Kathy's a
self-described introvert, and she talked about
how her superpower was, she was really good at
connecting with people one-on-one, and building
deep connections in that way. So she wasn't the
person who would sweep charismatically into
the room and everyone would know who she was,
but it was like one by one, by one by one she was
building up all these relationships that as she
got more senior in her company, everyone knew
who she was, they liked her, they trusted her,
and that turned out to be incredibly powerful.
Third idea, quiet people often are misunderstood
to be unambitious. So if you're an ambitious
person, you have to make sure that your
colleagues know about that. So I would look for
a mentor, and ask if you could have 10 minutes
to ask their advice. And most people love to be
asked for advice, and are happy to give it. And
let that person know what your goals and hopes and
ambitions actually are for one year, three years,
five years from now, and ask for their advice
on how you could get there. And they might come
up with one little strategy that will make a
huge difference for you, or they might start
being the one to go to bat for you now that they
know that you have the ambition to do X, Y, Z.
This is awesome. Okay, let me summarize some
of the stuff you've shared. And this is kind
of a list of things you as an introvert can
do to be more successful in your career,
and probably in your life. And I'll include all
the things you shared, because it's all useful.
So one is look for a role model that's
really successful that's an introvert,
to show you you can do this. You don't have
to be this extroverted, charismatic CO person.
Two is show your value, make sure people
actually see the value you're providing,
because a lot of introverts don't. Three is
actually lean into public speaking and work
on that skill. To your point, it's looked at very
highly if you can do that okay. And your advice
is just like do little bits. You don't need to
give a 30-minute, all-hands presentation, just
a little bit of time on stage goes a long way.
I'll give one recommendation. I had this person
on the podcast and I found this public speaking
course the most useful of all the things I've
done. It's called Ultraspeaking, and it's very
much based in doing it versus intellectualizing
how to speak better. And it's made up of these
very low-risk games that you play with other
people, and you just talk without much support
and it's low risk, but it's at the edge of scary,
and keeps kind of leveling up a little bit.
Okay. And then, okay, I'll keep with through list,
four is connect one-on-one with
people. So instead of just like,
I need to be amazing in this meeting it's like,
make sure you connect with everyone one-on-one
in the company and they understand how awesome
you are, and you end up being more... Look more
awesome when you're going one-on-one with people
as an introvert. And then five is kind of make
it... Is the advice here around ambition? It's
like introverts are ambitious, but they may not
understand how to achieve this ambition. So it's
less like make it clear you're ambitious, more so
come up with a plan to achieve this ambition by
getting advice from someone. Is that the advice?
Yeah. And first of all, I'm amazed that you
could do that. I don't know how
you pulled that off just now.
Quick notes.
And I would add to it to make sure to kind of lean
into your strengths. And I was just thinking about
your case of when I said that I look at your
newsletter and I was pretty sure you were an
introvert, it wasn't because, oh, this is a person
who's writing for a living. That piece actually
hadn't really occurred to me. It was because
you're so obviously someone who goes really
deeply and really thoroughly into a subject of
passion. And then it's almost like a little,
here's journey. You're going into the
forest of your passion, and then you're
bringing the treasures for the rest of us to
enjoy. And this is something that introverts
do very naturally. We tend to have one
or two or three passions in our lives,
and one or two or three people in our lives who
are very devoted to you, and we lavish everything
in the direction of those passions and those
people. And that is an incredible superpower.
And so very often if you look at introverts who
have become great leaders in a broad variety of
fields, they're not the kind of people who
when they were a kid everybody was like,
"That child is a natural leader." They're not
that person. They're usually people who have
these incredibly deep passions. And if you have
those, you end up acquiring a lot of expertise,
and building a network of people who have those
same passions, and inspiring a lot of trust
from people who care about the same stuff
that you do, and that's a real superpower.
The way you describe it makes me want to
just hire a company of introverts. They go,
they spend all this time finding treasures
for you and bring them back quietly and very.
That's funny. But actually, I'm glad you said
that because what I really do think, and the
research bears this out too, the best-performing
teams and companies really are a mix of both. We
so desperately need both types. And introverts
and extroverts tend to really enjoy each other's
company because we compliment each other so
well. And it's very easy to admire strengths and
traits that we don't have ourselves. So there's
a kind of mutual admiration that goes on as well.
Speaking of that, it reminds me of, I don't know
if this was in your book or a different book,
there's some data that shows salespeople that are
more introverted are actually more
successful. Does that ring a bell?
I think that the most recent study I've seen shows
the most successful salespeople are ambiverts,
because they're extroverted enough to close
the deal, they're introverted enough to do the
listening that good salesmanship usually requires.
But having said that, you could be successful any
which way. And in Quiet, my book, I profiled a guy
who was like, I don't remember the exact detail,
but something like the leading salesperson of
the year of Cutco Knives, and he talked about
how he would just go and do these deep listening
sessions with his customers and really figure out
what they needed, and they trusted him because he
was authentically, curiously listening to them. So
yeah, which is to say there's, whatever strength
you have, you figure out how to maximize it.
That resonates with product work. A
lot of people, a lot of the part of
the job of a product leader is to figure
out what to build, and a lot of that is
talking to users, research and things
like that, and actually listening. And
so it's interesting how similar that sales
anecdote is to being a great product person.
Something that this brings up for me is
the importance of saying no to things as
an introvert that are not things that bring you
energy, and will distract you from this sort of
thing. And I know Tim Ferriss is writing this
new book called The Notebook. I was listening
to your interview with him, that's why I had his
in my mind. But I guess, is there anything you've
learned about just, or any tactics you've
learned about saying no to things that one
will de-energize you and two, just allow you to
go deep on stuff that you want to go deep on?
Well, I mean you might've heard the following
advice before, when I first heard it, it came
as a revelation to me. But it's, when someone
asks you to do something that is three or four
or five months away, there's a tendency to say
yes to that because it feels so safely in the
distance. So before you say yes, you should
ask yourself how you'd feel if you had to do
that thing tomorrow or next week. And that's
the real test. But also and more broad level.
Okay, I love the psychologist
Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi,
late psychologist. He did all these
studies on creativity and wrote a book
about it. And at the beginning of this book
he talks about how he approached all these
deeply famously creative people who he wanted to
study. And he said that he got back answers from
some of them saying, your study sounds
interesting, but if I said yes to these
kinds of things, I wouldn't, I wouldn't be
able to do the creative work that I did.
Love that.
Yeah. And that leapt out at me,
and I think about it all the time now when
I regretfully say no to this and that.
That reminds me of something that I often think
about. Naval has this, basically the same advice.
He has this insight that you start doing something
really well, you become successful with it,
you start getting invited to parties, and events,
and talks, and collabs. You start doing that,
you have no longer have the time to do that
thing that made you successful well, and it
all falls apart. And the trick is don't fall for
that, and keep doing the work that you're doing.
I know. It's really tricky, it's
very tricky because the thing is,
when you do go to those kinds of events, you
actually usually do meet incredible people
who you're really happy to know. I mean, in
my experience, and some of the people I've
met at those kinds of events over the years
have become my best friends. So I just try
to think of it really strategically. I just
pick a few of those things that I say yes to,
and then I say no to all the others. But
I don't like to say no to all of them,
because I do feel like there's something
meaningful that happens at every single one.
I'm more extreme than you. I actually created
a policy with myself. No events, no talks,
no other podcasts. Just like, the default
is no, and once in a while I break the rule,
but that's what I find is what I need.
Because otherwise I'm just like, "Oh,
that'll be fun. Let's go to this dinner thing."
Wait, wait, wait. This is fascinating. So okay,
you saying how often do you break the no rule?
Pretty rarely. If it's like a work thing, if
it's like friends, like meeting with baby,
or friend, or something like that. But yeah,
it's pretty rare. I try really hard. Probably
because I get invited to a bunch of random
VC stuff, and talk and podcast things, so-
Yeah, yeah.
... I'd say maybe 5% of the time I break it.
Interesting. Okay. Yeah, no, I understand.
And I actually do, I still do... I used to do
a ton of speaking for companies and schools
and so on, and I still do do some of that,
but I have consciously limited that so
that I can focus on other projects instead.
I find having a policy where
I could just tell people,
"I have this policy that I just invented in
myself," is a really good way of saying no.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, I've gotten past the
point of feeling guilty about the no,
most of the time. Most of the time. Because yeah,
life really is just too busy. And especially if
you're a parent the way you are, there's that too.
Yeah, I have this post where I shared all
my tricks for saying no that will link to,
that has a bunch of templates you can use, and I
am excited to see this booked in first writing,
because I imagine he has to say no a lot.
Yeah, yeah, absolutely.
One other thought along these lines is also a
Naval lesson, and it's interesting how much these
insights stick in my head and make it, like change
the way I operate. His other piece of advice is
around networking, because what you're talking
about a little bit is like there's actually power
in meeting people and networking, essentially.
And his advice is instead of networking,
do things that are valuable, and people
will come to you and want to meet you,
versus you trying to meet them. And
I found this to be absolutely true.
I find it to be so true also. And also
even just for attending networking events,
like if you've done something valuable, those
events are much easier because people want to
talk to you about whatever that thing is, and
you want to talk to them about their thing,
and then all the other things that you didn't even
know about each other. But, I don't know.
My other mode or MO for networking types of
events is, I feel like if I meet one or two or
three people at one of those events who I truly,
truly like, truly want to stay in touch with,
truly want to be helpful to, I consider it a
success. And then I feel like I can go home or
spend a lot of time in the hotel room after that.
Whereas I have friends, I see it, like
sometimes I'll go to one of these events
and I have friends who make a point of meeting
every single person who's there. And then we'll
be talking a few months later and they'll mention
such and such person. They'll like, "Yeah, don't
you remember? They were at that event." And I have
no idea who they're talking about. And so yes,
it would be probably a more maximum value approach
to meet every single person as long as you're
there. But I don't believe that to be true if
you're not wired that way. And I think the power
of, over a lifetime, of just trying to have
from every situation in life, one or two people
where the connections are true and deep, over a
lifetime you have a network that you really love.
All right, shoot. I got to
go to more events, I guess.
No, no, no. Oh my gosh. I hope
I'm not making it sound that way,
because the truth is I go to so few.
Very few, yeah. This episode is brought to you
by the Fundrise Flagship Fund. Full disclosure,
real estate investing is boring. Prediction
markets are exciting, meme coins are a thrill
ride, even the stock market can swing wildly
on a headline. Hello Deep Zeke. But with
real estate and investing, there's no drama, or
adrenaline, or excuses to refresh your portfolio
every few minutes. Just bland and boring stuff
like diversification and dividends. So you won't
be surprised to learn that the Fundrise Flagship
Real Estate Fund is a complete snooze fest.
The fund holds $1.1 billion worth of
institutional-caliber real estate managed
by team of pros focused steadily growing
your net worth for decades to come. See,
boring. That's the point. You can start investing
in minutes, and with as little as $10 by visiting
fundrise.com/lenny. Carefully consider
the investment objectives, risks, charges,
and expenses of the Fundrise flagship fund before
investing. Find this information and more in the
fund's prospectus@fundrise.com/flagship.
This is a paid ad.
I want to come back to tactics for introverts
to be more successful. One common I think
challenge introverts have is in big meetings
with loud voices, having their ideas heard,
and even... Heard and then actually acted on. Is
there anything you've learned in those situations
or tactics you've seen people implement that
make them more successful in these situations?
Yeah, so one very helpful tactic is to prepare
in advance for a meeting a couple of points you
might want to make, or questions you might want to
raise. Don't assume you have to be spontaneous the
way other people appear to be. If you're more of
a preparer, you should prepare. And then also to
give yourself a push to speak up early in the
meeting. Both because ideas that get advanced
early tend psychologically to be anchoring ideas
that people pay more attention to. But also for
you, you'll start to feel more like you are part
of things, you're more at the center of things,
people will be directing their eye contact towards
you if you speak up early, and that becomes a kind
of virtuous cycle. So that's one thing.
Another is to realize that yes,
humans respond to the voice that's loudest
and deepest and all that stuff, but as humans
we also respond in an unconscious kind of
way to others who are speaking from a deep
sense of conviction, like from a sense of
truly believing what they're saying. And
that is a muscle that you can strengthen. So I
would say even when you're not at the meeting,
get into the habit of thinking, am I speaking
from here? Am I speaking from a deep place?
I'm not talking about voice right now. I mean like
mentally. When I say that I love this movie, do I
really believe I love this movie? And people will
know it if you're coming from that place, so that
you don't actually have to be the loudest person
in the room in order for people to pay attention.
I just did a short meditation retreat and somebody
there had this really interesting way
of doing exactly what you're describing,
where he visualizes this lightning cable
going form his... Instead of unplugging
it from his brain and plugging into his heart
and listening to that, into what you're saying.
Yeah, it's just funny how that works. I think
one of the main hacks to understand about how
we humans relate to each other is how
much we are picking up unconsciously,
a thousand different cues that we're
sending out without even knowing that
we are. And that's why speaking from that
place makes such a difference. And so yes,
it can be helpful to think about your tone of
voice and all that kind of... And your gestures
and all of that kind of stuff. But I would
start with what's actually there, the substance.
And again, this is a good example
of why introverts are so valuable,
is I feel like it's probably easier to do that,
to be kind of talking from your heart and be
authentic. This tip you shared of speaking early,
I think is really interesting. It connects to,
this is going to sound crazy and weird, maybe.
There's this whole pickup artist world of just, I
forget what the book was called, where they wrote
about mystery and this whole like, the art of
picking up women. And one of the tricks that they
share with... Guy, and I did not do this, this is
just an interesting story, is if you're trying to
talk to someone in a bar, you should talk to them
in the first five seconds of you seeing them and
thinking you should talk to them. Because once you
keep thinking about it too much, you'll never do
it, it gets super scary, and it only gets scarier.
And I think that's true in meetings.
You just sit there and keep ruminating,
"Oh my god, am I going to say something?" And
the more you do it early, the easier it all is.
Oh my gosh, it's so, so, so true. And
it's so funny to apply it to that setting,
but it makes total sense. You reminded me of
how I first discovered this technique. It dates
all the way back to, I used to be a lawyer,
strangely, many years ago. And in law school,
the way the classes were conducted, it was like
you'd be sitting in this gigantic amphitheater of
people, and the professor would just call on you
cold, and you had to answer all the questions.
Oh my God.
Yeah, exactly. Oh my God. And so my strategy to
avoid that, which I did from the first day was I
would be one of the first people to raise my hands
when they would ask for volunteers. And I figured,
okay, if I've volunteered and there's 150 other
people sitting here, they're going to call on
those people, they're not going to call on me who
just volunteered. So that was my strategy. And not
only did it work in that way, but then I started
to realize, especially if you're one of the first
people who's ever spoken, the professor kept
referring back to things I had said, not because
it was the smartest comment that had been made
all year long, but just because it was one of the
first ones. And so it sticks in the mind. So it's
just one of those phenomena of human relations.
And you also probably just, like
you're participating more and you
end up being more successful in
the class, and get better grades.
Yes. Yeah, so virtuous cycle again.
Man, I love it. Okay. What about from the
perspective of a manager or a founder that
has introverts working in the company,
what advice can you share to make the
most of these folks that you probably might
be not noticing, or not paying attention to?
First of all, I would think about how you're
running your meetings. So there's a statistic from
the Kellogg School that in your typical meeting
you have three people doing 70% of the talking.
But it's your company, and you want to make
sure that you're actually hearing from everyone,
because you want to hear the best ideas. So
I would do things like techniques like go
around the room and make sure you're hearing from
everybody. Or if you have a specific person who
you know to be thoughtful and reticent, you might
say to that person before the meeting, "Hey Bob,
I know that you have a lot of great thoughts
about such and such topic. Can I look to you to
talk about that during the meeting?" And now Bob
is much more likely to step up and talk about it.
But also, for many introverts, we like to
be able to process our thoughts before we
articulate them. So you've now given Bob advanced
notice, and he has more time to do the processing
before speaking. Another technique you could
use is a kind of brain writing where you,
let's say everybody has to offer their thoughts
on how to solve a problem. Have people write
their ideas out on post-its, and then you
collect all the post-its and then you present
them. And now all the ideas are out there
without anyone having had to jockey for time
or space. It's just the ideas on their own.
Your introverts are going to appreciate the
following thing more, but it will benefit
everybody. To make sure that you're giving
everybody space to put their head down and work
in a state of flow without being interrupted.
That's huge for human productivity, but
the introverts need it especially. So if
you can create times of the day, depending on your
workflow where there are no meetings or whatever,
or people can work from home on such and
such a day or time, that can go a long way.
Oh man, that super resonates. What I did when
I had a regular job is I, well first of all,
we had no meeting Wednesdays, which was
like the day everyone got all the work done.
Yeah.
And then the other thing that I worked... And I
have this post I'll link to productivity tricks,
and one of them is around deep work. And I created
this block on Wednesdays and Friday mornings for
two hours that it was just work, deep work time.
And I labeled it, "Do not book time over this,
or I will slap you." And it worked, and
I did not get in trouble. Be careful.
Yeah, and I'm sure people
appreciated the humor of it too.
Yeah. Yeah, they did
That's genius.
HR never said anything. Okay. So just to reflect
back, the tips you shared, which are awesome is
one is, just like actually ask everyone in the
meeting just like, "Hey, do you have anything
you want to add?" Make sure everyone has a
chance, at least if they don't want to volunteer.
Two is give people, if someone you think is going
to have good ideas, just tell them ahead of time.
"Hey, I just want to make sure you share this
idea, or you have a chance to say something,
please say something in the meeting." Three is
give people a chance to write ahead of time or
in the meeting, just create space for people just
to write their ideas down, not have to jockey for
raising their hand and sharing something, and
then everyone hands in there their work. And
then four is create deep work time, you give
people a chance to get into flow. Awesome.
Okay. I want to go in a totally different
direction. I don't know if it was your
second book or third book. It was for kids,
kids that are introverts. I am, I have a kid,
he's one and a half-ish. It's pretty clear to me
he's an introvert. We went to a birthday party,
he just went into the other
room and played with the toys.
Yeah.
He often just wants to observe for a while,
and then he starts to feel comfortable.
Yep.
Do you have any advice for
raising an introverted kid?
Yeah, I mean we could talk about this
for the whole entire time, very easily.
Okay, this will be the next podcast.
Yeah. But what are some thoughts?
Yeah, but I'll just give
you a few top-line thoughts.
Awesome. Perfect.
The first thing I always say is
to understand that introverted
and/or shy children, have we taken a second to
distinguish between introversion and shyness?
No, let's do that.
I don't know if we have.
No.
Okay, this applies to adults as well as kids. But
introversion is more about just a preference to
be in less overstimulating environments, more
mellow environments, less sound, less noise,
fewer people, just fewer stimuli coming at you.
And shyness is more about the fear of social
judgment. So it's a kind of over-exaggerated
response to any situation where you're being
judged. Could be new people at a party, could
be the public speaking, could be an interview.
And you might have situation A that doesn't
bother you, and evaluative situation B that
really does, because people are complicated.
So anyway, for children, whether they're shy,
i.e. fearful of judgment, or whether
they're introverted, i.e. I prefer to
play in a mellower way. The key for both of
those kids is to understand that they will
tend to have a longer runway that they travel
down before they take off and fly. And this
applies to a gazillion parenting situations.
So when it comes time to introduce your child
to school, it is very likely from what you've
just described to me, you said it's a boy, right?
A boy, yeah.
Yeah. Okay. So it's very likely that he is
going to be a little bit slow to warm up at
the beginning. And it might be that all the other
kids get dropped off at the door of the school,
but your child might really want you to walk him
all the way down the stairs to his classroom. And
that's okay. It's not okay for it to stay that
way forever, but remember when we were talking
about desensitization with public speaking?
Where you do things step by step by step.
So you might walk him to the classroom a few times
and then say, "Okay, we're going to do a game,
and tomorrow I'm going to walk you almost all
the way, but the last two steps you're going
to do by yourself." And then you celebrate it
with whatever little treat. Then the next day,
maybe it's not two steps, maybe it's five steps.
Little by little by little you are moving away,
and he's going down that runway, and
eventually he will get to the point
where he doesn't even remember that
he needed you to walk him into school.
This is going to happen again and again. When he's
learning to swim, a lot of quieter children are
uncomfortable with the water at the beginning.
And you might feel as a parent, like, what did
I do wrong? Because I see all these other kids
who are just jumping in the water and my kid's
not doing that. So first of all, give yourself
a break, because this is natural. And second,
you apply the same technique. You maybe get to
the pool on a day when there aren't a lot of
people around, so it's not overstimulating. Quiet.
And maybe the goal for that day is you're asking
your child, do you think you can put your big
toe in the water? And he puts his big toe in,
"Yay, yay, yay," we're celebrating. And then
you little by little go from there. And again,
eventually you will not be able to tell the
difference between that kid and the one who
jumped in right away. Longer runway, it's okay.
Okay. So that was my first piece of advice.
My second is, self-confidence comes from mastery,
and not the other way around. So we tend to think,
we live in a culture that's really big on
self-confidence, so we see self-confidence as the
key to everything else. But in fact, if you master
a skill, you become self-confident as a result of
that mastery. And this is true for all children,
it's especially true for quieter children.
Introduce them to a lot of activities, and figure
out which are the ones they really truly love,
and gravitate to, and excel in, and those
will pay off great dividends, not just in
their mastery, but in their self-confidence.
The third thing I would say is when they're
feeling shy or uncomfortable, just talk about
it openly in a light way. It's not a big deal.
Share your own experiences. Let's say a child's
afraid to go to a birthday party. You could say,
"Oh yeah, I used to feel that way too. It's
really common. Here's what I would do when
I felt that way. And you know what? I still
feel that way sometimes." And you could say,
"So what I like to do is, I like to get to the
party early before everybody else is there,
because then I feel more comfortable.
So why don't we get there early today?"
I do actually love to do that.
Well, there you go. Yeah, and a lot of
kids do best when they're one of the
first people to arrive, because then
they feel like it's not overwhelming,
and they own the space. But the key is that
you're showing them that you understand,
and are cool with who they are, and it just
becomes no big deal. As opposed to many kids
quickly absorb from their society the idea
that there's something wrong with their
shyness. So you're trying to undo that sense
of shame and stigma, and make it no big deal.
That is really helpful. I forgot to ask you this
question at the beginning, but I am really curious
what percentage of people are introverts?
Whatever you label that along the spectrum.
I've seen different studies. Some say it's
30%, some say it's 50%. It's always higher
than you think, but it's basically one out
of every two or three people, so it's a lot.
So it feels like one of the core
pieces of advice you're sharing
is if you're an introvert, you don't
need to become an extrovert. It's,
become more of who you are, and you
can be really successful in that.
Yeah. I'm just going to add to that,
while also making sure that you acquire
the skills that you need. I'm not saying
never step outside your comfort zone,
or don't acquire those skills if they're crucial
to what you're doing, like public speaking,
the way we were talking about. But bottom line,
the goal is to use those skills to be who you are.
And that was an awesome point. So it's not
just like, okay, I don't need to go out of my
comfort zone ever, I'm going to be the amazing CEO
just being exactly how I am. Your advice is no,
you actually do need to build some
stuff and build some of these skills?
Though I do want to say, on the other hand,
if the job you have taken on or the career
you've taken on is one that requires
you to wake up every morning feeling
dread because you're going to be so far out
of your comfort zone for so much of the day,
and so much of the week, is it really
worth it, in that case? I mean,
you basically want a life where you're waking
up, looking forward to what you're doing. Yes,
with obstacles along the way, but more or less
you should feel like you're in the right zone.
So the advice there is find work that connects
with your introvertedness as much as you can.
With your temperament, yeah.
With your temperament.
Same for extroverts. I've heard
from extroverts who will say,
"I work in this company of very introverted
engineers, and everybody's super quiet and
heads down, and I'm going crazy."
So that's not right for you either.
Yeah. And it's not like you can't, like what
this makes me think about is we did a test of
all the PMs at Airbnb while I was there, like
a personality test. And it's interesting how it
was all over the map, and there wasn't like you
need to be this energetic, charisma person. You
could be just a thoughtful, quieter person,
and those people were just as successful.
Absolutely.
A big part of your advice is figure out who
you are and become more of that. Connect to
your introvertedness, and you can be very
successful there. Is there any advice,
just what to do to do that, to what should you be
looking at? Which parts of you should you be like,
okay, this is where I'm strong
and I should be leaning into,
and this is how I can become the best, most
successful people in spite of my introvertedness?
I mean, I might start by just asking,
what do you like to do? How do you like
to spend your time? What are you most
interested in? Again, that question of,
if you had no social or professional obligations,
how would you be spending your time? Basically,
you just need a really honest conversation
with yourself of what you like to do.
I love that it comes back to your kind
of heuristics at the beginning of just,
if you had a free weekend, how
would you spend that weekend?
Yeah.
And then would you do a pie chart of
the activities to give you, here's how I
want to generally spend my time, like 20% social,
40% on my own. Is that one way to think about it?
You know, that's funny because you
were mentioning Tim Ferriss before,
and I remember when I was talking to him
on his podcast, he kept asking me, "Okay,
do you have a system for this and a system for
that?" And it was like, "I'm not a systems person
the way you are." And I think his systems are
super helpful, I just tend to have a different
approach, like a more just intuition-based
approach or something, just like what feels right,
and what feels wrong. And if you ask yourself
that simple question, I think you know.
That's actually, that alone is a... It connects to
something I often try to do. Just asking yourself,
does this feel right or does this feel wrong?
Some advice I recently heard along these lines,
another way to ask this question
is, what is my body saying?
Yes.
I was invited to do this talk and I was
just like, I guess it could be good for the
newsletter if I do this thing. And I actually
used your piece of it, the trick you used of,
if this were tomorrow, would I be excited? I was
like, no, definitely not. And then she actually
is like, here's another trick at you. Because
I told her that, that's how I decided not to
do it. She's like, yeah, just like, what
is my body saying? And I was like, no,
definitely not. My body does not... Like, the idea
of it not happening made me feel really relieved.
Yeah, that tells you so much. And I guess what I
would add to that is also you need to distinguish
between the goal and what it would take to get to
the goal. Okay, so I'm thinking of a young woman
who I talked to after she gave a successful
Ted Talk, and had a successful book, and she
was trying to figure out what the next step
should be on the coattails of these successes.
And what she said in the course of our
conversation is, she knew that she could
build a whole company around her ideas
that were now out in the world. But she
knew from experience that she had had working
at other companies that she wouldn't actually
be happy having to wake up and run a team
every day. And so she knew whatever I do,
it's not going to be based on team management,
that needs to not be part of the picture.
And I thought that was a really useful way
to look at it because it wasn't, I think she
would've loved to actually have the company and
put products out into the world that the company
would've made, but she wouldn't have enjoyed her
life to get to that goal. And so that question of,
do I want to wake up in the morning doing what
it takes to reach that goal, is a really big one.
There's two things that brings up for me. One is
I had the co-founder of HubSpot on the podcast,
which is like a gabillion dollar business at
this point. And he had a conversation with his
co-founder early on and he told him, "I never
want to manage anybody." And even up to today,
he has never managed any, there's
nobody under him at the company,
and he's still the co-founder,
still operating on his own.
Wow, that's-
So, it's possible.
... fascinating that he could pull that off.
Yeah, he's a fascinating guy. We're
going to link to that episode,
it's so interesting. The other is, I made
a role for myself with this new life along
those lines that you just shared, which is,
I never want to have full-time employees.
Yes, me too.
Okay.
Me too. I did the exact same
thing with my Substack. No, none.
Great.
Yeah. And I do have different
people who I work with.
Yeah, same.
And including my colleague Renee and I
have been working together for 10, 11,
12 years amazingly. But it's a very loose type of
working structure, and that's what works for us.
That's exactly how I operate. And the major
downside is people sometimes leave because
they're not full-time and there's
like, oh, here's a cool full-time
role that they found. But I find people
want this. They prefer to be a part-time,
flexible thing, not this is their
life and this is all they're doing.
I think a lot of people like that too.
It's such a... But there's always this temptation.
Okay, but what if one person and they just deal
so much for me, I think it also limits just how
much work you take on, which is really healthy.
It's so funny because when I started
my Substack, I talked to one of my now
colleagues and I remember saying to him, if
in a few months I wake up and my day consists
of going to meetings, then I'm going to know
the whole thing... I went down the wrong path,
and this was a mistake. So we have to build
it in a way where it's not about that at all.
Along those lines, I have a rule of no
meetings before 3:00 PM, to reduce the
number of meetings I have except for podcast
episodes that we do sometimes in the mornings,
and that helps me there. Yeah, funny
enough, when I started the newsletter
and it started doing well, I was like, okay,
this is awesome. What a life. Just write a
newsletter once a week and make a living, and
so I had this rule. I'll never do a podcast,
I'll never do a course, I'll never do
a conference, I'll never do a book. And
I've actually crumbled and done almost all
those things. The only thing left is a book.
That's really funny. So those
things that you ended up doing,
have you enjoyed them, or were
your initial instincts correct?
The podcast, I am very happy I
did it. It's extremely cool to
have the dynamic of the newsletter and
the podcast. Energy-wise it is, it takes
energy. I have to pull in the
extrovertedness side of me to-
I get it.
Yeah. Versus like, I'm just going to sit in
the cafe and work on the newsletter. So yeah,
it's mostly great, but I do have to get
up to do it, hide myself up into it.
I so, so understand.
And then the course, I decided not to do it.
It was too much of that. I stopped doing that.
The conference was awesome. Probably we'll do it
again. And the book, still have resisted the book.
Wouldn't the book be more along the lines of what
you like doing? Like you could sit in your cafe?
You would think, you would think. The problem is
it just would be too much work. It's
just like the load of, as you know.
I do.
I think it took you seven years to
write your first book, is what I read.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. And then, well my second book
was the one for kids, that didn't take quite
as long. But then my third book, Bittersweet
was the same thing. I took like seven years,
and I just sent in a book proposal to my agent two
days ago for another book, which will undoubtedly
take five, or six, or seven years. And I have
wondered how I'm going to do it together with
the Substack, but I don't know. I feel very
impassioned about both, so I think it's fine.
Yeah, you have to really want it.
Part of the reason I don't want
to do a book is all the talks I
have to do to promote it after.
Oh, I so understand. I think that's part of the
reason I take as long as I do to write them,
because I'm like dreading the promotional
period, so I'm just putting it off.
Oh, man. Well I'm impressed you overcome that.
I mean, for me, my dream
always was to be a writer,
so that was the primary, primary thing.
So I'll overcome anything for that dream.
I get that. Okay Susan, we've covered everything
I've wanted to cover. Is there anything else
that you think might be helpful to leave
listeners with that, especially introverts,
that are trying to be successful, feel
better about their way of the world?
There is a phrase, an aphorism, a saying from
Gandhi who said, who is very shy and very
introverted, by the way. Like, extremely. His
autobiography, very fascinating. He talks a lot
about this. He was such a shy kid, he would
run home from school after class because he
didn't want to have to talk to anybody. He was
really like that his whole life. He was just,
he was one of these people I was talking
about who had a very deep conviction,
and then attracted other people who shared
that deep conviction. And so he said,
"In a gentle way, you can shake the world."
And I deeply believe this to be true.
That's an excellent role model to think
about in back, going back to your other
exercise of Gandhi as an introvert. I did not
know that. That's awesome. Susan, with that,
we've reached a very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
I'm ready.
First question, what are two
or three books that you find
yourself recommending most to other people?
So I was talking earlier about the psychologist,
Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi. He famously wrote a
book about flow. It's literally called Flow.
And flow is the state of mind you get into
when you're totally engaged in an activity,
and you're completely absorbed by it, and
you're feeling neither bored nor anxious,
you're just in it. And the book just describes
all the research on this date and what it is,
and it completely changed my life, so I recommend
that one all the time. And also The Power of
Myth by Joseph Campbell, who was just a great
mythologist, and completely fascinating, and-
Hero's journey.
Hero's journey, yeah, and he talked about the need
to participate joyfully in the sorrows
of the world, which I really believe in.
Which I know your third book was about.
Yeah, that's right. Bittersweet.
Bittersweet. Find that on Amazon or your local
retailers. The flow book, can you say his last
name again? Because I think nobody actually
knows how to pronounce it, and I love that you-
No one does.
... can say it so comfortably.
Yeah, because my agent taught me how.
It's, you go cheek, like your cheek.
Oh my God, that's great.
Sent, me, high. So that's more
or less how you pronounce it.
Csikszentmihalyi. Oh my God.
Yeah.
What a win for a tip right there. Okay,
next question. Do you have a favorite recent
movie or TV show that you've really enjoyed?
I never have anything recent, but so my
husband and kids and I just watched The
Sopranos recently. I had never seen it
before, and we loved it. And I also just
recently saw The Talented Mr. Ripley, which
I know it's really old, but so, so good.
Wow, I love how old these are.
I know, I know. But basically
anything that you see where
there's just something dazzling
happening in it. Like Jude Law's
performance in The Talented Mr. Ripley
is pure enddazzlement, if that's a word.
This connects to advice I often hear, which
is don't read books that are... Either read
books that are just very new, or 10 years or
older. I think that's the advice. Don't read
books that are sort of... Because you want
to only read things that have have survived
and people continue to come back to. Quiet,
I think is definitely an example of that.
Thank you. Yeah, I do think there's
something about that, like that... Yeah,
if it's survived that long, it's for a reason.
Yeah. [inaudible 01:12:02]. Oh, yeah.
Okay. Can I say something that
will not be lightning roundish?
Please. Sure.
Okay. Because what you just made me think of is,
there's this, I guess it's an organization or
institute, it's called the Tugboat Institute,
I think is the official name. And anyway,
it's basically it's four founders of companies
who are not interested in starting their company
and then making a quick exit three years
later. These are people who are trying
to build something evergreen, and something
built to last. And so this is an organization
for the founders who have this mentality. And
I've talked to the head of this organization,
I'm actually going to be speaking there in
June or July, and he told me that they have
tons of introverts in this group of CEOs. I do
think there's something about that mentality of
seeking the timeless and the evergreen that
is one of those underappreciated strengths.
That's awesome. That sounds
like a sweet place to be.
Yeah.
Hopefully not too many extroverts get in there
and they're just like, "What the hell is going
on here? I don't want to be here." Okay. I'm
going to keep going with lightning round.
Yeah.
Let's see. Okay. Is there a favorite product you
recently discovered that you really love? Whether
it could be an app, could be something you bought,
physical, something laying around the house.
I will say the art of roasted vegetables.
Cool.
Yeah, I've started just roasting
my vegetables with tons of spices
of all kinds, and it's such a revelation.
And it's not a gadget, you just roast
them in a cooking sheet sort of thing?
Yeah, I just toss them with olive oil, and
maybe some lemon juice, and almond slices,
or curry, or whatever I feel like
doing, and it's like candy. So good.
Interesting. And this is just like easy
way to eat healthy, and it tastes good.
Yep.
What a life chip. I just read this book,
Good Energy. I don't know if
you've heard of this. It's about-
No.
... what foods give you good energy
and what foods are bad energy.
Interesting.
And it's based on metabolic
health and blood sugar,
and which ones spike you and help you,
and you're eating good energy food.
Yes.
Takeaway. Okay. Two more questions. Do you have a
favorite life motto that you often come back to,
find really useful in work or in life,
maybe share with friends and family?
Yeah, I mean, I will give the one
that was the dedication to and the
inspiration for Bittersweet. This is
a quote from Leonard Cohen who said,
"There's a crack in everything.
That's where the light gets in."
I love that. I want to make a big poster out
of all these mottos someday of all these-
Yeah. Yeah, you really should. You
probably have have amazing ones collected.
So many, oh man. Final question.
You have a very active Substack. I'm
very impressed with how often you publish.
It's very hard. Where can people find it,
and just what should people know about
the Substack that you've started?
Oh, well, it's called thequietlife.net, so that's
where you can find it. And it's basically a place
for people who want to live in the realm of
the quiet, and thoughtful, and sensitive,
and bittersweet. I've kind of been exploring
that realm for 20 years, and this is a place to
be with other people who are in that realm also.
And so some of the time I'm posting things about
tips along the lines of what we've been talking
about for this podcast. And sometimes it's more,
I don't know, just sharing art and poetry and
things. So tomorrow I'm posting an exclusive
excerpt from Sahil Bloom's new book, The Five
Types of Wealth, about how much time do you have
remaining with your loved ones, and how are you
spending that time? So I would say it's dedicated
to how to live a good life from the perspective of
the quiet, and the thoughtful, and the sensitive.
Sounds like a wonderful place, corner
of the internet. How do people find it?
Just so we can LinkedIn, we'll
LinkedIn in the show notes too.
Yeah, so thequietlife.net, or I guess if you go
to Substack and just look up my name, you could
probably find it there. But yeah, it's become a
huge labor of love because it's a way I'm able to
write to people who have been reading my stuff for
years, but now we have a dialogue and a community.
And I think people really feel like having a place
to go that is a very specific wavelength that you
can't find elsewhere can be something special, and
I know I feel that as the person writing into it.
Okay. Final question then is, how
can listeners be useful to you?
I usually ask how do people find
you online? We just talked about
that. So I'm skipping that question.
How can listeners be useful to you?
I don't know. I guess I would say the Substack
that I'm doing is my baby and my labor of love,
so if you want to partake of it,
I would love to have you there.
Awesome. Susan, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you so much for having
me. So nice to talk to you.
Solely my pleasure.
I really enjoyed it.
So nice. Just introvert connection.
Yes, exactly.
Okay, bye everyone. Thank you so much for
listening. If you found this valuable,
you can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review,
as that really helps other listeners
find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.