You are ostensibly a professor at
Stanford Graduate School of Business,
and you shared that when
people come ask you for advice,
the most common question you get
is, "What should I do with my life?"
Imagine that you're walking home from work, you
see this bright, shiny object, and you realize
it's a magic lamp. And you rub the lamp and this
genie comes out and the genie says, "Hey, I can
give you one wish. Whatever you throw yourself
into with your whole life and your career,
it's going to turn out great." If that were true
and you had that genie, what would you wish for?
At some point in this one life we get, you want
to get yourself on that path of that journey.
This whole exercise connects to
something that you're a big advocate of,
this idea of getting out of
autopilot mode in your life.
You're unconscious, and you may not even
realize why you're doing what you're doing
or even realize what you're doing. So for
example, I get up, work out, drive into work,
fight traffic, commute, maybe I return some
emails, fight traffic on the way home, rush
through dinner, go to bed. It's not a day that
is intentional. It's not a day where I've said,
"Where do I want to be going with my life?
What's important to me in this world?"
You another quote, which is, "Everything that
you want is on the other side of worse first."
Pick anything. You want a better body? Okay,
you're going to need to go to the gym. When
you go to the gym the first few times, it's
going to not be that fun. The first move is
negative. If I'm optimizing for tomorrow and
I just want to have a great day tomorrow, I'm
going to stay exactly where I am. So many people
I see have this happen, where they hit a plateau
and they never move past it, because they're not
willing to have that hard day, month, week, year.
When should you quit something, because
some things are just not worth it.
I think the time to quit is
when you can no longer ...
Today, my guest is Graham Weaver. Graham teaches
a top-rated course at Stanford's Graduate School
of Business, a course which is technically called
Managing Growing Enterprises. But as you'll hear
in our conversation, he ends up mostly helping
students figure out what to do with their lives
and how to get out of the autopilot mode that
most people are in. He recently won Stanford
Graduate Business School's 2024 MBA Distinguished
Teaching Award. And teaching is actually his side
gig. His full-time job is founder and CEO
of Alpine Investors, a private equity firm,
which based on my research, is one of if not
the top-performing private equity fund in
the world. So the advice you're going to hear
today is coming from someone who is actually
doing the thing, not just teaching the thing.
In our conversation, we cover practical exercises
that can help you figure out what you should do
with your life, including something he calls the
genie framework and the nine lives exercise. We
talk about why life is suffering, and you may as
well choose something worth suffering for, also,
why most things in life that are worthwhile take
more time than you expect, some practical advice
for creating accountability in your life to help
you achieve your goals, and so much more.
If you listen to this episode and actually
try some of the exercises that Graham shares, I
promise you that your life and your future will
be better off. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in
your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's
the best way to avoid missing future episodes,
and it helps the podcast tremendously.
With that, I bring you Graham Weaver.
This episode is brought to you by Merge. Product
leaders, yes, like you, cringe when they hear
the word integration. They're not fun for
you to scope, build, launch, or maintain,
and integrations probably aren't what led you to
product work in the first place. Lucky for you,
the folks at Merge are obsessed with integrations.
Their single API helps SaaS companies launch over
200 product integrations in weeks, not quarters.
Think of Merge like Plaid, but for everything B2B
SaaS. Organizations like Ramp, Dorada and Electric
use Merge to access their customers' accounting
data to reconcile bill payments, file storage data
to create searchable databases in their product,
or HRAS data to auto-provision and deprovision
access for their customers' employees. And yes,
if you need AI-ready data for your SaaS product,
then Merge is the fastest way to get it. So want
to solve your organization's integration
dilemma once and for all? Book and attend
a meeting at merge.dev/lenny, and receive a
$50 Amazon gift card. That's merge.dev/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Persona, the
adaptable identity platform that helps businesses
fight fraud, meet compliance requirements,
and build trust. While you're listening to
this right now, how do you know that you're
really listening to me, Lenny? These days,
it's easier than ever for fraudsters to steal PII,
faces and identities. That's where Persona comes
in. Persona helps leading companies like
LinkedIn, Etsy and Twilio securely verify
individuals and businesses across the world.
What sets Persona apart is its configurability.
Every company has different needs depending on
its industry, use cases, risk tolerance and user
demographics. That's why Persona offers flexible
building blocks that allow you to build tailored
collection and verification flows that maximize
conversion while minimizing risks. Plus, Persona's
orchestration tools automate your identity process
so that you can fight rapidly shifting fraud and
meet new waves of regulation. Whether you're a
startup or an enterprise business, Persona has a
plan for you. Learn more at withpersona.com/lenny;
again, that's withpersona.com/lenny.
Graham, thank you so much for
being here. Welcome to the podcast.
Thanks so much for having me,
Lenny. I'm super excited to be here.
Okay, so you are ostensibly a professor
at Stanford Graduate School of Business,
of a class called Managing Growing Enterprises.
But I was reading an interview with you,
and you shared that when people come
ask you for advice, they're not asking,
"How do I start a company? How do I
manage my growing enterprise? How do I
make my company grow faster?" Most of the
questions, the most common question you get,
which is surprising to me, is, "What should I do
with my life?" First of all, is that accurate?
Yeah, that is accurate. About half of all the
times I meet with students, that's the question
they ask. It's really funny too, because sometimes
they'll come with a PowerPoint presentation and a
two-by-two matrix and an expected value and all
that. But really they're asking the question of,
"Hey, what should I do with my life,"
which is, by the way, a great question.
Why do you think that's the case? That's not what
I would imagine someone at an MBA school
in a business class asking for advice on.
My typical meeting with a student will say, the
student will start to tell me about these two
or three different career or job alternatives
that they have, A, B and C. Let's just use two,
A and B. And then they go through and they start
talking about A, and they tell me all the pros and
the cons of A, and they go through it. And then
they go through B, and they start telling me all
those things. And I start asking some questions.
And after about five or 10 minutes into that,
I can tell that their heart and their soul and
their energy is really for B. That's really what
they want, but they're talking themselves out of
B, and they're going to talk themselves into A.
So what I try to do is, A, first, I try to let
them realize that their real energy is for B,
just let them feel that and understand that.
And then secondly, I try to figure out,
what are the limiting beliefs they have? What
are the fears? What are the obstacles? What
are the voices in their head? What are all the
societal pressures that are keeping them from
doing B? And then we try to deconstruct those
and get them to go do B. So that's the process.
Is there an example of a student going ... just
this actual conversation you had with someone?
Absolutely. So there's a great example
of a student of mine was from Brazil.
And he came in and his prior job prior to
business school was he worked in consulting.
And that was more or less what he wanted to do.
And then at some point I asked the students,
"Okay, imagine you knew you were going to
be successful and you were going to have a
dream. And whatever you dreamed was going to
come true, what would you dream for?" And he
wanted to start a nonprofit in his home country
of Brazil to help students have more access
to education. That was what came up for him.
And over the course of our class, we just chipped
away at all the fears and limiting beliefs of why
he shouldn't or couldn't do that. And by the end,
that's what he did. And so that's a real life
example. And there's all kinds of other examples,
but that second one of going and starting a
charity, it's not on the beaten path. It's
not what probably your parents are thinking you
should do. There's probably 100 reasons not to do
it. You probably don't know exactly how to start,
and so it's intimidating. But if you start with
this idea, "Hey, five years out, 10 years
out, I know I'm going to be successful,"
and work backwards from that, you're
going to come up with a better answer.
This is a framework that you call the
genie methodology or the genie framework,
this question that you just asked that we
should spend more time on, which is ... I guess,
you tell the story of the genie and how
to think about this [inaudible 00:09:20].
Well, when I was 13 years old, I used to listen
to these motivational tapes, mowing lawns. And I'm
pretty sure it was Brian Tracy had this exercise.
And I've adapted it, so I'll use my exercise
now. So I say basically imagine that you're
walking home from work and you see this bright,
shiny object. You walk over and you realize
it's a magic lamp. And you rub the lamp and
this genie comes out and the genie says, "Hey, I
haven't been in this bottle for 10,000 years yet,
so I'm not fully formed. So I can't give you three
wishes. But what I can do is I can give you one
wish. And the wish I can give you is whatever
you throw yourself into with your whole life
and your career, it's going to turn out great.
It's going to work out great. It's probably
going to take longer than you think. It's going
to be harder than you think, but you're going
to be really happy you did and it's going to
work out beyond your wildest imagination." If
that were true and you had that genie blessing
you with that wish, what would you wish for?
And then the students come up with an answer
that's really close to their heart. It's a
thing they would do, absent the fear of
failure. And then the second part of the
exercise is basically that's what you should go
do. You should be spending your life in pursuit
of your genie goal. Maybe you can't start that
tomorrow; you have financial obligations, maybe
there's some experience you need. But at some
point in this one life we get, you want to get
yourself on that path of that journey. And that's
the exercise that I go through with the students.
It's such a simple idea, that I can totally
see how it could be so powerful. And
I love the way it's framed as not like
it'll guarantee you'll be successful. It's
instead, I'll guarantee you'll be happy.
You'll be happy that you took the path.
And the reason I say that is that usually
the genie goal is the not well-trodden path.
So you don't even know exactly what the goal
is. This charity to start education
for underprivileged kids in Brazil,
that takes its own form over the course of
a decade. And it will almost certainly turn
out differently than you think. So it's more that
you'll be really happy you went and started that
journey, and it will go great. It'll probably go
differently and take longer than you think though.
What are some other examples of
genie goals folks have followed
that are kind of non-traditional and
they've ended up being happy about it?
Mine was buying companies in my dorm room at
business school. I have a student who's starting
an amusement park in Texas. That's a pretty
crazy example. Many students who are leaving
their job and doing startups. A lot of students
who going in the nonprofit world. So really just
lots of examples. It's as variant as the number
of students I have. And that's the magic of it,
because you have inside of you some really unique
dream that you maybe haven't even shared. And the
goal is that that's your uniqueness, and that's
what you should be bringing into this world.
This whole exercise connects to something that
you're a big advocate of, this idea of getting
out of autopilot mode in your life. And the way
I think about it is people ... and I'm going to
ask you to describe it, but just it's almost
like you're driving and you've never turned
off the cruise control in your car, and you
don't realize it. Talk about this idea that
most of us are in autopilot and why it's so
important to realize that and get out of it.
You start off and you're unconscious, and
you're kind of going through the motions.
And you may not even realize why you're doing
what you're doing or even realize what you're
doing. So for example, a typical person gets up,
they have whatever their morning routine ... I'll
use myself. I get up out, work out, take a shower,
drive into work, fight traffic, commute. I'm late.
I get in, I'm late to a meeting, I'm kind
of rushed meeting; meeting, meeting. Okay,
quick break for lunch. Maybe I return some emails;
a few more meetings, a couple of Zoom calls.
Fight traffic on the way home, rush through
dinner, get back on email. Go to bed. Okay,
that's my day. And that's a busy day. I felt like
I did a lot. I'm exhausted, but it's unconscious.
It's not a day that is intentional. It's not
a day where I've said, "Where do I want to
be going with my life? What's important to
me in this world? What are my values? What
10 years from now will I wish I was starting to
embark on?" Adding that level of intentionality
and then working backwards from that is really
the magic of getting to that 10 years from now
and looking back without regret and getting to a
later point in your life and feeling like you're
doing the thing you're put on the earth to do
as opposed to just going through the motions.
So the question then here is, how do you get out
of that autopilot mode? Because first of all,
no one really realizes this is the case.
And I'll tell a quick story. We're going
to different preschools and daycares for
our son. He's a year and a half oldish.
And we went to this Montessori school, and the
teacher's like, "I'm going to be very clear:
what we're doing here is informing your child's
subconscious. That's what they're learning here.
And that's a huge responsibility. We put a
lot of love into that idea, but it's very
important you understand that's what we do at
the school." And I never thought of it that way.
That's amazing that they said that. So
you just opened up another part of this,
which is depending on what research
you read, somewhere between 95% and
98% of our thoughts are subconscious.
And those get programmed in somehow,
some way. A big part of that, by the
way, is media, our friends, our parents,
our boss, our coworkers, what we think we're
supposed to do, social media: "This is cool,
buy this Ferrari," all these different things. And
then you're just operating out of that. And so the
idea of being intentional is create space,
get out of that, get out of the fog of war,
make some space. We'll probably get to this in a
little bit, but I do it with an executive coach,
and really ask deep questions, make space, ask
questions, create the intention that you want in
each of the areas of your life. And then start
having your calendar reflect that intention.
And so this genie exercise is one approach,
is just ask yourself this question. Can you
say it again just for folks so they don't miss
it, what's the question you should ask yourself?
I mean, the biggest question I think with
respect to your career is, within reason,
what would you do if you knew you
wouldn't fail? That's the biggest
question. I'll give you a few more if you want.
Yeah, please.
Different questions trigger different
things with people that could be helpful,
trigger in a good way. So here's a few
more. If you didn't have to make money,
what would you do? And that'll answer what you
enjoy. Naval Ravikant has a great question,
which is, what's play for you that is
work for other people? So for you, Lenny,
that might be a podcast. That might be play for
you; that's really fun. You're always going to do
better at that. You're going to spend more time,
you're going to enjoy it more. That's a good one.
Another one is, what's the thing you really
want to do? But you're just too embarrassed
to say it? And my answer to this question was
that I wanted to be a motivational speaker like
Tony Robbins. And I was super embarrassed to say
that, but that actually works into a lot of my
life at this point. Another question, who are some
people that you admire and want to be more like,
and what do they do? Where do you find those
people? What are some things you want to learn
and how do you want to grow over the next five,
10 years? So I know a lot of your listeners are
working in tech. So five, 10 years from now,
you're amazing, you're best in the world at
X. What's X? And how do you start to work toward
becoming great at X? So there's just a few more
other questions you could throw in to help you
figure out some things you're excited about.
You mentioned this idea of limiting beliefs.
And I think a lot of people listening to this
are probably having these beliefs right now of,
"Okay, but I have a family to support. Am I going
to go start a charity in Brazil? That's absurd. It
sounds easy, but I can't actually change my life
this radically." Can you just share something
to help people get past that in some way?
Sure. The first thing I would say
about limiting beliefs is they're the
most powerful and the most dangerous when you
don't even know what they are. So when they're
in the recesses of your subconscious
mind, that is 95% of your thoughts,
that's when the limiting
beliefs are the most dangerous.
So a simple example might just be like I have a
limiting belief that I'm not funny. That's in my
subconscious and I don't even realize I have
it. So I avoid things where I'm trying to be
funny or tell jokes. I mean, that's a silly
example. But let's use your career now and
come up with some maybe deeper ones. Let's use
that charity example, the Brazilian charity,
"I'm going to start a Brazilian charity." What
are the limiting beliefs? Well, oh my gosh,
there's a million. "I don't know how to start.
I don't know how I would pay for myself. I have
business school debt. I don't really know what
I'm even talking about. I don't even have a plan
for it. How would I get funding?" Those are
all these things that are flooding your mind.
So the first exercise is just write all that down.
Just get it down on paper, and then two things
will happen. One is when you get it down on paper,
it will almost immediately strip that limiting
belief of a lot of its power and a lot of its
scariness. Because now it's just something like,
for example, "How would I fund this?" So the
second thing that is that a lot of that scariness
becomes just a to-do item. In the recesses
of your subconscious, that is a very scary,
limiting belief that will actually keep you from
doing the thing you love. Once it's on paper,
now it's just a to-do item that you can
actually deal with with your conscious mind,
just like you do anything else. So, "How
would I fund this," just becomes a plan, like,
"I need to design a plan where I'd get funding
for this charity." And then that just is a problem
like any other problem. It's not this nebulous,
scary fear. It's just literally a to-do item.
So the first part of limiting beliefs,
write them down, understand what they are,
look at them in the cold day of light on paper,
and then translate them into things that are just
obstacles to be overcome. And by the way,
if you're listening to this podcast, you've
overcome millions of obstacles in your life, and
these are no different once they're down on paper.
Are you actually doing these
exercises with your students?
They're taking a class about growing
their enterprise and then it's like,
"Okay, let's analyze what you want to do
with your life"? Is that how this class goes?
That's a really good question. So I'll give
you a little bit of background. So I was a
case guest at Stanford Business School while
I was buying companies in my dorm room. And
it was talking about all the things that went
wrong. And so it's kind of a really fun case.
And I did that for 12 years. And I started to
realize that was my most energetic day of the
year. And so long story short, I started
teaching a class full time. So I did that
for four years. And I was teaching the Xs and
Os of being a CEO, basically: hiring, firing,
having hard conversations, managing a board,
fundraising, selling, all the things you would
imagine that a young CEO would need to know.
After about four years, I started to realize
that was great, except that no one went and
did it. So the class is on entrepreneurship,
and they learned how to be an entrepreneur. There
was only one problem: they didn't actually become
entrepreneurs. So then I said, "Well, wait a
sec. I have to readjust my class a little bit,
and I have to spend some time on the stuff we've
just been talking about: finding out what your
dream is, your limiting beliefs, starting to map
out goals toward your actual entrepreneurship
dream or whatever your genie goal is."
So the way I say it is the university
allows me to teach the class because
I teach them entrepreneurial tricks,
tactics, tools that will help them become a great
CEO. But the real reason I teach is because I'm
trying to help people really go find the thing
that they're excited about and get into the life
path of doing that thing. So I do both, but I do
the second one kind of ... maybe that's not the
headline of the course, although I think that's
probably why people like the course so much.
It's like a Trojan horse element.
Exactly, yeah. Tony Robbins used to say that
people hire him for success, and he has to
give them that so that he feels like he earned
his money, but what he really delivers them is
fulfillment. And it's a little bit like that.
People take my class to learn how to be a CEO,
but what they really get is hopefully on
the path of doing the thing they want to do.
A lot of what you've been talking
about, it's almost an assumption that
you'll be more successful and happier if you
follow your energy, your passion, versus the,
"Here's how I'll make a bunch of money. Here's how
I'll move up the ladder." Can you speak to that?
Yeah. Gosh, Lenny, it sounds so
cliche when you say it like that,
that I almost cringe a little bit. Let me try
to give it a little bit different framework
where it won't sound as ... because
cliches are cliches because they're
true. But let me try to give you a little
bit different framework to think about it.
I think about it as you have sort of your
heart or your soul or your internal scorecard,
and then you have your head and your mind and the
world's external scorecard. And I'll speak from
this from experience. So when I graduated from
business school, I took the job I was supposed
to take. And it was the safe job at the big
private equity firm that paid well and looked
great on my resume. And I took that job. That was
the external scorecard. My head said that. I built
an expected value calculation, all that stuff.
The problem was it wasn't my internal scorecard.
It had nothing to do with what I actually
cared about and wanted to do with my life.
And so the way that shows up is just this
tension, friction, stress, anxiety, burnout,
all those things. And you can will that, you
can will yourself through for long periods of
time. In fact, if you want, you can will
yourself through that your whole life.
But then once I got into the path of the thing
that I was excited about, that's when I really
felt my energy change dramatically. And I
developed almost a superpower in that thing,
because I had more energy. I was willing to
work longer, I was willing to do it. I've
been running my company now for 23 years. I was
willing to do it for a longer period of time. I
thought about it in the shower. I thought about
it when I went on runs. I talked to people. They
wanted to join because I was excited. And it
was a whole different level of power and life
force that I was able to bring to that.
So I'm saying this from experience,
that you're going to show up so much differently
in the thing that you're excited about, that that
alone is going to make your life a lot better.
But the great irony is you're going to do so
much better in that thing than you are the thing
you are, quote, "supposed to do." And I certainly,
certainly understand that people have real
life constraints on their finances. And I 100%
get that. And so a big part of what I do with
students is work through those things and say,
"Okay, great. Let's talk about this job you're
going to take for X years and you're going to
pay off your loans or whatever. But during
that time, let's get you on the path of the
thing you really want to do." So sometime soon
in your life, you want to get on that path.
There's a bunch of directions I want
to go here. One is I'll just share,
what you're describing is exactly what happened
to me, without knowing this advice. I just
started writing things online because the poll
was there and people seemed to enjoy it. So I
just kept following that path. And the whole
time, my wife's like, "You can't make money
writing on the internet. That's not a thing. Why
would you do this? You have all these skills,
that you can make a lot more doing other things."
But I just kept doing that, and that's what led me
to this life now where I make much, much more than
I made as a product manager at Airbnb. And also,
it's a lot less stressful. And so, I'm
a living example [inaudible 00:26:39].
Yeah. And if you go back to what I was saying
before, you probably were answering the question,
"What would I do if I didn't have to make money?"
You just did that because you enjoyed it. What's
play for you that's work for other people? What
do you do in your free time? You were answering
all those questions. And then I think a lot of
people just say, "Oh, well, that's just a side
hustle or a hobby." It is until it isn't,
right? And you're a great example of that.
Just to set it some expectations with folks, you
tell me, how often does this actually work out for
someone where this ended up being the right path
for them, that it ended up working well for them?
Just because people can hear this and be like,
"Yeah, okay, I'm sure it works for some people;
probably not for most people." What's the success
rate, however you define that, for your students?
Okay, so the short answer is I don't know,
because I don't have full information about
how my students do or what their path would
have been had they not done it. So it's a kind
of difficult question to answer. But what I would
say is that the formula you're solving for is you,
excited about something for a decade or more. So
what has to happen? You excited about something.
We just talked about what that is. The decade
or more is going to come true more likely if
you're excited about it. But also, you have
to go in at the beginning with that mindset
and the structural ability to stay at it for a
long period of time. So the missing ingredient
in most of the people that fail is time.
And I'll use myself as an example. I started
Alpine. We lost money on our first fund. We
started doing well. We got hit by the recession,
we started digging out, whatever. But long
story short, I was 14 years into running my
firm until I could say with confidence we were
going to even stay in business, let alone be
really successful. And probably 18 years until
we were what I would say really successful by
external standards. And now 23 years, we've had a
great run. But if you take away the time period,
then I would've gone down as one of the,
quote, "failures," as opposed to, I would say,
one of the success stories using this methodology.
So time is the variable. And I think the biggest
part of that is it's really, believe it
or not, not typically the finance or the
structural piece. It's the entrepreneur or the
individual's willingness to actually stay with
it. And then upstream of that, it's their belief
about how long it's supposed to take. And I really
hate this about the social media and just media in
general, where they try to paint this picture that
things are going to happen overnight. And we've
invested in 600 businesses. Let's say 550 of those
are founder-started businesses where we're the
first money. I've never, in one of those examples,
seen anyone who did something quickly. They've all
been very, very long stories to get to that point.
This reminds me of a quote I read. I don't
know if you wrote this or you shared it,
this idea that the life is suffering,
so choose something worth suffering for.
I wrote that, yeah.
You wrote that. Talk about that, because
it feels like it's exactly what you're
describing. It's going to take a
long time to figure something out.
Exactly. Yeah, exactly. I'm glad you brought
that ... Yeah, I mean, think about it. Again,
using myself as an example, the first job
I had, I wasn't suffering any less. I was
getting on planes, I was working late hours.
My time was not my own. If I would've had kids,
I'd be missing their little league games and all
that stuff. So I'm doing that anyway. I'm just
doing it for something I don't care about.
And then I start my own company and I was,
quote, "suffering," getting
on planes, doing all that.
It was just something that I cared about. So
yeah, the quote, "Life is suffering. So figure
out something worth suffering for," you're going
to suffer either way. And that's another thing
I think people don't realize, is there isn't
really a path that is easy that I've ever found.
You have another quote along these lines,
which is, "Everything you want is
on the other side of worse first."
Yeah, I mean, I know those are two
non-super optimistic quotes perhaps,
but I think they're true. The second one,
everything you want is on the other side
of worst first, and this is something where I
almost can't think of many exceptions to this.
Pick anything. You want a better body? Okay,
you're going to need to go to the gym. When you
go to the gym the first few times, it's going to
not be that fun. You're going to set your alarm,
you're going to get sore. It's not going to be
great. You're going to have to probably make some
changes to your diet. That's not going to be fun,
at least initially. And so that's one example.
You want to change careers, you're going to
have to learn a new career. You're going to
have to leave your career. You're going
to have to maybe interview for new jobs,
or whatever it is. In each case, the first move is
negative. The first move is negative to getting in
shape. The first move is negative to get out
of a bad relationship, to get into a career
you want to be in. The reason I think that's
important to say is because if I'm optimizing
for tomorrow and I just want to have a great day
tomorrow, I'm going to stay exactly where I am,
because my life will be better tomorrow if I don't
make any changes. I don't have to break up with my
girlfriend, have a hard conversation, have the
tears, be alone, go on dating apps. I don't have
to do that if I just stay in it one more day.
So if you realize this and instead ask the
question, the version of myself five years from
now, what would they wish I was going to do right
now? So I can guarantee your five-year version
of yourself will say, "Get out of that toxic
relationship, no matter how painful it is for the
next two months." And if you can make decisions
from that, and then on top of that, realize it's
going to get worse first, then that's why I say
everything you want is on the other side of worse
first. But if you don't do that, you just end up
plateauing. And so many people I see have this
happen where they hit a plateau and they never
move past it because they're not willing to have
that hard day, month, week, year whatever it is.
I am imagining many people hearing this right
now are like, "Yeah, I see what I need to do
now." That was really powerful advice.
It makes me think of parenting advice,
some parenting advice I recently saw.
Dr. Becky has this advice of your job
as a parent isn't to make your kids
happy, but it's to make them resilient.
I love that, yeah. By the way, watch how people
parent. They parent exactly the opposite of that.
Exactly [inaudible 00:34:09].
You and I both live in Marin. I don't
know if you have kids or how old they are,
but when you get kids in school
in Marin, you see parents,
they try to clear all obstacles away from
their kids. It's the worst thing you could do.
Today's episode is brought to you by Liveblocks,
the platform that turns your product into a
place that users want to be. With ready-made,
collaborative features, you can supercharge
your product with experiences that only top tier
companies have been able to perfect until now.
Think AI copilots like Notion, multiplayer like
Figma, comments and notifications like Linear,
and even collaborative editing like Google Docs,
and all of that with minimal configuration or
maintenance required. Companies from all kinds
of industries and stages count on Liveblocks
to drive engagement and growth in their products.
Join them today and give your users an experience
that turns them into daily active users. Sign up
for a free account today at liveblocks.io/lenny.
I want to talk about another exercise that you
have, but before I do that, there's all this
advice you're sharing that people might be hearing
and be like, "Yeah, yeah. Okay, this is great."
I'm going to share this in intro, and we're not
going to talk a lot about your fund, but I did
some research on it. And from what I understand,
it's one of the top performing PE funds in the
world, which is very hard, considering how many
smart people run PE funds and how ruthless that
industry is. Anything you can comment on there?
Yeah, I think that's important for people to know.
Well, I think one of the things I would say
is that I never stand up in front of students
or be on a podcast like this and say anything
that I'm not doing myself or that I'm advising
students or people who work at Alpine to do. And
so I appreciate the kind words. And I think that
the things that I'm talking about are rooted in
real results. And this is not just happy talk
podcast. The formula, I think, for greatness is to
be intentional, get in the path of the thing that
you're most excited about, and then give yourself
several decades to do it. And that's based on
investing in 600 companies and building my own
business. So I appreciate the kind call out.
Yeah. For people that are listening and
be like, "Okay, I'm motivated. I want to
do this," other than taking your class,
anything you can recommend to just do
these sorts of exercises, ask yourself
these questions that you've seen work?
I mean, the answer is accountability. How do
you keep yourself accountable to living the
life you want to live? And the analogy I would
use is let's say that your number one goal in
life is you've got to get in better shape. You
just have to. Let's say you have even medically,
you're going to have real health problems if you
don't do that. I would say you hire yourself a
personal trainer, pay what you need to pay.
Okay, maybe you don't have a ton of money,
but that's where I'd spend it. That person, A,
they're going to hold you accountable to showing
up at a certain time, and B, they're going to
show you the exercises. They're going to call
you if you're not there. You're just increasing
the chances of success. Plus you spend some money,
you want to get your money out of it.
The equivalent of that in your life is
an executive coach. And I figured this out in 2009
in the dark recesses of the recession. I hired my
first executive coach. And I was like, "Wow, it's
a personal trainer for me for two things." Number
one, make space to ask yourself the big questions
in life about your career, your relationships,
your health, your spirituality, your children.
Whatever the big things are in your life, ask
the big questions, find out what your intention
is. What are you looking for in those areas? And
just have, in my case, several hours a week to get
clear on those things. Okay, so that's part one.
And then part two is that person can hold you
accountable. I have one coach that I can't even
have the call with the coach unless I fill out
a piece of paper or an online form that says,
"Here's what my one year goals are, outcomes I
want to have this year are. Here's what I did last
week, based on those. Here's what I'm going to do
next week toward those. And here's the outcomes I
want to have for the call we're about to have."
And even if I never had the call, just having
to fill that out every single week is incredibly
powerful and allows me to hold myself accountable.
So 100%, that's what I'd recommend. Let's back
up and say, okay, let's say you can't afford a
coach or you're worried about that. And this
is the same thing as, let's say you couldn't
afford a personal trainer. I would give you the
same advice, which is find a very like-minded
friend of yours and sit down and do it for each
other. So if you're using the workout example,
okay, you're going to go on a run Tuesdays,
Wednesdays and Fridays with your friend,
and they're going to meet you at 7:00 AM at this
trail, or 6:00 AM at this trail. That's your
accountability. And you're going to be more likely
to do it. You don't want to let them down. They're
going to beat you up if you don't get there.
Same is true with this. This is how I started.
I did this with my roommate in business school.
And we would go on a walk for 30 minutes and
talk about my dreams and hopes. Then we'd turn
around and talk about his. And it was great,
because we made room for each other to have
those conversations, and we also developed a
great friendship. So short of having an actual
executive coach, find a really-minded person
that could get into this with you, and that
would be another thing. But accountability is
huge. I'm going to just say one more thing. I'm
sorry. I'm going on a little bit long on this.
[inaudible 00:40:20] please.
There's another thing that happens that's kind
of magical, which is you activate a different
part of your brain when you talk. You actually
activate more of your brain when you talk than
when you think or write. So thinking activates
the least amount of your brain. Writing is a
little bit better, but talking activates a whole
different region of your brain. So that's the
other big benefit of not doing this just on your
own, is being able to talk about it with someone.
I love that there's a whole spectrum of ways to
create accountability for yourself. I love the
second coach you've shared, where just filling
out that form was basically the biggest benefit.
I learned this from these audio tapes. When I
was in college, I had this green notebook. And
I was trying to row crew, and I never row crew
before. And I wrote down at the top of the page
every single morning, I wrote down, "I am the
number one rower in the country." I wasn't. I
was a freshman novice, 135 pound Midwesterner,
never had been in a boat. But I wrote that down.
And then I wrote down three things I was going
to do that day to move toward that goal. And I
did that every single day that I was in college.
And it's just incredible. We talked earlier about
your subconscious mind. You're just locking
your subconscious mind into your goals and
where you want to go and who you want to be and
how you want to show up. It's really powerful.
And that's advice anybody can implement. "I want
to be the best [inaudible 00:41:51] founder"-
You could do that. You could do
that [inaudible 00:41:50] exactly.
Yeah. It's such a simple thing. "I want
to be the best product manager. Here's
three things I'm doing today
to help me along the lines."
Absolutely. My students have to do this
twice a week. It's one of their assignments,
and they actually have to turn it in. And I have
so many students that say five years later, "I
still do this a couple times a week, and it's been
unbelievable." I'd say this to all your listeners:
you will get more done writing down your goal and
three things you're going to do to move toward
that goal, you'll get more things done in three
months than you will in three years without that.
That's an awesome thing to just try
tomorrow at work. Write this down,
see how it goes. The coach point, I just want
to highlight that. What convinced me to get a
coach back when I was working is I just realized,
one, every athlete has a coach that tells them,
"Here's how to become better," slash, everyone
that you work with that is a leader and exec
basically has a coach. And the people that have
an exec coach will do better in their career and
life than those who don't. So why would you not
have someone there just helping you become better
at this craft? It just makes so much sense if
you can afford it. There are different price
points for different coaches. Most people can
probably afford it in some [inaudible 00:43:09].
That's right. That's right.
Sweet. Okay. Let's talk about another
framework that you have that you call
nine lives. And this is essentially another
way, it's like another way to hack your brain
to come up with things you really should be
doing, probably. Talk about this exercise.
So this idea of what's my passion and what's
my career goal, it can be really intimidating.
And it is intimidating. And so this exercise is
to make it less intimidating. And you basically
come up with nine lives. So you say your first
life, life one is the life you have now. So when
I did this exercise ... let's pretend I did
this exercise when I'm right out of school,
taking that job. So life one is I'm working
at this big firm, I live in the Bay Area,
here's what I'm doing. That's life one.
There's two rules. The first rule is all the lives
have to start from today. So you can't go back in
time. They all start from today. And the second
rule is you have to be excited about all these
lives. So I might say, "Hey, my second life is
I want to start a private equity firm and be
a founder and be a CEO." And that's life too.
And life three is I want to be an author and I
want to write whatever fiction or nonfiction.
And then life four would be I want to be a
professor and teach. And life five is maybe
I want to make videos and be on social media.
And life six, I want to be an actor. And you
go through this whole list of these lives.
And the idea is that ... A couple of things
from this exercise. One is let's say that
you're in a position where you need to be
working in the job you're in. There might be one
of these lives that gives you the most energy,
and it's the thing if you knew you wouldn't
fail, you would do this one. And it's good to
recognize what that is and then pull that
life a little bit into your current life.
So let's say, Lenny, that you were a product
manager, but you really loved doing podcasts,
and that was one of your nine lives. Do a podcast
every other week, and just pull it into your life,
which it sounds like what you did. You
started doing it as a side hustle. And
then that'll have two amazing effects. One is
you will just have more energy everywhere else
in your life. Forget if you ever do this full
time or not; just the act of pulling something
into your life you're really excited about
will give you a tremendous amount of energy.
And then the second thing is you'll ideally find
the path that is the thing that gives you the most
energy. The other thing that I've learned
in doing this exercise is you actually can
have pretty much all nine lives.
You can't have them at once,
but if you're fortunate enough to live long
enough, you can have all of these things. So
I have had the corporate job, been the founder,
been the professor, been a writer, had videos,
taught people. I've been able to bring
most of those lives into this current life.
There's a couple things there that come up
as you talk about. One is, on that point,
what I do now is my fourth career. First I
was an engineer, then I became a founder,
then I was a PM, and now I do whatever
the heck this is. And I think people
don't realize that's how life often goes.
You think you're going to do one thing,
and then you have many different careers
that pivot into [inaudible 00:46:46].
Exactly. And I think that's the thing.
It's just trying to make it a little
less intimidating. You don't have to
have this one life purpose, passion,
thing that you do for the rest of your
life. If you just follow the thing that
gives you energy at each time, it'll probably be
a good indication of where you want to be going.
The other thread there is, I know one of your
other really important pieces of advice is to
avoid this not now idea, where everyone's
like, "Here's the thing I should be doing,
my genie goal, but not now." Thoughts on just
how to think about that, of just like, "Okay,
I know I have these lives I could
live, but not now," on this or that?
Yeah, I mean, in 20 years of teaching, I've never
had a student come to me and say, "Hey, Graham,
my real dream is to do X, but I'm just going to
give up on it. I'm not going to do it." No one's
ever said that. Instead, they say, "Not now." And
not now, if they're not careful, will turn into
not ever, because not now is just really another
way of saying, "I'm not going to do it." And then
there's a million reasons why you can't do it now.
And those reasons, some of them are legit and some
of them are just fear in another form.
In terms of how to overcome that, I think
it's kind of hopeful to realize that it's never
really the right time. When you're making a change
or you're going to go do something different, it's
never going to feel secure and safe. You're always
going to have some fear. You're always going
to feel like you're not ready. You're going
to feel like it's too soon. You're going to feel
like you don't know exactly what that path looks
like. And so just understanding that's normal.
That's called entrepreneurship. That's called
life. And if you wait for the clouds to part and
this ray of sun to come down and say, "Now is the
time," you're going to wait your whole life.
And so I think that realization can maybe be
helpful. And then try to figure out, what are the
things that need to be true for you to launch? And
usually for my students, it's something financial
that is the big bottleneck. And what I tell them
is, "You know what? People have raised money
to start a business before. That's happened,
where you've had people who've started
businesses without their own money that
have been able to pay themselves. And
that's not a reason to not do it. It's
an obstacle. It's something you have to solve,
but it's not not an insurmountable obstacle."
This touches on a quote I definitely wanted
to get to, something that you wrote not long
ago. Here's the quote: "The most important thing
I've learned in the first 50 years of my life is
that the true game of life is an internal one,
not an external one. And that journey starts
with three powerful words: I am enough."
Talk about that. Why is that so important?
Well, I mean, that's a really a deep topic, but
I'll talk about the internal and external journey.
So life presents itself as a series of external
obstacles and events. And it feels very much
like an external journey. And it can feel that way
your whole life. But I think what you'll realize,
and I started realizing this when I really
started meditating and spending time distancing
myself from the subconscious thoughts, is a very,
very large part of life is internal. I say a very
large part because obviously you need some
food, clothing, shelter, some basic needs that
are external. But for most people that have the
ability to even listen to this podcast, I would
say the vast majority of your life is internal.
So what do I mean by that? I mean that you're
writing a story about what it is you think you
need to be happy, or you're writing a story about
things you think you need to be to be enough
or to be respected or to feel worthy or to get
admiration of other people. You're writing that
story, and it's just a story. And if you really
follow this logic, you'll realize that. You'll
realize it is 100% just a story, or it's a story
that you should even care. And then that opens
up a lot more agency that you have over deciding
what is important to you, what is your internal
scorecard, what are the things that matter to you,
not what the external world thinks or the story
you've been writing for a long time. When you
start to open this up, it's really kind of scary
at first, because you'll start to realize most of
the things you're operating from are
really just stories that have been
written at some point in your life. And
so it's actually terrifying at first,
and then it starts to become really liberating.
Was there an example of that in
your life? Because externally,
it feels like you're killing it: a killer PE fund,
teaching at Stanford. The scorecard is looking
good. So it's interesting you say that.
The first time I really realized this, it
was in 2015. I mentioned to you it took
me 14 years to be successful. So we had just
sold the last company from our second fund,
which is where we really got paid. I had a
financial event that was ... it wasn't like
I never have to work again in my life. It was
just like I could exhale a little bit. I knew
I was going to be able to pay my mortgage and
put my kids through college. It was that kind
of an event. And for a couple days I was
euphoric, because I felt like I'd worked
so hard for this. I'd been, again, at this
for 15 years, but really longer than that,
if you go back to getting into college. And
the whole thing had been a long journey.
And then it hit me that nothing changed.
Nothing internally changed at all. I still
had the same problems. I still felt the same
way about myself. I still had a lot of negative
thoughts about myself. This goal that I thought
that I had for this whole long period of time,
it didn't actually change anything. It
changed externally, for sure. Like I said,
I could exhale and pay my mortgage. And those are
all really good things. But that was the first
time when I realized, "Oh, wait a second. It's
really up to me to find things that are going
to give me joy. And the achievement of some kind
of external event is not one of those things."
And I know that sounds really, really weird, but
there's so many people that I've heard that have
had very, very similar stories. And so it was
really disorienting for me. And actually it was
the first time in my life where I experienced
depression, because I just had this thought of,
"I think I was working my whole life for
that, and it wasn't what I thought it was
going to be." And so now I was thinking,
"Well, what is it then? What is the thing
that's going to give me joy?" And that takes
some introspection to ask those questions.
I was just having a conversation with
a friend who's an angel investor,
and he just had a bunch of exits. And he's like,
"Cool, I got some money in my bank account now,
but I don't feel anything. I
thought I'd be like, 'Holy moly,
this is exactly what I was hoping for. And
nothing changed.'" Exactly how you're describing.
I think you get a little bit of peace of
mind when you have some financial security,
which is valuable. But in terms of now my
life changes, now I'm enough, now I am happy,
now I feel good about myself, none of that
changes, for really anybody that I know.
And the hardest part, as you said,
is you think it will. You think, "Oh,
I'll be so happy once I achieve this thing."
And I think an example of this is there's a
lot of miserable billionaires, from what I've
read and see. And that should tell you a lot.
Yeah, exactly.
Maybe a second-to-last question; I'm curious
if there's anything recently you're focused on,
have been thinking a lot about that
maybe you changed your mind about,
or has changed the way you think about the world?
The last two years, I had my two oldest boys
go off to college, 2022 and then 2024. And
that really hit hard. You would think that I
would've been preparing for that for 18 years
for each of them, but for some reason it just
really hit me really, really hard. And I think
it was a real wake up call of mortality, I
guess, and to realize that nothing goes on
forever. And these wonderful people that I had
lived with, each for 18 years, were no longer
going to really be a part of my daily life.
And that really set me off on a journey of a
lot of spiritual work, doing a lot of meditating
and working with some gurus. And it's been really
profound. And it's put me a lot closer in touch
with the things that really matter to me. I've
given myself more permission to spend time doing
those things than the normal external world type
things. So that was a pretty profound change for
me. And the spiritual journey is arguably really
the important journey. And this could be a longer
conversation. And maybe you have the luxury of
doing that journey as you get older or something,
but it's been a really profound, profound journey.
I'm excited to see what insights come out of this
part of your life. Final question before we get to
our very exciting lightning round. We have this
segment on the podcast called Failure Corner,
where people come on this podcast, they share
all these wins: "Oh, I have this amazing PE
fund that's killing it. I teach at Stanford. I've
launched all these things. All these students,
they're so great. Life's amazing. Nothing ever
goes wrong," when in reality, it does. And those
stories often aren't told. So I'm curious
if there's a story you could share of a time
you failed in your career and, if you learned
something from that experience, what you learned.
Yeah, I'll tell a couple stories. So
when I was in high school, I wrestled.
And I cut a lot of weight to make the
varsity team. And I was not in the best
mental place because of cutting weight. But
anyway, I lost a big match my junior year.
And I quit and I never wrestled again.
And that haunted me. So first of all,
that was a failure, a big failure for me. And
it really haunted me. And so I, after that,
made a promise to myself that it wasn't going to
have that happen again. When I went to college,
I tried to row crew. I failed year after year
trying to make the team, trying to make the boat.
Eventually had some real success my senior year,
but prior to that, just failure after failure.
And then at Alpine, I mean, we lost money on
our first fund. We had real trouble during the
recession. I think five of my first eight
investments I ever made in my life, I lost
money. And in venture world, that's one thing, but
in private equity, that's a whole different ratio,
which is not a good ratio at all. When I first
started teaching, I wasn't good at teaching,
had a lot of insecurities. I was really
young when I started, and I didn't feel
like I had really anything to share with the
students. And I think that showed up, and it
took me a long time to kind of figure that out.
So I guess almost my entire track record is one
that starts with things not going well, and then
just over a long period of time of chipping away,
looks like a success on paper. But anytime early
in the process would look like an abject failure.
So I'm quite familiar with failure in the form
of setbacks. I think the ultimate failure though
was the wrestling one, where I just quit. That
was really the only one I would characterize as
a failure. The other ones, because I kept going
and staying with it, turned out to work out well,
with a lot of scars and bruises, but
the failure would've been quitting.
I love that the circles back to your core
advice of stick with it. Most things that
are important take a long time and there's
a lot of suffering [inaudible 01:00:24].
Yeah, they do. Yeah.
Something I wanted to ask, I can't help
but ask at this point, because I think a
lot of people are wondering this, just when
do you quit? When should you quit something?
Because some things are just not worth it.
Is there any advice there you could share?
Yes, for sure. I think the time to quit is
when you can no longer see the vision and
you can no longer really believe the vision.
And then when that happens for a long period
of time ... or maybe you're no longer even
excited about the vision; somewhere in there,
I think. The excited one, you have to be a
little careful of, because in the dark days,
exciting is not the word you're going to use.
But at least in our company, for the first 10
years it was not going well. But each time, we'd
make fewer mistakes, we'd start to see something
working. We'd do one really good deal in this
fund, we'd start to learn from that. We'd get one
really good hire, we'd learn from that. We would
little by little start to see these green shoots.
And I have this unbelievable statement. I didn't
write it. Dan and Chip Heath wrote it in their
book, Switch, which is "Scale your bright spots.
Find what's working and do more of that." And as
you start to progress, for me, for example, at
Alpine, almost all the time, we always had at
least a small glimmer of a bright spot. And then
we'd scale that and then we'd continue forward and
we'd find some more and we'd scale those. And over
time, all those bright spots became our business.
That became what we did. That became our
strategy. That became how we hired people.
That became where we recruited from. All those
bright spots just started to magnify until the
entire business was pretty much a bright spot.
But it took time, because we had to figure out
where those were. And we had to do a lot of things
wrong to figure out where the bright spots were.
Graham, is there anything else that you
wanted to share or you think is important
to leave listeners with before we get
to our very exciting lightning round?
I mean, I think what I would say is
just in general, you got one life,
you get one shot. And so take the time to
really figure out and answer the question,
what does a wonderful, amazing, incredible life
look like? And just get as clear as you possibly
can on that. No matter how crazy or aspirational
it seems, write it down. Write down that thing
is write down that thing that would make this
life amazing. And write it down for your life,
your career, your relationships, your
friends, your body, your spirituality,
your financial situation. And just the first magic
is just knowing what you want. And I'd say 90% of
people never even know what they want. So take
the time to do that. And the more clear you are
on that, the more invested you are in that,
the more likely you are to make it come true.
What I love about that is you
don't have to do this thing,
just step one is understand what
it could be if you could do that.
Exactly.
And it's almost like understand where
your Google directions could take you
if you turned off autopilot. Oh, man. Okay. Well,
with that, Graham, we reached our very
exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
Let's do it.
First question, what are two
or three books that you find
yourself recommending most to other people?
So in the realm of a lot of the
topics we've been talking about,
which is your internal and external game, I love
the book Untethered Soul. And I love the book,
Don't Believe Everything You Think. They
have very similar themes, but they come at
it differently. But I think both of those will
really change your perspective if you read them.
And then a very, very practical book that's
probably the book I've read more than any
other book, is How to Win Friends and
Influence People, by Dale Carnegie,
which was written in like 1930. There's no
other book it. There's a reason that people
are still recommending it 100 years after it's
written. So it's definitely worth checking out.
Yeah, that book, I still think about it
often, even though I read it 30 years ago
at this point. I love that recommendation.
And it's like a very old book to read,
but you have to get past the fact that
it was written a long time ago. Okay,
next question. Do you have a favorite
recent movie or TV show you really enjoyed?
I, for the first time, watched the movie Where the
Crawdads Sing. And I just loved it. It's kind of a
romantic comedy, or not comedy, sorry, romantic
love story meets murder mystery, meets coming
of age. And it really, really touched me. Then I
promptly read the book as well, so I love that.
Do you have a favorite product you've
recently discovered that you really love?
I'm a really big fan of sleep. I think it makes
a massive difference in your life. And that's a
whole other topic we could go down another time.
So I have a few things that have helped me on
that. So if you saw me sleeping, I have earplugs,
I have a noise machine. I have a sleep mask,
and then I have a Chilipad that goes on my
bed to keep the bed cool. And I sleep great.
All those things really help. The earplugs and
mask and noise machine allow you to not hear
the ambient noise. And then there's a lot of
research actually on the temperature at which
you want to sleep. And your body goes up and
down throughout the night. So this Chilipad
that goes under your mattress, there's a whole
bunch of versions of that. And that helps a lot.
I also sleep with an eye mask. My
wife and I rotate the earplugs,
because someone has to pay attention
to the baby, in case he wakes up.
There you go. Yeah.
And this Chilipad, is this the Eight
Sleep, or is this in just a cold bag?
Well, no. So I actually bought the
Eight Sleep, and it was too much.
Yeah, it's a lot.
It would turn on and off. And I would
wake up. And then it would track my sleep,
and then I'd start to freak out because
it'd tell me I wasn't sleeping well. So
I actually returned it and I got a really
simple one called OOLER. And it just turns
on and off. There's no timing. There's no any
weird functionality. And it was a lot cheaper,
and it works better for me. So everyone use their
own thing, but that one worked better for me.
Okay, two more questions. Do you
have a favorite life motto that
you often think about that you
find useful in work or in life?
I love this quote that sums up a lot of what we
talked about in the podcast. It's
by Howard Thurman. And he says,
"Don't ask what the world needs. Ask instead
what makes you come alive, because what the
world needs most is for you to come alive." And
I think that just talks about it's really about
you coming alive that's the most important thing.
And that is going to have so much positive exhaust
in the world. And things from that will
come that you can't even imagine right now.
I was thinking of that quote as you
were describing your philosophy. Final
question. I feel like a lot of people
might be listening to this being like,
"I came here for one of the most legendary
private equity investors of all time,
and you don't talk about private equity at
all." So let me just use this opportunity
to ask you just a question here. What do
you look for in a company that you want
to buy that maybe other people don't?
Is there some insight you could share?
Yeah. Well, I'm happy to talk about private
equity, by the way. It's just that we talked-
We'll do another episode on that. This could
be a whole podcast episode. I understand.
Really happy to talk about that about.
So I'll answer the question more like,
what's a little bit of a different philosophy
that we have? So when we were coming out of
the recession and I hired this coach, we looked
at all of our companies. And we were looking for
where did we make our most money, and what was the
most consistent trend? And we looked at valuation,
growth rates, capital structure, geography,
industry. We cut the data every way you could
imagine. And we had these three companies
that kept showing up on all these lists
that were three of our top performers, but they
didn't seem to really have anything in common.
And then we're like, "Well, they have one thing
in common, which is they started off really badly,
so badly in fact that we put our own person
from Alpine in to go run the company,
and then they ended up becoming our best
companies." So we said, "Wait a second. Maybe
that's the highly correlated thing, is us putting
our own team in place, and even upstream of that,
maybe just having an incredible management
team." So that was foundational. And now,
we put our own leadership team in 100%
of the time. And not only that, but we
have spent an inordinate amount of time
trying to build a program to help people
who are in their late 20s, early 30s learn how
to become CEOs. And that's been foundational.
So the thing that we probably believe to be true
that not that many people agree with us on is that
the management team is really where we think all
the alpha comes from. You can't get the industry
wrong, because if you hire the best management
team in the world to run a typewriter business,
you're going to lose money. So you can't be wrong
on the industry, but you also don't have to be
perfect on the industry. You have to have a good
enough industry and then a world-class management
team. And we found that to be a really good
formula for consistent returns. And it's way more
fun because you're literally in a board meeting
with someone that is on your side of the table,
because you hired them and put them in. And so
you're building the company together. And they're
bringing a lot of similar values. And so
it's been a real differentiator for us.
I have so many questions, but I'm going
to cut it off there. We could do another
episode going deep on all this. Graham,
this was amazing. I think we're going to
be helping a lot of people with what they want
to do with their lives, and if nothing else,
give them a little opportunity to break out of
autopilot, at least for a little bit. Two final
questions. Where can folks find you online if
they want to maybe follow up, ask maybe some other
questions that they are thinking as they hear
this? And then how can listeners be useful to you?
My website's grahamweaver.com, and I have
a blog on there as well as a lot of videos
and different things. And then on Instagram and
TikTok, I'm grahamcweaver. And then on LinkedIn,
I'm Graham Weaver. And on YouTube, I think
I'm Graham C. Weaver. So Graham C. Weaver
will pretty much get you on all those channels.
How can listeners be helpful? I would say I'd
love to hear from you. So my best way
to reach me is grahamweaverblog.com.
And tell me what's on your mind. I may not
respond 100%, but I will read all the emails.
And then if you're interested, subscribe to my
blog. So go to my website, grahamweaver.com,
and I have a blog where I talk about a lot
of the topics that we're talking about today.
Amazing. Graham, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you, Lenny.
Bye, everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review, as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
LennysPodcast.com. See you in the next episode.