We're socialized to bullshit not
only ourselves, but everybody else,
especially in the entrepreneurial community. All
our companies are moving up into the right. Every
product is working. We don't really have any
problems because we're crushing it, and that's
just a lie. The question that I often ask is how
have I been complicit in creating the conditions
I say I don't want. The purpose of this question
is actually to evoke your own agency. A perfect
example of that would be, I say I don't want
to feel busy all the time, but the truth of the
matter is I feel really unnerved and disconcerted
if my agenda isn't jam-packed. So if you want to
create a high-functioning team, do your work, and
it starts with the person who has the most power.
Today, my guest is Jerry Colonna. Jerry is one
of the most well-known and respected executive
coaches in the world. He's co-founder and CEO of
Reboot, an executive and leadership development
firm grounded in the belief that better
humans make better leaders. Prior to coaching,
Jerry co-founded Flatiron Partners with Fred
Wilson, which ended up being one of the most
successful early-stage investment funds in the
world. He's also a partner at JPMorgan Chase and
the author of two books, Reboot and Reunion. As
you might expect, this ended up being a very real
and very open conversation about being busy and
self-inquiry and the dangers of a growth mindset
and the reasons that leaders and teams most
often fail, and it's not what you think. Also,
we talk about a very simple equation that Jerry
and his team use to cultivate great leaders.
This is an episode that everybody should
listen to and spend time with. It'll make
you a better person, a better partner, and
a better leader. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in
your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. Also,
if you become an annual subscriber of my
newsletter, you now get a year free of Linear,
Superhuman, Notion, Perplexity, and Granola. Check
it out at lennysnewsletter.com and click bundle.
With that, I bring you Jerry Colonna.
This episode is brought to you by Eppo.
Eppo is a next-generation A/B testing and feature
management platform built by alums of Airbnb and
Snowflake for modern growth teams. Companies like
Twitch, Miro, ClickUp and DraftKings rely on Eppo
to power their experiments. Experimentation is
increasingly essential for driving growth and for
understanding the performance of new features. And
Eppo helps you increase experimentation velocity
while unlocking rigorous deep analysis in
a way that no other commercial tool does.
When I was at Airbnb, one of the things that
I loved most was our experimentation platform
where I could set up experiments easily,
troubleshoot issues, and analyze performance
all on my own. Eppo does all that and more
with advanced statistical methods that can
help you shave weeks off experiment time
and accessible UI for diving deeper into
performance and out-of-the-box reporting that
helps you avoid annoying prolonged analytics
cycles. Eppo also makes it easy for you to
share experiment insights with your team,
sparking new ideas for the A/B testing flywheel.
Eppo powers experimentation across every use case,
including product, growth, machine learning,
monetization, and email marketing. Check
out Eppo at geteppo.com/lenny and 10X your
experiment velocity. That's geteppo.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Contentsquare,
the analytics platform that helps companies
build better digital experiences. Ever wonder why
customers drop off before converting or why some
pages perform better than others? Contentsquare
takes the guesswork out of digital experiences,
giving you real-time insights into
how users interact with your site
or app. With AI-powered analytics, automatic
frustration detection, and clear visualizations,
you'll know exactly what's working and what's
holding your customers back. Whether you're
optimizing an e-commerce checkout, refining a B2B
lead flow, or improving a mobile app experience,
Contentsquare pinpoints exactly what needs
fixing and why. Contentsquare powers better
customer journeys across 1.3 million websites and
apps. Discover the insights you've been missing
at contentsquare.com/lenny. Jerry, thank you so
much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Well, thanks for having me, Lenny. It's really
a delight to meet you and to be with you today.
I want to start with a very classic Jerry
Colonna piece of advice that I've heard
you share in other places, and I just
want more people to hear this advice,
and this is a question that you ask
people when things aren't going their
way, and I'll give you a hint. The
question contains the word complicit.
Right.
Can you share this question and why it's
so important to ask this of yourself?
The question that I often ask is how have I
been complicit in creating the conditions I
say I don't want? And if it's helpful, let
me break down the question a little bit.
Please.
So I purposely chose the word complicit
because complicit does not mean responsible,
and that's a really important distinction. And
as I often say, to understand the word complicit,
think of the word accomplice. As I will
share, you are driving the getaway car,
you're not sticking up the bank teller.
The second half of that question is I say
I don't want. And sometimes people hear
that question and they interpret it as,
how have I been responsible for the shit in
my life? And that is not the purpose of this
question. The purpose of this question is actually
to evoke your own agency, is to look at the ways
in which you may have been diluting yourself.
A perfect example of that would be,
I say I don't want to feel busy all the time,
but the truth of the matter is I feel really
unnerved and disconcerted if my agenda isn't
jam-packed. And the reason that this is all
really important is part of my approach not only
to coaching, but to the process of growing up,
is to use what I call radical self-inquiry, to
really cut through our own delusions and say,
how does it serve me to feel completely busy to
the point where I feel exhausted? And perhaps
there's another more conscious way of getting
that feeling than feeling like crap all the time.
This is a good segue to something that
I hear you. You have this equation that
you and your firm use to think about how
to create and cultivate great leaders,
and it includes one of the variables
is radical self-inquiry. Can you share
this equation and just how you work
with folks to build this in them?
Sure. I'll tell a little story about that.
I remember one time I was, this is how the
equation came to be. I was doing a talk, I
think here in Boulder at Naropa University
where I used to be on the board of trustees. It's
a Buddhist university, and as is often the case,
I'm winging it as I go and I'm walking around
probably without shoes on because that's what
I do. And there was a dry erase board behind me
and I was trying to explain what it was that I do,
what it was that I encourage people to do. And
I jumped up at the board and I wrote practical
skills. And in writing that, what I was trying
to convey, what it is that people typically
come to a coach for. They want to understand
how to do their job. They want to understand
how to live. They want to understand the how.
And then, I wrote plus, and then I sketched
out radical self-inquiry. And I said in that
moment, I said, "People will come and ask me how,
and I will drive them crazy because I will
say something like, tell me about your father,
or tell me why you chose to be in the job
you're in the first place, or tell me about
your relationship to money, or tell me about your
relationship to self-worth." And then, I expanded
it and I put another plus sign and I said, "Shared
experiences." And then, I drew an equals equation
line underneath the whole thing, and I said,
"Enhanced leadership plus greater resiliency."
And so, the equation is practical skills plus
radical self-inquiry plus shared experiences,
that is the process of actually talking about the
craziness that goes on in your head equals greater
leadership. That all makes sense. But then, there
was this other piece, enhanced resilience. And
when I do this on a dry erase board, I will often
circle that phrase, and I say that is the purpose
of this whole thing, because the truth is, if
you follow my story at all, you know that in my
late 30s, the depression that had really marked
most of my life had gotten so bad that despite
my outward success, I was suicidal and lost.
And I will turn to the audience and I say,
"I get you want to be a great CEO, I
get you want to be a great executive,
but what I really care about is you not killing
yourself in the process." So if we take a step
back, the whole point of what we refer to as the
equation really boils down to that point, how do
we grow up and become the leaders, the adults
we were born to be without feeling like crap?
And there's this huge implication
here that a lot of people think
that when they reach a certain point, become
successful, make a certain amount of money,
get a beautiful house, still be happy.
And essentially what you're saying here
is that's very often not the case.
Maybe in most cases, not the case.
It's not only not the case, it's the big lie
that we're socialized with since childhood.
I remember one time I was on the road doing a
talk for, I was promoting my first book, Reboot,
and I was at, I think it's called the Fitler Club
in Philadelphia. I was doing a fireside chat. And
after talking with my conversation partner, a guy
named Chris Fralic who was one of the co-founders
at First Round, really, really good guy. We
turned to the audience and there was a Q&A as
there often is, and this young guy shoots his
hand up and he introduces himself and he says,
"I'm 19." And he looks over to his right
and his mother's sitting there and he says,
"And my mother brought me here," which I laughed.
And he said, "So what you're telling me is you
don't have to be an asshole to be successful."
And I could not think of a better summation
of everything that I'm about than for
a 19-year-old kid to look up and say,
"You don't have to be an asshole to be
successful." And of course, the corollary
to that is you don't have to feel miserable
just because you're trying to create a career.
As people start to think
about this and think, okay,
I feel like I've been heading in this direction
of I just need to keep climbing the ladder,
making more money, as they hear you talk,
what's the pivot that folks should make
in their mind around where they should
actually be heading? What is a direction
where they'll end up not wanting to kill
themselves, in spite of being successful?
To be clear, not everyone ends up in that
level of depression, but the hack, if you will,
is consciousness. So what do I mean by that?
Part of what makes radical self-inquiry radical
is we're socialized not to ask certain kinds
of questions. So for example, someone says,
"It's really important for me to be ambitious
and achieve a particular goal." What's radical,
a radical question to ask is, and what will
that do for you? What is it that you believe
being "successful" will do for you? How do
you define success? Where does that come from?
In Reboot, my first book, I tell the story of
what I refer to as my pursuit of lemon drops.
And briefly, when I was a boy, there was a lot...
I grew up with an enormous amount of chaos and
insecurity, financial and otherwise. And a big
source of stability in my life were my mother's
parents, my grandfather and grandmother. And
Grandpa Guido, who was an ice man and emigrated
from southern Italy in early 20th century, always
seemed to have, well, he had this endless supply
of lemon drops, and they were always kept in this
green pantry outside of the kitchen. And for me,
the stability and what I considered wealth seemed
to match to this notion of this endless supply of
lemon drops. And when I got to my 30s and I was
outwardly successful and I was a hot shot BC,
I had lemon drops, but I didn't
feel safe, which was a mindful.
And so, I told that story in Reboot as part
of my exploration into the core question of
how did my relationship to money shape my
career choices, shape my school choices,
shape my own sense of safety and self-worth? So
long-winded response to your question, what I
encourage people to do is to ask themselves these
kinds of questions so that they can raise their
level of consciousness so that they can be in the
driver's seat of their lives and not some learned
behavior that they developed as a child to answer
perhaps their parents or grandparents' anxieties.
I feel like a lot of people hearing
this are afraid to ask these sorts
of questions. The reason they don't ask
these questions is because they worry
that this is going to be like, okay, I
got to quit my job, move to the woods,
give up all these luxuries they have.
I don't even want to think about that.
I got a whole family to support. I got to succeed.
Advice for getting over that hump of just like-
So let's just pause, Lenny. Okay,
so what you're doing in this moment
is empathetically imagining what
may be going on for your listener,
but the empathy is actually based on your own
question because you invited me on the show,
you knew I was going to get to this point.
So I'm imagining that as you take this in,
that thought stream shows up for you. "Jerry,"
says Lenny, "If I open up that closet,
all the shit's going to fall out, and what am I
going to do with it?" Does that resonate at all?
This is why I was nervous to have
you on this podcast. I knew what you-
So answer my question.
I don't think it's that strong for me to
be afraid of that because I've taken a
different path already and gotten off the career
ladder climbing treadmill. On the other hand,
back to your original question, we talked
about being busy. I'm very guilty of that. I'm
constantly trying to do less, but constantly
doing more, and my life is just very busy.
Thank you for giving me more of that answer. And
trust me, your listeners are going to appreciate
you being fully there in just the way
you were. So let's take a step back.
The fear is, if I can reflect back to your
original question, the fear is if I go there,
I don't know what's going to happen as a
consequence of that. If I pause and ask myself,
is this relationship working out for me? I
might end up leaving this relationship. If I
pause and ask myself if this career isn't
working for me, I might leave my career.
And the good news bad news is that's true.
That is absolutely true. And if we look at
some of the other observations we were making
before like anxiety and depression, we have
this belief system that if I pay no attention to
the thing that I'm afraid of, it's somehow going
to magically go away. If we pay no attention to
the source of discomfort, it's somehow going to
go away. And that's not actually how life works.
More often than not, what we do is we respond to
the source of challenge, whether it's a discomfort
in our relationship, whether it's a discomfort in
the way my life has unfolded. We respond to it
by plasting over band-aids and sometimes they're
relatively healthy, we become obsessed with
working out, or sometimes they're unhealthy.
We become obsessed with work or substance
abuse or that kind of thing. Or sometimes,
and this is super popular right now, we lean
into what I would call as a spiritual bypassing
where we go to Peru and we go do ayahuasca or we
spend the weekend doing mushrooms with friends...
And what we're really not doing, Lenny,
is confronting the parts of ourselves that
need some tending to because we're afraid of the
consequences. But I'll tell you a quick quote. One
of my favorite books is Bruce Springsteen's
autobiography, and about in the middle of
the book, he has this passage where he talks
about having spent 25 years in psychoanalysis.
So let me just let that statement land. Bruce
fucking Springsteen, 25 years in psychoanalysis.
And he has this passage where he talks about the
unsorted baggage of our childhood. And what he
rightly asserts is that we all have unsorted
baggage, and at some point we're going to pay
the price of not sorting that baggage. And
the price more often than not is in tears.
Now, this is Bruce Springsteen talking about this.
This is not some airy-fairy transpersonal Jerry
Colonna coach. And the reason I draw that out
is we as children are socialized not to develop
these consciousness skills. We are socialized to
develop what I would call bypassing skills. And
as he correctly points out, if you continue to
bypass sorting out your baggage, there's going
to come a day where you're going to have to pay
that price. It could be in your own depression,
it could be in, I've seen this a thousand times
Lenny, entrepreneurs sabotaging their successful
businesses because the belief system from their
childhood goes something like, I don't deserve
success so let me blow it up. We put this all
under the rubric of midlife, but I don't know,
when does midlife begin, 35? When does it end, 70?
What I do know is it's the bulk of our adulthood.
Okay, I think you've done an excellent
job convincing me and others to spend time
on this now, and I think there's
an assumption of it gets harder,
the tears get more intense as you wait
longer. There's this ticking time bomb
that better some amount of tears now than
10 times more tears later. Is that right?
Well said.
Okay. So coming back to this equation, I
think I want to give people some things to
do now that they may be likely convinced, okay, I
should really rethink what I'm doing. So back to
the equation, practical skills plus radical
self-inquiry plus shared experiences equals
enhanced leadership and greater resilience. So the
three things you can work on are practical skills,
radical self-inquiry, shared experiences, skills
I think people get. So radical self-inquiry,
these are essentially questions
to dig into what drives you,
what makes you happy. What are some
questions again that people should
be asking there as they're listening
or maybe after they finish listening?
In the time since I've been a coach, which
is now going on 27 years, the popularity
of journaling has gone up, which is awesome. And
part of what happens is people journal, but they
don't know what they should be journaling or how
they should. So let me give some questions then,
and this is a way to approach it. Let's imagine
that what we're trying to do, whether we're
sitting in meditation, whether we're journaling,
whether we're taking time away, we're just pausing
and starting to ask ourselves questions. So my
famous questions include things like, what am I
not saying that I need to say? So let's imagine
ourselves in a relationship that's not working.
Talk about something that could be terrifying.
What am I not saying in that relationship that I
need to say? By the way, this is a good question
to ask if one is responsible for leading people
too. Corollary questions to that would be, what
am I saying that's not being heard? And then,
of course, what's being said that I'm not
hearing? So if we just pause and look at
those four questions, how have I been complicit
in creating the conditions I say I don't want?
What am I not saying that I need to say? What
am I saying that's not being heard? And what's
being said that I'm not hearing? Can you feel
the power of all of that in those questions?
Yeah. Scary questions.
They are scary questions. You know you're in the
radical self-inquiry zone when the questions take
your breath away, when the questions, and by
the way, you don't have to share the answers
to these questions with anybody but yourself.
Now, there could be some power in sharing them
in a group of friends and sharing them with a
group of colleagues, sharing them with a coach,
sharing them with a therapist. But the most
important person with whom you should share
the answers is oneself. This is a little
bit of Buddhism here. Self-delusion along
with attachment are the biggest contributors to
our own suffering. Self-delusion. Everything's
great. How you doing? Everything's great.
Bullshit. Can we just not bullshit each other?
So let me just pause. Those are just four
questions. My first book Reboot has a set
of questions after every single chapter. We also
have a journal that we put out that has questions
and questions, but the more important thing to
take away from this is questions that startle us,
questions that may cause us to be a little
afraid of the answer, that's where the gold is.
And we'll point people to the book for many
more of these questions and the worksheets.
For the third party equation, shared
experiences, can you explain what that is?
We were talking about socialization, for
example. Prior to launching Reboot, the company,
my co-founder, Ali Schultz and I, the roots
of Reboot the company began with me designing,
or Ali and I designing these boot camps. And the
original iteration of the boot camp, we used to
call CEO Boot Camp because it was originally we
would get first-time CEOs together and we would do
a bait and switch. We would pretend to sell them
practical skills, and then I would start asking
really tough questions like who would you be
without the story of who you are? It's like what?
The notion of shared experience as an important
component grew out of that. Because what would
happen is imagine sitting in a circle of people
who just have your back, who really care about you
as a person. And imagine then discussing some of
the answers to those questions. Who would you be
without the story of who you are? What is it that
you wish that people in your life knew about you,
but you're too afraid to tell them? And imagine
sitting in a group of people who can just
hold that space without fixing you, without
telling you what you're doing right or wrong?
We, too often than not, especially in what I
would say the entrepreneurial community are
socialized to bullshit not only ourselves, but
everybody else. All our companies are moving
up into the right, every product that's working,
we don't really have any problems because we're
crushing it, and that's just a lie. Imagine
having the capacity to be in relationship with
people where you can just tell the truth.
That's what shared experiences are about.
My wife does a women's circle where they gather
and just share what's really going
on within in their lives. And it's-
That's it.
And it's very confidential.
There's a ritual to it,
and it feels like that's a really
good avenue for things like that.
What circle do you sit in?
No circles. This is my circle.
But there is something powerful here. I think
in the last 15 years, the rise of podcasts,
good podcasts. What I think what happens is
let's hope this is happening for your audience
right now, good quality intimate conversation
between people who are authentic and real,
creates space for someone to be authentic and
real, even if it's just with themselves. So
you're doing a mitzvah, you're doing
a good deed by creating this space.
Thanks, Jerry. Let's go back to the busyness
point, and I'll talk about myself a bit to get
it real again, because I think it's also something
a lot of people struggle with. I listen to this,
they're just like, I'm so busy, and every
time someone ask me how I'm doing, busy,
so busy, like swirly eyes
emoji, swirly eyes emoji.
With a little head shake.
That's right. And the melting face
emoji. And that's very much me. And
it's funny because I started this journey of
the newsletter of just like I call the project
avoid getting a real job. And it was just
like, cool, just do this newsletter thing,
not have the job. It'll be chill, write an email
once a week. But I just find myself taking on
endlessly more and more. And for me, I feel
like the drive is it's just fun to see it grow
and for it to keep building and doing well.
This reminds me, there's a quote that Will
Smith shared once that I think you'll like.
Someone asked him what it's like to be famous,
and he's like, "Really awesome as you're
going up to fame. Pretty okay as a famous
person. Really bad when you lose that fame."
And that's how it feels with the growth of this
thing. It's just like growth is up. Oh, life's
good, and then it starts to stall. I'm like,
oh, no, it's all going to fall apart. So I
think that's where a lot of that comes from
for me. It's just like, oh, what's next? I
got to, let's see what else I can do here.
Well, how do you feel about yourself
when you're on that growth trajectory?
I feel great.
Say more.
I feel like I'm achieving and heading
in a... Part of it is just fun. It's
like fun to win. So it's just like,
yeah, we're doing it. It's working.
And when you're not growing,
how do you feel about yourself?
About myself. There's this sense that it's all
over. Oh, maybe it's all going to fall apart,
and maybe I'm not as good at
this as I thought, and maybe-
Okay, so stay in that spot for a moment. So
imagine, and I don't know that this is true,
but I can imagine that there's a little whispery
voice in your head that's always there that says,
"Lenny, you're not as good as you think you
are. In fact, Lenny, they might even find out."
Yep. Yeah, imposter syndrome.
Oh, shit. So by being busy and by being on that
growth trajectory, that voice maybe sounds a
little less persistent, maybe a little less
loud. Now, I want to offer a different potential.
What if you could enjoy the puzzle of trying to
create something new, trying to create magic,
something out of nothing, but it doesn't matter to
your sense of self-esteem if you succeed or fail.
What if what drove you was not quieting
that voice, but what drove you was, oh,
this is just fun? Seth Godin, who's a dear,
dear friend of mine, talks about art projects.
Also a former podcast guest.
So what if you just approached the
project as if it was an art project?
I think it's going to show up this way.
What if it turns out it's wrong? What if
it's this? What if it's that? And your sense
of self-esteem is not attached to the outcome.
What's interesting is that's how I
started this whole thing. I had no
intention of it being a career and way I
make a living. It was just, this is cool,
people seem to like it, I enjoy it. Let's
just see where it goes. No expectations.
And then what happened?
And then it worked.
It became successful.
That's right. It worked out.
Right. It became successful, meaning you developed
an audience, meaning you developed a following.
And then, income. That was a big part of it.
And then you developed an income,
and then the stakes went up,
and then all of a sudden, my heart, the anxiety.
Not quite that strongly. At times it
is, but there's a bit of just, oh,
wow, I am relying on this now.
I can't just let it fall apart.
Because my life would fall
apart if I let it fall apart.
Yeah, life would change in a big
way if this whole thing ends.
Right. Right. So what you're talking about, what
we're talking about right now, remember before I
said in Buddhism, we talk about self-delusion and
attachment. Now, we're talking about attachment.
When we become attached to the outcome, we
inadvertently fuel our own suffering. When
we become attached, and in this case, okay, I get
it. There's a financial reality. This is important
because it helps pay the bills, if it doesn't
entirely pay the bills. Great. Got it. Fabulous.
But really the deeper attachment
is see, I'm not nothing. See,
I'm not a nobody, I'm a somebody, and
that's the source of the suffering.
That is so true. That is very much a part
of what has driven me is I was always a very
shy kid growing up, and I don't think people
expected a lot of me except my mom and dad,
I guess. And so, I always had the sense, I'll
show them, I'll show them what I could do,
and that's always, it's this chip on the shoulder
thing that I know drives a lot of people.
How old are you, Lenny?
43.
Okay. So maybe now at 43, you
can take in the fact that you
are somebody regardless of what
you do. What's your wife's name?
Michelle.
Is she going to love you
even if the podcast fails?
Absolutely.
What, is she an idiot? No, she's a smart person.
The people who actually know you and care about
you may be proud of your efforts, but their
love for you is not dependent upon its success.
And that's like a rewiring. Do you have children?
Yeah, we got a 22-month-old now.
Oh, mazel tov. That's wonderful. My children
are 34, 32, and 28. So I'll speak like the old
man that I am. When we take that test, that
spelling test, and we stick it with magnets
on the refrigerator, it's at a pride. The
challenging message that we inadvertently
can send to our children is that we only love
them because they got an A on the spelling test.
And so, it's really critically important
that we as parents do our own internal work
to convey that unconditional love that is our
birthright as human beings. And we hold onto
the goal because the goal is cool, because
solving a puzzle is fun, because doing hard
work and experiencing the reward from that is
affirming, but your value as a human being is
unshakable. Now, as a father, isn't that
the feeling you want your child to have?
Absolutely. And there's a lot of parenting
advice these days that helps you learn
to do that. There's all these TikToks now,
don't say good job. Just say good choice or
great, hard work. Great job working hard on that.
Right, right, right. I don't know how I feel about
getting parenting advice from TikTok, but okay.
I'm excited to have Andrew Luo joining
us today. Andrew is CEO of OneSchema,
one of our longtime podcast
sponsors. Welcome, Andrew.
Thanks for having me, Lenny. Great to be here.
So what is new with OneSchema, I know that you
work with some of my favorite companies like Ramp
and Vanta and Watershed. I heard you guys launch
a new data intake product that automates the hours
of manual work that teams spent importing and
mapping and integrating CSV and Excel files.
Yes. So we just launched the 2.0 of OneSchema
file feeds. We've rebuilt it from the ground up
with AI. We saw so many customers coming
to us with teams of data engineers that
struggled with the manual work required
to clean messy spreadsheets. FileFeeds 2.0
allows non-technical teams to automate the process
of transforming CSV and Excel files with just a
simple prompt. We support all of the trickiest
file integrations, SFTP, S3, and even email.
I can tell you that if my team had to
build integrations like this, how nice
would it be to take this off our roadmap
and instead use something like OneSchema?
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many
horror stories of outages from even just
a single bad record in transactions,
employee files, purchase orders,
you name it. Debugging these issues is often like
finding a needle in a haystack. OneSchema stops
any bad data from entering your system
and automatically validates your files,
generating error reports with the
exact issues in all bad files.
I know that importing incorrect data can cause
all kinds of pain for your customers and quickly
lose their trust. Andrew, thank you so much
for joining me. If you want to learn more,
head on over to oneschema.co. That's oneschema.co.
Just to close loop on this, I think as people hear
this, I feel like, okay, cool, everything
falls apart. Sure, my parents will love me,
my wife will love me, they won't think less of me.
However, it's nice to get that really nice couch
and that nice hotel and the income, the comfort
that comes with income at a certain level is hard
to give up. How do you help people get past
that that might go away and feel comfortable?
Well, the good news is, and again, this is a
Buddhist reference. The good news is there's
a wisdom tradition that teaches all about this.
So very briefly, the Buddhist story is in his
mid-30s, he wakes up to the truth of birth,
old age, sickness, and death. Birth, old age,
sickness and death. And he wanders into the
forest and he becomes a wandering mendicant
and he becomes a holy man, and he's still not
satisfied. And as I like to tell the story,
one day he decides, fuck it, I'm just going to
sit under the Bodhi tree and I'm not going to
move until I figure this shit out. And so, he
sits and sits and sits, and the story is he sat
for 40 days living on a single grain of rice
every day because always right, crazy stuff.
And when he woke up, he woke up to the four
noble truths and the four noble truths are
life is filled with suffering, that which we
do to push away suffering increases suffering.
The third noble truth is that there's an end
to suffering. That's a really important one.
And the fourth noble truth is what's known as
the eightfold path to the end of suffering.
So let's focus on the second noble truth because
that's really what you're talking about. When we
acquire that nice couch, when we buy that nice
house that stretches our income to its maximum,
if we're doing it to enjoy the couch or
the house, then A-OK. But if we're doing
it because we're trying to push away the
suffering of am I good enough to be loved,
to feel safe, and that I belong, that which
we do to push away suffering will increase
suffering. And in this case, oh my God, what
if they take my house away from me? Oh my God,
what if I fall backwards down that staircase of
life? Oh my God, what if all of those people who
have signed up to my Substack suddenly disappear?
You see how the attachment becomes that source of
suffering? You see how the thing that we
do to make ourselves feel better in fact
fuels the tenuous hold that we have on our
OK-ness? I'm okay just as I am. I'm okay.
It all comes down to why we're doing what
we're doing. Now, to be clear, this is hard
for me. I think it's hard for everybody.
When my first book came out, Dan Harris,
who's a really good friend and client from
10% Happier said to me, "Don't read the Amazon
reviews." The truth is, I've read two reviews. I
read it in the first hour after it was released,
and I've never read a review since because there's
no way I can experience those reviews without
becoming attached to how people feel. So thank
you. I'll put it over here and I'll just stay
focused on the experience that I get from writing.
And yes, do I want to sell thousands of books? Do
I want people to feel moved by my writing? I do,
but you know who gets the most out of my writing?
Me, because when I sit down, this is my file
folder for whatever I might do for our next book,
what I'm trying to do is answer questions that
I have. For example, Captain Chaos is running
the country right now. What is it that the world
is going to need two or three years from now? And
what's my contribution to that world? Now, just
as I say that, how does that feel to you? It's
kind of settling. So I know that in order for me
to feel good about my existence on this planet,
I have to ask myself these questions and I have
to attempt to answer these questions. Whether
it turns into a book that people buy or not is
secondary, I have to do this work regardless.
That super connects with exactly again, the
way I started this whole thing is I started
writing just to crystallize my own thinking,
and it ends up being useful to other people.
Yes.
People hear this and they're like, why would I
want to give up this great couch and house and
car and all these things? That's really hard.
And risking that by just doing something that
feels good versus it'll make income, but
it actually works. That's what I found.
If you focus on a thing that is useful to
yourself and interesting and not come at
it from how do I make the most amount of money
and turn this into whole thing, but more just,
this is really interesting. I'm going to
see where this goes. It will work for me.
Lenny, you implicitly asked a how question
a few minutes ago. How do I do this? How do
I do this radical self-inquiry? And I asked,
I responded by offering a few questions.
Let's build upon that for a moment, because what
you are articulating right now is in the process
of asking those questions, you can go back
to what Simon Sinek would say is your why.
You could go back to your core principle. You
could go back to the centerpiece within you,
which is what do I believe to be true about the
world and how do I want to be in that world?
You know what animates me right now is a question?
With my children being fully fledged adults,
I am really focused on what kind of ancestor to my
descendants would I like to be? 20 years from now,
30 years from now, 40 years from now, I'll
be gone. What would I like those who follow
after me to believe to be true about me?
And you just paused. I can tell from the
Adam's apple jumping up and down, that that
question landed for you. It's a question of
legacy. It's a question of meaning and purpose. At
the end of my days, this is a question in Reboot,
at the end of my days, what would I like the
people who come after me to say about me?
And what I want people to say about me
is that he gave a shit about the world,
he cared, and he tried, and he was kind.
Those are the things that matter to me.
I'm always reminded of that frame of reference
when I go to a funeral and people reading the
eulogy and the old advice of what do you want your
eulogy to say and making that your mission. But
on the flip side, there's this viral video of Mike
Tyson. Someone was coming up to him I think before
his big match recently, and asked him about his
legacy, and he's like, "I don't give a shit about
my legacy. It's just a made up thing that doesn't
matter." So let me just ask you this. Why is it
important to think about legacy? Does legacy
even matter? We're dead. What's the difference?
Far be it for me to criticize Mike, and don't hit
me Mike, because even as an old guy, I wouldn't
want to be hit by Mike Tyson. I don't know what's
behind his response, but I can tell you what's
true for me. I made oblique reference to Captain
Chaos in the world as it is right now. The world's
a tough place right now. We live in a world where
it's almost normalized that a teenager will shoot
other teenagers in school. It's almost normalized
that people are dragged off to jail. Something is
happening, something that's really disturbing.
Now, to be clear, we've always had disturbing
times. I mean, I was reminded recently, I'm
reading a book called Soldiers and Kings,
which I highly recommend, which is about human
smuggling from Central America into the United
States, and it's an extraordinary book. And in
reading that, I was reminded of policies that
the US government has used over the years, whether
it's supporting dictators in Central America or
other sorts of things, things that I oppose,
that feel immoral, if not directly immoral.
Why does this come up for me? I can't shake the
feeling that someone down the line in my lineage
is going to ask of me, "And what did you do,
grandpa? And what did you do, great grandpa?"
I know what I want that answer
to be, which is I tried. Lenny,
God gave me the ability to put two sentences
together in a way that people listen.
I feel a moral responsibility to use that
God-given gift to help create the world,
that I would like to see, a world of kindness
and empathy, a world where poverty is diminished,
a world where people feel safe however the fuck
they identify. I don't give a damn. So is that my
legacy? Yeah, and maybe there's some ego implicit
in that, but can I go on for just a bit on this?
Absolutely.
At the end of Reboot, I write about this moment,
and in this moment I am in Marin County. My wife
Allie and I are together. And I'm once again
torturing myself with this question. Have I been a
good man? I drive myself crazy with that question.
Have I been a good father? Have I been a good
partner? Have I been a good man? And she says,
in a very frustrated way, "All right, already.
Enough. You're a good man. Stop." And so, I go
for a walk, and as I'm walking, I encounter this
toppled over oak tree and the roots are all torn
up and you've seen trees like this, and clearly
the tree died and clearly a wind came and clearly
knocked the whole thing down. And I look at the
tree and I say to myself, "Here lies a good man."
And I liken myself to this toppled over oak tree,
and I imagine that that tree had lived its life
with its limbs gnarled and twisted by actions that
it should have taken and actions that it shouldn't
have taken, but good choices and bad choices. But
that for the majority of its 75, 80 years, it
lived into its purpose of providing shelter and
shade for those that may have come from beneath
it. And I make this point that at the end of my
days, I want to be like this tree just slowly
dissolving into the earth, having done the best
job I could of being purposeful. I feel better.
My suffering is eased when I can lean into that,
which then makes me able to be present for the
other person, whether it's a coaching client,
whether it's a podcast conversation, whether it's
just going for a walk with one of my children. I
just feel better, and I think I am a better
person when I think about things like that.
So far be it from me to disagree with
Mike Tyson, but I think he's wrong.
Good callback. It sounds
like The Giving Tree to me.
Oh, yes, yes. Shel Silverstein.
To give people something to do with this area
of legacy. How did you approach coming up with
figuring out what you wanted your legacy
to be? Are there some questions you asked?
Is there something you recommend folks do
to help think through this for themselves?
Well, it's delightful that we've ended up here
because I think that I'm still working through
those questions. As I said before as we both
connected with, I use my writing to find my
way to answers to questions. So part of what
I'm dealing with right now is, look, I'll turn
62 this year. That feels old, but it also feels
settled. And part of what I'm trying to figure
out is what do I want my elderhood to be like? And
I'll be honest, I'm enjoying this time of my life
where I'm finding myself being a voice of comfort,
being a voice of maybe even sanity in a time where
that feels really insane and challenging. So maybe
that's what my legacy will be. I'm not 100% sure.
Is this maybe hinted the new book you're working
on? Is this the topic you're
thinking about or is this not?
Yeah, and other things.
That's right. That's right.
Speaking of the world being very crazy
right now, you talked about your kids,
AI is very top of mind for a lot of people in
particular. It's stressing a lot of people out.
In a lot of ways, it's quite unsettling
in future careers, in skills, people-
It is unsettling, isn't it?
Quite unsettling, but there's a world
where we don't need humans in the future,
potentially. Just what advice do you
share with clients to help them work
through this period of worry with the
future, with AI being the core of it?
Well, if we go back to the equation for a moment,
I think it's really important that we actually
talk about these things. I would say a year ago, I
likened it to the experience that I had. Remember,
I'm old enough to remember when not everything
had an IP address. Now, our refrigerators have
IP addresses. I mean, it's freaking crazy.
I'm old enough to remember when you had to
install an IP stack into your personal computer in
order to connect to the web. That's how old I am.
Did you have the phone modem
where you had to put the phone?
Absolutely. Absolutely. It was a big, big deal
to go from 1,200 baud to 2,400 baud to 56K. Oh
my God, it was like a rocket ship. A year ago, I
thought we were going through a similar kind of
transition. We're clearly not. This is different.
And in the coaching therapeutic world, everybody's
like, "Oh my God, ChatGPT is going to replace me."
And I don't know, maybe. What I am finding is...
I wear glasses. So for those of you who are only
listening to the audio, you may find that news.
What I am finding is in my own life, it's like
I have put on a pair of glasses that are really,
really sharp and helpful, and it is disturbing and
unsettling because I think it does challenge this
question of what is our role as human beings?
Now, what I come back to, and I could be wrong,
but what I come back to is we're talking through
a medium, a mediated experience. My signal is
bouncing up into the sky and to a satellite.
I won't name the company, it's coming back
down. I don't know what your access is. We're
using this platform or a site to record this,
but somehow we're still finding the capacity to be
present for one another in a heart-to-heart way.
And so, when I look at these phenomena, what I
lift up is that. What I am hopeful about is that
that which does not matter in the experience of
being human gets burned away and is taken care of,
call it by AI, but that that which matters,
which is presence and connection, human-to-human
contact, strategic thinking, formulation, you
want to talk about it in terms of engineering, the
conceptualization, that that gets elevated and our
skills get better at doing that. And in the most
optimistic point of view, what ends up happening
is we spend more time on that which matters,
and less time on that which doesn't matter. And
I could be completely wrong and we could all be
out of work and making sure that the robots
are well-oiled, and that becomes our purpose.
Along these lines of glasses and even coaching,
the world of coaching, there's a really
interesting use case I saw today that Dan Shipper
shared that I think you'd love, which is now that
ChatGPT has memory, remembers everything you've
said, and you can think back, you can ask it,
"What are blank spots in the way I see the world
that I'm not seeing?" You could also upload all
your chat transcripts from your meetings and
ask it what could you do better in meetings?
Look, one of my colleagues in the coaching
company, he has uploaded, he kept all of his
journal entries, I think over 10 years journal
entries from Evernote, and he uploaded that.
I think he uses Claude, and he's asked Claude
to highlight things. What am I not saying that
I need to say? What am I saying that's not being
heard? He's asked it to reflect back, and I think
it's been incredibly helpful for him. I think
the result is that he is a better coach, which
is interesting, because the feeling is, well,
does this replace it? I am finding, I'm using
ChatGPT really as a writing and thinking partner
in a way that I did not have before, and I'm still
using my live real human writing buddies, which
are really important to me. Where does this all
end up? I had no idea. It is unsettling, it's
uncanny, and it's also enlivening and exciting.
Well put. I love that you can ask
these hard questions of Claude/ChatGPT,
these questions that make you really scared could
ask it what are the answers, and even not have to
do the hard work and maybe get a better answer.
I doubt that that will give you the best answers.
Well, what it might do, which
I think would be wonderful,
is it might give you more questions to ask
yourself. I'm a huge fan of powerful questions
and the answer I give to a question like what am
I not saying that I need to say? That question,
you can ask yourself that question every single
day. The question of how have I been complicit in
creating the conditions I say I don't want? You
can ask yourself that question every single day.
To take a step back, the subtitle of my first
book is Leadership in the Art of Growing Up.
The Art of Growing Up is a practice. It's not
a scientific moment where one day you wake up
and you're done. It's an ongoing practice of not
continuous improvement, but continuous inquiry
that can feel exhausting when you contemplate
it, but enlivening when you live it.
All this, some people may think of as this
whole idea of growth mindset. I know that
you're not a big fan of this term, that it's
used in a harmful way a lot of times. Can you
just talk about that why you find that growth
mindset as a concept isn't necessarily useful?
Here's what I have a problem with. First
of all, having a growth mindset is a very,
very helpful thing. What I have a problem is
in having and how we can turn a notion like
a growth mindset into a fixed mindset, which
is, it's this funny little trick the ego does,
and the ego says, "Okay, well, this is a growth
mindset. Oh, this is not a growth mindset. Okay,
then this is good. This is not good. This is
bad. This is..." What Buddhism has taught me is
that everything's falling apart all the time even
our growth mindset. When we get too fixed on the
proper way to do things, we're setting ourselves
up for attachment and therefore suffering. So if
you can hold something like a mindset loosely with
that attachment, go for it. Have a blast. Enjoy
it. But the minute you start to nail it down to
the floor and say this is the way it ought to be,
I ought to always have a growth mindset, you've
become fixed. And that's what the ego does.
To be more explicit about it from a business
context for example, the great business writer
Peter Senge says, "It is virtually impossible to
challenge the assumptions that made you rich in
the first place." So think about it in our
experience of starting a business. We have
what the Zen Buddhist would say, beginner's
mind, all things are possible. And then,
we experience, you were talking about it a little
before, a little bit of success, and the ego,
which is so terrified of not having success, start
to say, "Aha, this is the way to do it." And then,
we start to deviate from that because life happens
and then the anxiety starts. So the question is,
how do you hold a growth mindset loosely knowing
that you ought to stay present to the world as
it is, respond to the changing dynamics,
figure out what's next because that's the
growth. So put succinctly, stay attached to
the growth and hold mindset a little loosely.
I love that. It reminds me of advice.
I did a meditation retreat once,
and there's always a sense with Buddhism,
and it's interesting how often Buddhism
and advice from Buddhist teachings
comes up on this podcast by the way.
When the student is ready, the teacher will
appear. You are inviting it in, but keep going.
That makes sense as you say that.
Interesting. So there's this
fear I think people have with
Buddhist teachings that you
will not be as ambitious and you will not
achieve as much if you're not attaching.
If you're not anxiously chasing something.
Yeah, exactly. If you're just like, "Why do
I need that? I don't need to be the CEO of
the VP because like, oh, I won't attach
to that." And then, so people fear that
downside. So I asked this question at this
retreat and the advice they shared there
was don't attach to this idea, but just point
your cart in that direction and head there.
Yeah, I like that. Look, the fear you're talking
about is the fear of complacency. And if we look
at the structures of the mind and we look at
our socialization, the way we're socialized to
ward off complacency is anxiety. And so, if we go
back to some of the things we were saying before,
if I grow up believing that the way I'm going
to make my parents love me is by achieving,
then if I become complacent, then
what's at risk is their love for me.
So just like we made the connection before
where unconditional love exists, unconditional
positive regard for self, otherwise known as
self-compassion can be a powerful motivator,
especially when you get to the point where
you say, "As painful as it is for me to write,
I enjoy writing. I enjoy working out. I enjoy
pushing myself. I don't necessarily enjoy it
in the moment." But I certainly, when I look at
two books on my desk and I say, "You know what?
That feels good. That makes me happy."
To me, the ability to hold the seeming
contradiction of those things is a hallmark of my
adulthood. It's to get satisfaction out of hard
work for me is a much greater motivator than fear
of complacency. As I've sort of slip-slided my way
into that place, I have found... I work seven
days a week. I don't have to, but I enjoy it.
There's another, maybe a last area I want to
spend some time on, which is around teams and
what often causes trouble for teams. What breaks
teams? What breaks companies? You have this
point, you make that it's rarely lack
of talent on the team, lack of strategy,
lack of execution, that it's something
else. What is that something else? What
often do you find as the source of the
problem for teams that aren't working?
Well, it's the unresolved, I'll be dramatic with
the language, demons from their childhood. It's
the unsorted baggage. Here's what happens. Teams
are groups, and there are group dynamics that
always happen. There is the scapegoat, there is
the truth-teller who has to say, "Let me tell you
what's really wrong with everything going on."
Without the individual's radical self-inquiry
skills, groups tend to be condemned to repeating
patterns oftentimes of their family of origin.
I'll tell you a quick story. There's a very famous
software blogger, blogger-owned software that
I coached for many years, and we were doing an
executive team meeting, and something happened in
the group as we were talking that I observed
once, twice, and three times, and finally,
I said, "Okay, guys, I'm seeing something happen
here. Every time we get close to talking about
something that's really painful, somebody makes a
joke and all the energy disappears and everybody
laughs and everybody's nice." And as soon as I
said it, my client who was CEO at the time said,
"Jesus Christ, that's just like my family." It
was like, yes, that's just like your family.
Carl Jung once said, "Until you make the
unconscious conscious, it will direct your
life and you will call it fate." Let's apply it
here. Until you make conscious the unconscious
patterns operating in the group, the group
will continue to repeat those patterns and
you will blame somebody in the group. Romantic
relationships from a Buddhist perspective,
part of what we do in romantic relationships is
we find the perfect foil for us to work out our
unconscious phenomena. When we join a group,
when we form up in teams and organizations,
we are unconsciously finding the perfect
foils for us to work out our own shit.
So if you want to create a high-functioning team,
do your work, and it starts with the person who
has the most power in the group. If that person
refuses to do their work, the entire group will
become a manifestation of early dysfunction in
the individual's lives. Does that make any sense?
100%. And this comes up a number of times
on this podcast, just the impact the leaders
issues have on the rest of the team, and
also just this idea that the conditions
they're trying to avoid are the conditions
they invite in because they're avoiding.
That's it. That's it. One of my favorite
teachers and dear friends is Parker Palmer,
and he builds on, I think
it was Socrates who said,
"The unexamined life is not worth living."
And he builds on that and makes a joke,
and he says, "But if you choose to live an
unexamined life, please don't take a job
that involves other people." And that's it. You
have a responsibility to examine your own shit.
So say you're on this team, so there's two
sides of this. You're on a team, the leaders
clearly got some stuff that they need to work
through, but they're not. Is there something
you can do there other than just, "Hey, please,
this is hurting us?" And then from the leader's
perspective listening to this, what should
they do? Is it get a coach? What can you do?
So for the one who has less power?
Yeah.
One of the things to ask oneself is what draws
me to this position in the first place? How
have I been complicit, not responsible in
creating the conditions I say I don't want.
How have I benefited from the dysfunction that
exists in this organization? And benefit is a
funny word. It doesn't necessarily mean I'm
making more money. It means, for example,
a benefit might be, boy, this feels familiar.
I always find myself working on teams that are
dysfunctional in this way. What is there in that
experience for me to learn? So that's one thing.
You asked about the person who has power. You were
using the word leader. I will talk about power,
and you threw out, well, should they get a
coach? Let's put it into larger context. Should
you examine your life with radical self-inquiry?
Yes. I would argue that the more power you have,
the more moral responsibility you have to
actually pause and figure out what it is that
you're doing to be complicit in creating
the conditions you say you don't want.
To be a very quick example what I'm talking about.
A couple of years ago, I was doing a talk at a
venture firm's CEO portfolio summit, the portfolio
company's CEO summit. And we're sitting in a room,
and of course I'm walking around again with
shoes off and whatever, and people are firing
questions at me. And one woman says, "Well, I'm
the CEO of this 15-person company, and I have
a question for you. Why is it that nobody on my
team can make a decision without me?" And I said,
"Who hired them?" And she, "Well..." I said,
"Okay, how does it make you feel when they
make a decision that you disagree with?" She
said, "I'm furious." "Well, how can you hire
people whom you expect to make decisions without
running them through you if you can't tolerate
them making a decision that you disagree with?"
You want to build a scaled leadership team,
you have to be willing to have them make
boneheaded decisions. And that's really,
really hard, especially if we're "in founder mode"
driving all the decisions. So that's your growth
edge. We were talking about before about growth
mindset. That's your growth edge. How can I be
with the people in my life making boneheaded
decisions about something that I care so much
about and what is the best way for
me to be in relationship about that?
So much of this comes back to that question
we started this with of just how are you
complicit in creating the conditions you
don't want? A big takeaway for me here,
and it just keeps coming up and again and
again, is if you're struggling as a leader,
if your company's not working as well as you
wanted to, if you're having a hard time with
your team, going back to that equation, it's not
about building more skills like public speaking
skills or email skills, or I don't know, financial
skills. It's self-awareness, radical self-inquiry,
understanding what drives you, what makes
you happy. Is that generally correct?
Lenny, I was just going to say, you just
made me so happy you saying what you just
said. Yes. I've been coaching now, as I
said for a couple of decades. Before that,
I was a VC for 15, 17 years. What
you just said is the wisdom of my
40 years as an adult. That's it. This is why
radical self-inquiry is so damned important
because it leads to a little bit less
suffering and a lot more resilience.
For folks that want to actually do that,
well, they can rewind back to the middle
of the episode where we actually ask the questions
that are associated with the radical self-inquiry,
and then obviously if they want to
dig deeper, they can buy your book.
Or 10 copies of the book.
Or 100 copies for everyone at the
company willing to Amazon. Jerry,
is there anything else that
we haven't touched on that you
think is really important for people to
hear maybe as the last piece of wisdom?
Now one of the hopes that I have you ask me
at the start like what would be my hope is
that we ended up being closer and friends, and I
feel that. Let me extend that out to everybody.
What I always hope from all of these intimate
conversations that I try to do in podcasts is
that people walk away going, "Geez, I'm not
alone." We've made different references to
the fact that it's a hard time. The truth is it's
always a hard time. And what makes it hardest is
to feel like I'm the only one who's going through
this. So what I appreciate about what you do,
Lenny, is that under the guise of talking about
product, you're really talking about the process
of being human. And that is a mitzvah. That's
a good deed. And so, I hope in the process of
listening to this, people walk away going,
"Okay, I feel a little bit better today."
I really appreciate that. The way I think about
these sorts of conversations and episodes,
I call them Trojan Horse episodes where
people come for the other stuff, tactical,
practical stuff, and then they get
stuff they really need to hear. And so,
I appreciate you. Jerry, thank
you so much for being here.
Thank you for having me. It was a delight.
Same for me. Bye, everyone. Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable,
you can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can
find all past episodes or learn more about
the show at lennyspodcast.com.
See you in the next episode.