I often use this analogy of if you're doing
a home renovation, you can have the most
beautiful rendering of the new bedroom and we're
going to have these lamps on the side of the bed
that are coming out from the wall. But if you
haven't checked if there's electricity in that
wall there or not, it's going to drastically
change the cost and the time and everything.
What we need to do in a shaping session is we come
out with some kind of diagram where engineers,
product and design, they're saying, "We
understand that." So the first thing is
we are not going to start something unless
we can see the end from the beginning. We're
not going to take a big concept and then
say, "What's the estimate for this thing?"
We're going to go the other way around and we're
going to say, what is the maximum amount of time
we're willing to go before we actually finish
something? How do we come up with a idea that's
going to work in the amount of time that
the business is interested in spending?
Today my guest is Ryan Singer. Ryan was
one of the first few hires at 37signals,
and through his experience of building Basecamp
and 17 years of building product at 37signals,
he wrote a book called Shape Up, which shares
a very different approach to building software.
Appetites instead of deadlines. A big
focus on bringing design engine product
together into a room to shape the plan
versus writing long PRDs or trying to
finalize designs before you start building.
I've noticed more and more teams adopting the
Shape Up method, and especially with AI starting
to change how we work and build product, there's
this shift coming in how product teams will
operate. And so I thought this was the perfect
time to do a deep dive into the Shape Up method.
This episode is basically going to give you
everything you need to give Shape Up
a shot on your team or at your company
to see if it fixes the problems that
you're having shipping great products.
A big thank you to Des Trainer, Bob Moesta
and Chris Speck for suggesting questions and
topics for this conversation. If you enjoy this
podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow it
in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube.
Also, if you become a paid subscriber of
my newsletter, you get an entire year free of
Perplexity Pro, Notion, Superhuman, Linear and
Granola. Check it out at lenny'snewsletter.com.
With that, I bring you Ryan Singer.
This episode is brought to you by
WorkOS. If you're building a SaaS app,
at some point your customers will start asking
for enterprise features like SAML authentication
and SCIM provisioning. That's where WorkOS
comes in, making it fast and painless to
add enterprise features to your app.
Their APIs are easy to understand so
that you can ship quickly and get back to
building other features. Today, hundreds
of companies are already powered by WorkOS,
including ones you probably know like Versel,
Webflow and Loom. WorkOS also recently acquired
Warrant. The fine-grain authorization service.
Warrant's product is based on a groundbreaking
authorization system called Zanzibar,
which was originally designed for Google to
power Google Docs and YouTube. This enables
fast authorization checks at enormous scale
while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases.
If you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features
like single sign-on SCIM or user management,
you should consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in
replacement for Auth0 and supports up to 1 million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
workos.com to learn more. That's workos. com.
This episode is brought to you by Merge.
Product leaders, yes, like you, cringe
when they hear the word integration. They're not
fun for you to scope, build, launch or maintain,
and integrations probably aren't what led
you to product work in the first place?
Lucky for you the folks at Merge are obsessed
with integrations. Their single API helps SaaS
companies launch over 200 product integrations
in weeks, not quarters. Think of Merge like
Plaid, but for everything B2B SaaS.
Organizations like RAMP, Dorada and
Electric use Merge to access their customer's
accounting data to reconcile bill payments,
file storage data to create searchable
databases and their product or HRAS
data to auto-provision and deprovision
access for the customer's employees.
And yes, if you need AI-ready data for your
SaaS product, then Merge is the fastest way
to get it. So, want to solve your organization's
integration dilemma once and for all? Book and
attend a meeting at merge.dev/lenny and receive
a $50 Amazon gift card. That's merge.dev/lenny.
Ryan, thank you so much for being
here. Welcome to the podcast.
I am really happy to be here. Thanks a lot.
I think this is going to be a legendary episode.
There's a lot of interest these days in different
ways of working, especially ways that are Agile
and SAFe and Scrum and all these ways that people
hear about working. Especially in this world of
AI where everything's just changing. It feels like
there's just an increased interest in exploring
different ways of working and specifically it
feels like there's been a rise in interest
in Shape Up the stuff that you talk about.
So, I am really excited to basically help
people understand what is this way of working,
is it right for them? What are ways to
start implementing it? What are maybe
some pitfalls you may run into? And as much
as possible get into a lot of real talk about
how things are actually going on product
teams that people often don't like to hear.
So, first of all, have you also seen
this increased interest in Shape Up?
Yeah, I think it's interesting that we're talking
now. I mean, the book came out in 2019 and it's,
I've been hearing more and more like, "Oh, we
know somebody who's trying it or we're hearing
it when we go talk to other companies." So,
I think, it's a wave that's slowly building.
And it's funny, when it came out, I even tried
to have an online forum to get everyone who's
interested to talk together and what I started
to learn pretty early on is that people don't
like to talk about their struggles shipping.
Especially CPOs and CTOs don't like to go on
a public forum and say, "Our company isn't
shipping or our engineering team is stuck,
or our team is always lost in the weeds." That's
not an easy community topic on an online forum.
So, I think, there's also some reasons why
it's been word of mouth slowly gathering steam.
That's something I struggle with on this podcast.
As you said, it's a product and product teams
don't want to be sharing when things aren't
going great. That's why I introduced Failure
Corner on the podcast where it's like, "Okay,
but tell me a time things didn't go well."
Oh yeah, that's great. Yeah, because it's so
hard to get to that, right? And it's not all
just this golden path, rosy, where we're all
shipping beautiful, meaningful things all day.
It's a hard business and there's no perfect school
either that produces expert product managers and
CPOs and CTOs and stuff like that. So we're all
trying to figure this out and we don't have a
lot of sources, so there is a lot of struggle.
And there aren't many options for how to
build product. All people really read about
is Scrum/Agile/SAFe as they scale and then there's
Waterfall, which, "No, I never do Waterfall." Then
there's the start up way of just ship and maybe
one or two week cycles and then there's Shape Up,
so it feels like it's one of the rare
other options that exists. And so-
That's one of the things I've been hearing.
It's, I hear like, "Oh, we thought there
was only Scrum or Kanban, and then we heard
there was this Shape Up thing. What's that?
And I think it's always been connected to
Basecamp. We're going to talk about that. Just,
it works for companies that are nothing like
Basecamp. Maybe just touch on that briefly.
Well, I mean, that came as a surprise to me.
I mean, when I wrote the book, I had been in
Basecamp at that time, I think 15 years, and I
actually didn't even know the outside world. I
mean, it was Jason's idea to even write the book.
Because he said, "Look, a lot of people are going
to want to know about this. A lot of people
are struggling." And I'm like, "Well, okay."
I knew our inside story of we had some growing
pains and we had to be able to formalize the
way that we were working and shipping so that
as we brought new people in that they could
participate in that and we could stay fast. So,
I knew our internal struggles, but I honestly
didn't know anything about the outside world.
And it was only after the book came out that
it gave me this excuse to start talking to
people from all kinds of different companies,
and it's been really interesting. There are
some really amazing cases of companies of very
different characteristics from Basecamp,
like VC funded, significantly bigger,
very different pressures, different team
structure, different skills who are doing it.
At the same time, there is also a lot
of questions that are coming in my way
because honestly, there are so few teams
that are structured just like Basecamp,
that there are a lot of gaps in the book of like,
"Well, what about this, and what about that,
and how do we do that in our situation?"
So, a lot of my focus today is actually
closing those gaps and helping people figure out
how can I make this work for me or for our team?
And you specifically told me, you just now call it
instead of Shape Up it's Shape Up In
Real Life or Shape Up For Real Life.
Yeah. Well, my wife heard me saying the same
thing over and over again on every phone
call. And she's overhearing me and she's like,
"You have to make a course, you have to do
something. You always are saying the same thing."
So then this led to this course that we made,
which is called Shaping and Real Life. And well,
yeah, the idea is the real life part, right? How
do I make this work if my designers don't code?
It's very contentious to get engineering time.
You know what I mean? When there's all these
different pressures that Basecamp didn't have.
We're going to get into the nitty gritty of
how this actually works and the key elements,
but can you just give a very short overarching
summary of how Shape Up is different
from how other product approaches are?
I think the way it's different starts with
how the way we were working was a little bit
different. So, I started working with Jason
and David on the first version of Basecamp,
which was the flagship product of 37signals
back in 2003. We were a team of three.
And, I mean, I think, it's for any really
small team, when you're just starting out,
you don't need a process. You don't need a way
of working. It just happens organically because
you're together. You don't have to explain it to
other people, it just happens on its own, right?
But there was always this really intense
urgency from both Jason and David,
"We've got to get to something we can
ship. We have to finish this and move
on. We have to get to something that's
done." There was just no tolerance for
big things that got fuzzy and started to
drag. There was always this sharpening
to get to what is this thing really and
when are we going to get to the end soon?
And on top of that, even when we were building
V1, David wasn't actually full-time as our only
technical person. He was programming 10 hours
a week. So, we had this really intense pressure
of how can we really use David's time well?
We don't want to ever give something that
this is the thing we want to build, and then it
turns out not to be what we want and we have to
throw it away and then come back again or you
know what I mean? Those bad cycles of waste.
Let me actually ask about this because
this is really interesting. So this is
DHH. He was working part-time
when he started 37signal.
10 hours a week. Yeah.
Was he working on Ruby
basically and that whole thing?
Well, Rails came out of the first... So,
he told Jason, "I want to try building
this in Ruby," because before they had done some
collaboration and David had done things in PHP
before that and he had this new idea, he wanted
to try Ruby, this language he fell in love with.
And then the framework, Ruby on Rails, he ended
up releasing that after Basecamp was standing.
Because it was extracted from the things that
were necessary to give V1 of Basecamp to stand up.
So that's what he was doing the
rest of his time instead of-
I don't know. I don't know what
he was doing the rest of his time.
Probably something great. Something-
But he's always been like that. He's always doing
something interesting. He's either racing or who
knows what, you know what I mean? But all I
knew was that we got 10 hours of that time.
Yeah, I love that that was a constraint to
design a way of working that uses
engineering time most efficiently.
Yeah, I mean, put that together. So, David's
constraint of 10 hours a week and then Jason
has this, I mean, I think, many really successful
founders and especially CEOs have this thing,
it's like all they want to see is movement. You
know what I mean? Forward, forward, forward.
So when do we get to see it? When do we get to
try it? When do I get to put it into somebody's
hands? So that combination, there was just so
much urgency even though there was no outside
pressure. You know what I mean? It was completely
just let's say cultural energy of how do we keep
getting somewhere and getting to something
that we can celebrate and get excited about.
I love that. That's an attribute, I think,
of a lot of successful founders.
So that makes sense to hear that.
Totally, totally. And that's why where I come
back to you, this is the part of the story where,
I think, so many companies would say, "Yeah, I
know that experience," right? Because, I think,
that's probably the seedling of, as
you said, of successful companies.
Is that combination of urgency and also that those
guys were so talented and that they had a clear
vision of what they wanted to do and all of that.
It's this amazing time actually, these early days.
Is there anything more to the backstory that's
important to share or super interesting?
Yeah, I mean, the other big piece of it
was, so Jason and I were this product,
what do you call it? The two thirds.
So, I was doing UX at the time
and I was doing hands-on coding as well. So
we're very, very integrated. Everybody does a
little bit of everything. All of us were coding.
Jason was in the actual app templates as well
doing HTML and CSS to do the views. He's doing
hands-on design. We're all very much connected
with why are we building this? What is this?
David's doing the bulk of the programming,
and Jason and I were having these little sessions.
These little sessions where we would really figure
out what the idea was and there would be this
moment where you would have a few strokes of
this Sharpie pen on a big pad of paper and all of
a sudden you'd be like, "Oh yeah, that's the idea.
That's the thing we want to go try to build."
And for me, those sessions with Jason,
they were these short, very, very intense
sessions where you're trying to crack the nut
together. Where's the idea? What's the concept?
How can we go... What's this thing that we're
going to go and 10 hours later, right, David's
going to come back and we're going to be like,
"This is awesome. This thing works and it
does something we're excited about," right?
That was really the seedling. I mean, actually
that continued over years and years and years,
those sessions. And that's the seedling of
this word in the book shaping. What does
it mean to do shaping? It wasn't
sitting alone writing a document,
it wasn't making a bunch of requirements.
It wasn't making a beautiful Figma file
to represent a concept that could maybe
be a feature. It was this super intense,
really exciting collaborative, "What about
this? What about that? Oh, maybe this." So
that was a really big part of how we worked also.
Very intensely collaborative sessions to figure
out what the idea is and getting it sharp enough
and crispy enough that we could very confidently
get a yes from David. That he would know exactly
what it is and what it means and come back.
It would be what we pictured and it
would work the way that we hoped so
that we would keep going and we wouldn't have
to reverse or go back to the drawing board.
What it sounds like is essentially you're
trying to maintain the startup way of
working as the company grows. Everything you're
describing is how it feels to be at a startup,
and this is a method to keep
that. Does that sound right?
That's exactly what became Shape Up, was how do
we hold onto that as much as possible? I mean,
one big ingredient, we had an advantage
also, which was that Jason and David
hired so deliberately slowly, and this
is a fortunate side effect of the fact
that they didn't take investment money.
So there was never that moment of now's the
moment when we grow. It was always one person.
And then the organism adapts. One more person.
And so, this natural way of working, it was
organically spreading. There were, I think,
maybe 10 years before we had the first, "Wait a
minute, what just happened?" That project didn't
go well, that's not how things normally run.
Of course there were always ups and downs,
but it was about 10 years later when we had the
first project. I mean, I remember the project. I
remember being at the end of... It was at that
time already, it had been maybe six weeks or
seven weeks. We hadn't yet completely locked
the six-week thing that went into Shape Up.
And I remember we had a review session and
there was a fairly new person who's doing
half of the work on that team, and we had the
review session and it was like instead of,
"Oh, look, this is about ready to ship." It was
like, "There are a lot of open questions here."
"And not only are there a lot of open questions
here, we're not getting quick answers as we're
asking." And what we're starting to realize is
like, "Oh, not only is this not going to ship,
but we can't even see the end of this."
That was one of those moments where you're like,
"Oh, this isn't going to automatically,
organically just keep it spreading as we
hire forever." You know what I mean?
We did reach a point where it's like,
"Oh, we're going to have to figure out when this
goes well, why does it go well and what do we do
differently and how do we formalize that so it's
reproducible as we keep onboarding more people?"
That's actually when Shape Up as a framework
started. That's when I really started to lean in
and I took over that responsibility
of, "Okay, how do I systematize this?"
That's a great segue to let's actually
talk about how the Shape Up method works.
Maybe just at a high level, what are the
core ingredients to the Shape Up method?
There's basically three maybe big things. So, the
first thing is this notion of we are not going to
start something unless we can see the end from
the beginning. So, we're not going to take a
big concept and then say, "What's the estimate
for this thing?" We're not going to say, "Oh,
we need to build a calendar and then do a whole
bunch of Figma files or write a whole bunch
of requirements and then ask for an estimate."
We're going to go the other way around and we're
going to say, "What is our appetite for this? What
is the maximum amount of time we're willing to go
before we actually finish something?" And
we have that startup moment that we talked
about. That moment of like, "Ah, you know what I
mean? It works. We got somewhere." At least this,
if not the whole project, this meaningful
piece, we can literally walk away from.
So then what we found was that there was a lot
of experimentation. We found that six weeks is
the maximum that we can see into the future
where we could actually say, "How do we work
backward and figure out something we could
build in that six weeks and really land it?"
That's the first piece. Is working backward
from the amount of time we actually want to
spend on something and say, "What can we do? What
could we shape so that after that amount of time
we've gotten to somewhere we want to be?"
It's like if you're going to buy a car or
you're going to buy a house or you're going to
rent a new flat or whatever, you have to have
a budget in mind, right? And the budget then is
how you choose between all kinds of alternatives
and make a lot of hard choices and trade-offs to
figure out like, "Well, I want the faster engine,
but I have to give this up, or I want it to be fun
to drive, but we also need space for longer road
trips." You're making all these trade-offs, right?
So, this second piece is this work that we call
shaping and the shaping work is, how do we
actually take this fixed amount of time that
we've given for ourselves and vary the scope? How
do we come up with a idea, some version of this
that's going to work in the amount of time
that the business is interested in spending?
So, this is those creative sessions that I was
talking about where we're jumping all over the
room in front of the whiteboard and getting
to an idea. And there, the really key thing is
that we're getting to an idea where we can see
the idea. We understand why we're doing this.
We're wrestling with the problem and we're
wrestling with the solution until we have an idea
that we can actually say, "This is what we want to
go build." So it's not just calendar or dashboard
or newsletter builder, but it's this idea of
how we're going to tackle this problem about the
calendar request, right? So that's the shaping.
And then the third piece is when we've actually
carved out a fixed amount of time, when we've
shaped a solution that is from a experience
standpoint, from a functionality standpoint, from
a technical standpoint, doable and desirable,
something that we can make happen in that
amount of time, then we can give it to a team.
We don't have to do the sometimes called scrum,
the paper shredder. That's where you take an idea
and then you split it into 100 tickets, right, and
you hope that it all glues together still after
you've done that step. We don't want to do that.
Instead, we want to have a whole idea, give it
to a team so they see the whole, they really
understand it, right? And then they can come
up with their tasks and they can figure out
how to track that and break it into pieces so
they can actually take more responsibility.
And so what we see is way more engagement,
especially from the technical team, right?
Because instead of, "Here's your ticket," or
"Here's your user story," it's like, "Here's
the thing you understand, that makes sense,
and now you're going to have freedom to figure
out how to actually make this a reality."
There's going to be a million things
to solve in the implementation detail,
and now you have a bunch of fun problems and
you don't have to keep asking questions to
other people to understand what this is or
how do I make a trade off or that thing.
One of the core elements of this, and I
want to confirm is that you can pick and
choose these things into your team. You
don't need to do this wholesale, correct?
You don't need to do any of it. So,
this is where it helps to look at what's going
wrong and what are we trying to fix? And then
what do I want to bring into this, right?
And usually, what I notice is that people,
they like to start sometimes with,
"Oh, I want to give the team,
let's say six weeks and I want to give the team
more latitude or let's say more creative freedom,
that they're going to be responsible in this
six weeks to figure out how to make it happen."
And usually a lot of the drive for that
is, "I'm getting tired of having so many
meetings and rituals and things that are
not actually working on the problem and
doing the work." I mean, especially scrum
teams, they often complain about that.
So, what they sometimes see in this is like, "Oh,
I love this idea that the team is just going to be
cooking for six weeks and they're not going to,
we're going to meet as needed and we're going to
workshop things, but we're not going to be busy
with all these rituals all the time," right?
Now, the thing that's tricky is that if you
want that reality of the team happily buzzing
and humming like some happy bee colony for this
six weeks, they need to have a lot more clarity
around what's the thing that we're solving, right?
And so when we start working backward from that,
then what we see is that, "Oh, well, if we don't
shape better, then the team isn't going to have
the clarity that they need to take over that
responsibility, so they can make choices and make
decisions and make trade offs so that they can get
to the end of this thing." And the worst is that
sometimes see cases where people are like, "Okay,
we're doing Shape Up. So, you guys are going to
build the newsletter builder, okay? But you only
get six weeks to do it. So use your fixed time,
vary your scope and enjoy your responsibility."
You know what I mean? Which is just cruel, right?
Because I think I'll quote Bob Moesta,
who's been on your show a couple times,
"You can't put 10 pounds of crap in a five
pound bag." So, it's a high academic statement
and we can't just take any project, no matter how
giant it is, and then throw it at a team and say,
"Figure it out and ship something meaningful
in six weeks by cutting away scope," right?
So, it starts to raise questions about how do
we actually decide together what this project
is? Do we actually have clarity around what
the idea is and what we're going to build?
Let me follow up on a couple of the elements.
So appetites, I think for any product manager,
engineer, designer, anyone that has experienced,
"Okay, we estimate this landing page is going
to take a couple of weeks. Great, let's
work on it," and then it ends up being
six weeks can understand why this makes sense.
It's just like, "This landing page is not that
important to us. Let us just say we will commit
two weeks to it. We'll do as much as we can in
two weeks and then we move on. And scope is not
allowed to go beyond that." Makes total sense.
This just makes so much sense as you listen
to this, especially for people that have...
So much sense as you listen to this, especially
for people that have just fallen into the problems
of estimates not being accurate. Then there's
a six-week element and the key there is your,
and this is counter to maybe two-week sprints
like Scrum, is that kind of the where this comes?
So, actually, it turns out that the
six-week is only a maximum and that's
really where this number does some work for
us. If we think of six weeks as a maximum,
that's going to force us to ask some really
good questions to ourselves about what piece
of this do we really think we can land?
Because if you try to say, in six months,
we're going to ship this thing, you can't get
your arms around all of the problems that have to
get solved for an entire six-month chunk of work
to actually happen. There are so many unknowns,
there are so many ticking time bombs of things
that we didn't understand or couldn't foresee,
but if we set a ceiling at six weeks, we have a
much better chance of, I think that's the size
of something where we can actually shape
it and surface enough unknowns and reveal
that complexity before we're in the middle of it.
It doesn't mean that we can't use this technique
to do a two-week project, especially if you're
on a growth team, you don't want to wait six
weeks or, you know what I mean? You're going
to have to artificially bundle things together
to do six weeks. It's like, look, I've got
something I want to ship in the next week
and then I've got a thing that might take two
weeks after that and then a week after that. So,
it's more a question of what we're trying
to take on. It's really that upper limit.
Okay. So, it could be a two-week
cycle and the appetite is-
It could be a two-week thing.
Cool. So, it's like we're going
to build this new landing page,
we're going to give it two weeks and
then do a shaping session on that.
Now, the other side of that is when it
comes to feature development or building
something that's going to be needy enough
to sell, then there's very few things that
are going to be a substantial value add to
a product that you can do in two weeks. So,
then you get into a point where, well now, we're
just sprinting and we're just taking one bite
after the other. And then that's where we can
land in that situation where we feel like, "Ah,
I can never see the end of this. I just keep going
back and saying, one more sprint, one more sprint,
one more sprint." But six weeks is this long
enough chunk or sometimes, four weeks that the
question is kind of, what's big enough that we can
actually get somewhere with this amount of time?
And there's an implied element to this
that I think is worth highlighting.
The whole idea is you commit to the
appetite and if you are not on track
to hit that instead of extending the
date you cut in order to still hit it.
This is a tricky one.
So, you're right that it's implied,
but the thing is, in real life, if you make a
commitment and you get alignment that we are
going to spend six weeks of engineering time
building this thing, if you get to that end
of that six weeks and something is going wrong,
it wasn't shaped, we can't see the end of it.
It's more complicated than we thought. All these
different things. And by the way, we can also talk
about why those things happen, but when we get
in that situation, if we're at the end of the six
weeks and it's not looking good, we can't just
cut off what we agreed to that made this thing
valuable. We can't just cut the scope and say,
"Oh, well now, we managed to ship inside of six
weeks." That's going to kill everybody's morale.
Everyone's going to feel disappointed. We're going
to feel like this wasn't really worthwhile.
And now, we go into the next cycle with this
debt feeling that we didn't actually finish
the thing we were supposed to finish, so now,
we're like overtime. None of that is good. And
if we also go the other extreme and just say,
well, should we say in the book, we had this
principle at base camp which was this notion
of the circuit breaker. If a project is not on
track to actually finish after the six weeks,
we're just going to cancel it and rethink.
Almost no teams have the stomach for that,
but the version of that that's more stomachable
is look, we can't just cancel the project and then
say, "Let's see what comes next." But what we can
do is say, "We're not going to keep reinvesting
in something that we don't understand."
So, let's take this out of build mode and
bring this back into shaping mode, which might
mean different people, a different conversation
asking different questions, doing a different
kind of work to suss out what is it that's fuzzy
here? What is it that we couldn't see? What do we
not understand? How do we get to the clarity that
we need, so that we can actually say this thing
is going to happen if we give it another whack.
I love just how real this approach
is not this theoretical. Okay,
cool. After six weeks, use just
the scope and it's all that's cool.
Yeah, you just cut the scope.
Yeah.
No problem.
Shape your gut, put your gut.
I've seen some Shape Up adoptions that looked
like that by the way, and that's not the way.
The shaping step is crucial. And what you
mentioned with your landing page example,
by the way, it's so seductive because we can
imagine, oh, Parkinson's law, right? If you give
me six weeks to do the landing page, I'll find
a way to use it, but if you give me two weeks,
then I'll stop after two weeks. But when it
comes to real product work, where there's some
functionality that we have to figure out how to
make it exist, we can't just cut the scope if we
run out of time. So, what it means is that the
shaping work is really working hard together to
figure out what are the main moving pieces of this
thing. How do we narrow down our understanding
of the problem and how do we identify what the
moving parts are of the solution and what actually
connects together for this feature to work?
And when we really get to the level where we can
say, "Oh, we need to do this, this, and then the
engine is going to turn," that's the place where
we can say, "Oh, this is well-shaped." And it's a
different kind of work. In shaping in real life,
we call it, we actually teach it as doing live
shaping sessions, and this was how I did it
for years with Jason. We'd get into the room
and I had both the technical and the UX side,
so both sides were represented there in one
person in that case, but for a lot of teams today,
we actually teach them how to bring the senior
engineering person who isn't just senior in title,
the one who actually knows where the bodies are
buried, how the old stuff works and what's truly
possible and what's hard and what's easy in our
infrastructure, like the person that really knows.
You bring that person together with the product
person who deeply understands the backstory of
why this is an opportunity and what we're trying
to solve with this. And then a designer in the
room and they're whiteboarding and wrestling
with each other to get to what's a version of
this thing that we believe in that's real
that we can actually finish in that time.
This is great. Let's go one level
deeper on this shaping session. So,
a few tactical questions. How long are these
sessions? It sounds like the people that join
are a designer and an engineer and an NPM. So,
add anything else there. And when do they happen
is at the end of a... Do you call it a cycle
by the way or sprint, the six-ish week period?
What I actually like is time box
actually, because the thing is that
some teams need regular cycles because they
have parallel teams and they need that cadence
in order to reduce management overhead. But if
you're small and you only have one or two teams,
you might not need to be on a fixed cadence or
a cycle plan. You might be able to just set one
time box after another. So, the key thing
is actually that that time is pushing back
at you and that you're being intentional about,
what's my time budget that I need to shape into?
Let me take a quick tangent because
if you're, that's so interesting that
the time boxes can be very different
lengths. Imagine at a larger company,
this gets complicated when other teams are trying,
there's dependencies and timelines launch and go
to market dates and all these things. What's the
largest company this approach has worked at?
What's the ideal company stage for Shape Up?
It can function in very large companies. We
have, for example, I have some friends at a,
what is it called? They're doing clinical
trials. So, they're in the pharmaceutical
industry and the companies, thousands of people,
and it's not that every team is doing this,
but they have a few teams that are working in
important areas and they're doing this and it's
completely possible in that context, if you have
someone who's at a senior level on the engineering
side who is able to make the right architectural
choices and also do some negotiating and be
the backstop to make sure that someone isn't
going to get pulled away onto something else,
if you can carve out, oh, this system can be
worked on independently of that system. This
was actually what David at Basecamp has always
been amazing at is this dependency, how...
It's actually not. It's not. So many people
are used to it and they think that it's just
how it is, but it's actually not. It
is possible for engineering leadership,
good engineering leadership untangles things,
so we can work on this system without having
to be thinking about this other system somewhere
else. So, when you have some untangling with your
infrastructure and with your architecture from
an engineering standpoint, then you have some
freedom. And then if you can also figure out
the capacity management side of I'm going to
protect this team from that other work for this
number of weeks, you can really get a lot done.
This insight that you can operate this way
at a larger company and the whole company
doesn't have to operate this way, I
think is really freeing to a lot of
people. What's the adapter? And I want to
come back to the actual shaping process,
but I can't help but ask this. Say the company's
operating a quarterly cadence or six month cadence
and then there's a team operating in a two
week, sometimes six weeks, sometimes four
week cadence advice on how to, what's the
adapter that connects those two cadences?
So, there's two different things. So, I've seen
cases where they've decided on a four-week plus
two-week or so they'll do five-week and then one
week of cool down in between and then they time it
so that it adds up to a quarter. I've seen that.
The other thing I've seen is when the team is
just continuously delivering meaningful things, it
doesn't have to line up because from the executive
level, if you are CP or CTO or in these bigger
cases, it's more like a VP in some area, but
you're coming to the table where you're supposed
to be reporting of what your group is doing. And
when you are consistently saying, "We said we were
going to do this and nothing finished and now,
we're doing this and it's going to finish,"
and the next time you say, "We said we were
going to do that and it's finished, without
excuses and without, well, maybe another few
more months or we're working at it," that's
what everyone wants to see is that movement.
Yeah, if you're doing great, people
will leave you alone. That makes sense.
For sure. For sure.
I love that. I love that point. Okay, coming
back to shaping, maybe one way that would
make it real easy for people to understand,
what's the output of the shaping session?
The output of the shaping session is, and by the
way, about shaping session, maybe we can talk a
little bit about what shaping is not because
we need the contrast sometimes. So, very often,
when people try Shape Up, what I see is a
product team creating either a lot of Figma files
or maybe a lot of documentation, like a PRD with a
bunch of requirements and a bunch of backstory and
good reasons why we're doing this and stuff like
that. And what you see is that when you give that
to a team as this is what we shaped, what happens
is it blows out. So, you probably know about what
happens when the Figma file makes first contact
with the engineering team. There's a reality check
that happens there and very often, there's a back
to the drawing board. So, when there's a lot of
solutioning all the way down to detail without
engineering involved, usually, that's a painful
recipe and then it's like, "No, we can't do
that," or, "Actually, it doesn't work like that."
And then on top of it, the other big challenge
is that there's so much that you can't see on
the surface of a UI. How do we flow from here
to there? What are the different cases of logic?
In which case do we move from here to here to
here in the flow? What is happening behind the
scenes? It's like the engineering team, they
have to put on their x-ray goggles and study
this thing to try and understand what's happening
underneath. I often use this analogy of if you're
doing a home renovation, you can have the most
beautiful rendering of here's the new bedroom,
and we're going to have these lamps on the side
of the bed that are coming out from the wall,
and you can have the perfect rendering and
the perfect lamp and the perfect color,
but if you haven't checked if there's
electricity in that wall there or not, it's
going to drastically change the cost and the time
and everything if you're going to have to rip open
those walls to feed some lines up to those lamps.
So, what we need to do in a shaping session when
it's going well is we come out with some kind
of drawing or diagram where engineers, product,
and design are all looking at that and they're
saying, "We understand that. I know exactly what
to go build." I'll use the example of the calendar
from the book. So, what is a calendar? So,
first of all, there was this work that we had to
do before we could even shape it, which is like,
can we actually narrow down this problem? In
shaping in real life, we call this framing. And
in the book, there's a chapter called Setting the
Boundaries where we get into this and it's like,
look, we are not going to just build calendar,
which is Google Calendar. Who knows where it ends?
We narrowed it down to we understand that for our
specific customers who are requesting this again
and again, it's more about I need to see empty
spaces and in the existing agenda view, I can only
see things that are already scheduled and I can't
see free spaces where I could book something.
So, we got to that point of what we're trying to
solve here is the empty spaces. So, that's a good
frame. Then what are we actually going to build?
We came to, here's a good rule of thumb. If it's
shaped well, you can usually describe it in less
than 10 moving pieces. If I can say, "It's going
to have this, this, this, this, this, and this,"
and that's how we're going to let people see the
empty spaces, that's a good indicator that it's
clear enough that it's shaped well. So, in this
case, when you go to an airline and you want to
book something, you see this two-month grid. So,
it's like there's going to be two months side
by side, but they're just going to have dots
in them to indicate if there's a free day or
not, if there's something in that day or not,
like the iPhone calendar, I think still has
this where it's just dots on the month view.
And then if you tap a day with a dot in it or
without a dot in it, there's going to be an
agenda view that slides underneath, which is going
to show you what's scheduled in that day. And then
there's going to be navigation to go forward and
back in the months, there's going to be a create
button to create an event, and that's more or less
it. So, what you can see here is it's not like,
what is a calendar? It's not a calendar. It's
a two-month dot grid with scrolling agenda view
underneath and the ability to hit new when you're
looking at an empty space to create something in
what you're viewing. So, that's the kind of thing
where that's shaped and we can talk about what
that means and what it entails, and we can have
a really practical, realistic conversation about,
is that a thing we can do in six weeks?
That's going to be a real conversation and
not looking at a whole bunch of mock-ups and
trying to x-ray to figure out what's actually
the intent here and what's really real and
what's not and what's possible and what's not.
That was a great example. This is really
helpful. So, if I were to try to describe
this, essentially what you're coming out of it
with a shaping session with is like the user
experience with just wire frames/sketches of
the screens and the key buttons and flows. So,
it's like the architecture with key components,
not like a dock of spec and not final design,
and also not just a user story. As a user,
I need to be able to see empty spaces.
Exactly. So, because the thing where
it goes wrong. If we're going to commit
engineering time and it's like we believe
there's some way to see empty spaces,
but the way is a question mark, it's
a really risky way to spend that time.
Because you're committing, right? It's like-
Yeah, we're committing and that time is really
valuable. That's six weeks of engineer's time,
and that time wasn't easy to get in
the first place because, of course,
there's all these other forces in the company that
want to be doing something with the engineers. So,
if we want that team to be really using
that time well where they are moving,
they understand what they're solving and they're
creatively engaged because they know what it's
supposed to be doing, they need to have that
clarity both on the problem side of this is
about the empty spaces and on the solution
side of it's a dot grid with two months and
a scrolling agenda view and a button. There's
still a million interesting creative tasks
there in the actual high fidelity design in the
code. There's so many things to solve there,
but that is something that they can all hold
in their heads and understand and work on.
This episode is brought to you by Airtable
ProductCentral, the unified system that brings
your entire product org together in one place. No
more scattered tools, no more misaligned teams. If
you're like most product leaders, you're tired of
constant context switching between tools. That's
why Airtable built ProductCentral after decades of
working with world-class product companies. Think
of it as mission control for your entire product
organization. Unlike rigid point solutions,
ProductCentral powers, everything from resourcing
to voice of customer to road mapping to launch
execution. And because it's built on Airtable's
no-code platform, you can customize every workflow
to match exactly how your team works. No
limitations, no compromises. Ready to see
it in action? Head to airtable.com/lenny
to book a demo. That's airtable.com/lenny.
You mentioned, and I think a lot of people
listening to this are going to be like, "Oh,
I'm scared of doing this," is if you get
too detailed, the engineers and designers
on the team are just like, "What the hell?
You're just telling me what to build. That
sucks. I don't want that kind of work." So,
is the solution to that the engineering lead
was super involved and detailed, and
the design lead was super involved,
and so you can trust that you're not just the code
monkey building the thing they told you to build?
That's really interesting. I got to tell you,
the dominant failure case that I see in the real
world is always, again and again, not enough
detail. And it's also the most common failure
mode where the engineers run back to the product
folks and say, "I'm not getting enough from you."
It is really like that, but I can understand
why the hair stands up on the back of the neck
a little bit thinking about it because, of
course, if you give a senior engineer like,
"Here's how I want you to go implement the
schema for this database change for this
model," they're going to be like, "What do you
think? Who are you? Who are you?" You know what
I mean? But what's really interesting is it's not
a universal thing. The amount of detail that the
team is going to feel helps them is a dial that
we can turn that depends on who's on the team.
So, if you have a more junior person who's on
the build team and then you have a more senior
engineer who's involved in the shaping, they can
make that junior engineer much more successful
with additional detail. So, we're going to do
this and I would suggest approaching it like this,
this, this, and this. That junior person is, when
they don't know how to do it, they're not going
to ask because they don't want to show that they
don't know, and they're going to hide the fact
that they're lost and it's going to blow up
later in the project. And on the other hand,
if they are given more guidance, they're
going to be able to be successful. They're
going to learn about this is how this person
who knows well, kind of approached it and then
in the next round or a few projects later,
you can dial it back and say, "Well, let's
give less detail and see how they handle it."
So, you can really give people bigger shoes to
grow into and help them to be successful. And
then, of course, you can also do it the other
way around where if you've got some really
stellar talent on the team and you have a
long history and you have a lot of trust that they
are going to be able to understand and solve it,
then of course, you can leave things out.
But the thing that I often see is if there's
someone on the build team who really feels
that they should be involved in the fundamental
decisions about the approach, then a better
solution would be to actually bring them into
the shaping and have them play that technical
role in the shaping session. If they have the
right skills and the right perspective and
the right knowledge to play that role well,
then just bring them into the shaping. So, it's
all about how do we bring people into a moment
where we are using their strengths and then we're
giving them an input, so that whatever their work
step is that they're able to apply the maximum
creativity, but also have the maximum clarity,
so that they can really use that time well
and also feel good about what they're doing.
It feels like the core of this is de-risk
the biggest risks and address the biggest
unknowns as much as possible. There's
probably this 80% of here are the risks.
Let's just understand them deeply
before we commit to this appetite.
That is exactly right. There are these, we
can call them rabbit holes, we can call them
time bombs. There are these things where
we say, "Oh, it'll be fine." One example,
simple example, I worked with a team and they
had a step of onboarding in a FinTech product
and there was this step of onboarding and they
would lose a lot of people in the funnel at that
step because you had to fill out a whole bunch
of information, and they figured out that they
could actually pipe that data in from one of the
partners that they had. They were partnered with
banks and they're like, "Oh, we don't even need
to be asking people this. So, we're going to fix
conversion. We're going to eliminate a step from
our user experience. It's going to be great."
The thing that they didn't look at was if you
go into the code on that step of the onboarding,
it's not actually one step. There's like three
different branches of that step depending on which
bank the customer is integrated on. And so, that's
the kind of thing where it all sounds so great and
simple, and then you get into the weeds and you
realize like, "Oh, wait a minute." You know what
I mean? So, now, we have decisions to make.
Now, if you're in the middle of a project and
it's already been resourced and people are already
on the hook that we're supposed to be doing this,
and you already got the alignment that the
engineering time is happening for this,
and you're finding that out in week four. You know
what I mean? You did all these beautiful drawings,
by the way, and now, you're finding this
out in week four, that's a bad place to be.
But if we're in the shaping room and we
didn't kick this thing off yet, we didn't
even green light the project yet, and we have
an engineer there, not just the product people,
not just the designer, but we have that
engineer who really insists on sometimes,
I like to think of it like the grumpy old plumber
who's seen everything and he insists on opening up
the walls and looking at the pipes before he'll
give you a quote. So, it's like when you've got
that person in the room, they're saying, "Yeah,
that all sounds great. Let's take a quick look
at the code and figure out what screen you're
actually talking about. Just let's just take
a quick look." And it only takes a moment to
open up the code, find this thing that we're
talking about, and really look at it and say,
"Oh, it's more complicated than we thought."
And now, it's not like, "Okay, now, we're screwed
and the project is going to be bigger." Now,
we can have a really cool conversation
about trade-offs. So, let's say we've got
three different integrations here, three different
segments integrated into different banks. How big
are they relative to each other in terms of the
deals we made or the percentage of customers who
flow through those three different conditions?
If we just did this on one of those branches,
would it be a win? And if we did it on all
three, how much more time would we have to
negotiate for and would it feel worth it? You
see, we're getting into this horse-trading of
what is important, what's worth it, what do
we need to get out of it? And that's really
productive. And when you're doing that before
the project starts off, that feels like, "Oh,
we're talking about the important things. We're
not failing right now. We are engaged in the
hard questions that are going to enable us to
really ship something that's successful later."
Well, let's go one level deeper on this shaping
session, because clearly, that is so core to this
working, and I know you have a whole book about
how to actually do this. So, we're not going to-
... to this working, and I know you have a whole
book about how to actually do this, so we're not
going to answer all the questions, and there's
a lot of detail and nuance. But a few questions,
how long do these usually take? It sounds like a
whole day experience, and then it sounds like you
invite as few people as possible, but not too few
people. What's your guidance on who should join?
In this shaping and real life course, we've been
doing workshops where we try to help people to
learn what it's like in a shaping session. One
of the things that's always interesting to me is
how... So Kathy and I will be running the session
and we have to... People aren't used to working so
fast. What are we actually doing right now? What's
the decision? What's an idea right now? We're not
going to go away and draw something, and then I'll
comment on a document and then come back and get
together tomorrow. What ideas do we actually
have right now starting from zero? So imagine,
we've narrowed down the calendar problem
too. It's about empty spaces. We are willing,
from a business standpoint, to spend
six weeks on a whack at this where it's
solved. We believe there's a way that's
possible, so what can we come up with?
And that's the input to the framing
session or sorry, the shaping session.
Exactly. Having a narrowed down
problem from the framing work,
and this is a whole other topic of very often
the PMs are sometimes just taking something at
face value and not negotiating down to really
narrow down what is this really, and where is
the value in this? But let's suppose that that's
happened, that we've narrowed down the problem,
so now we've got a narrow problem. So now
what we need to do is try out different ideas,
and this is the real thing. We have to try
to break them. So I want to draw an idea,
and then I want the technical person to find, oh,
this isn't going to... You know what I mean? This
isn't going to work because of this reason. Or
the product person is going to be looking in and
saying, "I get that that's really an easy way to
do it technically, but I don't think that we're
actually delivering the value if I play through
the customer scenario here." You know what I mean?
So there's these different angles where the
idea can fail, and one of the things that we
also coach people to do in a session is not
just to go down one path and then be stuck in
one idea and now you're going in circles around
little details of one idea for three hours, but
to really step back and say, "Here's an approach.
What if we had the scrolling agenda view, okay?
And that's idea A. Then what's a very different
way of doing this?" Do you know what I mean? If
we didn't want to have the agenda view there, is
there a way to do this where it's just a month
view? Let's see if we can draw that. So that's the
thing that's happening. You asked about the time,
and I started with people aren't used to just
going all the way in to actually trying ideas.
So there is a little bit of learning how
to just face that blank page and start
trying things together. What we find is that a
three-hour session can be very, very productive
to help you figure out what do we already have
that are possible approaches to this? What are
some major missing things? Like, okay, I've got
the calendar dot grid, I've got the agenda idea,
but what about multi-day events? Do you know what
I mean? So there can be these things, these what
abouts. So then maybe we break and we think for
a little bit, and somebody sketches some ideas on
that and does a spike or two on something, and we
come back again for another three hours or we come
back the next day. And what I would say is if the
project that you're trying to do is doable with,
let's say, your existing technology, you're not
inventing a new algorithm, you're not inventing
some new database or... You know what I mean?
You're not doing a new AI model. It's more
about how do I use the APIs and the frameworks
and the tech stack that we have? How do I put
that together to build something? Then if
the problem is clear and the time is now,
you will be able to come to a conclusion about
what's possible to build in three sessions,
something like that. The key thing is leaning
into those sessions and really wrestling with
each other. If you have just the product and
the designer there and then it's like, well,
we'll show this to the technical person later,
then it can all blow up. And then you find out
it's more complicated than you thought and
you have to go back to the drawing board. We
need to have all the necessary information in
the same room for these sessions to go fast.
There's so much genius built into this approach,
and it sits on top of human nature. One is just,
you need to actually spend... go into the
deep edge cases and nuances and not just-
Yes.
Yeah, that's fine. Let's go
with [inaudible 00:59:34].
More concreteness.
Very concrete, very in depth, and then
the appetites are... There's just so
many elements of this that just connect with the
way humans work versus the theory of just like,
"Yeah. Well, let's see how long this will take.
It'll be a great... and we'll figure it out as
we're building. We don't need to really figure
this out. Yeah. We don't have time for that."
And we're solving a puzzle together, if it needs
to be doable in this amount of time. But it also
has to hit these points in terms of the problem
we're solving. You know what I mean? It has to do
these things, but in this time. One other thing
that I would mention is that we can't be drawing
Figma files. By the way, I'm being very mean
to Figma so far in this conversation. There is
a time when it's the right time for the Figma
file. What we want to do is have that clarity
around the... Let's say, we already
know where the sink is going in the
kitchen and now we can make final calls
about the tile and the exact fixture-
Grout color.
... and stuff like that. Right, grout color. We
don't want to have to throw it all away every time
something changes. So there's a time and a place
where Figma is amazing and feels good and it's
like, oh, now it's beautiful. Now, it's amazing.
But in a shaping session, you can't collaborate on
something so high fidelity. So we need also some
ways to collaborate, and this is where you see
these techniques in the book, like breadboarding
and fat marker sketching. These are tools to help
us express an idea very, very clearly in detail.
We're going to hit this button and from this
button, go to here. This calculation runs, then
we get this answer, and then we have this choice
to go here or here. That's the thing that we
need to be seeing and that's the level of detail
where we can move fast together but still see
something real as more this breadboarding level.
Fat marker session is very evocative
of what this whole session is about,
is very high level sketches. That's a great term.
The danger there that I often see is
that what we don't want is to say, "Oh,
Figma isn't the right thing at this level.
So instead, we're going to do fat marker
sketches," and what you get is the equivalent
of a blurry Figma. Do you know what I mean? Just
less detailed. What we need from a fat
marker sketch for it to be valuable to
us as builders is it has to really communicate
the idea. When I look at that, I'm like, "Oh,
now I get it?" And if it's more this general
wire frame of dashboard goes here and there's
going to be four reports, and it's like
I still don't know what to build, right?
Mm-hmm.
So if it's not telling me what to build, so maybe
this is a way to come back to your question about
what's the output of the shaping session,
it's like it's shaped if we can give this
to a technical person and they say,
"Yeah, I know what to go build now."
I'm very happy with our overview of the
process. I think we've done a really good
job giving people the gist. And obviously,
if they want to actually implement it, they
can get the book and dive in or work with you,
which we'll point people to. Say someone's like,
"This is awesome. I want to do this." What
would you say is a good first step for a team
that's currently... let's say, they're in startup
land, and they're just shipping every two weeks,
maybe every week? So maybe for that bucket
of folks and then also for a larger company,
I don't know, Agile Scrum SAFe, and they're
just like, "Oh, let's try something different."
Sometimes dev teams, they like the
idea of not having the Scrum ritual,
so they want to take in the six
weeks, but unless the engineering
and product come together to figure
out how to collaboratively shape,
like we talked about before, that
time box isn't going to go well. So I-
They think they're going to not have to do
standups, but now it's a day of hard thinking.
Well, it turns into even more meetings,
because we don't know what to do.
And the more meetings is just that
shaping session specifically. Right?
No, what I mean is that if we didn't-
Oh, right. I [inaudible 01:03:46] right.
If we only adopted the six-week cycle and
said we're going to figure it out and we
didn't adopt the shaping, then we just don't
know what to do. And then we reached the end,
and we're basically scrambling to shape
it as we go. And then we run out of time,
and then we feel like this wasn't... It was
nice to get a break from the Scrum rituals,
but we can't say that we are knocking
the champagne bottle on the boat because
we're celebrating the launch or
whatever, again and again. Right?
That's a good, actually, time to maybe talk about
there's obviously the spring kickoff in
Scrum. What's main difference for people,
because they may be thinking, "Oh, this
is just like a spring kickoff." That's-
Oh, that's a good one.
... big deal.
That's a good one. So what you often
see in a Scrum team is that there's
somebody who creates these tickets
of these are the things that are
going to happen inside of the sprint.
Really, in my opinion, too many cases,
it's not the person who's doing the
building who's creating those tickets.
So your product owner.
So there's a big, big gap there.
We could talk a lot about that,
but there's gaps in context. The person who's
writing the ticket doesn't actually understand
the work that's involved. You know what I mean?
So there are so many unknowns and time bombs
waiting in those tickets that sound reasonable,
but they weren't really created by the person who
understands the work that needs to happen. So
the key difference is two things. So in Scrum,
you have a person who's not the builders making
tickets, and this is what in the cruel picture
is the paper shredder. In the shape-up world, you
have a single idea that was shaped. This is the
thing we shaped with the two months in the agenda
view and da da. Go make your own tasks, because
you're the professionals. Do you know what I mean?
So the contractors, if you're building a house,
they have to know the plans, but you don't have to
tell them, "Now take the hammer and go over here."
That's their, right? So in a shape-up world,
a kickoff is, here's the well-shaped idea,
and now this time box starts. At Basecamp, it
was really, really loose because they are just
stocked with senior people. They have so many very
senior engineers and all the designers are coding.
They're very technical, really, really skilled
people. What I found is helpful when the team is
a little bit more mixed, if they're not all super
senior, is a simple exercise of at kickoff, take
whatever was shaped and just draw a grid with nine
boxes, and give me nine boxes of the nine major
chunks that you think have to get implemented from
an implementation standpoint. So translate this
into nine major scopes of implementation that need
to somehow happen over the time box. So really,
really useful exercise to kick things off,
and we have a lot of teams doing that now.
If you take six weeks, that's 30
business days. You divide that by nine,
it's four days per box. So you're going to get a
lot of clarity from a quick exercise. And again,
this is done by the builders. This is a really
also good exercise for them to notice like, "Oh,
wait a minute, we think there's too much scope
here. Even though it seemed reasonable, when we
put it into nine boxes, it's like, I don't think
we can do this all." Or it's also a good moment
where somebody who's more junior might describe
their implementation approach, and then someone
who's senior can review that and say, "Actually,
we've done that before, and we'll run into this
trouble if we don't use this other thing." So
those really nice coaching moments can happen.
If you were to try this approach
and have a shaping session,
this is a sign you're heading in a good
direction, is if the output, the team
that's building it can come up with nine...
Does it have to be nine? Is six cool, 10 cool?
What I found is if it's more than 10,
then you just get into ticket land of,
here's a million things I have to do. You
know what I mean? If you have 100 things,
that doesn't tell me anything.
But if it has to be nine or less.
Nine or less. Okay. Okay, cool.
I actually think... I'm speculating here, but
the UX designers in your audience will know
about this rule of seven, plus or minus two. It's
this cognitive science principle that was found
about how many things someone can hold in their
head at once. So this nine is the upper limit of
seven plus or minus two, and it basically...
It's like, do we actually have a picture of
what it means to build this that we can also
hold in our heads? Can we see the whole castle?
So what I'm hearing is if you're on a, say,
Agile Scrum team today, if you want to start
trying this out, it's schedule a shaping
session, assume it's six weeks to start,
try to come into it with a framing of
here's the problem we're trying to solve.
Is that a good way of thinking about it,
like the problem we're trying to solve?
Yeah, for sure. The question is what problem are
we trying to solve, because the shaping work is
more what are our options for the solution?
And if the problem is too fuzzy and big,
if the problem is just calendar, then the
shaping is going to be this ever-expanding,
never-ending thing, and we're not
going to be able to get anywhere.
Yeah. Okay. So you spend three hours,
maybe six hours in the first session.
Would you recommend try to keep it to this
many hours when you're first trying it up?
No, I wouldn't do that. I think the key
thing is actually if you get to the point
where you're trying to hold a shaping session
and you manage to get product and engineering
into the same room to do it, you are far along.
You're doing great if you're at that point. Oh,
so much of the challenge is getting to the point
of aligning between product and engineering that
we cannot have projects that are dragging and
dragging and dragging. We can't keep ending in a
place where this is the end of a sprint or the end
of a cycle and we still can't see the end of it,
or we have to make so many cuts and compromises
at the last minute that it's not the quality
of... or it's not really matching what it was
supposed to be in the first place. When those
problems are happening or... Also by the
way, this is surfacing at the exact level.
Imagine, you're the CPO, you're the CTO,
and you are supposed to be answering to,
"How's that work going?"
And it's like, "Well, actually,
we're working on it. I can just think of a
couple of times when I needed to go to Jason,
and he expected me to be making progress on
something and I had gotten nowhere on it. And that
feeling when you are with top leadership in the
room and you don't have a good answer for where
you are on something is like... Oh, it's brutal,
right? And then from the CEO's perspective,
it's like, "Where's the movement? We're running a
business here. Really, nothing is shipping still?"
This can't just keep happening. So there's some
recognition somewhere either at the higher levels
or within the team of, we don't want to keep
dragging, we don't want to keep being lost in
the weeds, and then this can be the activation
energy. You gather the power to be like, "Okay,
we actually want to try something different."
And in that case, what I would say is what usually
works best is, okay, we're going to try a pilot
project, and what we want to do is, as you said,
choose a problem that's important enough to all of
us that we think it's meaningful, it's going to be
worth trying to do well. And it doesn't have to be
six weeks. It could be something that is a little
bit smaller, maybe you feel comfortable taking
on three week thing for the first time. What's
important is just matching these things together.
Here's a problem that we actually care about. It's
timely, something that we would like to be
shipped soon. It's not so small that we're
not going to actually learn this new muscle, and
it's big enough that it's going to feel like we
really achieved something. So maybe that's going
to be four weeks, maybe it's going to be six,
maybe it's three, I don't know. And then getting
to a place where we wrestle a bit with the problem
to get the problem narrowed down. We get into our
shaping session, and then we do our best. Do you
know what I mean? And usually, what happens too
is if we have an engineering team that's going
to become free to do this work for those X number
of weeks, that's the upper limit on how long we
can spend to shape, and that's another real
life thing, is sometimes we talk about if...
On the one hand there's this universe of never
ending documents back and forth to get feedback
and comments, and then on the other
hand there's like the team is going
to be available. We're trying to actually do
this, so actually, we've got a week to shape
because engineering needs to kick off next week.
Do you know what I mean? That's a little bit more
the real scenario when you're actually in this
aligned world of we want to ship something now.
Yeah, real life constraints. That's
a really helpful way of telling you
how much time you have to do this. For
people that are just like, "I don't know,
any friends that are using this. It's like
weird, this way of working. It's not a thing
I hear about all the time." What can you
say to them to help them be like, "Okay,
I should actually give this a try. Here's
how many people are using it. Here's impact
that you've seen." Anything you can share
that would help them get over that hump?
I would say wait until it hurts more. If the
unfamiliarity is the big problem with it,
then maybe the things are fine. Because it's
not like this is the only way. It's more like,
changing is really hard, and if there's a good
reason to do it and it's like, look, we've done
it the old way. We've tried different experiments.
We've even already churned through a new head of
product, or we've got a different CTO in and we're
still having the same problems, then there comes
a point where it's like, I know that this is
uncomfortable, and I don't know somebody who's
done it, but I think we need to try something
different because we can't continue this way.
That is a great answer. Following that
same thread, just what are signs that
it's time to try something? What sort
of pain do you often see that's like,
okay, you shouldn't look into this seriously?
There are pains all along the journey. So I think
the place where it's most obvious is at the end
of the line when we thought we were going to
be done and this thing is just dragging and
dragging and dragging. The teams, we're not
shipping things. We're running in place. We
keep going in circles on this like we don't see
the end. Of course, that's the culmination, but
there's also a lot of pain points along the way.
So if we go all the way upstream, if we go to the
source of a project, sales talk to a customer...
You know what I mean? Or sales talk to a lead,
and they have this idea of this thing we
need to build, or the CEO had this idea in
the shower the other day, or the product team
did a whole bunch of research and they have a
big case for why this is the thing that's
important to build next. Whatever it is,
there's a source from the business perspective
of this is the thing we should do next.
If we just say dashboard and we don't negotiate
what that means, if we just say calendar and we
don't negotiate what that actually is, then
what do we experience? This fuzzy thing where
it's really hard to get to a conclusive answer
about, yeah, that's what we need to go do. It's
like the ever expanding blob. So if you've felt
that before, that's already a first pain. And
then of course, where does it go from there? So
we say calendar, so we don't know what it means,
but we say calendar, so now we give it to product
and we've either got a whole bunch of Figma files
or we have the PRD with a million requirements
about what a great calendar is. Of course,
I don't want to be cruel to the people who
are putting their hearts into that work,
because the Figma file is beautiful. It's just
coming a little early. And the PRD is full of
a lot of true things that are probably really
important for decision-making in the project,
but the way that it's packaged at that moment
isn't something that gets absorbed. You write this
document and I'm sorry, who actually reads it? You
know what I mean? I know it's painful, but it's
like that. And then even when we try to read it,
because it wasn't shaped and we didn't get down
to it's this, it's that, it's that, and that's how
it works, it's hard to walk away from reading that
and have anything that's in your head as, this is
what we're going to go build. It's like a million
puzzle pieces that you're going to have to solve.
So what we see is either there's the Figma file
and then there's the pushback from engineers.
There's the PRD, but then it's like, okay,
but we still don't actually know what to build.
There's all those things where, instead of moving
forward, there's more and more questions, more
and more pushback, more and more going back to
the drawing board. So that's another big indicator
that something is going wrong. And then when we're
in the building and we thought we knew what
we agreed to, we thought we all said, "Yeah,
this is what we want to go make," and it's
just more and more questions coming out. More
and more unexpected complexity, things that we
didn't anticipate, and it just doesn't feel like
we're getting warmer and coming closer. It just
feels like it's getting harder and harder. Those
are all the signs that whatever process you use,
that there's a lack of clear shaping and there's
a lack of clear framing because there's a lack
of clarity around what it is that we're doing.
Before we started recording, you made
this interesting point that there's
always talk of feature factories
and that rarely are they actually
efficient factories. They don't
actually work. Talk about that.
Yeah. Well, I understand what the feature factory
critique is supposed to be. It's actually to
the framing point of we're not negotiating the
value and the outcome we're trying to get from
something. We're just taking it and building it.
And then of course, in the end, according to the
feature factory critique, we just built it because
somebody said we should build it, and then people
didn't use it and didn't value it, and the product
is just getting bloated. The thing is that,
I would say if you have a feature factory, meaning
you're continually cranking out features, you're
probably quite healthy. All you need to do is feed
a different input to the beginning of the factory.
What most teams are struggling with is that
they don't have predictable repeatable shipping
of things. At least from my experience,
the bigger really widespread struggle is,
stuff isn't moving, it's dragging. I can't see
the end. I'm losing my... I'm feeling burned
out. You know what I mean? It's not exciting
to work on this anymore, all that a thing.
Maybe last question here is what's the
sweet spot stage for a company to start
using Shape Up? You basically worked in
this way from the very beginning when
it was just three people. What do you
find... Should startups that are just
starting out start working in this way,
or do you find it's more useful later on?
We didn't formalize it until we had to, and there
was a long time where there wasn't a fixed length
for projects. There was just an understanding of
the urgency and a feeling of what too long felt
like. And it didn't actually click into, oh,
this is a cycle length and this is six weeks,
and then we pause, and this is who comes together
to make the decision of what's the next project,
and here's who is mainly doing the shape. You
know what I mean? All that stuff didn't get solved
until we had reached a certain size. Usually, the
main tipping point if we start from smaller to big
is there's a phase when the founders are still
involved in everything, and so it doesn't matter
what your process is, it's going to be fine.
But then you start to hire the first other
people and then for the first time you try to
delegate some of those things and the founders
try to be less involved, and that's often where
a lot of these problems start to appear. And the
founders start to ask themselves like, "We used
to be fast, and now we hired people because we
needed to scale, but now we're slow. So how
do we be fast again? Because we know what-
... well. So like, "How will we be fast again?"
Because we know what it's like. If we just got
back in there as founders and got our hands
dirty, like we could make this go. But how do
I get the people that we've brought in to make
these trade-offs and make these decisions and
how do I get the work to flow again? So that's
something that we definitely see there. So that's
a really good moment. I'm onboarding new people. I
don't know what to tell them how to work. I don't
want to introduce a bunch of scrum rituals. Just
winging it on Kanban isn't working, because they
don't have enough clarity around what to go after.
So I have to babysit them all the time. You know
what I mean? Like these kinds of things.
There is another extreme, which is I...
We've already gone past that. We've been scrum or
whatever for years. The company has been growing,
like revenue is coming in, like sales is doing
their job, like things are running. But man,
nothing is getting out the door. And we're years
in and we have an entrenched development. We
have like an entrenched engineering team,
which is a wall away from an entrenched
product team and everybody's apart. And
this thing is like, we're like stuck.
And that is more where there's going to be
some tensions that are starting to appear
at the executive level. There's going to be some
finger pointing. There's going to be some like,
"Why isn't this moving? Why isn't this happening?
How can we be spending so much money in all these
engineers and we don't have anything to show
for it?" And that's a point where there can
be kind of a... Some hard conversations need
to start happening about, "How do we actually
start to negotiate around how we spend time?"
And we can't just have endless refactorings
and infrastructure projects, but we need to be
actually building things that we can sell again.
What an idea.
Yeah. You know? But it can... There are a lot of
engineering orgs that have been standing around
for a while and it's all refactoring all day
and tech debt and stuff like that. And there's
reasons why all those things got there, but there
comes a point where we have to figure out how to
cut through it and make some hard choices so that
we can carve out time to build the stuff that's
actually going to be needle moving again and not
just sustaining us where we are to run in place.
I imagine this latter bucket
is who you mostly work with,
the kind of companies that bring you in.
It's been a lot of the folks who still
remember what it was like to be fast and
they're kind of newly too big and they don't
like being slow. I've had a lot of that. I
think that your intuition is right. That the
market for the last category is the biggest,
but it's hard to reach them. It's not easy to
talk about these things. These are sensitive
topics. Do you know what I mean? Like, "Our
engineering team isn't shipping," and it's
happening at leadership level. There's a ton
of complaints happening deeper in the org,
but nobody down in the org can change anything. At
the end of the day, it's actually the interface at
the executive level of being able to say, "How are
we using our time? We have to change something."
To make it even more concrete
in that first bucket,
what's the size of org that you find
is most in need of this? It's like,
"How many engineers?" Or is it like when they
hire the first PM? Like what's kind of the-
I sometimes have the like, "How the heck do I hire
the first PM and what do they do?" conversation.
But usually, it's later than that. It's after they
hired the first PM, after they hired the second
PM, and maybe even the third. And they're getting
to the... Product and engineering together are
like 30, 50 people and it's like, "We thought we
put everybody in the right roles. We kind of did
what we were supposed to do and everything
is just grinding. And why are we so slow?
Perfect. So 30 to 50-ish people seems
like a good time to... Basically,
you're finding that's when things
start to really break down.
That's when they show themselves and I
think... I mean, if someone hears this
and it all starts to make sense
and they're earlier in that wave,
then of course the earlier that you
can anticipate it, the better, right?
Yeah. That's a good point.
So if you're-
When it's too late is when they come out so-
I mainly hear about it when it's too
late. That's why they're reaching out-
Got it. So maybe closer to 30. Okay.
Honestly, I think it starts the
first project where, for example,
the founding engineer is hands off and then the
new hire is taking over responsibility. Or the
person who was like sort of founder/CEO is first
giving it to a PM to kind of thinking they're
going to carry it through. And then, it's not
exactly meeting their expectations of what they
thought was going to happen. I think that's when
those disconnects actually start. It's the first
step away from the work where the seeds
of all of these problems actually start.
I want to talk about Basecamp and how maybe not
every company can operate like Basecamp. Before
we get there, is there anything else along the
lines of Shape Up that you want to add or share?
Yeah. There's one key thing, which is the
role of the PM. I think what we see today,
out of necessity in a lot of teams, is that the
PMs spend a lot of time chasing around inside of
the build phase, inside the time box, to try and
make sure that people aren't stuck and getting
lost in the weeds and try and keep things moving.
And it can sometimes be too close to project
management rather than product management.
And what we see in Shape Up teams when
they hit their stride is that the PM
moves upstream. So the PM is less busy
with, "How do I get this project to not be in a
bad state when it's getting built?" And they're
way more in, "How do I understand the business
context? How do I narrow down the problem? How
do I negotiate back and forth with maybe the
CPO who brought this to me to understand where
the core of it is?" That really getting the
deeper understanding of the business and the
problem and the customer domain and like what
problem is worth solving and what's even slice
of that problem is the valuable slice to argue
that we should spend a few weeks on. That's the
place where the PMs can really contribute a lot in
the Shape Up world. That's kind of what they do,
rather than shepherding the process or being
a ritual master or something like that.
That sounds pretty wonderful. I've been doing
some thinking about what an AI-oriented world
does to the role of PM and it feels like very
similar to that actually, where the building
now is going to happen for you with AI tooling.
And that means the bigger question now is like,
"What the hell should I build? And is the thing
I've built right and correct and likely to work?"
And it feels like this is similar, it's like
the PM spending a lot more time upfront thinking
through what to build. And then, the building
is a lot more hands off. So hands off it gets
done in like five minutes when you're just like,
"Well, build this thing for me." "There it is."
Yeah. Let's see. Let's see. Yeah.
Let's see.
I'm also very curious. Yeah.
Oh, man. What a wild time. Okay. Let's
talk about Basecamp. I think we talked
about this ahead of the podcast that...
You want people to know that Basecamp is
very unique and not everyone can work the
way Basecamp works. Just talk about your
insight there and your advice there when people
see all this advice coming out of Basecamp.
I got to tell you, I had no idea how unique
we were until I was outside and there are
so many things. For example, it's a lot
of the things that people ask me about
that are not in the book that started
to reveal those things to me. That's so
many things that I was just taking for
granted. I mean, every designer codes.
Imagine, if every designer codes and I don't just
mean HTML. I mean, like running the app locally,
going in to the place where that view is rendered
to make that thing look the way that they want it
to look or whatever, right? I mean, like really
codes, every designer. So every designer codes,
where's the wall between design and engineering?
Where is the moment where you arrive with the
Figma file and then the disappointment and
all of your hopes get destroyed because
the engineer is telling you no, right? Like
those moments don't even exist in that world.
And then, also, I think also there was this
lack of distance between sort of the business
objective, the thing that we're trying to...
The reason we want to maybe do this project
and the blessing of the founders and the...
Like, there wasn't this kind of executives
far away with some big targets and then some
layer of PM and then some building. I mean,
the founders were always there, right
there in the problem definition still.
I mean, I can't say today, but I mean up until
2021 when I was still there. So it meant that
there was so much clarity all the time around
what we're solving and why and why we're making
time for it. And then, of course, on the
engineering side as well. I mean, imagine,
you have no sales org, you have no marketing.
That all of selling and marketing is happening
by the unicorn founders. So it means that
there isn't contention for engineering time,
that there isn't like all these different sources
of requests that you have to wrestle with,
And David did such an extraordinary job of... I
mean, the more I see the real world, the more I'm
amazed at how every six weeks, there was clear
runway in engineering of like, "We have time for
whatever the... Whatever we'd agreed together is
the most important thing." Just blank check like
six weeks at a time. Not a blank check, but you
know what I mean? Like a blank six weeks, yeah?
Yeah.
Again and again and again, years without end.
Keeping that engineering capacity focused on
readiness for product and totally leaning into
what's exciting to do to build for the product.
And not getting lost in all this refactoring and
new infrastructure and technical debt and stuff
like that. I mean, those are amazing. So those
are some really big differences. And it doesn't
mean that you have to be Basecamp to do Shape
Up. But what it does mean is that when we say,
"Oh, just have a shaping session and if you have
the pressure of the time box, then you can make
trade-offs together." It's like, "Well, if we are
used to having a big wall between, for example,
engineering and design, then we're going to have
to learn..." Somebody who wants to start shaping
is going to have to learn like, "Well, oh, I
need to figure out who to bring together and
how to have that session and how do we interact
with each other. So that we are combining all of
that knowledge that maybe at Basecamp was
all in the same head in a lot of cases."
This is such an important point for people
to hear, because there's so many people that
come on podcasts like this and share, "Here's
how to do it," based on their experience. And
there's so many just assumptions about their
resources, the people they hire, the way the
founders operate. Like no sales team, I think
that's like... I don't even think about that.
Yeah. Imagine, no such thing as a request from
sales, yeah? No such thing as pressure of like,
"We need this thing in order to
upsell or to close this deal." Never.
It sounds like you're in this Basecamp...
By the way, was it called 37signals? Like
it's interesting you call
it Basecamp not 37signal.
Yeah. I mean, so it's just like the timing of
when I left. We were originally 37signals and
then Basecamp became so big that
we renamed ourselves to Basecamp.
I didn't know that.
Yeah. And then, so for example, on the book,
it says Shape Up and there's a Basecamp logo
on the bottom, not a 37signals logo. But then,
since I went back, so it's 37signals again. So
I sometimes struggle with I don't know what to
call it but it's both. Whatever people
can recognize, it's the same powerhouse.
Okay. Cool. I'm glad I'm not the only one that's
confused. But 37signal is the current name. Great.
Yeah. Yeah.
So you said that it felt like you left and
it was like this bubble you got out of. Was
there like a moment where you're like, "You
wrote this book. Everyone..." You're like,
"Hey, this is how you should
work," and then you're like, "Oh,
wait. This doesn't actually work in real life
for a lot of people."? Is there a moment there?
It wasn't that this doesn't work, I was just in
a foreign country. It was like we tried it and it
didn't work. One of the common things I would hear
is the projects kept running over. "We weren't
finishing them at the end of the cycle. They
kept running over and running over." And then,
I would be like, "Huh. So can you show me
your shaping work?" And then, they would
show me a PRD and I'd be like, "That doesn't
look like what's in the book." And again like,
"Can you show me your shaping work?" And
they'd show me like a bunch of Figma files.
And then, what I started to understand
was like we have some people in a role
who were used to making a certain artifact at
a certain step and they just kept doing that.
And I didn't appreciate... It took me a while
to realize like, "There's no engineer in the
picture here." And it was when we started
to actually do the course, I said... Well,
I did actually a couple projects where I helped
teams hands-on and I learned that they...
It was the first actually consulting project that
I did where I helped a team who was stuck. And
what we did was we chose the engineer who was best
suited to come over to product and be there in the
shaping. And that was the moment when it was like,
"Ah. Now, I'm in the world I know again," when
we had all of that mixed in the same room again.
And so, that was kind of like... That was really
something... I mean, it was a total learning curve
for me and there's a lot of things like that. But
that was, for example, a really big one. It's
like, "Oh, we have to get engineering in there."
You're the type of guest I most love having
on this podcast, because you basically
work with many, many companies, study what's
working, what's not. You're not in the clouds
pontificating about something. You're working
with teams to make things better. And then,
you take all of that learning, put it into
a book, and share with us all. And so,
the ROI is just incredible for us all because
you've spent so much time doing this and you've
actually done the work. You're not just in theory
about it. So this is amazing. But we're not done
yet. One question I wanted to ask is, Jason
was tweeting that there's... He's working
on a follow-up Shape Up book. What's happening
there? Are you involved in that? What's the story?
So I also saw the tweet. And I have to admit,
I was a little surprised when I saw this tweet,
but I had had a conversation with Jason a year
earlier. And he reached out and he said, "Hey,
we're thinking about doing a second edition of
the book." And my first reaction... Imagine,
I was actually really in the middle of
learning all these things that teams need
to learn in order to catch up to what
was natural for Basecamp to do. And so,
for me, it was like, "Interesting.
I have a lot of new things. I have
a lot of new ideas. Maybe collaborating
on the second edition could make sense."
But what I understood was that what he wanted
to do was to make an updated version of how
they work, because that's always been a big thing
of how... I should use the right name, 37signals,
of how they market and also how they lead is they
like to really show a clear example. Not like,
"This is how you could do it. This is how some
people do it," but like, "This is how we do it."
And I think it's their strength that they are
very, very clear like, "This is how we do it
and take it or leave it." What I understood
was that if I did another version of the book
that was just how Basecamp does it, I think it
would leave so much opportunity on the table.
Like there's so many people where what they need
to learn is more like, "How can it come closer to
where I am? If I have the wall today between
product and engineering, how do I bring the
right people together into a shaping session?
How do we actually do that? How do I overcome
all of these little challenges because this
is so far from our current way of working?"
So the work that I'm doing with, for example,
with shaping in real life is all about those gaps.
And then, I don't know what's going to be in the
second edition because they are... I guess someone
there is going to be working on that. But what I'm
guessing is it's going to be an update on kind of,
"Up on top of the mountain over here, this is
what Basecamp is doing." So hopefully, it'll be
a cool thing to look at as like, "Here's a model
of what they're doing." And then the question is,
"What can I take from that and what do I need
in order to actually be able to make it work
in the real situation I'm in?" And that's
kind of where... Well, that's my focus.
This is so interesting. Thank you for sharing.
It sounds like a fork. You forked it and these
are going potentially in different
directions but inspired by each other.
Mm-hmm. Totally.
So interesting. Ryan, is there anything else
that you want to share before we wrap up?
One thing I could throw out there is sometimes
people reach out to me because their projects
aren't shipping, there's a lot of struggle,
there's a lot of lack of clarity. But the
root cause is actually that the input
at the very beginning of the process
is too unclear or... Like we don't actually
know what's important to customers or we're
not actually sure where the value is or this
kind of a thing. So there is this link, this
framing step that we talked about of, "What is
really the problem?", before we go into shaping.
This is the link to product strategy also. And
this is the place where it can be really useful to
reach for a lot of, for example, Bob Moesta stuff
with the Jobs-to-be-Done and the demand-side work,
trying to get clear about big... So that's the
tool that I reach for at that phase. And you can
think of kind of this... Before the problem
definition, there's this question of like,
"What's the demand? Where are people
struggling? Where is really the place,
the itch they're trying to scratch?
And then, a lot of the Shape Up stuff is
kind of when I have something where I think
there's an opportunity or I think there's
something meaningful there because of what we
learned from customers or the job to be done,
research, or whatever it was. Now, how do I
turn that into something that we can actually
go do and ship in a reasonable amount of time?
That's the supply side. That's where the Shape
Up part fits in. So maybe it just might
be cool for people to see a link there.
That's a great plug for a Bob Moesta episode.
We talked in-depth about the Jobs-to-be-Done
framework and how to actually apply
it. What's the book you'd recommend
there? It sounds like basically it's like
Shape Up plus this book gives you a lot.
Actually, the one that I recommend the
most is Demand-Side Sales 101 and it's
funny because it's like sales.
Especially for a product person,
you're like, "I'm the product person, not the
sales person." But it's such a good dive into,
"What are people really trying to solve?"
And getting into that mindset of, "What's
the struggle? What's the problem?" I think
that's a really good entry point for that.
Yeah. I don't love that title.
I feel like you could have done
better there with that book's title because-
It's-
Yeah.
What's interesting about it is that it's very,
very pointy for like if you are trying to make
progress on sales, then it's this other kind of
sales, this demand side sales. So I think maybe
it's more for us who are kind of using it for
different purposes. Like we're the product people
trying to pull something out of it. That it's a
little bit less aligned, but it's still useful.
Yeah. But basically it's like
the Jobs-to-be-Done book is what-
Yeah. It's kind of like the Jobs-to-be-Done
book that's a bit more tactical. If you're
really curious about the general spirit of
Jobs-to-be-Done, then Competing Against Luck is
a really good intro. That's the one that Clay
Christensen wrote with a lot of... I think
there's a lot of stuff that Bob worked on that's
in there. But for a little bit more tactical like,
"What's it look like to do the interview? And
how to think about the struggling moment?"
and stuff like that, this Demand-Side
Sales is good for this strategy stuff.
Awesome. And we'll also link to this episode where
you could get the gist of it in one hour's time.
Oh, that's right. You did... That episode
was great by the way. That's... Yeah-
Thanks, Ryan. Thanks, Ryan.
Okay. We did it. This was amazing. I think
this is going to help so many people-
We got through it.
We're not done yet. Two final questions for you.
Where can folks find the book, find you if they
want to work with you? Anything else that you want
to share? And how can listeners be useful to you?
Well, they can find me at my website.
That's ryansinger.co. I'm also on
X on RJS. I'm on LinkedIn. So just
reach me there. And how can people
be useful to me? I love hearing from
people who are having these problems.
If you're having these problems where it's like,
"Things are dragging," or, "We can't see the end
and we're not getting the quality we need," and
all this stuff like man. I mean, this is how I
learned all this stuff is by talking to people
who are in it. So even if it's not clear what's
the next step yet. If that problem is real, it
would be cool to hear about it. I'd love to chat.
Be careful what you wish for about Moesta. He was
just on the podcast and he told me he's got over
a hundred LinkedIn DMs with people sharing their
struggles with their job search. So here you go.
Oh, yeah. Job moves, that's a big one.
I think that's a broad appeal. Yeah.
Yeah. That's true. I'm going to ask you to
explain that when you do consulting work,
just like how does that work? Who's that for?
Just because I know that's something else you do.
So it basically starts with uh, either often
first CPO or CTO often reaches out first. And
when it works well is when we actually get
them together and then they understand that
they need to change something or we have like
a head of product and a head of engineering,
that kind of a thing. If those two are both
seeing eye to eye that there's a problem,
then we can start a conversation around,
"Okay. So who would be the right people for a
pilot team? What are the things that are going on
business-wise that could be a good pilot project?"
And then, I can help to figure out like, "How do
we actually..." So almost like guiding through,
like narrowing down that pilot project framing
so that they have the support that it's going to
be successful in shaping. And then, coaching
the team so that they actually learn those
shaping skills so that they can get through a
session and come out with much more clarity.
Like how do they actually run those sessions.
So it's kind of first working with leadership,
"Who do we need to get to do this work? Who
are the right people? How do we bring them
into a pilot project?" Narrowing down,
doing some framing work on the pilot,
so it's going to be clearer in the shaping.
And then, giving some guidance on how to get
through that shaping with some feedback
rounds. This is usually a good approach.
Amazing. And they can find this on your
website if they want to explore this?
Yes.
Amazing. Ryan, thank you so much for being here.
Yeah. Thanks a lot. You had amazing
questions. It's a subject that can
go in so many directions and you kept
bringing us onto some kind of a main track,
so I'm really pleased. It was
really nice. Thanks a lot.
I do my best.
Yeah.
Thanks, Ryan, and bye, everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe
to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.