My, probably, most spectacular failure was, I
was the first PM on Hangouts. We had thousands
of people working for me. We had entire power of
Google. We had Larry literally sitting with us
saying we can do anything we want Chrome to do and
we still didn't manage to build a great messaging
product. The main learnings from that is, don't
take on projects that are going to be six months,
a year, because you just generally don't have
control over the macro. The challenge with being
a product manager is, everybody thinks they
can do the job. Anybody who uses the product
thinks they have ideas, so at some point in
time, you're like, "What is my discipline?
What is my science?" The moment you build
experimentation, you've now made it scientific.
A lot of new people in their career are like, "Oh,
I just want to think about strategy. I'm
going to think about the big picture."
Strategy is a little bit overrated for
product. For most product managers,
your strategy should be, "How fast
can I go from hypothesis to data?"
Today, my guest is Mayur Kamat. Mayur
is Chief Product Officer at N26,
one of the most successful fintech startups
in the world and which, in my research, came
in amongst the top five companies in the world
who are hiring and producing the best product
managers. Prior to N26, Mayur was Global Head
of Product at Binance, VP of product at Agoda,
which is over a $100 billion dollar company based
in Thailand, and a PM at Google and Microsoft. In
our wide-ranging conversation, Mayur shares what
he's learned about hiring and developing great
product managers, what he learned from his time
working at Binance, which, as you'll soon hear,
was one of the wildest and most unique ways
of working, what he learned from the failure
of Google's early attempts at Hangouts, where
he was the first PM. Also, the pros and cons
of working in Asia versus Europe versus the US,
and why you should be starting your career on the
West Coast of the US. Also, why comp early in
your career does not matter and so much more.
This episode is so full of golden nuggets and
advice for product people throughout every stage
of their career. If you enjoy this podcast, don't
forget to subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. Also, if you become an
annual subscriber of my newsletter, you get a year
free of a bunch of amazing products, including
Superhuman, Notion, Linear Perplexity, Granola
and more. Check it out at lennysnewsletter.com and
click Bundle. With that, I bring you Mayur Kamat.
This episode is brought to you by WorkOS. If
you're building a SaaS app, at some point,
your customers will start asking for enterprise
features like SAML authentication and SCIM
provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in, making
it fast and painless to add enterprise features
to your app. Their APIs are easy to understand, so
that you can ship quickly and get back to building
other features. Today, hundreds of companies are
already powered by WorkOS, including ones you
probably know like Vercel, Webflow and Loom.
WorkOS also recently acquired Warrant,
the fine-grained authorization service. Warrant's
product is based on a groundbreaking authorization
system called Zanzibar, which was originally
designed for Google to power Google Docs and
YouTube. This enables fast authorization
checks at enormous scale while maintaining
a flexible model that can be adapted to even
the most complex use cases. If you're currently
looking to build role-based access control or
other enterprise features like single sign-on,
SCIM or user management, you should consider
WorkOS. It's a drop-in replacement for Auth Zero
and supports up to one million monthly
active users for free. Check it out at
workOS.com to learn more. That's workOS. com.
Many of you are building AI products, which
is why I am very excited to chat with Brandon
Foo, Founder and CEO of Paragon. Hey, Brandon.
Hey, Lenny. Thanks for having me.
Integrations have become a big
deal for AI products. Why is that?
Integrations are mission-critical
for AI for two reasons. First,
AI products need contacts from their customer's
business data such as Google Drive files,
Slack messages or CRM records. Second, for AI
products to automate work on behalf of users,
AI agents need to be able to take action
across these different third-party tools.
Where does Paragon fit into all this?
These integrations are a pain to build.
That's why Paragon provides an embedded
platform that enables engineers to ship
these product integrations in just days
instead of months across every use case
from rag data ingestion to agentic actions.
I know from firsthand experience
that maintenance is even harder
than just building it for the first time.
Exactly. We believe product teams should focus
engineering efforts on competitive advantages,
not integrations. That's
why companies like You.com,
AI21 and hundreds of others use Paragon
to accelerate their integration strategy.
If you want to avoid wasting months
of engineering on integrations that
your customers need, check out
Paragon at useparagon.com/Lenny.
Mayur, thank you so much for being
here, and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you. This is super
exciting. Thank you for having me.
I want to start with your time at Binance.
You've worked at Google, you worked at Microsoft,
you worked at a company called Agoda. Now,
you're at N26. I imagine Binance was the most
unique place that you've worked at, and I've also
never heard much about what it's like to work at
a company like Binance. I was just looking them
up on Wikipedia. I saw they started in China,
they moved to Japan, they moved to Malta. Now,
they have no official headquarters. What was
it just like working at Binance? How was it
most unique from other places you've worked?
Yeah. Maybe just a background for Binance,
because I think a lot of people have heard it,
some in positive connotations, some not so much.
The scale of Binance is pretty mind-boggling. Just
to give the history, they started in 2017
as a crypto exchange, when there were other
crypto exchange on the market for years, like
Coinbase. Within six months, they became number
one. That's unprecedented. That's like launching
a search engine today, and then, six months later,
beating Google. Then they went within five years
to at a peak valuation of somewhere like $400
billion or so with 2000 employees. That's zero
to $400 billion in five years. It's at a scale
that's never been done before. Google couldn't
do it, Facebook, none of the names that you hear.
It's remarkable. When I was there as the head of
product, my top line KPI was the trading volume,
and my monthly KPI was in trillions of dollars.
Just the scale was mind-boggling. We had teams of
10, 20 people running multi-billion dollar
profit businesses. That brings in with it,
first, how did they do that to that scale, and
two, what kind of culture requires to keep that
running? Both are very fascinating. I think
we could spend a lot of time talking about it,
but the truly interesting thing, the first
one is, you can't do this by having a
traditional log structure. CZ, the founder
and CEO at one point had 55 direct reports,
and his direct reports had about the similar ones.
For a large portion of the history of the company,
there was just one level between the individual
employees and the CEO. That leads to an extreme
level of decision-making and execution. You cannot
have one-on-ones when you have 55 direct reports,
so there's a culture of one-to-many
and doing that as often as possible.
The leadership team, for example, met every
day, and because the leadership team was spread
across the world, we met at 11:00 PM when I was in
Singapore every day. That includes the weekends,
holidays. The leadership team was there, 11:00
PM every single day, which meant that none of
the decisions were blocked for more than 24 hours.
Most of them, we made it on chat even within those
24 hours, but if there was something big, it was
escalated, decided. We executed largely based on
this concept that I now take with me. I call it
running products via daily meeting. We would pick
a owner for something really urgent at the nightly
leadership call. Then that owner would be expected
to have all hands on deck for however long that
problem is every single day and then report the
updates on the daily call. Some of these were
really massive topics, like how do we get 15
financial licenses in 15 countries in the next
three months? It wouldn't be at a scale that was-
You've got 24 hours.
Yes, and people did it. It's extremely interesting
to see that when you have really smart people,
you give them really hard problems, you have no
constraints on what can you need to solve them,
whether it's money, people, except time.
Time is always at a premium. People can move
mountains in a small amount of time. That extreme
ownership culture, I think, probably was the most
fascinating part of working at Binance that I've
now tried to take. There's some good parts of it
in terms of attention to detail, being able to
pick certain areas and own it, irrespective of
what your title is and how many people report to
you. There are certain downsides in terms of the
amount of randomization that it can cost teams,
especially if it's not super well-thought through.
I'm trying to see what are the great parts of
that that I can bring to different roles, but that
concept of daily meeting, if there's something
super urgent, how can you own it directly and run
it yourself, where you are in the details so your
team knows that they need to be in the details,
and then be able to execute that. That's probably
the most fascinating. There's several war stories.
I was there for two years and the amount of
interesting stories that happened during that time
is a lot, but then, maybe I can follow up
later if you have specific questions there.
I would love to hear a war story. This is
definitely as interesting as I was expecting
it to be. Just what I'm hearing so far is just
things that worked well for them to operate at
this insane pace and scale is the entire
leadership team meeting every single day,
11:00 PM your time. Hopefully, at better
times for other folks around the world.
There's some people in Sydney,
Australia, so it was 1:00 AM for them.
Good grief. This idea of a flat
structure, yeah, it's interesting,
because I imagine that's not necessarily
great for other reasons and then this idea
of being in the details. Let me ask about that,
actually. What does that actually look like? I
think a lot of people, a lot of leaders
are like, "Oh, yeah. I'm in the details,
we should be in the details." What does that
actually look like in real life at Binance?
Let me give an example. One of the areas, when I
joined, one of the biggest product problem we had
was, crypto before was fairly unregulated, so you
could just sign up with an email address or even
just a wallet and start trading. There was almost
zero friction. Then it suddenly became regulated,
where you would almost have a full KYC flow like
a bank. That just meant that the conversion rate
dropped from, let's say, 100% to 2%. Now we had
to solve this problem. This was the daily meeting
level problem. It's okay if you're operating
in one country. You can do it easily. If you're
operating in 200 countries where there's not even
a standard for what a document acceptance criteria
might look like, now you have a significantly
larger problem. You cannot say, "Let's work
with the KYC vendor and do the onboarding."
We had to, literally have this, the top
50 countries, the top 10 document types,
this spreadsheet of basically 500 cells,
the conversion rate at each level. Then we are
looking at, okay, a passport in Kazakhstan has
very low level of conversion. What can we do
about that? Do we need a new vendor? Do we need
better imaging technology? Do we need a new SDK
from a vendor? Then we go cell by cell based on,
let's say if I was running a typical product
team, I would say, okay, let's just look at
maybe the top 90 percentile of our users, but this
was Binance and then CZ is like, "No user left
behind. Even that one user in Congo is important
because this is financial inclusion for them."
Then all of those 500 sales matter, no matter
how low their impact to the conversion rate is.
That's a little bit of Binance flavor there.
It's extreme customer focus and it doesn't really
matter. Customers are not a number. It's a person
at the end of the screen and we care about them,
so you would need to know, you would get questions
like, why is the driver's license acceptance rate
in Kenya falling suddenly? When you have,
and that's just one piece of the problem in
a large product with 80 different products. You,
of course, cannot do it for every single product,
but the concept of, what is the most leveraged
decision you could be working on right now? If
it is for your growth, it's the onboarding, then
you'd better know exact every single screen of
the flow, why is there a drop-off and what are
your teams doing for it? That level of detail,
and you just do it on different products
at different parts of your journey.
I imagine there's people listening where
they're like, there's the team responsible
for the onboarding flow and the KYC flow of
their product and it's so hard. They're like,
oh, there's all these problems with our
flow. Imagine that for 100 different
versions of the flow across 100
different countries. Good God.
And documents. It gets very
tricky. It gets very tricky,
but we also had resources.
At one point in time we said,
we had a team of 20 people working on KYC and we
said, "For the next three months, we want 500."
Which has its own downsides, too.
Has its downside, but if you're running
in this extreme mode and you're less,
not as worried about just the team's stress
and personal development aspects of it,
you're just purely looking at the execution
of the product, there's a surprising amount of
power that comes with it. This was probably the
second time in my career where I had that, wow,
you can do this because in other companies it
would take years to do it. The first one was,
this is going back at Google. I remember
I joined Google. It was my first day at
onboarding and I was the product manager
for Gmail for mobile, for sync. I was in
my onboarding meeting when they pulled me out
and said, "Hey, we have an issue. The service
is down and Wall Street Journal is writing
an article that Google, Microsoft, Apple
not working together causing the service to go
down, so we need you in this war room right now."
It was a bug in iOS 4. This is a long time ago,
which caused every single user to pull their
entire Gmail inbox, re-sync the whole inbox.
A bug on the Apple side is going to take two,
three weeks to fix, and it was causing 1000x
load to our servers. I remember Connie Wurz,
who was the Head of Infrastructure at Google,
and he's like, "Sure." He flipped a button and
there were 1000x servers that showed up
for the next two weeks. I was like, "Wow,
that is scale," right? This was my second
time feeling that wow moment where like, oh,
we just put 500 people in and solve the problem.
It's less about having the 500 people and being
able to maneuver them that quickly. I don't think
I've been able to do that at any other company.
To close the loop on some of these radical
ways of working, this idea of 50 reports
per person and this idea of caring about a
person in Congo not being able to sign up,
do you think that's a good idea? Do you take
those in the way you work now or is it just,
in this particular situation it's
important? Other places, maybe not.
There are several preconditions. One is you're
growing really fast. The growth for the employees
comes just from seeing problems at scale that
are growing every day that it needs less of a
manager's attention to figure out what you need
to grow. The best way to grow in general is that
you work at a very fast-growing company. If
that's true, two, your people are extremely
well compensated, so they care about the KPIs
more than they care about what's the next stage
in my career and how do I get promoted?
Our bonus structure went from 0% to 500%,
so a lot of people didn't really care getting
a 10%, 20% pay. They just want to do incredible
work because they know they would be taken
care of. Three, it's a mission driven company,
still believe at the end of the day that
you're doing this just beyond the KPI.
At Binance, there was a very strong belief
that 80% of the world doesn't have access to
financial tools. They don't even have an access
to currency that they can trust. When we look at,
live in Europe or in US and we think about crypto,
it's largely about speculation or bitcoin. For
most of the world, they just need access to a
US dollar, stable coin and just knowing that my
currency is not getting deinflated because of
things beyond my control. Everyone having come
from these, a lot of our employees were across all
these countries, they had a very strong mission
belief that what we are doing will truly empower
billions of people. There's a power in that. A
lot of people go through, "Hey, I'm going to move
mountains because it's not just about the money,
it's just not about my career. It's about
doing something that will change the world."
Let's follow this thread on accelerating your
career, and talk about where you're at today,
N26. As you know, I've been doing a bunch
of research on which companies hire and
produce the best product managers.
I've done a couple passes at this,
and N26 has come up in the top five
of both ways of approaching this,
essentially which companies alumnis go on to do
the best in their career. N26 is way up there. I
want to come at this from a couple directions.
One is what N26 as a company does to hire and
incubate the best people, but also just you
personally, what your advice is to people
and how you help them become great PMs. Let's
actually start in that second bucket. What is the
most common and most impactful career advice that
you share with product managers that you manage,
that you find most helps them move ahead in
their career and get unstuck in their career?
I think the number one thing I shared before,
the best thing you can do is find companies
that are growing fast because it compounds your
learning at a much faster interval. Just the
basic compound interest formula, even if your
interest rate is low, if you're compounding
daily versus compounding yearly, after two
years, you will be at a whole different stage
at the end point. Companies that are growing
fast just lets you get that learning much,
much quicker. I remember joining Microsoft first
in my career. Some of the products I worked on
during my internship had not shipped till I left
Microsoft three, four years later. That's a very,
very low rate of compounding. Microsoft's a whole
different company now 20 years later, thankfully.
Then you contrast that something like Binance
where every day or every hour, every minute you're
shipping something and then learning from it.
The faster you can compound your learning,
the faster you will grow. The second piece
generally is, you need to optimize for what you're
great at. Now having two kids, I'm fairly in the
fact that your strengths get defined very, very
early, right? I'm looking at my nine-year-old and
twelve-year-old, and they have a whole different
set of strengths. If you're 25 years old early in
your career, it's very hard at that point to say,
"Oh, here are all my weaknesses and I need to
improve on those." A lot of the career feedback
typically tends to be around, "Hey, here are the
things you need to be better at. Why don't you
do more of that stuff, right?" Formally in the
camp that you need to know what you're great at,
what are your superpowers, and you need to
find jobs where success is determined by
how much of that superpowers you get to use.
Early in your career, you can't get away with
the fact that there's some stuff you're not going
to be great at and you just have to manage around
it. If you get higher up in your career, then
it gets easier because you can build a team that
complements your strengths, but again, if you're
early in your career, find places that, if you're
a great creative person, if you can look at a
product and think of 100 things you can do better,
you are always about what's the next best
thing and how quickly can I implement it,
you need to be working in teams that have a
high experimentation culture. You need to be
working in growth teams in large companies. If
you work in a FinTech company on a compliance
side project or launching a new business
vertical, you're going to struggle, right?
On the same time, if you have extreme management
structured thinking, you have great stakeholder
management, you have high EQ, you should work in
teams where there is a large amount of complex
people management and process management.
You would struggle in a growth team where the
expectation is you're doing things really quickly.
I would look at first very introspectively,
what are my true strengths? What do I, and
then look at jobs where that has a much
higher profile of winning. Thirdly, largely
I would say do not optimize for compensation,
especially early in your career. If you're truly
on a track to become an executive someday or found
your own company and make it successful, you will
find that the compensation is so much backloaded
that you would make 90% of your compensation
in the last five years of your career,
so optimizing for 10%, 20% early in your career.
If you have two jobs, I would rank in your first
15 years of your career, I would say do not look
at the compensation. Then the last one, this was
strange. I never thought about this longer, but
now I think this is probably the most interesting
advice I can give people is determine very early
in your career if you truly want to be a C-level
someday, you want to be an executive someday,
because it's almost like if you're ambitious and
successful, you enter product management. You are
in top of your, it's almost an expectation of you
that you would become that and you'd never really
challenge or question yourself, is this the thing
that needs me, that I need to do to get there? Is
there something I'm going to truly enjoy? Not just
the destination but the process to get there.
A lot of people think that and they make
suboptimal decisions based on that. There's
incredible careers you can build and incredible
lives that you can live by just being great
at what you do, doing more of that stuff. You
end your career maybe as a director, maybe as a
group product manager, but throughout the stuff,
you have built a holistic life that doesn't
revolve around your work and gives incredible
meaning to you, or you can be saying,
you know what? Work is a huge part of my
identity. Somebody asks me what wakes me up in
the morning and what gives me that energy? It's my
work. I can't separate my identity from your work.
Then maybe you should pursue that C-level path
because it'll truly be fulfilling and you would
be able to make those challenges and sacrifices
that are going to be asked of you to make that.
If you can calibrate that early and have that
true conversation with yourself like, "Yes, I want
to go down that path and I want to do," you would
make different career choices. In that path, I
would definitely say don't look at compensation.
There are two jobs. Look at the three things. Is
it going to give me high compounding of learning?
Is it high overlap with my strengths, and am I
going to have a lot of fun doing it? If you have
fun doing it, then it becomes a virtuous cycle
and you do more of it and you're great at it.
On the question of decide if you
want to be a CPO, essentially-
Do you want... Decide if you
want to be a CPO essentially,
is the, the implication there is,
if you do, that's a big sacrifice,
you're going to be stressed. Work-life balance
is worse. Is that kind of the core question?
No, no, no, absolutely not.
Okay.
Absolutely not.
It's like, if you truly enjoy your work and what
you're doing, it won't feel like a sacrifice. When
you're constantly, when you look at a new product,
you're walking down the street, you see a new
product, you're on the app store, you see a new
product, and you're like, "Oh, this is cool. Oh,
look how they're doing the onboarding. Oh, look
how the app store entry looks." If that truly
fills you up, it fills your cup, every moment
you're looking at why things can be better,
how you can be better, how a certain thing...
You would, the sacrifice will not feel like
sacrifices. It'll not feel like you're working
long hours. You'll not feel, hey, when you're
talking to PMs and giving them some guidances,
when you're building things, when you're
recruiting new people, all that stuff, it fills
your cup, it doesn't drain it. Then you would
have incredible fun on the journey. So, it's less
about that your sacrifices or work-life balance.
The moment you start having those conversations,
you are probably not on that track. You should
not be on that track because the moment the
word work-life balance comes, I think Jeff
Bezos has this thing that he hates the word
because it means there are opposite things
that need to be balanced, right? It needs to be
work-life awesomeness or something like that,
where every moment is awesome whether you're
working or you're living. But for some people,
that comes naturally because that's how they're
wired. And those people should absolutely pursue
it because it would be incredibly fulfilling, and
the things that are challenging would also feel
not as onerous. Whereas for everything
else, it would feel like a sacrifice,
could feel like something you need to balance. And
then you would, again, even if you're great at it,
you're not going to have fun doing it, and
at some point you will not be great at it.
For folks that are PMs today, there's
almost an implication their career
is heading towards CPO eventually.
That's kind of the ladder they're on.
What are the, say, top three most
common other options you've seen,
other paths you've seen of folks that you
manage, so that people can think about, "Okay,
I don't need to maybe just keep climbing this
ladder. There's these other directions I can go."
I mean the number one, and that's I think
back to your original question on N26,
if you work in incredibly high growth companies,
especially FinTech where there's a higher,
people end up being founders because it's probably
a whole different kind of track we can go down on,
the founding your own company is probably the most
kind of obvious/exciting alternate path. The only
thing I ask there is, again, the same question,
what you're good at and what you love doing. The
challenges with founding a company is a large
portion of running a company has nothing to do
with building a great product, especially as the
company gets bigger. I've worked for founders now
for 17 of my 20-year career, right. So, even at
Google and stuff, Nikhil was my boss at Google,
used to be a founder, and the CEOs now, the
thing they tell me when they hire me is,
"I wish I had your job," because that's what
I used to do. That's what I have loved doing,
and now I spend 90% of my time doing stuff
that is not the stuff that I truly enjoy.
But folks enjoy building stuff as a PM, there's
a lot of things you don't have control over,
and you feel like, "Hey, that's stopping me from
growing. That's what's topping me from truly
enjoying." Founding is a great path. You have
that control now, you own the decision-making.
There's rarely times you can say, "Hey, this
did not work because of that person." Right?
If you're constantly hitting that, then
founding is a great path for you because then
you have the ball control for better or worse.
The other is just, I mean, it's less about being
a CPO and just growing your breadth and your
depth instead of just the ladder, right? So
you are incredibly, either getting specialized in
a specific domain where there is now enough value
for you to separate yourself from the pack,
whether it's, like in FinTech, now we have
folks who are onboarding experts with KYC. We have
people who are fraud experts, [inaudible 00:29:37]
who have really great understanding of how card
schemes work and how MasterCards work and where
can we get the right incentives for the user.
The folks who are experts on customer loyalty
and retention. You build that domain expertise
and then you realize that everyone needs that,
right? And that could be an incredible way to
specialize. So, you may lead growth at certain
team even though you're not a CPO, right? So,
that's kind of the second way of doing it.
And the third one, again, just not to knock it
out, is you realize that work is not going to
be my big part of my identity. My identity is,
who am I as a parent? Who am I as a community
member? Who am I as a son to my parents? Who
am I as an artist or a contributor? And that's
what my death is going to be, a well-rounded
person. And a job is great, I'm great at it,
but I'm going to do it as much as it's needed.
And the value and meaning, the top part of the
Maslow's pyramid comes from everything but work.
And then< you just lead kind of a balanced life
because then work is a certain portion of
it and the rest kind of fills the picture.
So, just to summarize these four really good
pieces of advice for how to essentially keep
your career going and get unstuck and accelerated,
is work at companies that are really high growth
because your learnings will compound, and also the
network you build, you didn't even mention that,
that becomes really valuable because especially
if the company does well, sometimes companies grow
really well and there's extra benefits there,
but even if they aren't, you still earn a lot.
Absolutely. Well, let's say N26, one of
the reasons why they have so many founders
is the fact that it was a category defining,
like we were the first kind of mobile bank,
right? So, a lot of the problems we saw in
early days, nobody else saw them, right? So,
every product manager had to solve it for the
very first time in history. And that kind of
is a whole different level of kind of trial by
fire. Same thing with [inaudible 00:31:44]. They
both started about the same time. Those are the
companies that show up in the top rankings because
you did this before anybody could do it, and you
learn by literally moving mountains. I think two
is also the fact that you see, we have this whole
PayPal mafia. When you see this early success,
everyone sees it together. So, when they go,
they have that network, as you said, built-in.
These are, maybe it's a product manager who
starts a company, but maybe there is a business
development manager who has also started
this company and now you can collaborate
and have partnerships. So, that success, a mutual
success, which a lot of early startup see, that
creates kind of a more denser network than you
working at a large company where not all of you
see the success at the same time. And 3Ls
comes down to the founders as well. They're
incredibly mission-driven founders. I always
find it super admiring now when I look back
at Valentine and Max here at N26, or I look at
CZ. They have reached from a whatever metric you
can define of success, whether it's the size of
the company, whether it's the personal network,
beyond whatever anybody would think success
means, right? And then, to wake up every day
and to do this hours and hours single day,
every single day, you are driven by a whole.
These are the voyagers of, these are the folks
who would go explore new planets in the future
or the folks who sailed out on the seas in
1600s to discover new land. That being access
to these people directly is extremely, extremely
empowering. You not just learn from it, but you
get inspired by it. If you have an X definition
of success, now your definition of success is 10x,
you automatically push the boundaries more. So, I
think those two things are, or those three things,
early start, category defining companies,
mutual success and creation of dense networks,
and just being inspired by incredibly,
incredibly successful and talented people.
You pointed out this really interesting
insight that I forgot to mention with
the list of companies that seem to hire and
create the strongest PMs. There's a lot of
FinTech representation there, and I think you
touched on why that might be the case because
all these problems are extremely complicated and
never been solved and they're solving at scale.
Here's the thing about FinTech, which
is probably the most interesting is,
FinTech, you have two customers. You have your
usual customers and you have your regulator,
and you need to keep both of them happy.
And usually, what makes one happy, it makes
the other one less happy, right? So, you are
constantly dealing with trade-offs. In most PMs,
in most companies you have some trade-offs, but
they're not existential. Whereas in FinTech,
every trade-off is existential. When you found
a company, every trade-off is existential. You
may not exist as a business if you
make a wrong decision. In FinTech,
a lot of the PMs see that day in day out,
and that probably kind of conditions them to
a whole different level of juggling balls
than you would be a PM at other company.
Yeah, that's such a good point. Just really good
stakeholder management influence dealing with
all these trade-offs. I think that's a really
good point. I'm going to come back to the
strength stuff because that's really important
and I've been meaning to come back to it. So,
just to reflect back, the four things you
pointed out are really what you want to look
for to accelerate your career. Companies that are
growing really fast, working on things that you're
good at, and finding a role that leverages your
strengths versus things that you're not good at.
Not optimizing for comp really is such a good
point there. Your point essentially is you'll
make most of your comp later, probably
the 50%. The second half of your career,
you probably make, I don't know, 10 times more
than you make the first part of your career.
And so, optimize for the future cop, not
today's comp. And then this idea of making sure,
ask yourself, do you want to be CPO? Do you
want to go down the C-suite route or do you
want to maybe probably plan to start a company,
something else? And that informs the role you're
in. Coming back to the strength stuff, how do
people figure out their strengths? Do you have
any advice for someone sitting around, they're
like, "What am I actually good at? I don't know."
So, there's several ways to do it. I remember
I read this book, this was, I don't think it
shaped my understanding of it because I was
already operating in that mode, but it used
to be called Now Discover Your Strengths. I think
now it's called Strength Finder 2.0. It's still 20
years old now, but there's a lot more newer ways
to do it. There are two things I have done and
they're both kind of, I'm not sure how accessible
they are, but I'll give you the examples. So,
at a Agoda, we used to pay a psychologist
$5,000 for every single PM we interview,
right? So, after you finish your PM rounds,
we would send you to this psych assessment.
It would be a six-hour psych assessment and
they would tell me what your strengths are,
not just that it would be an IQ component.
So, we would know what percentile you are, and not
just like an IQ score like Einstein or not, but IQ
score across different, across pattern recognition
or structured thinking, across numerical ability,
verbal ability, right? So, a lot of people say
they hire the smartest people. At Agoda, we
literally hired the smartest people because
we paid the psychologist a lot of money to tell
whether they're smart or not. But other than that,
they also give you your strengths and weaknesses.
It used to be called, I know the company still
around, it's called Q4, and it's called Q4
because they had this four quadrants on two axes,
one is on dominance and one is on warmth, right?
So, you want people who are high dominance,
high warmth in the 4 quadrant, and that as you can
realize, if you also want smart people, to find
those who land in that quadrant is literally
looking through a needle through a haystack.
But when I, I almost didn't do it. I was like,
this is like I've been doing products for 15
years, this is insulting that I need to go do
a six hour... The only reason I did it at that
time was my son was four and a half years
old and I was teaching him, because you're
going to go to kindergarten, I was starting do
some math with him, and then in six months he
knew all the math that I knew. He was solving
quadratic equations and stuff. And we thought,
oh, we have a genius in the house. We got to
get him tested. So, we were testing him, and
that's the only reason I took this test because
I thought it would be interesting to understand
what this process looks like. But then when I
got the results, I was like, it was so spot on.
It was incredibly spot on in saying areas where
I would do well, areas where I would struggle and
need help. So, that's one way to do it. It's super
extreme. A little bit a year, two years ago, we
had the [inaudible 00:38:40]. CZ is good friends
with Ray Dalio. So, we had Ray Dalio come to our
executive offsite, and he walked us through how he
and his company does strengths assessment. So he
has a, that one is lot more accessible. I think it
costs like $50. You can go to, I think you search
for Ray Dalio's strengths, there's a website
that you can go and... The way it works, slightly
differently for executives because you do it, so
those are your components, tells you how good you
think you are, and then it has your leadership
team vote you on certain different aspects. So,
there's a two layer assessment, how good you think
you are and how good everybody else think you are.
And then, the overlap is where your true
strengths are. And as a CEO, I can say,
"Oh, Mayur is great at design. Everybody else
knows that Mayur is great at design. We should
give design problems to Mayur." Right? So, that's
another way of kind of... So, there's a scientific
way of doing this and it's gotten a lot better
since I read that book long time ago. Again,
if you're truly, truly curious, it doesn't take
that long and now it's a lot more accessible.
That's one way to do it. And it kind of separates
in terms of execution, in terms of structured
thinking, innovation and design, creativity,
stakeholder management, EQ. You get a little
bit of a more scientific picture on what your
strengths are. But this is also a simpler way.
As a PM, you do pretty much a large portion.
Everybody does the same few things, right?
You think you're designing the roadmap, you are
coming up with what you think is the product
strategy. There's a lot of time around just
managing engineers, making sure they do stuff.
There's stakeholder management, marketing,
compliance, whatever. There's launch and just
tracking data analytics. So, this part is true
for most PMs. Some jobs require more of one versus
the other. And you just know when you do these
things, which ones one you're truly great at and
you have a lot of fun doing, right? Maybe you just
don't like Jira and the ticket tracking and just
following people on that, and that's the worst
part of your job. Stay away from more structured
complex stakeholder management jobs. Or you find
that, hey, you do really well at that and somebody
ask you, "Hey, what are the 15 things we're
going to do next week to improve a conversion?"
That's where you kind of have a hard time, you
just sit down, spend hours thinking about it,
then maybe that's not your strength. And so over
time, you kind of build this self calibration on
areas that you have fun doing and
areas where you don't have. And then,
when you look at the next job, just try and gauge,
are they hiring me because I did really well at
some of the stuff that I didn't love doing?
And if that's what they're hiring you for,
probably you're not going to have a lot of
fun or high acceleration if you go there.
There's so much there. There's I think
an important point that I'll add,
and I'm curious if you agree. A lot of new people
or new people in their career, like, "Oh, I just
want to think about strategy. I'm going to think
about the big picture. I don't want to just sit
there and optimize the roadmap and be in Jira."
But it's actually, that's your job when you're
just starting out. You need to earn the right
to contribute to the vision, to the strategy.
There's one of the, and as a pre-conversation
we talk about contrary and view,
product strategy by definition seems like
a... This is going to be controversial.
Great.
Not really... Those two words feel very
at odds with each other for me. A product,
you have hypotheses and if you can test it, you
don't need a strategy. Right? If I say, "Hey,
if I build this and I know this will add this much
users and this time with this conversion rate,
this customer acquisition cost and this LTV,"
that's your hypothesis and you could test it
in the market very quickly. And if it works,
you have your strategy. Keep doing more of it.
Strategy is always keep doing more of it or don't
do it, right? That's all that is to strategy.
The key part is just figuring out which
one goes in which bucket. And if you're
really executing fast enough in a kind of
structured, experimentation-driven manner,
your strategy becomes a largely solved
problem. So, for most, and that's a challenge.
A lot of people think strategy is about looking
at Porter's [inaudible 00:43:18] forces, a lot of
slides, we're looking at some data and slicing
it and saying, "We need to go here or there."
All of it is largely in some sort of package
intuition. And the challenge with that is,
usually you go with the loudest voice in the
room. And if you're a junior in your career,
it's a very frustrating exercise because you
think you know the strategy better. But it's
all it is. It's a sense of package intuition, and
then the guy with the loudest, biggest title or
the loudest voice is going to go do it. It was
very early in my career, Jonathan Rosenberg,
he was the head of, he was the CPO at Google.
All the PMs reported to him. He was not called the
CPO back then. And he had this one thing he would
say all the time that, "Come to me with data. If
you come to me with ideas, we'll go with mine."
Right? That was the saying. You can come with
any ideas, we're just going to do what I think,
but unless you come with strong sense of proof to
override me. So again, strategy is a little bit
overrated for product. For market expansions,
for investments, for licenses, compliance,
there's several areas where it makes sense
and it's kind of useful. But for most product
managers, your strategy should be, how fast can
I go from hypothesis to data, right? The faster
you can go there, the easier your strategy gets.
That is certainly a hot take. So the idea here,
I'm curious how you operationalize this
with folks at N26. Is it just like,
"I don't need to see a whole strategy for the
year. Just give me, here's the plan, here's
what we're going to test, here's our hypothesis?"
Are you actually, what do you tell your PM team?
We use this tool. I'm going to give a shout-out
to Statsig because they're awesome. Vijay used
to run the experimentation at Facebook and
has this tool. There's several of those.
But if you're running proper experiments,
I just look at the Statsig dashboards,
right? And I'm looking at experiments, I'm looking
at what metrics they're moving, I'm looking at the
P-value, I'm looking at how quickly can they get
to statistical significance. And I'm like, "Oh,
this is working. Let's do more of these." Right?
So, now there's some areas where you can't do it,
like in compliance, in legal aspects,
in Europe, especially pricing. In US,
you can run pricing tests. In Europe, it's
a little bit different. So, those areas,
you would need to have a lot more kind of deeper
thinking, understanding of your cohorts. You're
coming up with more structured reason for why you
should do it, but you can't really test and know
within a couple of days or a couple of weeks
at max whether this was a good idea or not.
Those, if there are either irreversible decisions
or they're just extremely time-consuming to
find out, then do some pre-work. We look at
largely, find a lot of companies that really
look at data without looking at cohorts
that make completely bad decisions, right,
because if you look at your dashboard as a mixture
of users over 10 years, 20 years, even six months,
and they all behave differently. If you look
at a cohort level development of certain users,
you generally end up making better decisions. But
even over there, it's still lot more, there's a
lot of noise between the moment you start tracking
it than moment you start making decisions based
on it. The world has changed in that meantime. By
now, this was kind of a very foreign concept when
I brought this in. I'm like, oh, the conversions
down now, even though the product's done really
well because Bitcoin has crashed, right?
Nobody wants to go sign up for an Exchange
account. So, if you just measure pre and post, you
would think that you have done something wrong in
the product. If you measure it as an experiment,
you would know that, yeah, between the variant
and control, it's still doing great, even though
overall conversion is down. So largely, the more
you kind of, one of the first thing kind of doing
when I take on a role, the company already doesn't
have an experimentation culture. That's largely
why they hire me in the first place, right?
So, for now, the first thing is to say, how can we
bring it in? First, the kind of right culture, the
right incentives and the right tools. And then,
once it's set up, it gets a lot of fun. Get a lot
of fun for the PMs because you have democratized
performance for the product managers. And the
second thing, which I tell my PMs now, which is
truly kind of empowering if you think about it,
the challenge with being a product manager is
everybody thinks they can do their job, right? You
go to... The CFO might have an idea, the head of
kind of accounting has an idea. Anybody who uses
the product thinks they have ideas, right?
So, at some point in time, you're like,
what is my discipline? What is my science?
Nobody goes to the accounting guy and says,
"Hey, I have a great idea for how to cook
our books." Nobody does that because there's
a science behind it. There's a science for
financial forecasting. Even in technology,
a lot of the times people just don't go and
say, "Hey, just dump this thing and let's use
this code that the AI code generator has used."
Right? There's a little bit of science there.
Whereas in product, you largely find that it's
a combination of data and ideas and stuff, and
anybody thinks they can... The moment you build
experimentation, you'll now make it scientific,
right? Now, somebody comes up with an idea, say,
that's a bad idea. Here, this is why it's a bad
idea, because we have done this experiment six
times and it has failed across this user groups
at this exact level of impact created. So, it kind
of gives the PMs the kind of, hey, I'm not just
a general purpose technician, I'm a specialist
now. And it's extremely empowering once we can,
it takes a long time to move the team in that
direction. But once you get it there, the PMs
just, it's a natural kind of dopamine hit every
time you run an experiment and see more metrics.
I'm a huge fan of experimentation.
I think most guests on this podcast
are on your side of the debate. I feel like we
could do a whole podcast episode on just how
to create a culture of experimentation,
how to change culture. This episode is
brought to you by Vanta, and I am very
excited to have Christina Cacioppo,
CEO and co founder of Vanta joining
me for this very short conversation.
Great to be here. Big fan of
the podcast and the newsletter.
Vanta is a longtime sponsor of the show,
but for some of our newer listeners,
what does Vanta do and who is-
... show, but for some of our newer listeners,
what does Vanta do and who is it for?
Sure. So we started Vanta in
2018, focused on founders,
helping them start to build out their
security programs and get credit for
all of that hard security work with compliance
certifications like SOC 2 or ISO 27001. Today,
we currently help over 9,000 companies, including
some startup household names like Atlassian,
Ramp, and LangChain start and scale their
security programs and ultimately build trust
by automating compliance, centralizing
GRC, and accelerating security reviews.
That is awesome. I know from experience
that these things take a lot of time and
a lot of resources and nobody
wants to spend time doing this.
That is very much our experience, but before
the company. And to some extent during it,
but the idea is with automation with AI, with
software, we are helping customers build trust
with prospects and customers in
an efficient way. And our joke,
we started this compliance
company, so you don't have to.
We appreciate you for doing that and you
have a special discount for listeners,
they can get a thousand dollars
off Vanta at vanta.com/lenny.
That's V-A-N-T-A .com/lenny for $1,000
off Vanta. Thanks for that, Christina.
Thank you.
I want to come back to the question of what
N26 has done well to create and hire great
PMs. So you've spent a bunch of time
on here's career advice that I often
give and what has helps people most in their
career. Just to kind of close this thread,
is there anything N26 did or is doing
that either from the hiring perspective
or from training? I know you haven't been there
from the beginning, just like as a business,
as a company that they've done really well
that other companies may want to copy.
Some of it is just the hiring philosophy. One of
the advantages you get for being a big fish in a
small pond is you get to have your pick of the
cream of the crop. So in Europe here where we
don't have the same level of unicorn or decacorn
density you have in the Bay Area being one of
the first ones or the few ones, you do get a
little bit of that branding working in your
favor. So some portion of that is just the input.
If you're taking really smart people, very chance
at N26 they will stay smart. Two is again, the
level of problems that they work on are harder.
Just the print tech angle we mentioned and now
with this whole experimentation driven kind
of change that we made in the last year or so,
there's also a new kind of tool kit that they get,
especially if they're going for larger big
growth company as the next step of the career.
All the people companies I talk to, the amount
of companies that are truly world-class at
experimentation is so low that if you work in one
of these companies and you build this tool set,
you can build a whole career on this. You can
go to any other company and say, "This is what
I'm going to bring to the table." Because there's
no growth without, as I said, without compounding
wins faster. Nothing compounds wins faster than
experiments and there's no company out in the
world that says we don't want to grow. So that
is an incredible kind of brand that you can build
alongside with it. Then the third piece is just
the scale. One of the other interesting aspects of
banking is what I call a hundred percent product.
It's actually more than a hundred percent, they're
more bank accounts than human beings because a
lot of people have more than one bank account.
So you never run out of target addressable
market. It's as big as it can get, which
means that there's no upper bound on how much...
Because at some point if you're, I don't know,
building in kind of an AI code generator, your
market is capped that maybe developers or people
want to be developers. Or you're building, I don't
know, AWS, it's a massive market, but it's still
like all the company that need online hosting.
They look at banking everybody needs and the fact
that it's oldest or the second oldest, depending
on how risky you are or not... Or profession
known to man. It is a self-hedged product. When
things get tough on one side of our business,
the interest rates, let's say, go high, spending
goes down, but we make money on deposits. When
interest rates go down, spending increases,
so we make more your money on interchange,
[inaudible 00:54:36] investments. So it's a very
self-hedged business that lets you go through the
troughs and the peaks better than most companies.
And that understanding that how do you build
naturally hedged products is probably another
kind of reason why... It just influences how
you make decisions and how do you kind of scale
your core product portfolio. Just one example,
for about a year and a half ago, we were largely
year bank with a card and we were the first mobile
bank and that was a big enough market. But in the
last year or so, we have just fleshed out that
product portfolio. We have a big lending portfolio
now. We launched savings last year. We invested
heavily in savings because the interest rates
were high, was a super amazing tool to attract
new users by offering high interest rates.
But as the interest rates are going down now,
which is investing heavily in lending because
now you can get loans for lower prices,
which was super hard to get last year. So being
able to build products that complement the macro
also gives you that kind of additional
balancing act that you don't get in
typical single focus companies. So I think
it's a combination of few of those things,
being able to get great talent, being able
to train them now more so especially around
experimentation and just see how we can build
a product portfolio that complements each other
but also naturally hedges against each other, just
gives you a better, well-balanced way to operate.
I think this explains something really
interesting. As you were talking,
I realized that a lot of these companies
that produce the best PMs are to your point,
non-US based, but incredibly successful in their
location. And so it draws in the most talented
people in that region. So I know Intercom I think
technically is... So Intercom was number one on
this list of companies that produce the best PMs.
Intercom, Palantir, Revolut, and then N26, Chime,
Stripe, Dropbox were kind of at the top. And
four of those essentially, or three of those
are non... Intercom I think was Ireland for a lot
of their team is based in Ireland. Then Revolut is
the UK and then you guys. So it's interesting,
that explains some really interesting insights
of just be the best, be the big fish in a
small pond, draw in the best talent and then
work on really hard problems and be really
successful. There you go. There's a formula.
Yes, yes. It's very simple
when you put it that way.
Oh, man. Okay. You interestingly have
worked in a lot of different places. I
want to spend a little time here. So you've
worked in Europe, you've worked in Asia,
you worked in the US obviously. For someone
that is maybe thinking about moving out of
the US or maybe moving to the US, what
have you found are the big trade-offs?
Yeah, so I would say early career you want to
be in intensely talents dense areas for all the
reasons that we mentioned before. Finding the high
growth companies, finding the networks that will
make you successful. For general tech, there's no
better place than West coast of the US. Everybody
doesn't have the option, especially now with
the immigration policies and so forth. I mean
things were always hard. They seem extremely
harder now. So you may not have that option,
but if you do have that option, I would encourage
everyone, there's no better place than West Coast
to start your career. There's some exceptions,
like for crypto, I would say Dubai is very strong,
very great, has a really high density there. But
again, it's a very industry specific. Bangalore,
if you're Indian, has managed to recreate some
of the magic of Silicon Valley, not at the same
scale, but getting better. If you're in finance,
maybe there is London, Singapore, and Asia has
now at least not as much new innovation, but
each of the big companies has a presence there.
So at least secondary talent densities
there, those would be our options if US
is not available early in your career. And in
some ways it helps define you, right? If you
work at Microsoft or Google or OpenAI or some
of these companies that become brands later,
it's something you can take with you when going...
The second part of your question is if you decide
to move, having that experience and that brand
and that kind of achievements there can help
you find great opportunities elsewhere. I mean,
I've been a little bit privileged that some of
these opportunities I found me like N26 here in
Europe or Binance before in Asia where I wasn't
really in that super talent dense area in the
first place. But luck's not a great strategy.
So if you're planning for it, I would say build
your early career in the US. Honestly, when we
moved to Thailand 2018, at that point, I didn't
think I was making a great professional decision.
We were just struggling in the US with both me
and my wife working. Both our kids in Seattle were
tiny. My daughter had asthma at that time and she
was just constantly sick. And it was a struggle
for us to kind of manage both work and life. And
when I talked to Agoda, I had never heard of the
company and the only reason I ended up taking
the job was like, hey, Bangkok's a hot place. My
daughter might not have asthma there and we might
have some help in the house. So we could probably
balance some of the things that are really not
adding value to our life right now. And that was
the hypothesis there that I can do a lot more on
work because I was literally not able to focus as
much on it, everything else that was happening.
And as I said, everything on an experimentation
that we just hit a home run on all the hypothesis.
My daughter, the heat cured her asthma.
Just having a support structure allowed us
just as a family to spend a lot more time
with each other and allowed me a lot more time
to work and be on my career when I'm not doing
dishes and not doing laundry and not throwing out
the trash and not mowing the lawn. There's just
so much hours that show up in the day that you
could be doing things that you're great at and
add to your career. And then Agoda just turned out
to be almost like a bootcamp for understanding how
an experimentation based product culture might
work. Because before that I worked at Google,
I worked at startups. My [inaudible 01:01:31]
claim to fame was building big stuff and Agoda
just taught me a lot of the growth comes with
incredibly small things done faster. So it's
part of Booking Holdings. So if you heard of
Booking.com, it's a $170 billion company. And
what's interesting is that 10 years ago it was a
$10 billion company which sold flights, hotels,
and cars. 10 years later it still sells flights,
hotels, and cars, it's a $ 170 billion company.
Oh, wow.
It's an incredible growth story. And
that tells you you really don't need
from a strategy perspective to do
something completely different if
you can truly compound your growth by
optimizing every single thing really,
really well. So there are the pros that
come with, as I said, when you move,
most of the time you're building products that
are global, especially if you're based in the US.
Very few times you're building product that
just work in the US. Now, that's not true for
a lot of the countries. Like in India, a lot of
products are only designed for Indian market,
a lot of products in China only designed for
Chinese market, but from the US you're designing
product for the world and a lot of the times
you don't experience the same constraints or you
don't empathize with the user at the same level
because you just haven't lived that user's life.
So in terms of just being able to calibrate
yourself on what a global product might look like,
being able to live in different places and
understanding some of these constraints first
hand, definitely a pro. As I said, especially if
you have built that early reputation, you get to
work at some of the best companies when you go
abroad. And so there's a hit to compensation,
at least initially for sure. Nobody pays anywhere
close, especially here in Europe. But as I said
before, don't optimize for compensation early in
your career or even middle part of your career.
So if you follow that advice, it'll not matter
because you will have kind of something unique
to offer. Even if you come back to the US
later having worked in different... Having
understanding, especially if you're in FinTech
where the actual laws are different in different
countries and that one you truly do not appreciate
working in the US. Even at Google and stuff, when
we would launch products, I would be like, oh,
the lawyers, they're just making life difficult.
But the many of now have a true appreciation of
how different the world truly is. It just makes
you a better stakeholder when you talk to the
legal team, when you talk to compliance team,
when you talk to marketing. So I think those are
all the pros. The compensation could be the con.
The other big con is that today, if you're in
Silicon Valley, I spent 15 years in Seattle,
I worked at four companies, I could change
jobs and stay in Seattle because there's enough
companies there. You're not going to run a ceiling
at some point, in Bay Area, there's no ceiling,
right? You can keep growing. The challenge now is
that if I'm in Bangkok and I'm working at Agoda,
at some point I need to find a new job or
because let's say I'm at the CPO level,
I want to be CEO now. Agoda already has a CEO,
so I need to find, be a CEO somewhere else. Guess
what? That company is not going to be in Bangkok.
Now I have to move and move my whole family
to Singapore, which I did. Then you hit somewhere
over there or then you hit another ceiling,
now you need to move back or go somewhere else
with Thailand, which I did. And then you're like,
oh, maybe there's a great opportunity in Europe
which would give you a whole different scale. Then
you need to move to Spain, which I did. So at some
point your family's like, what's happening? It
turned out to be what turned out to be one step to
go from A to B is now just a every year journey.
So that's something to calibrate, especially
later in your career that it's extremely hard
if you like the job and don't like the location or
vice versa, 'cause they usually come as a package
deal now. We see this in Bangkok now where
there's not that many great tech companies,
and if you're at Agoda and you're doing
really well, but it's just one company,
you just don't have options. And especially
if you love Bangkok, which is a great city,
probably my vote for the best place to live in
the world, that's a struggle. You love the city,
but if you need to move your career
ahead, you need to go somewhere else.
So interesting. I feel like Thailand is
very popular right now with White Lotus.I
think White Lotus had the most views of any
show or some crazy... It was very popular.
I feel like there's a lot of tourism
coming to Thailand more than they've had.
Yes, yes.
Yeah. I want to come back to one piece of
advice that we were chatting about before we
started recording that I think might be helpful to
people, which is, and this is kind in a different
direction, but I want to make sure we touch on
it, is Shreyas Doshi's point about leverage. I
know this is something that you think a lot about.
He has this really good advice and we'll point to
the episode if people want to dig deeper around
finding the highest leverage opportunities for
you to work on as a PM. Can you just share that
advice for folks that haven't heard this before?
This is true for no matter what level of
career you are in, but you have a finite
amount of time and largely you have more problems
than you have time to solve them. The question is
which ones you work on. And this becomes even
harder, let's say you're a CPO now because all
of them are important, otherwise they will not
come to you in the first place. The question is,
which one do you work on? And the principle is
simple. You work on problems that have a 10X
positive or a negative impact. I mean the number
can be 10, 5, 300, depending on finance it would
be a hundred, some companies might be three. And
in most FinTech companies one of two problems,
it's a growth problem or a compliance problem
because both of them can have a negative or
positive 10X impact and that's what you focus
on. That's what you spend bulk of your time.
What was interesting for me, my first executive
roles, that was Google, I was a product manager.
I joined what was White Pages back then as a VP
of product. I was my first kind of... And White
Pages, Alex Allgood, Seattle, founding legend,
three companies, all unicorns now. Incredible,
very good personal friend and mentor. What was
truly interesting when I joined it, they're like,
"Okay, this is your desk, this is the product
area. So we had two offices, this is when
everybody worked in office five days a week." And
I'm like, "Okay, where does Alex sit?" And he's
like, "Oh, he's sitting with accounting." And I'm
like, I didn't think about it because I thought
his office is near accounting. Then I find out
he doesn't have office, he has a floating desk.
So all the other desks were fixed, but he had a
movable desk and he would move his desk to one of
the departments, which I think had the highest
leverage opportunity. And he would sit there
at that desk when that department till that
either problem was solved or the opportunity
was realized, and then he would literally move his
desk and then go to product or tech or finance.
And that was his way of... You could literally
visualize him working on the highest leverage
problem by his desk moving. And then that combines
that with what we talked before about details and
a little bit, I think I didn't mention it
about the humility that you need to have to
be working in the detail. A lot of the times,
especially later in your career, you're like,
hey, this is beyond me. This is below me.
Why do I need to do that? I have so many
PMs or data analysts or somebody should do it.
Why would I do it? And that was kind of again,
just a quick story there. I remember we were
trying to figure out our growth channels and
we found out that, hey, we are kind of really
tapping out on paid, on social, on referrals,
but SEO was something we just hadn't worked on
for a while. We're building a caller ID app and
what we wanted to do was when somebody types a
phone number in Google, we want to be the first
link to say, hey, is this a spam call or not?
Or whose number it is. And if we could then we
could get them to download our app. That was the
hypothesis. So I present at the executive team
meeting to Alex, like, "Hey, I have a team. I want
to hire a product manager focused purely on SEO
and because I think that's one of our highest
leverage areas right now." And Alex is like,
"Hey, the whole White Pages, I built based on SEO.
People who type people's name and the first thing
used to be a White Pages link. I'm one of the best
people in the world to work on SEO." I'm like,
"Yeah. So?" He's like, "Let me run this product."
I'm like, "Okay, what do you mean?" He's like,
"No, no, I will be the product manager for
this for however long you need it." I'm like,
"How's [inaudible 01:10:54]?"
"They don't worry about it. Just
tell me about the engineers." So again, he
moved his desk to where that product team sat,
and for the next three months he was the product
manager on that scrum. So he would come to my
product team meetings, give us update on what's
happening with the SEO scrum, and then an hour
later I would be in the leadership meeting giving
my update to him, and truly he was operating
it saying, this is high leverage area for the
company, high leverage for my yards. It should
be high leverage for me. I'm the best person to do
it. I'm going to be in the details and do it. CZ,
same at Binance, there were a lot of products that
he would just sit on himself. There were very few
people at Binance who would say no to CZ, but one
of my lead PMs who worked on the products that CZ
worked on, he would tell them no all the time.
They would just baffle all the other executives,
how is he saying no to CZ and none of us are doing
it? Hey, that was his product area that CZ was
working on, and there was that mutual respect
there that, hey, we know this thing and he is
going to say no to me because probably not a good
idea. So that humility and attention to detail is
required to work on the high leverage problems.
A lot of the high leverage problems are not,
as I said, not strategy decisions. They're not
language markets to go after and stuff. A lot of
them are like, why is this thing not working
as well as it needs to be? And a lot of time
the devil is in the details and you need
to be over there. I think combining that,
knowing what is high leverage or not, and two,
both having the humility and the patience to
be able to go dig deeper and solve that.
Some of them are quick ones. Like if I'm
looking today at, let's say how many of our signed
up users convert into a long-term monthly daily
active user, that could be something I focus
on for a month. Because we're running a lot
of experiments on early onboarding screens, early
rewards, early incentives, early loyalty program,
and at some point it might be like, oh, the
team's got it. I've given all my... What I could
do there. It's functioning. We have great PMs.
I trust their execution on this. Let me just go
focus on some of the compliance challenges that
we have or fraud issues that we have in France.
Those kind of being able to kind of...
The only way that works for me is I keep
a very three calendar because you cannot do this
without that. If you have hundreds of meetings,
hundreds of one-on-ones daily standards, a lot of
recurring meetings, you just can't find time to go
work on high leverage problems. So that would be
my kind of other stuff is you should have plenty
of open spaces on your calendar. A full calendar
is a badge of shame, not a badge of honor.
These are awesome stories. Just the
metaphor of the moving desk is so good.
That's the epitome of a... Like what you're
describing is what people now call founder mode,
where the founder just goes in the details
working on the problem. Brian Chesky actually
did this at Airbnb while I was there. He
took on a new product and was like mini CEO,
essentially. I don't know if he'd called
himself the product manager 'cause I don't
think he loved product managers. He kind
of famously got rid of product managers,
which he didn't actually... But yeah, he
did that very much and he sat with the team,
kind of created a whole space for the team that he
was in. These are awesome stories and really good
example of a founder using their power to unblock
and finding the highest leverage opportunities.
To kind of start to close off our conversation,
I'm going to take you to a couple recurring themes
on this podcast, recurring segments on this
podcast. First, we're going to visit AI Corner
and in AI Corner I ask, what's a way
that you have found to use AI in AI tool,
a bunch of AI tools in your work to work more
efficiently to work to create better quality work?
I still haven't found a game
changer for me personally.
Something that I use right
now and I'm a little bit not-
He was like, now I am a little bit not sure that
am I not doing something right, what the other
people are, or I'm a little bit too jaded for it.
So we have Gemini across the work. So for meeting
notes and stuff, works great, especially
for folks who don't make it. We use a tool
called Writer for our copywriting and UX
teams, especially because we are operating
in Europe across several languages. So
being able to generate that very quickly,
especially for illustrations and in-app
messages and stuff that's been a,
several tools now. But Writer just has, the
copywriting market is really well done over there.
If you ask me across N26. But even when we did
this at Binance or at Agoda, there are three
areas where AI is complete game changer. One is
on coding. Again, you can use whatever latest tool
for prototyping or not most value, especially
for the companies I have worked at, which are
fairly large companies, very large code bases.
Having some sort of co-pilot that's integrated
with your repositories. Rough data, maybe
somewhere between 18 to 25% productivity
boost for a developer, which is fairly massive,
right? So that's one category, game changer.
Customer support, game changer. Whether we should
do it at scale or not, that's a different kind of
more ethical/human question to ask there. But
for solving the bottom 70 percentile problems,
"Why is my card declined? Why is there a hold on
my account? What happened to the replacement card
I shipped? Why is it not arrived?" Basic
questions, AI automating now almost 60,
70% of that. Customers getting
that real feedback. Game changer.
And the last one is just on fraud and being
able to just understand patterns better on
real customers versus not. At Binance, we had
this product where users could exchange crypto
with each other. I could pay you Bitcoin and
get Thai bath in return, huge amount of fraud.
And they're using AI just to understand language
patterns of fraudsters versus not fraudsters.
Massive. So again, as a company level, there is an
incredible set of advancements across these three
areas: developer productivity, customer support,
and fraud. But for me personally, I'm like,
what would I use that suddenly makes me a better
CPO? I'm still struggling a little bit over there,
but I don't think we need something at that level
because largely what still remains the domain of
humans is decision making and taking the brunt
of the impact of what decisions you make because
I would love to blame AI for some of my bad
decisions. That's not why [inaudible 01:18:10].
You can still do that. You can
still do that even if it's not.
Yes, yes. But again, hopeful to, generally not
a big fan of ... The thing I call a little bit
jaded. You have tools now that you write few
things and they make a long essay for it. And
then you have tools that compress long essays
into few words. You could have just said few
words in the first place and save the whole round
trip. It's like a reverse zip. I remember when we
had zip and it was a game changer, but there was
a big file you needed to send over a slow network,
so you compressed it and sent it and then
expanded it. We're doing the reverse now.
We have a small thing, we make it big and then
send it over and somebody's making it small.
But on these three areas, if you're at
all skilled companies, if you don't have a
great tool for developing productivity,
you're not looking at essential basic
LLM bots for deflecting customer service
and you're not looking at patterns on user
transactions or user communications or detect
fraud, that's the first area I would focus on.
Okay, I'm going to take us to another recurring
segment on the podcast. It's called Fail Corner.
And the idea here is folks like you come on this
podcast, there's all these wins, killing it, CPO,
this and that, and just moving into
Thailand, it worked out incredibly,
what a win all the time. In reality, that's
not how things go. So the question to you here
is just what's the story of a failure in your
career when things didn't go well and it was a
big deal for you, and then what you learned from
that experience, how that actually impacted you?
Yeah, so from the product side, my probably
most spectacular failure was I was the first
PM on Hangouts. And if you ask Nikhil,
he'll probably say he was my boss then.
It was an effort the size I've never seen before
or after in my career. We had thousands of people
working for me. We had entire power of Google.
We had Larry literally sitting with us saying we
can do anything we want Chrome to do. And we still
didn't manage to build a great messaging product.
So when I look at pure product-sense, product
decision-making was, there's several reasons
now I'd had luxury of 15 years to analyze
that on solving for the wrong audience,
solving for the wrong DNA of the company. I have
this premise that certain companies can never
succeed at certain type of products like Microsoft
with mobile or Google with social or Facebook with
enterprise, it is just the DNA of the founder
actively acts against you succeeding there.
I would've said Google with enterprise as well.
But then Sundar came and Larry was no longer the
CEO and that's when the enterprise took off.
They literally had to change the CEO to win
in certain segments, but more, and then
again, I worked in Nagoda during COVID,
so travel company during COVID, Binance during its
probably most tumultuous area of compliance and
government scrutiny. There's a lot of missteps
there around externalities. I think one of the
main kind of learnings from that is just don't
take on projects that are going to be six months,
a year, because you just generally don't have
control over the macro. Things just move way
more faster. And that's probably cemented my
kind of now product philosophy of just doing
small things very quickly, spending most of the
times doing that. You still launch big products,
but even over there we try and get early signals
as soon as possible. But because in Nagoda, like
one of the big projects we launched was we wanted
to control the payments infrastructure for all the
hotels and we thought if we had that device in
the hotel's desk, so not only for bookings made
online, but for everything that happens at the
hotel, if we control that infrastructure, not only
would we make money, but we had a touch point with
the users that went beyond booking the travel.
Travel as you know, is not a high
frequency activity. You book once,
then you book six months later and most of the
time people would not come to Nagoda, they would
just go to Google and go to some other website.
So we wanted that touch point that stayed with
them and thought payments would be a great avenue
to do that because that's something you do every
day. And again, we did it in the Nagoda style.
So we did an experiment. We started very small
and literally went to the mall and bought these
$50 Android devices where we ran our software that
people could just scan the credit card by a camera
and charge it. It was incredible. We had thousands
of hotels use it. And then COVID hits and then
there's literally nobody going to hotels anymore.
But it took us like six, nine months because
of the licenses, and so to launch it. And
in hindsight probably, I mean you couldn't have
thought about COVID with that sense, but still the
amount of time it took to launch the product was
something we could have done better. So learnings
for most of it is don't take too long to launch,
don't take too long to validate your hypothesis.
The Hangout story is amazing. It's like a classic
product. People now make fun of just Google,
why can't you get this right? And it's
been changed. Names have changed a hundred
times. Interestingly, Meet ended
up being really good, Google Meet.
That's the last thing I did when I left Google.
Oh, Okay.
After we built the Hangouts, they're
like, "Okay, this is not going anywhere.
We are going to start this new product
called Allo." Which also didn't work.
One of the many names,.
But then I said, you know what? We should
still, because I used to work for Android
Enterprise team before, I'm like, what if we
just made it an enterprise product? Let me
at least write the spec for it on, hey, what
would we do differently for, I still called
it Hangouts by Enterprise. They rebranded it
later. But that was my salvaging moment for,
but from the sense, I mean the Hangouts team
invented WebRTC. Now every single communication
in the world happens on WebRTC. So if you think
from the cultural and technological impact
that the Hangouts team had is insane. Like this
tool we are using every single meeting product,
every single WhatsApp, voice calling, video
calling, every Zoom, everything runs on WebRTC.
From a technology side, I think that was a pretty
massive win that the team came up with that.
That's the power of having Chrome having a
browser, also, just introducing technologies.
Yeah. Yes, absolutely.
Final question before we get to a very
exciting lightning round, is there anything
else that you want to leave listeners with
or maybe a point you want to double down on
just to kind of leave a little last little
nugget before we get to the lightning round?
I mean, just summarize, it depends on
the audience. A lot of the folks who
probably listen to it or coming it from a
perspective of like, "Hey, how does this
help me be better at my job tomorrow than I
was today?" And for them I would say, again,
if you're truly working in areas where you think
you're optimizing your strengths and having fun,
just keep doing it and just keep that as your
kind of north star, as you look at new pieces.
When you talk to new companies, try and
evaluate the overlap of superpowers. What
is your superpower? What is the company's
superpower? Will they feed each other?
If you get a very strong resonance there,
I think that would be a great career step
irrespective of whether it's in Bangkok or Spain
or however the compensation is going to be,
because truly you'll find that you grow much
faster because it's a kind of self-fulfilling
prophecy at that point. But just keep looking
for overlapping superpowers all the time and
not just in professional life, even the concepts
beyond maybe even for relationships and stuff like
folks who are extremely complementing strengths
and whose superpowers feed each other make for
great life partners. So there's maybe that
analogy can be extended beyond your career.
Wow, that's a powerful point right there. Well,
what a cool way to end that. Well,
with that Mayur, we've reached our
very exciting lightning round. I've got
five questions for you. Are you ready?
Yeah, let's do it.
What are two or three books that you find
yourself recommending most to other people?
The one that I read most recently,
so I generally don't read a lot of
books because I read a lot of
content like, small content.
Tweets.
And tweets and then Substacks and Discords and
WhatsApp messages, and so book takes a mind share
shift for me to go read a book. The one I read
most recently, which I thought was pretty amazing
and a lot of overlap with what I said today,
The Five Kinds Of Wealth. That one was very
well articulated, especially the last point I made
very early. One of the potential paths is you just
do well on your job and then you find meaning
elsewhere. This book is probably an incredible
structured way of thinking around it. What is
your wealth in terms of your health, your physical
health, your mental health, your relationship
health, your community and your wealth that you're
generating financial wealth is and how do you
think holistically? Because at the end of the day,
you are what you optimize for. If you optimize for
financial wealth, you'll become wealthy, but you
might not be wealthy in a full spectrum manner.
The Strengths Finder 2.0, I said very early on.
It's still an interesting book to just think
about how you would think about your strengths,
but again, if you don't want to read the book, I
would just do one of these kind of online quizzes
for it. But The Five Kinds of Wealth then Strength
Finder 2.0 would be maybe what I would suggest.
The first book by Sahil Bloom friend of
the podcast willing to tell this stuff. I
forgot to mention the story briefly about
the Strength Finder stuff. So I actually,
when I was leaving Airbnb and looking for my
next thing and even thinking about leaving,
I took a strengths test and I was working with
executive coach and I saw the results and she's
like, "What do you see in these results? What
are these results telling you?" I'm like, I don't
know. She's like, this tells me you should start
your own company and work on your own. All the
strengths that are popping up here are things that
you as a founder need and that really helped me.
What's your one person data
point on that? Was it a good one?
Was it is a good decision, you mean?
Yes, relying on that strength
test to make a career.
The best. So great. I am such a huge
fan of Strengths Finder and any kind
of strengths test and interestingly, people may
be afraid of taking them because they'd be like,
here's what I suck at. It always
makes you feel good. It's like,
here's the stuff you're good at and it's not
like, here's what you're bad at. It's just,
here's the stuff you're best at and it's
always positive. It's never like you suck
at this stuff. It's just not your strength. So
it was a huge win for me. I highly recommend it.
Awesome.
Especially if you're trying to make a
career move. So yeah, fully aligned. Okay,
next question. Do you have a favorite recent
movie or TV show you've really enjoyed?
The one I saw that kind of TV shows usually I
watch to kind of give it down time, so usually
I watch just periodic shows, the House or Big Bang
Theory and stuff. The one that I saw recently that
kind of shook me a little bit was Adolescence.
Again, it's a tough topic around teenage mental
health and violence in schools and just the
way it was shot. I would see the first episode,
even if it's not your genre because it's shot
in a single camera motion and the whole episode
for an hour, there's no cut. Camera just keeps
moving and it just makes bizarre, you feel a
little different than watching it. Irrespective
of this topic, which is also pretty intense.
Just visually you feel different, and if you're
motion sick like me, you really feel different.
That's wonderful. It sounds like what a ...
I would watch that. I need to watch
The White Lotus because everybody keeps
bringing it every time I tell them I'm
from Thailand and I haven't seen it yet,
so I'm behind on my mean culture a little bit.
Yeah, you are. It's like you, no one else has
not seen it. I think you're the only person left.
Yes, I'm the only one.
Okay. Do you have a favorite product you've
recently discovered that you really love?
So products, so I spend most of my time using
banking and trading products, and I would give
a plug here. If you're in Europe, try N26 or even
revenue, incredible product. If you're in the US,
Robin Hood, just the motion design they have
done and the onboarding is just a joy to use,
whether you use it for banking or trading or
just for their card. I just find the product
design and motion, especially as you touch and
swipe and try to be done. Anything that Nikita
Beard launches. So I just downloaded
Bible study or Bible chat yesterday.
I saw a tweet about that. It's like in the top
10 of all social apps and it's like bible study.
Yeah, it's top ten. And I can tell why
I have got three messages right now to
treat my anxiety by reading Bible today,
and one of the time I was feeling slightly
anxious, so maybe there's some magic there.
But the one app that I would just for personal,
I used to write in Hindi. I used to write poems
growing up as a kid, and that was just now this
app Suno.com. I can make songs from them and
they're incredible songs, at least I think so.
Nobody else thinks it so far, but just the fact
that you can write something and now you have a
song is just magical. The first time that AI,
I saw a use case, I said, it's nothing so far
that makes me a better CPO right now, but as
an artist or at least the bathroom artist,
it's just incredible that you can think of
something, put it down there and you can actually
see what would a professional singer and a
band and a musician if they were to compose it,
what it would look like. So that's probably the
most wild I have been by technology, the recent
times, the Suno.com. They're onboarding
flow sucks and their growth product is,
if I were the PM on Suno, I would do things a
lot differently, but their core tech is magical.
I'm a huge fan. One of my favorite things
to do at Suno, I think it's Suno.ai also,
is just ask it to make a song in the
style of a sea shanty. It's so fun.
And they give you a few options, so you could
be like, here's this version, that version.
Yes, yes.
Okay, two more questions. Do you have a favorite
life motto that you often come back
to find useful in work or in life?
One, I kind of relates to the things we talked
about is there's no right or wrong decision.
There's just low and fast decisions. Now, there
are some extreme caveats to that around you're
doing something that might kill your user like
healthcare or military or even compliance,
which can kill your company. Don't use it. But
everywhere else in generally goes back to the
strategy thing we talked about as well. A lot
of the times if it's you make a wrong decision,
if you make it fast enough, you would know it was
wrong and you would correct it and you would still
do it faster than thinking months for the right
decision. So for anything that's reversible,
anything that's not going to get
you in jail or kill your company,
no right or wrong decisions,
just slow or fast decisions.
Final question. You've lived in a bunch of
places. You've lived in Spain, Thailand,
Mumbai, Seattle, I think Texas,
even for some period for school?
Yeah. College, yes.
Okay. There's probably other
places. Which has the best food?
Bangkok, no question. Barcelona comes closer for
some, but Bangkok, you can have a three Michelin
star, one of the top five restaurants in the
world, spend $500 a meal or you can have a
$1 street food, stir-fried pork and rice with
basil. Incredible. Just the spectrum of entire,
from the cheapest food you can think of,
the most expensive food you can think of
in that same one kilometer walkable
area, having thousands of these,
literally there's the density of food. No
one comes closer. Barcelona has incredible
restaurant. The best restaurant in the world
is like a block away from here. It's called
Disputar. Takes like two years to get on the wait
list there, but that's on one end of the spectrum,
Barcelona, that probably comes close second.
But that cheap, get down 2:00 A.M. walk down
and have an incredible meal for a dollar.
nothing comes closer to it than Bangkok.
This episode's a great ad for Thailand. Let's go.
You definitely got to watch White
Lotus. Mayur, this was awesome. We
covered so much ground. I feel like I got
to know you so well. We covered so many-
Thank you so much.
... perspectives in all this.
Yeah, we're not done yet. Two
final questions. Where can folks find
you online if they want to reach out,
maybe check out if there's roles at N26 and
then how can listeners be useful to you?
Find me, this is one of the things being old
is I was one of the first users of LinkedIn,
so linkedin.com/mayur. [inaudible 01:36:10]
Facebook, so facebook.com/kamat or N26.com.
mk@N26.com. If you're especially
curious about how we do stuff here,
we are hiring, we are growing really fast. As I
said, banking's a great business to be in. We're
not going to go out of flavor for the next few
thousand years. So if you're thinking of a career,
you're thinking about Spain or was thinking
about Berlin, just a whole different interesting
lifestyle and different kind of product thinking,
please reach out on any of those channels.
If you're in Europe, download or
try N26. Like we go by the motto,
love your bank. Our founders say that people would
rather go to a dentist than to a bank branch,
and that's why we build this. We truly feel like
for an everyday banking, it's just use the app
and you feel like, I want to use my banking
app every day. There's some bit of magic,
which I didn't have that much contribution yet.
I made it a little bit simple and seamless, but
magic was there before and so if you're in Europe,
you're looking for a new bank account, N26.com.
There we go. Mayur, thank
you so much for being here.
Thank you. Thank you, Lenny,
and thank you everyone.
Bye, everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
LennysPodcast.com. See you in the next episode.