Let's talk about product market fit.
You have to deliberately not act on the
feedback of many of your early users,
and this is at the same time as listening
to people intensely and building what people
want. That's what we're here to do, is to make
something that people want, but it can't be all
people. And the question becomes, how do you
listen to them? And then even of what they say,
what do you pay attention to and
what don't you? The trick here is-
You're not doing what a lot of CEOs think
they need to be doing with their time.
A lot of CEOs think they need to spend
time on hiring or org building and you
intentionally, "I will spend time
on product and marketing design."
This is a technique that I call the switch
lock. It's born out of the observation that
your calendar says what you thought you were
going to do, but it's really only your trail
of work that describes what you actually
did. How can we capture that? So I came
up with the following idea. What if I
just did whatever the heck I wanted?
What's the most pivotal moment
in your career, in your life?
I learned the real secret behind
virality. There is no such thing
as a truly viral product. What
then is the true secret? It is-
Today my guest is Rahul Vohra. Rahul is the
founder and CEO of Superhuman and one of the most
thoughtful and insightful and articulate founders
that I've met. As you'll see in our conversation,
it's hard not to be captivated by Rahul's
storytelling skills and also his really insightful
takes on how to build great products and teams.
This episode is for anyone who's looking to build
their product taste, help their teams move
faster, learn how to think better from first
principles. And also learn about Superhuman's
very unique approach to building their company,
including why they manually onboarded every single
new user for years and why they decided to stop.
Why they ignored most of their customer feedback
on their way to finding product market fit,
and also how you can use his approach to finding
product market fit for your own company. Also, the
power of game design in building great products,
a very contrarian take on pricing strategy,
what Rahul has learned about building scaled
products on top of AI and LLMs and so much more.
A huge thank you to Ed Sims, Conrad
Irwin, Bell Trenchard and Gaurav Vohra for
suggesting questions and topics for this
conversation. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. Also, if you
become a yearly subscriber of my newsletter, you
get a year free of Superhuman that you can start
using immediately. You also get a year free
of Notion, Perplexity Pro, Granola and Linear.
Check it out at lennysnewsletter.com.
With that, I bring you Rahul Vohra.
This episode is brought to you by Eppo. Eppo is a
next generation A/B testing and feature management
platform, built by alums of Airbnb and Snowflake,
for modern growth teams. Companies like Twitch,
Nero, ClickUp and DraftKings rely on Eppo to
power their experiments. Experimentation is
increasingly essential for driving growth and
understanding the performance of new features,
and Eppo helps you increase experimentation
velocity while unlocking rigorous deep analysis
in a way that no other commercial tool does.
When I was at Airbnb, one of the things that I
loved most was our experimentation platform where
I could set up experiments, easily, troubleshoot
issues, and analyze performance all on my own.
Eppo does all that and more, with advanced
statistical methods that can help you shave
weeks off experiment time and accessible UI for
diving deeper into performance. And out-of-the-box
reporting that helps you avoid annoying prolonged
analytic cycles. Eppo also makes it easy for
you to share experiment insights with your team,
sparking new ideas for the A/B testing flywheel.
EPO powers experimentation across every use case,
including product, growth, machine learning,
monetization, and email marketing. Check
out EPO at get epo.com/lenny and 10 x your
experiment velocity. That's geteppo.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by the Fundrise
Flagship Fund. Full disclosure, real estate
investing is boring. Prediction markets are
exciting. Meme coins are a thrill ride. Even
the stock market can swing wildly on a headline.
Hello, DeepSeek. But with real estate investing,
there's no drama or adrenaline or excuses
to refresh your portfolio every few minutes,
just bland and boring stuff like diversification
and dividends. So you won't be surprised to
learn that the Fundrise Flagship Real
Estate Fund is a complete snooze fest.
The fund holds $1.1 billion worth of
institutional caliber real estate managed
by team of pros focused on steadily growing
your net worth for decades to come. See,
boring. That's the point. You can start
investing in minutes and with as little as
$10 by visiting fundrise.com/lenny. Carefully
consider the investment objectives, risks,
charges, and expenses of the Fundrise
Flagship Fund before investing. Find this
information and more in the fund's prospectus
at fundrise.com/flagship. This is a paid ad.
Rahul, thank you so much for being
here. Welcome to the podcast.
Hello, hello and thank you for having me Lenny.
I have so many questions for you. We're going
to have so much to talk about. I actually want
to start with your time before Superhuman. When I
was preparing for this chat, I actually asked you,
what's the most pivotal moment in your career
in your life? And you told me that other than
starting Superhuman, it was selling your
previous company Rapportive to LinkedIn.
So let me just start there. What was
that experience like? What do people
not know about this phase in your
life and just why was it so pivotal?
So for folks that don't know, Rapportive was my
last company. It was the first Gmail extension
to scale to millions of users. Basically on the
right-hand side of Gmail, we would show you what
people look like, where they work, links to
their recent tweets, their LinkedIn profile
and everything else that they were doing
online. So if you were hiring, marketing,
selling in BD, super useful. It turns out we
somehow attracted most of LinkedIn's daily
active users onto this one free app, and
I then ultimately ended up selling that to
LinkedIn. That by far, as you said, was the
most pivotal thing I'd done in my career,
prior to starting Superhuman.
Now, had I known that we'd amassed
most of LinkedIn's active users onto one app, I
would have sold it for far more. But the actual
pivotal moment was really who I got to work with.
Because I reported to LinkedIn's head of Growth,
Elliot Shmukler. He was responsible for scaling
LinkedIn from 25 million members to when I joined,
north of 250 million members. And during my
first one-on-one, I learned the real secret
behind virality and big hint, it's not about viral
mechanics. Overall that acquisition experience
gave me the time to figure out what was next
and the resources to truly swing for the fences.
Okay. Well, I have to follow this
thread that you put out there,
what the secret is to virality.
What did you learn there?
Well, in my first one-on-one, I sat down with
Elliot and I said, "Hey, I'm here to learn.
Please teach me everything that you know
about virality." And he said, "Okay. Well,
hate to burst your bubble, but there is no
such thing as a truly viral product." I said,
"What do you mean? How do you explain Facebook
for that matter? How do you explain LinkedIn?"
And he said, "What I mean is, no app has
sustained a viral factor of greater than
one for any real period of time." Even Facebook
in its heyday had a viral factor of about 0.7.
And he told me that lasted for perhaps a year,
so one person was creating about 0.7 new users.
I double-clicked again and I said, "Well Elliot,
what about the address book import?" This is one
of the things that LinkedIn got famous or infamous
for. You could import your address book and then
it would spam slash invite everyone who happens
to be members of LinkedIn in your address book,
and then eventually it would just invite
everyone to LinkedIn. And he said,
"That's an amazing feature, but you have to
remember not everyone is going to use it all the
time." So even that feature had a lifetime viral
factor of about 0.4, and that's considered good.
0.4 is good for a viral feature, 0.6 is
great, something like 0.7 is absolutely
incredible. You're in the stratosphere
up with Facebook at that time. So I said,
"Well, okay, all of these things by definition
are going to Peter out. There's going to be an
asymptote. None of these viral mechanics keep
on compounding. Which actually makes sense,
it would be a little absurd if things just kept
on growing. What then is the true secret behind
virality?" And he said, "It is word of mouth.
It is the virality you can't measure that isn't
a mechanic that isn't in a feature. It is
when one user spontaneously tells another
user about your product." That really colored how
I think about growth and virality. Since then,
it has shaped so much of what we do at Superhuman
and so much of how I think about growing brands.
Wow, you're such a great storyteller. I'm just
listening here, just captivated, "What is he
going to say next?" That was fascinating. I
actually have a post that I'm going to link
to that, that very much aligns with what you're
talking about, which is titled, Virality is a Myth
mostly. It's based, I forget, on this book where
they do all this research on actual viruses. It
turns out they're not actually spreading in this
exponential way, there's one person that spreads
it to a lot of people and it keeps happening.
That's actually apparently what the data shows.
I'm curious if you found this same thing, which
is, when people think of an app as going viral,
it's one person with a massive platform sharing
it and their audience adopts it and that's just
one to many and then it just happens a couple
of times and it looks like it's going viral,
but it's a person to many people, not many
people to many people. Thoughts on that?
Yeah, we've definitely found that there
are whales, to use the gaming terminology,
that one person is going to be responsible
for inviting 25, 50, 100 people, and they
may have various motivations for doing that.
In Superhuman, as an individual subscriber,
if you refer somebody else and they sign
up, you both get a free month, which is a
great incentive if you're paying out of pocket.
We have people who send many, many hundreds of
invites and there are some people who essentially
have free Superhuman for life now due to how many
people they've invited. But of course that
incentive doesn't necessarily work inside of
a company or inside of a team where ultimately
it's the company paying for the product,
so you have to then come up with new motivations
for those people. That's where there really isn't
any substitute to having a genuinely multiplayer
or a genuinely collaborative product. That's one
of the huge evolutions we've taken Superhuman
through over the last, probably about two years.
Early last year we launched what we
call Superhuman 2.0. The basic idea is,
we saw almost every single other app of
note become collaborative by default, Figma,
Notion, Loom. These are all multiplayer
or collaborative by default. Yet email,
the one tool that we all
use more than anything else,
even more than things like Slack, was still
firmly stuck in its single-player origins.
I want to come back to something that
you mentioned that I didn't come back
to you that I think is really core to
what you just shared, which is word of
mouth being so important. People talk about
all these viral features and sharing contact
books and all these things. And your point
is, that takes you to a place, but really
what helps a consumer-ish product spread is word
of mouth, people sharing with each other. Which,
then the question is, how do you do that? We're
going to talk about a lot of things that you
did to make Superhuman something people
want to share, but in the end it's just
making something people want to share. That's
the definition almost. Then it's like, what
makes people want to share stuff? It's amazing,
it's helping them, something that is remarkable.
Well, it turns out, because you mentioned
remarkableness, that is one of our core company
values. If you think about what a company has
to do, it has to grow. How do things grow? Well,
let's take Elliot's advice at face
value, and I believe it's true,
it's creating something that people share.
You mentioned one way of doing it, which is
something that people want to share. There's
actually another way, which is simply creating
something remarkable, and you used that word,
and that is one of the core values of Superhuman.
We have, create delight, create something that is
so joyful that really truly brings people delight.
We have deliver remarkable quality, something
that is so striking, so compelling and worthy of
attention that people can't but help tell others
about it. Then we have build the extraordinary,
which is a measure of the efficacy or the
innovativeness of what we want to build. That's
another trick, which is literally baking these raw
ingredients for growth into your company values.
I didn't know that was one of your
values. That makes so much sense. Okay,
we're going to come back to that, because
I think that is... There's so much to learn
about how you think about product and how you
think about building the company that builds
the product. But I want to actually start
here with how this conversation came to be.
The CEO of Product Hunt, Rajiv, tweeted months
ago, he tweeted this and we're going to show
this if you're on YouTube, "Superhuman's product
velocity feels like it's kicked into another gear
as of late. Does anyone else notice this?" I
saw that, I'm like, "I completely have noticed
this. It feels like there's just feature shipping
left and right, AI this, AI that. It feels like
it's just a new company." And I tagged you on the
tweet. I'm like, "Hey Rahul, what's changed?" And
you answered with a few things and it just made it
clear there's a lot to learn about what you did.
Because a lot of companies are in this phase
of just, "Things aren't moving as fast as we
want. We used to be so much faster, we used
to ship all these features and now we don't."
So I think this is a really cool real case study
illustrative example that we can analyze. So let
me ask you this, what did you notice that told you
something needed to change at Superhuman? And then
what did you change that actually had the most
impact on your ability to ship and move faster?
I think what we noticed was this sentiment,
and we felt it first ourselves, but we also
started hearing it from the market,
from our users, from our customers,
that we'd slowed down. And as a founder, as a CEO,
that's the absolute last thing you want to hear.
It's our job after all to speed things up. When
I ask people what do they mean by slowing down,
they didn't mean the product, of course, the
product wasn't working any slower, but that the
pace of delivery seemed to have slowed down.
I think to break this down, it's important
to start by defining what we mean by a slowdown.
There's the kind of slowdown that is unavoidable
in certain spaces, and then there is the
kind of slowdown that is quite avoidable. We
actually had both. So starting with unavoidable
slowdown, you can classify anything that you
build in a company into one of two categories,
solution deepening and market widening. Now,
solution deepening means making your product
better for its existing users, but not making it
available to more users. Whereas market widening
means making your product available to more users,
but not making the product itself any better.
There are some spaces, there are some markets,
there are some platforms where market
widening is really fast and really easy,
and there are some spaces, email is one of
them where market widening is really hard
and really slow. But when we started we had a
great deal of focus. We only supported Gmail,
we were only on the web. In those early years,
we could pour every ounce of R&D energy,
every engineering dollar, into solution deepening,
making the product better for existing users. And
of course users loved it. It's how we got to
product market fit. It's how most startups do.
But at a certain point, almost every company then
has to start investing in widening the market.
For example, the market of people who will use
a new Gmail front end but without a mobile app,
does exist, but it is relatively small. This is
something that every new email startup is going
to learn sooner or later. In order to keep
on growing, you are going to have to need to
add an iOS app and then a MacOS app, and then a
Windows app, and then an Android app. Then you'll
soon want to support Office 365. But that's
not one thing, that's actually three things,
because you have to support Office 365
on desktop and then on iOS and then on
Android. That's all much easier said than done.
I think we at Superhuman now know things about
these APIs that literally no other company knows,
and I would not wish it upon my worst enemy. So
fast-forward to today, and Superhuman now works
wherever you do on every combination of Gmail,
Outlook, Mac, Windows, Web, iOS, Android, and this
actually turns out to be a really great technology
moat. Almost no other email app can claim this.
It's taken many years of intense investment.
I think we'll touch on this later, but
it's one of the main reasons why we can
sell into the enterprise, because
we now know everyone can use it.
But this is the hard part, when you're doing that
market widening, you're not solution deepening,
so your perceived product velocity may
decrease. You can avoid some of these
things with some smart technology decisions,
but mostly you just have to grind through it,
and it is worth it to get to the other side. Then
there's the kind of slowdown that is avoidable.
If I remember my answer to Rajiv's tweet, that was
the kind I was talking about. In that case it was
our management structure, or who does what.
When we hired our initial executive teams,
I followed very conventional wisdom. I
ended up with a set of VPs and eight,
I think direct reports, maybe even nine.
I thought that's what you were meant to
do. That's how startups are meant to scale.
But as anyone who's been there knows, eight
direct reports is a lot. It's a lot of hiring,
it's a lot of goal setting, it's a lot of OKRs,
it's a lot of accountability conversations, and
fortunately also it's a lot of firing. No CEO
ever gets their executive team right on the first
try. That time I had for the things that I think
I can genuinely be world-class at things like
product and design and technology and marketing,
that all began to rapidly disappear, and as
a result the organization began to slow down.
Unfortunately, I was also tracking my time very
closely, I had this crazy way of tracking it. At
one point I noticed I was spending six to 7%
of my week on these areas, these areas where
I can truly be world-class at. So I had two
realizations. Number one, as CEO, once you
get to a certain scale, and we were definitely
at that scale, you can actually define what you
want the role of a CEO to be at your company. And
number two, the Superhuman opportunity deserves
everyone who works at the company to spend as
much time as possible in their zone of genius,
so that includes me as well as everybody else.
What I did is, I hired a really great president,
I went from eight direct reports to two, and the
amount of time that I spend on product design,
technology and marketing went up from
six to 7% to about 60% to 70% of my week.
Just to mirror back a few things. One is, people
may feel like you are not shipping as much as you
used to because you're actually building things
they don't care about, which is support for
office and all these things that they don't need,
but the business needs to expand, integrations
with Microsoft and Android and all these things. I
think that's such a good point, that it looks like
nothing's happening when there's a lot of good
stuff happening for other users that aren't you.
Then there's this point about people delegate.
Then a leader of delegates, hires all these execs
and they're like, "This is not what I wanted.
Why have I done this?" And you think it's going
to speed up, but it slows down. A couple threads
here that are really interesting. One is this time
tracking thing, I need to know how do you do this?
The fact that you knew seven to 8% or whatever
the number is, to that granularity of your time
you're spending on things you wanted was that low,
how do you do time tracking? Let's not go
super far, but just what's your approach?
This is a technique that I call the Switch
log. It's born out of the observation that your
calendar says what you thought you were going to
do, but it's really only your trail of work that
describes what you actually did. So how can we
capture that? And actually, how can we create a
system of work that isn't tethered to a calendar,
where you aren't at the behest of what some
timetable says you do or you don't have to do?
So I came up with the following idea, what if I
just did whatever the heck I wanted? What if every
single time I change task I just Slack DM'd my EA,
but this also works in Slackbot, it just has to go
somewhere. I Slack DM'd my EA and I said, "TS:,"
and then a few words for the task I was doing.
Well, that would create certain changes. Instead
of having to constantly look at the calendar and
think, "Oh, should I stop this task, start that
task, I can just do what I want." If what I feel
right now is, "Oh boy, I really need to prepare
for Lenny's podcast, I'll go ahead and do that."
And if I get bored or distracted eight minutes in,
which sometimes happens because something else
just bubbles up to the top of my mind, well,
there's a reason that my body is bubbling it up to
the top of my mind. I also practice transcendental
meditation, so I'm very keen on the idea of
being aware and listening to what's bubbling up.
So it's okay for me to then go and attend to
that thought as opposed to start to expend my
focus points or my discipline or willpower
on the thing that I thought I was meant to
be doing. All I'd have to do is I'd go back to
Slack, "TS: Dealing with this other thing." And
by the way, you should obviously turn up for your
meetings. I'm not saying just blow through your
meetings and not turn up for your one-on-ones.
Definitely do those things. What I'm saying is,
do what feels right for as long as it
feels right to do. Then at the end of
the week you can see where your time is going.
I realized at one point that I was spending only
in those days 5% of my time on recruiting, whereas
perhaps I should be spending 20 or 30% or more of
my time on recruiting. But the biggest thing was,
I saw I was only spending six to 7% of my time on
product, on design, on technology and marketing.
These are things where I know I'm really good at
them. I should either be teaching people how to
do them or doing them or some combination of both.
That's probably the best thing for me. It keeps
me really happy, very joyful, it keeps me sharp,
but it's also scaling the organization. So that's
how we had that kind of an insight. Once you have
this Slack Log, you can then graph it and chart
it and see where your time is actually going.
How cool. Clearly this is an app
opportunity or an agent opportunity
where you're just telling this thing every
time. It's essentially tracking context,
which we're always hearing, try not
to avoid context which switches.
I think context switches are fine.
There's definitely this idea that,
for every interruption you have, the brain does
take roughly 21 minutes on average to recover,
to get back to the efficacy before that you
were disturbed. It's a big deal, of course,
I'm building productivity software, we designed
Superhuman to minimize the amount of distraction
and disruption that's possible within the app. But
if you are working on something and at the back of
your mind something bubbles up, you have to attend
to it in one way or the other. Sometimes I just
write it down, actually, I don't have my notebook
with me, but it's really big. I have a gigantic,
whatever twice the size of A4 is, I guess
A3 sketchbook and I always have a 4H pencil,
so whenever one of those thoughts comes up, I
just scribble it down. Or I actually stop what
I'm doing and I attend to that task, because
there's a reason it's bubbling up right now.
I love that you know exactly the type of paper
and pencil, 4H pencil, A3 paper, [inaudible
00:24:51]. Okay, this is going to be a theme. You
mentioned meditation, you said you do TM, so you
do 20 minutes in the morning, 20 minutes... Do
you do it that style or you do a longer session?
I do about half an hour in the morning,
including rest time. The physical rest
component of it is very important to me. So
it's 20 minutes of the actual meditation,
then 10 minutes of rest. I do that in the morning
as well as in the afternoon at around 3:00 PM
And you just carve that out in your calendar.
Everyone knows Rahul at three
o'clock, he's going to be out.
Absolutely. My EA knows, they're the one
who's organizing the calendar and making
sure things happen when they need to happen.
They also know that nothing can override this
TM block. Without it I genuinely start to fall
apart. But with it, I'm able to access some very
deep competencies that I didn't have before. I've
been doing this now for about four or five years,
and initially I simply felt happier,
occasionally even more euphoric coming
out of a really great meditation session. But
over time I found that my ability to focus was
increasing. I could hold attention on something
for much longer, but I also was able to become
much more creative and much more expressive.
These are well-known side effects, as it were,
or intended effects for some people of TM. And
interestingly about TM, if you compare it to
other forms of meditation, they don't have quite
the same impact across quite as many executive
functions. So there's something particularly
interesting that's going on with transcendental
meditation as opposed to other forms that folks
are still trying to unravel and figure out.
If folks want to, if they're inspired and they
want to check out this form of meditation,
any advice on where they could go learn?
Absolutely, a lot. But in summary, have a coach
teach you. I had many false starts myself with
meditation, trying the various apps, learning
from books. None of it really worked for me.
What worked was having one-on-one teaching
from someone themselves who had been taught
one-on-one the Yogic or the Raja tradition
of teaching. This person in particular
had also been a venture-backed founder
multiple times over, so they're very
well aware of the kinds of stresses that I
tend to be under. And all of his clients are
mostly in technology as well. If you're in
the Bay Area, this person's name is Laurent
Valasek. They run an institution called the Peak
Leadership Institute. And this is all about how
we can live a more integrated and whole life.
Integrating wellness practices like meditation,
but for the purpose of unlocking peak
performance in life and in business.
Thank you for sharing that.
That is very actionable. We're
going to link to that in the show notes.
Okay. I'm going to try to bring us back on
course. The other thing you mentioned
that I think is really interesting is
hiring a president. A lot of founders and
leaders might be hearing this and be like,
"Going from eight reports and doing all these
things I don't want to, spending most of my
time on the product and design and marketing,
amazing." What did this president take off your
plate and what is their responsibility and that
allowed you to do the stuff you wanted to do?
The biggest thing was taking off the operations
and the management of the executive team and
the rest of the company. Think of the president
role in Superhuman as an operationally extremely
challenging and a very growthful role. It is
perfect for someone who wants to go on to be
a CEO in their next role. Instead of hiring
and firing that team, instead of managing and
setting their goals, instead of the accountability
conversations, someone else who's now doing that.
In addition, because that's not the only job,
in addition, they're also a very strong thought
partner when it comes to corporate strategy.
When it comes to, where do we take act one,
our email product? How far do we go down the
multiplayer path? How aggressively should we
lean into AI? What's a reasonable gross margin
in a world with AI? Are we from a financial
perspective okay dipping now and then coming back
later? When should we start building our second
product? How do we think about our R&D strategy?
Should we keep on hiring in the Bay Area,
or as we've done for many of our recent hires,
should we continue hiring in Latin America? Should
we consider other time zones as well? And so on
and so on and so on. I'm just randomly coming up
with questions, but the list is truly endless.
Another way to think about it is, it's almost
like a grown-up co-founder. The two people I
co-founded the company with, Comrade and Vivek,
they've long since gone from Superhuman. We're
now a 10-year-old organization and I'm one those
rare founders that is persisting and thriving
actually 10 years in. That said, the journey
never gets easier, it gets different and you still
need that co-founding energy around you. I have a
handful of people in the organization who are
in their roles providing that kind of energy,
that kind of input, and who thrive off doing so.
Then the president role is definitely one of them.
Incredibly interesting. There's so much
there. One, just a couple of things I'll
share and then I want to move on to a different
topic. One is just, it's cool the solution to
helping you move faster and do the work you
want to do is org design. That feels like a
really doable thing. If you're finding you're
not spending time on things you want to spend
time on and things aren't moving as fast as you
want, it's essentially you can find people to
take on things that you don't want and shift the
way that the org is structured and that could
solve a lot of problems. That's what it did for
you. Then I think it's also really interesting,
there's this lesson here of as a founder,
if you're just feeling depleted or just
don't have the partner you want, you could
bring someone on that could be that person.
Absolutely.
Okay. There's so much there. That was
much more of a rich area than I even
expected. I want to zoom out a little
bit, and there's a couple themes that
came up again and again when I talked to
folks that you've worked with, investors
in Superhuman. The two themes are contrarian
thinking, in terms of building the company,
and strong attention to detail. Let's spend a
little time on attention to detail. Like I said,
this is one of the things that came up again and
again when I was asking people about you. So I
have this quote from Ed Sims, and maybe your
first investor. Were they your first investor?
Yeah, that there's a bunch of people on Twitter
who are going to fight for that. But to set the
record straight, Ed Sim did actually write
the first three checks into Superhuman.
First three checks? At subsequent rounds.
Well, yeah. Quick sidebar on that, he runs
Boldstart Ventures alongside his partner Elliot
Durbin. They have a particular interest in backing
second-time founders, but they'll also back
first-time founders, and they love application
and infrastructure areas like Superhuman,
so we were like the perfect investment.
He also wrote a check from his previous
fund into a Rapportive, and I think I'd made him
five X that money. Nothing to write home about,
but definitely, "I'm going to back this
guy again." So I went to him and I said,
"Hey listen, this is going to sound crazy.
I want to take on Gmail." He said, "Do you
have a deck?" I was like, "Yeah, here it is one
slide, here it is." And there was a screenshot of
Gmail with most of it scribbled out, "I want
to build that and it's going to be amazing."
So he said, "Cool, we're in. Can I wire you the
money?" And I said, "No, I don't even have a bank
account yet." I come back two days later with
a bank account and he's like, "Cool, I want to
wire you 750 K." And I said, "I don't even know
what I'm going to do with that money. I'm not
paying myself, I won't for a while. We don't have
any employees. I can't think of anything I want
to spend it on. Tell you what, I'll just take 250
K." And he was like, "What?" I'm like, "Yeah, I'll
just take 250 K." We start having the conversation
around venture economics. I'm like, "Yeah,
it's fine, we'll figure it out." Then a few months
back I took another 250 K and a few months back
I took another 250 K as I began inventing ways
and finding channels to deploy capital properly.
I love this story. I love all these stories you're
sharing I've never heard before. And by the way,
it is awesome. We're talking
about him coming on the podcast,
maybe breaking our VC rule. So
specifically the story he shared
with me that is maybe an example of
you and your attention to detail is,
he said that you created your own font because
existing fonts weren't good enough. Is that true?
Kind of. Okay. The font that we use
today is a modified version of Adelle
Sans. The story there is, I looked
at all of the major font families,
and honestly none of them was what I would
call truly excellent. That may sound like
an odd thing to say. So let's, if you will
permit me to talk about typography and email-
Please.
The first thing we did was, we took our UI and
we laid it out in about 15 different styles
using examples of the major font families. We
actually printed these out and we left them on
a desk in the middle of our office. Sometimes with
design, you want to tune in to your immediate most
visceral response, but sometimes you want to
truly let a design marinate. And this was the
latter. So we let these designs marinate, we
let these font choices percolate. Like I said,
none of them was truly excellent.
Number one, I was looking for a font
that was in and of itself gorgeous. Number two,
I was looking for a font that could also convey
a message of any kind, without overpowering the
sentiment of that message. For example, does the
font work when this is inviting you to a party?
Many fonts, including almost all serif fonts,
are actually too somber or too sober for that.
Or to pick another extreme, does the font work
if it is informing you of somebody's passing, many
fonts are just too jaunty for that. You wouldn't
want that kind of message in Comic Sans, for
example. And number three, I was optimizing for
a font that made reading speed and comprehension
really fast. And number four, I was looking
for a font that made email addresses themselves
look great. So I discarded all the 15 because
they weren't good enough, and after searching high
and low, I came across a font called Adelle Sans,
which is designed by a foundry called Type
Together, type-together.com. They have a whole
bunch of lovely fonts, go check them out.
And if you go through my list, number one,
Adelle Sans is gorgeous. I think each character
is a work of art. It's beautifully formed. Number
two, Adelle Sans is, I would say upbeat, it's
optimistic, yet it's serious enough to convey any
kind of message. It has just the right amount of
personality, yet not too much personality. Number
three, Adelle Sans is also unusually narrow,
and that actually fits email particularly well.
One of my pet peeves with Gmail, which by default
uses Ariel, is that the lines are as wide as your
window. So if you're in a wide screen, then
the lines get really arbitrarily long. The
problem with really wide and really long lines,
is that they decrease reading speed. Because by
the time you've reached the end of one line,
your eyes have lost track of the start of the
next line. And Ariel itself has fairly wide
characters, which further exacerbates that.
So at Superhuman we, if you've used the product,
you know this, we fix the line length or the
typographical measure to the optimal length for
reading speed, which depending on the font is
around 90 to 120 characters. And Adelle Sans is
quite narrow, so it actually lets us do this on
quite small windows with fairly dense line. So we
get a lot of information on fairly small windows
without getting a very long typographical
measure, optimizing for reading speed and
for comprehension. Then number four, finally
Adelle Sans has very unusual treatment of the
at symbol in an email address. It actually
puts the base of the A in the at on the
same baseline as the rest of the text.
So for example, if your name has an A,
my name does Rahul at Vohra, three A's and or
two A's and an at, they're all actually on the
same baseline. It's a small thing, but it makes
the email addresses look incredibly natural. If
you look at that and then you actually look
at email addresses laid out in other fonts,
those other the fonts look really clunky and
awkward because the A is kind of shifted around
and it just looks a bit silly in my opinion.
Now Adelle Sans isn't perfect. So we then worked
with a type designer on some of the specific
details that there are some of the glyphs,
which get a little pinchy as it were, and what
we use today is very close to retail Adelle Sans.
And this was pre-launch or this
was after you'd already launched?
We'd probably had about 10, 15 users at the time.
So I think that's pretty contrarian unique to
be this focused on the font and the typeface
before you even launched. This was like,
"Is this even going to be a thing? Will
anyone even care?" And I think this says a
lot about the way you think about product.
Oh yeah, that thought never crossed my mind.
I think we'll probably come to it later,
but the idea that, is this never going to be a
thing? I think that's a dangerous thought. We
can't start thinking that way, because at what
point do you stop second-guessing yourself?
Interesting. So you were confident this was going
to work, so because I am so confident it'll work,
I need them to get this right. There's also
this trap founders fall into of just spending
too much time perfecting a thing that never
works and there's always advice launch early,
launch often. Thoughts there? How do you
find that balance? What's your advice there?
How much to spend time ahead of launch really
does depend on the markets and the structure,
the nature of your business model. For example,
let's say you are building a marketplace in a
greenfield opportunity, so imagine the Lyft
or Uber in their heyday. There's a strong
network effect, because the more cars you have
on your platform, the shorter waiting times are,
therefore people are going to preferentially
use your app versus the other person's app.
That's when there's no time to spare, that's when
you probably shouldn't even be sleeping. You're
going to hire the most aggressive maniacal people
possible. You're going to work 120-hour weeks,
because every marginal minute actually does
matter. Every marginal minute in the market,
growing compounding is going to
make your next year even better.
That's actually not true of all startups and it
certainly isn't true of something like Superhuman.
Yes, working harder is always better and we work
tremendously hard at Superhuman, but not to the
point where it made sense to release something
that didn't work. I'm reminded of a story of a
founder that was in Y Combinator, told me about
their demo day experience. They used Mailbox,
which some folks may remember was also a startup,
and Dropbox famously acquired them for about
a hundred million dollars. The reason that they
were well known, apart from the acquisition,
is they were the first to popularize, swipe to
archive or swipe to mark down, which of course is
now standard in Superhuman and every other app.
This founder was using Mailbox and was having
an amazing demo day. They're working the room,
they're meeting investors, they're pitching their
photography app in this case. He went home that
night and went to his laptop, fired up mailbox and
sent off a bunch of follow-up emails. He waited
the day, didn't hear back, he waited two days,
didn't hear back. On the third morning he
figured something was up, so he fired up Gmail,
went to his sent mail, and you guessed it, there
were no sent mails there. So something had broken
with mailbox. So he's cursing to himself trying
to remind himself everything's going to be
okay. Sent all the same emails from
Gmail manually and they all came through.
But then one of the investors said, "Hey, by the
way, you might want to check your email clients,
because I've been getting some of your emails
twice." Now he goes back into his Gmail, he sees
that yes, actually the original emails that were
queued up in mailbox have now indeed been sent,
and some of the investors, and unfortunately most
of the investors he actually pitched twice. Now,
is this the end of the world? No, an investor can
overlook that. Probably a good thing that you're
trying new apps. But was it horrifying
and was it really scary? Absolutely.
Imagine this wasn't investors, imagine this
was a customer, someone who you were trying
to convince to buy your thing and that you knew
what you were doing and you had attention to
detail and you had everything just buttoned up
and under control. Well, now you've lost face,
now you look foolish. That's why when you have
mission-critical products like email where you are
interfacing with customers, with candidates, with
investors, it turns out to really matter. Email is
mission-critical. It's not something where you
can simply launch with a half-baked product.
This is such an important nuance
take on, there's always this debate,
how much to focus on craft and user experience,
how much to focus on time to launch and get it
out and speed. What I'm hearing here, which
I completely agree with is, it depends on the
market you're in and the criticality essentially
of your product. So if it's email, it just needs
to work and you need to get that right, you need
to spend all the time, you need to get that right.
This reminds me of something else that
when your early investors shared with me,
Bill Trenchard from First-Round Capital. He
talked about how speed was the thing that you
just dialed up as a lever to 11. That's where
you just, "We will make this the focus. Speed,
speed, speed." I think maybe the lesson
there is, you pick the thing that you
think will most differentiate you, make you
significantly better than what's out there.
So just thoughts on how you decided speed
was the thing you were going to obsess with,
and advice for folks that are trying to
decide where to dial up things to 11?
Bill is right and I agree with him, you have
to pick something. Knowing what to pick is the
trick. In the early days of Superhuman, I read
a book on positioning that really influenced my
thinking. It is, I believe called Positioning
the Battle for Your Mind. It struck me how the
most well-known brands have stood for one clear
thing, they have a clear position. So in order
for Superhuman to be memorable, I believed
that we needed to occupy a clear position
that was unique and which was available
and which reinforced our product strategy.
In the first year of Superhuman, therefore, I
interviewed hundreds of potential customers about
their experience with Gmail and with Outlook.
And predictably, almost everybody says that
email takes way too much time. But interestingly,
many people also said that Gmail and Outlook were
way too slow. That was how I first thought
that speed could be an interesting position
for us. I then asked myself, "Is the position
of speed unique and is it available?" And the
answer was overwhelmingly yes, because almost
no software was being sold or has ever been
sold on the value proposition of speed. The last
time I could remember anyone trying to do this,
was when Google launched Chrome, and obviously
that went incredibly well for them. You may
remember they had slow-motion videos where
they were comparing Chrome render webpages and
showing that was faster than an actual strike
of lightning. No one had done it since then.
I then asked, "Well, does speed reinforce
our product strategy?" And again,
the answer was overwhelmingly yes. I knew that
our competition was not going to be startups,
it was incumbents. And I also knew that
incumbents generally struggle with speed,
because by definition they have massive scale and
usually entrenched architecture. Then finally I
did what I call the cocktail party test, which is
to look at the cocktail parties and to watch how
people pitch your product to other people. In our
case the pitches were simple. People would say,
"Dude, you have to use it, it's really fucking
fast." And that's it. That was the pitch.
That's how I knew that speed would be a
really great position for us to start with.
I'm excited to chat with Christina Gilbert,
the founder of OneSchema, one of our
longtime podcast sponsors. Hi Christina.
Yes, thank you for having me on, Lenny.
What is the latest with OneSchema? I know you now
work with some of my favorite companies like Ramp,
Vanta, Scale and Watershed. I heard
that you just launched a new product
to help product teams import CSVs from
especially tricky systems like ERPs.
Yes, so we just launched OneSchema of FileFeeds,
which allows you to build an integration with any
system in 15 minutes, as long as you can export
a CSV to an SFTP folder. We see our customers all
the time getting stuck with hacks and workarounds,
and the product teams that we work with don't have
to turn down prospects because their systems
are too hard to integrate with. We allow our
customers to offer thousands of integrations
without involving their engineering team at all.
I can tell you that if my team had
to build integrations like this,
how nice would it be to be able to
take this off my roadmap and instead
use something like OneSchema. Not just to
build it but also to maintain it forever.
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many
horror stories of multi-day outages from
even just a handful of bad records. We are
laser focused on integration reliability to
help teams end all of those distractions
that come up with integrations. We have a
built-in validation layer that stops any bad
data from entering your system and OneSchema
will notify your team immediately
of any data that looks incorrect.
I know that importing incorrect data can cause all
kinds of pain for your customers and quickly lose
their trust. Christina, thank you for joining
us and if you want to learn more, head on over
to OneSchema.co. That's one OneSchema.co.
The next area I want to spend time on and
I imagine we'll have much insight is, some
of the contrarian ways you approach building
Superhuman that a lot of companies never thought
about doing that you did that worked out for
you. So the first is manually onboarding every
single new user. Sure, startups have done this,
founders bring on some folks and then cool, show
it to them and then they stop doing that and then
it's self-service or sales teams. How far did
you scale this manual onboarding phase of your
company? How many people did you have onboarding
people, how many people did you manually onboard?
So for folks that don't know, in those early days
we insisted on one-to-one concierge onboarding,
and it was absolutely the right thing to do. You
couldn't use Superhuman unless you went through
the onboarding experience. Now it's almost the
reverse. Almost every new Superhuman customer goes
through self-service. The onboarding experience is
still there, but again it is absolutely the right
thing to do. To answer your question, at peak
we had about 20 people doing manual onboarding.
Okay, so it's not that many people. That's really
interesting. Because I always imagined it was like
a massive team, but 20 people can handle a lot, is
the takeaway there. What was the scale where you
stopped manual onboarding, just for folks that are
thinking about doing this and then when to stop?
I think the reason to stop is that there
will always be certain personality types
who do not want to go through a one-on-one
onboarding. At a certain point those people
will become very important, and you'll need to
be ready with a world-class self-service option.
When we started building self-service,
it seemed nearly impossible. In fact,
it was terrifying, because it's difficult
to overstate how much the entire DNA
of the company was built around this idea that
we would onboard users manually. After all,
we did so much in our one-to-one onboardings and
there's only so much that software can do. Now,
we did after a lot of grind and
persistence eventually figure it
out and we have a world-class self-service
experience today, but we did not at the time.
So the flip side is, why would you even do this
to begin with? What we found is two things. Number
one, the user metrics are excellent for things
like engagement, retention, product market fit
score, MPS, virality, for all of those metrics. I
think you you'll significantly beat your industry
benchmarks if you go to the effort of one-on-one
onboarding your early customers. It becomes so
powerful to have that early cohort of super fans
when it comes to things like building a brand. If
folks remember that conversation from way up at
the top, what is it that creates true virality?
It's not viral mechanics, it's word of mouth. It
is brand. This is how you can kickstart a brand.
And number two, in a world where you can
easily and quickly raise funding, like for
example the zero interest rate phenomenon era,
you can actually use dollars to avoid building
a first-time user experience and all of the
normal growth loops that you would then have
to build. You would then instead focus all of
your engineers on finding product market fit or
in solution deepening or in market widening, but
not for example on a first-time user experience,
not for example on activation, because you have
humans doing activation for you. By contrast I
saw other companies often competing spend almost
half their engineering dollars on those things,
on self-service flows for products that
ultimately did not find products market
fit. So makes sense to do if you really
want to create that brand, which I think all
consumer-ish companies need to do. And if there
is money falling off trees, for whatever reason,
which we did have for a period of time, arguably
AI companies have that again today. So if you
can weave this into your strategy, I think you
should, but you should also know when to stop.
Super interesting. I guess some factors
to think about, because I wanted to ask
you when should people consider doing this?
If they're hearing this and they're like,
"This is awesome, so many problems solved if I
just have somebody onboarding every new user,
everyone's activated. Amazing." So some
of the variables you're sharing is, do you
have like cheap cash to invest in say, it doesn't
have to be 20 people, it could be a few people to
start. Then if there's an LTV, ACV element of just
are you going to make enough from a new customer?
Imagine that's a variable. Is there anything
else you think founders should think about?
Absolutely. You don't want to lose
money doing this. We always made money
doing onboarding to be clear, it's just
that at a certain point the mass market,
whether it for us it's enterprise or all
of the prosumers in the world, you hit a
top of funnel width, it needs to be wide enough
where manually onboarding no longer makes sense.
Awesome. Okay, let's talk about product market
fit. I know that everyone, when they think of
Rahul, they think product market fit. You wrote
this epic First Round post that described the way
you guys approach product market fit. We're not
going to spend a lot of time on describing it,
because people can look it up. So let me just
ask you this, what are a couple of things that
you think people still don't understand about
finding product market fit, getting to product
market fit? Considering it's the most important
thing you got to figure out as a founder. If
you don't find something people want, nothing
else matters. Anything there you want to share.
The core ideas are still weird enough that
I'll start there. Which is number one,
you can measure product market fit. Number two,
you can optimize product market fit. Number three,
you can systematically, even numerically increase
product market fit. And number four, you can even
have an algorithm write your roadmap for you, and
that is a roadmap that is guaranteed to increase
product market fit. Now, if that sounds crazy, I
would be the first to admit it doesn't seem like
that should be true, but go check out that post.
I think it is still the most widely shared post on
First Round Review, it's called How Superhuman
Built an Engine to Find Product Market Fit,
or just Google the Superhuman Product Market
Fit Engine. And you'll see the algorithm laid
out there fully explained and why it works.
I'd say the second thing is to get to product
market fit, you have to deliberately not act on
the feedback of many of your early users. This is
at the same time as listening to people intensely
and building what people want. That's what we're
here to do, is to make something that people
want. But it can't be all people. It can't be
everybody. The question becomes, how do you listen
to them? And then even of what they say, what do
you pay attention to and what don't you? All of
that's covered in the Product Market Fit Engine.
Okay, I got to follow this thought on
algorithmically building your roadmap
to increase product market fit.
Talk about how one would do that.
Well, that's really the meat of the engine.
Let's see if I can condense it here in a very
easy to grok fashion. Let's assume for the
sake of argument, that you can put a number
on product market fit, and it turns out you
can. Very simply, you're going to ask people,
"How would you feel if you can no longer use this
product?" You give them three responses. One of
them is very disappointed, the other is somewhat
disappointed, and the other is not disappointed.
Very disappointed means, "I'd be devastated.
I love this product. I need this product."
What Sean Ellis found, Sean Ellis, if you don't
know him, is the guy who coined the term growth
hacker, and he instrumented, benchmarked
this initial question. What he found,
is that the companies that struggled to
grow almost always had less than 40%,
very disappointed. Whereas the companies that
grew the fastest almost always had more than 40%,
very disappointed. And this question, this metric
is way more predictive of success than something,
for example, like net promoter score.
Okay, so far so easy. How do we make
this number go up? Well, you want more people to
be very disappointed without your product. The
trick here is not to act too much on the feedback
that the very disappointed people are giving you,
because they already love your product. Also, not
to act at all really on the feedback that the not
disappointed people are giving, you because
they're so far from loving your product that
they're essentially a lost cause. But to focus on
the segment of the somewhat disappointed people,
they kind of love your product,
but something, and I would wager
something small, is holding them back.
You then divide them into two camps,
the camp for whom the main benefit of your product
resonates and the camp for whom it doesn't. What
do I mean by that? Well, you go back to the people
who really love your product and you basically ask
them why? What is it about my products that you
really love? In the early days of Superhuman,
it would have been speed and keyboard shortcuts
and the overall design aesthetic as well as the
time that we were saving you. You then go
back to the somewhat disappointed users,
and in the Superhuman example, I would simply ask,
"Wait, do you like Superhuman because of its speed
or for something else?" And if it's something
else, well, and this is hard to do, but politely
disregard those people and their feedback. Because
even if you built everything that they asked for,
they're still pulling you in a different
direction. And the thing that they like
the most from your product isn't actually what
the people who en mass love it the most for, is.
You have then articulated the subsegment of the
subsegment that it makes sense to pay attention
to, and there's another question in the engine to
figure out what they don't like about the product.
Now you have a list of things people love,
you have a list of things people don't love,
and you can work down that list to make
the product market fit score go up. And
basically at the start of every planning cycle,
I advise spending half your time doubling down
on what people really love and half your time
systematically overcoming the objections of the
somewhat disappointed users, but specifically
those for whom the main benefit resonates.
That was an excellent summary. I know I
said we wouldn't spend a ton of time here,
but I'm really glad we did. That was
really helpful. Let me ask you this,
I know you used this initially in the early days,
are you still operating in this way in some form?
We don't run the engine as is for Superhuman
as a whole. There are enough subcomponents
of Superhuman now that are almost individual
products. For example, Superhuman for Sales,
our multiplayer and collaboration features, how we
think about the enterprise, AI is its whole thing,
but we do sometimes run it on those individual
pieces. For example, we'll ask a salesperson,
the Product Market Fit Engine, as it
relates to Superhuman for sales. As
we think about starting new products, we would
absolutely deploy the product market fit engine.
Awesome. The way you ask this question is
an in-product interstitial
sort of survey pop-up thing?
You can do it however you want. The
way Sean initially benchmarked the
number was via email surveys. I think email
surveys work just fine. The key thing is,
and this applies to any survey methodology, if
you're going to change the method of surveying,
all of your old numbers are invalidated.
So it's just a new baseline going forwards.
Got it. We had Sean on the podcast and he
describes this method in detail. So if folks
want to explore the Sean Ellis test,
listen to that podcast. We'll link to it.
Okay, next topic that I'm excited to get your
take on, is game design versus gamification. This
is one of the more unique ways you think about
designing product. When people hear you talk about
this, they think it's like, "Oh, gamification
making things like games. Oh, it's Zynga,
Farmville, I don't want to do that." But you
actually have a really different perspective
on why you need to think about game design as you
design products. Talk about your insights there.
Well, I strongly believe that we should make
business software like we make games, because
when we make products like we make games, people
find them fun. They tell their friends, they fall
in love with them. It's another way actually of
backing into where we open this conversation,
which is you're making a brand, you are giving
reason for word of mouth. It's actually an
altogether different kind of product development.
So how do we do this? Well, as you've said,
it's not gamification, that doesn't work. Game
design works, but game design is not gamification.
It's not, for example, simply taking your product
and adding points, levels, trophies or badges.
To understand why gamification does not work,
we actually have to start with human motivation.
There's a very interesting study from Stanford
that demonstrates the difference perfectly. In
the 1970s, these Stanford researchers recruited
children who were aged three to four years old,
and all of these kids were generally
pre-interested in drawing. Some kids
were told they would get a reward, a certificate
with a gold seal and a ribbon. And some kids were
not told about any reward and they did not
even expect one or didn't know of one. Now
each child was then invited into a separate
room to draw for six minutes and afterwards
they would either get the reward or not.
Over the next few days, the children were observed
to see how much they would continue to draw
by themselves. So the children with no reward,
they spent 17% of their time drawing, but the
children who expected a reward, sadly they
only spent 8% of their time drawing. The very
presence of a reward halved their motivation.
So what's happening? What's happening here, is
researchers differentiate intrinsic motivation
and extrinsic motivation. With intrinsic
motivation we do things because they are
inherently interesting and satisfying, and with
extrinsic motivation, we do things to earn rewards
and to achieve external goals. That's the problem
with rewards, is they just massively undermine
intrinsic motivation. That's why gamification
doesn't work. And when gamification does work,
it's because the underlying experience
was already designed like a game.
What makes something like a game? I
know Superhuman is really good at this,
of just your inbox zero quest that you're
on. Just to make that a little more real,
what is game design? What does that mean
to you? What makes it feel like a game?
Well, maybe folks don't know this, but before
I was a founder, you can probably tell, I was
actually professionally a game designer. And as
it turns out, there is no unifying theory of game
design. To create games, what we need to do is
draw upon the arts and the science of psychology,
mathematics, storytelling, interaction design.
And at Superhuman we've identified five key
areas that we really care about, goals,
emotions, toys, controls and flow. And
across these we've identified many principles
of game design. One example principle would be,
make fun toys and then combine those into games.
A question I like to ask is, are toys the same as
games? They do seem different. For example, we
play with toys, but we play games. A ball is a
toy, but football is a game. As it turns out,
the best games are constructed out of toys.
Why? Because then they are fun on both levels,
the toy and the game itself. So for example, in
Superhuman, one of our favorite toys is the time
auto-completer. If you use Superhuman, this is the
thing that appears when you hit H, when you snooze
or set reminders on emails. You can type whatever
you want, it can be gibberish and it does its best
to understand you. For example, if you type in 2D,
that becomes two days, 3H is three hours, one
MO is one month. The time auto-completer is
fun because it indulges your playful exploration.
In onboardings, it wasn't long before I saw people
asking, "What can it do? Where does it break?
How does it work? What happens if I keep on
typing in a series of tens? Well, it turns out
that's October the 10th at 10:10 PM. Well, how
about a series of twos? Well, that's February the
second, 2022 at 2:00 PM." Then you start trying
more complex inputs like in a fortnight and a
day, and that works, which is a pleasant surprise.
And it's not long before you find more pleasant
surprises like time zone math happens without you
thinking about it. You can just type in 8:00 AM in
Tokyo and it turns out that's 8:00 PM Eastern Time
and you no longer have to do the time zone math.
Then most people were really delighted to find
out that if you really want, you can snooze emails
until never, i.e. you can literally type in never,
and the email will never come back. It had like a
little shrug emoji at the same time. Is this toy
going to win awards? Nope. But is it fun actually,
surprisingly yes. So what I would encourage people
to do is, think about the features of their
product. Do those features indulge, playful,
exploration? Are they fun even without a goal? And
do they elicit moments of pleasant surprise? If
so, you have a toy and you can combine that with
other toys and actually start to build a game.
If people were to listen to this segment of the
podcast, they would never guess we're talking
about B2B software and email, which I love. Let's
talk about pricing strategy and your approach to
pricing. Another very contrarian approach that
you guys took where you charge $30 a month for
email that was free, that people don't need
to pay for anywhere. And it's worked and now
a lot of companies are thinking of it this way.
You've even raised your prices recently. What
have you learned about pricing strategy
that you think might be helpful to folks?
I always say the same thing when it comes to
pricing, which is before you figure out pricing,
you must first figure out positioning. Superhuman
is the best email tool on the market. We
fortunately have the metrics to show this. One
of the cool things about selling an email tool,
is you can compare the 30 days prior to using
Superhuman to the 30 days after, or the year
before to the year after. We do that obviously.
We're able to show that people get through their
email twice as fast with Superhuman, that they
respond one to two days faster, and that they save
four hours or more every single week. Because
of that, we're very confident in saying that
Superhuman is the best email tool on the market
and that we're building it for high performing
teams and high performing individuals. In other
words, we serve the high end of the market.
Once you understand your positioning, you
can then move on to pricing. And one of the
best books on this is a book called Monetizing
Innovation by Madhavan Ramanujam. And Madhavan
covers a lot of ways to develop pricing. We
used one of the easiest methods, which is the
Van Westendorp Price Sensitivity [inaudible
01:07:08]. In the early years, we asked,
I think it was around a hundred of our earliest
users, the following four questions. Number one,
at what price would you consider Superhuman
to be so expensive that you would not consider
buying it? Number two, at what price would
you consider Superhuman to be priced so low
that you'd be worried about its quality
and you wouldn't buy it? At number three,
what price would you consider Superhuman
to be starting to get expensive, so that
it's not out of the question, but you'd have to
give some thought to buying it? And number four,
at what price would you consider Superhuman
to be a bargain? A great buy for the money?,
Now most startups orient around price point
number four. This is especially true for
greenfield opportunities, marketplaces, you've
got to set the transaction value around price
0.4. Basically when you want as many people to
sign up as is humanly possible, at the top of
the funnel. But the price point that supports
our best in class, best in category position,
is actually the third one. It starts to feel
expensive, but then you sit down and you think
about the time that you spend in email, the ROI,
and you still buy it anyway. It turns out that the
median answer for the third question was $30
per month, and that's how we picked our price.
And once we picked our price, we then do a
quick gut check on market size. For example,
we're a venture scale company, but at the time
the question that we had to ask is, "Could we
grow into a billion dollar valuation?" Well,
let's assume that at that point our valuation
is 10 times our ARR, so our ARR would have to
be a hundred million dollars. Well, that would
be 300,000 subscribers at $30 per month. That is
conservatively assuming no other ways to increase
ARP. You mentioned price increase, you can also
go up market, you can sell new products and so
on. We asked ourselves, without those tricks, do
we think we can get to hundreds of thousands of
subscribers? And we answered emphatically,
yes, so we went ahead with that price.
Okay, there's a couple more things I want to
chat about in the time that we have and then
I know you have to run. One is around AI and the
work you guys are doing there. I know that's been
a big unlock. And then two, the stuff you're
doing in the enterprise. Then if we have time,
there's a question I want to ask that I think
is a really interesting way you guys operate.
Let's talk about AI first. It feels like there's
this being in the right place at the right time.
It feels like you guys have been building this
for a while, and then AI just unlocked another
stage in what you're able to do with email. Just
talk about what you've done and what how you think
about AI integrating into what you're doing,
how it's enabled you to kind of take off again?
It's true that sometimes startups boil
down to being in the right place at the
right time. We actually had a massive
AI launch recently about two weeks ago,
but even before then we had multiple flagship AI
features. Our first AI feature was write with AI,
jot down a few words and we'll turn them into
a fully written email. We actually match the
voice and tone in the emails you've already
sent. So unlike Co-pilot, unlike Gemini,
unlike basically every other email app, the email
sounds like you. This AI feature is way more
popular than I expected it to be. On average
today, users are using it 37 times per week.
Number two, our next AI feature was auto
summarize, which shows a one line summary
above every conversation. And as new emails
arrive, it updates instantly. Again, unlike
Co-pilot and Gemini, it's pre-computed. One of the
things we do is, we go above and beyond to make
these features really premium and feel amazing.
The next AI feature after that was instant reply.
Imagine waking up to an inbox where every email
already has a draft reply. You would simply edit
and then send, and sometimes you wouldn't even
need to edit. I can share because we just finished
this analysis, that over 2024, the percentage
of emails that are AI written and sent with
Superhuman has grown four times just in one year.
Then if I remember correctly, the feature after
that was Ask AI. Email of course, is this treasure
trove of critical information, things like project
statuses, customer communication, meeting updates,
deal execution, and so much more. And for over 40
years we've had to rely on what we hilariously
call, search. You have to remember senders,
guess keywords, scan subject lines, and now you
can just ask, "Where is the queue one offsite?"
or, "What are my flight details?" Or, "What is
the top five most positive customer responses
to the Ask AI launch?" A task by the way, which
previously used to take me 20 or 30 minutes to
read through all the emails and then create that
report now happening in less than five seconds.
Recently we, like I said, announced our biggest
evolution yet. Superhuman AI is constantly helping
you. It's organizing your inbox. It's also
making sure you never drop the ball. We have
things that we call Auto Labels. You can now write
a short prompt like job applications or requests
to review work, and you can then immediately see
when emails match that prompt, when people apply
for a job or they ask you to review work. With
Auto Reminders, if your email needs a response,
Superhuman will now automatically set a reminder.
You don't have to remember to do that and you'll
never drop the ball again. All you need to do
is hit send. With Auto Drafts, Superhuman will
now automatically draft your follow-up emails
for you and will soon be drafting replies to
basically every email that needs a response.
And finally, with what we call Workflows,
you can now turn email into repeatable automated
workflows. For example, I often get emails from
people who are interested in working at
Superhuman, and I would normally reply to
that candidate and I would let them know that the
team will take a look. I'll then forward to the
original message, including any resume or any
letter to our head of people and operations
and ask her to reach out, if interested. With
Workflows, I can now automate this entire
process. It's, you can imagine, creating a little
flowchart of what has to happen. Not only does
that save a huge amount of time, with Workflows
you don't even have to be in your inbox. In fact,
you don't even have to be working. You could be on
vacation while Superhuman AI is working for you.
This sounds like product market fit
to me. This all sounds wonderful.
It just makes sense. This is
the stuff we've been promised,
our underwater cities and flying cars and
then just email that just works magically
and replies for us and all these things.
I love all these things you're doing.
For folks that are building with AI. I'm
curious, what's maybe been the biggest surprise,
either good or bad, building so deeply on
top of AI models that you think might be
helpful for folks to just, "Watch out
for this," or, "Hey, check this out."?
I think for me the biggest surprise has
been how unpredictable the user love has
been in terms of what they love and what
they don't love. For example, write with
AI. This sounds like a commodity feature and
on all surface level it is. Every email app,
every writing surface has a write with AI feature
in. I would wager ours is the best at emails and
surprisingly that's what we do. But the surprising
thing was just how much people love it and how
often it gets used. 37 times per user per week is
still mind-blowing to me. I had not expected that,
so that's the most surprising thing.
And on the flip side, there were certain
AI features where I did expect a ton of usage,
but we didn't quite get the usage that we were
perhaps hoping for. Hopefully I'm not AI Kramer,
but basically everything I thought would work out
well, people use it less than they thought
they did. And everything where I was like,
"I don't know, but let's build
the thing," people love that.
Interesting.
Maybe I should just create an
anti-me to do AI road-mapping.
That's in a simple agent right there,
whatever Rahul says, do the opposite.
Yeah.
Okay. Another maybe a last topic. I
know that you guys are starting to
move into the enterprise. When people think
of Superhuman, they think of it's consumer-y,
it's for people, and you guys are doing
a lot of work to make it a B2B enterprise
product. For founders maybe that are starting
to think about this transitioning from PLG to
sales led and B2B enterprising, what have
you learned about just what it takes to
get to that point and what does that
sales motion look like for you guys?
In some ways, it's very like selling to prosumers,
except these users are not coming from Gmail where
prosumers would normally come from, they're
coming from Outlook. And Outlook users have
very different expectations to Gmail users.
For example, Outlook users expect their email
app to also be a fully featured calendar
app, whereas Gmail users are happy with
those two things being entirely different. As a
result, we've invested in calendar very heavily
and we continue to do so. There's only so
much I can say, but it's pretty exciting.
[inaudible 01:16:49].
Outlook users are also used to certain safeguards,
like if you've used Outlook in an enterprise,
warnings when a recipient is external to
your domain or what Outlook users might
know as sensitivity labels. And as a result
we've built support for external recipient
indicators and sensitivity labels. But in some
ways it's very different to selling to prosumers
because there are other stakeholders involved. For
example, we've built support for enterprise mobile
management by implementing Microsoft Intune.
We recently sold one of the big three
strategy consulting firms, which is
super exciting. I can't say which one,
but they love Superhuman and they have thousands
of people internally using Superhuman. This is
after a year... They've been piloting for a year
and then accelerating over the last few months.
We only just got them the mobile app, believe
it or not. Because, at an enterprise like that,
there are significant controls on what a allowed
compliant mobile app can and cannot do. For
example, IT needs to be able to control which
apps can save attachments or which apps you can
copy and paste text into from email. And for many
enterprises, those controls are super important.
Wow, okay. So it sounds like
essentially just building all
these features that large companies need,
is kind of the road you're on right now.
Exactly. And there's two stakeholders. There's the
users, which are actually quite different because
they're Outlook users and Calendar is one
of the main ways that manifests. There's a
whole bunch of other stakeholders, IT is one of
them, but there are others as well. For example,
companies this large have workplace
management groups who want to see
analytics of how people are working, how
they can make their teams more efficient,
so it truly is a multi-threaded
sale with multiple stakeholders.
They had a product from Linear on the podcast
[inaudible 01:18:51], and he actually,
I don't know if you heard that episode, but he
talks about how they decide what to prioritize,
the thing they never build is middle
managers needing to track how their
reports are doing and things like that.
That's an interesting opportunity for
you guys maybe to cut stuff. I don't know.
Anyway, I want to end on one more nugget. Okay,
I'm glad we have time for this. You shared
that you have this system internally at
Superhuman for making decisions. You call it
Single Decisive Reason, SDR. What is that?
SDR is a thinking tool that I picked
up from Reid Hoffman during my time at
LinkedIn. The idea here is that for important
decisions, you should be able to identify one,
one reason that on its own supports the decision.
It's based on the observation that all too often
we rely on a collection of weak reasons to
justify decisions. It's very, very easy to do
this. Imagine you are contemplating a decision,
you write a list of the pros and the cons.
There are three pros, but let's say there
are 10 or 15 cons. The sheer number of cons,
the effort of thinking them through, the time it
took to write them down, is going to affect you,
consciously or worse subconsciously. This is
especially true, I've seen in group settings,
which just in general are a little bit more risk
averse and a little bit more consensus driven.
So whenever anyone is making a decision and
they bring that decision to me and they say,
"Well, we want to do this because of X, Y, Z,
and there are multiple reasons." I ask them,
"What's the SDR? What's the single decisive
reason?" If they can't yet isolate it,
that tells me they haven't yet figured out why
they want to make the decision. It doesn't mean
the decision is wrong, it just means that they
haven't figured out the singular reason why we
should do the thing. They can then go through
their list of reasons and ask, "Is this alone
enough to support this decision?" Meaning if this
was true and all the other things were not true,
would I still do it? And sometimes we still
do, but actually sometimes we don't. We realize
that a collection of weak reasons alone means
that, for example, the outcome is less likely
than we thought it was, or it was hiding a really
strong reason on the other side of the decision.
That is very cool. This is just when
someone comes to you with a decision,
the way you use this idea is, you ask
them what's the single decisive reason?
Pretty much. Yeah. And what they
can't do, obviously this happens,
people are human and natural, they'll usually
start mentioning three or four things,
and that's fine. And then I will say, "Okay,
but if only one of those was true and you're
still advocating for this decision, what is it?"
I think that's just a bar for a good decision.
Why is that so important? Because you found that a
bunch of low quality reasons just don't
add up to a good reason to do something?
Multiple reasons, which is ironic. But that's
my SDR for why SDRs work. Which is yes,
multiple low quality reasons rarely add up
to a high quality reason to do something. But
there are also other things as well, which is,
any decision you take has an opportunity cost.
Any feature you build is another feature that
you didn't build. If we're going to build this
for a collection of weak reasons, whereas
we could build that for one strong reason,
I'd much rather build that for one
strong reason. Now this is all other
things being equal, and these things
often end up being quite complicated,
but you can apply SDR all the way down. You
just did that to me, what's my SDR for SDR?
There we go. Rahul, is there anything that we
haven't covered that you wanted to cover? Is
there any last piece of wisdom you want to
leave listeners with before we let you go?
I feel good. I think we covered a lot. Thank you
for asking amazing questions. This was really fun.
This was incredible. Okay, so let me
just ask you this then. Where can folks
find you online? Where can they check
out Superhuman? What should they know
before they try it out? And then just
how can listeners be useful to you?
If you want to find me online, I am generally on
X. That is x.com/rahulvohra, R-A-H-U-L V-O-H-R-A.
My DMs are open, so feel free to ping me. If
you're going to do that, I would suggest also
emailing me, that's rahul@superhuman.com,
and hopefully I'll see your message soon.
If you haven't tried Superhuman, then gosh, what
are you doing? This is my call to you to do so,
because your time is worth more than
whatever you think it might be. So go
download Superhuman and give it a shot. Invite
your team. The metrics are real. I know they
sound like the kind of metrics that startups make
up, but getting through your email twice as fast,
responding one to two days sooner, saving four
hours or more every single week, they're all real.
Actually, speaking of which, the consulting
firm I mentioned earlier, because they're
so into data and into analysis, they wanted
to corroborate those numbers for themselves,
and so they did. They ran their own internal
case study on Superhuman, and they were like,
"Yeah, you're saving our partners 3.3 hours per
person per week. And there's only one other tool
that we've bought that does that, which is
ChatGPT. So thank you. We love Superhuman.
We're rolling it out." If that sounds interesting
to you or your company, please do give it a shot.
That is super cool. Reflecting back on what
I imagine this conversation would look like,
a lot of contrarian thinking and attention to
detail, I think that's exactly what it was. Rahul,
you're awesome. Thank you so much for being here.
Thank you. Bye everyone.
Bye everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you can
subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also, please
consider giving us a rating or leaving a review,
as that really helps other listeners
find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.