You don't want to walk into the gym on
day one and try and deadlift 300 pounds.
So when someone comes to me and they're
a first time entrepreneur and they say,
"I'm going to make the next great AI
company," I think that is the equivalent.
I feel like you've actually started and
run more companies than maybe anyone else
in the world. What is your best advice
for coming up with a great startup idea?
Charlie Munger, Warren Buffett's longtime
business partner, has this amazing quote.
Fish where the fish are.
The biggest mistakes I've made have
been going into business models where
other people have repeatedly failed
and thinking, I can do this better.
It's so funny to watch you on Twitter.
Clearly you've become AI obsessed.
It's like having the world's most
reliable employee who costs $200 a
month and works 24/7. So many knowledge
work jobs are going to change massively.
I think the fundamental question is, do
all jobs just become a single prompt?
Today, my guest is Andrew Wilkinson. Andrew
is the co-founder and CEO of Tiny, a holding
company that's often called the Berkshire
Hathaway of the internet. They own over 40
businesses ranging from Dribble to WeCommerce to
the AeroPress coffee maker, and they focused on
buying profitable businesses from founders and
holding them for the long term. Andrew and his
co-founder bootstrapped the business from zero
to hundreds of millions of dollars in value,
and Andrew personally was worth over $1 billion
at one point. In our wide-ranging conversation,
we cover a bunch of strategies for coming up with
a good business idea, what common business ideas
you should avoid, his experience automating much
of his work and life using AI, and what that means
for employment in the near future. Also, what
he's learned about happiness and money and how
they're not directly related, and also how getting
diagnosed with ADHD and then taking SSRIs was the
thing that most impacted his happiness in life.
This is both a powerful and also a very tactically
useful conversation and I'm really excited
for you to hear it. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in
your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. Also,
if you become an annual subscriber of
my newsletter, you get a year free of a
bunch of amazing products including Bolt, Linear,
Superhuman, Notion, Perplexity, Granola and more.
Check it out at Lenny's newsletter.com and click
bundle. With that, I bring you Andrew Wilkinson.
This episode is brought to you by Sauce. The way
teams turn feedback into product impact is stuck
in the past, vague reports, static taxonomies,
unactionable insights that don't move business
metrics. The result, churn, lost deals, misgrowth.
Sauce is the AI product copilot that helps CPOs
and product teams uncover business impact and
act faster. It listens to your sales calls,
support tickets, churn reasons, and
lost deals, surfacing the biggest
product issues and opportunities in real time.
It then routes them to the right teams to turn
signals into PRDs, prototypes, and even code
that drives revenue retention and adoption.
That's why Whatnot, Linktree, Incident.io and Zip
use Sauce one enterprise uncovered a product gap
that unlocked $16 million ARR, another caught a
issue and prevented millions in churn. You can
too at sauce.app/lenny. Sauce built for
AI product teams, don't get left behind.
This episode is brought to you by Enterpret.
Enterpret is a customer intelligence platform
used by a leading CXN product orgs like
Canva, Notion, Perplexity, Strava, Hinge,
and Linear to leverage the voice of the
customer and build best-in-class products.
Enterpret unifies all customer conversations
in real time, from Gong recordings to Zendesk,
tickets to Twitter threads, and makes it available
for your team for analysis and for action.
What makes Enterpret unique is its ability to
build and update a customer-specific knowledge
graph that provides the most granular and
accurate categorization of all customer
feedback and connects that customer feedback
to critical metrics like revenue and CSAT.
If modernizing your voice of customer program
to a generational upgrade is a 2025 priority,
like customer-centric industry leaders
like Canva, Notion, Perplexity, and Linear,
reach out to the team at enterpret.com/lenny.
That's E-N-T-E-R-P-R-E-T.com/lenny.
Andrew, thank you so much for
being here. Welcome to the podcast.
Oh, thanks man, great to be here.
I've been wanting to chat with you for so
long. There's so much that I want to talk
about and I want to start with a topic that
I know that you think a lot about and that
it's also in the minds of a lot of people,
which is coming up with a great startup idea
and this is something that a lot of people are
thinking about right now because AI makes it so
easy to actually build your idea into something
real, and I feel like this is something you spent
a lot of time thinking about. I feel like you've
actually started and run more companies than,
I don't know, maybe anyone else in the world. I
feel like you're in the top a hundred, top 10,
something like that. I don't
know. Does that feel right?
I've definitely had a lot of experiences and
I've probably started or been involved with
75 different projects or businesses where I've
been a primary contributor and I wouldn't say
that's anything to brag about because I've been
an inch deep in a mile wide. So that's been in
a lot of ways kind of my Achilles heel is I
get too excited about ideas and I start too
many businesses, but as a result I've seen
almost every business model under the sun.
Amazing. Okay. Yeah, I think the benefit is for
us is we get to learn from your experience. Let
me just ask you this question, what is your best
advice for coming up with a great startup idea?
Ultimately the best thing is something you're
going to be interested in, but I think a mistake
a lot of people make is they choose something
that everybody is interested in. So for example,
they say I don't know anyone that has hadn't
had the thought, man, I would love to start
a really cool restaurant or I want to have
a cool cafe or something. And in reality,
what they think about is how cool would it be to
come up with an amazing logo or all fun stuff,
design the menu and stuff. But in reality,
operating those businesses is miserable and
it's also a very hard business because every
morning millions of people wake up and they go,
I should start a cafe. But on the flip side,
almost nobody wakes up every morning and says,
"You know what? I'd love to start a funeral
home," or "I would like to start a pest control
business," or "I should start software that
helps people fill out forms for the government."
And Charlie Munger, Warren Buffett's longtime
business partner, has this amazing quote. He says,
"Fish where the fish are." And he gives this
example, he says, "If you're a fisherman and
you see a large pond and all around the pond,
there's a whole bunch of fishermen and they're
all elbowing each other out of the way. They're
all using the best lures, the best fishing line,
they all have amazing strategy. You actually
want to walk off into the forest and find a
small fishing hole with lots of fish and very
little competition. And I think that's probably
the most important thing in business is actually
to find those niches where you can actually make
real money because competition equals lower
margin. The more competitors there are,
the lower your prices have to be and the
more competitive the business is ultimately.
It doesn't feel intuitive to go
after small markets and to find
niches. So let's just follow that thread. Well,
why is that actually a source of some of the
best ideas starting really small and niche?
I don't necessarily think it has to be something
that is small forever, but it has to be something
that like I think about if you're a first
time entrepreneur or a student or something,
you don't want to walk into the gym on day one
and try and deadlift 300 pounds. So when someone
comes to me and they're a first time entrepreneur
and they say, "I'm going to make the next great AI
company," or "I'm going to launch a new bank," or
something like that, something that is very, very
rigorous and complicated and highly competitive
and regulated, I think that is the equivalent.
I think you really want to take the baby weights
and start slowly building your muscle. And I think
about my own experience starting a business, I was
so lucky because the first business I ever started
my web design agency, which became Metalab, that
was so easy and it worked immediately because all
I had to do was know how to build websites
and be able to talk to potential customers.
And then once they said, "Yes, I will pay you
$5,000," I just had to send them an invoice,
do the work, and that was it. It was a
very simple business. And because of that,
I got immediate positive feedback and I
built my own narrative. And my narrative was,
"I'm good at business, I can do this, keep going."
And then I went off and I started taking my money
that I made from that original business and
that's when I fucked up. So I went out and I
started a pizzeria and I lost all my money.
I started a designer cat furniture business,
a online DJ school, a skin cream business,
all of these things. I've just lost all my
money almost immediately, but because I had
that first win I kept on going. And I just
think it's so critical that people choose
a business where they get that initial win.
Okay, this is a great topic. This is just like how
do you avoid creating a job for yourself that you
hate? There's a lot of business opportunities
and ideas that like, "Yeah, you can make this
work," and then it works, and then you're
stuck doing this thing running a restaurant.
My wife tells a story where a friend started a
coffee shop and then he's like, "I thought I was
starting a coffee shop, but I'm just replacing
milk and buying milk all day. That's my job
now." So just kind of along those lines to help
people avoid creating a beast that they didn't
expect any advice for Just how to know this is
maybe even though this may work and make money,
you probably don't want to be spending
your life doing this sort of business.
So I just started a pressure washing business.
I was speaking at a local business school and
after I spoke, one of the kids walked up to me
and he said, "Hey, I'm an entrepreneur. I've
started two or three businesses in the past doing
landscaping and I'm not enjoying school." And so
just on the spot, I said to him, "Why don't you
drop out and we'll start a business together?"
And I'd been cooking on this idea of a pressure
washing business because I'd studied that industry
a little bit and I knew a few friends who'd
done it in other cities. And I had this unfair
advantage, which is I owned a whole bunch of media
properties where I could advertise it for free
basically. And so we started this business and
I think for him, he kind of had this moment of,
do I really want to be washing people's
driveways for the rest of my life?
And what I said to him is, "Look, if this gets
to scale, you'll never touch a pressure washer
unless you want to." If the business can
get big enough where you can have employees,
he can just focus on sales or digital marketing
or whatever aspect of the business that he really
loves. And I think that's the biggest thing
that a lot of entrepreneurs miss. They say,
"I don't want to do that for the rest of
my life. I don't want to be in the back
of a dry cleaner dry cleaning clothes." And
to me it's just a question of scale. I think
the cafe is a great example because a cafe, if it
doesn't get to a reasonable scale is just a job.
There's a big difference between a
business and a job. I think if you
could start a pressure washing business where
you're the only employee, yeah, that's a job,
but if you can get to a scale where you can
drive 10 leads a day, then you don't have to
do any of the pressure washing and you just do
what you love. So I think a lot of people have
this kind of Protestant work ethic where they
think, well, I've got to be the person to do
everything. And I think they really need to lean
into what I call lazy leadership, which is how do
I get away from the things I hate as quickly as
humanly possible? How do I be Teflon for tasks?
It's interesting that this business
is non-software related at all,
this pressure washing business. So I guess
just for folks that are coming up with ideas,
and I imagine most ideas are there's
a pull to make it software oriented,
something AI is going to help build for you and
help you run. What's your calculus on just going
down a direction of real world physical business,
like a restaurant power washing business versus
a software just like what are the benefits
of that direction when should someone
actually seriously think about doing a
business like a power washing business?
I think if someone's listening to this podcast,
odds are they're someone who's kind of a digital
native. And I think the question is, what's your
unfair advantage and what are you great at? So for
me, I think I have reasonably good taste. And so
what I could do is I identify and I knew enough to
identify great design and development talent, but
mostly I was lucky because I was a talker. I was
good at meeting with clients and selling myself.
And so ultimately my highest and best use my
superpower was sales. And so that can be applied
to anything, anything where you need to go out and
you need to sell a customer. And so really it just
comes down to what do you get drawn to and then
how do you find the profitable business within
that? So here's an example. A friend of mine,
he owns a restaurant and he said, "Oh, I love
it. I'm so passionate about it. It's this
stunning beautiful restaurant in my hometown."
And he said, "But it's really just a job for a few
different people and we can't make any money at
it, but I've been noticing that there's all these
vendors that service the restaurant and those guys
are making a killing." And so he told me about a
business that cleans grease traps, another
one that cleans exhaust vents for kitchens.
So I think looking around and seeing where your
passion is and then sniffing around within it,
probably somewhere within your passion, there's
an opportunity. So for example, I love movies.
My happy place is a dark theater. That's the
best way for me to de-stress is go to a dark
theater and watch a movie and get lost in it. And
probably about four or five years ago, I was like,
"Man, how cool would it be to invest in movies
in some way to be a part of that creative world?"
And so I started looking into funding movies
and I realized that when you fund movies,
like 90% of the time you lose all your money.
And even if you do make some money, you rarely
make a good return. But I spend a bunch of time
understanding the industry and learning about it.
And then two years ago I was in New Zealand and
I met the founder of Letterboxd and I realized,
"Oh my God, this is a business where this
has a moat, so it has a network effect,
it's a huge social network for film reviewers.
It's something I'm passionate about and it's
something that we can buy at a fair price."
All those things came together and I was like,
"Oh my god, I can invest in film now."
In the same way I used to be a barista,
we ended up buying the AeroPress coffee maker
company. So I follow my passions and spend a
long time learning different industries and
then I find the profitable niche within.
Okay, and this is a great takeaway essentially
when you're thinking about startup ideas,
make sure there's some connection to
something unique to you where you have
some unfair advantage. This makes me think
about Brian Armstrong. I saw him do a talk
once and he gave this really amazing insight
about why Coinbase did well and why he started
Coinbase. And it's because if you look at
his background, he had this really rare
Venn diagram of background of computer science
and I think it was cryptography and economics,
which is the exact set of skills you need to
start something like Coinbase. So I think the
tip there is just what is that unique Venn
diagram of skills in your background and
just ideally what you're building connects
to that and gives you an unfair advantage.
Well, yeah. I just met another UVic student at
the local university student. She is interested
in marketing and so she's gone out and she's found
some local clients, so small restaurants and stuff
and managed their social media and she said,
"Yeah, it's okay. I can make a thousand bucks
a month, but it's a lot of work," and the owners
really want a lot for their money. And I said,
"Well, if you just pivot that idea just ever
so slightly, and instead of doing restaurants,
you did realtors or wealth managers who have
quite a large marketing budget and are used to
spending serious money and it only has to work
a little bit to make a lot of money for them.
Those people, you can charge $5,000 a month."
So I think often it's you find your passion,
your skill set, you zero in, and then you just
kind of pivot and you find the most profitable
way to do it. When I started my web design firm,
I started mostly with local and small projects,
but very quickly I found a job board in
San Francisco where startups would share
projects they needed help with. I could charge
five times the amount for five times less work.
This point about fish where the fish are
I think is really important. You can start
something that's awesome that you love, that
you're so excited about, but nobody needs
it. Talk a bit more about just what that looks
like. What have you seen when you're thinking
about ideas that tell you that there's fish
but also not overfished as you pointed out?
I think it's hard like Warren Buffett has this
great quote, "I'm a better businessman because
I'm an investor and I'm a better investor because
I'm a businessman." And I feel like in order to
know what problems are valuable to solve,
you kind of need to have valuable problems.
So it's a bit of a hard thing because I
remember when I was like 20, I would say,
I hate how all the cat furniture I can buy
for my cats is I bet people would pay a
lot of money to solve this, but I didn't
understand anything about the realities
of that business model. I didn't understand
how little people were actually willing to
pay. I didn't have a enough life experience
to go, "Yes, that's actually a worthwhile
opportunity." And I think that being able
to know what people would pay to solve the
problem realistically is incredibly valuable.
So my example of a realtor selling a house,
because I've studied that industry, I know
that a realtor can make like 20 to $50,000
selling a single house. So I can intuit that
they'd be willing to spend a lot of money if
I have a unique way of getting them clients
that'll buy houses that'll convert at a high
conversion rate that is worth $5,000 a lead
maybe, right? So I think you kind of have
to understand the problem in depth before you
really know. Because when I was starting out,
I would go down every rabbit trail, every
infomercial idea I had I would think was genius.
Or people, I don't know, that don't have this
experience, which is most people. Is there one
thing you do, maybe a heuristic that gives
you a sense, maybe there's something here,
maybe there's a lot of fish, maybe it's a value of
prompt or no, the soul tell me it probably isn't.
No, unfortunately, I think it's mostly gut. I mean
Munger and Buffett talk about having a whole bunch
of mental models in your brain and they form a
latticework, right? And they all kind of piece
together. And I feel like for me, there's so
much of this that is, it's almost like I'm an
AI model and I've trained on all this data of
what works and what doesn't and what's a good
moat and what's a bad business, et cetera. And
when I see it, I just immediately know. I mean,
I think all entrepreneurs are so lucky now to be
able to go into Claude or ChatGPT and just say,
"Hey, I'm thinking about starting a Botox
clinic. Can you break down the numbers? Is
this a good business? What's hard about it? What
is the regulatory moat? What would my payroll
look like?" I didn't have any of that and so I
started so many incredibly stupid businesses,
but I think there's no excuse at this
point. You should be able to do it with AI.
That's a really good tip actually. Then
there's this point you made about boring
is good. That's a really good piece of advice.
A lot of people are going after flashy stuff,
things they condemn on Twitter. Your
advice here is boring is actually a
really good thing because fewer people are
going after it. Is that the general tip?
Totally. I mean, so I started this business, one
of my first called Flow and Flow was basically
Asana before Asana came out. So it was a way to
manage your to-do's and projects with your team
in a web app and we basically did the thing. We
made the mistake that so many entrepreneurs make,
which is to go after an industry that everybody
goes after just like cafes. Everybody has the
idea, man, I wish I could design my own project
management system or my own to-do system. And
not only that, but everybody loves new things.
They love jumping around. I know me personally,
in the last three years, I've probably used three
different productivity systems and I love jumping
around in them and I didn't understand that and
I ended up losing $10 million trying to compete
with venture-backed businesses and bootstrapping.
It was all my own money, poured $10 million, lit
it on fire trying to compete with Asana because
I didn't understand how the business world worked
really as they had raised hundreds of millions
of dollars and they were run by the co-founder of
Facebook and it was a little bit like, I'm Fiji
and I'm deciding I'm going to invade the United
States in retrospect, just completely silly.
Now on the flip side, if I'd taken that same
amount of energy and I'd instead focused on, let's
see, what's a really boring one I've heard about,
there was a business I saw recently.
They were making $30 million a year and
all they did was help people fill out forms to get
government assistance in certain programs. So it'd
be like your uncle is disabled and you need to
access government funding. The process to do it
is incredibly time-consuming and miserable and
you have to fill out all these forms. They just
have software that fills out the forms for you
and it says, look, you're going to get $20,000
as a grant, pay us a thousand bucks, and that
is such a boring, nobody wakes up and goes, "I
want to make form filling software," but I think
they would if they could make 20 million a year
Along these lines of just bad ideas, things people
shouldn't start, what are a few ideas that you
think everyone thinks is going to be a great idea
and then they do it and then they always fail?
Well, I think the biggest mistake,
I can speak from my own experience,
the biggest mistakes I've made business-wise have
been going into business models where other people
have repeatedly failed and thinking,
I can do this better. So for example,
me and one of my best friends about 10
years ago, we really wanted to start a bar.
We just thought it'd be so cool to have a
bar where us and all of our friends could go,
we thought it'd be great for the city. We thought
we can run this really high margin because we're
tech guys, we know how to build systems, we're
good at business, and we were utterly humbled.
We realized that we didn't know anything about
business compared to someone who runs a pizzeria.
If you think about it, like my example earlier of
if you run a software company, what has to happen?
You have to hire a bunch of nerds, they need
internet connections and computers and you need
to pay them and you need to coordinate online and
everyone can work asynchronously. Nothing has to
go right. It's not that complicated, at least
at small-scale. A pizzeria, it's like if the
baker doesn't wake up at three in the morning and
start prepping dough, the entire thing is effed
and all along the way there's a hundred different
failure points from front of house, back of house,
the deliveries, arriving on time, all this
logistics. And so I think it's been stuff like
that. I mean also I got into the news business,
the local news business. I ended up buying an old
paper in Vancouver and it's the exact same
thing. It's like you can't take a brilliant
management team and change a bad business
model. Ultimately the business model wins.
This is really good advice. Basically if
there's a bunch of dead bodies in that space,
there's probably something there that
keeps killing them that you're probably
not aware of until maybe somebody figures
something out, right? Once in a while,
once in a blue moon, someone's like, "Okay,
here's how we do this and then it works."
Well, look at Instacart. When Instacart came out,
everyone said, "Well, Webvan failed. This is never
going to work." And we still don't necessarily
know if Instacart is a great business. I don't
know, I haven't studied it, but I think it was
like, okay, enough technology has changed that
it can happen, but would it be easier to start
Instacart, Amazon or Coupang or would it be easier
to start an enterprise SaaS software company?
Definitely the enterprise SaaS software company.
I see. So this is I guess is the
advice there. The thing that is
easy to start is the thing you should not
do because everyone's going after that.
Well, it goes back to my gym analogy of
if you're going to deadlift 300 pounds,
trained for 15 years, you should have already
had three startups and they should have worked
and you've really built up the reps. And I
think that if I was going to start Instacart,
that's different than someone who's 20
starting it. Not that I would be good at it,
but at least I would know what I'm getting into.
Let's talk about something that is this endless
debate on Twitter. Maybe it's a false dichotomy
between lifestyle businesses, bootstrap
businesses, this idea of not raising money,
just making revenue, living off the revenue versus
venture-backed venture scale companies feels like
you're very good at the first bucket and a lot
of people, this is their dream, "I'm just going
to start something. I'll start a lifestyle
business, make a few million a year, never
raise money. Who needs VCs? VCs suck." Advice for
deciding which route to go with an idea you have.
Well, I think it's just not true that a
"lifestyle" or bootstrap business can't get huge.
I mean, we bootstrapped the entire business and
now across all of our companies we do almost $300
million in revenue. And the whole time I had been
focusing on taking, starting small businesses,
small ideas, simple ideas, often buying small
companies and watching them grow really big.
And I think that the only difference between what
we do and what a venture capitalist does is the
level of tolerance of burning money on fire.
And I just haven't seen that If we choose the
right businesses that aren't in incredibly
competitive markets or where they have some
sort of moat. So what I mean by that is a great
brand or a network effect like a social network
or something like that, I don't feel we're holding
them back by not letting them light up a bunch of
money on fire because these things naturally grow.
The numbers, I mean they're like balloons, they
just go as long as we don't mess them up too much.
So I think the decision ultimately comes down to
how hairy do you want your big, hairy, audacious
goal to be? And if your big, hairy, audacious goal
is I'm going to start the next satellite business
that creates some sort of crazy technological
revolution. Yes, you're going to have to raise
a venture capital unless you're already a
billionaire or something like that. But if you're
wanting to just tinker and solve a problem that
you think is not going to be hyper-competitive, so
for example, that form-filling thing or software
that just does a narrow thing that doesn't require
20, 30, 40 million to be lit on fire before it can
make money, then you can have a wonderful life
and build a wonderful company that can scale
into the hundreds of millions of dollars if you
play your cards right without ever raising money.
Per the story you shared with Flow where you're
competing against a venture-funded company,
if there is a venture-backed company
in this space, is the advice you're not
going to win competing with them most
likely and try to do something else.
Well, look at Things. Do you know Things?
I have used Things
I do too. It's awesome. Things still exist and
Things has existed for 20 years. It's run by
I believe one or two or three people. It's not
a big team, certainly under 10 people, it was,
I believe, bootstrapped and it's just consistently
delivered an exceptional product and built up a
loyal following. They have their 10,000 true
fans who use it, and that's enough for them,
but they don't do a lot. They've been very
intentional. They don't do any AI stuff,
they don't have an API. They're not on
Android. They're very focused and I think
they have succeeded. But the question is, what
would an MBA or a business professor say about
their success? If the measure of success is
did they maximize taking as much market share
as possible and grow to be as big as possible,
then the answer is no because Asana and other
people have built multi-billion dollar companies.
If the goal is the founder has an incredible life,
probably has three houses, flies all over the
place, does whatever he wants, has recurring
revenue and he gets to work with headphones
on building beautiful piece of software that
people love, then I think he's won. I am generally
much more in the camp of the Things guy has won,
not Dustin Moskovitz. Dustin Moskovitz is just
playing a different game than the Things guy. And
if Dustin Moskovitz was running Things, he'd be
miserable and if the Things guy was running Asana,
he would probably kill himself because he
wants to put his headphones on and build.
I wonder why nobody has come. It feels
like just with lifestyle businesses,
if it's working and you would think
somebody would come in with more money
and more funding and just eat their
lunch, is the key that the market is
too small for a VC to ever be excited and
so that's why no one's coming for them?
I think so. I mean, I think Things probably, I'm
just guessing, I don't know any of the numbers
or whatever, but I would assume it makes
between five and $25 million of revenue,
which to a VC is not even worth considering
a VC. For a VC to invest in your business,
you need to have a story where it's worth
300 million to a billion dollars or more.
So it's just not that exciting to them, which
again, going back to fish where the fish are,
you don't want to be fighting against the
commercial fishermen. If you just want to
have a little business where you get enough fish
to feed your family and your village or whatever,
find the other fishing hole.
Don't go where the trawlers are.
This is great advice if you're trying to start a
non venture backed company is find. This metaphor
just keeps working for us, which is fish where the
fish are, but not where the professional fishermen
are. Also, ideally not where there's just a ton
of, I don't know, fishermen from all over the
place. I don't know, solopreneur fishermen. Okay.
Coming back to just starting a successful company,
what would you say are the keys to an amazing
business model, an amazing business broadly,
what should you be thinking about and looking
into? I know you spent a lot of time thinking
about this. When you're buying companies, what
are a few bullet points that you want to focus on?
What I do for a living is basically buy
businesses. So in my early career I started one
business, then I started about 10 more, and then
I realized starting businesses was extremely hard
and I was doing pretty well. I was making quite
a bit of money and I'd sold one of my businesses
and I was looking out at the next 10 years and
really asking myself what do I want my career to
be and am I happy doing what I'm doing? And the
answer was no. I did not starting businesses and
experiencing that failure rate, it was incredibly
stressful. And so I picked up a book about
investing and I got lucky. The first one I bought
was about Warren Buffett, and for those that don't
know, Warren Buffett is he's counter to every
VC kind of hustle culture thing you might hear
because he basically just sits quietly in a room
and reads all day, despite owning 260 different
businesses and being one of the 10 wealthiest
people in the world, his life is incredibly calm.
He only does what he wants and he spends most of
his time quietly reading and once or twice a year,
he makes a big decision to buy a business. And so
when I read about Warren Buffett, I just thought,
wow, I'm a sucker. I'm running around like a crazy
person trying to run all these businesses. Why
am I not just buying businesses and letting
them run? And so when I'm buying a business,
what I'm really looking for is
something that I can't mess up.
Right now, obviously we buy a business, we try
not to mess it up, and we're very intentional,
actually very odd in that when Tiny buys a
company, we generally just leave them alone.
If they already have management in place, we say
nothing changes, no one should know that we've
even bought them. Obviously people know that,
but really there should be no change whatsoever.
The only change that we generally make is
if the founder wants to leave the business,
then we'll bring in a CEO to run the company, and
that's probably the most important decision that
we make. So I'm looking for a business though
where it is so good that it's hard to mess up,
and most businesses are very easy to mess up.
One person leaves and the whole business falls
apart because it's held together with dental
floss and duct tape. And so I'm really looking
for what Warren Buffett would call a moat. So
a moat is basically a brand, so that could be a
brand like Coca-Cola, Tylenol, Advil, something
like that. So something that gives you pricing
power where you can consistently charge and you
have loyal customers or where we usually find a
lot of opportunity is in network effects.
So typically we're looking for a community
that's gotten so big where people don't want to
go elsewhere. So for example, we own Letterboxd,
which is the largest social network for film
lovers. And the question is, if someone else
wants to compete with us, why would someone go
to their social network that has a small number
of users when all their friends are already on
Letterboxd? And so you see that same kind of thing
with Instagram or Facebook or similar. And so
we're looking for businesses like that, something
that has staying power that is hard to compete
with and that we can hold over the very long term.
It was interesting when Elon bought X,
how that was such a test of the power
of network effects. If you think about
it, back then he changed the name. So
the brand completely changed the team.
80% of the people left. What was left,
it was the network and the network effect
and the simplest way. Just for folks that
aren't super familiar with network effects, the
way I think about it is just network effect is
where every additional user that joins the
network becomes more useful for everybody.
There's another moat, which is high switching
costs, which I don't really like because it's not
really very consumer friendly, but an example
might be Salesforce where no one wants to,
they've spent years and they've done all the
implementation and trained everyone on it,
and it's kind of the standard, everybody
hates it, but ripping it out and switching
is such a pain in the that they just won't
bother. That's another form of sometimes a
great business, but again, that's more
depressing. I don't love that one.
What's the last company you guys bought?
We bought Serato. Serato is the largest DJ
software company in the world. So if you
ever see a DJ playing and they've got a laptop
in front of them, probably using Serato to DJ.
Wow, that is super cool. What I'd
like a funding to be walking into.
I used to DJ so I was aware of them and it
was one of those moments we talked about
earlier where I understood the business. They
had a really interesting mode of this huge
passionate user base and deep hardware
integration. And I also love DJing and
I was able to analyze the business and luck
comes to the prepared mind and it worked out.
This is another great callback to your
excellent piece of advice of just ideally
what you're working on, whether you're
starting the company or buying the company,
is you have a unique unfair advantage or some kind
of unique background that connects to that idea.
Let me ask you one more question before we shift
a whole different topic, hint, hint, AI. Something
that I know you talk a lot about, something you
believe strongly and something you deal with a
lot is when you buy companies is just as people
and the challenges of management and hiring and
people. So what have you learned about just how to
successfully, I don't know, find amazing people,
keep amazing people, help people be more
successful within the companies that you operate?
My business partner, Chris, has a really great
quote. He says, "There are no problems. There is
only people problems." And so we've found that
you could tell us that there's a disaster that
one of our business units is about to fail or
something like that. As long as I'm surrounded
by really great smart people, I feel fine. But
when we have a bad actor, we have a psycho or a
narcissist or a really horrible, difficult person
we're dealing with, all bets are off and life
becomes incredibly stressful. So I'd say I spend
probably 20% of my time just trying to make sure
we're filtering people very carefully and ensuring
we're working with people that we enjoy. And I
could talk about it in the AI, I've done some
really interesting stuff to help me screen and
identify difficult people, but I've just found
that the biggest mistake I made in my early career
was I would hire people because I liked them on
gut and I would think that I could change them.
So it's kind of like in romantic relationships,
it never works out well. If you get married to
someone and you go, "Okay, well this is
going to be a great relationship as long
as I can convert them to Christianity or I can
change their parents or their personality," or
whatever it is. And so I've just found that I've
never been able to change someone. You can never
mentor someone out into being a good employee. And
the kind of heuristic I have is if I ever think,
should I fire this person even once, I should
fire them immediately. It has always been a
signal, at least for me, that when someone's a
superstar, I can't imagine firing them. I think
it's impossible, I'd be lost without them.
But when I repeatedly start going, "Man,
is this person going to work out?" Almost always
within six to 12 months, it doesn't work out. And
so I really try and be really direct about stuff
like that and just cut when it's not working. So
I'd say the lesson really is hire for what
you need. Don't hire just for potential,
which is counter to what a lot of people say. A
lot of people say hire for potential and coach
them into being whatever you need. I just haven't
found that. I think you need to hire someone who
already is fully formed and can do what you
need. But again, everyone does it differently.
This is big advice. Powerful advice. Is
this true not just for the CEOs of the
companies you run? As for folks
under lower down the ladder too?
Well, for CEOs, one of the most interesting things
we've observed is, so I'll give you an example.
We had a CEO come in and we were interviewing
them and in my opinion, the business needed to
grow via organic marketing. In his opinion, it was
enterprise sales. And so when we're interviewing
him, he keeps going back to his experience
building with enterprise sales. And there's
this great saying, "To a man with a hammer,
everything looks like a nail." And so for him,
he's looking at this business and going enterprise
sales, that's the way to grow. I hire him, but I
say, "Look, if we're going to hire you, we need
you to do the organic marketing." Lo and behold,
of course, he goes off and he does the enterprise
sales thing. And I've just found that hiring CEOs
is like they're an elephant and you're the rider.
They're going to go wherever it is that they want
to go. And so listening incredibly carefully to
people's words and their experiences, because
generally people will do the thing they tell you.
So what I look for when I interview a CEO now,
I want to be nodding along. I want to go, that's
exactly what I would do or that's way smarter than
my idea. And then I just leave them alone because
I've found that anytime I try and pull them in a
certain direction or coach them or whatever,
it just doesn't work. And again, this could
be my problem. I might be the world's worst coach
and mentor, but for me, that's been what's true.
I imagine there's also an element of
they won't love the job if they want
to be doing say enterprise sales, and then they're
creating viral TikTok videos all day and
tweeting. They're like, "What the hell?"
Well, I've also found people will shoot
themselves in the foot. If I tell them an
idea in a board meeting and I say, "I really need
you to try this," it never works because usually
they sandbag it, right? They don't really put
their heart into it or they're just placating
me and they don't want it to work. They want their
idea to work. And so I've learned not to do that.
This episode is brought to you by Miro. Every
day new headlines are scaring us about all the
ways that AI is coming for our jobs, creating
a lot of anxiety and fear. But a recent survey
for Miro tells a different story. 76% of people
believe that AI can benefit their role, but over
50% of people struggle to know when to use it.
Enter Miro's innovation Workspace, an intelligent
platform that brings people and AI together in a
shared space to get great work done. Miro has been
empowering teams to transform bold ideas into
the next big thing for over a decade. Today,
they're at the forefront of bringing products
to market even faster by unleashing the combined
power of AI and human potential. Teams can work
with Miro AI to turn unstructured data like sticky
notes or screenshots into usable diagrams, product
briefs, data tables, and prototypes in minutes.
You don't have to be an AI master or to toggle
yet another tool. The work you're already doing
in Miro's canvas is the prompt. Help your teams
get great work done with Miro. Check it out at
Miro.com to find out how. That's M-I-R-O.com.
Let's talk about AI. It's so funny to watch you
on Twitter. Clearly you've become AI obsessed,
AIphile. I don't know what the term is, and I
love that you're not just the kind of person that
just talks about it and tweets pontifications,
you're clearly using it in every facet of
your job and looking for more ways to use
AI. So I have a lot of questions here because
I think this is where more and more founders
are going to be where you are today. First
of all, just what's in your AI stack these
days? What are the tools you find yourself
coming back to most or finding most useful?
So the primary tool I use is a tool called
Lindy, Lindy.ai. And what it basically lets you
do is build workflows and agents. So it's very
simple. You might say, "When I get an email in
the Gmail API, I want to add an AI agent that
reads the email and labels it based on that."
Or you can build a crazy Rube Goldberg machine
that sends different emails all sorts of different
places. So for example, when I get an email and
it's related to my kid's school, one of the big
problems I have is that my kid's school sends
so many emails, the field trip is on Thursday
and you need to bring the following things. And
meanwhile, there's parent teacher interviews and
all these things get added to my calendar. The
AI agent automatically takes that, puts it onto
my calendar, makes sure there's notes for all the
things I need to prepare and stuff. So I have just
basically tried to take every single thing a human
could do in my inbox and automate it with Lindy.
And you're sitting there in Lindy
doing this yourself or do you have
people that you've trained to help
build these sorts of things for you?
No, I do it myself.
Okay. How many agents, if that's the term you
want to use, do you have running for you roughly?
Oh man, I think I probably have not a
crazy amount within... Let's see. Well,
each workflow probably has four or five agents.
So for example, my inbox has four or five agents,
and then I have a whole bunch of
other, I've got a calendar agent,
I've got a meeting agent, I've got an email
agent, I've got a scheduler, I've got a CRM,
and basically they're all different workflows.
So the whole bunch of agents within.
Okay, and you're not an investor in Lindy,
right? You're just a fan, super user.
No, no.
Fun fact. I actually am. So this is great.
Oh, no way. That's awesome.
Tiny angel investor. So just
want to put that out there,
which I love that this came up organically. What
are a couple other really interesting use cases,
workflows you've built that
people might be inspired by it?
Let me go through the email one a little more. So
basically emails come in and the first agent says,
does Andrew even need to see this? Let's say
you're in a thread and you've already chimed
in and everyone's just saying, cool, that works.
I don't need to see that. So just archives that
never. So that immediately reduces my email by
about 20%. Then it decides is this something that
is time sensitive? Is this something that needs
to be dealt with in the next 24 hours? And if so,
it labels it in a special 24-hour label. So when I
go in my email, one of the biggest stresses I find
is I go, "Shit, there's 200 emails in here, and
if I don't go through all of them, I don't know
if there's an emergency burning somewhere." So
now I do. Then it takes any email or every single
email and it decides, is this a simple decision?
So for example, let's say you email me and you
say, "Hey, do you want to get lunch?" So it emails
me privately and it says, "Hey, Lenny wants to
get lunch. Do you want to say yes? Do you want to
say yes, but in a few months? Do you want to say
no? How do you want to say no?" And it gives me
multiple choice. I just can say four, number four,
and then it'll email you as me and it'll write out
a nice thoughtful email or whatever. So stuff like
that is so freaking cool and helpful. And I'd
say that it's replaced stuff that my full-time,
I used to have a full-time assistant just working
on email that's all completely automated and
there's all sorts of other cool stuff I'm doing
there. Other agents, I'm working on one right now
to manage my calendar, which is really complex. I
do a lot of scheduling and a lot of rules. I have
another really simple one. It adds emojis to
every single calendar event. So when I look at
my calendar, I've got beautiful little emojis
for every single calendar event. Very silly.
What are the emojis? Do they represent something?
Yeah, so if I write weightlifting, it'll just do a
guy weightlifting or whatever. I've got one that,
this one's cool. Basically what it does, every
time I email someone, it looks them up online,
it figures out what city they live in.
It checks my CRM and air table. It says,
"Okay, I don't know where do you live."
In Marin, in the Bay Area.
Okay. So it'd say, "Okay, you email Lenny,
he lives in Marin." It puts in the database
you live in Marin. And then next time I travel
to the Bay Area, the agent will see two weeks
before and it'll say, "I saw you're going
to San Francisco. Here's all the people in
San Francisco you should try and have coffee
with." Right? So just all these things that-
I would pay for that.
Yeah, yeah, exactly. All these things
that I've dreamed of having my assistant
do that my assistant could just never
consistently do because she gets distracted,
we're doing an event, there's
something going on. It's like
having the world's most reliable employee
who costs $200 a month and works 24/7.
Okay, I want to follow that
thread, but first of all,
what other tools do you have? Lindy's
one, what else do you find really useful?
So the other one is Replit. So Replit is
basically a vibe coding platform. You can
literally go into it and say, "I want to make a
website for my sound software business. Here's
a big document with a bunch of details,"
and it'll go and design a pretty impressive
website. But then you can also build web
apps now. So you can literally be like,
"Yeah, build a Python web app that does XYZ,"
and the design is getting so good because it
uses Claude 4. You can start saying, "Do it
in the style of Stripe. Think this through,
rewrite all the copy and the tone of David
Ogilvy or Malcolm Gladwell," or whoever you like,
and it does a really incredible job. So what I'm
finding is that things that previously would've
frustrated me because I would've had to rely
on a team of five, I can just do entirely on
my own when it comes to web projects and stuff
like that. So I'm having a blast with that.
That's cool. So your team Replit versus
Lovable, Bolt, v0, is that roughly right?
I mean, they're all great. I, just am the most
familiar with Replit, and it seems like it has
the most functionality. It has a lot of
beef to it, whereas Lovable and Bolt seem
a little more basic. You might have to deal with
deployment and stuff in a fiddlier way with them.
Awesome. Okay. Anything else?
Another one I love, so Limitless.
I don't know if you've seen this.
I've got one of those.
It's really cool. So clips to your shirt. I
actually just put it on my pocket so no one
actually notices that I've got it on usually,
and I just have it on all day. And what it
does is it just records everything I do. And
then I can say, the other day I had a coffee
with someone and I'm the kind of person
where I go a mile a minute and I say, "Oh,
I'll send you that and I'll do this," or whatever.
And so at the end of the day, I can just say,
"Hey, what did I promise to people today?"
Or even better, everyone loves this use case,
I have a fight with my girlfriend. And she says,
"You didn't say that." And I'm able to say, "Well,
actually you did." And you can query it as an LLM.
So you can say you're a couples counselor. Look at
this fight. What did each person need? How did
it start? What are the key lines? Where did it
change? How could you do this better? And so
honestly, from a relationship standpoint is
probably where it's been the most useful. What's
cool too is that has an API. And so eventually,
I haven't gotten there yet, but eventually
you'll be able to just have it record your
entire day and then automatically go
into your Todoist or whatever it is,
and add to-do's or send emails
or whatever you need it to do.
Wow, this is so fun. Or just per
your point with the relationship,
ask it, "What could I have done better
today? Where did the day go downhill?"
Yeah, I saw a guy on Twitter.
He said, "Every day I ask it,
'How could I have been a better dad?'"
And it'll be like, "Oh, your daughter
tried to get your attention about this. You
should have paid attention," or whatever.
And that was with the Limitless data. Oh,
man, I love that. With the relationship,
you didn't go where I thought you were going to
go, where it's like, "Oh, but who actually said
it? What did you actually say?" I love that It
became much more wholesome of just like how could
we have communicated better holistically? Okay. My
wife actually is like, "Don't wear this around."
You just got to wear it really covertly. Honestly,
I know it sounds kind of cheesy because you think
like, "Oh, it'll tell her," right? But in reality,
usually you're both guilty in the fight. And my
girlfriend has actually appreciated it because
there's been half the time it'll be like,
"Oh yeah, Zoe said this and it triggered
this," but a lot of the time it's me too.
And I think I'm totally right. So I find
it actually really helpful. Other tools,
I mean otherwise, it's the basic stack of Claude
and ChatGPT and Gemini. And Gemini I use mostly
for things that are really large. So for example,
all my medical records, I have trained on Gemini
2.5 just because the other ones can't really
go through it all. Claude, I use for writing
very extensively. I find it's the best for that.
And then ChatGPT for everything else. In terms of
cool things I do, recently, I went through
my entire medicine cabinet and I just took
big photos that showed all the different medicines
and stuff. And now I can say something like, "Hey,
I'm really tired and stressed out today. What
supplement should I take and what dose?" Or
I'll say, "Remember all the medications I'm
taking, whenever I ask you a health question,
always remind me in the context of I might be
taking that medication." So a few times it's said,
"Hey, you shouldn't take this other medication
because your genetics say you're not compatible
with it and you're already taking this other
one." So stuff like that's been really helpful.
For that use case, do you come back to
a specific conversation where you've
given it that context, use a project or something-
No, I say remember. I just say
remember these supplements,
this is what I have in my medicine
cabinet or this is what I take every day.
I see. So just tap into the memory of ChatGPT.
Yeah.
This is awesome. This makes me remember that. And
this connects to other points you've been making,
I've started to use ChatGPT deep research
to prep for these conversations. I used to
have a researcher who did this for 400 bucks.
They did research on every guest that I had,
four to 500 bucks, and gave me a whole doc,
"Here's everything about them. Here's their
background, here's questions you might want
to ask." Deep research is better. Just
as of recently, especially with o3-pro.
We were talking earlier about agents. I forgot
one of my favorite agents. So it looks on my
calendar 30 minutes before I meet anyone. It
goes on to Perplexity and it does a deep dive
on the person and it sends me, it goes into my
email and it gets the context of the meeting.
So often I book meetings three months out.
So I usually look at my calendar and I go,
"Who is this person? I don't even remember booking
this meeting." It'll text me before and it'll say,
"Here's who you are, here's your background,
here's the email context of why we're meeting."
And it basically does all the research
for me. So I do the same thing. I also
use deep research and say, "If I'm meeting
them, you know everything about me. What
are our commonalities and what are all
the fun things we should talk about?"
Oh my God, I just want to plug and play
all these agents you've built to use them
myself. Interestingly, I tried to create an
agent to do this research kickoff for me,
but I don't think you can automate
ChatGPT deep research. Okay.
Only Perplexity. Yeah.
Okay. Perplexity is great too, but it's different.
Okay. So let me follow this thread I was going
down, which is around job displacement. I
know you think a lot about this. So with me,
this researcher as a contractor I
was working with for a few months,
I no longer need them. Your assistant,
you no longer need. Thoughts on just the impact
we're going to see on jobs as a result of AI.
There's this great William Gibson quote, "The
future is already here, it's just not evenly
distributed." And I think that we are in the
Palm Treo phase. Do you remember the Palm Treo?
No.
So when I was, let's see, in 2007 I think,
was that when the iPhone came out? 2007?
I know [inaudible 00:55:19].
Something like that. In 2007, there was this
device called the Palm Treo and it was like
a little PDA with a stylus and it had a little
modem attachment. And so what you could do is
you could get your email anywhere and that was
this shocking thing. It had a black and white
or barely color screen and you could go in and
email people. And I remember walking through
the mall buying shoes while answering business
emails and going, "This is the ultimate freedom.
This is incredible." But the problem with that
device was it sucked. You had to use a stylus,
it's not a good user experience. And then the
iPhone comes out and you're like, "Okay, this is
what I was waiting for. This is the real thing."
But I got a little preview with the Palm Treo
and so right now people like me who have the time
and skillset to nerd out and build the agents can
do this. It's just not accessible to everybody.
And I think that if it was accessible to everybody
in terms of if you could just open ChatGPT
and say, "Hey, ChatGPT, I run a business,
can you help me?" And it started asking you
questions and it said, "Oh well you do sales.
Do you want me to set up a sales agent? Okay,
great, plug in your HubSpot API, now tell me a
few things and then give me access to all your
data." And then before you know it, it's just a
digital employee that's on the other end of the
phone on ChatGPT just like in the movie, Her,
that you can talk to and it can go do stuff.
I think that is kind of the iPhone moment that
we're going to have in some time in the next five
years. And so I think that if AI doesn't progress,
we will see some serious job displacement, like
what you already mentioned, the translators,
the researchers, the admin, some assistant
jobs, depending on the kind of work they do,
those jobs will definitely be massively affected.
But I think pretty quick, all knowledge work jobs
could be affected if the models scale in the
way that they say they're going to. I mean if
you trust Sam Altman and Dario Amodei, I mean
Dario Amodei said by, "2027, our models will be
smarter than all PhDs." So in any subject. That
is a staggering statement. And he's been a very
conservative kind of almost fearful voice in the
AI world. Very cautious to say things like that.
And so when he said that, I perked up and started
listening carefully. I don't know that that's how
it's going to play out. He might be trying to
fundraise, we have to take it with a grain of
salt. But if that's true, then I think so many
knowledge work jobs are going to change massively.
Okay, there's a lot here. I actually
had Mike on the podcast, their CPL,
Mike Krieger, and he pointed out that Dario,
every prediction he's had so far has been
right over the past few years. And so there's a
reason to listen to his insights. Okay. Andrew,
I know you're not going to have all the
answers for people. But let me ask you
kind of a two-part question for new grads and
for people currently in the workforce say like,
I don't know, senior product manager advice on
what they should do, where should they focus?
What skills will matter most? What jobs do you
think will last? What advice can you give us?
Everybody 10 years ago, do you remember there
was this whole movement that we should
teach kids how to code? Remember that?
Mh-hmm.
Now teaching kids how to code is teaching kids
Basic and we have a GUI, right? You don't need to
learn punch cards and basic programming or MS-DOS
because we all have keyboards and mice. We don't
have to do that. And I feel like coding has really
gone away because of that. And I think now people
are saying people need to learn how to prompt,
which I think is very true for the tool set right
now. But I don't know how relevant that is in
the future because I think we're still, again,
in the Palm Treo phase, I think that the AIs will
be very good at eliciting what the actual problem
you're trying to solve is and reinterpreting
it in a way that it can optimize the query
to get the right answer and solve the problem.
And so I think the fundamental question is do
all jobs just become a single prompt? For example,
does a CEO just grow the business while making the
customers happy and turning a profit or something
like that? And it is able to actually be an
omniscient presence that can run a whole company.
Now that's a big I'm someone building AI agents.
I can barely get it to reliably do calendar
entries and that kind of stuff. So I don't think
that's totally imminent, but I can certainly see a
world where that's coming. And so the question is,
what is one to do when that reality is barreling
down at you? For people who have resources, I
think there's a lot of things they can do in terms
of investment, they can invest in the companies
that'll benefit from this, companies that have a
lot of compute or energy or that sort of thing.
So that's one thing, but that's not really the
question. The question is what do you do if you're
a smart 18-year-old or 19-year-old or whatever?
In my opinion, I think the best thing to do right
now is to get incredibly good with these tools
and utilize them to build enough wealth that
you can put the money into diversifying into
compute and energy. And I do think that while
everybody thinks that all jobs will go away
in five years and robots will be everywhere,
people generally overestimate things in the
short term and underestimate them in the long
term. So I think there's going to be this
long window where robotics is not anywhere
near good enough to even do raking leaves
and stuff. And I think there's going to be
a ton of opportunity for people to just spin
up new businesses that never existed before.
I was talking to some friends and we
were like, "What do you do in a world
of abundance where everything is really cheap
and companies operate almost autonomously?"
I think there's a lot of weird skillsets
that we can't imagine right now. For example,
just being funny, right? Being funny to hang out
with them. Think about OnlyFans, right? Right now,
there's this whole idea of OnlyFans where
people are paying for comfort and connection,
but in a romantic sense. Imagine people did that
day to day, they just love hanging out with funny
people. So you have a funny guy who you chat with
or comes over to your house or whatever it is,
I'm making stuff up. Maybe it's a guy who
comes to play pickleball with you or something,
I don't know. But I can imagine that in this
weird world, there's all these weird new jobs.
So I think my take is things will either be
totally fine or they will be terrible and we'll
all be dead. And I can't predict which those is
there. I don't think it's worth thinking about
all of us being dead. And so I think it's
really just lean into what are the tools,
how do you stay cutting edge? How do
you build businesses and wealth in
this new world? But I am certainly
feeling a little bit like all of
our brains could be defunct in the next 10
years. And that's kind of a scary thought.
I'm picturing this dystopian world where
humans are just going around making jokes.
Where does status come from in a world
of abundance? Where does status come
from? Maybe it is just like being
the best at hiking or something.
Well, let me ask you this because this is
where it gets even more real is just with
your kids. What are you encouraging them
to learn? What are you encouraging them to
get good at? Because this is the real problem a
lot of people are having right now is what will
matter in the future. Obviously we don't know,
but what are you encouraging them to focus on?
Well, I don't know. I mean there's so little,
they're five and eight. And so really what I'm
focused on is making sure they're socialized
and they're polite, very basic. So are they
comfortable talking to adults? I often send
my son, whenever he wants something at a cafe,
I always make him go up, ask nicely, pay himself,
all that kind of stuff. But at this point I feel
like for the first 10 years of life, you're
just trying to make sure that they're not
traumatized or rude. And I think it's going
to be really interesting when they're 10 plus
where they're really aware of this stuff and can
start building with these tools. And to be honest,
I just don't know. I think I just want them to
lean into whatever they're passionate about and go
from there. But I have no idea. And to be honest,
it's not something I'm worrying about because it's
too hard to worry about. I don't know, it's too
multivariate. There's too many ways it can go.
I feel like a core part of your message is just
get good with these tools. There's this classic
quote, "AI won't replace you, it'll be somebody
very good using AI is going to replace you," at
least for a while. And so it feels like a big
part of this is just use these things. Before
we started recording, we were having a mic issue
and I love you just went straight to ChatGPT,
"ChatGPT, how do I connect this mic to
reverse side and make it work?" And I
feel like that's just a habit to build
is just like go to ChatGPT whenever you
have a problem like that. I've been
doing that a lot. I was connecting a
subwoofer from what wire do I need to buy
to connect the subwoofer to the receiver?
Well, the best part about ChatGPT is I used
to just get stuck and I have ADHD. So when I
got stuck, let's say, what's an example?
I was redoing my home IT security. And
what will happen is I'll be in the terminal
and I'll enter something and then something
goes wrong and it just keeps erroring. And
then I'm like, "Well, I'm out." I have ADHD,
I can't tolerate this. I just lose the thread
completely. And ChatGPT allows me to stay
on track and go so much further and faster
than I ever could before. I love not being
artificially stopped in your tracks and being
able to continue the flow state as a result.
And also I noticed you were using voice
mode, which is what I've been using more
and more. And I feel like that's something a
lot of people sleep on is just the voice mode
where you could talk to it and not have to sit
there and type your questions. Okay, so let me
go in a different direction. You've been spending
a lot of time, you wrote a whole book about this,
of just your journey from, you call it Barista
to Billionaire where you started serving coffee,
then you ended up being very successful, then
realize that didn't make you happy. You're quite
unhappy with lots and lots of money. I think a lot
of people hear these stories, they see this stuff,
they're like, "Yeah, okay, I sort of get it."
But they still do the same sorts of things. They
still assume they will be happy once they reach
that next goal, that next title, make certain
dollar amount. What can you share? What have you
learned about just what it actually takes to be
happy that you think people are still not really
recognizing and still kind of are confused about?
Do you remember when you're in your early 20s? I
remember when I was in my early 20s, I'd always
be like, "I need to move away to Europe. I need
to go discover myself." And I'd be really anxious
and stressed out and in an existential crisis
and then I'd fly to Europe to go backpacking or
something and I'd still feel anxious and have my
existential crisis. It's just now I'm in Europe.
And I think the reality is that whatever's
in your brain, whatever that anxiety loop is,
doesn't go away just because you have a bigger
house or more money in the bank account or you're
in Bali or wherever it is, that's a chemical
reaction happening inside you that relates
to your past and your DNA and all that stuff
that creates that soup. And for me, I've always
been a very anxious person. I've always worried
about tomorrow, I rarely enjoy today, I'm always
worrying about what could go wrong in health or
my businesses or with my family or whatever it is.
And so when I started my business, all I thought
was I just don't want to work for someone else. If
I can just wake up in the morning, do my own
thing, make 60K a year, then I'll be happy.
So I got that and then it was once I make a
million dollars a year and I can buy a house,
well, I got that and so on and so on and so on
all the way up to at one point being worth over
a billion dollars, by the way, should redo the
title of the book from Barista to Billionaire,
now it's former billionaire because our stock
went down, but it didn't change anything. I'm
still just as anxious as ever. I remember
a month ago, I had this day where I was
sitting in the sauna and I was stressing about a
bunch of business problems and money things and
I stopped myself and I was like, "Wait a minute."
10 years ago I had all the same thoughts and I was
stressed out about similar kinds of problems and
our revenue was $20 million bucks or $15 million
bucks. Now we're at almost 300 million and I'm
still stressed about the same things. And the
saddest part was as I met more and more wealthier
people all the way up to multibillionaires, I
realized they were all still comparing themselves
to their peers, competing over who has what and
tracking stuff and still unhappy that anxiety
loop or depression was still in their brain.
I remember I had this moment where I met this
guy who is a single-digit multibillionaire,
and he goes, "Oh, Jeff Bezos, he's just
so fucking rich." And I was like, "Wait,
what do you mean you're worth $5 billion?
What can he do that you can't?" And he goes,
"He can buy a super yacht." And it's like, "What?"
You can look at that guy and you can say, "Oh,
that's a wacko and all the other stuff." But the
reality is that we're all just comparing ourselves
to our peers, whatever our peers have that we
don't feel hard done by. And I remember just
thinking like, "Oh my God, how do I avoid becoming
this?" And that's the scary reality is no matter
how lucky you are, I mean we're also fortunate.
For me, I live in Canada. I have every opportunity
that I ever could have hoped for. And
there's people all over the world who
have nowhere near what I had growing up.
And yet I felt hard done by because in my
neighborhood I was the poor kid. I wasn't
poor globally. I wasn't even poor based on
Canada. But all my friends had big screen
TVs and would go to Hawaii and I never
got to do any of that stuff. My parents were
stressed about money. So I feel hard done by.
There's a phrase of friend's
financial advisor once shared,
"The Joneses are doing really well," and
that's hard to get over. So what changes
did you make to just be happier? It's hard to
give up money. It's hard to give up more money
you could make. It's hard to give up things that
money buys, I guess just so what did you change?
Well, there's a few things. I mean, one was
reframing money to some degree to have it be
something that wasn't just about feathering my
own nest and making it better. So for example,
I was talking to a friend who's very wealthy and
I was saying all the feelings I described of have
all this and yet I don't feel better. And he said,
"Well, what are you working for?" And I said,
"Well, I guess I'm just working for the numbers
to get bigger and have more employees and that's
nice. Our businesses do good things in the world
and help more people and stuff, but ultimately
it's just to pile up cash." And he said, "I've
reframed it so that all my money, 90% of my money
plus, goes into my philanthropic foundation and
then it gets given away to great causes. So when
I think about working really hard or losing a
deal or an investment going well, the win isn't
for me. The win is about doing something good."
So I did that and that definitely helped. I also
stopped spending as much money. I found that
the more stuff I had, the more houses I had,
the more people that directly worked for me to
manage all that stuff, the less happy, I was
owned by my stuff. And then I work really hard not
to have people... I try not to beat people over
the head with it. I drive a normal car. I don't
bring people to my house until I know them really,
really well. I meet them on neutral ground, I
meet them in a cafe. I dress like a schmo. I just
try not to be a weird out of touch rich person.
But the biggest thing, which is a weird answer,
is actually medicating myself. So basically
all my life I've been really anxious.
And in 2020, I remember I was watching a
movie with my ex-wife and I was looping on,
"I need to respond to this email. If I don't
respond to that email, this person's going
to be mad." And then I realized that I was
watching a movie for the last 20 minutes and
I didn't know anything about what was happening
in the movie. And then I was going, "Oh my God,
my wife is going to be mad at me. We're going
to get in a fight," and I'm projecting all
this negative stuff. And in that moment I was
like, "Okay, maybe I do need to try an SSRI
or something. This is not sustainable." And so I
went to my doctor and I got prescribed with one,
and I remember I was so scared of it
that I cut it into 10 pieces. I said,
"I'm just going to take a tiny little piece."
And it took me six months after that to try any.
But I started taking these pieces every day and I
just noticed that within about three or four days,
it was like someone had turned down the volume
on the nasty voice inside of me doing all that.
And for the first time in my life I felt
relief. No amount of money or success or
attention or anything else had done what this
little tiny yellow pill could do for my mental
state. And so now I've been on an SSRI for
four and a half years or something like that.
And then I also started medicating my ADHD.
And I would say that my brain went from Times
Square to a quiet library. And I think a lot
of people are scared of that, but ultimately
most people are acting out something that's
going on inside of them. There's a trauma or
something medically going on and that's creating
this anxiety, this depression, this feeling and
addressing that is so much more important than
trying to get praise from the external world.
Wow, it's really powerful. I really am really
thankful you're sharing this. The advice most
people hear, the general, I don't know,
culture is just like, "No, don't take meds.
Don't medicate yourself, I don't know, there's
all these downsides, all this risk. The pharma
industry is trying to make money." I love this
other perspective of it. It's actually really
effective and actually makes a big difference
in your life and it may be the only solution.
Well, it's funny because if you have a
headache, I don't think many people say,
"Oh, don't take Tylenol, you're benefiting
Johnson & Johnson, big pharma." They go,
"Yeah, you take a Tylenol when you have a
headache." Or a lot of people have seasonal
allergies and they take antihistamines and they
forget that histamine is not just in your nose,
histamines in your brain and everywhere
in your body. And so when you take an
antihistamine or even a Tylenol, you're changing
your brain, you're changing the way you think,
you're changing everything. And yet for some
reason, people are so scared, myself included,
of taking an SSRI or similar medication to treat
something that is ruining their life. Anxiety was
ruining my life. Every minute of every day I was
convinced that something terrible was about to
happen. And even now medicated, I still have that
voice. It's not like that frankly beneficial voice
that helps you grow your business or whatever
becomes unproductive at a certain point.
And I think that it is wonderful to be able to
actually just get a little bit of solace from it.
Well, for folks that, I mentioned many folks
listening, are like, "Oh man, I should really
explore this," what's the best way to explore
is to talk to your primary care physician?
Yeah. I think talking to your doctor, and one
note I think a lot of people miss is when I was
so scared of side effects because you hear about
all these horrific side effects of people lose
their libido and feel terrible and stuff. And so
I looked into it and a lot of the side effects are
due to the way that people metabolize different
drugs. And so you can actually do your 23andMe
or similar DNA test and you can find out
how you metabolize different SSRIs. And
then I chose one that I could metabolize well.
And so I've had no side effects or problems.
And I know every time I mention this, I get a
lot of people that say exactly what you say,
big pharma and all this other stuff. But
I just ask everyone listening, if you take
a Tylenol or you take an antihistamine
or other medications, I don't know why
something that can be so profoundly helpful
is something that people need to be afraid of.
Amazing. Andrew, we've covered so much ground.
I love the spectrum of topics we've gone after.
Is there anything else that you wanted to share?
Anything you wanted to double down on? Any last
nugget you want to leave listeners with before
we get to our very exciting lightning round?
One thing that was shocking for me was I was
doing... My doctor asked me to get a cognitive
test, not because I had any problem, but he said,
"Look, it's really important to get a baseline in
your 30s because then as you age, we can make sure
that you're not getting Alzheimer's or dementia
or whatever." So I go and I do this test with a
neurologist and she asked me a bunch of questions.
It's, "Remember these 10 digits and say them
backwards and all this stuff." And finally when
I get my test results back, she said, "Look,
your crystallized intelligence, your ability
to remember stuff, long range is totally fine.
You're above average. Your short-term memory, your
working memory is 10th percentile, very, very bad.
And you probably should get checked for ADHD."
And I was like, "Nope. There's no way. I don't
have ADHD. I'm organized. I've got to-do lists.
I built a business. I wasn't the hyper kid in
school or anything like that." And she said,
"Well, look, just humor me. Just go get tested."
And so I went through this crazy process.
You can go online and just quickly get tested
or whatever. But I went through this really,
really five-day process to get tested. And it
turned out that I do have it. And it's really
interesting because if you take the normal
population of about 5% of people have ADHD,
but about 30% of entrepreneurs have
ADHD. And many entrepreneurs I talk to,
they love new things. They love jumping around
between a million different topics. They're an
inch deep and a mile wide like I described.
And they describe themselves as unemployable.
And frankly, I remember I was so skeptical
of ADHD that when my girlfriend told me,
a friend of hers got diagnosed with it, I
sarcastically said, "Oh good, she better
take some meth," talking about stimulant drugs.
Previously I was very, very skeptical of ADHD,
but it is a real brain disorder if you
actually dig into it. It's a very real thing,
very objective that people have poor executive
function. And for me, it's given me a lot more
empathy for myself and my behaviors because
at work, if you have ADHD, you can delegate to
other people and build systems to get around your
disability. But at home, that's where it really
plays out. And so for me, it's like my girlfriend
asked me to take the garbage out, and I say,
"Of course." And then I forget three times in
a row. And she views that as you are being very
hurtful and you're not caring for me. And it
causes all sorts of different problems at home.
And so for me, not only did it make my work
life better because I was more focused,
but it actually really helped me in my personal
life and it made me feel not broken. I always
felt a bit broken. I couldn't put my finger on
why, but I just went, "I'm not good at doing
all the things everyone else seems to be able
to do no problem." And so I think especially
because you have an entrepreneur audience, I
think a lot of entrepreneurs should consider
getting checked for ADHD. Just go and ChatGPT say,
"Ask me a of questions and tell me if you think
I might have it." But I was very surprised,
and that's been really impactful for me too.
Man, this garbage story is
very descriptive of my life,
and so I'm going to do this. There's this
implication that it's good to know this,
right? It feels scary to feel like, "Oh,
shit I might get diagnosed with ADHD."
Your advice I imagine is it's better to
know because you could do stuff about it.
Totally. I think it's like any medical thing,
right? It's like there's an Alzheimer's gene,
right? And if you know you have it, there's a
lot you can do to slow the disease or prevent
maybe getting it or whatever. It's always
better to know. Even if you don't medicate,
I think there's a lot of lifestyle interventions,
dietary interventions, and just things you can do
to make your life easier, even if it's
just explaining to your partner, "Hey,
I need things to be explained to me this way
so that I can be effective in loving you."
Beautiful. Okay. Well, Andrew, with that,
we've reached a very exciting lightning round.
I've got five questions for you. Are you ready?
Let's go.
First question, what are two
or three books that you find
yourself recommending most to other people?
If I could only recommend two, I would
recommend The Laws of Human Nature by
Robert Greene. It's basically like a compendium
of every single type of personality disorder
or psychological effect. How do people work
their minds to make bad decisions? What is a
narcissist? What is a psychopath? All that
kind of stuff. And Robert Greene does such
a great job of telling all that in a really
engaging way by using storytelling. So every
single chapter has a story about someone with
that personality disorder. So I love that book.
The other one that I love is a book by
Felix Dennis called How to Get Rich. It's
hilarious because the whole book starts
out saying, "I got rich and I regret it,
and I wish that I'd become a poet." And instead he
went off and he built this huge publishing empire,
became a poet in his sixties, and then he
died of throat cancer. So it's his story,
he basically says, "I'll tell you how to build
the business even though you probably shouldn't."
And I read that when I was in my 20s, and I found
it so exciting and inspiring, and then I recently
reread it and I was like, "Oh my God, why didn't I
listen to this guy?" Everything he said came true.
Next question, do you have a favorite recent
movie or TV show that you have really enjoyed?
I love Challengers. I don't know if
you've seen it, but it's amazingly acted,
amazing cinematography. It's like this amazing
romantic triad tennis movie. Really, really good.
Do you have a favorite product
you recently discovered that you
really love? You already mentioned
Limitless. Is there anything else?
I'm one of those people who really believes in
the idea of a robot vacuum. I've probably spent
$10,000 on different robot vacuums over the
years, probably five or six of them. And I
finally got one that actually works. It's called
the Matic Vacuum, M-A-T-I-C. And basically,
I think it's like former Google Engineers
basically built like a mini Waymo car.
So it has machine vision and it will avoid
absolutely everything and never get tangled,
and it can mop your floors and vacuum.
I've been super impressed with it so far.
I've got one of these myself. Completely agree. My
wife loves it, which I did not expect. She's like,
"Turn that Matic on." It's very delightful. It has
his little personality and it just does a really
good job. And I'm not an investor, and that's
awesome. I'm a huge fan. Okay, next question.
Do you have a favorite life motto that you often
come back to find useful in work or in life?
Yeah. My favorite is a quote by Jerzy Gregorek.
It's, "Easy choices, hard life. Hard choices,
easy life." And I often find that anytime that
I'm making the easy choice, my life gets hard.
And when I make the hard choice to shut down the
business, fire the person, say bye to a project
that I was excited about, it's almost always the
right choice and it makes my life a lot easier.
Final question. Okay, so let me know if this
is true. I found that when you were a teenager,
when you're running Macteens, you interviewed
Steve Jobs at a conference. Is that true?
So when I was a teenager, I had a tech news
website and I emailed the Apple PR people and
I said, "Hey, could I interview Steve Jobs?"
And they kind of laughed at me. They're like,
"Yeah, there's no way. You're not
going to interview Steve Jobs, but
hey, why don't you go to this tour of
the Apple Store?" So this is no other
Apple Store has existed. This is in New
York at Macworld back in 2004, no, 2003,
something like that. And so I was really excited
about that. So I show up to go do this tour and
there's 30 other journalists there, and I'm first
in line, and this big black SUV pulls up and this
man gets out and the man is wearing gray New
Balance, little circular John Lennon glasses,
the mock turtleneck. And my brain finally puts
it together and I realize it's Steve Jobs.
And he walks directly up to me because I'm first
in line and he shakes my hand and he says, "Hi,
I'm Steve." And I'm like a quivering mess. I'm 17
years old. He is my hero. He's my Jesus. And so I
was just so high on adrenaline that I just started
asking him questions. As soon as we walked in,
I basically just stayed at his side, and
I just picked his brain about all sorts of
different stuff. So it's not like I got to ask
him questions about life. I was asking him about
the new 17-inch iMac or whatever. But it was
a pretty cool experience to get to meet him.
That is awesome. There's such a funny
thread recently with guests. Everyone,
there's like a Steve Jobs connection for the
past couple months of guests. That's an awesome
story. It just shows that it wasn't luck. You
made this happen. You got there first in line.
The lesson for me was ask big and maybe
you'll get something great. Ask for amazing,
you'll get something great, which I did.
Yes, door in the face technique,
I think people call it.
Yeah.
Andrew, this was incredible.
Two final questions. Where can
folks find you if they want to reach
out? I know you're buying companies,
investing in companies. Just talk about what
you're looking for there in case people are like,
"Oh, this is me." And then finally,
how can listeners be useful to you?
Yeah, my business is Tiny, T-I-N-Y.com, and we buy
businesses. Basically, when we sold the business,
we hated it. We went through this process where
we talked to all these douchebags that ran private
equity firms that would show up in our office
in suits and use a bunch of words we didn't
understand. And we ended up going, "Man, why can't
we just sell to somebody who's like us?" And so
we basically started Tiny to become the buyer we
wish we could have sold to. And we're looking for
businesses that have some of the qualities
I mentioned before. So really high quality
businesses that do something positive in the
world and have happy customers, happy employees,
and some kind of competitive advantage that
will make them continue into the future. So
we own AeroPress, Letterboxd, Dribble, which is a
design social network, whole bunch of businesses
like that. So if somebody is thinking about
selling their business, definitely get in touch.
Amazing. Okay. And then how can listeners
be useful to you if it's not just that?
I just would say if there's anyone really
interesting coming to Victoria, Canada,
which is where I live, send me an email
and would love to have coffee with you. The
reason I love going on podcasts is because
I get to meet so many interesting people,
both randomly. If I'm in a cafe and someone
sees me and says hi, I often make a lot of
friends that way, or if someone comes to
my hometown. So yeah, just get in touch.
Amazing. Andrew, thank you so much for being here.
Yeah, thanks, dude. That was fun.
Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.