The business you're building, the team you're
building, the way you're operating is the very
bleeding edge of how companies are
trying to operate in this AI era.
We have a head of AI operations. She's just
constantly building prompts and building
workflows that I and everyone else on the
team are just automating as much as possible.
What are some things that you believe
about AI that most people don't?
I hate the headlines that are like,
"Entry-level jobs are taken away by AI."
Whenever I see a kid with ChatGPT, I'm like,
"Holy shit, they're going to go so much faster
than any other person that I've worked with."
We have this guy, he made a year's worth of
progress in two months because every time
I sat down with him and told him, "Okay,
here's how you tell a story, here's
how you think about a headline," he
recorded all of it, put it into a prompt,
and he never made the same mistake twice.
There's this sense we're getting to a place
where you don't have to write any code,
you have a product team not writing code at all.
No one is manually coding anymore. Organizations
like ours, people who are playing at the edge,
we're doing things that, in three years,
everybody else is going to be doing.
Today, my guest is Dan Shipper. Dan is the
co-founder and CEO of Every, which is a company
that is at the very bleeding edge of what is
possible with AI. Their team of just 15 employees
has built and shipped four different products.
They publish a daily newsletter, and they have
a consulting arm that helps companies adopt the
latest AI best practices. On their product team,
their engineers don't handwrite a single line of
code and instead use an arsenal of agents who help
them craft requirements and build their products.
Their editorial arm uses AI to publish better work
faster, and they even have a person whose
entire job is to help every employee at the
company become more efficient using the latest
AI workflows. In our conversation, Dan shares
a bunch of tactics that they use internally to
increase the leverage of their own employees,
his personal AI tool stack, the one predictor
that he's found for whether a company will
successfully find huge productivity gains
through AI, how he's building his company in
a really unique way, a bunch of predictions
for where AI is going, and so much more.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. And also, if you
become an annual subscriber of my newsletter,
you get a bunch of amazing products for free
for one year, including Superhuman, Linear,
Notion, Perplexity, Bolt, Granola and more.
Check it out at lennysnewsletter.com and click
bundle. With that, I bring you Dan Shipper.
This episode is brought to you by CodeRabbit,
the AI code review platform transforming
how engineering teams ship faster with AI
without sacrificing code quality. Code reviews are
critical, but time-consuming. CodeRabbit acts as
your AI copilot providing instant code review
comments and potential impacts of every pull
request. Beyond just flagging issues, CodeRabbit
provides one-click fix suggestions and lets you
define custom code quality rules using ast-grep
patterns, catching subtle issues that traditional
static analysis tools might miss. CodeRabbit also
provides free AI code reviews directly in the IDE.
It's available in VS Code, Cursor and Windsurf.
CodeRabbit has so far reviewed more than 10
million PRs, installed on one million
repositories, and is used by over 70,000
open source projects. Get CodeRabbit for free for
an entire year at coderabbit.ai using code Lenny.
That's coderabbit.ai. Today's episode is brought
to you by DX. If you're an engineering leader or
on a platform team, at some point, your CEO will
inevitably ask you for productivity metrics.
But measuring engineering organizations is hard,
and we can all agree that simple metrics like
the number of PRs or commits doesn't tell
the full story. That's where DX comes in.
DX is an engineering intelligence solution
designed by leading researchers, including
those behind the DORA and SPACE frameworks. It
combines quantitative data from developer tools
with qualitative feedback from developers
to give you a complete view of engineering
productivity and the factors affecting it.
Learn why some of the world's most iconic
companies like Etsy, Dropbox, Twilio, Vercel,
and Webflow rely on DX. Visit DX's website
at getdx.com/lenny. Dan, thank you so much
for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you for having me. I've obviously been a
huge fan for a long time and
so it's an honor to be here.
It's my honor, Dan. I feel like this is
a podcast that was meant to be. I'm so
happy we're finally doing this. There's
so damn much that I want to talk about;
there's so damn much we can talk about. I thought
it'd be fun to start with just some hot takes.
And the reason I want to start here is I feel
like you spend more time thinking about AI,
building with AI, using AI, evaluating AI
than anyone else I know nearly. And so I
really respect your insights and your
perspectives on where things are going.
So let me just ask you this question
and see where this goes. What are some
things that you believe about AI using
AI tools that most people don't believe?
I'm going to go with my hottest take, and this
is the take that I have the least evidence
for. So let's just start with that. I have
other more well-reasoned takes to give you,
but this is my hottest one, which is I think that
AI may be one of the biggest force for reshoring
American jobs. And so I think everyone is worried
about it unemploying people. And for sure, it
will change the skills needed to do the jobs that
you're doing, but I think it may actually reshore
a lot of jobs, and it'll do that in two ways.
One is, there are a lot of expensive services that
rich people and big companies are paid for
right now, so in-house counsel or call center
or whatever. And what cheap intelligence does
is it makes those kinds of things affordable for
small companies and individuals. So it stimulates
demand. The other thing that it does is it allows
people who are in those jobs to serve more people
cheaply. It may not get rid of customer service,
for example, but it may allow 10 people in
the Midwest, who would normally be working at
a call center, to serve hundreds of thousands
or millions of people. Maybe that's too much,
but a lot more people than they would ordinarily
if they were the ones on the phone all the time.
And so it becomes much more cost-effective for
American companies to hire people in the US. And I
think the people in the US are going to be better,
in a lot of cases, at using these AI tools to
do work. So I think it may actually make it more
effective to have those jobs in the US run by
people sitting in the US who are using it to get
work done. And also, the model companies are here
too. So there's a lot of American stuff happening,
and you can decide whether or not you think that's
a good thing, but I think it's quite lost in the
conversation over whether AI will get rid of jobs.
I like optimistic takes about AI, so this is
great. And to your point, TBD if this is good
for other countries, but good for the US. What
else? What else you got? What other hot takes?
Okay. Another big hot take, and this is
less contrarian and more just, I think,
people are truly sleeping on it. I
think people are truly sleeping on
how good Claude Code is for non-coders. And
I'll extend this to not just Claude Code,
but Google just came out with the Gemini CLI
command-line interface. So things like that.
And I'll tell you for people who are listening
that don't know what Claude Code is. Claude Code
is just the command-line interface. It's those
black terminals that programmers use. It's a
command-line interface that you can boot up. It
has access to your file system, it knows how to
use any kind of terminal command and it knows
how to browse the web, all that kind of stuff.
You can give it something to do and it will
go off and it'll run for 20 or 30 minutes
and complete a task autonomously, agentically.
Especially with Claude Opus 4 that just came out,
it's this gigantic leap forward in AI's
ability to work by itself. And Claude
Code can even spawn multiple sub-agents
that do a bunch of tasks in parallel
and it's incredibly useful for programmers.
Everybody inside of Every is using it all day,
every day. Everyone's agent-pilled. They've got 15
agents doing all this kind of stuff. It's crazy.
But non-programmers don't use it because it's
intimidating to use the terminal. But for example,
you can download all your meeting notes and put it
in a folder and just be like, "Okay, I want you to
read every single one of my meeting notes and tell
me..." Something that I do, for example, is, "Tell
me all the time that I subtly avoided conflict."
And it writes a little to-do list for itself. It
can have a little notebook, it can go and
read each little thing and then write into
its notebook, go down its to-do list and give
you a summarized answer over multiple turns. So
it's not just stuffing everything into context,
which is what you'd be doing with ChatGPT chat or
a regular Claude chat. It's actually processing
every single file that you give it. And so I
think it's incredibly powerful for any kind of
task that involves processing a lot of text.
So as a simple way to think about
this, you basically have an agent
on your local computer that can read
your local files and do your bidding.
Yes, exactly. And it can do that for long
amounts of time without going off the rails.
Interesting. And so there's a small hurdle
that non-technical people have to overcome,
which is using their terminal and giving
commands, but once they get it running,
it's just you talk to it in
English and ask it to do stuff.
Exactly.
So the hot take here is just Claude Code,
which most people think is for engineers,
is the most underrated tool
for non-technical people.
Yeah, exactly.
What are some other ways you imagine people
seeing this? This meeting note example is
really cool and I could see people using this.
What else have you seen or thinking about?
Something that I've done a lot, so
I'm a writer for a lot of my job.
And I know you're going to ask me about books
I love, so I'm going to give you a sneak peek,
which is I love War and Peace. I
just read it for the third time.
Wow, that's a long book.
It's so long, but it's so good. I think Tolstoy is
a brilliant writer. And one thing that I wanted to
do is I was like, "I want to inflect some of my
writing with some of Tolstoy's style." And the
way I did that is I think he's incredible at
these little subtle sentences where he shows
you what a character is thinking and feeling
just by how they behave, how they move their
face or the mismatch between the intonation in
their voice and the expression in their eyes,
all that kind of stuff. He's just an incredible
student of human behavior and psychology.
And so I just downloaded War and Peace to my
computer, which you can do because it's public
domain. And then I had Claude read the first
three chapters of War and Peace and pull out
all of those descriptions, and then make a guide
for itself for how to do character descriptions
like Tolstoy. And you could totally do this with
a regular Opus command, but you couldn't put all
of War and Peace into it. It would take a lot more
hand holding to get it to do this. And it just did
this by itself without my really intervening.
I had it download a Russian version of War and
Peace and the English version, and then start
comparing different scenes that I love to tell
me about things that I might've missed in the
translations, so that you can get as deep and
weird and nerdy for whatever subfield you
care about as you want to. Same thing for
if you've got tons of customer interviews or
tons of customer data you want to go through,
it's incredibly powerful for going and figuring
stuff out from big data sets like that.
You actually inspired me to use... This is not
what you're describing, but it's also something
that's very cool. This is going to sound so
nerdy. I'm reading Anna Karenina right now.
Yes.
Also Tolstoy. And this is recommended by a
previous podcast guest. And so I was like,
"All right, I got to read this."
Also very long. I'm on my Kindle,
I'm just like, "All right, 13%
in, I've been reading for months."
Hot take, I think War and Peace
is better than Anna Karenina,
especially for a tech person.
But they're both good.
Okay, there we go. There's my year. I saw you
tweet this use case that I love that I've been
using, which is just while I'm reading,
having ChatGPT voice sitting around and
then just asking it questions. Because you
don't actually have to feed it the book,
it knows the whole book. And Anthropic just
shared this. I don't know if they shared or
someone found this in their legal briefings
that they actually bought tons of books and
scanned them themselves, is how they did fair use.
And so it has all this context. So just sitting
there and asking it, "What the heck is this
thing in Russian society?" is super fun. Okay,
so this is awesome. So the tip here is just coming
back to your hot take. The tip is you basically
can have an agent using local files and doing
all kinds of cool stuff on your computer versus
having to upload it into projects or into your
prompts and things like that. Super cool. So the
bet here is that people are going to discover
this and start using this just day to day.
I think they absolutely will. And I also think
probably the model companies are going to start
making this more accessible. I think one of
the things that will just come from Claude Code
and other things like it into everything else
you use, whether it's on the web or wherever,
is all of the original AI apps were pasting a chat
box into an existing UI. So you've got Copilot,
it's got the auto-complete in
the IDE. You've got Cursor,
it's got a little sidebar with a little
chat. And the difference with Claude Code
is you never look at the code. It's not meant
for coding, it's not meant for coding by hand.
It's meant for you to say, "I want you to get
something done," and it goes and does it. And
I think we're just getting to a point where
for pretty much all the usual applications,
AI is going to be good enough that we can
get rid of the interfaces more or less where
you're digging into all the things that it's
actually doing and you're interleaved with its
execution and you're more just like,
"I'm delegating, it's going to go do it."
Yeah. I had Cursor's CEO, Michael Truell,
on the podcast, and this is his big
vision is, "What comes after code?"
English.
Exactly. Exactly. I also just had the founder
of Base44 on the podcast who built this company,
sold for 80 million bucks to Wix. And he
shared that he's been around for six months,
the company. For the last three months, he
hasn't touched a single line of front-end code,
all Cursor and other tools he's
using. So this is happening.
Same thing for people inside of Every,
no one is manually coding anymore.
Okay. Definitely need to talk
about that. Before we do,
any other hot takes that
you want to throw out there?
I have one other hot take, which is I have a
definition for AGI. And so AGI is famously hard to
define. What does it mean for it to be artificial
general intelligence? The Turing test was one,
but we'd pretty much blown past the Turing
test in a lot of ways. So we have no good
one. And so what I have noticed is that
you can tell how much better AI is getting
by how long a leash you can give it to do work.
So with Copilot, you can tab complete and that was
the beginning. With ChatGPT, you ask it a question
and it returns a response and that's maybe
slightly better than a tab complete. And then
now with Claude Opus 4 and Gemini and all that
kind of stuff, also with deep research, it can go
off and work for 20 or 30 minutes. So that leash
is getting longer where you have to intervene.
And I was thinking about this and it reminded
me of Winnicott, who was a child psychologist. He
wrote this book called Playing & Reality. And his
conceptualization for what it means to become an
adult, what it means to go from being an infant
to a child to an adult is when you're first born,
you're effectively fused with usually your mother,
your caregiver. There's no difference between
you and her or you and whoever your caregiver is.
And growing up is this process of being gradually
let down in certain moments where you can handle
being let down. So you learn that there's a
separation between you and your caregiver. So
for infants, it's instead of being fused at the
hip for every hour of every day, you get left
alone. Maybe you get left alone to cry it out.
Who knows if that's the right thing to do with
infants? A lot of consternation there. But that's
teaching you that there's a separation between
you and your mom or you and your dad. There's
not going to always be someone to pick you up.
And raising a child is about knowing when
they're ready to be let down a little bit
and have to stand up on their own. So I
think there's that same leash with human
development. You get longer and longer
periods of time where you can be on your
own. So we're still in the 20 to 30 minutes
is maybe... I don't know, you probably can't
leave a toddler alone for 20 or 30 minutes,
but it's a little bit older than a toddler.
Maybe 20, 30 seconds.
With a toddler, you can be in the same room but
not interacting with them every single second
for 20 minutes sometimes. So it's around there.
I think we have that similar leash with AGI. And
so I think a good definition of AGI is when does
it become economically profitable for people to
run agents indefinitely? So it just never turns
off. It's a Claude Code that's always running,
it's always doing something, you just never
turn it off, and you don't need to because
you know that it's worthwhile to keep it on.
It's never waiting for you to be like, "Okay,
next thing." It'll always respond to you
when you're like, "Okay, next thing."
But it's off just essentially living its life
like a teenager and that is profitable for you.
You'd rather have it do that than just
wait for you to tell it what to do next.
Interesting.
I think that's a good definition of AGI.
The profitable piece is also just the
cost of running that thing and having it.
It's partly the cost and partly the value.
And obviously, you can game this a little bit
and be like, "Cool, I'm just going to tell
Claude to run in a loop forever." But I'm
talking about more than that, more widespread
adoption of agents that work all the time.
And I like the profitable thing, because
if it costs a little bit of money and the
bar is profitability, it has to actually be
doing something useful for you to keep it on.
It's interesting how the metaphor of
a senior employee and autonomy and
essentially the more autonomous they are,
the less instruction you have to give,
the less reviews you have to do, is also just
directly correlated with how senior they are.
Totally.
Okay, great. Anything else along these lines?
I have plenty of them. I hate the headlines that
are like, "It's going to replace jobs," or "It's
going to unemploy two thirds of the workforce."
I don't think that's true. I hate headlines that
are like, "You don't use your brain when you
use ChatGPT," or another good headline is,
"Doctors alone, doctors plus AI, or just
AI, which one is better? AI is better,
therefore, doctors are going to be outmoded."
All that stuff is, I think, pretty dumb.
So for the doctors plus AI example, I think it's
important to recognize that using AI is a skill.
And so if you study doctors in a vacuum that
don't really have a lot of experience with AI,
you could probably create a situation such that
it's better to just use an AI. And sometimes it
is going to be better. But there's so many
contexts that doctors need to make decisions
and do things that it's really hard to take
one study and make any conclusion about that.
And it's especially hard when you're dealing with
a technology that's developing so rapidly that
doctors can't really be expected to be experts
at it yet. But I would guess in five or 10 years,
that will be totally and completely different. For
the student example or the "AI turns your brain
off" example, I think it's really important to
understand that in the history of technology, it
has always been the case that you give up certain
skills in order to get other ones. For example,
Plato is famously very skeptical of writing
because he thought it would harm your memory.
And it did. We don't remember things quite as well
as they did back in the day because they had to
remember long epic poems to entertain each other.
But I think writing is a worthwhile trade for
having a slightly worse memory. And I
think something similar is going on with
AI where you may be slightly less engaged
in certain tasks, but if you use it right,
you're going to be way more engaged in other tasks
where you have much more power. And so you can
construct a study that says brain connectivity
goes down when you use AI in the same way that
you could construct a study that says people's
memory are worse when they have writing skills.
But I don't think anyone would want to go
back to a world where no one was literate.
That is super interesting. There's all these
studies that are showing the benefits of AI
to students with these studies in Nigeria and
just how fast people progress. So I think it's
really important, this context you're
sharing that you will lose some things,
but the hope is the gain is much higher,
and so far it seems like it will be.
Yeah. I think people always, especially
at the beginning of a tech hype cycle or
a revolution paradigm shift, it's always
easy to underestimate how quickly things
are going to change. And the example I always
use is, I live in Brooklyn and the tailor down
the street from me doesn't accept credit cards.
Credit cards have been around for a long time,
so it takes a long time for technology like
this to be adopted even in the best case.
And I think it's really easy to underestimate how
complex specific contexts are that humans know
how to deal with. And just because you can get a
really good score on a test... It's incredible.
I love AI, it's so incredible, but it doesn't
actually give you an intuition for how difficult
it is to actually be replacing specific parts of
work or activities that you would do. I think a
really good thing to give you maybe a little bit
of an intuition for it is I built this thing over
a weekend a month ago that was, "0.3, can it
predict what I'm going to say in a meeting?"
That's a benchmark. It's the CEO benchmark.
And the reason I did that is because the gold
standard for OpenAI for testing how powerful a
model is, is they test it on their internal code
base. So they say, "How good is the new model
at predicting what comes next in our internal
code base?" Because that's not anywhere out on
the internet. So it's a really good benchmark
for that. And so I was like, "Well, my meeting
transcripts aren't anywhere on the internet.
A lot of what I say is on the internet and
there's some overlap, but it'd be interesting."
And so I ran a bunch of the frontier models
on this, on just my Granola transcripts,
and they're pretty bad. They are pretty bad, and
it's not because they're not smart. There's this
real push now. Tobi from Spotify coined this term
called "context engineering," which is getting the
context to the model, the right context at the
right time, is at least half the performance.
And I think that's 100% true. It's something that
I've been writing about for three years. At the
time, I called it knowledge orchestration. I think
context engineering is probably a better term. But
it's totally true, and that's a very,
very hard problem to solve. It's not
just a one- shot problem where it's gigantic
context window and we're done. It's going...
... that problem, where it's like gigantic
context window and we're done. I think it's
going to get better over time, but the
minute it gets good at predicting what
I'm going to say next in a meeting, I'm just
going to use it as a tool, and that's going
to change the entire dynamic of what I say next
in a meeting. So it's not as easy as it seems.
Interesting. I imagine you can
build a GPT from that. And then,
instead of having a meeting with Dan now, just
talk to this thing, and he'll make decisions.
Yes, definitely. And I mean we do this a little
bit. It's not the same as being able to predict
exactly what I'm going to say in a meeting. But
I think if you're a CEO, or founder, or manager,
it's really stunning how much of your job is just
repeating yourself. And that is one of the best
things about this AI, particularly AI revolution,
is that you don't have to repeat yourself.
And so we had it last quarter. I tend to set one
or two quarterly goals. And one of my big goals
for us last quarter was don't repeat yourself.
So I don't want ever say the same thing in a
meeting twice, if I can help it. So for us,
at Every, one of the big parts of Every is we
have a daily newsletter. And I'm spending a lot
of time giving feedback on headlines, or giving
feedback on, "How do you write an intro," or
"Is this idea any good," that kind of stuff.
And we've started to codify all of that into
prompts that basically... It's not the same as
mimicking me. It can't exactly say exactly what
I'm going to say in a meeting, but it pushes my
taste out to the edge so that writers who are
not able to talk to me, by the time I see it,
they've already talked to some simulation of a
simulation of me. And that's incredibly powerful.
Let's follow this thread. This
is exactly where I want it to go.
I feel like the business you're building, the
team you're building, the way you're operating
is the very bleeding edge of how companies
will operate and are trying to operate in
this AI era. You guys are trying to be super
AI-first. And it's super aligned with just
so much of your writing. There's just so much
reason to study what you guys are doing. So-
Well, thank you.
Yes. And this is benefiting
all of us, so thank you.
So first of all, just tell people what the
heck Every is, and then share a few insights
into just how you operate. It's funny that you
laugh at [inaudible 00:26:20] whatever you say.
Everyone asks that because it's a very weird shape
of a company. You can actually see other companies
that have this shape from earlier eras, but
it's less common. It doesn't make as much sense.
And I think it's newly enabled by AI, and we can
talk about why. But the way that I typically talk
about Every is we do ideas and apps at the edge
of AI. So the core of the business is we have a
daily newsletter. We've been doing it for about
five years. We have about 100,000 subscribers. All
of the people from the top AI labs read us. Anyone
who's basically interested in or working in AI at
the frontier and wants to know what's on reads us.
We do a lot of... For example, whenever OpenAI
or Anthropic drop a new model, we get our
hands on it early, and then we get to play
with it and write about it, which it's
my ideal job. I love it. It's the best.
It sounds like it.
I don't if I can curse on this podcast, but-
You can.
... it's the fucking best.
Perfect. Excellent use. And you call
those "vibe checks", is that the-
Yeah, we call them vibe checks-
Vibe checks, love those.
... which I think is really important
because... And this gets to the next part,
the apps part of what we do. I think it's really
important to do vibe checks and to call them vibe
checks because they're about how does it feel to
use this thing and how does it feel to use it for
work for things that you would normally use it
for in your job or in your life. Because I think
that captures something that standard benchmarks
just don't capture and really can't. And the best
people to tell... to write a vibe check are people
that are actually at the edge using it for stuff.
And so what we've found over time is we have...
We love, we think the best writing and content
about technology is from people that are
actually using it and building with it.
And so we've always had this sort of function,
where we're always building little experiments
in addition to our writing, and that helps us
write great stuff. And that has turned into
a suite of apps that we run internally.
And the people who are building those
apps are also writers, and they're
contributing to things like vibe checks.
So you get a really inside look into how is
this stuff being built from people who are
actually using it every day. And the suite
of apps that we have, one's called Cora.
We just launched Cora publicly on the day that
we're recording this, which is really awesome.
Congratulations.
Thank you. You can think of it like a chief of
staff, an AI chief of staff for your email. It
helps you manage your email with AI. It's very
cool. We can go into more of it later. We have
another one called Sparkle, which is an AI file
cleaner. We have another one called Spiral that
does content automation with AI. We originally
incubated Lex, which is an AI document writer,
which we spun out into its own company,
and my Every co-founder runs that.
And basically we bundle everything
together. So you pay one price,
and you get access to all of the software that we
make, and we're constantly putting new stuff in
the bundle. And I can tell you more about what
kinds of things do we like to incubate and how
do we like to incubate it because I think there's
some really interesting, special things in there.
But I've been blabbering for
a while, so I'll stop there.
There's also a consulting firm, which I want
to talk about, but let's hold off on that.
Yeah, we have consulting.
Yeah.
We also do that, and that's the third leg of the
stool in the business. It doesn't fit quite as
nicely into my ideas in app streaming, but
we spend a lot of time with big companies,
where we teach them basically how to be
AI-first. We train all the people on how
to use AI. And it's very cool, it's really
fun, and a very important part of what we do.
That feels like a billion-dollar business
right there. I want to come back to it.
[inaudible 00:29:50].
Because everybody wants to learn this.
Okay, so share a few ways that you guys
operate. You mentioned that your team doesn't
write any code. What are just some ways that
allow you to operate this efficiently? I know your
team's really small. You have a daily newsletter,
you have three, four products, you have a
consulting arm. How big is the team at Every?
We have 15 people.
15 people? Okay.
Yeah.
So just give us insight into some of the ways
you operate that are at the bleeding edge.
Okay, so a couple of things. One, and I think
everyone should do this, is we have a head of
AI operations. I sit with her once a week. And
every time I'm doing something repetitively,
we put it in a to-do list. And she's just
constantly building prompts, and building
workflows, and stuff like that so that I and
everyone else on the team are just automating
as much as possible. And I think that has been
a big unlock because it's really hard to...
If you're working in a job all day, you're
fighting fires, and you're like, "Okay,
am I going to do this in the way that I know how
or am I going to do it in the new way that might
not work?" I don't want to spend a bunch of
time [inaudible 00:30:54] you're building some
no-code automation. I don't want to do that. And
having an AI operations lead lets you basically
identify those things and have them solved
without people who are doing the work
actually having to take time to do it, which
I think makes it much more likely it happens.
There's always a trick with that, where it's
like you have to make sure it gets used.
So it's basically you're developing little
applications internally, but if you're good
at making applications people use, it's great.
Highly recommend having an AI operations lead.
I imagine you saw the [inaudible
00:31:25] Quora tweeted about this,
wanting to hire exactly this sort of person.
Yeah.
So clearly this is a trend.
So the idea is your point that this needs to be
somebody who's outside of the day-to-day work of
the company, and is specifically focused on
helping the team be more efficient with AI?
Yeah. Yeah.
And then is this person mostly
just you automating you,
or can they help other people? Are they helpful-
No, she helps everyone, basically.
Everyone? Okay.
Where we're starting right now is with the
editorial operation. So there's so much stuff in
the editorial operation, where I or our editor in
chief, Kate... Kate, is constantly doing little,
small copy edits to make sure everything is
in Every style, and it takes hours a day.
And so now Opus is at a point where you
can give it a style guide and a prompt,
and it will go through anything you're
writing, and copy edit it, which is amazing.
The trick is it's not just building that. You also
have to get Kate to be like, "Did you put this
through the prompt yet," anytime someone gives her
something. So there's a little bit of behavioral
update too that has to happen, which I think is
a really interesting organizational challenge.
And I think for us it's a little easier
because everybody inside the org is very
AI-first and just wants to go do it.
We don't have anyone really who's like,
"I don't know. I don't really want to do this."
And that's a whole different challenge, which I
think a lot of organizations face, but there's
always a problem of getting people to use it.
That is super cool. What is her
background, this AI operations person?
Her name is Katie Parrott. She actually does
a lot of ghostwriting for us. So she also,
when people inside of Every who are builders...
Often they just write themselves, but sometimes
they want help, and she'll help them write about
whatever they're working on. So that's how she
started with us. She still does that, but she also
spends a lot of time doing the AI operation stuff.
And then before that, she worked at Animalz,
which is a content marketing agency, one of the
top content marketing agencies. And they're very
process oriented. And I think the reason Katie is
so good is because she's incredibly good at that
kind of process stuff or thinking about that,
but she's also a great writer and she's also
just incredibly excited about AI. She just
wants to tinker and wants to use it. And that
was the thing that got me to be like, "Okay,
you should just come and do that. Instead of
just ghostwriting, we should add this to your
plate." And it's been really fantastic.
At minimum, you really just want someone
who's just like, "I want to tinker. I want to
build stuff." There's also people who have a
little bit more of that process orientation. I
think that is important. And to the extent they
understand the craft of the thing that they're
trying to build for, that also helps a lot.
This is an amazing tip. I feel like
everyone's going to start hiring these people.
I think so. There's a couple other people who talk
about this. I heard Rachel Woods, who's another...
She thinks a lot of AI stuff. She's talking
about it. I think it's becoming a thing,
and I think it's really important, and it just
bleeds out into every other part of the org.
So we're doing this inside of the editorial
org, but there's a lot of copy that goes out
on Cora. And by the way, Cora is spelled
C-O-R-A, so it's different from Q-U-O-R-A,
slightly confusing. There's a lot of copy that
goes out on Cora, or Spiral, or Sparkle that we
want to have that same Every quality bar for. And
so we have engineers sending Kate, like, "Here's
the Figma file. Can you go and do copy edits?" And
that sucks for everybody. And Kate is one person,
and it's just really hard to do that.
So one thing that we did, Nityesh,
who's one of the engineers on Cora, built a
Claude Code command that just uses that prompt,
and checks through the entire code base for all
the copy edits, and then creates a pull request
on GitHub, and then sends the pull request to
Kate. So she's just looking at the pull request,
and being like, "Does this make sense?"
And so you can translate that prompt into,
for example, a format that engineers
can use. And suddenly your engineering
team is writing marketing copy in the
style you want. I think that's so cool.
That is extremely cool. I'm going to take
us on a little tangent. You keep mentioning-
[inaudible 00:35:42].
... Claude, and I'm curious just what is in the
stack of tools that you find yourself using,
your team ends up using. It seems
like Claude is a core part of it.
I do love Claude. I would say I'm generally... My
first thing that I open is o3. I'm a ChatGPT boy.
And I think o3 is super high quality. I think
it's great for writing, it's great for coding,
it's great for all that stuff. And what it has
that really makes a difference still from Claude
is it has memory. And I just love that. I've
spent so much time yelling at ChatGPT about,
"I need my writing to be punchy and
concise." And it just knows that now.
So I think when I ask it to write something for
me, it's actually better than yours. Or maybe
not yours, but your average ChatGPT user. And
I also find I use it a lot for self-reflection
and personal growth type stuff. So it knows me. So
when I send it a meeting transcript, and I'm like,
"How did I do?" It's like, "Well, you
did that thing that you normally do,
but you're way better on this other thing."
And I like that. I think that's really great.
So day-to-day, o3, that's my go-to.
I think Claude Opus is... First of all,
Claude Code, everyone inside Every,
that's basically what we use.
If you're building something, you're using
Claude Code. It's crazy. It's so good.
Gemini just came out with something, so I'm very
excited to try that because I think that's the
model that we use most for the apps that we build,
inside the apps. It's incredibly powerful and it's
incredibly cheap, which is great. So I want
to try the CLI tool that they came out with.
We also use Codex a bit, which is
OpenAI's coding tool. And that's for,
like, "I want a one-off, self-contained...
I want to pick off this little feature."
What else do I use? Going back to Claude, Claude
Opus 4 can do something that no other model,
except one other model that I can't
talk about... can do something that no-
[inaudible 00:37:39].
... other model can do.
Okay, we won't go there. We don't want
to get you in trouble. Okay, go on.
But yeah, no other model can do this. Which is
earlier versions of Claude, and I think generally
versions of other models, when you ask them,
"Is this piece of writing any good," Claude,
for example, would always give it a B+. And then
if you did another turn of the same conversation,
you're like, "I updated this," it
would always go to A-. And then if
you give it another turn, it would go to A.
So it doesn't have the same kind of gut. It's
thinking about what you probably want hear too
much. And there's various methods that you can
use to prompt engineer around this, like give it a
template or whatever. And they sort of worked, but
it just still doesn't have that thing where it's
like, "Can it tell if writing is interesting or
any good? Does it have that gut sense?" And Opus 4
has it. It's really wild. And I think that's super
important because it opens up all these use cases
where you might want to use a language model as a
judge. So for us, for example, we're working on
a new version of our product Spiral, which does
content automation. You've used that in the past.
And we're doing essentially Claude Code, but for
content style product, where you say, "I want it
to write a tweet," you give it all the documents,
it has a bunch of memories, it creates a to-do
list for itself, and then it goes and writes.
And one of the things that is so
interesting is now, because it can
judge things, part of its to-do list is, "Okay,
I wrote three tweets. I'm going to judge whether
I think these are any good," and then it
can improve before it comes back to you.
And that's just a huge, huge unlock, that
we were struggling for three months to build
this crazy system to try to get it to judge
writing. And then Opus 4, just one-shotted it,
and we're like, "Great, this product works. Let's
start chipping it." So yeah, I love it for that.
Are there any other AI tools that you
just use regularly? You mentioned Granola,
even outside of the bottles. So what are some
that you think maybe people are sleeping on?
I use Granola. So I used to use Super Whisper
and Whisper flow, which I think are fantastic.
We have an internal version of that called
Monologue that will be shipping in a month
or so that I use now, but you can think
of them as roughly equivalent. And I think
generally speech to text interfaces are the
future, and more people should be using them,
and more people should be building them as
affordances. We use Notion all the time,
and I specifically use their meeting
recording. I think that's mostly the stack.
Okay. That was really helpful
and super interesting.
This episode is brought to you by PostHog,
the product platform your engineers actually
want to use. PostHog has all the
tools that founders, developers,
and product teams need, like product
analytics, web analytics, session replays,
heat maps, experimentation, surveys, LLM
observability, air tracking, and more.
Everything PostHog offers comes with a
generous free tier that resets every month.
More than 90% of customers use PostHog for
free. You are going to love working with a
team this transparent and technical, you'll see
engineers landing pull requests for your issues,
and their support team provides code-level
assistance when things get tricky.
PostHog lets you have all your data in
one place beyond analytics events. Their
data warehouse enables you to sync
data from your Postgres database,
Stripe, HubSpot, S3, and many more sources.
Finally, their new AI product analyst, MaxAI,
helps you get further faster. Get help
building complex queries and setting up
your account with an expert who's always
standing by. Sign up today for free at
posthog.com/lenny and make sure to tell them
Lenny sent you. That's posthog.com/lenny.
Let's go back to ways that your team operates.
You mentioned having Kate. Was that her name?
Yeah.
Okay. What else? What else do you
do that you think other companies
should be doing or will eventually start doing?
So the Cora team, which is
Kieran and Nityesh, basically-
[inaudible 00:41:43] that's the team, two people?
That's the team, yeah. Well,
with Cora, it's Kieran, Nityesh,
and 15 Claude Code instances, so
it's more powerful than you think.
I love that. This is just,
again, a glimpse into the future.
One of the things that we do that I think is
really cool, and they basically invented this,
I had nothing to do with this, is they invented
the idea of compounding engineering. So basically,
for every unit of work, you should make
the next unit of work easier to do.
So an example is, in a Claude Code
world, where you're not coding a lot,
you end up spending a lot of time essentially
typing PRDs. Like, "Here's a document with
exactly the stuff that I need to do," right? And
so you could just be like, "Okay, cool. That's
my job now. I'm going to just write PRDs." And so
each successive PRD, it's the same amount of work.
Or you could spend a little bit of time being
like... There's a sort of platonic ideal of a
PRD. And what I'm going to do is write a
prompt that can take my rambling thoughts
and then turn that into a PRD. And so you
spend a little bit of work to make all of
the next PRDs that you're doing easier to
write because you're writing less of them.
And so finding those little speed-ups,
where every time you're building something,
you're making it easier to
do that same thing next time,
I think gets you a lot more
leverage in your engineering team.
And so, yeah, we have Kieran and Nityesh.
And Cora, it just became public. It was in
private beta. It had 2,500 active users. And
there's millions of emails going through it.
And that's one of the products that we do
as a 15-person company. It's kind of crazy.
It is crazy. How do you do
the speed-up thing? Is it
prompts that they continue to
refine [inaudible 00:43:44]?
A lot of it is prompts, and
automations, and stuff like that. Yeah.
Got it. For automations, what's the tool? What's
the tool you use for automating automations?
What they're using a lot of is Claude Code.
So you can do slash commands in Claude Code,
which are repeated prompts that you're doing.
Got it. Okay. So basically they're building
a library of prompts that make the process,
of, "Here's what I want to
build," to a good solid PRD
that you can feed into Claude Code
more correct and more efficient?
Exactly.
Super interesting. And they just keep a file or
they put this into a project? Is
that how they store this stuff?
It's a GitHub. It's a GitHub GitHub-
[inaudible 00:44:22].
... where they can share it with each other.
Another thing that they do, which I think is very
cool, is they use a bunch of Claudes at once,
but then they're also using three other agents.
There's an agent called Friday that they love.
That's an AI Asian product called Friday?
Yeah, yeah.
Hadn't heard of that. Okay, interesting.
There's another one called Charlie that they
really love. And in particular, I think the thing
they like about Charlie... We have a whole
video about this, which I can send to you.
Yeah, I'll point to it.
They did an S-tier through F-tier of AI
agents, which I think is so funny. And
one of the things I really like about
Charlie is that it lives in GitHub,
so when you get a pull request, you can just be
like, at Charlie, "Can you check this out?" And
that seems to work really well to have different
agents that have maybe slightly different
perspectives. It's like different people that have
different perspectives and have different taste.
Kieran, he's one of those serious Rails-files,
who they just love Rails, and they love the way
that Rails feels, and so I think he has a
real sensitivity to... Okay, this agent,
ChatGPT for example, it feels very terse, and
minimal, and professional, and it has a particular
kind of style that maybe he likes. Versus,
I don't know, Claude is a slightly different
style. And I think all of that is so interesting
that these things have personalities, and that
that changes what you might want to use it for or
why you might want to use three of them at once.
That is so fascinating. It makes me think
about Peter Deng's conversation again,
where he talks about his hiring strategy and
one of his key lessons. And he ended up hiring
the current head of product for ChatGPT,
the current head of marketing at ChatGPT,
the current head of engineering because
he hires these incredible people.
And his philosophy is to hire a team of Avengers,
where everyone is strong at certain things,
and together they're the perfect team,
versus everyone... versus the best at
everything. And it's interesting that you
can almost do that with different product,
different agents from different companies.
You definitely can.
And it makes me feel like there's a bigger
market than people think potentially,
where people will want different companies,
agents, not just all Devins or not all Codexes.
I think there really is. It's definitely
not one agent to rule them all at all.
So interesting.
Yeah.
Oh, my God. The two people on the Cora team,
what's their background? Are they
both engineers or what are they?
They're both engineers.
Okay.
Kieran's got this crazy background, where... They
both have really interesting backgrounds. Kieran's
got this crazy background, where he was previously
VP Eng at a startup, so was effectively the CTO of
a startup, or maybe two startups, and was one of
the founders. But before that, he was a composer,
a professional composer. And before that, he was
a baker. So we did a team retreat in France last
year, and he taught us all how to make croissants.
My croissant was horrible. His was beautiful.
Seems [inaudible 00:47:16].
And generally, I think that kind of
multidimensional type of talent is the
kind of person that I love having at Every.
Because we're all generalists. We all want to
use AI for all these weird, awesome, creative
things. And someone who has that background
is going to have a good taste for not only
agents, but, "What should the landing page
look like," or whatever. Which I think is
increasingly important, where you're trying
to scale a team of generalists of 15 people to
five products. So that's Kieran's background.
Natasha's background is... I'm jealous because he
only started learning to code when ChatGPT came
out. He had wanted to learn to code forever,
and he's only known how to code in an AI
era. And I keep telling him, "Dude, I learned
to program in middle school from books." I had
to go to Barnes & Noble and buy a book. And
there was nothing... I couldn't Google any-
I had to go to Barnes and Noble and
buy a book and there was nothing...
I couldn't Google anything about
why this function wasn't working.
No Stack Overflow even back then.
Yeah, yeah. There wasn't that overflow. There was
weird BB net forums and stuff that I was like 12
and I probably shouldn't have been on there
or whatever. So he has gone so much faster
than any other engineer, I think in a pre AI
era. And I see the same thing in the rest of
the company. I think there's this huge question
about what happens when kids... Entry level jobs
are taken away by AI. And my take is like that's
worth thinking about and it's possible that that
might be a problem at some point. But my take
is whenever I see a kid with ChatGPT, I'm like,
holy shit, they're going to grow so much faster
than any other person that I've worked with. We
have this guy Alex Duffy who works with us, he
writes for Context Window and he just launched,
we taught AIs how to play diplomacy
with each other, which is really cool.
And he did that whole thing and I think he's
really, really, really talented. And when he
came to us, I guess almost a year ago now, it
was one of those classic cases which I've seen
over and over at every... Which is, you have great
ideas, but you're not a good writer yet and it's
really hard for me to do anything with you until
you're good enough at it. So I have to give you
small little things until you get better and blah,
blah, blah, whatever. And what I noticed with him
is he was just making a year. He made a year's
worth of progress in two months because every time
I sat down with him and told him, okay, here's
how you tell a story. Here's how you think about
a headline. He recorded all of it, put it into a
prompt, and he never made the same mistake twice.
And I think he's so much accelerated from
where he would have been because of this stuff,
and I see that in lots of other parts of the
work. So Natasha is another good example.
And so I think generally people are going
to figure out that some 20-year-old with
ChatGPT subscription is super powerful if you
just mentor them. And I think that's great.
Man, there's so many threads I could
follow here. There's all this fear of
entry level people will never... The roles
are disappearing for entry level people and
so how will we ever have senior people if
these people can't learn to do things as
an entry level person? And what you're saying
is ChatGPT and these tools help you accelerate
really quickly so you don't really need
to be at the bottom rung for a long time.
Yeah. You're effectively learning how to be one
level above the entry level from the beginning
and this is sort of my whole allocation economy
thesis where when you look at skills are going
to be valuable in the AI era, one big group
of skills are the skills of managers. Today,
they're human managers, tomorrow everyone's a
model manager. Right now, AI is not... Right now,
management skills are not broadly distributed,
because it's very expensive, another expensive
thing that... So 8% of the workforce is managers.
It's now going to be much cheaper to manage,
so more people are going to have to do
it. And so that's the thing that kids,
20-year-olds, whatever, I see is now are going
to start to have to learn in addition to,
it's not like you can just say, okay, go do it
and then come back. You have to be able to go
into the work that's being done and help make
it better. But they're learning both at the
same time. They're learning how to manage and how
to do the actual work so that they're good at it.
And the managing here is managing agents. Right?
Yeah. You're managing AI.
And so coming back to your point about how this
core team, and I guess you said everyone doesn't
write code, zero code written, now it's just
managing agents that are writing code for you.
Yeah.
Okay. I've never heard of a company at
this stage, so this is extremely cool.
So the workflow is they give it, here's what
I want. I refine it using this cool prompts
library that they build on and agents build
code, write the code. Then basically the time
is spent reviewing code and then reviewing the
output. What does it look like? What does it
feel like? And then continuing to refine,
wow. So you guys are at where Michael from
Cursor said we will be. So I chatted with
him a few months ago. He said in a year,
this is where he thinks the thing will be.
We're not looking at code anymore. You guys
are already there. Although you were looking
at code. Okay, you're still looking at code.
They definitely are looking at code. So you're
doing a code review before you do anything. And
I do think Danny, who runs Spiral, which is the
cloud code for content tool I was talking about
that we're building, he spent a couple of days
digging into the internals of some third party
library that we were interested in just because
it's helpful to know, it's helpful to understand
those things, but then he's not actually
writing any code. Once he understands it,
he's just off telling cloud code what to
do. And I think that's really important.
This is an insane milestone we're
hitting here. There's this sense
we're getting to a place where you
don't need to really understand code,
you don't have to write any code. We'll get
there and you guys are there. I think this
is so easy to overlook how wild this is. You
have a product team not writing code at all.
It is really wild. I think it's really wild
in particular, just having a small group of
people that have... Everyone has all these
different skills. Everyone's a generalist,
everyone's AI forward. So what you can do in an
environment like that with just still a small
team is crazy. And you're kind of inventing all
these new principles for how do we work together,
how do we do engineering, all that kind of
stuff. And I think that's what makes the
writing... That's why I like doing that
is because the writing that we do from
that I think is really good because we can talk
about it from a sort of position of experience,
but I do want to say something else which
is we're not at a point yet where the
people that work at every could do what
they do if they didn't know how to code.
Yeah, this is what I was going to ask.
Which is a different bar, and I think for a long
time it's going to be valuable to know how to
code for a long time, but this is a progression
that is not a new progression. So for example,
when I was in middle school learning to code,
the new hot thing was scripting languages,
which is Python and JavaScript.
But if you were a real programmer,
you would understand the language underlying
Python and JavaScript, which is written in
C. and scripting language weren't totally real.
And in order to really do anything interesting,
you had to be able to learn both parts of
the stack. Same thing for C programmers,
when I guess in the seventies C was invented, it
was like you got to be able to write assembly.
And English is just a layer on top of scripting
languages. So I think all of those things were
right in the sense that there's... Especially
during transitions, there's a lot of reasons
why it's important to be able to go down a layer
in the stack and it gets less and less frequent
over time, but that still takes a long time.
And there's some times when even if you're a
JavaScript or a Python programmer, it's useful
to know how that stuff works, how it's written,
and see how it's implemented. Today it's
much less important than it used to be,
but that took 10 or 20 years. And I think
that the same thing is going to be true
for programming. Having that skill is super
important and will accelerate you significantly.
It will sort of start to get less important
over time, but we're not close to that yet.
Okay. That's a really important point. I'm
glad you went there. So do you have a sense
of how far we might be from you hiring someone
to build another product that isn't an engineer?
Like a real SaaS product?
So hey, we have this idea we want to
bring someone on to actually lead it.
Very far. Not within sight, but there's a lot of
things that could be products that are a level
down from that I think that you could do almost
now. So an example, we were talking about DIA,
the new AI browser from the browser
company. DIA has these things called skills,
which are effectively little AI apps that you
can run in the browser. You can prompt them
and they run on the web page and do work for
you. A non-technical person can build that,
same thing for custom GPTs from ChatGPT. A
non-technical person can definitely build
that. So I think while I will definitely
maintain that we're not anywhere close to
anybody being able to build a conventional
SaaS app with zero programming knowledge,
aside from just a demo, there are
going to be other forms of software.
One of my things is like software is becoming
content. There's going to be other forms of
software that don't look like the software today,
but you can run, start and run as a business,
as a non-technical person even if you don't know
how to code. And that'll happen very soon. I mean,
it's already kind of happening. It doesn't
look like the thing that you're asking about.
It's sort of like the difference between
a Hollywood movie and a YouTube video.
I think that's really reassuring to a lot
of people. Basically what you're seeing is
AI just supercharges people who have a
skill and allows them to do a lot more.
Yeah.
Okay. Is there any other way that you guys
operate that is really interesting that
might be worth sharing that helps you operate
really quickly, helps you do more with less?
I mean, I would love to talk about how we think
about building products, what products to build,
what do we end up building? Because I think that
there's something sort of special about it that
probably there's a playbook that is useful for
people. So when I think about... This is only
sort of snapped into focus recently. So a lot of
this was just doing it intuitively without really
a thought for it. But when I think about the
kind of things that we have ended up incubating,
it's basically goes back to something I said at
the beginning, which is there are these things
that were historically really expensive that only
rich people or big companies could buy. So a chief
of staff for your email, I think a therapist
or a lawyer is another interesting example.
Someone to organize your closet or organize
your computer is another example. Someone to
go straight for you, that are becoming orders
of magnitude cheaper so that everyone can use
them even if you're at a small startup.
And so basically when you're running, we
are sort of this AI first company. You're running
into all these little things where you're like,
I wish I had a ghost writer right now, but ghost
writers are really expensive. Or I wish I had a
lawyer but it would cost me like $25,000. Lawyers
are really expensive and there's a lot more
demand for those services than can be fulfilled
because they're so expensive. And what AI does
is it allows you to be like, oh, I could just use
cloud for that. I can use ChatGPT for that. And so
you're able to use the demand that you have that
we can afford a lawyer. We have ghost writers,
but there's a lot more that we can't
do because we can't afford it. So we
still have our lawyer and we still have our ghost
writers, but we just do a lot more of that stuff.
And so we notice that. We start to
then use ChatGPT and cloud first,
these general purpose tools to try it and see is
this useful? Does this actually work? All that
kind of stuff. And then if it does, we will
unbundle it into its own separate thing that
becomes an app. And I think what's really special
about this time is the entire game board has been
totally reset in terms of things you can build.
Where five years ago it was like you're going to
build another Notes app. We've been building notes
app for forever, another B2B SAS app. It's all the
same stuff in slightly different packaging.
And now it's totally new territory. No one
knows what's going on. Everyone's inventing it
as it happens. All these new workflows are being
created in a very similar way to, I don't
know, for example, when spreadsheets were
first a thing on computers, we were figuring
out all these new workflows on spreadsheets.
They got unbundled in the B2B SAS, same thing for
ChatGPT and Claude. And what's really cool is you
can be like, cool, I'm using using ChatGPT for
this. It's really useful for me. And you might
be one of the first people to really notice that.
And then because everybody that works at Every is
AI first and came to us because they reads Every,
they read Every, so we all have the same vibe
and we're all kind of doing similar stuff. They
become our first users. So we measure the success
of the product by is it a banger inside of Every,
monologue the app that I was talking to you about,
everyone just started using it and we're
like, okay, we've got something here.
And what's really interesting then is if everyone
inside of Every uses it and people read Every,
they have a similar vibe to us too, so they
become the next set of users. And that's a really,
I think, interesting pipeline for building
applications or building apps. It's a totally new
greenfield so that all the stuff you're thinking
about, it's probably new, which is really cool.
And over time, what I think is organizations like
ours, people who are playing at the edge, we're
doing things that in three years everybody else
is going to be doing. So it may be kind of niche
for now, but it will be a big deal in three years
when everyone else has the same needs that we do.
That is really cool. What I'm hearing is GPT
wrappers are a good idea and are worth building.
100% thank you. GPT wrappers are amazing and
they've been much maligned for absolutely no
reason and people don't understand
how absolutely valuable they are.
I think there's also just you guys raised a
sip seed round. This is a good time to maybe
talk about that. Just these products don't have to
become some mega-billion dollar hits. You kind of
have this portfolio of companies, you have the
content business. So I think there's a really
interesting approach to how big these need to
get to be successful. Maybe just talk about that.
Yeah. I really want Every to be an institution
that teaches people how to live a better,
more human life with technology, particularly
with AI. And both teaches them how to do it
with writing and the content we make and then
builds tools for them to do that. But I think
fundamental to building an institution is, at
least for me, the way I would like to do it is
I want internally it to feel like this creative
playground where we have the opportunity to take
risk and do stuff and do weird stuff that just
doesn't make any sense. We can't justify anyone,
but we just feel like it would be fun. And
so I think I'm always playing with that
dynamic tension between institution serious,
we want this to be lasting and important and
it should just be fun. Let's play around. And
I think having that tension is really valuable.
And so I've always been sort of hesitant to raise
a lot of money because I think it locks you into
having to be that serious thing that's totally
going for it. And there's lots of companies
that figure out that balance. But just for me
personally as a founder, I'm like, I want to
keep the optionality alive and I want to keep
the kind of playful feeling alive. And I think
part of that comes from I know I have the control
to do what I want more or less. There's probably
also some deeper psychological things going on
there, which I'm happy to talk about if you want
to get into it. But I think there's also just...
That's what I want. And so when we started Every,
we raised a very small 700K pre-seed round, and
this was at the height of the creator economy.
So we both started our newsletters. He and I
started our newsletters around the same time.
It was the hypest, craziest thing. People
were throwing money around. It was wild. But
we raised 700K because it was like, I want to
raise enough for us to be able to experiment,
have a little cash cushion, but not so much that
it locks us into anything. And we sent an email to
all of our investors being like, and you're one of
our investors, so you've probably got this email.
Tiny investor. But I'm in there, I'm in there.
We sent an email to everyone being like, this is
probably not a venture business, so you should not
expect us to raise again. And we even raised on
this slightly modified safe that gave everyone the
option to convert to equity in three years, even
if we didn't raise more money. So we did it in a
way that allowed us the option to get really big
and do the traditional thing and also the option
to do it the way we want to do it. Maybe it's not
a huge business, but we love it. That's great.
And we did the same thing for this recent
round where we raised up to 2 million from
Reid Hoffman and starting line VC. And we did
it as what I've been calling a sip seed round,
which is basically they've committed $2
million, but we can pull it down whenever we
want and we just do it on a safe at a set cap.
And for me, that's really helpful because it
allows me psychologically to take a lot more risk.
If we go to zero on the bank account, I can get
more money. Great. I don't have to think about
it. But what's also really helpful is I'm not,
and the rest of the team is not staring at a
gigantic number in the bank account being like,
cool, we can burn this. Let's burn it. And also
for our investors, I think Reid very much wants
us to succeed, but I don't think he cares what
size of business this is. I think he's more
philosophically aligned with the thing that we're
trying to do. And if it becomes a huge business,
he's psyched for it. And I think that kind
of alignment is what I was looking for. I
think there's this core creative spirit
to the thing that I want to maintain
and I really care about having a big impact.
But I think there's a lot of ways to have an
impact. And one of them is building a $10 billion
business. I think another way is really changing
how people see the world, see themselves in the
world. And I think that's what stories do. And
you don't necessarily... Sometimes you
do that by building a gigantic company,
but you don't necessarily always have to do
that. A lot of the stories that we care about
most are from people who maybe they weren't rich
at all. And so I really like creating this place
where we can make a really good business.
And I care a lot about that. But also the
core of the soul of it is about changing
how people see themselves in the world.
I love that you've kind of innovated a
new middle ground way of fundraising,
not bootstrap and not just regular VC. It's a
seed. And I love that this two... If I raised
50 million, it'd be like, okay, I get it.
Let's not put 50 million in our bank account,
but you do have 2 million. It's too much for
us. We don't want to see that in our account.
That's another thing. And we'll see how this
ages. I might be back here in two years crying
the blues because we didn't raise enough money
or whatever. Who knows? But that's the other
thing is I do think we can get so much further
with very small amounts of money. Like Cora,
I think all in to build Cora, we've spent
maybe 300K, Maybe. That's crazy because-
And that includes salaries?
Includes salaries. Yeah.
Wow.
This product was not even technically possible
even if you had billions of dollars three years
ago. Not possible because you can't do email
summarizing and automatic responses and all
that kind of stuff without GPT. So not only
was it totally impossible, but now we can get
with two engineers, we can get the amount done
that would've taken a team of 20 people. And I
think that means that we need less money. And I
don't think that VC has really caught up to that
yet. And I think there are other companies that
are doing... There's a term called seed strapping,
so there are other companies that are starting
to wake up to this too. And I'm curious about
how it changes the VC model. For sure for
us, we have a specific incubation model,
which is a bit different from a VC model. And I
think there's some differentiation in the stuff
that we can do with founders, which is kind of
cool. But yeah, I'm just trying to figure out
a shape that works for me and that's different
from other people and we'll see how this goes.
We'll revisit in a couple years. Seems like it's
going great from the outside. I'm going to ask
about a couple other things before we wrap up.
One is around this consulting arm that you have.
I think it's really interesting because like I
said, I feel like this could be a billion-dollar
business. I feel like every company right now is
trying to figure out what the hell's everyone else
figured out that we're not doing. I've had so many
emails from chief product officers at companies
being like, can you introduce me to some chief
product officers that have done cool things with
AI that we should learn from? So many people
and I would just introduce them to each other
and it's cool because you guys are basically
solving that problem for a lot of companies.
So one is just maybe share a bit about what that
side of the business for folks. And then two,
I feel like I imagine you've seen companies that
have done this really well, have adopted AI,
things have worked really well, they
found really good productivity gains,
and then you found companies that don't. What
do you find is the difference between those two?
I love this question and I have a very
specific opinion about this. So one, yeah,
the consulting arm, basically we spend all
of our time playing around with new models,
writing about them and building stuff with them.
And we have a big audience. So naturally we've
gotten companies over time being like, can you
just come and teach us how to do this? And so we
started to do that. This is pretty nascent. It's
probably been over the last six to nine months,
but it's a pretty big business now. It'll
probably double this year. Last year we
did about a million. Maybe it'll be more this
year. We'll see. It depends on a couple... We
have a couple of big contracts out,
so it might be way more than that.
A billion. I predict a billion
dollars in a few years.
But yeah, basically people are like, can you come
help us learn how to do this? So what we do is
we spend some time going and researching your
organization. So we go in and try to understand
what are all the different teams doing, what
are the repetitive tasks, some of the stuff we
were talking about earlier. And then what we
will do is first we present a little report,
tells you here's everything that we found. Here's
not only that, but you have a chatbot where you
can chat with all the interviews that we did
and you can pull out your own insights. We have
a whole dashboard where it shows you, here are
the teams that are really into this, here are
the teams that are not. Here's how much leverage
you might be able to get on different teams based
on the interviews and based on the AI analysis.
It's pretty cool. And that's an app that I coded
over a weekend with Devin a year ago. And then
Alex runs part of the consulting has helped
upgrade it. Then what we do is we have a training
curriculum. So we go in and train each team and
we customize it based on the interviews that we
do. Because one of the interesting things about
AI is it's such a general purpose technology,
and I think people who work inside companies,
10% of them are like, I'm super
curious about this. 10% are like,
I will never touch this. And 80% are like, if
you tell me how to do it for my job, I'll do it.
And so we customize the training to be like,
here are the exact prompts you're going to use
and here's the exact situations you're going to
use them. And that really, I think helps drive
the adoption. We spend four weeks with each
team, an hour a week, that kind of thing. It
seems to be really cool. And then we'll often also
after this, go and build automations and do some
of the AI operations stuff we were talking about
earlier. Companies really like it. I think we work
with a lot of big hedge funds and PE firms and
big companies, all that kind of stuff. To your-
Companies, all that kind of stuff. To your
second question, which is, "What separates
the good companies from the bad, or the companies
that end up adopting this?," I think the number
one predictor is, "Does the CEO use ChatGPT?,"
or insert your own chatbot. If the CEO is in it
all the time, being like, "This is the coolest
thing," everybody else is going to start doing
it. If the CEO is like, "I don't know, this is for
someone else," no one else is going to be able to
lead that charge, and they're either going to have
... Either they're going to be negative on it, and
so definitely no one's going to do it, or they're
going to have way unrealistic expectations because
they have no intuition for what's possible, and
they're just going to get really disappointed.
But the CEOs that are using it all the time
are able to both drive the excitement and set
reasonable expectations for what can
be achieved, and so those things end
up working really well, and the people that
do this really well ... So, for example, we
work with a hedge fund called Walleye, which
I had the founder on my podcast, AI and I,
a few weeks ago, their gigantic $10 billion
hedge fund. One of the things that they do,
which I think they're basically the model for
how to do this, first thing you did, which
a lot of CEOs are doing is send the, "We're an
AI-first company" email. Everyone's got the memo.
You just got to really do it, and one of the
things he said in his memo, which I love, is,
"I wrote this email with ChatGPT, and
you should too." So you got to like ...
In the memo.
Yeah. You got to lead from the front in that way.
And then, what he does in, I think what a lot of
other really cool companies do is they're doing
weekly meetings where people share prompts and
share use cases. They do a weekly email to their
entire company, being like, "Okay, here are our
usage stats for ChatGPT. Here are the people that
came up with a new prompt and contributed to it."
Create this sort of awareness and momentum,
because going back to the point I made earlier,
about 10% of people are early adopters, those are
the people inside of a company that you need to
find and highlight because they're going to just
go spend all this time figuring out what works,
and then all you have to do is translate what
they learn into the rest of the organization. And
so if you create forums for them to be rewarded,
you're going to automatically transfer a lot of
their learnings to everybody else, and encourage
more of it, and I think that's kind of the secret.
That is awesome. I love this advice. So
just to reflect back, what you just shared,
a few kind of tactics you find that you encourage
within companies, one is just send this memo,
the Toby memo. I don't know if that's the right
way to describe it, who I think it was first
along these lines just, "We're AI-first." It's
going to be part of your performance review.
It's going to be asking, "Can you do it in AI
before you could talk to anyone else?," all
these things, and then just note, "I wrote
this using ChatGPT's," it's a great idea.
This idea of a weekly meeting, so it's like
a live or Zoom meeting, where people share,
"Here's the thing I've learned about using AI,"
and then this weekly stats email of, "Here's
how much we're using ChatGPT across the org.
Here's some people that did some awesome work."
Yeah.
Amazing. And I especially love
this very simple heuristic of,
"If you're a CEO, uses ChatGPT or Claude,
or whatever daily, it's going to work out."
Yeah.
That is super cool. I know it's early,
but what kind of impact have you seen
from a company, kind of leaning into this
and adopting AI widely? Anything you've
seen either anecdotally or numbers-wise?
It's early. It's really hard to say other than
... I think generally, people who do this well
now feel like they can do way more work than they
used to without having to hire more people, and
so they're just going further faster at the same
budget. I don't see a lot of people being like,
"Cool. We're going to fire a bunch of people."
Also, I don't really want to do consulting work
like that. That sucks. But we've never had to say
no. Mostly, people are like, "Cool. I'm just going
to go further with the people that I have."
I think also, back to kind of the first point
I made about reshoring American jobs, I have seen
some companies, not the ones that we worked with,
but I have seen some companies of people that I'm
friends with, where they're like, "We have a call
center somewhere, but I think I can get the same
amount done with two employees in the U.S. that
use one of these customer service platforms."
They're still not totally automatic. I think that
Klarna CEO thing, that was bullshit. But, yeah,
you can have a couple people in the U.S. that
maybe you pay a little bit less to than you would
for 100 people somewhere else, and obviously,
that's the calculus that everyone has to make for
themselves, but I've definitely seen that happen,
and yeah, I think that's the get more
done with the same amount of people.
Maybe to close out our conversation, I want
to come back to this idea that you referenced,
but I want to spend a little more time on this,
which is this idea of the allocation economy. If
I understand it correctly, we've been in this
knowledge economy, where people get paid to do
a thing, and your thesis is that we're moving
to this allocation economy, where the manager
skills become more important, and we're going
to be spending more of our time managing. And I
think what's amazing about this is it also tells
you which skills will matter more in the future,
which is something I think a lot of people are
thinking about. So maybe just answer that question
and share whatever you think is important to share
to give people a sense of what you're thinking.
Yeah. So this is based on our article I wrote two,
two and a half years ago. So this is back before
agents were even thought of as viable. And I was
really trying to think about, "How do I express
what ... In my experience, using this every day,
what skills are useful for me?," because I think
that'll be the case for a lot of other people, and
I think that's kind of the best method, I think,
to do these sorts of predictions, is you have to
be doing it all the time yourself, and then that
informs your opinion about this stuff.
So what I noticed using, at the time,
like GPT-3 or maybe GPT-4, was that I was spending
a lot of time, for example, thinking about,
"How do I communicate the problem? How do I
gather the right information for the problem?
How do I put it in the right way so that the
model that I'm working with gets it? How do I
pick which model to give it to you, and how do
I maybe divide up the task to be like, 'Okay,
this model does this, this model does this,'
based on what I know to be like, 'What's good
and what's bad?'? How do I give them feedback?"
"How do I have a vision for what I want and a
set of criteria for whether it's good?" All
that stuff is exactly how I found myself
using these tools, and I was like, "Oh, that's
just managing." And once that clicks for you,
I think you'll start to see a lot of other
things. So a really good example is there's
a big complaint that it's like, "Well, how can
I have AI do this? I can't trust that they're
going to do it well, so I just do it myself."
And I'm just like, "Yeah, that's exactly what
Every first-time manager says." You always have
this problem, where you're like, "Okay. Well, if
I delegate it, it's not done in the way that
I want it to be done. If I do it myself, I get
no leverage." And so that's how a manager has to
learn how to be a manager is like, "When do I lean
in and maybe micromanage a little bit, and when
can I delegate, and how can I trust it, and how do
I divide up the task and all that kind of stuff?"
And so I think there's a lot of overlap in those
skills. And those skills are not
broadly distributed right now,
but they will be in the future because it
will be so much cheaper to be a manager.
And specifically, I was looking at the
article you wrote, the skills that you
highlight will be more valuable is
evaluating talent, vision, taste,
and to your point, when to get into the
details, when it makes sense to dive in.
Yeah.
Awesome. And then, there's also kind of a
connected point you made that you referenced,
which is that generalists will
become more and more valuable
in the future. You mentioned that
everyone at Every is a generalist.
Yeah.
Share a little bit about that.
Yeah. I find ... I mean, maybe
it's because I'm a generalist,
so you should take this with a grain of salt.
Same, same.
But I think that's one of the things
that has made AI so awesome for me,
is I love to dabble in different things. So
it's like in one day, I can be coding an app,
and making a video, and making images,
and writing, and all that kind of stuff,
and ChatGPT is right there with me. And I think
basically what has happened, as civilization has
progressed from Ancient Greece to now, is what
we've discovered is the more that we specialize,
the better we can coordinate across many
different people. And so it's like the Adam Smith,
like there's a pin factory and someone's
making a pin or whatever his thing is,
is specialization against our trade. And there
have been a lot of really good impacts of that.
One of my favorite examples of this is back
to Ancient Greece, Ancient Athens. Athens
was a civilization of generalists, at least for
citizens. They have a bad history with women and
people who are slaves, but let's just put that
to the side for a second. If you're a citizen,
generalist. You could be expected to be a
fighter, a judge, a juror, maybe a general.
You could expect it to have many
different roles inside of your society
in your lifetime. That changed though, because
Athens became an empire. And as it became an
empire, if you're going to send a general
off to go and invade Sicily or whatever,
you want that person to be pretty skilled. And so
it started to break the general kind of thing into
people start to have specific roles, and they
coordinate with each other and all that kind
of stuff, and I think that pattern has actually
been really good for developing civilization,
but it's also, in a lot of ways, it is not as fun.
It's actually really cool to be a well-rounded
person. And I think the interesting thing about
AI is that it's a little bit like, you can think
of it like having 10,000 PhDs in your pocket.
It knows so much about every little branch of
human knowledge and every art form and every
way of making things or building things,
and you just have access to that, so it's doing
a lot of the ... It's good for doing a lot of
the specialized tasks that you might've had to
spend 10 years getting good at learning about this
particular species of cicada, so you know exactly
how they reproduce. But now, you've got this thing
in your pocket that can tell you all about that
in any given context at any given time, and so
you're empowered to jump a lot more between
all those different domains of skill, and you
can get more done as, for example, like a founder,
where I think we can stay at 15 people much longer
than we would be able to. So the people inside of
Every can stay generalists for much longer, and I
think that that may sort of ripple out into the
rest of the economy, where instead of gigantic,
massive corporations, where each person is doing
one little button turning, you have many more
smaller organizations with more generalists, and I
think that would actually be a really good thing.
This reminds me, I was talking to my personal
trainer that I'm trying out for a little bit,
and she said that she's a very big vision, kind
of high-level person, and not good at executing,
like we're staying organized, and
ChatGPT is such a godsend for her,
because she's just like, "Here's what I want
to do roughly. Just help me get it done."
That's great. I love that.
And so, yeah. And it really made me think
about just how much value all this stuff
is going to unlock. This was amazing. It was
everything I wanted it to be. But with that,
we reached our very exciting
lightning round. Dan, are you ready?
I'm ready.
Here we go. What are two or three books that you
find yourself recommending most to other people?
Well, I already recommended one, which is
War and Peace. Definitely got to read that.
If you want a like Tolstoy primer, I
would read The Death of Ivan Ilyich.
Another good one is A Swim in a Pond in
the Rain, which is by George Saunders,
and that's a collection of Russian short stories
that is also about writing. And in particular,
I really like the Russians because a lot of
the Russian novelists are dealing with the
effects of technology on the traditional
Russian way of life, and they're very
kind of in this really interesting middle
ground between a sort of romantic outlook
on the world and a more rationalist like, "
We're progressing, we're making progress."
And that's one of the things
you'll find in Anna Karenina, oh,
and ... God, what's the guy's ... Levin is
out in the fields with the peasants, doing the
scythe thing. That's Tolstoy kind of thinking
about, "Oh, what would it be like, instead of
being a nobleman who's trying to make farms way
more efficient, I was just like with my scythe,
that was really happy?" Anyway, so they're dealing
with a lot of similar stuff to, I think AI.
The Master and His Emissary is another
really good one, and that's about
basically how the different hemispheres of the
brain view reality. It's really, really good,
and I think it relates to a lot of AI stuff too.
Yeah, I think those are my three or four. Yeah.
Excellent list. I think nobody's mentioned
any of these, so that's always a good sign.
Do you have a favorite recent movie
or TV show you've really enjoyed?
Yes. I really love Deadwood. Have you seen it?
I absolutely love it. I remember when they stopped
it for some reason. I think he had to go
do something else at HBO. It was so sad.
Yeah.
It's amazing, yeah.
David Milch is incredible, national treasure,
incredible writer. But what I really love about
it, and I only recently watched it, is he
talks about Deadwood being about how order
forms out of chaos. So it's this like
frontier town, people are going to it,
and there's no law, there's no rules.
And by season three, there's a mayor,
and all the industry has come in, and it's like
a real proper town, and I just love that. And I
think there's a lot of parallels from the
Western frontier to technology frontiers,
and so I think that show is a really
interesting study in that kind of dynamic.
I love how everything connects to how tech
works and how AI came to be. I love this.
Thank you.
Do you have a favorite product you've
recently discovered that you really love?
I don't have a good answer for that because I just
spent a lot of time using our internal products,
but my stock answer is Granola. So I do
really love Granola. My one gripe with them,
and I hope they listen to this podcast,
is I really want to export all my notes.
I want an API, but other than that,
I think it's a fantastic product.
That is definitely the most mentioned product
in this segment for the past couple months,
so good job, Granola. I can't help but mention,
you get a year free of Granola if you become an
annual subscriber of my newsletter. Well,
what a freaking deal. And not just you,
but your whole company gets free
Granola for a year. What a deal.
This is not a paid promotion by me. That's just
how I feel. So I'm glad it's part of the bundle.
Yeah, incredible. Okay. Do you have a favorite
life motto that you often come back
to find useful in work or in life?
So basically, I use ChatGPT all the
time, and it has memory. So I was like,
"I'm going on Lenny's podcast. What
would my life motto be?," and it said,
"Your life motto is witness deeply, build
bravely. You prize slow, attentive seeing,
whether it's reading Tolstoy, tracking
meditation themes, or X-raying a David
Milch paragraph." So it's hitting all the
stuff I just mentioned, which is really funny.
And then, Build bravely, you turn those insights
into concrete things, like Every in Quora and
longform essays and all that kind of stuff. So
I think there's something about that. Actually,
this reminds me, this actually reminds me of
the actual motto, which is ... And I didn't
come up with this. I think it's like Pliny the
Younger said, "Do things worth writing about,
and write things worth reading."
Seems like a pretty good summation.
Do things worth writing about
and read things worth reading.
Write things worth reading.
Write things worth reading. That should
be the motto of both of our newsletters.
Yeah.
That is really good. Okay. And by the way, I love
that you asked ChatGPT, "What's my life motto?"
And wait, this is interesting. So it didn't
give me the answer, but inspired the answer.
Yeah.
And I think that's actually exactly how I use it.
[inaudible 01:28:55] Wow. It's an
extension of our brains already.
Yeah.
Last question. I was reading somewhere, where
you wrote that you stopped writing at one point.
You were just like, "I need to do other things, I
need to build this company," and then you realize,
"I need to get back to writing," because things
started going sideways. And I feel like this is
such an interesting corollary to a lot of the
stuff you talked about, of just things that
make you happy, stay close to enjoy. Just share
what happened there, because I didn't know that.
This is definitely not a lightning round thing,
so I'll expound, but I'll try
to do it as quickly as possible.
Perfect.
I think generally, when you're building a company,
even if you do it the way that I do it or did it,
which is you don't raise a lot of money and you
try to stay in control, there's a big temptation
to try to run the company in the way you think
you should. And I have this weird thing where I'm
like, "I really love writing, but I also really
love business," and there were not a lot of models
for me of people who had successful businesses
that were also writers. It turns out there are,
but I didn't know about that for a while. And so
early on at Every, it was growing really well,
because I was writing a lot, and Nathan was
writing a lot. And when I stopped writing,
the business didn't work as well because media
businesses don't follow the same pattern as tech
startups, because if you're a media business
and you are a founder who then hires people
to make the product, which is right, if you
have product market fit before, you lose it,
and maybe you hire people that are good writers,
but that's hard. It's total opposite pattern for
startups. So you build the first version
of the product, and then you hire people
to build the rest of it, and so that's what I
did. And I also really struggled with, "Okay,
what are the implications for that and for my
career," and I think it was hard for me to admit,
like I actually want to write because I
just didn't have any examples of someone
being the kind of writer that I wanted to be. And
what's really interesting is three years into the
business ... The business has been pretty flat.
I was pretty miserable because I was not doing
the thing that I really wanted to
do, and I asked ChatGPT, I was like,
"Are there any examples of writers that have built
businesses?" And it was like, "Yeah, Joel Spolsky,
who built Trello and Stack Overflow. There's
Jason Fried who I've known for a long time,
and I've always looked up to, but I forgot about
in this context. There is Sam Harris who's got a
great podcast, and he's got a gigantic meditation
app. There is Bill Simmons, who's incredible
podcaster and also built The Ringer, sold to
Spotify for a couple hundred million bucks.
There's a lot of these people, and there are
patterns that they use to build companies that
are pretty well-understood. They're just
not typical Silicon Valley patterns. And
so I was like, "Cool. I just want to be
a writer. I think it'll be really fun."
And so I sort of flipped. I still
have the builder, entrepreneur,
founder part of my identity, but I sort of
flipped it to be like writing is at the center,
and I'm unapologetic about it, and that's actually
good for the business. It's good for me and it's
good for the business. And the more I've leaned
into that, doing the thing that ... If you told
anyone that you're starting a business, where
it's like, "Well, we're going to be a newsletter,
and we're going to incubate all these apps,
and we're going to do consulting and whatever,"
they would be like, "You're nuts."
"Everyone wants to do that. Of course,
Every founder wants to do that, but you have to
focus. You can't write, whatever." But every time
I've kind of just leaned into something that feels
like the most, the ultimate luxury of my hidden
secret desire, it's actually worked a lot better,
and I think you end up ... What it really is,
is there's a huge tax to doing something
every day that you don't quite like that much,
or you're not quite a fit for, and by sort
of giving into those secret desires, you end
up finding a shape for the work that you do and
the business that you build that is good for you,
and that's always going to be a somewhat unique
shape from other businesses that have been built.
It's always going to rhyme with other things,
but I think finding that unique shape,
instead of just kind of cargo culting, like
what you think a company should look like is
definitely a much better way to be successful,
and it's also a much better way to live.
I think this is going to hit hard with
a lot of people who are listening,
who are maybe founders or want to be founders,
and this resonates with a lot of people that have
been on this podcast sharing similar lessons.
Dan, this was incredible. Two final questions.
Where can folks check out Every, find you
online, and how can listeners be useful to you?
So you can find us at every.to. I'm
also on Twitter at @danshipper. You can
go there to check out our products, our
newsletter, if you want to stay on top of AI,
all that kind of stuff. I also have
a podcast. It's called AI and I.
You can find it on YouTube and on Spotify.
And how can people be useful? Honestly,
I think that the most useful thing for
someone like me, based on what I want to do,
is I want people to find interesting, cool
ways to use AI that actually helps make their
lives better. So just go do that, and tell me
about it, and I think that'll be great, and so-
What's the best way to tell you? Is it comments
on your YouTube show? Is it emailing you, DM you?
I would say tweet me.
Yeah.
If you subscribe to Every, you
can also reply to those emails,
and they eventually get forwarded to me.
So tweet me. Reply to Every. And if you
want to comment on YouTube, great. I'm not in the
YouTube comments as much as I should be, though.
Don't do that. Maybe don't do that.
Yeah.
Okay. Well, Dan, this was incredible. Thank
you so much for sharing. Thanks for being here.
Thanks for having me.
Bye, everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review, as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.