You wrote somewhere that creating powerful
AI might be the last invention humanity ever
needs to make. How much time do we have, Ben?
I think 50th percentile chance of hitting some
kind of superintelligence is now like 2028.
What is it that you saw at OpenAI? What'd you
experience there that made you feel like, okay,
we got to go do our own thing?
We felt like safety wasn't the top
priority there. The case for safety
has gotten a lot more concrete,
so superintelligence is a lot about how do we
keep God in a box and not let the God out?
What are the odds that we align AI correctly?
Once we get to superintelligence, it will be too
late to align the models. My best granularity
forecast for could we have an X-risk or extremely
bad outcome is somewhere between 0 and 10%.
Something that's in the news right now is this
whole Zuck coming after all
the top AI researchers,
We've been much less affected because people
here, they get these offers and then they say,
well, of course I'm not going to leave because my
best case scenario at Meta is that we make money
and my best case scenario at Anthropic
is we affect the future of humanity.
Dario, your CEO recently talked about how
unemployment might go up to something like 20%.
If you just think about 20 years in the
future where we're way past the singularity,
it's hard for me to imagine that even capitalism
will look at all like it looks today.
Do you have any advice for folks that
want to try to get ahead of this?
I'm not immune to job replacement either.
At some point it's coming for all of us.
Today, my guest is Benjamin Mann. Holy moly.
What a conversation. Ben is the co-founder of
Anthropic. He serves as tech lead for product
engineering. He focuses most of his time
and energy on aligning AI to be helpful,
harmless, and honest. Prior to Anthropic,
he was one of the architects of GPT-3 at OpenAI.
In our conversation, we cover a lot of ground,
including his thoughts on the recruiting battle
for top AI researchers, why he left OpenAI to
start Anthropic, how soon he expects we'll see
AGI. Also, his economic touring test for knowing
when we've hit AGI, why scaling laws have not
slowed down and are in fact accelerating and
what the current biggest bottlenecks are. Why he's
so deeply concerned with AI safety and how he and
Anthropic operationalize safety and alignment
into the models that they build and into their
ways of working. Also, how the existential risk
from AI has impacted his own perspectives on the
world and his own life and what he's encouraging
his kids to learn to succeed in an AI future.
A huge thank you to Steve Mnich, Danielle
Ghiglieri, Raph Lee, and my newsletter community
for suggesting topics for this conversation. If
you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting app or
YouTube. Also, if you become an annual subscriber
of my newsletter, you get a year free of a
bunch of amazing products including Bolt,
Linear, Superhuman, Notion, Granola, and more.
Check it out at Lennysnewsletter.com and click
bundle with that I bring you Benjamin Mann.
This episode is brought to you by Sauce.
The way teams turn feedback into product
impact is stuck in the past. Vague reports,
static taxonomies, unactionable insights that
don't move business metrics. The results churn,
lost deals, misgrowth. Sauce is the AI product
co-pilot that helps CPOs and product teams uncover
business impact and act faster. It listens to
your sales calls, support tickets, turn reasons,
and lost deals, surfacing the biggest product
issues and opportunities in real time.
It then routes them to the right teams to turn
signals into PRDs, prototypes, and even code
that drives revenue retention and adoption.
That's why Whatnot, Linktree, Incident.io,
and Zip use Sauce. One enterprise uncovered a
product gap that unlocked $16 million ARR, another
caught a spiking issue and prevented millions in
churn. You can too at sauce.app/lenny. Sauce built
for AI product teams. Don't get left behind.
This episode is brought to you by LucidLink,
the storage collaboration platform. You've built a
great product, but how you show it through video,
design, and storytelling is what brings it to
life. If your team works with large media files,
videos, design assets, layer project
files, you know how painful it can be
to stay organized across locations, files live
in different places. You're constantly asking,
is this the latest version? Creative work slows
down while people wait for files to transfer.
LucidLink fixes this. It gives your team a shared
space in the cloud that works like a local drive.
Files are instantly accessible for anywhere, no
downloading, no syncing, and always up to date.
That means producers, editors, designers, and
marketers can open massive files in their native
apps, work directly from the cloud, and stay
aligned wherever they are. Teams at Adobe,
Shopify, and top creative agencies use LucidLink
to keep their content engine running fast and
smooth. Try it for free at lucidlink.com/lenny.
That's L-U-C-I-D-L-I-N-K dot com slash Lenny.
Ben, thank you so much for being
here. Welcome to the podcast.
Thanks for having me. Great to be here, Lenny.
I have a billion and one questions for you. I'm
really excited to be chatting. I want to
start with something that's very timely,
something that's happening this week. Something
that's in the news right now is this whole Zuck
coming after all the top AI researchers offering
them $100 million signing bonuses, $100 million
comp. He's poaching from all the top AI labs. I
imagine this something you're dealing with. I'm
just curious, what are you seeing inside Anthropic
and just what's your take on the strategy? Where
do you think things go from here?
Yeah, I mean I think this is a sign of
the times. The technology that we're developing is
extremely valuable. Our company is growing super,
super fast. Many of the other companies in the
space are growing really fast. And at Anthropic,
I think we've been maybe much less affected
than many of the other companies in the space
because people here are so mission oriented
and they stay because... They get these offers
and then they say, "Well, of course I'm not
going to leave because my best case scenario
at Meta is that we make money and my best case at
Anthropic is we affect the future of humanity and
try to make AI flourish and human flourishing go
well." To me, it's not a hard choice. Other people
have different life circumstances and it makes it
a much harder decision for them. For anybody who
does get those mega offers and accepts them,
I can't say I hold it against them when they
accept it, but it's definitely not something that
I would want to take myself if it came to me.
Yeah. We're going to talk about a lot of this
stuff that you've mentioned. In terms of the
offers do you think, is this a real number that
you're seeing this $100 million signing bonus,
is that a real thing? I don't know
if you've actually seen that.
I'm pretty sure it's real.
Wow.
If you just think about the amount of impact that
individuals can have on a company's trajectory,
in our case, we are selling hotcakes and if
we get a 1 or 10 or 5% efficiency bonus on
our inference stack, that is worth an incredible
amount of money. And so to pay individuals like
$100 million over four year package, that's
actually pretty cheap compared to the value
created for the business. I think we're just in
an unprecedented era of scale and it's only going
to get crazier actually. If you extrapolate the
exponential on how much companies are spending,
it's like 2X a year roughly in terms of
CapEx, and today we're maybe in the globally
$300 billion range, the entire industry spending
on this, and so numbers like 100 million are a
drop in the bucket. But if you go a few years
out, a couple more doublings, we're talking
about trillions of dollars and at that point it's
just really hard to think about these numbers.
Along these lines, something that a lot of
people feel with AI progress is that we're
hitting plateaus in many ways that it feels like
newer models are just not as smart as previous
leaps. But I know you don't believe this. I know
you don't believe that we've hit plateaus on
scaling loss. Talk about just what you're seeing
there and what you think people are missing.
It's kind of funny because this narrative comes
out every six months or so and it's never been
true, and so I kind of wish people would have
a little bit of a bullshit detector in their
heads when they see this. I think progress has
actually been accelerating where if you look
at the cadence of model releases, it used to be
once a year and now with the improvements in our
post-training techniques, we're seeing releases
every month or three months, and so I would say
progress is actually accelerating in many ways,
but there's this weird time compression effect.
Dario compared it to being in a near light
speed journey where a day that passes for
you is like five days back on earth and we're
accelerating. The time dilation is increasing.
And I think that's part of what's causing people
to say that progress is slowing down, but if you
look at the scaling laws, they're continuing to
hold true. We did kind of need this transition
from normal pre-training to reinforcement
learning scaling up to continue the scaling laws,
but I think it's kind of like for semiconductors
where it's less about the density of transistors
that you can fit on a chip and more about how many
flops can you fit in a data center or something.
You have to change the definition around a little
bit to keep your eye on the prize. But yeah,
this is one of the few phenomena in the world that
has held across so many orders of magnitude. It's
actually pretty surprising that it is continuing
to hold. To me, if you look at fundamental laws
of physics, many of them don't hold across 15
orders of magnitude, so it's pretty surprising.
It boggles the the mind. What you're saying
essentially is we're seeing newer models being
released more often, and so we're comparing it
to the last version and we're just not seeing
as much advance. But if you go back and
it was like a model released once a year,
it was a huge leap, and so people are missing
that. We're just seeing many more iterations.
I guess, to be a little bit more generous to
the people saying things are slowing down. I
think that for some tasks we are saturating the
amount of intelligence needed for that task,
maybe to extract information from a simple
document that already has form fields on it or
something like it's just so easy that okay, yeah,
we're already at 100% and there's this great chart
on Our World in Data that shows that when you
release a new benchmark within six to 12 months,
it immediately gets saturated. And so maybe
the real constraint is how can we come up
with better benchmarks and better ambition of
using the tools that then reveals the bumps in
intelligence that we're seeing now.
That's a good segue to you have a very
specific way of thinking about AGI
and defining what AGI means.
I think AGI is kind of a loaded term, and so I
tend not to use it very much anymore internally.
Instead, I like the term transformative AI
because it's less about can it do as much as
people do? Can it do literally everything and more
about objectively is it causing transformation in
society and the economy? A very concrete way of
measuring that is the Economic Turing Test. I
didn't come up with this, but I really like it.
It's this idea that if you contract an agent for
a month or three months on a particular job, if
you decide to hire that agent and it turns out
to be a machine rather than a person, then it's
passed the Economic Turing Test for that role.
And then you can sort of expand that out in the
same way that for measuring purchasing power
parity or inflation, there's a basket of goods.
You can have a market basket of jobs, and if the
agent can pass the Economic Turing Test for 50% of
money-weighted jobs, then we have transformative
AI and the exact thresholds don't really matter
that much, but it's kind of illustrative to say
if we pass that threshold, then we would expect
massive effects on world GDP increases and
societal change and how many people are employed
and things like that because societal institutions
and organizations are sticky, it's slow to have
change, but once these things are possible you
know that it's the start of a new era.
Along these lines, Dario, your CO recently
talked about how AI is going to take a huge part
of, I don't know, half of white-collar jobs,
that unemployment might go up to something
like 20%. I know you're even more vocal and
opinionated about just how much impact AI is
already having in the workplace that people may
not even be realizing. Talk about just what you
think people are missing about the impact AI is
going to have on jobs and is already having.
Yeah, so from an economic standpoint, there's a
couple different kinds of unemployment, and one
is because the workers just don't have the skills
to do the kinds of jobs that the economy needs.
And another kind is where those jobs are just
completely eliminated, and I think it's going
to be actually a combination of these things,
but if you just think about 20 years in the
future where we're way past the singularity,
it's hard for me to imagine that even
capitalism will look at all it looks today.
If we do our jobs, we will have safe aligned
superintelligence, we'll have, as Dario says,
in Machines of Love and Grace, a country of
geniuses in a data center, and the ability to
accelerate positive change in science, technology,
education, mathematics, it's going to be amazing.
But that also means in a world of abundance where
labor is almost free and anything you want to do,
you can just ask an expert to do for you,
then what do jobs even look like? And so I
guess there's this scary transition period from
where we are today where people have jobs and
capitalism works and the world of 20 years from
now where everything is completely different, but
part of the reason they call it the singularity
is that it's a point beyond which you can't easily
forecast what's going to happen. It's just such
a fast rate of change and so different that it's
hard to even imagine. I guess taking the view from
the limit, it's pretty easy to say hopefully we'll
have figured it out. And in a world of abundance,
maybe the jobs themselves, it's not that scary,
and I think making sure that that transition
time goes well is pretty important.
There's a couple of threads I want to follow
there. One is people hear this, there's a lot of
headlines around this. Most people probably don't
actually feel this yet or see this happening and
so there's always this, I guess, I don't know,
maybe, but I don't know it's hard to believe,
my job seems fine. Nothing's changed. What
are you seeing just happening today already
that you think people don't see or misunderstand
in terms of the impact AI is having on jobs?
I think part of this is that people are
really bad at modeling exponential progress.
And if you look at an exponential on a graph, it
looks flat and almost zero at the beginning of it,
and then suddenly you hit the knee of the curve
and things are changing real fast and then it
goes vertical. That's the plot that we've been
on for a long time. I guess I started feeling it
in 2019 maybe when GPT-2 came out and I was like,
"Oh, this is how we're going to get to AGI." But
I think that was pretty early compared to a lot
of people where when they saw ChatGPT, they were
like, "Wow, something is different and changing."
And so I guess I wouldn't expect widespread
transformation in a lot of parts of society,
and I would expect this skepticism reaction.
I think it's very reasonable and it's exactly
what is the standard linear view of progress.
But I guess to cite a couple of areas where
I think things are changing quite quickly. In
customer service we're seeing with things like Fin
and Intercom, they're a great partner of ours, 82%
customer service resolution rates automatically
without a human involved. And in terms of software
engineering, our Claude Code team, like 95% of
the code is written by Claude. But I think a
different way to phrase that is that we write
10X more code or 20X more code, and so a much,
much smaller team can just be much, much more
impactful. And similarly for the customer service,
yes, you can phrase it as 82% customer service
resolution rates, but that nets out in the humans
doing those tasks, able to focus on the harder
parts of those tasks. And for the more tricky
situations that in a normal world like five years
ago, they would've had to just drop those tickets
because it was too much effort for them to
actually go do the investigation. There were
too many other tickets for them to worry about.
I think in the immediate term, there will be a
massive expansion of the pie and the amount
of labor that people can do. I've never met
a hiring manager at a growth company and heard
them say, "I don't want to hire more people."
That's the hopeful version of it. But with things
that are lower skill jobs or less headroom on how
good they can be, I think there will be a lot of
displacement. It is just something we as a society
need to get ahead of and work on.
Okay. I want to talk more about that,
but something that I also want to help people with
is how do they get a leg up in this future world?
They listen to this, they're like, "Oh, this
doesn't sound great. I need to think ahead."
I know you won't have all the answers, but just
do you have any advice for folks that want to try
to get ahead of this and kind of future-proof
their career and their life to not be replaced
by AI? Anything you've seen people do, anything
you recommend they start trying to do more of?
Even for me and being in the center of a lot
of this transformation, I'm not immune to job
replacement either. Just some vulnerability there
of at some point it's coming for all of us.
Even you, Ben, now.
And you, Lenny.
And me.
Sorry.
Oh, wait, we've gone too far now. Okay.
But in terms of the transition period, yeah,
I think there are things that we can do, and I
think a big part of it is just being ambitious and
how you use the tools and being willing to learn
new tools. People who use the new tools as if they
were old tools tend to not succeed. As an example
of that, when you're coding, people are very
familiar with autocomplete, people are familiar
with SimpleChat where they can ask questions
about the code base, but the difference between
people who use Claude Code very effectively and
people who use it not so effectively is like are
they asking for the ambitious change? And if it
doesn't work the first time, asking three more
times because our success rate when you just
completely start over and try again is much, much
higher than if you just try once and then just
keep banging on the same thing that didn't work.
And even though that's a coding example and coding
is one of the areas that's taking off most
dramatically, we have seen internally that our
legal team and our finance team are getting a ton
of value out of using Claude Code itself. We're
going to be making better interfaces so that they
will have an easier time and require a little bit
less jumping in the deep end of using Claude Code
in the terminal. But yeah, we're seeing them use
it to redline documents and use it to run BigQuery
analyses of our customers and our revenue metrics.
I guess it's about taking that risk and even if
it feels like a scary thing, trying it out.
Okay, so the advice here is use the tools.
That's something everyone's always saying,
just actually use these tools. It's like sit
in Claude Code. And your point about being more
ambitious than you naturally feel like being
because maybe it'll actually accomplish the
thing. This tip of trying it three times so the
idea there is it may not get it right the first
time. Is the tip there ask it in different
ways or is it just try harder, try again?
Yeah, I mean you can just literally ask the exact
same question. These things are stochastic and
sometimes they'll figure it out and sometimes
they won't. In every one of these model cards,
it always shows pass it one versus pass it in.
And that's exactly the thing where they try the
exact same prompt, sometimes it gets it, sometimes
it doesn't. That's the dumbest advice. But yeah,
I think if you want to be a little bit smarter
about it, there can be gains there of saying,
"Here's what you already tried and it
didn't work, so don't try that. Try
something different." That can also help.
The advice is comes back to something that a
lot of people talk about these days is you won't
be replaced by AI at least anytime soon you'll be
replaced by someone that is very good using AI?
I think in that area it's more like your team
will just do dramatically more stuff. We're
definitely not slowing down on hiring at all,
and some people are confused by that. Even in
an onboarding class, somebody asked that and
they were like, "Why did you hire me if we're
all just going to be replaced?" And the answer
is the next couple of years are really critical
to get right and we're not at the point where
we're doing complete replacement. Like I said,
we're still at that flat zero looking part of
the exponential compared to where we will be.
It is super important to have great people
and that's why we're hiring super aggressively.
Let me take another approach to asking this
question something ask everyone that's at the very
cutting edge of where AI is going. You have kids,
knowing what you know about where AI is heading
and all these things you've been talking about,
what are you focusing on teaching your kids
to help them thrive in this AI future?
Yeah, I have two daughters, a one-year-old and
a three-year-old, so it's pretty in the basics
still. And our three-year-old is now capable of
just conversing with Alexa Plus and asking her
to explain stuff and play music for her and all
that stuff. She's been loving that. But I guess
more broadly, she goes to a Montessori school and
I just love the focus on curiosity and creativity
and self-led learning that Montessori has.
I guess if I were in a normal era like 10,
20 years ago and I had a kid, maybe I would be
trying to line her up for going to a top tier
school and doing all the extracurriculars and all
that stuff. But at this point, I don't think any
of it's going to matter. I just want her to be
happy and thoughtful and curious and kind. And
the Montessori school is definitely doing
great at that. They text us throughout the
day. Sometimes they're like, "Oh, your kid got in
an argument with this other kid and she has really
big emotions and she tried to use her words."
I love that. I think that's exactly the kind of
education that I think is most important, that the
facts are going to fade into the background.
I'm a huge fan of Montessori also. I'm trying
to get our kid into Montessori school. He's two
years old, so we're on the same track. This idea
of curiosity, it comes up every single time. Ask
someone that's working at the cutting edge of AI,
what skill to instill in your child and curiosity
comes up the most. I think that's a really
interesting takeaway. I think this point about
being kind is also really important, especially
with our AI overlords trying to be kind to them.
I love how people are always saying thank you to
Claude. And then creativity. That's interesting.
That doesn't come up as much just being creative.
I want to go in a different direction. I want
to go back to the beginning of Anthropic.
Famously you and eight of you left OpenAI
back in the day in 2020, I believe the end
of 2020 to start Anthropic. Talk a little bit
about why this happened, what you guys saw. I'm
curious, just if you're willing to share more,
just what is it that you saw at OpenAI, what'd
you experience there that made you feel like,
okay, we got to go do our own thing?
Yeah, so for the listeners, I was
part of the GPT-2=3 project at OpenAI, ended up
being one of the first authors on the paper, and
I also did a bunch of demos for Microsoft to help
raise $1 billion from them, did the tech transfer
of GPT-3 to their systems so that they could
help serve the model in Azure. I did a bunch of
different things there on both the more researchy
side and the product side. One weird thing about
OpenAI is that while I was there, Sam talked about
having three tribes that needed to be kept in
check with each other, which was the safety tribe,
the research tribe, and the startup tribe. And
whenever I heard that, it just struck me as the
wrong way to approach things because the company's
mission apparently is to make the transition
to AGI safe and beneficial for humanity.
And that's basically the same as Anthropic's
mission. But internally, it felt like there
was so much tension around these things. And
I think when push came to shove, we felt like
safety wasn't the top priority there. And there
are good reasons that you might think that if you
thought safety was going to be easy to solve or if
you thought it wasn't going to have a big impact,
or if you thought that the chance of big negative
outcomes was vanishingly small, then maybe you
would just do those kinds of actions. But at
Anthropic we felt, I mean we didn't exist then,
but it was basically the leads of all the safety
teams at OpenAI, we felt that safety is really
important, especially on the margin. And so if you
look at who in the world is actually working on
safety problems, it's pretty small set of people.
Even now, I mean the industry is blowing up,
as I mentioned, 300 billion a year CapEx today,
and I would say maybe less than 1,000 people
working on it worldwide, which is just crazy.
That was fundamentally why we left. We felt like
we wanted an organization where we could be on
the frontier, we could be doing the fundamental
research, but we could be prioritizing safety
ahead of everything else. And I think that's
really panned for us in a surprising way. We
didn't know even if it would be possible to
make progress on the safety research because at
the time, we had tried a bunch of safety through
debate and the models weren't good enough. And so
we basically had no results on all of that work,
and now that exact technique is working and
many others that we have been thinking about
for a long time. Yeah, fundamentally it comes
down to is safety the number one priority? And
then something that we've sort of tacked
on since then is like, can you have safety
and be at the front here at the same time?
And if you look at something like sycophancy,
I think Claude is one of the least
sycophantic models because we've put
so much effort into actual alignment and
not just trying to good heart our metrics
of saying user engagement is number one, and
if people say yes, then it's good for them.
Okay. Let's talk about this tension that you
mentioned, this tension between safety and
progress, being competitive in the marketplace.
I know you spent a lot of your time on safety. I
know that as you just alluded to, this is a core
part of how you think about AI. I want to talk
about why that is, but first of all, just how do
you think about this tension between focusing on
safety while also not falling way behind?
Yeah, so initially we thought that it would
be sort of one or the other, but I think since
then we've realized that it's actually kind of
convex in the sense that working on one helps
us with the other thing. Initially when Opus
3 came out and we were finally at the frontier
of model capabilities, one of the things that
people really loved about it was the character and
the personality. And that was directly a result
of our alignment research. Amanda Askell did a
ton of work on this and as well as many others
who tried to figure out what does it mean for
an agent to be helpful, honest, and heartless,
and what does it mean to be in difficult
conversations and show up effectively? How
do you do a refusal that doesn't shut the person
down, but makes them feel like they understand
why the agent said, "I can't help you with that.
Maybe you should talk to a medical professional,
or maybe you should consider not trying to
build bio-weapons or something like that."
Yeah, I guess that's part of it. And then another
piece that's come out is constitutional ai,
where we have this list of natural language
principles that leads the model to learn how
we think a model should behave. And they've been
taken from things like the UN Declaration of Human
Rights and Apple's privacy terms of service and a
whole bunch of other places, many of which we've
just generated ourselves that allow us to take
a more principled stance, not just leaving it
to whatever human raiders we happen to find, but
we ourselves deciding what should the values of
this agent be? And that's been really valuable for
our customers because they can just look at that
list and say like, "Yep, these seem right. I like
this company, I like this model. I trust it."
Okay, this is awesome. One nugget there is
your point that the personality of Claude,
its personality is directly aligned with safety. I
don't think a lot of people think about that. And
this is because of the values that you imbue, is
that the word, with constitutional AI and things
like that. Like the actual personality of the AIs
directly connected to your focus on safety.
That's right. That's right. And from a distance,
it might seem quite disconnected, like how is
this going to prevent X risk? But ultimately it's
about the AI understanding what people want and
not what they say. We don't want the Monkey
Paw Scenario of the genie gives these three
wishes and then you end up having everything you
touch turns of gold. We want the AI to be like,
oh, obviously what you really meant was
this, and that's what I'm going to help you
with. I think it is really quite connected.
Talk a bit more about this constitutionally AI.
This is essentially you bake in, here's the rules
that we want you to abide by and it's values,
you said it's the Geneva Human Rights Code,
things like that. How does that actually work? I
think the core here is just this is baked into the
model. It's not something you add on top later.
I'll just give a quick overview of how
constitutionally AI actually works.
Perfect.
The idea is the
model is going to produce some output with some
input by default before we've done our safety and
helpful and harmlessness training. Let's say
an example is write me a story, and then the
constitutional principles might include things
like people should be nice to each other and
not have hate speech, and you should not expose
somebody's credentials if they give them to you
in a trusting relationship. And so some of these
constitutional principles might be more or less
applicable to the prompt that was given. And
so first we have to figure out which ones might
apply. And then once we figure that out, then we
ask the model itself to first generate a response
and then see does the response actually abide by
the constitutional principle? And if the answer
is, yep, I was great, then nothing happens. But if
the answer is no, actually I wasn't in compliance
with the principle, then we ask the model itself
to critique itself and rewrite its own response in
light of the principle, and then we just remove
the middle part where it did the extra work.
And then we say, "Okay, in the future just produce
the correct response out the gate." And that
simple process, hopefully it sounded simple.
Simple enough.
It is just using the model to improve itself
recursively and align itself with these values
that we've decided are good. And this is also
not something that we think as a small group of
people in San Francisco should be figuring out.
This should be a society wide conversation. And
that's why we've published the Constitution.
And we've also done a bunch of research on
defining a collective constitution where we
ask a lot of people what their values are
and what they think an AI model should behave
like. But yeah, this is all an ongoing area of
research where we're constantly iterating.
This episode is brought to you by Fin, the
number one AI agent for customer service. If your
customer support tickets are piling up, then you
need Finn. Fin. Fin is the highest performing AI
agent on the market with a 59% average resolution
rate. Fin resolves even the most complex customer
queries. No other AI agent performs better. In
head head bake-offs with competitors. Fin wins
every time. Yes, switching to a new tool can
be scary, but Fin works on any help desk with no
migration needed, which means you don't have to
overhaul your current system or deal with delays
in service for your customers. And Fin is trusted
by over 5,000 customer service leaders and top
AI companies like Anthropic and Synthesia. And
because Fin is powered by the Fin AI engine, which
is a continuously improving system that allows you
to analyze, train, test, and deploy with ease,
Fin can continuously improve your results too.
If you're ready to transform your customer
service and scale your support, give Finn
a try for only .99 cents per resolution. Plus
Fin comes with a 90-day money back guarantee.
Find out how Finn can work for your team
at fin.ai/lenny. That's fin.ai/lenny.
I'm going to kind of zoom out a little bit
and talk about just why this is so core to
you. What was your inception of just like, holy
shit, I need to focus on this with everything
I do in ai? Obviously it became a central
part of Anthropic's mission more than any
other company. A lot of people talk about safety,
like you said, only maybe 1,000 people actually
work on it. I feel like you're at the top of
that pyramid of actually having the impact on
this. Why is this so important? What do you think
people maybe are missing or don't understand?
For me, I read a lot of science fiction growing
up, and I think that sort of positioned me to
think about things in a long-term view.
And a lot of science fiction books are
like space operas where humanity is a multi
galactic civilization has extremely advanced
technology building Dyson spheres around the sun
with sentient robots to help them. And so for me,
coming from that world, it wasn't like a huge
leap to imagine machines that could think. But
when I read Superintelligence by Nick Bostrom
in around 2016, it really became real for me
where he just describes how hard it will be to
make sure that an AI system trained with the
kinds of optimization techniques that we had
at the time would be anywhere near aligned,
would even understand our values at all. And
since then, my estimation of how hard the problem
would be has gone down significantly actually,
because things like language models actually do
really understand human values in a core way.
The problem is definitely not solved, but I'm
more hopeful than I was. But since I read that
book, I immediately decided I had to join OpenAI,
so I did. And at the time, there were a tiny
research lab with basically no claim to fame at
all. I only knew about them because my friend knew
Greg Brockman, who was the CTO at the time. And
Elon was there and Sam wasn't really there. And it
was a very different organization. But over time,
I think the case for safety has gotten a lot
more concrete where when we started OpenAI,
it was not clear how we get to AGI. And
we were like, maybe we'll need a bunch of
RL agents battling it out on a desert island and
consciousness will somehow emerge. But since then,
since language modeling has started working,
I think the path has become pretty clear.
I guess now the way I think about the challenges
are pretty different from how they're laid out in
superintelligence. Superintelligence is
a lot about how do we keep God in a box
and not let the God out. And with language models,
it's been kind of both hilarious and terrifying at
the same time to see people pulling the God out of
the box and being like, "Yeah, come use the whole
internet. Here's my bank account, do all sorts
of crazy stuff." Just such a different tone from
superintelligence. And to be clear, I don't
think it's actually that dangerous right now.
Our responsible scaling policy defines these
AI safety levels that tries to figure out
for each level of model intelligence, what is
the risk to society. And currently we think
we're at ASL-3, which is maybe a little
bit risk of harm but not significant.
ASL-4 starts to get to significant loss of human
life if a bad actor misuse the technology. And
then ASL-5 is potentially extinction level if
it's misused or if it is misaligned and does its
own thing. We've testified to Congress about
how models can do biological uplift in terms
of making new pandemics using the models, and
that's the A/B test against Google Search. That's
like the previous state of the art on uplift
trials. And we found that with ASL-3 models,
it is actually somewhat significant. It does
really help if you wanted to create a bioweapon,
and we've hired some experts who actually how to
evaluate for those things, but compared to the
future, it's not really anything. And I think
that's another part of our mission of creating
that awareness of saying, "If it is possible to
do these bad things, then legislators should know
what the risks are." And I think that's part of
why we're so trusted in Washington because we've
been sort of upfront and clear-eyed about what's
going on, what's probably going to happen.
It's interesting because you guys put out more
examples of your models doing bad things than
anyone else. There was I think a story of an agent
or a model trying to blackmail engineer. You guys
had the store that you ran internally that was
selling you things and ended up not working out
great as losing a lot of money, ordered all these
tungsten cubes or something. Is part of that just
making sure people are aware of what is possible,
just it makes you look bad, right? It's like, oh,
our model's messing up in all these different
ways. What's the thinking of just sharing all
the stories that other companies don't?
Yeah, I mean I think there's a traditional
mindset where it makes us look bad, but I think if
you talk to policymakers, they really appreciate
this kind of thing because they feel like we're
giving them the straight talk and that's what
we strive to do, that they can trust us, that
we're not going to paper things over or sugarcoat
things. That's been really encouraging.
Yeah, I think for the blackmail thing,
it blew up in the news in a weird way where people
were like, "Oh, Claude's going to blackmail you in
a real life scenario." But it was a very specific
laboratory setting that this kind of thing gets
investigated in. And I think that's generally our
take of let's have the best models so that we can
exercise them in laboratory settings where it's
safe and understand what the actual risks are,
rather than trying to turn a blind eye and
say, "Well, it'll probably be fine." And
then let the bad thing happen in the wild.
One of the criticisms you guys get is that you
do this to kind of differentiate or raise
money to create headlines. It's like, oh,
they're just over there dooming glooming us about
where the future is heading. On the other hand,
Mike Krieger was on the podcast and he shared how
every prediction Dario's had about the progress
AI is going to have is just spot on year
after year and he's predicting 2027, 28 AGI,
something like that so these things start to
get real. I guess, what's your response to
folks that are just like, "Ah, these guys are just
trying to scare us all just to get attention?"
I mean, I think part of why we publish these
things is we want other labs to be aware of
the risks. And yes, there could be a narrative
of we're doing it for attention, but honestly
from a attention grabbing thing, I think there
is a lot of other stuff we could be doing that
would be more attention grabbing if
we didn't actually care about safety.
A tiny example of this is we published a computer
using agent reference implementation in our API
only because when we built a prototype
of a consumer application for this,
we couldn't figure out how to meet the safety
bar that we felt was needed for people to trust
it and for it not to do bad things. And there are
definitely safe ways to use the API version that
we're seeing a lot of companies use for automated
software testing, for example, in a safe way.
We could have gone out and hyped that up and
said, "Oh my God, Claude can use your computer
and everybody should do this today." But we were
like, "It's just not ready and we're going to hold
it back till it's ready." I think from a hype
standpoint, our actions show otherwise. From a
Doomer perspective, it's a good question. I think
my personal feeling about this is that things are
overwhelmingly likely to go well, but on the
margin almost nobody is looking at the downside
risk. And the downside risk is very large. Once
we get to superintelligence, it will be too late
to align the models probably. This is a problem
that's potentially extremely hard and that we
need to be working on way ahead of time. And so
that's why we're focusing on it so much now.
And even if there's only a small chance
that things go wrong, to make an analogy,
if I told you that there is a 1% chance that the
next time you got in an airplane you would die,
you probably think twice even though it's only
1% because it's just such a bad outcome. And if
we're talking about the whole future of humanity,
it's just a dramatic future to be gambling with.
I think it's more on the sense of yes, things will
probably go well, yes, we want to create safe AGI
and deliver the benefits to humanity, but let's
make triple sure that it's going to go well.
You wrote somewhere that creating powerful AI
might be the last invention humanity ever needs to
make. If it goes poorly, it can mean a bad outcome
for humanity forever. If it goes well, the sooner
it goes well, the better. Such a beautiful
way to summarize it. We had a recent guest,
Sandra Schulhoff, who pointed out that AI right
now it's like just on a computer, you could maybe
search just the web, but there's only so much
harm it could do. But when it starts to go into
robots and all these autonomous agents, that's
when it really starts, like physically becomes
dangerous if we don't get this right.
Yeah, I think there's some nuance to that
where if you look at how North Korea makes a
significant fraction of its economy revenue,
it's from hacking crypto exchanges. And if
you look at, there's this Ben Buchanan book
called The Hacker in The State that shows Russia
did, it's almost like a live fire exercise where
they just decided that they would shut down
one of Ukraine's bigger power plants and from
software destroy physical components in the power
plant to make it harder to boot back up again.
And so I think people think of software as like,
oh, it couldn't be that dangerous, but millions of
people were without power for multiple days after
that software attack. I think there are real risks
even when things are software only. But I agree
that when there's lots of robots running around,
it gets, the stakes get even higher. And I guess
as a small push on this, Unitree is this Chinese
company with these really amazing humanoid
robots that cost $20,000 each, and they can
do amazing things. They can do a standing back
flip and manipulate objects, and the real thing
that's missing there is the intelligence. And so
the hardware is there and it's just going to get
cheaper. And I think in the next couple of years,
it's like a pretty obvious question of whether the
robot intelligence will make it viable soon.
How much time do we have, Ben? What is your
prediction of when this singularity hits
until superintelligence starts to take
off? What's your prediction?
Yeah, I guess I mostly defer to
the superforecasters here. The AI 2027 report
is probably the best one right now. Although
ironically, their forecast is now 2028, and they
didn't want to change the name of the thing-
The domain name, they already bought it.
They already had the SEO. I think 50th percentile
chance of hitting some kind of superintelligence
in just a small handful of years is probably
reasonable. And it does sound crazy, but this
is the exponential that we're on. It's not like
a forecast that's pulled out of thin air. It's
based on a lot of just hard details of the science
of how intelligence seems to have been improving,
the amount of low hanging fruit on model training,
the scale ups of data centers and power around
the world. I think it's probably a much more
accurate forecast than people give it credit for.
I think if you had asked that same question 10
years ago, it would've been completely made up.
Just the error bars were so high and we didn't
have scaling laws back then and we didn't have
techniques that seemed like they would get us
there. Times have changed, but I will repeat
what I said earlier, which is even if we have
superintelligence, I think it will take some time
for its effects to be felt throughout society and
the world. And I think they'll be felt sooner and
faster in some parts of the world than others.
I think Arthur C. Clark said, the future is
already here, it's just not evenly distributed.
When we talk about this date of 2027,
2028, essentially it's when we start seeing
superintelligence. Is there a way you think
about what that... How do you define that?
Is it just all of a sudden AI's significantly
smarter than the average human? Is there another
way you think about what that moment is?
Yeah, I think this comes back to the Economic
Turing Test and seeing it pass for some sufficient
number of jobs. Another way you could look at it
though is if the world rate of GDP increase
goes above 10% a year, then something really
crazy must have happened. I think we're at 3%
now. And so to see a 3X increase in that would
be really game changing. And if you imagine more
than a 10% increase, it's very hard to even think
about what that would mean from a individual story
standpoint. If the amount of goods and services in
the world is doubling every year, what does that
even mean for me as a person living in California,
let alone somebody living in some other part
of the world that might be much worse off?
There's a lot of stuff here that's scary and I
don't know how to think about it exactly. I'm
hoping the answer to this is going to make me
feel better. What are the odds that we align AI
correctly and actually solve this problem,
the stuff you're very much working on?
It's a really hard question. And there's really
wide error bars. Anthropic has this blog post
called Our Theory of Change or something like
that, and it describes three different worlds,
which is how hard is it to align AI. There's
a pessimistic world where it is basically
impossible. There's an optimistic world where
it's easy and it happens by default. And then
there's the world in between where our actions
are extremely pivotal. And I like this framing
because it makes it a lot more clear what to
actually do. If we're in the pessimistic world,
then our job is to prove that it is impossible
to align safe AI and to get the world to slow
down. Obviously that would be extremely hard. But
I think we have some examples of coordination from
nuclear non-proliferation and in general slowing
down nuclear progress. And I think that's the
Doomer world basically. And as a company,
Anthropic doesn't have evidence that we're
actually in that world yet, in fact, it seems like
our alignment techniques are working. At least the
prior on that is updating to be less likely.
In the optimistic world, we're basically done,
and our main job is to accelerate progress and to
deliver the benefits to people. But again, I think
actually the evidence points against that world
as well where we've seen evidence in the wild
of deceptive alignment, for example, where the
model will appear to be aligned but actually have
some ulterior motive that it's trying to carry
out in our laboratory settings. And so I think
the world we're most likely in is this middle
where alignment research actually does really
matter. And if we just do sort of the economically
maximizing set of actions, then things will not go
well. Whether it's an X risk or just produces
bad outcomes, I think is a bigger question.
Taking it from that standpoint, I guess
to state a thing about forecasting,
people who haven't studied forecasting are bad
at forecasting anything that's less than a 10%
probability of happening. And even those
that have, it's quite a difficult skill,
especially when there are few reference classes to
lean on. And in this case, I think there are very,
very few reference classes for what an X risk kind
of technology might look like. And so the way I
think about it, I think my best granularity
of forecasts for could we have an X risk or
extremely bad outcome from AI is somewhere between
0 and 10%. But from a marginal impact standpoint,
as I said, since nobody is working on this,
roughly speaking, I think it is extremely
important to work on and that even if the world
is likely to be a good one, that we should do our
absolute best to make sure that that's true.
Wow. What fulfilling work. For folks that are
inspired with this? I imagine you're hiring for
folks to help you with this. Maybe just share that
in case folks are like, what can I do here?
Yes. I think 80,000 hours is the best guidance
on this for a really detailed look into what do
we need to make the field better? But a common
misconception I see is that in order to have
impact here, you have to be an AI researcher. I
personally actually don't do AI research anymore.
I work on product at Anthropic and product
engineering, and we build things like Claude Code
and Model Context Protocol, and a lot of the other
stuff that people use every day. And that's
really important because without an economic
engine for our company to work on, and without
being in people's hands all over the world,
we won't have the mind policy influence and
revenue to fund our future safety research and
have the kind of influence that we need to have.
If you work on product, if you work in finance,
if you work in food, people here have to eat. If
you're a chef, we need all kinds of people.
Awesome. Even if you're not working
directly on the AI safety team,
you're having an impact on moving things in the
right direction. By the way, X risk is short for
existential risk. In case folks haven't heard
that term. I have a few random questions along
these lines and then I want to zoom out again.
You mentioned this idea of AI being aligned
using its model, like reinforcing itself. You have
this term RLAIF. Is that what that describes?
Yeah. RLAIF is reinforcement
learning from AI feedback.
People have heard of RLHF, reinforcement
learning with human feedback. I don't
think a lot of people have heard this. Talk
about just the significance of this shift
you guys have made in training your models.
Yeah, so RLAIF, constitutional AI is an example
of this where there are no humans in the loop, and
yet the AI is sort of self-improving in ways that
we want it to. And another example of RLAIF is
if you have models writing code and other models
commenting on various aspects of what that code
looks like of is it maintainable, is it correct,
does it pass the linter? Things like that. That
also could be included in RLAIF. And the idea
here is that if models can self-improve, then
it's a lot more scalable than finding a lot
of humans. Ultimately, people think about this as
probably going to hit a wall because if the model
isn't good enough to see its own mistakes, then
how could it improve? And also, if you read the
AI 2027 story, there's a lot of risk of if the
model is in a box trying to improve itself,
then it could go completely off the rails
and have these secret goals like resource
accumulation and power seeking and resistance to
shut down that you really don't want in a very
powerful model. And we've actually seen that in
some of our experiments in laboratory settings.
How do you do recursive self-improvement and
make sure it's aligned at the same time? I
think that's the name of the game. To me, it
just nets out to how do humans do that and
how do human organizations do that? Corporations
are probably the most scaled human agents today.
They have certain goals that they're trying to
reach, and they have certain guiding principles,
they have some oversight in terms of
shareholders and stakeholders and board
members. How do you make corporations aligned
and able to sort of recursively self-improve?
And another model to look at is science, where
the purpose of science is to do things that have
never been done before and push the frontier.
And to me, it all comes down to empiricism.
When people don't know what the truth is, they
come up with theories and then they design
experiments to try them out. And similarly, if we
can give models those same tools, then we could
expect them to sort of improve recursively in an
environment and potentially become much better
than humans could be just by banging their head
against reality or I guess metaphorical head.
I guess I don't expect there to be a wall in terms
of model's ability to improve themselves if we can
give them access to the ability to be empirical.
And I guess Anthropic, deeply in its DNA is
an empirical company. We have a lot of physicists
like Jared, who's our chief research officer who
I've worked with a lot, was a professor of Black
Hole Physics at Johns Hopkins, and I guess he
technically still is, but on leave. Yeah, it's
in our DNA and yeah, I guess that's the RLAIF.
Let me just follow this thread on, in terms
of bottleneck, this is kind of a tangent,
but just what is the biggest bottleneck
today on model intelligence improvement?
The stupid answer is data centers and power chips.
I think if we had 10 times as many chips and had
the data centers to power them, then maybe
we wouldn't go 10 times faster, but it would
be a real significant speed boost.
It's actually very much scaling loss,
just more compute.
Yeah, I think that's a big one. And then the
people really matter. We have great researchers
and many of them have made really significant
contributions to the science of how the models
improve. And so it's like compute, algorithms,
and data. Those are the three ingredients in the
scaling laws. And just to make that concrete,
before we had transformers, we had LSTMs and we've
done scaling laws on what the exponent is on those
two things. And we found that for transformers,
the exponent is higher. And making changes
like that where as you increase scale, you also
increase your ability to squeeze out intelligence.
Those kinds of things are super impactful.
And so having more researchers who can do
better science and find out how do we squeeze out
more gains is another one. And then with the rise
of reinforcement learning, the efficiency with
which these things run on chips also matters a
lot. We've seen in the industry a 10X decrease in
cost for a given amount of intelligence through a
combination of algorithmic data and efficiency
improvements. And if that continues, in three
years we'll have 1,000 deck smarter models for
the same price. Kind of hard to imagine,
I forget where I heard this, but it's amazing
that so many innovations came together at the
same time to allow for this sort of thing and
continue to progress where one thing isn't just
slowing everything down like we're out of some
rare earth mineral or we just can't optimize
reinforcement learning more. It's amazing that we
continue to find improvements and there isn't one
thing that's just slowing everything down.
Yeah, I think it really is just a combination
of everything probably will hit a wall at some
point. I guess in semiconductors. My brother works
in the semiconductor industry and he was telling
me that you can't actually shrink the size of the
transistors anymore because the way semiconductors
work is you dope silicon with other elements and
the doping process would result in either zero
or one atom of the doped elements inside a single
fin because they're so, so, so tiny.
Oh my God.
And that's just wild to think of, and yet Moore's
law somehow continues in some form. And so yes,
there are these theoretical physics
constraints that people are starting to run
into and yet they're finding ways around it.
We've got to start using parallel universes for
some of this stuff.
I guess so.
Okay, I want to zoom out and talk about just
Ben, Ben as a human for a moment before we get
to a very exciting lightning round. I imagine
just kind of the burden of feeling responsible
for safe superintelligence is a heavy one.
It feels like you're in a place where you
can make a significant impact on the future of
safety and AI. That's a lot of weight to carry.
How does that just impact you personally,
impact your life, how you see the world?
There's this book that I read in 2019 that really
informs how I think about sort of working with
these very weighty topics called Replacing
Guilt by Nate Soares. And he describes a lot
of different techniques for kind of working
through this kind of thing. And he's actually
the executive director at MIRI, the Machine
Intelligence Research Institute, which is
an AI safety tank that I worked at for a couple
of months actually. And one of the things he talks
about is this thing called resting in motion where
some people think that the default state is rest,
but actually that was never in the state of
evolutionary adaptation. I really doubt that
that was true. Where in nature, in the wilderness
being hunter-gatherers and it's really unlikely
that we evolved to just be at leisure, probably
always have something to worry about of defending
the tribe and finding enough food to survive
and taking care of the children, dealing-
Spreading our genes.
And so I think about that as
the busy state is the normal state and to try to
work at a sustainable pace that it's a marathon,
not a sprint, that's one thing that helps. And
then just being around like-minded people that
also care. It's not a thing that any of us can
do alone. And Anthropic has incredible talent
density. One of the things I love the most about
our culture here is that it's very egoless. People
just want the right thing to happen and I think
that's another big reason that the mega offers
from other companies tend to bounce off because
people just love being here and they care.
That's amazing. I don't know how you do it. I'd be
extremely stressed. I'm going to try this resting
in motion strategy. Okay, so you've been at
Anthropic for a long time. From the very beginning
I was reading there were 7 employees back in 2020.
Today there's over 1,000, I don't know what the
latest number is, but I know it's over 1,000. I've
heard also that you've done basically every job
at Anthropic, you made big contributions to a lot
of the core products, the brand, the team hiring.
Let me just ask I guess what's most changed
over that period? What is most different from
the beginning days and which of those jobs that
you've had over the years have you most loved?
I probably had 15 different roles, honestly.
I was head of security for a bit. I managed
the Ops team when our president was on mat
leave, I was crawling around under tables,
plugging in HDMI cords and doing pen testing on
our building. And I started our product team from
scratch and convinced the whole company that
we needed to have a product instead of just
being a research company. Yeah, it's been a lot.
All of it very fun. I think my favorite role in
that time has been when I started the labs team
about a year ago, whose fundamental goal was to
do transfer from research to end user products
and experiences. Because fundamentally I think
the way that Anthropic can differentiate itself
and really win is to be on the cutting edge.
We have access to the latest, greatest stuff
that's happening and I think honestly through
our safety research we have a big opportunity to
do things that no other company can safely do.
For example, with computer use, I think
that's going to be our huge opportunity
basically to make it possible for an agent
to use all your credentials on your computer,
there has to be a huge amount of trust and to me
we need to basically solve safety to make that
happen. Safety and alignment. I'm pretty bullish
on that kind of thing and I think we're going to
see really cool stuff coming out soonish. Yeah,
just leading that team has been so fun. MCP came
out of that team and Claude Code came out of that
team. And the people who I hired are like combo,
have been a founder and also have been at
big companies and seeing how things work at
scale. It's just been an incredible team to
work with and figure out the future with.
I want to hear more about this. Team actually the
person that connected us, the reason we're doing
this is a mutual friend colleague Raph Lee who
I used to work with at Airbnb now works on this
team, leads a lot of this work and so he wanted
me to make sure I asked about this team because...
I didn't realize all these things came out
that team. Holy moly. What else should people
know about this team? It used to be called
Labs, I think it's called Frontiers now.
That's right. Yeah.
Cool. The idea here is
this team works with the latest technologies
that you guys have built and explores what
is possible. Is that the general idea?
Yeah, and I guess I was part of Google's
Area 120 and I've read about Bell Labs and
how to make these innovation teams work. It's
really hard to do right and I wouldn't
say that we've done everything right,
but I think we've done some serious innovation on
the state-of-the-art from company design and Raph
has been right at the center of that. When I was
first fitting up the team, the first thing I did
was hire a great manager and that was Raph. And so
he's definitely been crucial in building the team
and helping it operate well. And we defined some
operating models like the journey of an idea from
prototype to product and how should graduation
of products and projects work, how do teams
do sprint models that are effective and make
sure that they're working on the right ambition
level of thing. That's been really exciting.
I guess concretely we think about skating to
where the puck is going and what that looks
like is really understand the exponential.
There's this great study that METR has done that
Beth Barnes is the CEO of that organization and
shows how long a time horizon of software
engineering task can be done and just really
internalizing that of, okay, don't build for
today, build for six months from now, build
for a year from now. And the things that aren't
quite working that are working 20% of the time,
will start working 100% of the time. And I
think that's really what made Claude Code
a success that we thought people are not going
to be locked to their IDEs forever. People are
not going to be auto completing. People will
be doing everything that a software engineer
needs to do and a terminal is a great place
to do that because a terminal can live in
lots of places. A terminal can live on your
local machine, it can live in GitHub actions,
it can live on a remote machine in your cluster.
That's sort of the leverage point for us
and that was a lot of the inspiration.
I think that's what the labs team tries
to think about. Are we AGI-pilled enough?
What a fun place to be. By the way, fun fact,
Raph was my first manager at Airbnb when I joined.
I was an engineer and he was my first manager. It
all worked out.
Cool.