I want to start with talking about your pod model,
which is a really unique way of building
and organizing your product teams.
That was probably 2016, we're trying to figure
out how does the operating model look like for
product and engineering. The first bunch
of people we had was essentially a pod,
it was one product manager, a user experience
designer, backend engineers, a couple of
front-end engineers, but at some stage
we're starting to scale, we are kind of
contemplating do we go the traditional,
the old school of front-end engineers,
backend engineers, and then we said
let's try to replicate what we have.
Let's talk about how these pods work with
design partners, from what I've heard,
it's very unlike how any other company works.
We just took the pod concept to an
extreme, where every pod is working
with sometimes a dozen design partners,
sometimes two dozen design partners.
And this feels like a cheap code of
how to build new product lines. What
are the percentage of success
rate you have with new product?
I would say very close to 100% of the features we
build end up being used by a
significant number of people.
Does it feel crazy for companies
not to operate this way?
I wouldn't go back. I hate terms such as
risks because that's a very ambiguous term,
but just the risk of building something you're
not going to know if it's going to get used.
So, when I ask people at Gong what to ask you,
the most often term that came
up is autonomy and trust.
It's a very selfish thing, it's a
very personal thing, I just think...
Today my guest is Eilon Reshef. Eilon is
co-founder and chief product officer at Gong, he
was also a long-time chief technology officer at
Gong. As I share at the top of our conversation,
it feels like basically every company that has
a sales team uses Gong, and it's really rare to
build a product that is so ubiquitous and so loved
across the tech ecosystem. In our conversation,
Eilon shares some of the secrets of what
makes Gong so consistently successful,
including how their product teams work with
six to 12 design partners on every new product
and feature that they invest in, how he
creates a culture of autonomy and trust,
why and also how he optimizes for making decisions
quickly, even large one-way door decisions,
what he and his team have learned about
building AI-based products, since they've
been building AI-based products longer than
most other companies, and so much more. If
you're building a B2B SaaS company or product,
you will learn a lot from this conversation.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube, it's the best way
to avoid missing feature episodes and it helps
the podcast tremendously. With that, I bring
you Eilon Reshef. This episode is brought to
you by WorkOS. If you're building a SaaS app, at
some point your customers will start asking for
enterprise features like SAML authentication and
SCIM provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in,
making it fast and painless to add enterprise
features to your app. Their APIs are easy to
understand so that you can ship quickly and get
back to building other features. Today, hundreds
of companies are already powered by WorkOS,
including ones you probably know, like Vercel,
Webflow and Loom. WorkOS also recently acquired
Warrant, the fine-grained authorization service.
Warrant's product is based on a groundbreaking
authorization system called Zanzibar,
which was originally designed for Google, to
power Google Docs and YouTube. This enables
fast authorization checks at enormous scale
while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases.
If you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features,
like single sign-on, SCIM, or user management,
you should consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in
replacement for Auth0, and supports up to
1 million monthly active users for free. Check it
out at workos.com to learn more. That's workos.com
Hey, it's Lenny, if you want to boost your
clarity and confidence, I want to recommend a
podcast called Think Fast, Talk Smart. One of the
most essential ingredients to success in business
and in life is effective communication. Every
Tuesday, host and Stanford graduate school of
business lecturer, Matt Abrahams sits down with
experts to discuss the best tips and techniques
that enhance your professional development. Hone
your small talk, influence, presentation skills,
and so much more on Think Fast, Talk Smart. So,
what are you waiting for? listen every Tuesday,
wherever you get your podcast and find additional
content to level up your communication at
fastersmarter.io. Eilon, thank you so much
for being here, welcome to the podcast.
Thank you for having me.
So, it feels like on this podcast every guest
that I've had mentions Gong as a product they use,
it feels like it's just like in the ether of
tech companies these days. Also, I've heard so
many times how unique it is that you all operate,
how you all build your product teams and operate,
which is, I especially love hearing on this
podcast just different ways of operating,
so I'm really excited to dig into this, to hear
about the journey and things you've learned along
the way of building Gong, and essentially building
something that is so ubiquitous and so loved,
which is very rare. I want to start
with talking about your pod model,
which is a really unique way of building
and organizing your product teams,
and in particular how you work with design
partners. But let's start with the pod model,
can you just talk about what this pod model
is and how you organize your product teams?
Sure. And when we started the pod model, that
was probably 2016 before it became more popular,
I think that might've been even before the
Marty Cagan set of books, I don't remember
exactly. But at some stage we're starting to
scale, scaling is maybe from 50 people to 60
people, in the whole company or whatever,
and we're trying to figure out how does the
operating model look like for a product and
engineering. And the first bunch of people
we had was essentially a pod, it was one product
manager, yours truly, a user experience designer,
a couple of maybe backend engineers, a couple of
front-end engineers and whatnot. And we were kind
of contemplating do we go the traditional,
the old school of front-end engineers,
backend engineers or however it is? And then
we said let's try to replicate what we have.
So, what we essentially did is really replicated
that. So, up until now we have this pod structure,
product manager UX, fractional
writing, fractional analyst,
and then a team leader from an engineering
standpoint, five to I'd say seven engineers,
they get an agenda, think like we launched a
forecast product, that was a pod working on that,
and then they get to be pretty autonomous in
identifying how to solve the problems, and also
working with enough customers so I can go to sleep
knowing that they're not hallucinating is the term
that everybody uses now in different contexts,
but going in a very reasonable direction.
So, I want to talk about the autonomy piece,
so that's a really important point, but before
we get there, let's talk about how these pods
work with design partners. From what I've heard,
it's very unlike how any other company works,
and I think it's something a lot of people can
learn from. So, talk about the scale of
how these pods work with design partners.
So, I think we just took the pod concept
to an extreme, where every pod is working
with sometimes a dozen design partners, sometimes
two dozen design partners, maybe sometimes five,
if it's a very niche or fringe capability,
and they work with them hand in hand. So,
an interesting story, the same forecast product
I just mentioned, the product manager comes to
me one day and he's like, hey, I just going to
play with a design partner on the product. And
I kind of know what's going on and I know it's
not built yet, so I asked the product manager,
but we don't have that working. So, he said,
no, no we don't, but I showed him the half
built stuff, I asked him to hit save,
he hit save, and got an error message.
And I told him, let's meet again in a week,
and that save button was going to work. So,
it's very extreme in terms of working hand in
hand with the customer. Customers appreciate it,
I later got feedback that they appreciate
how the thing was making progress according
to their feedback, not what they said, but
interpreting what they said, digesting it,
and building something that makes sense. So,
every pod has this set of design partners.
So, these pods essentially
cross-functional product teams,
each one has... Do you organize it around an
outcome? How do you describe what each pod is
responsible for? Is it like move this metric,
or build this product, or something else?
We tend to be less metric-driven maybe
than your average, especially B2C,
but even other maybe B2B companies. Usually
it's more around some sort of a job to be done,
in our case it could be sales engagement, how
do you prospect? Or conversation intelligence,
how do you create a summary? How do you make it
easier for people to remove drudgery and consume
information fast? Once you get this agenda, you
pretty much have a lot of, you mentioned autonomy,
a lot of control over how you progress.
Ideally design partners guide you, not me.
Awesome. Okay. So, it's like, here's
the outcome we want this pod to achieve,
they have autonomy to work with design
partners to design this new product. So,
maybe let's stay on this example
of this forecasting tool,
can you just briefly describe what this
tool, what it gives you, what it does?
Yeah, it's a product we launched a couple of
years ago and it helps organization forecast where
they land in terms of the sales organization. So,
every sales organization, B2B sales organization,
has a bottoms up forecast process. People
submit numbers, people override that,
AI helps you, in our case, AI helps you predict
the right number, usually there's an analytics
component on top of it, it helps you assess
it at scale. So, that's the product itself.
Awesome. So, you created this pod,
here, build this forecast product,
make it successful, how do they find
these design partners? Is it reach into
existing customer base and figure out
who would be most interested in this?
Usually it's existing customers, very, very
rarely it would be a non-existing customers,
but customers with some stage expressed
interest in this capability. Not to over
give a plug to Gong, but of course we can
listen, all of our conversations are recorded,
so I can always look up our conversation database
and which customers express a need for X,
Y and Z, you can very easily reach out to them.
One of the maybe unique things we've done,
at some stage it just became, I think we got like
25 pods right now, maybe 30, it depends what you
call a pod. But it's a lot of effort, like this
whole management, at some stage I borrowed an
idea that comes from talent acquisition, and
in talent acquisition recruiting there is a
person called recruiting coordinator... If you
do that scale, which we had done over the years.
And that person, all they do is just set up
the meetings for the recruiter, who then sets
up the meeting for the hiring manager. So, in our
product team, there's one person who's basically
a research coordinator, and she's responsible for
reaching out and she basically talks with the PMs,
like what's your target market, ICP,
whatever you want to call that, give
me some... What do you want to learn from them?
She reaches us, we have a micro CRM for that,
and then sets up the meeting, and the PM comes
in, they have already a meeting in their calendar.
And these are the people at these companies
that are going to be their design partners?
Exactly. So, I might say, hey, what I want
to speak is with head of rev ops at midsize
companies, or IC seller at an enterprise
company, and then she can, of course, sift
through our customer base, slice and dice it, run
a micro email campaign, and get those to come in.
I love that detail, because as you said,
coordinating 12 companies and people at
these companies and timing is really stressful and
complicated and could suck the PMs life up. So,
that's really helpful. It's interesting, there
are some companies where product teams aren't
even allowed to talk to customers, salespeople
are like, no, don't mess with these people,
customer success is like no, we got this.
You were like the complete opposite,
each pod is working directly with, say, a dozen
customers helping build a new product for them.
Exactly. And in the early days we
didn't even tightly coordinate with
customer success. Nowadays, we do it much
better because there's always going to be,
this customers frustrated about something, or in
a negotiation about something, that's probably not
the right time to ask them about to be a design
partner. So, we double check, but it's not like
a process where we have to get signed off by three
customer success managers to talk with a customer.
That makes sense. Yeah, you don't want to
surprise people and mess up relationships. So,
is there any structure to the design
partner process or is it just teams
have these people available and they
talk with them when they want? Or is
there more structure to how to effectively
build the product with design partners?
It depends on the context. So, when you build
a new product, it's a more linear path. Ideally
you want it to be launched sometime. Ideally you
want to measure some progress, so usually what
we've done in this case is some sort of a weekly
meeting where we show them progress, and sometimes
bi-weekly depending on our own cadence. And some
other capabilities that we build might be more, I
want to say free form, maybe it's an enhancement,
maybe it's tweaked, maybe it's an extension of
the... I'll give an example, one of the things we
do right now is we let customers ask a question
about an account. So, coming to Gong, like
what's new with Cisco? If Cisco is a customer.
And at some stage you do it, we're doing it in all
languages. So, you want to recruit a specific set
of design partners who are non-English speakers.
So, that doesn't have a strict timeline, you want
to get enough of them so you see the thing works,
gets your reasonable quality results. You're not
going to get to all languages on the one hand, but
at the same time you don't have just Spanish. So,
that might be less structures, maybe it's a couple
of minutes with each one and then we move on,
you launch the feature, and you move
to the next "project or feature."
So, one thing that people might
be thinking as they hear this is,
all these customers are telling you, here's
what I need to be to use this forecasting tool,
for example, and as a PM it's always
this balance of doing what customers
ask you to do versus, oh, we have this
vision and here's how we keep it simple.
What guidance do you give your teams for
what to do with this feedback, essentially?
Yeah, I think this is core skill that I expect PMs
to have around this, this is exactly your job, try
to figure out what request is must-have versus not
must-have. We typically, they ask the customer,
what do you have right now? How happy are
you between zero and 10? Or whatever. So,
if you're at the six, we want to get you to an
eight or a nine, so that's maybe a high level
principle, but at the same time I expect them to
say, hey, this is a unique... I didn't hear it
from anybody else, maybe I'm going to practically
reach out to more customers, but that might be a
one customer thing. And we still do one customer
things in different context. So, if we have a,
I don't know, seven or eight figure deal, that
they have one customization that they really,
really need, and we know that they can't work
without it, every enterprise facing company
we're going to do that. But from a design partner
perspective, it's the opposite, it's more like
let's try to build something that works across
our customer base versus for a specific customer.
Which is why a dozen is probably
smarter than one or two or three.
Yeah, I think at some stage I guess you
get seven or eight or nine at some stage,
based on my experience, the request starts
to converge. There might be one outlier,
but generally you're going
to hear the same things.
I imagine this approach is rooted in how you
all started. We worked on a post back in the
day on how you all got your first 10 customers,
and I remember the story was you got, I think,
12 design partners when you first designed Gong,
and then you told them, okay, we're going to start
charging now, and 11 out of 12 are like, we will
buy this now, please charge us, and we love it.
Exactly, exactly. So, in a
way it's replicating this,
but it was successful at the time, it was
maybe 80% intention at a time and at some
point you take the stuff that works
and you make it 100% the attention.
What are the percentage of success rate
you have with new products because you
would think this approach is the best way
to consistently build products people will
end up buying and using. Is it like
100% of the time you end up building
things that people will buy and use, is
it something below that? What do you find?
I think it does increase significantly the
utility of the products, I would say very
close to 100% of the features we build end up
being used by a significant number of people.
We don't charge for all of them, for most of
them we don't charge, which doesn't mean other
things couldn't happen, maybe people use it,
but the value is not huge. So, it's like yeah,
design partner like it, but it ends up being
applicable to a smaller fragment or segment
of our customer base than what we had hoped.
It may be they're not as willing to pay for
it, although that's a little bit of a different
process, like real product launch. It could
be the quality is not good enough because
we're focusing on, is it providing value,
is it understandable versus did you find a bug
when you used, I don't know, Safari, on this
kind of computer. Because we're not building
the design partner program to solve for this,
maybe we should, but we are not doing it right
now. But generally speaking, I would say better
than that, more than 95% of the capabilities we
build are being used in a very significant way.
Which I think is probably higher than most
companies. And this feels like a cheat code of
how to build new product lines, expand a product
expansion, TAM expansion, like ways to add new
ways to charge your existing customers, and it
feels like a cheat code basically, just tell
us what you need, we'll work with you and build
it and we'll sell it to you and it'll be great.
Yeah, respectfully, yours truly, I do believe
customers know much better than what they need,
and then myself or my colleagues in
the executive team, whoever else,
it's you talk to a customer and they
describe the pain. They might not know
how to build it or what's the right way to
implement it, but the pain should be there.
Coming back to something else you
mentioned, this word autonomy. So,
when I ask people a Gong what to ask you and what
stands out about you to them as a product leader,
the most often term that came up is autonomy
and trust. How much autonomy you give teams,
how much you trust teams to do the right
thing. Can you talk about that way of working,
where that came from, and why you
think that is the way to operate?
It's very selfish thing, it's a very personal
thing. So, I think even beyond trust, it's just,
for me, it's selfish. I'll tell you why, I just
think you get more from everybody if you let them
be themselves, and do things in the way that they
believe is the right way. Of course within limits,
right? They're not going to develop, I don't know
what it is, software in different business. But
the story I always like to tell is, when my son
was in primary school, which was a while back,
one of the parents told me... And we had this
picnic where all the parents and the kids were
going to meet. And usually there's a list of
ingredients that people need to bring in, to
bring on a bottle of water, whatever the thing is.
And what's usually happened, there's even people
are joking about it, is people run to the list,
because it's usually a physical list, and then...
Or [inaudible 00:18:16] probably now it's already
in Google sheets always. And people run to just
mark the item that is as easy to get as possible.
Like, a bottle of water, and then I'm done. And
then, you always get the lowest common denominator
because everybody brings the sort of, I don't
want to even say cheapest, the easiest thing that
you can bring to such a picnic, and this lady told
me, here's a different method, just tell everybody
bring your own thing. I'm like, are you crazy?
People are just going to not bring anything, or
whatever you want. Or people are going to bring
the same thing. Multiple people are going to,
I don't know, bake some pie, or do something.
And she's like, no, that's not going to happen.
So, I trusted her, that's maybe a trust word,
but we tried it out, and what happened was really
kind of fascinating. People were going out to the
specialty stores and bringing special cheese...
I'm based in Israel, so they were going to this
hummus place, which is an Israeli thing. And
just driving 30 miles to your favorite thing,
people were baking and making stuff. So, we
had literally a feast. And the funny thing,
two things happened. Everybody was much, much
happier, they were happier because of course
they got better food. And also, most people, just
their personality, they brought it to the tables,
like I really like hummus, I don't like
whatever the other thing I would have to
bring. And we did it every year afterwards
because we did this thing at least annually,
and it will work every single time.
So, if you take it to the software, you can't
tell everybody just develop your own thing, but
if you can guide them towards, hey, do the thing
that... Give him more autonomy, essentially,
bring yourself to the game, be yourself,
don't try to put yourself in a box, I truly
believe you're going to get much better results,
short, and even more importantly, long-term,
because it keeps people thinking, it keeps
them being motivated, and they're like, how do I
contribute in the way I think is the right way?
It reminds me, I'm looking for daycares
for our son, he's almost 17 months now,
and there's this Montessori approach to
teaching kids, and it's a very similar approach,
which is just let them... If they're ever busy
with anything, don't even make eye contact, don't
interrupt them, let them keep doing the thing,
and let them choose what they want to work on.
Yeah, there's many, many of these education
systems or principles that are along those
lines. The person who told me that, I don't assume
she's invented it, but we all err on the side of
wanting more control. But I do the same thing with
my kids. So I would never... I never installed
any piece of software on my kids' devices.
So, not firewall protection, I don't know,
antivirus, error tag, nothing, because I'm
like this is your problem, and if you want
to protect yourself, it's your responsibility.
So, this is autonomy. And there was one time
where I had negotiated with my daughter, she
was like, I told her I think you're using your
computer too much, and we negotiated. She said,
maybe an hour is enough, I told her maybe more.
I think we agreed on a two-hour thing, and
then she came to me three days in a row,
could you please install the software on
my machine so I can... Help me control my
limits. And I love it when it's the other
way around because now she's responsible,
I'm helping her versus the other way around. So,
absolutely, I take it in my personal life as well.
So, how does this look day-to-day
at Gong on the product team,
when someone hears, oh, you
give them a lot of autonomy,
what does that actually look like? Help
people understand what that actually means.
It means that if you're working with design
partners and you get an idea from the customer,
it's your responsibility to decide are you going
to do it? Are you going to talk to your manager,
or to me? Now, I have, of course, group managers,
but it's your responsibility. So, we're not going
to "punish you" if you decided that you kind
of took it an opinion from a customer and went
ahead and did it, it's your responsibility to
decide, do I know enough? Do I need more input?
How up do I go? And that requires them to
think, how confident am I in my decisions.
So, is the culture basically you give
them feedback and advice and the teams
can operate the way they want, they can
build the features they think are important,
work with design partners
that they think are important?
Yes, and of course you are expected to solicit
feedback. So, if you're going to build your own
thing for six months and it's going to be...
Well, we're going to review it along the way,
of course. But we expect you to initiate a
review. We have a weekly session where you
can bring up your reviews, but it's not us
forcing you to do it. You have to bring it,
you have to solicit and you
have to drive the process.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta. When
it comes to ensuring your company has top-notch
security practices, things get complicated fast.
Now, you can assess risk, secure the trust of
your customers, and automate compliance for SOC
2, ISO 20000-1, HIPAA, and more with a single
platform, Vanta. Vanta's market leading trust
management platform helps you continuously
monitor compliance alongside reporting and
tracking risks, plus you can save hours by
completing security questionnaires with Vanta
AI. Join thousands of global companies that use
Vanta to automate evidence collection, unify risk
management, and streamline security reviews. Get
$1,000 off Vanta when you go to vanta.com/Lenny.
That's V-A-N-T-A.com/Lenny. Is there an example of
a product or a really important feature that came
out of this way of working where a team just like,
hey, you don't think this is a good
idea, I'm just going to do it anyway?
I don't think it goes up to a whole product, it's
kind of very hard to... Because you have resources
to build a whole product. But I do think there
is substantial features that came out of it. Even
the AI fine-tuning example I gave you before,
it's like something came up in a hackathon, and
people were like, let's start to build it, let's
incubate it, and then they move forward. Of course
we had to give them resources at some stage,
but it wasn't like a top down, let's do this,
it was more like, hey, we're trying it out, hey,
we need a couple of more resources, we're trying
out more. And at some stage we realized it's super
important and then we "funded it" completely.
So, when people listen to this, some
product leaders might be thinking,
oh, I want to work this way, I want to
give my teams more freedom, more trust,
what needs to be true in your org for
this to work well, versus it become chaos?
Firstly, you as a leader need to sign up to
let go a little bit, not control everything,
willing to make some more mistakes than maybe
you'd make otherwise. So, that's the one thing.
I think the harder thing is, at least for me,
is you also have to get your peers on the same
boat. Because the head of sales is going to ask
you, hey, what's happening? How do I know what's
happening? If you don't have a control over every
feature. And the CFO is going to ask you, hey,
what's the, I don't know, the ROI of this, or
how do you justify those type of decisions? So,
there has to be some fundamental trust
within you and your team, you and your
colleagues, to at least experiment that way.
And of course if you do it on an ongoing basis,
you lose some visibility, and I think that's maybe
one thing you got to acknowledge, right? If you
give people more control, by definition you're
going to have less visibility in what you're
doing. So, give up a little bit of visibility,
hopefully get the benefit of higher velocity,
and higher "morale" or engagement from people,
and that should result in better products as well.
I love that, that's a really good
example. With the sales example,
which is great, do you encourage the sales
folks to talk directly to the pod to ask
about these sorts of things, or do you
discourage that sort of communication?
Oh yeah. I think sales from my perspective
are part of the virtual pod. So,
the core pod is as I mentioned,
product engineering, but part of the
virtual pod is there's product marketing,
customer success, sales, in all fairness,
salespeople are usually busy doing their work
versus actually sitting with us and helping us,
is this going to sell? Did you hear it from
customers? The type of questions that product
managers usually want to get, but if they're
happy to spend time, they'll be very involved.
Coming back to the design partner way of working,
does it feel crazy for companies
not to operate this way, to not
work this closely with design partners on
new products and features they're building?
I wouldn't go back. So, I think it's just like,
even I hate terms such as risks because that's a
very, I don't know, ambiguous term, but just the
risk of building something you're not going to
know if it's going to get used. And I was asked by
a very senior product manager of a very successful
big SaaS companies, why do we even do this?
I'm like, what do you mean? It's like, hey,
we launch products and then we see if people like
them. It's like I don't think that's a great idea
because that company's successful, bigger than
Gong, but at the same time I just think it's
leaving too much in the hands of, I would even
call it luck, right? Because how do you know?
Yeah. I was thinking it just feels like a
cheat code and just feels like something a
lot of companies can learn from how you all
operate there. Something that has come up a
bunch so far in our conversation is your focus on
speed and optimizing for velocity. Something that
I've heard about you is that you're really
big on just making really quick decisions,
even one-way door decisions that are really
big, your philosophy is just make it quickly
before you have all the information
necessarily, talk about that approach.
That's maybe a little bit of a personal thing, but
I would encourage people to look up, in Google,
there's... Maybe I'll do a spoiler for Isaac
Asimov, he's a science fiction writer I think
beginning of last century, and he has this short
story, The Machine That Won the War, so you can
look it up, it's a fun story, pretty short. But
it's basically the computer, the big computer at
the time, supposedly won the war, but the only
reason it won the war is because they wanted the
people to trust this superhuman machine. But what
they realized the machine was just giving crap,
just like our LLM hallucinations. So, the head
person, president, whatever it is, basically ended
up saying, I ended up tossing a coin. But people
wanted this, really believed that this is a smart
machine thing is going to help us win the war.
So, it's obviously a funny kind of story,
but I think there is truth to it. So, many, many
decisions when it's not a close call. It's like
should Gong open an office in China right
now? Well, probably not, there's so many
reasons why not. We don't really debate it. But
should we develop feature A and feature B? If
you look at them, they're kind of the same, I
don't know, call it same value or same cost,
whatever kind of mental framework you have
for deciding, you end up being like 51/49. No
decision is going to be super wrong. So, yes,
you can try to bring in more data and you can
try to bring more people, but both decisions
are okay, so just go ahead with one, hopefully
it's not huge mistake. I'll tell you, I had this
discussion with my co-founder Amit, who is the CO,
and a few years ago we were considering buying
a company, and just pretty strategic decisions.
And we're like, we don't know, there's pros and
cons, we're on the fence there, and we end up
not buying the company. We look up Gong, and we
haven't bought big companies. And I asked him,
maybe it was a couple of months ago, it's
like, what if we had bought that company,
do you think we would've been in a radically
different position? He was like, no. So,
it could have been better, it could have
been worse, but it would not have made a
huge difference. And the reason is it was a 51/49
decision wasn't a 70/30 decision. So, it's hard
for humans to make decision, you probably know,
there's like experiments that show, it's almost
like running or jogging or doing something
that is a physical, requires your physical
capacity to make decisions. So, I know it's hard
that you want to postpone it, but just do it.
It's such a freeing way of thinking about it.
It's interesting because there's been recent
conversations on this podcast where Spotify
has this kind of value they call talk is cheap,
and it's meant to be a virtue. Talk is cheap,
so let's just talk a lot before we make a
decision. But it's specific to Spotify because
there's a lot of regulatory challenges, and if
they make it a big decision, it's a long-term,
it's like they put a lot of effort into it. So,
it's interesting, there's such different ways
of operating. There's like, let's just talk
for months and make a decision versus we're
just going to make it and then it'll be fine.
Yeah, of course, like big, big, one door. Yeah,
this is of course, you're going to spend more
time on, but people tend to overthink I think
decisions. I also found out that personally the
quality of my decisions, if you sort of wake
me up in the middle of the night and ask me,
what do you think about X? And I'm
going to be like, I have no idea,
I'm sleeping. And then you're like, you got to
force me to decision, [inaudible 00:30:54] make
a decision, now you're going to give
me two weeks to ponder over it...
I don't think the quality of the decision is
going to be much, much higher, which is maybe
could be personal, but that's at least what I
found over my too many years of existence, so.
I think something that's probably necessary
for that to work out well is having a deep
experience in that space. You've been at this
for a long time, so I imagine your instinct
often is trained based on your past experience
of the market and customers. Do you feel like
that's a necessary component of trusting your
gut and instinct on these sorts of decisions?
Yeah, of course. You got at some stage know
what you're doing. Yeah, if I were now to
make a decision around, I don't know, entering a
different space, there's no way I would be like,
yeah, let's flip a coin, like the Asimov story,
and go for it. I go to a conference, learn it,
whatever the thing is, and then make that
decision. But most of the decisions all of
it make on a day-to-day basis is our domain
of expertise versus totally new things.
Awesome. Okay, let's talk about AI for a bit. You
guys were very early on AI, you were working on,
basically AI was like, your product was built
on machine learning back then is what it was
called before. Because it was cool and everyone
probably thought it was a waste of time, and no,
it's never going to work. Now, everyone's building
AI, building AI into their product. What have
you learned about working with AI over the years
that you think people maybe are not yet aware of,
or that will likely cause them pain that
you can help solve and avoid for them?
Yeah, funny, when we launched Gong,
we didn't use the term AI because
people thought it was a bad thing, it makes
wrong decisions, or they just thought it's
an [inaudible 00:32:26] item, an acronym.
When we founded Gong, I was in sabbatical,
and I actually went to this deep learning
course because I was bored, in all fairness,
and after that course I ended up buying Nvidia
stock, which I wish I had kept up until now.
But I did send an email saying, hey, this is the
next thing. So, we understood it's the next thing,
of course we didn't know it's going to be
LLM and GPT and other acronyms that evolved
over the years, and probably now that we're
talking end of 2024-ish, I think people should
not go from one extreme, which is, hey, we need a
bunch of data scientists for every small project,
which was the case five years ago, or three
years ago, to the other extreme, which is,
hey, LLM is going to solve everything.
Because LLMs don't solve everything,
they have huge utility. We use LLMs all over the
place, most companies that developed AI stuff use
LLMs, it's a great thing, but at the same time,
don't assume it does everything, you still need
some of the core competencies of AI. So, you
do want to have expertise, people who actually
know what they're doing, and help guide us PMs
around, is this something that can be built,
or no? Because if you're going to spend many,
many hours on asking an LLM to do, I don't know,
in the case of Gong, for example, tell me what the
good sales cycle looks like? LLMs don't do that,
it's just like maybe something else does, but we
have a field prediction model. LLMs cannot predict
fields, it's like we're very, very specialized.
So, I think you still need to have expertise,
you still want to have some measurements.
So, yes, version one, you can just go to an LLM
and say create something, I don't know, whatever,
but if you don't have measurements... Like in the
old machine learning, whatever metrics you use,
you're not going to advance, you're going to have
V1 and you're going to have V2 and you have
no way to know if you've made a progress. So,
we pay a lot of attention to, we have people who
are going to specialize in how you measure, we use
ELO system, which is the one used chess as well,
and we do have experts who can help us make the
right decisions. You can make a very good progress
without these, but I think there's a glass ceiling
if you don't figure out how to create a more
operational rigor around this whole AI thing.
So, what I'm hearing is don't assume you can
just outsource all your AI magic model building
to the foundational model companies, you need
to have your own AI expertise, ML expertise?
Yeah, or even if you end up outsourcing the
core work, at least you have to have the
expertise to understand what is doable, what is
not doable, what's the right way to approach it,
what's the input you get to the LLM, is this
going to be good quality or bad quality? Even
if you just take the product management aspect, if
the LLM gives you something that is 90% accurate,
or I don't know, people are going to think is
good, the product's going to look different than
if it's 50% good. So, just the way you even
think about it, the way you... I think Figma
calls their AI feature like First Draft, which is
a term I like because they realize it's not best,
it's not great, but it's a good first draft.
So, if you know what it is, it's easier not
just to name, but how conceptualize, how to
build a workflow around it, and what to train
users to assume for it, and I think there is
an expertise there that comes on top of LLMs,
even if you just use LLMs, and you can't
afford or you don't want to go deeper.
For folks that want to do this at their
company, what are the functions that you
have that help you do this/skills of people
you hire that you think are important?
So, I think you still have to have this kind of
"data scientist role," and data scientists could
be in the company, it could be advisors as well,
right? Not everything has to be a full-time in
the company. And the role of a data scientist is
help guide the company, field prediction model,
is this a LLM thing? Do you need to build a
model? If you need, what input do you need?
How long it's going to take, da, da, da. Also, in
our world at least data scientists are the people
who know how to measure these things. Is this
model better or is this model better? Is this
prompt better or is this prompt not better?
And they're not going to do the judgment,
so when Gong creates an account brief, the data
scientist is not going to know if that brief or
this brief is the right one, but they can guide
us through what's the right tool set you need,
to put it in front of customers and
how do you measure this and whatnot.
And then, I think at the end of the day, you also
need this [inaudible 00:36:56], now it's becoming
a common, the prompt engineer, the person who's
actually working with the LLMs and guiding them,
that is, it's a bit of a technical skill, but
you got to have it. And it doesn't have to be
a full-time person, but there needs to be
that expertise of somebody who's actually
optimizing things. Many, many customers tell
us that Gong AI is, well, it's more accurate
than others, yes, there is some combination
of models we build from scratch, fine-tune,
because we have AI expertise, but some of it
is also how we, the prompt we give to the LLMs,
how much rigor we put into optimizing them and
kind of finding the edge cases and ranking them
and improving them over time. If you want to
get really good AI, you have to invest in it.
As you're talking, I'm thinking about
how your pod model matches really well
with the world of things moving so quickly,
AI changing constantly, just giving teams
autonomy feels like a huge advantage in this
world where things are just changing weekly.
So, we have a couple of, maybe now it's
three different pods, we have an embedded
AI specialist team, either a specialist or
a team, or I don't know, a couple of people,
and then they can iterate very, very quickly
on using LLMs or using non-LLMs, SLMs,
people now say small language models, but whatever
the thing is, they can iterate very, very quickly.
Awesome. Okay, a couple more things I want
to touch on. One is the spiral model. So,
you mentioned that you just went to learn deep
learning on your own, you went off to the side,
I'm going to understand this new thing that
everyone's talking about, deep learning,
and you got really smart in machine
learning, basically, really quickly,
and you have this thing you call the spiral model
or the spiral method for how to learn something
complex quickly. You wrote a Medium post about
this, or blog post. What is the spiral method,
how does it work, how do people learn things
really quickly that are really complicated?
Yeah. I think it's even beyond just the speed,
but also how do you even know that you actually
learned it. So, there is a mathematical, or not...
Physical concept called annealing, which is how
certain material becomes the way it is, and it's
sort of the temperature goes slightly down and
eventually become crystal or whatnot. There is an
element to this I think in learning as well, which
is, you want to know what deep learning is, you
know nothing, you go find the person next to you
and you're like, what is deep learning? They tell
you something, of course you don't know anything,
you just heard it from one person, and the next
question you should ask, who else should I be
speaking with? They give you three other names...
I think in tech we all tend to be, have this very,
very kind cool ecosystem, people who are willing
to help as long as you don't ask too much of them.
So, then you speak with three other people,
and then they give you other names and you
sort of go around. And ideally at some stage
you feel like the first person you have no
idea what they're talking about, you probably
didn't even understand what they're saying,
the fifth person you might understand 50%, or 50%
is new, at some stage you're going to feel like,
well new stuff is 10%, or 5%, or 0%... I call it
the spiral because it's going in circles around
the target, and eventually you feel like, well,
I'm hearing the same thing again and again,
and you're like, well, if I heard it from
three people, I didn't learn anything new,
I'm at the bullseye. Of course, at the level
I am, so I'm never going to be a deep learning
specialist in the same way that true data
scientists are, but as a product manager,
I know it probably as well as I can,
given that everybody I'd spoken with
at the time was not giving anything new at
the level that I had desired at this time.
I love that. Is there anything you've been
studying recently that you've either used
this method for or something else you're excited
about learning that's new or on the cutting edge?
Usually I do this for use cases within our
customer base. For example, if I wanted to,
wanted to go after a certain persona, or
a certain use case for the product. So,
we had this notion of can we do a better job
for a specific persona within sales people who
are account managers? So, I would use a similar
method, like, hey, talk to one account manager,
talk to an analyst, or whatever the thing is, and
eventually when you start hearing the same things,
like what do they care about that's different
than [inaudible 00:41:03] people, like selling
new business or different than contact center
sellers. When you start hearing the same thing,
you're like, okay, I kind of got to where
I need to be, now I can make decisions,
I can always do another spiral and get one
level deeper, which is, I don't know, do
some user research, go all in, but at least at the
conversation level, I've got where I need to be.
I love how simple this is, is you just start
talking. Just find somebody to talk to,
ask about this, no pressure, and then just,
okay, who else should I talk to? You just
keep having conversations, spiraling deeper
and deeper into knowledge and wisdom. Okay,
one thing I wanted to touch on, which has
always stuck with me about your approach
initially when you were starting Gong, is how you
found your initial ICP, who to go after. And it's
really funny how narrow you got when you all
decided here's who we're focusing on for our
first dozen customers. So, I have the list here.
So, when you decided here's who we're targeting,
here's the list of constraints, we're going to
target people selling their product in the US,
in English, over video conference, using
WebEx, which was the big one at the time,
selling software that is worth 1000 to $100,000,
and there was only 5,000 companies in this bucket.
Can you just talk about why you found
it was so important to get so narrow,
and just the power of getting really narrow,
which is very counterintuitive to a lot of people,
where they're like, oh, we're just going
to be for everyone, it's a huge market?
I think it's sort of the traditional,
I call it the bowling alley, or
however you want to form the-
Crossing the chasm.
Yeah, the crossing the chasm kind of methodology,
which you want to start narrow, you want to create
this kind of small pond, where people talk
about each other, and you can light the fire
in there. In my previous company, by the way, I
did read Crossing the Chasm, and I told myself,
nah, I can do way better than that. So, we
had one customer in, I think it was L'Oreal,
or one of the cosmetics companies, and American
Express, and Cisco, different industries,
and there was no way we could scale it
because everybody had their own lingo,
the way they thought about the technology and
whatnot. So, by having a smaller set of customers,
or I see, definition of customers, you can
develop much more focused, and then it's easier
to light the fire, because people move right?
At some stage, I think it was year one into
the business, we heard from a company
that they interviewed a salesperson,
and the salesperson asked, "Are you using Gong?"
And they said, "We are thinking about using Gong,
but we're not." He's like, "Well, I'm only
going to work for companies that use Gong."
And that's sort of the power of a small pond
with companies that are like each other,
because you get this viral effect that
is not common in B2B, but it's as close
as you can because of those conversations.
That other customer became a Gong customer,
literally because they interviewed a person
who told him he's not going to come unless
they bought Gong. You can't do this if you have
a wide market, where people don't even talk to
each other, and there is an assumption that
you're not burying yourself in this market.
I love... Because today, like I said at the
very top of this conversation, you're just so
ubiquitous, everybody seems to be using Gong.
And I love that you started with something,
where there was seven, I don't know, different
constraints to narrow down who you're going after,
and it's such a good example of the power of
starting very focused and then expanding from
that, which is what you've done. Okay, last
question before we get to a very exciting
lightning ground, we have a segment on this
podcast called Fail Corner, where so many of
these podcast conversations, everyone's always
sharing all the successes, everything's always
going great, nothing ever goes wrong, when
in reality it does, things often go wrong.
Can you share a story from your career or just
the journey of Gong when things didn't go well,
when there was maybe a failure, and if you learned
something from that time, what you learned?
Yeah, I always joke that in my previous company
we had done so many mistakes, that if life limited
you to a certain number of mistakes, I wouldn't
have any left I think. I still do mistakes,
but just so many. So, every one of them probably
done twice, and then it's like at some stages,
third time's a charm. So, the one I
just gave you is probably the worst,
is crossing the chasm, you start a company, you
have this technology, I was thinking let's go
horizontal. And that technology was whatever,
web integration, something, eventually ended
up being an e-commerce content syndication, or
[inaudible 00:45:28] management SaaS software,
which is the right way to go because you want to
specialize in a certain market. But initially,
just going on in was just ridiculously
not smart, and the other thing we did
together was that was, the previous company
started year 2000, so that was the bubble,
one of those very, very nice bubbles.
So, we're like, you know what? We actually
got three customers, admittedly in totally three
different segments, now let's go and scale. Now,
we all knew we need one salesperson, one SE and
[inaudible 00:45:59] what's now called product
market fit, I don't know that the term even
existed there, and we're like, nah, you know what,
investors told us you got to hire more people.
So, we hired, I don't know, 20 salespeople, all of
them failing miserably, because A, we didn't have
a true product market fit, but even what's worse,
we didn't have a true focused ICP with a
very, very repeatable product market fit. So,
if you sort of hear me talk about how we started
Gong, Amit is the CEO, and he drove a lot of that
business strategy, but me being sort of a co-pilot
there, it definitely bringing the same, I'm not
going to make that mistake again, I might do new
and fun ones, but not that same mistake again.
Awesome. Thank you for sharing that. With that,
we reached our very exciting
lightning round, are you ready?
Sure.
Let's do it. First question, what
are two or three books that you
find yourself recommending most to other people?
There is a set of books, I think one that is the
starter one is, I think it's called, right now,
the Ideal Executive. People don't really
know it, it's sort of a management book,
how to run a team and whatnot. I think the
original version is, funnily enough, I think
it was called Mismanagement, but nobody wants
to buy a book called Mismanagement, you'd much
rather buy a book that's called Ideal Executive.
Because you, of course, are not mismanaging,
you're the ideal executive altogether, so you're
just reinforcing your self. But jokes aside,
it basically gives you the... It tried
to define people by four characteristics,
I think misnamed, but are you an administrator?
Are you, he calls it a producer, basically get
the job done? Integrator, which brings people
together, and the fourth one, it's basically
change agent, do a lot of mess and change stuff.
Usually entrepreneurs kind of include that part,
of course. And basically, his claim is that nobody
does the whole four, maybe you're good at one,
maybe okay at the other, and personally
I'm horrible in administration. I obviously
acknowledge that, and I try to sort of compliment
myself. So, I think there's two things in it,
firstly, just those, I thought there was
the four good ways of looking at people,
as a manager, as a leader, of course, that's one,
but I think even if you disagree with those four,
just understanding that you want to
look at the people in the organization,
yourself included [inaudible 00:48:20]
key characteristics, and you can select
the different framework, helps you a lot with
creating high-velocity discussions with others.
Because I can talk with somebody and say,
hey, you're a P. He's going be like, well,
I'm not P, an I, whatever the thing is, and that
makes a discussion that is much, much faster,
and more comprehensive than just trying to explain
this from scratch. Like, hey, you tend to do this,
and you might want to do this, and you might
want to strengthen that. So, I'd recommend
starting from this, but there's probably other
methodologies you can pick, and maybe some of
the listeners here have already had one, but
that's one I like because I found it useful.
And it's called the Ideal Executive?
I think so, I'm pretty sure. Yeah.
Great. Any of other books before we move on?
That one's probably-
That's the one.
I like Crucial Conversation, that's going
to, in the beating path, it's like how to
conduct conversations with people in your
organization. I think it's never bad to-
[inaudible 00:49:16].
... reimmerse yourself into how to
speak properly with other people.
We have an episode coming up where we're going to
share scripts and phrases to use
to have better hard conversations.
Ah, it's good.
Yeah, I'm excited for that/scared. Okay,
next question, do you have a recent
movie or TV show you've really enjoyed?
I didn't have TV, like broadcast TV for many,
many years, so nowadays there's Netflix so you
can find stuff. But my taste in TV and movie
tend to be pretty esoteric, French. So, I've
recently watched this British TV series called
Slow Horses, with Gary Oldman, and it's a really
kind of fun sort of funny spy thing, which I found
amusing and intelligent at the same time. So,
some kind of comedies tend to be pretty lowest
common denominator, that one seems still fun and
witty at the same time. So, that's my latest that
I really enjoyed watching even this third seasons.
I love Slow Horses, it's like...
I don't think it's that obscure,
I think it's one of the ones Apple
promotes often. I will say this,
last season was not my favorite,
but the other two were awesome.
Yeah, I 100% agree, which I said,
even the third season was okay,
but the first two were really, really good and-
Yeah. It's super fun.
... [inaudible 00:50:32] the fourth.
It took me like three tries to
actually get into the show initially,
because people kept telling me it's so good,
and I started watching, and it's just like,
who's this old messed up guy, just complaining
endlessly? But you got to keep watching. Okay.
Do you have a favorite product you've
recently discovered that you really like?
I assume you have a silverware
caddy in your dishwasher, right?
Oh yeah, to put forks and knives. Yeah.
The cutlery... So that's my favorite product as of
lately, and I'll tell you why. It's a funny story,
I lost mine, and you can ask yourself, how can
you freaking lose one of those baskets? And it
was in the dishwasher, of course, and for
some reason I couldn't find it, that's like
you have to be really out of your mind to not
find. Anyway. So, I go to some Amazon or eBay,
wherever, I just buy a new one, and then of
course a day later I find it's [inaudible
00:51:20] somewhere within the dishwasher. Now
I have two. So, this is my latest invention,
if you have two of those baskets, you can put one
of them in the sink and you can just continuously
load your cutlery or silverware while the
thing is working, or you haven't vacated it.
So, it kind of changed how we organize our
kitchen with something that probably costs
$10. No product manager has ever thought about
offering two of those with your dishwasher,
I don't think it even tried to upsell any of that.
And I told it to some people and they actually
ended up buying a second one, and said it was
successful, which is the most ridiculous thing,
it's like spend $10, $15, get something organized
in a completely obscure and unintentional way.
I'll give you an even crazier idea that a previous
guest suggests, Rory Sutherland has this pitch
that you should have two dishwashers,
everyone should have two dishwashers,
because one is your clean and one is dirty. And
you just take your plates and things out of the
clean one, use it and put it straight into the
dirty dishwasher. And why are we just putting
things away constantly, just like go from one to
the other and one to the other? So, there you go.
Similar idea.
Similar idea, next level.
Mine is like $15 though, a
little bit, maybe cheaper.
Yeah, exactly. Houses are not designed for
two dishwashers. Okay, two more questions,
do you have a favorite life motto that you often
come back to, find useful in work or in life?
One that I use, it's going to sound funny,
but it's actually real and I use it,
and I actually believe in it. It's, I'm
not sure if you know for philosophy,
there's like razors, like Occam's
razor, which is basically-
Oh, there's other razors.
Yeah, there's so many razors, and there's one that
I think came in in some Murphy book or whatnot,
and it's called Hanlon's razor, you can look it
up, Wikipedia or wherever. And it basically says,
it goes like, "Never attribute to malice, that
which is adequately explained by stupidity." So,
it obviously sounds funny, and it's trying
to be funny, but it's so helpful because
so often do we attribute people's behavior,
think in a company, customer, I don't know,
personal life sometimes, to malice like, oh,
this person's not returning my calls because X,
or this person hasn't given me feedback
or has given me feedback because of X.
And it's sort of like we all, I think there's
a saying, it's like always assume well,
or good intent, or whatever, and this is sort
of the more funny way to sort of say that, yes,
the person is... And again, stupidity is obviously
a funny way to do it, maybe inappropriate. But
it's basically, yes, they just didn't know,
they didn't care, they didn't think about it,
they weren't trained, whatever the thing is, and
if you take this model on your day-to-day life,
at least I find that it's so true, and so
often true, that is funny, but inspiring.
I really love that quote. I think of it often
when somebody's doing something that's annoying
me. Final question, you mentioned that
you are from Israel, you live in Israel,
you mentioned delicious food, hummus is
one example. Is there another Israeli food
that you think people are sleeping on, that you
think people should try when they have a chance?
Israeli food has become a little bit to be in
fashion lately, so people coming from the US
to visit us in the office are like, oh, Israeli
food is so good, and I'm like, what do you mean?
It's the same food we've had for 20 or 30 years.
I think the taste change because you kind of eat
more healthy and less oil these days. Most
of Israeli food is sort of Arabic in nature,
or Turkish, so there's great falafel, great
hummus, pita bread, Turkish delights of sort,
so a lot of those. And some very, very obscure,
and if you come to Israel, I'll show you around
some very less known food that only special
guests get to taste. I can't say here because-
What's one... Yeah, say it
here, [inaudible 00:55:00].
There is a thing called Sabich, for example,
nobody knows of it. People claim it came from
the people who came from Iraq, but my
wife's father came from Iraq, he's like,
we've never seen this before. It's sort of pita
bread filled with hummus and eggplant and eggs.
Oh wow.
And maybe something else, I have no idea.
Tahini, maybe. I don't know. It tastes good,
but it's such a weird combination, and it's become
a little bit of a thing, and nobody knows what the
origin is. I think somebody made a mistake and
gave you the name, and now it's like ubiquitous.
You are making me hungry. Eilon, this
was amazing. Two final questions,
where can folks find you if they
want to reach out and learn more,
maybe ask some follow-up questions,
and how can listeners be useful to you?
I'm pretty available, and LinkedIn is
probably the best way. I tend to read
my inbox in LinkedIn and respond
when I can. And then useful to me,
if you want to come work for Gong,
check out our careers page, of course.
The product team is mostly based in Tel Aviv and
Dublin, Ireland, so maybe a little bit remote for
most people, but there's sometimes folks in
the US and sometimes non-product, of course,
roles. We're hiring quite a few people these
days, so we'd love to at least give us a chance.
Awesome. Eilon, thank you so much for being here.
Thanks for inviting me.
Bye everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening, if you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
Lenny'sPodcast.com. See you in the next episode.