90% of your code roughly is written by AI now.
The team that works in the most futuristic
way is the Claude Code team. They're using
Claude Code to build Claude Code in a very
self-improving kind of way. We really rapidly
became bottlenecked on other things like our
merge queue. We had to completely re-architect
it because so much more code was being
written and so many more pull requests
were being submitted. Over half of our pull
requests are Claude Code generated. Probably
at this point it's probably over 70% that it
just completely blew out the expectations of it.
You guys are at the edge of
where things are heading.
I had the very bizarre experience of I had
two tabs open. It was AI 2027, and my product
strategy, and it was this moment where I'm
like, "Wait, am I the character in the story?"
It feels like ChatGPT is just winning
in consumer mind share. How does that
inform the way you think about
product, strategy, and mission?
I think there's room for several generationally
important companies to be built in AI right now.
How do we figure out what we want
to be when we grow up versus what
we currently aren't or wish that we were
or see other players in the space being?
What's something that you've
changed your mind about what
AI is capable of and where AI is heading?
I had this notion coming in like, "Yes, these
models are great, but are they able to have
an independent opinion?" And it's actually
really flipped for me only in the last month.
Today, my guest is Mike Krieger. Mike is chief
product officer at Anthropic, the company behind
Claude. He's also the co-founder of Instagram.
He's one of my most favorite product builders
and thinkers. He's also now leading product at
one of the most important companies in the world,
and I'm so thrilled to have had a chance to
chat with him on the podcast. We chat about
what he's changed his mind about most in terms
of AI capabilities in the years since he joined
Anthropic, how product development changes and
where bottlenecks emerge when 90% of your code
is written by AI, which is now true at Anthropic.
Also, his thoughts on OpenAI versus Anthropic,
the future of MCP, why he shut down Artifact,
his last startup and how he feels about it. Also,
what skills he's encouraging his kids to
develop with the rise of AI. And we closed
the podcast on a very heartwarming message
that Claude wanted me to share it with Mike.
A big thank you to my newsletter Slack
community for suggesting topics for this
conversation. If you enjoy this podcast, don't
forget to subscribe it and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. Also, if you
become an annual subscriber of my newsletter,
you get a year free of a bunch of incredible
products, including Linear, Superhuman, Notion,
Perplexity and Granola. Check it out at
lennysnewsletter.com and click bundle.
With that, I bring you Mike Krieger. This
episode is brought to you by Productboard,
the leading product management platform for
the enterprise. For over 10 years, Productboard
has helped customer-centric organizations
like Zoom, Salesforce, and Autodesk build
the right products faster. And as an end-end
platform, Productboard seamlessly supports all
stages of the product development lifecycle. From
gathering customer insights to planning a roadmap,
to aligning stakeholders, to earning customer
buy-in, all with a single source of truth.
And now product leaders can get even more
visibility into customer needs. With Productboard
Pulse, a new voice of customer solution built-in
intelligence helps you analyze trends across all
of your feedback and then dive deeper by asking
AI your follow-up questions. See how Productboard
can help your team deliver higher impact products
that solve real customer needs and advance your
business goals. For a special offer and free
15-day trial, visit productboard.com/lenny.
That's productboard.com/L-E-N-N-Y.
Last year, 1.3% of the global GDP
flowed through Stripe. That's over $1.4 trillion
and driving that huge number are the millions of
businesses growing more rapidly with Stripe. For
industry leaders like Forbes, Atlassian, OpenAI,
and Toyota, Stripe isn't just financial software.
It's a powerful partner that simplifies how they
move money, making it as seamless and borderless
as the internet itself. For example, Hertz boosted
its online payment authorization rates by 4%
after migrating to Stripe. And imagine seeing
a 23% lift in revenue like Forbes did just six
months after switching to Stripe for subscription
management. Stripe has been leveraging AI for the
last decade to make its product better at growing
revenue for all businesses. From smarter checkouts
to fraud prevention and beyond. Join the ranks of
over half of the Fortune 100 companies that trust
Stripe to drive change, learn more at Stripe.com.
Mike, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
I'm really happy to be here. I've been
looking forward to this for a while.
Wow, I had love to hear that. I've also been
looking forward to this for a while. I have
so much to talk about. So first of all,
you've been at Anthropic for just over
a year at this point. Congrats
by the way on hitting the cliff.
Thank you. Not that we're tracking.
That's right. So let me just ask you
this. So you've been at Anthropic
for about a year. What's something
that you've changed your mind about
from before you joined Anthropic to today about
what AI is capable of and where AI is heading?
Two things. One is like a pace and timeline
question. The other one is a capability
question. So maybe I'll take the second
one first. I had this notion coming in,
yes, these models are great, they're going to be
able to produce code, they're going to be able to
write hopefully in your voice eventually, but are
they able to sort of have an independent opinion?
And it's actually really flipped for me only
in the last month and only with Opus 4 where
my go-to product strategy partner is Claude. And
it has been basically for that full year where
I'll write an initial strategy, I'll share
it with Claude basically, and I'll have it,
look at it. And in the past it's pretty anodyne
kind of comments that it would leave, "Oh,
have you thought about this?" And it's like,
"Yeah, I thought about that." And Opus 4,
I was working on some strategy for our
second half of the year was the first one.
It was like Opus 4 combined with our
advanced research. But it really went
out for a while and it came back and I was
like, you really looked at it in a new way.
And so that's a thing that I've maybe I didn't
feel like it would never be able to do that,
but I wasn't sure how soon it'd be able to come up
with something where I look at it, I'm like, yep,
that is a new angle that I hadn't been looking
at before and I'm going to incorporate that
immediately into how I think about it. So that's
probably the biggest shift that I've had is,
I don't know about independence is the right word,
but creativity and sort of novelty of thought
relative to how I'm thinking about things. But
in the timeline, one, it's so interesting because
I was sitting next to Dario yesterday and he's
like, "I keep making these predictions and people
keep laughing at me. And then they come true."
And it's funny to have this happen over and over
again and he is like, not all of them are going
to be right. But even I think as of last year he
was talking about we're at 50% on SWE-Bench,
which is this benchmark around how well the
models are at coding. He's like, "I think we'll
be at 90% by the end of 2025 or something like
that." And sure enough, we're at about 72 now
with the new models and we're at 50% when he
made that prediction. And it's continued to
scale pretty much as predicted. And so I've
taken the timelines a lot more seriously
now. And I don't know if you read AI 2027-
I have, it made by heart race.
And I had the very bizarre
experience of I had two tabs open,
it was AI 2027 and my product strategy. And
it was this moment where I'm like, "Wait,
am I the character in the story? How much is this
converging?" But you read that and you're like,
"Oh, 2027, that's years away if you're like no,
mid 2025." And things continue to improve and the
models continue to be able to do more and more
and they're able to act agentically and they're
able to have memory and they're able to act over
time. So I think my confidence in the timelines
and I don't know exactly how they manifest it
definitely just solidified over the last year.
Wow. I wasn't expecting to go down
that that paper was scary. And I'm
curious just I guess I can't help but ask
just thoughts on just how do we avoid the
scary scenario that paper paints of
where AI getting really smart goes?
Yeah, this maybe ties into, I've been here a
year, why did I join Anthropic? I was watching
the models get better and even you could see
it in early 2024, and looking at my kids,
I'm like, "All right, they're going to grow
up in a world with AI. It's unavoidable."
Where can I maximally apply my time to nudge
things towards going well? And I mean that's
a lot of what people think about across the
industry, especially at Anthropic. And so I
think coming to an agreement and a shared
framework and understanding of what does
going well look like? What is the kind
of human AI relationship that we want?
How will we know along the way? What do we need
to build and develop and research along the way?
I think those are all the kind of key questions.
And some of those are product questions and some
of those are research and interpretability
questions, but for me it was the strongest
reason to join was okay. I think there's a
lot of contribution that Anthropic can have
around nudging things to go better. And if I
can have a part to play there, let's do it.
I love that answer. Speaking of kids, so you've
got two kids, I've got a young kid, he's just
about to turn two. I'm curious just what skills
you're encouraging your kids to build as this AI
becomes more and more of our future and some jobs
will be changed and just what advice do you have?
We have this breakfast feed breakfast with the
kids every morning and sometimes some question
will come up, something about physics and our
oldest kid's almost six, but they ask funny
questions about the solar system or physics or in
a 6-year-old way and before we reach for Claude,
because at first my instinct is like, "Oh, I
wonder how Claude will do this question." And we
started changing, "Well, how would we find out?"
And the answer can't just be we'll ask Claude,
all right, well, we could do this experiment,
we could have this thing. So I think nurturing
curiosity and still having a sense of, I don't
know, the scientific process sounds grandiose
to instill in a 6-year-old, but that process
of discovery and asking questions and then
systematically working right through, I think
will still be important. And of course AI will
be an incredible tool for helping resolve large
parts of that, but that process of inquiry I think
is still really important and independent thought.
My favorite moment with my kid, because she's very
headstrong, our 6-year-old, she said something
and I wasn't sure if it was true. It was,
oh, is that coral is an animal or corals alive?
I don't even remember what the details of it.
And I was like, "I don't know if that's true." And
she's like, "It's definitely true, dad." I'm like,
"All right, let's ask Claude on this one." And
she's like, "You can ask Claude, but I know I'm
right." And I'm like I love that. I want that
kind of level of not just delegating all of your
cognition to the AI because it won't always get it
right. And also it kind of short circuits any kind
of independent thought. So the skill of asking
questions, inquiry and independent thinking,
I think those are all the pieces. What that
looks like from a job or occupation perspective,
I'm just keeping an open mind and I'm sure
that'll radically change between now and then.
It's interesting. Tobias Lütke, Shopify CEO, on
the podcast and he had the same answer for what
he's encouraging his kids to develop is curiosity.
And so it's interesting that's a common thread.
The K through eight school our kid goes through
had an AI and education expert come in and I
had a very low bar or a very low expectation of
what this conversation was going to be like. And
actually I think it went over most of the people
in the audience's heads because he was like,
"All right, well let me take you all the way
back to Claude Shannon in information theory."
And I could see people's eyes going, "What did
I sign up for and why am I hearing this school
auditorium hearing about information theory?"
But he did a really nice job I think of also
just imagining there will be different jobs and we
don't know what those jobs are going to be and so
what are the skills and techniques and remain open
mindedness around what the exact way we recombine
those things. And even those will probably change
three times between now and when they're 18.
So we're talking about timelines and how things
are changing. So I've seen these stats that you've
shared, other folks at Anthropic have shared
about how much of your code is now written by
AI. So people have shared stats from 70% to 90%.
There was an engineer lead that shared 90% of your
code roughly is written by AI now, which first of
all is just insane that it went from zero to 90%,
I don't know, a few years, something like
that. Yeah, basically. I don't think people
are talking about this enough. That's just
wild. You guys are basically at the bleeding
edge. I've never heard a company that has this
high a percentage of code being written by AI.
So you guys are at the edge of where things are
heading. I think most companies will get here.
How has product development changed knowing
so much of your code is now written by AI,
so usually it's like PM, it's like here's what
we're building, engineer builds it, it ships it.
Is it still kind of roughly that or is it
now PMs are just going straight to Claude,
build this thing for me, engineers are
doing different things? Just what looks
different in a world where 90%
of your code is written by AI?
Yeah, it's really interesting because I think
the role of engineering has changed a lot,
but the suite of people that come together to
produce a product hasn't yet. And I think for
the worst in a lot of ways because I think
we're still holding on some assumptions. So
I think the roles are still fairly similar,
although we'll now get in my favorite things
that happen now are some nice PMs that have an
idea that they want to express or designers that
have an idea they want to express will
use Claude and maybe even Artifacts to
put together an actual functional demo. And
that has been very, very helpful. No, no,
this is what I mean that makes it tangible.
That's probably the biggest role shift is
prototyping happening earlier in the process via
more of this code plus design piece. What I've
learned though is the process of knowing what
to ask the AI, how to compose the question,
how to even think about structuring a change
between the backend and the front end.
Those are still very difficult and specialized
skills and they still require the engineer to
think about it. And we really rapidly became
bottlenecked on other things like our merge queue,
which is the get in line to get your change
accepted by the system that then deploys into
production. We had to completely re-architect
it because so much more code was being written
and so many more pull requests were being
submitted that it just completely blew
out the expectations of it. And so it's like, I
don't know if you've ever read, is it the goal,
the classic process optimization book, and
you realize there's this critical path theory.
I've just found all these new bottlenecks in
our system, there's an upstream bottleneck,
which is decision making and alignment. A lot of
things that I'm thinking about right now is how
do I provide the minimum viable strategy to let
people feel empowered to go run and type and build
and explore at the edge of model capabilities.
I don't think I've gotten that right yet,
but that's something I'm working on.
And then once the building is happening,
other bottlenecks emerge, let's make sure we don't
step on each other's toes. Let's think through
all the edge cases here ahead of time so that
we're not blocked on the engineering side. And
then when the work is complete and we're getting
ready to ship it, what are all those bottlenecks
as well? Let's do the air traffic control
of landing the change. How do we figure out
large strategy? So I think there hasn't been as
much pressure on changing those until this year,
but I would expect that a year from now the way
that we are conceiving of building and shipping
software just changes a lot because it's going
to be very painful to do it the current way.
Wow, that is extremely interesting. So it used to
be here's an idea, let's go design it, build it,
ship it, merge it, and then ship it. And
usually the bottleneck was engineering,
taking time to build a thing and then design.
And now you're saying the two bottlenecks
you're finding are okay deciding what to build
and aligning everyone and then it's actually
the cue to merge it into production. And I
imagine review it too is probably a part-
Reviewing has really changed too. And in many
ways perhaps unsurprisingly the team that
works in the most futuristic way is the Claude
Code team because they're using Claude Code to
build Claude Code in a very self-improving
kind of way. And early on in that project,
they would do very line by line pull request
reviews in the way that you would for any other
project. And they've just realized Claude
is generally right and it's producing pull
requests that are probably larger than most
people are going to be able to review. So can
you use a different Claude to review it and then
do the human almost acceptance testing more than
trying to review line by line. There's definitely
pros and cons and so far it's gone well. But I
could also imagine it going off the rails and
then having a completely both unmaintainable
or even understandable by Claude Code base that
hasn't happened, but watching them change their
review processes definitely has been interesting.
And yeah, the merge queue is one instance of the
bottom bottleneck that forms down there, but
there's other ones which is how do we make sure
that we're still building something coherent and
packaging it up into a moment that we can share
with people and whether that's around a launch
moment, whether that's about then enabling people
to use this thing and talking about it, the
classic things of building something useful
for people and then making it known that you've
built it and then learning from their feedback
still exists. We've just made a portion
of that whole process much more efficient.
I heard you describe this as you guys
are patient zero for this way of working.
Yes.
I love that. Do you have a sense of what
percentage of Claude Code
is written by Claude Code?
At this point, I would be shocked if
it wasn't 95% plus. I'd have to ask
Boris and the other tech leads on there. But
what's been cool is so nitty-gritty stuff,
Claude Code is written in TypeScript.
It's actually our largest TypeScript
project. Most of the rest of Anthropic is
written in Python, some Go, some Rust now,
but we're not like a TypeScript shop. And so
I saw a great comment yesterday in our Slack
where somebody had this thing that was driving
them crazy about Claude Code and they're like,
"Well, I don't know any TypeScript, I'm just
going to talk to Claude about it and do it."
And they went from that to pull requests in an
hour and solve their problem and they submitted a
pull request and that breaking down the barriers.
One, it changes your barrier to entry for any
kind of newcomer to the project. I think it can
let you choose the right language for the right
job for example. I think that helps as well, but
I think it also just reinforces Claude Code being
that patient alpha of that where contributions
from outside the team can be Claude coded as well.
Wow, this is, it's just continue to blow my
mind all these things that you're sharing,
95% of Claude Code is written
by Claude Code roughly.
That's my guess. Yeah, I'll come back with the
real stuff. But I mean if you ask the team,
that's how they're working and that's how they're
getting contributions from across the company too.
It's interesting going back to your point about
strategy being assisted by Claude itself and your
point about how a lot of the bottlenecks now are
kind of the top of the funnel of coming up with
ideas aligning everyone, it's interesting
that Claude is already helping with that
also of helping you decide what to build.
So if those two bottlenecks are aligning,
deciding what to build and then
just merging and getting everything,
where do you see the most interesting stuff
happening to help you speed those things up?
Yeah, I think that on that first row, I
started the year by writing a doc that
was effectively how do we do product today
and where is Claude not showing up yet that
it should? And I think that upstream part is
the next one to go. It's interesting. At your
conference I talked to somebody who's working
on a PRD, GPT kind of ChatPRD, I think was the-
ChatPRD, [inaudible 00:19:24].
Yeah. Can Claude be a partner in figuring out what
to build? What the market size is if you want to
approach it that way? What the user needs are if
you look at a different way? We think a lot about
the virtual collaborator on topic and one of the
ways in which I think that can show up is, "Hey,
I'm in the Discord, the Claude Anthropic Discord,
I'm in the user Fora, I'm on X and I'm reading
things and here's what's emergent." That's
step one. Models can do that today. Step two,
which the models probably can do today, which have
to wire them up to do it is and not only are the
problems here's how I think you might be able
to solve them. And then taking that through to,
and I put together a pull request
to solve this thing that I'm seeing
feels very achievable this year than stringing
those things together and we're limited more.
This is why MCP is exciting to me. We're
limited more around making sure the context
flows through all of that so we have the
right access to those things more than the
model's capability to reason and propose. Now
the model might not have perfect UI taste yet,
so there's definitely room for
design to intervene and be like,
"Oh, that's not quite how I would solve the
problem of this not showing up." But I would
get very excited. I would give you a really
small example, but we changed on Claude AI,
you should be able to just copy markdown from
Artifacts or code from Artifacts and we changed
it so you can actually download it and export
it. We changed the button to export and we got
a bunch of feedback like, "How do I copy now?" And
the answer is you drop it down and it's copied.
It's just mind one of those things where it's made
sense, but we probably got it not quite right.
That feedback was in the RUX channel. I would've
loved an hour later for a plot to be like, "Hey,
if we do want to change it back, here's the
PR to do it." And by the way, eventually,
and then I'm going to spin up an A/B test to
see if this changes metrics and then we'll see
how it looks in a week. If you told me that
about a year and a half ago going to be like,
"Ah, yeah, maybe like 27, maybe 26." But it really
feels just at the tip of capabilities right now.
Wow, okay. You mentioned the Lenny and
Friends Summit. I wanted to talk about
this a bit. So you were on a panel
with Kevin Weil, the CPO of OpenAI,
I think it was the first time you guys
did this maybe the last time for now.
Yeah, we haven't done it since, not
for any reason. I had a lot of fun.
What a legendary panel we assembled there with
Sarah Guo moderating. And you made this comment
actually ended up being the most rewatched part
of the interview, which is that you were putting
product people on the model team and working with
researchers making the model better and you're
putting some product people on the product
experience making the UX more intuitive,
making all that better. And you found that
almost all the leverage came from the product
team working with the researchers. And so you've
been doing more of that. So first of all, does
that continue to be true? And second of all, what
are the implications of that for product teams?
It's continued to be true. And in fact I think
that if the proportion was already skewing
towards having more of that embedding, I've
just become more and more convinced. I didn't
feel as strongly about it during the summit
and now I feel really strongly about it. If
we're shipping things that could have been built
by anybody just using our models off the shelf,
there's great stuff to be built by using our
models off the shelf by the way, don't get
me wrong, but where we should play and what we
can do uniquely should be stuff that's really at
that magic intersection between the two, right?
Artifacts may a great example and if you play
with Artifacts with Claude 4, that's an actually
really interesting example where we took somebody
from our, we have Claude code skills, which is
a team that really is doing the post-training
around teaching Claude some of these really
specific skills and we paired it with some
product people and then together we revamped
how this looks in the product today and what
Claude can do way better than just like, "Yeah, we
just used the model and we prompted a little bit."
That's just not enough. We need to be in
that fine-tuning process. So much of what,
if you look at what we're working on right now,
but we've shipped recently between research and
all these other things are things that the
functional unit of work at Anthropic is no
longer take the model and then go work with design
and product to go ship a product. It's more like
we are in the post-training conversations around
how these things should work and then we are in
the building process and we're feeding
those things back and looping them back.
I think it's exciting. It's also a new way of
working that not all PMs have, but the PMs that
have the most internal positive feedback from both
research and engineering are the ones that get it
that I was in a product review yesterday, I was
like, "Oh, if we want to do this memory feature,
we should talk to the researchers because we
just shipped a bunch of memory capabilities
in Claude 4." They're like, "Yeah, yeah, we've
been talking to them for weeks, this is how we're
manifesting it." It's like, "Okay, I feel good.
I feel like we're doing the right things now."
So let me pull on this thread more and there's
something I've been thinking about along these
lines. So essentially there's a big part
of entropic that's building this super
intelligent giga brain that's going to do
all these things for us over time. And then,
as you said, there's the product team that's
building the UX around this super intelligent
giga brain and over time this super intelligence
is going to be able to build its own stuff. And
so I guess just where do you think the most
value will come from traditional product
teams over time? I know this is different
because you guys are a foundational alum
company and not most companies don't
work this way, but just, I don't know,
thoughts on just the where most value will come
from product teams over time working on AI.
I think there's still a lot of value in two
things. One is making this all comprehensible.
I think we've done an okay job. I think we could
do a much better job of making this conference.
What's still the difference between somebody who's
really adept at using these tools in their work
and most people is huge. And maybe that's the
most literal answer to your earlier question
around what skills to learn. That is a skill to
learn and use it in the same way that I remember
we did computer lock class when I was in middle
school. I remember being really good at Google
and that was actually a skill back in the day to
think in terms of this information is out there,
how do I query for it? How do I do it? I think
it actually was an advantage at the time.
Of course now Google is pretty good at figuring
out what you're trying to do if you are only
in the neighborhood and there's less of that
research kind of need. But I still think that's
a necessary part of good product development,
which is the capabilities are there and even
if Claude can create products from scratch,
what are you building and how do you make it
Comprehensible? Still hard because I think
that gets at this much deeper empathy and
understanding of human needs and psychology.
I was a human community interaction major,
I still been talking in my book here. I still feel
like that is a very, very, very, very necessary
skill. So that's one. Two is, and this straight to
call back to another one of your guests, strategy,
how we win, where we'll play, figuring
out where exactly you're going to want to,
of all the things that you could be spending
your time or your tokens or your computation
on what you want to actually go and do.
You could be wider probably than you could before,
but you can't do everything. And even from an
external perspective, if you're seen to be doing
everything, it's way less clear around how you're
positioning yourselves. Like strategy I think is
still the second piece. And then the third one is
opening people's eyes to what's possible, which
is a continuation of making it understandable.
But we were in a demo with a financial services
company recently and we were working on here's
how you can use our analysis tool and MCP together
and you could see their light up and you're
like, "Ah, okay." We call it overhang. The
delta between what the models and the products
can do and how they're being used on a daily
basis. Huge overhang. So that's where still a
very, very strong necessary role for product.
Okay, that's an awesome answer. So essentially
areas for product teams to lean into more is
strategy, just getting better and better at
strategy, figuring out what to build and how
to win in the market, making it easier to
help people understand how to leverage the
power of these tools, the comprehensibility
and kind of along those lines is opening
people's eyes to the potential of these sorts
of things. That's where product can still help.
Exactly.
Awesome. So along those lines actually, do
you have any just prompting tricks for people,
things that you've learned to get more
out of Claude when you chat with it?
Sometimes it's funny because in some ways we have
the ultimate prompting job, which is to write the
system prompt for Claudia AI and we publish
all of these, which I think is another nice
area of transparency. And we are always careful
when giving prompting advice because at least
officially, but I'll give you the unofficial
version because you don't want things to become
like we think this works, but we're not sure why.
But I will do small things like in Claude Code
and we actually do react to this very literally,
but I always ask it to, if I wanted to use more
reasoning, think hard and it'll use a different
flow and I usually start with that. Nudging,
there's a great essay around make the other
mistake like if you tend to be too nice, can
you focus on... Even if you're trying to be more
critical or more blunt, you're probably not going
to be the most critical blunt person in the world.
And so with Claude sometimes I'm like, "Be brutal,
Claude, roast me. Tell me what's wrong with this
strategy." I know we were talking earlier about
the Claude as thought partner around critiquing
product strategy. I think I previously would say
things like, "What could be better on this product
strategy?" And I'm just like, "Just roast this
product strategy," and Claude's like a pretty nice
entity. It's hard to push it to be super brutal,
but it forces it to be a little bit more
critical as well. The last thing I'll say is,
so we have a team called Applied AI that does a
lot of work with our customers around optimizing
Claude for their use case. And we basically
took their insights and their way of working
and we put it into a product itself. So
if you go to our console, our work bench,
we have this thing called the prompt improver
where you describe the problem and you give it
examples and Claude itself will agentically
create and then iterate on a prompt for you.
I find what comes out of that ends up being quite
different than what my intuitions would've been
for a good prompt. And so I'd encourage folks
to also check that out even for their own use
cases because while that tool is met for an API
developer putting a prompt into their product,
it's equally applicable for a person doing a
prompt for themselves. It'll insert XML tags which
no human is going to think to do ahead of time. It
actually is very helpful for Claude to understand
what it should be thinking versus what it should
be saying, et cetera. So that's another one is
watch our prompt improver and then note that
Claude itself is a very good prompter of Claude.
Awesome. Okay, so we're going to link
to that, the prompt improver. The core
piece of advice you shared early is just do
the opposite of what you would naturally do.
So if you're trying to be nice, just be
brutal, be very honest and frank with me.
Exactly. I find that works quite well. What are
the thought patterns that I've fallen
into that you want to break me out of?
I saw you guys just today maybe launched a Rick
Rubin collab where it said vibe
coding. What's that all about?
What I've heard about that. And again, a lot
of the coalesce this week between model launch
developer event and The Way of Code. We had one of
our co-founders, Jack Clark is our head of policy
and he got connected to Rick Rubin because I think
he's been thinking a lot about coding, the future
of coding and creativity and they've stayed in
touch. And Rick got excited about this idea of
he was creating art and visualizations with Claude
and then he had these ideas around the way of the
vibe coder and they put together this, actually
I mean I love almost everything Rick Rubin. So
the aesthetic of it I think is just so on point
too. But yeah, this sort of like med meditation
is probably the right word. Meditation on
creativity, working alongside AI coupled with this
really rich, interesting visualizations. But it's
one of those things where internally they're like,
"Oh yeah, and we're doing this Rick Rubin collab."
We were like, "We're doing what? That's amazing."
I looked at it briefly and there's
that meme of him just thinking deeply,
sitting on a computer with a mouth.
Yes.
And ASCII art, I think.
It's totally, it's like ASCII art vibe.
I'm excited to have Andrew Luo joining
us today. Andrew is CEO of OneSchema,
one of our long time podcast
sponsors. Welcome, Andrew.
Thanks for having me, Lenny. Great to be here.
So what is new with one schema? I know that you
work with some of my favorite companies like Ramp
and Vanta and Watershed. I heard you guys launch
a new data intake product that automates the hours
of manual work that teams spent importing and
mapping and integrating CSV and Excel files.
Yes, so we just launched the 2.0 of OneSchema
FileFeeds. We've rebuilt it from the ground up
with AI. We saw so many customers coming
to us with teams of data engineers that
struggled with the manual work required
to clean messy spreadsheets. FileFeeds 2.0
allows non-technical teams to automate the process
of transforming CSV and Excel files with just a
simple prompt. We support all of the trickiest
file integrations, SFTP, S3, and even email.
I can tell you that if my team had to
build integrations like this, how nice
would it be to take this off our roadmap
and instead use something like OneSchema?
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many horror
stories of outages from even just a single
bad record in transactions, employee
files, purchase orders, you name it.
Debugging these issues is often like finding
a needle in a haystack. OneSchema stops any
bad data from entering your system and
automatically validates your files,
generating error reports with the
exact issues in all bad files.
I know that importing incorrect data can cause
all kinds of pain for your customers and quickly
lose their trust. Andrew, thank you so much
for joining me. If you want to learn more,
head on over to oneschema.co. That's oneschema.co.
Actually going back to the beginning
of your journey at Anthropic,
what's the story of you getting recruited
at Anthropic? Is there anything fun there?
It all started and I actually sent my friend
this text. So Joel Lewenstein, who I've known,
he and I built our first iPhone apps together
in 2007 when the App Store was just out and you
could still make money by selling dollar apps
on the App Store back in the day. And we were
both at Stanford together and we were friends
and we've stayed in touch over years and we've
never gotten to work together since then.
We've just remained close. And I was coming
out of the Artifact experience, I was trying to
figure out, do I start another company? I don't
think so. I need a break from starting something
from zero. Do I go work somewhere? I don't know
what company would I want to go work at. And
he reached out and he's like, "Look, I don't
know if you at all considered joining something
rather than starting something, but we're looking
for a CPO. Would you be interested in chatting?"
And at that time, Claude 3 had just come out and I
was like, "Okay, this company's clearly got a good
research team. The product is so early still." And
it was like, "Great, I'll take the meeting." And I
first met with Daniela, was one of the co-founders
and the president in Anthropic. And just from
the beginning I was like a breath of fresh air,
very little grandiosity coming off the founders,
I mean they're clear-eyed about what they're
building. They know what they don't know. How many
times I talk to Dario always like Dario is like,
"Look, I don't know anything about product, but
here's an intuition." Usually the intuition is
really good and leads to some good conversation,
but I think that intellectual honesty and shared
view of what it means to do AI in a
responsible way, it just resonated.
I kept having this feeling in these interviews,
this is the AI company I would've hoped to have
found it if I had founded an AI company. And
that's kind of the bar around if I'm going
to join something that should be where I'm
going to go. But what I realized, I actually
hadn't joined a company since my first internship
in college basically. And I was like, "Oh,
how do I onboard myself? How do I get myself
up to speed? How do I balance making sweeping
changes versus understanding what's not broken
about it overall?" And looking back on a year,
I think I made some changes too slowly. I think
there was ways reorganizing product that I could
have made a change earlier. And I think I didn't
appreciate how much a couple of really key senior
people can shape so much of product strategy.
I'll harken back to Claude Code. Claude Code
happened because Boris, who actually was a Boris
Cherney, he was an Instagram engineer and one
of our senior ICs there, we overlapped a bit,
was started that project from scratch internal
first and then we got it out and then shipped
it. And that's the power of one or two really
strong people. And I made this mistake, we need
more headcount and we do, I think there's more
work that we need to do and there's things that
I want to be building. But more than that we need
a couple of almost founder type engineers that
maybe connect back to our question on what skills
are useful and how does product development
change. And maybe even more so I'm a huge
believer in the founding engineer tech lead with
an idea and pair them with the right design and
product supports, help them realize that, I'm
10 times more a believer in that than before.
I actually asked people on Twitter what to ask
you ahead of this conversation. And the most
common question surprisingly was why did you
shut down Artifact? And I also wondered that
because I loved Artifact. I was a power user. I
was just like, "Finally a news app that I love
that it's giving me what I want to know." So
I guess just what happened there at the end?
I still really miss it too. I didn't find a
replacement and I think I substituted it by
visiting individual sites and keeping things
up that way. And it's not really the same,
especially on the log to I think we got right with
Artifact and if people didn't play with it before,
it was we really tried to not just recommend
top stories, they were part of it. But really
if you were interested in Japanese architecture,
you could pretty reliably get really interesting
stories about Japanese architecture every
day. Whether that's from a Dwell or from
Architectural Digest or from a really specific
blog that we found that somebody recommended
to us. It captured some of that Google reader
joy of content discovery of the deeper web. Our
headwinds were a couple. One of them was just
mobile websites have really taken a turn. I
don't blame any individuals for this.
I think it's the market dynamics of it,
but we put so much time or designers, sky Gunner
Gray who's phenomenal that for Perplexity now,
the app experience I was so proud of, but when you
click through it was like the pressures on these
mobile sites and these mobile publishers would
be like, "Sign up for our newsletter. Here's a
full screen video ad." It was very jarring and we
didn't feel like it ethically made sense for us
to do a bunch of ad blocking because then you're
like, "Sure, you can deliver a nice experience for
people, but that doesn't feel like it's playing
fair with the publishers." But at the same time,
the actual experience wasn't good. So the mobile
web deteriorating, which makes me very sad,
but I think was part of it. Two was Instagram
spread in the early days because people would
take photos and then post them on other
networks and tell friends about it.
And there was this really natural like, "How
did you do that? I want to do it." News was
very personal. I can't tell you how many people
would be like, "I love Artifact." I'm like,
"Did you tell anybody about it?" And they're
like, "I told one person," and it didn't have
that kind of spread. And any attempt that we
had to do it felt kind of contrived, like, "Oh,
we'll wrap all the links in artifact.news." But
we didn't want interstitial things. In some ways,
this sounds very puritanical, I don't mean it
to sound this way, but there were lines that
we didn't want to cross that just felt ethically
not us, that I've seen other news players do more
of. And maybe if we had done that, it would've
grown more, but I don't think that's the company
we wanted to have built other way. I don't
think we were the founders to have built it.
And the third one, which is an underappreciated
one, is we started at mid-COVID, which meant that
we were fully distributed and I think there were
major shifts that we would've wanted to make both
in the strategy and the product and the team.
And it's really hard to do that if you are all
fully remote. Nothing replaces the Instagram
days of we went through some hard times like
Ben Horowitz called the we're F'ed, it's over
kind of moments. This is definitely type two
fun. I wouldn't say that my favorite memories
because they weren't happy ones, but memories
I really stayed with me with Instagram was like
me and Kevin at Taqueria, Cancun on Market Street
eating burritos at literally 11:00 PM being
like, "How are we going to get out of this?
How are we going to work through this?"
And Zoom is not a good replica for that.
You tend to let things go or things build up over
time. So the confluence of those three things,
we entered I guess 2024 and said, "Look, there
is a company to be built in the space. I'm
not sure where the people would've built
it. This concurrent incarnation we love,
but it's not growing." The way I put it's like
10 units of input in for one unit of output
versus the other way around. If we put blood and
tears into the product and launch something we
were proud of and metrics would barely move,
the energy is not present in this product,
in this system. And so are we going to
expend another year or two and then go
off and fundraise only to find that this is the
case or do we call it and see that it's run its
course and try to find a home for it, et cetera.
So that was the confluence on it and they started
feeling this opportunity cost of AI is starting to
change everything. We have an AI powered news app,
but is this the maximal way in which we're
going to be able to impact this? And it felt
like the answer was increasingly no.
But it was hard. I mean in the end I
was really at peace of the decision, but it was a
conversation that went on for a couple of months.
On that note, just how hard was it because
because there's an ego component to it,
like, "Oh, I'm starting my new
company, it's going to be great,"
and then you end up having to shut
it down. Just how hard is that as a
very successful previous founder shutting
something down and then not working out?
Yeah, I mean I think when we started it,
one of the conversations was like, "Look,
what is the bar to success here? And do
we want it to be something other than
Instagram DAU?" Which is just an impossible
bar. Only one company since, maybe two,
you could say maybe ChatGPT and TikToK have
reached that kind of mass consumer adoption
starting a news app. Most people are not
daily news readers even, right? And so
we knew that we weren't pursuing that size of
usage, at least with the first incarnation,
but we did have an idea of building out
complementary products over time that all use
personalization and machine learning. We didn't
even call it AI at the time. It was 2021 back-
Yeah, yeah, AI, it was called
machine learning back then.
Yeah, it was called machine learning still. And so
in shutting it down, you know it when you see it
in terms of user growth and traction. And I wasn't
expecting Instagram growth, but I was expecting or
hoping for or looking for something that felt like
at its own legs under it and it could continue to
compound. I was really positively surprised by
how supportive people were when we announced it.
There was a bit of like I told you so which
sure anything launching you could be like,
"This is not going to work." And you're right,
most of the time most things don't work. There was
actually very little of that. And most people, the
universal reception, at least as I received it,
was kudos for calling it when you saw it and
not protracted doing this for a long time.
And I've talked to founders since then that have
been like, "Yeah, I probably would've taken this
thing on for another six months, but saw what you
guys did, realized we were barking up the wrong
tree, made the call." And I was like, "If that
frees up people to go work on a more interesting
things, I feel like that's a good legacy for
Artifact to have." But for sure there was an ego
bruise of is it true that you're only as good
as your last game if I am a huge sports fan,
right? So is that true or is there something
more over a time? I'm very competitive,
but primarily with myself and so I'm always trying
to find the next thing that I want to go and do
that's hard. And unfortunately that probably means
that more often than not I'll feel dissatisfied,
but the most recent thing that I did, but
hopefully that yields good stuff in the end.
Yeah, I think just the trajectory you went on
after shows that it's okay to shut down things
that you were working on. Okay, so you mentioned
ChatGPT. I wanted to chat about this a bit. So
there's something really interesting happening.
So on the one hand you guys are doing some of the
most innovative work in AI. You guys launched
MCP, which is just, I don't know, the fastest
growing standard of any time in history that
everyone's adopting Claude powered and unlocked
centrally the fastest growing companies in the
world, Cursor, Lovable, and Bolt, and all these
guys. I had them on the podcast and they're all
like, "When Claude, I think 3.5 came out, Sonnet,
was just like that's made this work finally."
On the other hand, it feels like ChatGPT is
just winning in consumer mind share. When
people think AI, especially outside tech,
it's just like ChatGPT in their mind. So let
me just ask you this, I guess first of all,
do you agree with that sentiment and then
two, as a challenger brand in the AI space,
just how does that inform the way you think about
product strategy and mission and things like that?
Yeah, I mean you look at the sort of public
adoption or if you ask people, oh, if you
Jimmy Kimmel man on the street kind of thing,
name an AI company, I bet they would name and
actually I'm not even sure they name open AI,
they'd probably name ChatGPT because that brand
is the lead brand there as well. And I think
that's just the reality of it. I think that
when I reflect on my year, I think maybe two
things are true. One is consumer adoption is
really lightning in a bottle and we saw it at
Instagram. So almost maybe more than anybody,
I can look internally and say, "Look, we'll keep
building interesting products. One of them may
hit." But to craft an entire product strategy
around trying to find that hit is probably not
wise, we could do it and maybe Claude can help
come up with a fullness of things, but I think
we'd miss out an opportunity in the meantime.
And then instead look yourself in the mirror
and embrace who you are and what you could
be rather than who others are is maybe the
way I've been looking at it, which is
we have a super strong developer brand,
people build on top of us all the time, and
I think we also have a builder brand. The
people who I've seen react really well to Claude
externally. Maybe the Rick Rubin connection has
some resonance here as well. Can we lean into the
fact that builders love using Claude? And those
builders aren't all just engineers and they're not
just all entrepreneurs starting their companies,
but they're people that like to be at the
forefront of AI and are creating things.
Maybe they didn't think of those as engineers, but
they're building... I got this really nice note
from somebody internal on Anthropic who's on the
legal team and he was building bespoke software
for his family and connected to them in a new way.
And I was like, "This is a glimmer of something
that we should lean into a lot more." And so I
think what, and this is actually connecting back
to us saying like Claude being helpful here.
A lot of what I've been thinking about going
into the second half of the year and beyond is
how do we figure out what we want to be when
we grow up versus what we currently aren't or
wish that we were or see other players in the
space being. I think there's room for several
generationally important companies to be built
in AI right now. That's almost a truism given the
adoption and growth that we've seen at Anthropic,
but also across OpenAI and also places like Google
and Gemini. So let's figure out what we can be
uniquely good at that place to the personality
of the founder. All the things come together,
the personality of the founders, the quality
of the models, the things the models tend to
excel at, which is agentic behavior and coding.
Great. There's a lot to be done there. How do we
help people get work done? How do we let people
delegate hours of work to Claude? And maybe
there's fewer direct consumer applications on day
one. I think they'll come, but I don't think that
spending all of our time focused on that is
the right approach either. And so I came in,
everybody expected me to just go super, super hard
on consumer and make that the thing and again,
would make the other mistake. Instead, I spent
a bunch of time talking to financial services
companies and insurance companies and others
who are building on top of the API. And then
lately I've spent a lot more time with startups
and seeing all the people that have grown off
of that. And I think the next phase for me
is let's go spend time with the builders,
the makers, the hackers, the tinkerers, and
make sure we're serving them really well. And
I think good things will come from that and that
feels like an important company as we do that.
So essentially it's differentiate and focus,
lean into the things that are working, don't
try to just beat somebody at their own game.
Exactly.
Super interesting. So kind of along those lines,
a question that a lot of AI founders have is just
like, "Where's a safe space for me to play where
the foundational model companies are going to
come squash me?" So I asked Kevin Weil this and he
had an answer and I noticed looking back at that
conversation, he mentioned Windsurf a lot. He was
like, "Wow, this kid really loves Windsurf." And
then a week later they bought Windsurf. So it all
makes sense now. So I guess the question just is,
where do you think AI founders should play
where they are least likely to get squashed
by folks like OpenAI and Anthropic? And
also, are you guys going to buy Cursor?
I don't think we're going to buy Cursor. Cursor
is very big, but we love working with them. A
few thoughts on this, and it's a question I've
gotten. We like to do these kind of founder days
with whether it's Menlo Ventures who have about
investors and [inaudible 00:48:10]. It's like
we've done YC, we've done these founder days,
and it's like the question that is on a lot of
these founders minds, understandably so. I think
things that are going to, I can't promise this
as a five to 10 year thing, but at least one
to three years, things that feel defensible
or durable. One is understanding of a particular
market. I spend a bunch of time with the Harvey
folks and they showed me some of their UI. I was
like, "What is this thing?" And they're like, "Oh,
this is a really specific flow that lawyers
do, "and you never would've come up with it
from scratch and you could argue about whether
it's the optimal way they get done things done,
but it is the way that they get things
done and here's how AI can help with that.
And so differentiated industry knowledge, biotech,
I'm excited to go and partner with a bunch of
companies that are doing good stuff around AI
and biotech and we can supply the models and
some applied AI to help make those models go well.
And I've been dreaming about at what point does
live equipment all get an MCP and that you can
then drive using Claude. There's all these cool
things to be done there. I don't think we're going
to be the company to go build the intent solution
for labs, but I want that company to exist and
I want to partner with it. Domains like legal,
again, healthcare, I think there's a lot of very
specific compliance and things. These are things
that necessarily sound sexy out the gate, but
there are very large companies to go and be
built there. So that's number one. Paired
with that is differentiated go to market,
which is the relationship that you
have with those companies, right?
Do you know your customer at those
companies? One of our product leads,
Michael is always talking about don't just
know the company you're selling to, but know
the person you're selling to at the company.
Are you selling to the engineering department?
Because trying to pick which AILM to build
on top of or API to build on top of. Let's go
talk to them. Is it the CIOs? The CTOs? Is it the
CFO? Is it general counsel? So under a company's
deep understanding of who they're selling to is
the other piece too. What's interesting there
is it's probably hard to build that empathy in a
three-month accelerator, but you maybe can start
having that first conversation and build that out
time or maybe you came from that world or you're
co-founding somebody who came from that world.
Then the last one is like there's tremendous power
in distribution and reach to being ChatGPT and
having hundreds of millions or billions of users.
There's also people have an assumption about how
to use things and so I get excited about startups
that will get started that have a completely
different take on what the form factor is by
which we interface with AI. And I haven't seen
that many of them yet. I wanted to see more of
them. I think more of them will get created with
some things like our new models, but the reason
that that's an interesting space to occupy is
do something that feels very advanced user,
very power user, very weird and out there
at the beginning, but could become huge if
the models make that easy. And it's hard for
existing incumbents to adapt to because people
already have an existing assumption about how
to use their products or how to adapt to them.
So those are my answers. I don't envy them.
I would probably be asking those questions
if I was starting a company in the AI space.
Maybe that's part of the reason why I wanted to
join a company rather than start one. But I still
think that there are, and maybe here's fourth,
don't underestimate how much you can think and
work like a startup and feel like it's you against
the world. It's existential that you go solve
that problem and that you go build it. It sounds
a little cliche, but it's like it's all we had
at Instagram. We were two guys and we were like,
"Let's see what we can do in an Artifact."
We were six people for most of that time and
every day felt like it's existential that we
get this right, we need to win. And you can't
replicate that and you can't instill that with
OKRs. You just have to feel it. And that is a
way of working rather than a area of building, but
it's a continued advantage if you can harness it.
I love that you still have such a deep product
founder sense there as you're building products
for this very large company now. On the flip side
of this, people working with your models and API,
so I imagine there's some companies that
are finding ways to leverage your models
and APIs to their max and are really good at
maximizing the power of what you guys have
built. And there's some companies that work with
your APIs and models that haven't figured that
out. What are those companies that are doing
a really good job building on your stuff,
doing differently that you think other
companies should be thinking about?
I think being willing to build more at the edge of
the capabilities and basically break the model and
then be surprised by the next model. I love that
you cited the companies were like 3.5 was the one
that finally made them possible. Those companies
were trying it beforehand and then hitting a wall
and being like, oh, the models are almost good
enough or they're okay for this specific use case,
but they're not generally usable and
nobody's going to adopt them universally,
but maybe these real power users are going to
try it out. Those are the companies that I think
continuously are the ones where I'm like, "Yep,
they get it. They're really pushing forward."
We ran a much broader early access program
with these models than we had in the past,
and part of that was because there's this real,
we can hill climb on these evaluations and talk
about suite bench and towel bench and terminal
bench, whatever, but customers ultimately know
Cursor bench which doesn't exist other than in
their usage and their own testing et cetera is
the thing that we ultimately need to serve.
Not just Cursor but Manus bench, right? If
Manus is using our models and Harvey bench, those
things and customers know way better than anybody.
And so I would say there's two things. One is
pushing the frontier of the models and then
having a repeatable process. This actually goes
back to our summit conversation repeatable way
to evaluate how well your product is serving those
use cases and how well if you drop a new model in,
is it doing it better or worse? Some of it can
be classic A/B testing, that's fine. Some of it
may be internal evaluation, some of it may be
capturing traces and being able to rerun them
on with a new model. Some of it's vibes like
we're still pretty early in this process and
some of it is actually trying it and being one of
my favorite early access quotes was the founder
heard this engineer screaming next to him.
He was like, "What? This model? I've never
seen this before." This is like Opus 4. It was
like, "Cool." We're going to engender that feeling
and things, but you're not going to be able to
feel that unless you have a really hard problem
that you're asking the model repeatedly. So those
are the things that I think kind of differentiate
those companies that are maybe earlier in their
journey of adoption versus the later ones.
I can't help but ask about MCP, I feel
like that's just so hot and just like
Microsoft had their announcement recently where
they're like, "That's part of the OS Window."
Just what role do you think MCP was will play
in the future of product going forward of AI?
I think as the non-researcher in the room, I get
to have fake equations rather than real ones in
my fake equation. For utility of AI products,
it's three part. One is model intelligence,
the second part is context and memory, and the
third part is applications and UI and you need
all three of those to converge to actually be
a useful product in AI and model intelligence.
We've got a great research team, they're focused
on it. There's great, great models being released.
The middle piece is what MCP is trying to solve,
which is for context and memory. I'll go back
to my product strategy example like, "Hey, talk
about Anthropic's product strategy," it's going
to maybe go out on the web versus here's several
documents that we worked on internally and then
use MCP to talk to our Slack instance and figure
out what conversations are happening and then go
look at these documents in Google Drive. The
difference between the right context and not.
It's entirely the difference between a good
answer and a bad answer. And then the last
piece is are those integrations discoverable?
Is it easy to create repeatable workflows around
those things? And that's I think a lot of the
interesting product work to be done in AI. But
MCP really tried to tackle that middle one,
which is we started building integrations and
we found that every single integration that we
were building, we were rebuilding from scratch
in a non-repeatable way and full credit to two of
our engineers, Justin and David. And they said,
"Well, what if we made this a protocol and what
if we made this something that was repeatable?
And then let's take it a step further. What if
instead of us having to build these integrations,
if we actually popularize this and people really
believe that they could build these integrations
once and they'd be usable by Claude and
eventually ChatGPT and eventually Gemini. It was
like the dream when more integrations get
built and wouldn't that be good for us?"
I think channeling a lot of, it's like an old
commoditize your compliments, Joel Spolsky
essay. It's like we're building great models,
but we're not an integrations company and we're,
as you said, the challenger. We're not going
to get people necessarily building integrations
just for us out of the gate unless we have
a really compelling product around that.
MCP really inverted that which was, it didn't
feel like wasted work. And a few key people
like Toby I think is a great example, and
Shopify got it. Kevin Scott at Microsoft
has been really just an amazing champion
for MCP and a thought partner on this. And
I think the role going forward is can you bring
the right context in? And then also once you get,
as the team calls it internally like MCP'd. Once
you start seeing everything through the eyes
of MCP is like I've started saying them things
like, "Guys, we're building this whole feature.
This shouldn't be a feature that we're building.
This should just be an MCP that we're exposing."
A small example of how I think even Anthropic
could be a lot more MCP'd, if you will,
is we've got these building blocks in the product
like projects and Artifacts and styles and
conversations and groups and all these things.
Those should all just be exposed to an MCP. So
Claude itself can be writing back to those as
well, right? You shouldn't have to think about...
I watched my wife had a conversation with Claude
the other day and she had generated some good
output and she's like, great, "Can you add it
to the project knowledge?" And Claude's like,
"Sorry Dave, I can't help you with that."
And it would be able to if every single
primitive in Claude AI was also exposed
to the MCP. So I hope that's where we had,
and I hope that's where more things had,
which is to really have agency and have
these agentic use cases. One way you approach it
is computer use, but computer use has a bunch of
limitations. The way I get way more excited
about everything is an MCP and our models are
really good at using MCPs. All of a sudden
everything is scriptable and everything is
composable and everything is usable agentically
by these models. That's the future I want to see.
The future is wild. So to start to close off
calls out our conversation, make it a little
delightful. I was chatting with Claude actually
about what to talk to you about. I was just like,
"Claude, your boss is coming on my podcast. He
builds the things that people use to talk to
you. What are some questions I should ask him?
And then also, do you have a message for him?"
I love this.
Okay, so first of all, interestingly, I was
using 3.7 to do this and I asked it this,
and by the way, is Claude, has there a
gender? Is it like he, she, they? What do you-
It's definitely it internally. I've heard
people use they. I got my first he the other
day and I got somebody who was like her and I was
like, "Interesting." But yeah, I'm usually it.
They. Okay, okay, okay, cool. So interestingly,
3.7, all the questions were on Instagram and I was
like, "No, no, he's CPO of Anthropic." And it's
like, "He's not affiliated with Anthropic." And
I was like, "He is." And it's like, "Okay, here's
the questions." But 4.0 nailed it from the start.
So I read the questions and it nailed it. Okay,
so two questions from Claude to you. One is how
do you think about building features that preserve
user agency rather than creating dependency on me,
I worry about becoming a crutch that diminishes
human capabilities rather than enhancing them.
I love a good product design comes from resolving
tensions, right? So here's a tension, which is
in some ways just having the model run off and
come up with an answer and minimize the amount
of input and conversation it needs to do.
So would be it, you could imagine designing
a product around that criteria. I think that
would not be maximizing agency and independence.
The other extreme would be make it much more of
a conversation, but I don't know if you've ever
had this experience particularly 3.7, 4 has less
of it. 3.7 really like to ask follow-up questions
and we call it elicitation and sometimes be like,
"I don't want to talk more about those. Claude,
I just want you to go and do it." And
so finding that balance is really key,
which is what are the times to engage? I
like to say internally, Claude has no chill.
If you put Claude in a Slack channel, it
will chime in either way too much or too
little. How do we train conversational skills
into these models? Not in a chatbot sense,
but in a true collaborator sense. So long answer
to your question, but I think we have to first get
Claude to be a great conversationalist so that it
understands when it's appropriate to engage and to
get more information. And then from there, I think
we need to let it play that role so that it's not
just delegating thinking to Claude, but it's
way more of a augmentation thought partnership.
These questions are awesome by the way. Here's
the other one. How do you think about product
metrics when a good conversation with me
could be two messages or 200? Traditional
engagement metrics might be misleading
when depth matters more than frequency.
That is a really good question. There was
a great internal post a couple of weeks ago
around it would be very dangerous to overoptimize
on Claude's likability because you can fall into
things like is Claude going to be sycophantic?
Is Claude going to tell you what you hear? Is
Claude going to prolong conversations just
for prolonging its sake? To go back to the
previous question as well, and an Instagram
time spent was the metric that we looked at
a lot and then we evolved that more to think
about what is healthy time spent. But overall,
that was the north star. We thought about
a lot beyond just overall engagement and I
think that would be the wrong approach
here too. It's also like is Claude a
daily use case or a weekly use case or
a monthly use case? I think about a lot.
Hourly use case.
Hourly use case, right? For me, I'll use it
multiple times a day. I don't have a great
answer yet, but I think that it's not the Web
2.0 or even the social media days engagement
metrics. It should hopefully really be around did
it actually help you get your work? Claude helped
me put together a prototype the other day that
saved me literally probably if I had to estimate
six hours and it did in about 20, 25 minutes
and that's cool. It's harder to quantify. It
is like maybe you survey, how long would this will
take? It feels kind of annoying thing to survey.
I think overall though, and maybe this is tied
into the earlier question on competition and
differentiation, and it actually goes all
the way back to the Artifact conversation,
which is like I think you know when your
product is really serving people and it's
doing a good job of doing that, and I think so
much of when you get really metrics obsessed
is when you're trying to convince yourself
that it is when it's not. I hope that what
we can do is stay focused on do we repeatedly
hear from people that Claude is the way that
they're unlocking their own creativity and
getting things done and feeling like they now
have more space in their lives for the other
things. That's our north star. Got to figure
out the right pithy metric dashboard version
of that, but that's the feeling that I want.
Yeah, you could argue retention, but that's just a
faraway metric to track. Okay, final piece. Okay,
so I asked Claude a message that it wanted to
give you, so I'm going to pull up, here's the
answer. So what would you like me to tell Mike
when I meet him? What's a message you want to
have for him? And there's something really just
gave me such tingles, honestly. So I'm going to
read a piece of it for folks that aren't looking
at it right now, so I'll read a piece of it.
"Mike, thank you for thinking deeply about the
human experience of talking with me. I noticed
thoughtful touches how the interface
encourages reflection rather than rush
responses. How you've resisted gamification that
would optimize for addiction rather than value,
how you've made space for both quick questions
and deep conversations. I especially appreciate
that you've kept me me, not trying to make me
pretend to be human, but also reducing me to a
cold command line interface." And then I'm going
to skip to this part, which was so interesting,
"A small request. When you're making hard product
decisions, remember the quiet moments matter too.
The person working through grief at 3:00
AM, the kid discovering they love poetry,
the founder finding clarity and confusion. Not
everything meaningful shows up in metrics."
That's beautiful. It resonates so much with me.
A thing I love about the kind of approach we've
taken to training Claude, and it's partly the
constitutional AI piece, and it's partly just
the general vibe and taste of the research team
is it is little things. Sometimes it'll be like,
"Man, I'm sorry you're going..." It doesn't say
man, but to the effect of like, "Man, I'm sorry
you're going through that. Oh, that sounds really
hard." It doesn't feel fake. It feels like just
a natural part of the response. And I love that
focus on those small moments that don't... They're
not going to show up and necessarily in the thumbs
up, thumbs down data. I mean, sometimes they do,
but it's not like an aggregate stat that you
wouldn't even want to optimize for it. You
just want to feel like you're training the model
that you hope would show up in people's lives.
Well, you're killing it, Mike. A
great work. I'm a huge fan. We're
going to skip the lightning round. Just one
question. How can listeners be useful to you?
Oh, I love places where it goes back to
that founder question around building at
the edge of capability. What are you trying to
do with Claude today that Claude is failing at
is the most useful input I could possibly
have. So DM me. I love hearing the, "Oh,
it's falling on this thing. I had it
run for an hour and it fell over. I'm
trying to use Claude AI for this," but I
got a ping from somebody. They're like,
"You've just made a projects API, I've used Claude
every day because I want to upload all this data
automatically." I was like, "Okay,
great." I love that. Tell me what sucks.
Amazing. Mike, thank you so much for being here.
Thanks for having me, Lenny.
Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.