I often see operators who explain
things poorly and then are shocked
and horrified when people are confused or
there's skepticism, there's apathy. I'm a
big proponent of asking myself, if I'm not
getting the reaction that I'm looking for,
how might I be contributing? How could I
explain this more clearly? How can I be
more compelling? How can I anticipate
any questions that they might have?
You are one of the best teachers of
communication I've ever come across.
I made a list of people's favorite tactics
and frameworks and approaches that you teach
in writing. Any tactics you can share
for someone to be a little more concise?
I think the blast radius of a poorly written
memo is way bigger than most people think.
If you are just shooting off a message in a Slack
channel with 15 other people, and it's confusing,
you didn't include information you should have
included, there's going to be a bunch of back and
forth. Whereas if you had just taken another look
at it, those 15 people would be off to the races.
You have an awesome framework called MOO.
MOO stands for Most Obvious Objection. A lot
of times we're surprised by the questions
that we get especially in meetings,
we feel blindsided. When really,
if you thought for even two minutes about what
are obvious objections that I'm likely to get,
you often immediately come up with what some of
those things are. Are you going to be able to
anticipate every single objection? No. But can
you anticipate the obvious ones? Absolutely.
Today my guest is Wes Kao. Wes co-created the
Alt-MBA program with Seth Godin. She Co-Founded
a company called Maven, which I often collaborate
with, which makes it easy for people to host live
cohort-based courses. She recently left Maven to
launch her own course on Executive Communication
and Influence. There's a quote that came to mind
after I stopped recording this conversation with
Wes by George Bernard Shaw, "The single
biggest problem in communication is the
illusion that it has taken place."
By the end of this podcast if you listen
to what Wes suggests, you'll be a lot closer to
becoming a world-class communicator. If you enjoy
this podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow
it in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube.
Also, if you become a yearly subscriber of my
newsletter, you get a year free of Perplexity Pro,
Superhuman, Notion, Linear and Granola.
Check it out at lennysnewsletter.com.
With that, I bring you Wes Kao.
This episode is brought to you by WorkOS.
If you're building a SaaS app, at some point
your customers will start asking for enterprise
features like SAML authentication and SCIM
provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in, making
it fast and painless to add enterprise features
to your app. Their APIs are easy to understand so
that you can ship quickly and get back to building
other features. Today, hundreds of companies are
already powered by WorkOS, including ones you
probably know like Vercel, Webflow, and Loom.
WorkOS also recently acquired Warrant, the Fine
Grained Authorization Service. Warrant's product
is based on a groundbreaking authorization system
called Zanzibar, which was originally designed for
Google to power Google Docs and YouTube. This
enables fast authorization checks at enormous
scale while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases. If
you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features
like single sign-on, SCIM or user management,
you should consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in
replacement for Auth0 and supports up to 1 million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
workos.com to learn more. That's workos.com.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta. When
it comes to ensuring your company has top-notch
security practices, things get complicated fast.
Now you can assess risk, secure the trust of your
customers, and automate compliance for SOC 2,
ISO 27001, HIPAA and more with a single platform,
Vanta. Vanta's market-leading trust management
platform helps you continuously monitor compliance
alongside reporting and tracking risks. Plus,
you can save hours by completing security
questionnaires with Vanta AI. Join thousands
of global companies that use Vanta to automate
evidence collection, unify risk management,
and streamline security reviews. Get $1,000
off Vanta when you go to vanta.com/lenny.
That's V-A-N-T-A.com/lenny. Wes, thank you so much
for being here and welcome back to the podcast.
Thanks, Lenny. I'm very honored
to be a second-time guest.
Very rare honor. No pressure, but
I think this is going to be one of
the highest leverage episodes I've done and
let me tell you why I think that's the case
in the newsletter and on the podcast, I often talk
about just how important and how high leverage the
skill of communication is to product leaders,
to leaders, just to people in general. There's
this quote that Boz, the CTO of Meta, he's been
on the podcast, he wrote this famous blog post,
"Communication is the job." And I think
that's true for product people, but it's
true for basically any sort of leadership role.
Anyone trying to get ahead. And you are one of
the best communicators I've ever met. You are one
of the best teachers of communication I've ever
come across. You have one of the most popular
courses on Maven, on executive communication,
so I'm really excited to have you here and
to help people become better communicators,
better at influence and all these things.
So thank you again for being here.
Absolutely.
Okay. So something that I often
do with guests on the podcast,
not even often, always, I ping people that
the guests have worked with and ask them,
"What should I ask Wes? What should I
know about Wes?" Let me read a few quotes
about you in regards to your communication
skills from folks that have worked with you-
All right.
And these are three different people.
Okay, so first, "Wes single handedly
raised the quality of the entire company's
writing by like two X across the board. I
always say the best writing course I ever
took was working with Wes for a year."
Wow.
Okay. That's one.
Great.
"Wes never just throws things out there,
she's precise with her use of language,
meticulous about examining her own ideas
before bringing them in front of others
and knows how to make her points in a way that
people will understand them and buy into them."
Okay. And third, "Wes includes a reasoning with
every proposal in the context behind all of her
recommendations so that everyone around
her learns in order of magnitude faster.
This also makes her an exceptional teacher because
she can clearly define what excellence is and why
something is the goal, and then break down the
steps and principles involved." Okay, reactions.
Those are really nice things. That's
amazing. Yeah, thank you so much.
And these are people across
different companies, so.
Cool.
Okay, so that was just to highlight of how
good you are at this stuff. And what we're
going to be doing with our chat is going through
a bunch of your tactics that you teach and that
have helped people become better communicators,
executive communicators, better at influence.
Before we get into the specific tactics, is
there anything that you think is important
for people to understand just broadly around
the skill of becoming a better communicator?
I often see operators who explain things poorly
and then are shocked and horrified when people
are confused or there's skepticism, there's
apathy, there's a lot of avoidable questions,
and I'm a big proponent of asking myself, "If I'm
not getting the reaction that I'm looking for,
how might I be contributing to that?" So,
you know, instead of blaming other people
for not understanding me, I think about how
could I explain this more clearly? How can I
be more compelling? How can I anticipate
any questions that they might have? So
I'm a big proponent of agency. And realizing
that we can only control our own behavior. And
so the best place to start, if you're not
getting the reaction you're looking for,
is reflecting on how can I get better at the skill
of communicating? And it absolutely is a skill.
So what I'm hearing is if you're having a
hard time people buying into what you're
trying to convince them to do or you're finding
people are doing not what you asked them to do,
it's likely an issue with your ability to
communicate, it's probably not their fault.
Yeah, I would say so. You can't
solve everything with improving
your communication, but you can increase
the likelihood of getting what you want.
Cool. Okay. Anything else along these
lines of just things that are important
to understand just broadly around
communication, executive communication?
I think another big one that I teach in my course
and really kick off with is practicing like it's
game day, playing like it's game day. So I see a
lot of operators who save their best behavior for
executives only. So you know, they want to shine
when they're presenting to senior leadership,
but with everyone else, they're kind of calling
it. And I just don't think that you're going to
be able to get enough reps to actually get good at
executive communication if you are only doing it
with executives. Because many of us only present
to execs once a month, right? Or a couple of times
a quarter. And that's just not a lot of chance
to practice. So really treating every single
stakeholder as if they are important because they
are, and you shouldn't be if you don't want to
waste your CEO's time, you also shouldn't waste
your cross-functional team members' time or your
manager's time or your direct reports' time. So
that's something else that I ask to keep in mind.
And maybe a last question before we get into
the tactics. When people think communication,
they think email, they think meeting
presentations, things like that. How
do you think about, when you talk
about executive communication and
communication in general, what's kind
of the umbrella of things that includes?
Yeah, I would say broadly the two mediums
are verbal communication and written.
So verbal being meetings, conversations,
presentations. And written being emails,
strategy docs, notion docs, Slack messages, text
messages, those two categories broadly. And I also
think about communication as more of a means to
an end, which might be interesting for some people
because I teach a course on communication. So you
would think that's like the end in and of itself,
but I really see it as a means to an end where the
end is getting the ideal outcome you're looking
for. So whether that is buy-in or making a good
decision as a team or moving to the next step,
whatever that might be, communication
is really in service of that end goal.
Awesome. Okay. So I made a list of people's
favorite tactics and frameworks and approaches
that you teach, and talking to folks that you've
taught and folks that you've worked with. So I'm
just going to go through a bunch and let's
just help people get better at these things.
All right, let's do it.
Okay. So the first is something you call
sales, then logistics. What is that about?
Yes. So a common mistake that I see is
overestimating the amount of buy-in that
you have from your audience. So that looks like
jumping straight into talking about the logistics,
the details of the how to do something, of the
process. When in reality your audience has not
yet decided if they even want to do the thing.
So what I see operators do in response then is
go even deeper into the logistics and the how,
thinking that, "Oh, if I just explain this more
than that person will want to do it." When really
a sales note is different than a logistics note.
A sales note is meant to get people excited to
do the thing you want them to do, and to agree
to do it. And only then after they have bought
in, does it make sense to share the logistics.
So there's an order of operations here.
If you switch the order of operations,
you will likely get a slow response or just no
response, right? We've all put a Slack message
in a channel and got crickets and tumbleweed.
So really starting off with selling the person
and making sure that they know why we're doing
this, why this matters to the company, why now,
and then sharing the logistics
tends to be a lot more effective.
Is there an example of that that might help
illustrate that point or that approach?
Yeah. So one of my clients is a head of
operations and she was trying to get the
rest of her executive team, which she was a
part of, to fill in some wins for the week so
that they could share this out with the whole
company. And this was going to be motivating,
it was going to shine a light on folks. And she
led with the logistics of which document to send,
to put the details in, what time to put it
in by, the format that you should put these
wins and didn't really get much of a response
from the leadership team, which makes sense,
right? Because this totally sounds like
one of those things that's another item
to check off on your list when you already
have so many other things to do and here's
this other process that like we're all
supposed to do now, like yay, right?
And so she wasn't really getting response. And
that's because she dove straight into logistics.
Whereas what she could have done is start by
selling folks, selling the other executives
on why are we doing this? Well, we're doing this
because this is a chance to shine a light on your
team members who are doing amazing work, for them
to feel motivated and to feel like the rest of the
company really sees them and understands what
they're doing. And this is all something that
is going to motivate your team, right? So sharing
why this is helpful and useful and how this is in
service of you and your team versus like,
"Oh, this is a favor that you're doing for
me to fill out this form and fill it out this
way and by this date," et cetera, et cetera.
I know that execs often want the opposite
where they're just like, "Okay, I know,
just tell me what you want to do. Just like,
okay, just get to the point. I don't want time
for all this context and background."
Any advice on when to spend any time
on the sales? Like what are signs that,
okay, maybe you don't have them sold yet,
or what are maybe contexts where you should
probably still try to sell them first?
Yeah. So I actually think that you should always
do a little bit of selling even for situations
where people have generally bought in. Because
most of us have a lot going on and we're not
actively thinking about whatever you're talking
about. So even though I agreed to something two
weeks ago, by the time you're telling me about
it again, like I thought about a billion other
things since then, right? So reminding me of
why are we talking about this? Why does this
matter? And then getting into it and framing
that conversation upfront is way more likely
for us to not get stuck in a cold start and
not kind of go two steps back one step forward.
The other thing is, you can frame a conversation
and sell a bit at the beginning very concisely.
So I'm not talking about spending 15 minutes out
of a 30 minute meeting selling, I'm talking about
one to two minutes, even a couple sentences,
and then transitioning into the main thing you
want to talk about. So I'm a huge proponent
of doing that and basically reminding people,
why are we doing this? Why are we here today? Why
does this matter? And then getting into the meat.
I love that. So basically you can do this really
briefly, it doesn't have to be a whole pitch for
half an hour. It's just a reminder, "Here's why
we think this is important." And I think that's
such a good point because a lot of times it's
like a leader is looking at this thing you're
asking them to do and they're like, "Why are we
even, why am I spending time on this?" And just
a reminder of like, "Okay, I see, I forgot this
was going to be, this a part of our strategy,
this has this much impact potential or here's
how it could help our team be more efficient."
Yeah. And you can really
do that in like 30 seconds.
Is there like a, I don't know, structure to
this? Is it just like why? Is there a kind
of a template you like or some way you
recommend of selling first? Is it like,
"Here's why we're doing this." Starting
like that? Anything along those lines?
Yeah. I think explaining why we're doing
this, why this benefits the business,
what problem this is solving. Again, you can
do a lot of this in a couple of sentences. And
then I also like asking or stating what I need
from the other person upfront. So saying, "Hey,
we're here today because two weeks ago we were
reviewing the product flow and realized that
there were a couple of parts that were kind of
confusing. So I took a stab at fixing those areas,
rewriting the microcopy, and I
want to present them to you today,
see if you agree with these changes, and then
we're going to roll them out. What I'm looking
for from you is feedback on the changes and if
you agree." So like that was like 15 seconds,
right? Super fast. And then now we're all
on the same page about why we're here. And
you can listen more intently knowing that
I'm looking for a certain kind of feedback.
I would love to hear it that way. I think
there's like an implication here that maybe
is worth sharing of just, a lot of this is about
communicating effectively to execs, which will
make you communicate better to most people. But
especially with folks up the ladder. They don't
have a lot of time, they have a million things
in their head. Maybe just share like why this
is so important, like what the state of mind of a
leader is that you need to kind of break through.
Yeah. So I call it the yes, yes, yes, next,
next, next mindset where if I'm listening
to direct reports present something to
me, very often I find myself thinking,
"Got it. All right, yes, let's keep going."
Right? And you know, on the other side of that,
I've often presented to executives where
I had a 15 slide deck and execs would do
that and I'd be like, whoa, whoa, whoa. Like
I have a whole sequence, I have a whole order,
you know? And sometimes they would give
me buy or make the decision by slide four,
you know? And I'd be like, "Okay, well you know,
slide 13, I want to show you this great graph I
put together." Right? And what was really helpful
for me was realizing that I should take the win.
Okay, if five seconds already agreed,
take the win and keep it moving, move on.
Yeah. What's that quote like? "If
you've sold them, stop talking."
Right. Yes. Yeah, you might
talk them out of agreeing.
Yeah. Okay. You mentioned being concise. Let's
talk about that. You have some really good
advice on just how to effectively be concise
and not too concise. What's your advice there?
Yes. One of my pet peeves is when people are too
concise and they equate being concise with brief,
being brief. And being concise is not about
absolute word count, it's about economy of
words. It's about the density of the insight
that you're sharing. And so you can have a 300
word memo that's meandering and long-winded and
a thousand word memo that is tight and concise.
And so not equating concision with briefness
I think is a really big one to understand.
The second thing is a lot of advice about being
concise, I think misses an important point. So
we've all heard, "Don't bury the lead, cut to the
chase." Main point, put the main point at the top,
bottom line up front, right? And all of these
pithy aphorisms assume that you actually know
what your core point is. So you can't cut to
the chase unless you know what the chase is.
You can't unbury the lead unless you know
what the lead is. And so that I found is
the bottleneck to being concise. It's actually
not really being clear of what you are thinking,
that's what's leading to being long-winded.
And you can kind of test this theory because
most of us have a go-to story that we've told
a bunch of times, right? We're like, you know
exactly when people are going to laugh, you know
when they're going to gasp or hold their breath,
right? And why are you so good at telling that
story and why are you so concise about it? Because
you've told it a bunch of times, you know all
of the beats. So in meetings though, at work,
we are very rarely talking about the same thing
that many times it's always something new. It's
something that we are also probably likely
processing ourselves and are in the midst
of processing as we are in a quick turnaround
time, telling someone else about it, telling our
team about it. And so you are basically asking
your brain to do a lot of different processes,
especially in a real time conversation. You're
listening to the other person absorbing,
making sense of it, processing it, figuring
out what you think and how you would react.
And then trying to say something cohesive
that makes sense, right? And then trying to be
concise about it. So it's just a lot
of different processes. And so the
only solution I found consistently
to being concise is preparation.
It's not a very glamorous solution by any means,
but the clearer I am going into a meeting,
going into a conversation, going into a pitch,
the better I am at being concise and being able to
bring the conversation back to the most important
points at being able to stay flexible, but also
firm and preparation. I don't mean spending hours
and hours preparing for a weekly meeting, even a
couple of minutes really makes a huge difference.
Most of us are so back to back in meetings that
we're doing zero preparation. It's like the
meeting has started 30 seconds in and you're
still unwinding from the last Zoom call that
you were on, right? So most of us are in that
mental state. So if you even take 30 seconds
to one minute to ground yourself on why am
I in this meeting? What do I want to share and
make sure I get across in the time that we have,
you're going to go in there so much more
focused and so much more able to be concise.
So the advice there, so this is for meetings
and I want to talk about writing also,
but for meetings, the advice here
is before you get into a meeting,
actually think about why am I in this
meeting? What do I want to get out of
it? Instead of in the meeting figuring
out a lot as you go, which to your point,
you're just going to ramble and be like, "Oh,
okay, here's what I actually want to say."
Yeah. And what might I want to share in the
meeting too? You know, especially for more
introverted folks. Sometimes you need to decide
beforehand that you want to speak and you want to
make sure you get a certain point across. So even
deciding that beforehand makes a huge difference.
Yeah, I found this extremely powerful just
like five minutes before you get into a
meeting. And it could happen earlier
in the day, right? It doesn't have to
happen right before the meeting, or worst
case, it's right before the meeting. Just,
"Okay, what do I want to get out of this?
What am I here? What do I want to say?"
And just like giving your brain a little bit
of time to prepare. Super powerful. In writing,
is there like any tactics you can share
for someone to be a little more concise?
I think the main tactic is to remind yourself
to be concise. And usually when I do that,
I end up trimming 20% at least of what I wrote,
tightening up some sentences. I also ask myself,
how might I be adding cognitive load to whatever
it is that I'm saying? So is there a tighter,
clearer, cleaner way that I can ask what I'm
asking or present the information I'm presenting
or make the recommendation that I'm making? And
usually if you even ask yourself that, your brain
automatically comes up with stuff. You just see
whatever you wrote differently and you're like,
"Oh shit, I could trim this entire paragraph
because that's secondary." And maybe you have
your primary message in Slack, and then within
the thread add some of the secondary stuff,
right? So I find that most of us, it's reminding
yourself to be concise. And once you think of it,
your brain naturally will see
places where you can trim.
There's a layer of advice under this that you're
not saying that I'm going to say, which is
actually look at the thing you wrote at least once
before you share it. Because I used to be really
bad at this. I just like, "Okay, I don't have
time. I wrote this doc, send it, get feedback.
... really bad at this. I just like, "Okay, I
don't have time. We wrote this doc, send it,
get feedback. All right. Send this email.
I don't have time to read this email."
And I find just forcing yourself to
look at it solves so much of this.
Oh, yes, yes, definitely. I was assuming
before doing that, but you're right,
some people might not be. And yes, definitely
reading your own message first is huge. And
yeah, I find that even doing that you can
often spot a lot of low-hanging fruit.
Right. You'll find the typos and
grammar issues and you'll be like,
"Oh, I don't need this word." Along those lines,
let me share two books. People always ask me,
"How did you learn to write?" I'm like, "I'm
not a writer, I don't know what I'm doing."
But two books really helped me write more
effectively. And one is specifically to help
you write more concisely called On Writing
Well. I don't know if you've read that.
Yeah.
Okay. And it's basically chapter after chapter
of, "Here's what you can cut. And you can cut
more. And look what more you can cut and
cut this stuff." And he has screenshots of
essays that students have written in his class and
he's like, "Look at all those words you cut and
nothing has changed. It's exactly the same message
and even is better with 40% of the words cut."
Is this by Sol Stein or another author?
I don't have it... It's somewhere in
my bookshelf. So we'll look it up.
Yeah, there's a writing book by Sol Stein that
I absolutely love. And I feel like it might be
called On Writing Well, but then also I could see
there being multiple books called On Writing Well.
There's also Writing Well I think by Stephen
King, that's another one that people love,
but there On Writing Well is the one I
really loved because it's very tactical.
Going back to something that you were saying
earlier with rereading what you wrote,
I think the blast radius of a poorly written
memo is way bigger than most people think. So
if you're just shooting off a message in
a Slack channel with 15 other people and
it's confusing and you didn't include
information you should have included,
there's going to be a bunch of back and
forth. All 15 of these people are reading
this being like, "Okay, what do I do with this?"
Whereas if you had just taken another look at it,
those 15 people would be off to the races. They
would've read your message and then known exactly
what to do next or what their part was or what
you were looking for from them. So I think about
that a lot too. It's not just me writing this and
sending it off. It's, "Who are all the people who
are going to come in contact with this message
who are going to refer to it and use it? And if I
just take 30 more seconds to make sure that it's
clean, how much can I unblock from their work?"
That's such a good point. I like that, I love
that term blast radius. It's such a good point.
Just like there's so much negative leverage in
writing inefficiently and inconcisely. If you
spend like... Inconcisely? I don't know the
word is there, but if you just spend three
minutes spending a little more time making it more
clear just like the impact and leverage that has,
that's such a good point. I looked up the
books, it's so funny. Okay, so there's On
Writing Well by William Zinsser. There's Stein On
Writing by Sol Stein, which is what you said you
were talking about. And then Stephen King has a
book called On Writing. Everyone's got the same.
Yeah. Common title.
Not ideal for SEO but On Writing Well is
the one that I love by William Zinsser.
There's also one called A Series Of
Short Sentences if you haven't seen
that one. It's a really good rate too.
It's just how to write short sentences
and just the power of just keeping
sentences short, which I struggle with.
Yeah. Yeah, I like that.
Okay. Back to our agenda. There's
another framework/tactic that I've
heard you recommend. It's called
signposting. What is signposting?
Signposting is using certain words, phrases,
formatting, and an overall structure in
your writing that helps guide your reader and
signals what is coming in the rest of the post.
So, this is especially helpful if you have a long
memo. It adds structure to where are we going and
what certain sections of paragraphs are about.
So some of my favorite signposting words are,
"for example," shows that you're about to
show an example because shows that you're
about to share your logic and rationale behind
something. "As a next step," is a great one.
People's eyes automatically zoom to, "as a next
step." Even "First, second, third," kicking off
a paragraph with that, you're not needing to
rely on rich text formatting with bolding,
italics, underlines and all that craziness. If
you kick off sentences with signposting words,
you can often signal, "Here's what I'm
about to talk about in this paragraph."
These are power words for clarity. There's
this whole concept of power words like, "free."
Yeah. "A gift."
"Gift." Yeah. For copywriting and these are
basically power words for helping your brain
see the structure and get to the thing you want
to pay attention to. So I'll read back the words
you just used. "For example," " because," "as
a next step," and then, "first, second, third."
Yeah. Yeah. You can use signposting in writing and
verbally too. So if you're doing a product demo,
you might say something like, "The most important
part to pay attention to is, blank." Or, "The part
that we were most surprised by is, blank." Or,
"The part that customers are," et cetera. Right?
So it's, you're signaling that whatever comes
after this thing is something that you may
want to pay attention to. So it's a great way not
only to add structure, but to also grab people's
attention back if it has strayed some time as
they were either listening to you or reading.
Along those lines, I find I find formatting
really helpful here, just bold and bullets.
I know you have a pet peeve with too much
formatting. How much is too much formatting?
I really hate excessive formatting. So, I've seen
memos where 30% of the note was bolded. And that
just negates the entire point of bolding because
if everything is bolded then nothing is being
highlighted, right? So I think using formatting
in general more sparingly than you think you
have to is probably a good rule of thumb. I also
dislike when people overuse bullets and sentence
fragments, phrases in bullets when they should
use complete sentences that actually show the
connected tissue between ideas, that show the
logical flow of what it is that you're saying.
And it feels faster and more concise to put
bullets and fragments, but a lot of times
your reader on the other end of that is needing to
decipher and interpret and guess what you actually
meant. So it net, net takes longer. And I also
think that it can be a little bit of a crutch,
it can be a little bit lazy because
you are telling yourself that you're
being concise when really, if you had to turn
your sentence fragment into a full sentence,
a lot of times it actually is harder than you
think because you realize that you actually
didn't really know exactly what you meant. So as
you're trying to turn it into a full sentence,
you're actually needing to use brainpower.
So that's I think a great litmus test of,
"Was that idea fully thought
out?" Because if it was,
you should be able to really quickly turn
it into a complete sentence. And many times,
you actually aren't. So I see people like
basically think, "Oh, I want to make this
easier to read, more skimmable. I'm just
going to throw a bunch of formatting and
bullets and turn everything into bullets."
And it's not quite that easy of a solution.
This is very much along the lines of the
whole Amazon six-page memo where Jeff Bezos
just realized, "If you can't write it out as
a long memo and explain yourself in prose,
you don't actually know what you're saying."
And it's a really good filter for helping
people actually crystallize and know themselves,
"Okay, I see. I don't actually know what I'm
doing here." And I love this is a microcosm
of that. Can you just make a bullet point a
real sentence versus a fragment of a sentence?
I'm thinking about as a listener being like,
"Okay, how do I actually get better at this?" So
maybe let's take a tangent. I know that you teach
a whole course, you do all this stuff hands-on
with people to help them actually build these
skills. For someone that hasn't taken the course
or isn't taking it, what's a good way to start
practicing these skills and know if what you're
writing is getting better, is good. Is it find
a mentor, find someone that you think is a great
writer and have them review stuff? Any tips there?
Yeah. So I have a pretty first principles driven
approach for this, which is to think about how
long does it take me right now to get to the
reaction I'm looking for from my recipient? If
it takes a bunch of back and forth and a bunch of
friction, then that's my baseline. And once you
start practicing some of these communication
skills, how does that speed up? If you would
have had seven different touch points of back
and forth, does that shrink to two to three?
Not every point of friction is going to be
avoidable, but a lot of it is if you get
better at communicating. So I like watching
for the reaction and how quickly and how
enthusiastically I'm able to get that reaction.
And for the things that are working, do more of
that. For things that are not working, adjust
your execution because it might not be that the
tactic doesn't work, it might be your execution
of it wasn't great. And keep trying, basically.
So the advice here is just see how well
you're writing/meeting/suggestion goes,
how well it does. And if it's not like there's
the ideal immediately, "Yes, let's do it." And
then there's the, "I don't really understand."
There's the spectrum of response. And what I'm
hearing is just pay attention to if the speed to
getting what you want is increasing in general.
Yeah, yeah. I don't think that there's any
single shortcut on how to get better besides
that. I do think that being fascinated by a
topic and being excited about it makes it more
likely that you're going to find it fun to try all
these different things and try different ways to
get through to people. So, I would approach it
with a hypothesis-driven experimental mindset
and almost like a game. Like, "When I do this, how
does that other person react? If I frame it this
way, do I get a different reaction? When I try
this, am I able to cut through the noise more?"
Yeah. So I really think it's about practicing. And
I will say that the way not to do it is to try to
incorporate 30 different tactics at the same time
and then beat yourself up when you don't remember
to do them. It's really easy when you are learning
a new field or function to get overwhelmed when
you're learning a new skill. And the way to build
a habit is usually not changing so many different
things at once. It's picking one thing that
you want to try and keeping that top of mind,
trying it in a bunch of different settings
in different ways. And getting it better at
that thing before moving on to the next thing.
So that's like a really common thing I see in my
course is people feeling overwhelmed.
And I always remind folks that,
"You are building a new habit here. And be
patient with yourself, take it step by step."
There's a lot of stuff we're talking about here
that a lot of people might be like, "This is so
minor. What? I just bullet point sentences, be
a little... Tell them the why at the beginning."
And I just want to share in my experience the
biggest jump I made in my career was actually
getting better at these very specific skills. I
had this manager, Vlad, who's been on the podcast
and I talk about him regularly, who was such a
stickler about communicating well and being very
clear and concise and thinking and just spending
more time on documents and emails, on strategy
docs. Just like, "No, this isn't ready. Spend
more time, here's something that's not clear."
And just doing that was such an accelerant for me.
And it's all these little things. That's what's
interesting about it. It's like everything
seems really minor but it all adds up to a
lot of impact because to your point, people see
it, "Okay, cool, I get it, let's go." Versus like,
"I don't like this idea." And then it's like it
all falls apart. So I guess any reactions to that?
Yeah. All these little things compound and make
a big difference. I often hear people think,
"Well, this individual instance, this individual
email, the Slack message is not worth spending a
couple more minutes on. It's just an email
or it's just a Slack message." The problem
with that line of thinking is that no one
instance of something is ever going to feel
important enough to spend a little bit more
time on that. And then, but when you zoom out,
that's like, "Well that's all your work then.
This is literally everything you've touched.
This is all your work output then." because any
piece of that process you thought wasn't worth
spending time on and now this is just the quality
of your work and it's not as good as it could be.
So yes, these might seem minor
but A, it compounds. And also B,
all the "big things," everyone else is already
doing. So, there's not a lot of alpha in that.
Whereas if you are paying attention to skills that
people think are boring or too basic and realizing
that's a lever that you can pull, that someone
else thought, "Oh, we're hitting diminishing
returns on that. I'm not going to spend more
time on that." But you realize that there's
actually more juice left to squeeze there and you
decide to squeeze that juice. Well, now, you have
extra juice that the other person doesn't have.
So yeah, in my experience I find that people
claim the point of diminishing returns way too
early. And this isn't just for communication,
this is for strategies, tactics, et cetera.
They'll try something once, a mediocre
attempt and be like, "This channel doesn't
work. This tactic doesn't work." It's like,
"Really? Because it's working for a lot of other
people who are getting really creative with it."
I'm not saying that everything has to work
for you but for you to claim, "This thing just
doesn't work," feels a little bit intellectually
dishonest. It's more likely that your skill level,
your creativity, your execution ability was not
good enough. And that's fine. Let's admit that to
ourselves because if we admit that, then we can do
the hard work of getting better at those things.
It feels like if you really boil
this down, all the advice comes
down to just spend a little more time
on all these things you're putting out.
I like thinking about it as a little bit more
upfront investment. And it is an investment.
It's not just time. It's an investment because
yes, it takes a little bit longer to make a
Slack message a little bit better, but net,
net if you save a bunch of questions and
back and forth and people asking you things
that you don't think they should be asking,
then by investing a little bit of upfront effort,
you've prevented all that from happening. So yeah,
it is a little bit more time in the moment
but reaps a lot of benefits down the line.
Today's episode is brought to you by Coda. I
personally use Coda every single day to manage
my podcast and also to manage my community. It's
where I put the questions that I plan to ask every
guest that's coming on the podcast. It's where I
put my community resources, it's how I manage my
workflows. Here's how Coda can help you. Imagine
starting a project at work and your vision is
clear. You know exactly who's doing what and where
to find the data that you need to do your part.
In fact, you don't have to waste time searching
for anything because everything your team needs
from project trackers and OKRs to documents and
spreadsheets lives in one tab all in Coda. With
Coda's collaborative all-in-one workspace, you
get the flexibility of docs, the structure of
spreadsheets, the power of applications, and the
intelligence of AI all in one easy to organize
tab. Like I mentioned earlier, I use Coda every
single day. And more than 50,000 teams trust Coda
to keep them more aligned and focused. If you're
a startup team looking to increase alignment and
agility, Coda can help you move from planning to
execution in record time. To try it for yourself,
go to coda.io/lenny today and get six months
free of the team plan for startups. That's
C-O-D-A.I-O/lenny to get started for free and
get six months of the team plan, coda.io/lenny.
You mentioned Slack. I have a great quote also
about you that I didn't read that I'm just going
to read right now from someone that worked with
you. She said she searched the Slack channel at
the company you worked at for old posts from
Wes for inspiration for what to ask you. And
she said you had zero half-baked thoughts,
100% complete sentences, perfect punctuation,
clear takeaways at the top of every message. It's
the kind of thing you don't notice in isolation,
but once you see everyone else's messages in
a remote-first company, it's a stark contrast.
Yeah, thank you. I will also say that
as someone who tries to walk the talk,
I feel like I get a pretty good response rate
pretty quickly for the things that I ask for,
for the recommendations I'm making.
It's not instant, it's not 100%,
but over time I've realized that improving my
communication has led to people receiving my
ideas better. Ideas that used to be locked in
my head that I would get frustrated that no one
else understood. People were now understanding
and that feels really good. That's very, very
exciting and it made me want to do it more and
pay more attention to that. So that's going back
to what I said earlier about watching for what's
working. There's momentum is really encouraging.
And I totally feel that. If you
start getting the things you want,
that feels great. I'd be like, "Okay, cool."
Yeah, more.
"Let's do more of that." Yeah, and
again, it's like very minor things.
It's like a couple more minutes on the Slack
message, a couple more minutes on email.
Very doable.
Yeah, which everyone can do. There's no
magic here, it's just spend a little more
time and use some of these tactics that
we're talking about. Speaking of that,
let me talk about another tactic. Apparently
you have some really good advice on finding the
right level of confidence in what you're
saying. There's always this question of,
"I come to this leader. How confident should
I be about, 'This is the answer,' versus,
'Here's a bunch of ideas'?" What do
you think? What's your advice there?
I find that people tend to naturally be on
the spectrum a little bit too confident as
a baseline or not confident enough. So people
who are too confident might state hypotheses as
if they are fact. So that really bothers
me. That's another one of my pet peeves,
where if you say, "This is X," or, "This
will X," that is different than saying,
"This could X," or, "This might X," or,
"This will increase the likelihood of X."
So I'm a big proponent of speaking accurately.
You can avoid a lot of problems if you speak
accurately about your level of conviction
and about the actual amount of evidence that
you have for something. It's okay for
something to be an initial hunch. Say,
"It's an initial hunch." Don't act like this is
something that you are super sure about. You've
proven out that this is absolutely this way
because the rest of your team is listening to
you at face value. And y'all might spend real
headcount and dollars pursuing something that
you have advocated for in a way where you
overreached with your level of confidence.
So, that's for people who are overconfident.
It's equally a problem if you're under-confident.
So I have some clients who their CEO asked them
to share some recommendations with another team
because they've run something before and so
they share all this amazing information and
at the end they're like, "Oh, but you can
ignore everything I just said. Obviously,
make your own decision. Do what you think is
best. And if you want to just ignore everything,
that's totally cool too." And it's like you just
didn't have to say that. You could say, "Make
your own decision, take all this into account,"
but you don't have to diminish to that degree.
And so again, speaking accurately, if you have
really strong reasons to recommend something
to the cross-functional team, it's almost
irresponsible to act like you are not really
sure and it's just this random idea, "Hey, try
it if you want to." We might lose a lot of money
and time if we don't take this idea, right? So
again, speaking accurately is so, so important.
Is a simple way to think about then the
right balance is have a point of view,
have a recommendation, present accurate
facts, and be clear when you are not?
"It's not actually 100% true, but here's a
hunch I have, or here's a theory we have."
Yeah, I think sharing a point of view, sharing
a recommendation, and then backing it up with
evidence, with logic, with first principles,
with examples, with data, if you have it. Not
every situation you're going to have data for,
especially if you're building something new. So
this is where first principles comes in. Even
explaining how you got to where you got to and
why you think this is going to work, that all
gives your team, your manager, something to push
back on, to poke holes on or to align on and say,
"Yeah, I agree here, but I disagree on this part."
So you can talk about ideas with a lot more
specificity when you share your thought
process. And you can frame it all kicking
off saying, "My initial thinking is," or,
"Based on what we know, my hunch is, blank." So
speaking accurately and then still bringing up
those facts so that we can all make as informed
of a decision as we can make given what we know.
Advice I got that really helped here for me
was to try not to be biased with how you frame
everything. You have your suggestion for how to
do something. It's easy to just bias all of the
data to point in that direction. And if people
notice that, they're like, "Oh, okay. Well,
I can't really trust this because I see you're
just like, you clearly have an agenda." So it's
a little bit like having an agenda and a POV, but
be clear about what is actually true. Be accurate.
Yeah. I think anytime people have to discount
what you're saying because you are
biased in this way is not great.
Is there an example by any chance that
highlights what you're describing here?
Yeah, so in my course I talk about not being a
single-minded martyr. So single-minded martyr
is someone who very much has an agenda, who wants
the recommendation to go through and is presenting
a bunch of evidence, supporting that direction.
And then gets really frustrated when other people
are not seeing it or are skeptical. And so one
of my clients was a single-minded martyr in a
recommendation she was making. So she was on the
growth acquisition side of her company. And was
having trouble with cross-functional team members
lending headcount to her project. And so everyone
would say like, " Oh, yes, we believe in this,
this is important," but wouldn't want to actually
give her half of their engineer for two weeks.
And we were talking about it and as we were
talking, she revealed that the CEO had at
the beginning of the year said that the
company-wide goal is retention that year.
That their biggest challenges and areas of
opportunity were in retention, not necessarily in
growth. And once she zoomed out and realized this,
she was able to put her recommendation in
context. And realized that it's not just-
... recommendation in context. And realize
that it's not just I'm the only one who
cares about this company. Everyone is a
hypocrite. They say they believe this,
but don't actually want to work on it.
Before that was kind of her narrative,
but once she zoomed out and realized she
was being a single [inaudible 00:48:16],
she could better fit her proposal in the context
of what else was happening in the organization. I
think actually this is a really big difference
between more junior people versus more senior
people. More junior people are like, "I need to
win. I need to get a yes for this proposal and
I'm going to keep advocating for it until I get a
yes." Whereas really sometimes the best decision
for the company is not right now. This doesn't
actually fit our priorities right now, right?
Or maybe yes, but let's right size the level of
investment. So it might look like half whatever
the size of what that recommendation actually
was, and having the maturity to realize that,
to put your idea into context is huge. That took
me a really long time to learn and I think that
goes under the umbrella of always do what's best
for the company, not necessarily what's best for
me, my career, my team, my wins. If you prioritize
what's best for the company, that helps you have a
more right-sized way of still advocating for your
ideas, but doing it with a bit more equanimity.
And also just connecting to what the
company is. Just this idea of if the
thing you're pitching is not aligned with
what is important to the company right now,
it's unlikely to be prioritized. It makes
sense. This is why leaders choose, here's
what matters most. We got to do the things that
are going to help us drive this thing right now,
like retention or revenue. And so that's just, I
think, a sub tactic there is just whenever you're
pitching something, connect that to the goal of
the person you're pitching to so that they're
like, "Oh, I see how this is going to help
me. That's great. Let's do it. Great advice."
And I think this is something a lot of people
run into. It's just, "Why aren't they listening
to me? Why don't they want... That's such
a good idea. They hate me." It's something,
"Oh, I bet they hate me. They don't trust me."
When it's just like, okay, this isn't a priority
right now. Let's come back to it another time.
Okay. I'm going to get to a couple more tactics
and then I'm going to shift directions to talk
about managers and being manager. You have an
awesome framework called MOO. What is MOO? What
does it stand for and what is it all about?
MOO stands for Most Obvious Objection. M-O-O.
And the thought there is that a lot of times
we're surprised by the questions that we get,
especially in meetings where we feel blindsided,
that was unexpected, and then we're on our back
foot. When really, if you thought for even two
minutes about what are obvious objections that
I'm likely to get when I share this, you often
immediately come up with what some of those things
are. So are you going to be able to anticipate
every single objection? No. But can you anticipate
the obvious ones? Absolutely. And so this is where
knowing your own argument in and out, including
counterarguments becomes so important. So knowing
your counterarguments as well as you know the
arguments for doing the thing. When you do that,
when you have prepared in that way, you're
less likely to feel caught off guard.
When you hear you talk about this, it's like,
obviously I shouldn't do this, but very few
people actually do this, actually spend a couple
minutes, " Okay, here's what I'm going to pitch."
Even a couple seconds, really.
Really, even a couple seconds,
your brain will think of something.
Is there a story or an example of this that you
share that highlights this
idea of the power of MOO?
I use MOO multiple times a day, every day, every
single day. Literally whatever I'm about to say I
think how might someone disagree with this or
what might an objection be? So whatever it is
I'm writing, saying, it's a really good mental
filter because it encourages you to think a
couple steps ahead in kind of a structured way,
right? If I'm about to say this, the person may
then say this to me. Well, if I take that into
account, I can volunteer that information upfront
or I can frame it in a way where they're
less likely to think that that's an issue.
And so it's muscle memory for me at this point,
and this might be something we include at the
end is something to start with. But putting
MOO on a post-it, Most Obvious Objection,
what is someone likely to object about? And then
just keeping that top of mind. It's a great way to
train yourself to empathize with your audience
and with your recipient. We all say that and
we all know we should do it, but for me this
is a really tactical concrete way to do it.
I think what's great about a lot of the
tactics you're sharing is not only is it
going to help you communicate it better, but
it helps you actually think and crystallize
it better for yourself because you may realize,
oh, that's a really good objection. Like, oh,
the objection's probably going to be this. Will
it drive enough impact for the business? Oh,
that's a great point. Maybe I
should not pitch this right now.
Yeah. It definitely helps shape your own
thinking. I think communication and thinking
are so much more interrelated than we think. I
think people think there's a thinking as phase
one and then communicating the thinking, and
the reality is a lot more intertwined. And I
loved your example there that thinking ahead
to what might be the most obvious objection
actually then prompts you to realize that maybe
there was a gap in what you were planning to
present and then you now have an opportunity to
strengthen that pitch before you say it out loud.
There's a quote I have highlighted on this
podcast a number of times that I love that
is exactly along these lines by Joan Didion. "I
don't know what I think until I write it down."
I know exactly that feeling. Okay. So there's a
couple more things that people have shared that
you are amazing at helping them get better at.
One is just keeping your cool and staying calm
during very high stakes, real-time conversations
when things maybe aren't going your way or if you
disagree with someone, any advice on that,
it feels like you're really good at this.
I think one thing that tends to throw people off
is putting a lot of pressure on themselves to get
the exact right answer. So if they are asked a
question and they don't know the answer, a lot
of people will then kind of freak out. And I was
taught early in my career that if you don't know
the answer, you should say, "Let me look into it,
I'll get back to you." So that's a fine approach.
It's definitely better than making something
up, right? So definitely don't make something
up. But if you are more experienced and have
some confidence in your subject matter area,
just saying I'll get back to you, is
sometimes a missed opportunity. You
can ask for a bit more information to be able
to continue the conversation in that moment.
So let's say that your exec says what percentage
of users came from mobile last month and you don't
have that number off the top of your head.
So person A says, "Let me look into it and
I'll get back to you." Person B might say, "I
don't have that number off the top of my head,
but in the last quarter the number has been
60 to 70% and it's grown in the past year,
so mobile is now a bigger part of our business,
et cetera. Are you wondering if we are investing
in mobile appropriately or where's that commission
coming from, basically? Right? And so being able
to answer a similar question in the direction
you think the person is asking about and then
validating why they're asking that question
allows you to still continue that conversation
in the moment. I call it the question behind
the question, sometimes you get a question, but
underneath there's a deeper underlying concern.
And many times people don't even know that it's
there, right? Subconscious. So it's not nefarious,
they're not withholding anything from you. But
when you are explaining something and you're kind
of getting multiple questions on the same thing,
it's a good sign that there might be a
deeper question behind the question and
it's our responsibility to figure out
what might that be. And so probing,
asking for a bit more information, answering in
that general direction and then validating these
are all techniques you can use when you are in
the moment without feeling like, oh, I must have
every single thing prepared and the moment that
I'm caught off guard, everything goes to shit.
Another tactic along these lines that's
very similar to what you're describing,
but I'll share that I learned that was really
helpful is just if you're not sure what to say,
basically just reflecting back their question
and just being like, let me just make sure
I understand what you're looking for. You
want to understand monthly retention for,
and then maybe clarify. And that one gives you
time to think about it as you're talking. Two,
it helps the person recognize,
"Oh, he hears me. Great. Okay,
this is good. He's thinking about this." And
then at the end of that you could be like,
"Okay. I don't actually have that specific number.
Let me think about it." Or, "I have the quarterly
number. Okay. That's what I know." So there's an
interim step almost that I'll add into your piece
of advice of just reflect back their question,
just better understand what they're looking for.
Yeah, I love that. Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Awesome. Okay, let's go back to what I said we
do. Let's pick one tactic that you think people
should try first, maybe one or two. So let me
read the ones we've gone through and then see
what you think would be a good first step. So
one is starting with sales, before getting to
logistics and giving people the why signposting
using specific words to help people guide the doc
and not get overwhelmed. Finding the right level
of confidence, having a POV, that sort of thing.
Getting better, being concise, MOO, not overusing
formatting, something else you shared. And then
this idea of when you don't know the answer,
not saying I'll get back to you as the default,
maybe giving them a different answer, maybe
asking them more questions. Across those,
which do you think someone should try
to like, "Okay. Let me start here."
I would start with Most Obvious Objection and
also framing your conversation up front. And
that kind of relates to using signposting words
if needed to help you frame that conversation.
Sweet. That's such an easy one to remember.
Just MOO. Okay. So stick a post it somewhere
when you're about to share something in Slack and
ask someone for something, present in a meeting,
send a strategy, and just think about for a few
seconds what might be the most obvious objection
to what I'm trying to ask them to do. Great. Okay.
So let's talk about management. And there's kind
of two sides to it. Being a manager and
being a person reporting to a manager,
you have a bunch of really good advice here.
One is there around managing up. One of my
most popular posts in the early days was advice
for managing up and just how important it is.
What advice do you have for someone to get better
at managing up? Why is that even so important? Why
do you think people may be under appreciating how
important it is to manage your manager, let's say.
One of the most common myths about managing up
that I definitely felt early on in my career
was that I would have to manage up if I were
more junior, but eventually I would outgrow it,
that I would get senior enough that I would no
longer have to do it. And it was a rude awakening
that no matter how senior I got, managing up,
I not only had to manage up, it actually became
more important. So I think managing up is one of
those skills that if you invest in learning it,
it serves you now and for the rest of your
career. And I realize that many senior people
are actually the best at managing up. That's
partially how they got to be so senior in the
first place. But also, the more senior you get,
the less likely that your manager is going to
give you really well-defined tasks and problems
on a silver platter and ask you to solve them.
You are going to be dealing with more
ambiguity and you're going to be dealing
with sometimes a mandate like make this
number go up or create this division,
right? Where you need to manage up and
make sure that your leader, your manager,
is in the loop about what you are about to try
and what you're about to do and make sure that
they're aligned. And so for me, realizing that
managing up is something that is ongoing and that
it shifts and evolves and looks different as you
go in your career, that was a big unlock for me.
Just that even if you become even a VP, if
you become a director and still something you
want to invest in, any specific tactic
or advice for how to manage up well.
The biggest one is to share your point of view.
So this some people are surprised by because they
think I'm going to say do a weekly recap of the
tasks that you worked on or what you contributed.
And that is a good idea, if you want to do it, you
can do it. But I think the more highly leveraged
way to contribute and manage up is by being more
vocal about sharing your point of view. When you
just ask your manager, "Hey manager, what should
we do?" You're putting a lot of cognitive load
on your manager to need to think about the
problem, think about potential solutions,
craft the solution, and then tell you what to
do. Whereas if you instead said, "Hey manager,
here's what I think we should do. How does that
sound? Where do you see gaps? Am I thinking in
the right direction?" You give them something
to build off of and that reduces the amount
of mental lift that they have to put forth.
And so sharing your point of view more readily,
backing it up with evidence, that's a wonderful
way of making your manager's life easier. And also
showing that you are an active rigorous thinker
who is thinking strategically about the business.
You're not just waiting to be told what to do,
you're not expecting them to figure things out
and then tell you you are actively looking
around the corner trying to solve problems,
forming hypotheses in your mind, observing and
noticing things. And again, sharing your point
of view doesn't mean that you have the perfect
answer. You can share that, "Hey, I've noticed
this problem popping up in a couple of different
places. Here's what I think might be happening."
Or when you share a report, don't only share the
report and expect your manager to come up with
insights and takeaways. You should look at the
report too and point out insights and takeaways.
So it's really changing that posture from more
reactive and more waiting to be told what to do
or kind of staying in this narrow box to being
willing to share your recommendation, your point
of view, share what you're noticing, and this
is something that even junior people could do.
I was going to say exactly that. I think not
only is it something junior people can do,
this is a really good way to get promoted and
to take on more leadership opportunities. You
coming to your manager with, "Here's something I
think we should do. Here's a perspective I have.
Here's an opportunity." If you were in charge,
you're like, how awesome would it be for people
to come to me with amazing ideas and have clear
recommendations? That sounds great. Everyone
wants that. So if you can do that, amazing. Who
wouldn't want that? But then what's interesting
is similar to how writing helps you crystallize
your thinking, you coming in with a recommendation
forces you to really think deeply about it because
that's putting your reputation on the line. So
there's a second order effect of it makes you
actually spend more time on the thing and be
clear about why you think this is a good idea
and do more research. So a lot of wins here.
There are a lot of situations where you might have
the most visibility into a problem. You might have
the most proximity into an issue. And so if you're
not speaking up about it and sharing what you're
observing, sharing what you're noticing, your
manager doesn't necessarily have visibility into
that. And so I've heard so many managers say that
they want their junior people to speak up more
because their junior people have often close
contact with customers, with support tickets,
with cleaning data, with a bunch of things where
the manager would love to hear insights from that.
If you're not having success with this, if you're
hearing this and be like, but it never worked,
my manager doesn't listen to me, listen
to the rest of this podcast we just did,
which is basically advice on how to effectively
convince someone of a thing. It's like, tell them
why this is a problem, be really concise about
it, sign post words, all these things. That's
exactly what this whole conversation's been about.
Okay. Let's see. We have a couple more really cool
tactics that people have suggested we talk
about. One is how to give feedback well,
how to do better, how to be more effective
at giving feedback. What's your advice there?
I have a framework called strategy, not
self-expression. And so the idea here is that most
of the time, by the time we are giving feedback
to someone, we have been frustrated for a while.
I used to be very conflict diverse, so I would
wait and try to convince myself that I wasn't
bothered by something until I really couldn't hold
it in anymore. Then I would schedule a one-on-one
with a coworker to tell them the feedback and it
would inevitably turn into a venting session where
I was in the name of sharing the impact of what
they did would share all my frustrations and all
the ways that they have basically harmed me and
made my life difficult. And this would be very
counterproductive because the person would either
feel like and feel really demoralized or they'd
get really defensive and they'd want to argue with
me about how what they did actually was not that
bad or it was partially my fault too or whatever.
And so I realized that a better way of giving
feedback is thinking about motivating the person's
behavior change. The goal is behavior change. So
if that's the goal, trim everything else that
you were about to say that does not actually
contribute to that goal and only keep the part
that will make the person want to change, help
them understand the benefit to them as well as
to the people around them. And so usually for me,
that's trimming 90% of the initial stuff that I
want to say and really keeping only that 10%. And
that's made a really big difference. Whenever
I am giving constructive feedback of any kind,
I always keep that in mind. And when I
don't do it, I almost always regret it.
Someone close to me in my life is working
on the skill, which is there's just,
"I want people to know how they messed up.
Justice. I need this to be fair." And what
I always recommend is just think about what
you want to get out of this conversation,
what do you want from them? And then, okay,
what's the best way to get that? Versus just
making sure they hear you and making sure
they understand how screwed up this was.
And that's basically what you're saying is
focus on the outcome you want to achieve,
not something that's useful, something
that will make you just feel better.
Yeah. I definitely think that having a space
to vent and to share those frustrations is
important. So you want to get that out before you
go into the conversation with your counterpart.
So whether it's talking to your therapist or
your partner or friend, you want to basically
get all that energy out because otherwise
you bring it into the conversation and it
doesn't take much to set you off. You might have
a whole script, you're controlled, you're calm,
and then you start talking and the other
person raises an eyebrow and is acting a
little incredulous at what you're saying, and
that's all it takes for you to snap and be like,
"You're surprised? You're incredulous? Why are
you incredulous?" Right? And then you're off,
right? Yeah. Getting that energy out, I would say
step one, so that you can go into the conversation
clear, grounded, setting that emotional tone
that is more positive and that allows you to
stay focused on only the part that will get them
to behave in the way you want them to behave.
Such good advice. And I think we come back to are
you getting the outcomes you want? If you're not,
this is another reason it might be the case is you
just need them to hear your mind. I just need you
to know. And I think a lesson here is that may
not be the best path to getting what you want,
but it may feel good. Maybe people are like,
"Ah, but I really want them to know this."
There's that great Einstein quote about insanity
being repeating things that you're doing expecting
a different outcome. And I feel like that applies
so much to the workplace and to communication.
Most of us have certain patterns that we are
used to and certain ways of responding, and if
you believe that there is untapped upside that
whatever you are at is kind of a local maximum
and that there's better out there, then that's
where switching things up could be useful and not
just doing everything that you've been doing and
getting the same result that you might be getting.
This resonates with Toby Lutke
when he is doing the podcast,
talked about how... He had this quote that I love
that just "No human in history has come anywhere
near their potential and everyone is way, way,
way better than they think are," and these are
really cool tactics and really effective ways
to actually get closer to your potential. Okay.
Two more things I want to talk about real
quick. One is your advice on delegating,
but also continuing to have high standards. This
is something I spent a lot of time on because a
lot of people don't delegate because they're
afraid it's not going to be as great. I just
want this to be really good. I don't trust that
it's going to go as well. If I did it my way,
it'd be great. So just advice on how to delegate
effectively while maintaining high standards.
Yeah. I have a framework called CEDAF. C-E-D-A-F.
Mm-hmm. I love all these acronyms.
It's kind of like Cedar, but with an F
at the end. I need acronyms for myself.
All of these are really reminders for myself
because I need a short way to remind myself. So
CEDAF stands for the C is comprehension. So
have I given this person that I'm delegating to
everything that they need to understand what it is
that I want them to do. That includes more simple
things like logins to all the right software
tools that they need to look up, whatever you
need to look up. And understanding what the end
result should look like, right? So that's all
under C for comprehension. E is excitement. Am
I explaining this in a way that is making this
as exciting as it could be? There are a lot of
tasks that aren't inherently that exciting, but by
explaining the why behind we're doing this or why
it's important to the project we're working on,
that makes people more likely to understand and
be excited about how this fits into everything.
So E is for excitement. D is for de-risk. Am
I de-risking any obvious risks from delegating
this? So usually when I ask clients this, they
immediately think of something. They're like,
"Oh yeah, I wouldn't want my direct report to
spend a ton of time going in the wrong direction,
filling out a hundred rows of the spreadsheet if
actually it took longer than we expected." Okay,
great. If that's a risk, then maybe you
have them do 10 rows, see how long it takes,
see if we need all the information that they're
actually gathering, and then regroup, right? So
what's an obvious risk? Another might be I can
see this person misunderstanding and thinking
I'm looking for this where I'm really looking
for that. Okay, perfect. Just tell them, "When
I explain this, you might think I mean this, but
really I don't want that. I actually want this,"
right? So just vocalize it. The A is for align.
So am I giving the other person a chance to-
The A is for align. So am I giving the other
person a chance to speak up and make sure we
are actually aligned, that they're picking up
what I'm putting down? Because you might be
explaining a bunch of stuff, but how much are
they actually absorbing? You won't ever know
if you wrap up your little spiel and then
say, "Okay, go off. Come back to me when
you're done." So give people a chance to ask
questions to see what parts are resonating,
what parts they might be a little bit
confused on. Usually, when I do this,
it's amazing. Because my team member will
say, "What did you mean by this part? How
does this part fit in?" I'm like, "Oh my God,
I totally forgot to mention this thing." Or,
"Oh yeah, I didn't even really explain
that well." Okay, so let's go into that.
And then F is feedback. How can you have the
shortest feedback loop possible? I am a huge
fan of shorting the feedback loop as much
as possible and then shortening it again.
So even within that initial conversation where I'm
delegating something, instead of waiting a week,
what if we waited a day and checked in on the
initial direction that person was going? And
let's do it even more. What if after I finished
explaining, at the end of that conversation,
we brainstormed a couple things that, that person
wants to do? So within this same conversation,
I'm delegating, I'm already getting a sense
of, where do you want to go with this? Once
you start, do you see any bottlenecks?
And so just really keeping that feedback
loop super tight. I found that when I run through
the CDAP acronym, there's usually one letter that
I could amp up a little bit more like, oh,
I didn't really put much thought into making
this exciting for the person. How can I connect
this to their career goals or to the company's
priorities this quarter or to something
else? So it's a nice mental checklist.
So much of your advice comes back to this idea
that we've touched on a couple of times. We just
spend a little bit more time upfront. Is that
how you described it, a little more time upfront?
Yeah, a little bit more time. A little
bit more of an investment upfront.
Upfront to save you tons of time
later. Okay. So as you described this,
I don't know if you're realizing this, but
you're basically just helping people work
better with AI and agents. This framework is
exactly I think what people need to effectively
delegate to this future world of this agent world
of society of agents doing work for us. Basically,
you're going to be delegating to these agents
in the future, and this framework is a really
cool way to frame it. So think about it. Am
I communicating this well, comprehension? So
CDAP. Comprehension is, again, can I make this
clear? Is that the way to think about that?
Yeah. Can I make this clear? Does this
person have everything they need to be
able to accomplish what I am asking them to do?
Okay. And then it's communicate why you're
excited about this, basically the why. And it's
interesting, there's this funny prompt technique
I've learned, prompting engineering technique of
just telling the AI, "This is very important to my
job." Just using that sentence, it does it better.
Oh, interesting, yeah.
It takes it more seriously. It's just
so weird. I have a post about this,
and that's one of the pieces of advice, just
tell me why this is important. I think people
take it to the extreme as someone will die if
you don't get this right. That actually works.
That is extreme. Cool.
It's wild. Okay, so CEDF, comprehension, excited,
de-risk, think about ways you can de-risk,
which is moot, basically. What's the most?
It's a similar concept. Just think ahead to
what might go wrong. Make sure you're aligned,
which is quite important in the AI space. Make
sure you're aligned. And feedback, get a quick
feedback cycle. And it's interesting with deep
research on some of these AI tools now, it's
like, "I'm off for half an hour. See you."
And I imagine more and more of them will
check in with you as it's going and ask you
questions. I used deep research recently
and it's really good at just like, okay,
let me have five questions for you before I go off
and do this work just to clarify what you want.
Yeah, I found that AI will often shorten the
feedback loop and align with you as well. When
you prompt it, when it comes back, it will not
do the entire task for me, sometimes. It'll say,
"I've done the first part of this. Does this sound
right? Is this what you're looking for? If so,
I will complete the next section." And then
sometimes I'm like, "Do the whole thing. Just
stop trying to conserve energy and just do.
I want you to do the whole thing." But that's
what it's doing, it's breaking it into smaller
chunks to de-risk that it's going to use all
this bandwidth to process this thing and I'm going
to say, "Oh, that's not what I was looking for."
I'm going to come back to AI
real quick, but before I do that,
I have one more question for you, but let me
just say, I feel like we've discovered an AI
version of your course now. Basically,
how to delegate well to AI agents that
I think people are going to find really valuable,
planting a seed. Okay. Before we get back to AI,
you have this other concept that I love
that I actually learned from you years
ago when I was working on my course
called the swipe file. Swipe file,
what is a swipe file? What is that about? What can
it help you with? Why should people be doing this?
Yeah. So swipe files are really common for
marketers, and I think other functions haven't
caught on as much, but I think it is really,
really useful. And basically a swipe file is
collecting inspiration that you can refer
back to later on. So some marketers will
collect examples of copy, landing pages, ads, et
cetera. For me, I have a file, an Apple Notes,
file called Smart Things People Have Said,
where I will basically paste in phrases,
words, things people have said that I thought were
well articulated or sounded really intelligent or
sounded strategic. And I don't actually go
back and look through my swipe file very often,
I think other people do, but for me, even the act
of adding it to my swipe file, I've already gotten
value from it because it's training me to be more
alert to noticing when something is working well.
I think there's so much happening around us all
the time that your coworker says something smart
and you're like, "Oh, that was nice," and then you
keep moving on. But when you stop and pause and
think, oh, that was really effective, let me add
it to my file, and also think about, why was that
effective and is that something I can borrow?
So in my course, I encourage folks to create a
work journal where they can jot down some of these
observations, some of these phrases, and basically
encourage yourself to be more alert to things
you can borrow from other people all around you.
Something else about the swipe file, you
use quotes. It could be screenshots of
cool designs. It could be strategy docs you
found to be really effective. It could be
conversion flows that are really cool. It
could be just whatever you're interested in.
Yeah. And the great thing about that
is you can then go back and analyze it
and break down the structure, break down
the argument, break down why was this so
effective? Whereas if you're not capturing it,
it's easy to just move on to the next thing.
Yeah, cool. And I did this for a while. I stopped,
to be honest, but I really want to be doing this.
So this is maybe some homework or something,
because I know a lot of people stick with it,
is just start like a folder or a Notes, note,
whatever you use for your note-taking, and just
start throwing stuff in there. And it could
be messy, right? It's just like, throw it in.
It can be super messy. I was going to
say, my back end system is super messy
and it's fine. It's not a problem I need
to be solving. It works. I find things I
need to find. So I like having as simple
of a process as possible. So Apple Notes,
I open it. It's just on my home screen, I
just add something. I'm not tagging anything,
I'm not putting it in certain rows and filling
information out. I'm just including it in a file,
and if I want to go back and look
at it, it served its purpose.
Awesome. Okay, so last question. AI, I'm going
to just come back to this briefly. We have this
segment on the podcast called AI Corner, and we
touched on this already, but I'm just curious
how you have found AI to be useful in your
work or your life, whether it's helped you
become a better communicator? Is there anything
you can share that might be helpful to folks?
Yeah. I love Claude. There are days when I talk
to Claude for three or four hours prompting as
a thought partner. So yeah, I think that AI is
really helpful for an initial draft of something
to bounce off of. Sometimes I'll paste in an
email that I am not quite sure how to respond
to and ask Claude, "Tell me draft reply." And
I'll usually give it some direction. So I found
that sharing my point of view makes the output
way better. If I just give it something and say,
"What would you say?" It's just not as
good. Whereas if I say, "I am not sure
about how to tell this person no, because I
previously said yes and so I feel on the hook,
but history has changed and so is there a
nice way where I can be really respectful
of our relationship and also make them
feel seen and heard, but decline?"
So if I explain, "That's the problem I'm dealing
with and here's what I would ideally like to be
able to do," Claude comes back to something
that's pretty good. And then from there I'll
edit it to my voice because usually it's a
little bit too formal sounding. And so I'll
make some edits and then I'll share it back
to Claude and say, "What do you think of this
version? Would you make any improvements?"
And then we go back and forth from there.
Wes, this is the most useful
thing I've ever heard.
[inaudible 01:21:44].
I need this and I need this immediately, just
nice ways to say no to stuff. This needs to be
an extension that I can have in my browser,
just, "Help me say no to this, please." Wow,
such a great idea. Okay, good one. Okay, great.
Wes, is there anything else? We've gone through
a lot. I imagine the answer is no, but before
we get to our very exciting lightning round,
is there anything else that you wanted
to share or leave listeners with?
No, I feel like we covered
a bunch of great frameworks,
principles, so lots for folks to get started.
All the things. And I love that so much of
this will apply to being more effective with
AI tools and I feel like people can go through
this again and just through that lens of,
how will this helped me get more out of
Claude and ChatGPT? I bet so much of this
will actually apply and I feel like there's
an interesting course there. With that, Wes,
we've reached our very exciting lightning round.
All right,
Are you ready?
Let's do it.
Okay. First question, what are a couple books
that you recommend most to other people?
One is High Output Management by Andy Grove,
which is a classic. Another one is Your Brain
At Work by Dr. David Rock. And that one
is all about better understanding your
own brain and attention span so that you can
allocate your mental resources appropriately.
So that one's great. Ever since reading
that, I hide my phone from view because
there have been studies that show that even
seeing your phone in the corner of your eye,
it's distracting. And I do the hardest
things earlier in the day when you have
more cognitive resources available. So
that one's really good. Yeah, those two.
These are great. I completely get that
phone thing. I'm just looking at my phone,
I'm like, "Dang, get out of here. Just go away."
I will stick it under my pillow on the
couch or hide it under a notebook. It's
huge. I'm always hiding my phone
so it's not in my line of sight.
I think Arianna Huffington has a product you
can buy that's a little bed for your phone
that you put to bed before you go to bed in a
different room and it has a charger attached.
Oh, that's cute.
So cute, so cute.
I don't know if I need a
separate bed for my phone.
But it's like a ritual, I guess, and
there's some theory behind it. Okay,
next question. Favorite recent
movie or TV show you really enjoyed?
I love Anything by Harlan Coben on Netflix.
Basically, I don't even remember any specific
movies or a TV series, but anything he puts
out, he's an author and then they've turned a
lot of his books into mystery thriller TV
series, and anything he puts out becomes
number one on Netflix. And I appreciate
that he gives the people what they want,
that he knows his craft, he knows his genre.
And yeah, he just has so many bangers. And I
don't remember any specific one, but if it's a
Harlan Coben show, I know it's going to be good.
I'm looking at a list now I just Googled
real quick. So it's all scary stuff, right?
Yeah, they're mystery thrillers, and I
think he does a good job playing with
time and revealing information over time.
It's usually something about someone's past
that is now coming to haunt them, and
so he'll skip between present day to
the past and then slowly reveal stuff.
And there's always a twist at the end.
There's a page, the Harlan Coben Collection on
Netflix. That we'll link to that has all this
stuff. I've never heard of this,
so this is great. Next question,
do you have a favorite product you
recently discovered that you really love?
I recently started using an electric
toothbrush and it's been life-changing.
So my husband got one and then a
couple weeks later he gifted me one,
and I was like, "Wow, this
is actually really nice."
Are you a Sonicare person,
Oral-B person, or something else?
It's Oral-B but I've not tried
any other brand. That was one that
our dentist gifted my husband this electric
toothbrush because he did Invisalign. And
I'm sure Invisalign is every dentist's dream.
Margins.
I feel like every time I get a cleaning, the
dentist is like, "So have you thought about,
are you interested in Invisalign?" I'm
like, "No." And so when they get a yes,
I'm sure they're really excited,
and then they lock you in,
the brand locks you in with these replacement
toothbrush heads that are way more expensive
than they should be. So it's a whole
razor and blades, ink cartridge and
printer model here. So I was horrified by
how expensive these replacement heads were.
But you got a free toothbrush. I think
the Oral-B is what I use, but I think
that's what the Wirecutter recommended, but
it's so loud. I don't know. One of them is
just really loud. I think it's the Oral-B, but
it's better, apparently. I went with Wirecutter,
but it's so loud. I feel like there needs to be
a Wirecutter for good design and experience...
Ooh.
... versus just the optimal efficient version.
Anyway, let's keep going. Do you have a life motto
that you often find useful in work or in life
that you repeat yourself and share with folks?
Yes. I actually have many, but I'll share two.
One is everything takes longer than you think.
So this applies whether you are calling customer
support for something or running an errand or
building your career, building skills. I find
it's useful to add buffers for yourself. This
applies for launches too. Just assume it will take
longer than you think and you'll be less stressed.
That connects to everything we've been talking
about. Just spend a little more time upfront
to make it. And maybe if you spend more time
front, it'll take less time than you think.
The other one is a riff on always be
closing, like Glengarry Ross. "It's
always be selling." This does not mean
pawning your wares, but rather putting
forth effort into convincing the other
person of whatever your recommendation is.
Love them. Okay, final question. So you've
been a long time, I hate this word operator,
but I guess that's the way people describe this,
where you've just been working at companies,
building companies, and you recently left
that just to become creative person. Started
a course on Maven. You do executive coaching,
things like that. Any just lessons or a lesson
from that jump that might be helpful to
folks that are maybe thinking about that?
I think when you are an in-house operator,
there's a lot about your role that you have
a little bit less control over, basically.
There's just certain things you have to do
because it comes with the territory. Whereas when
you are a solo operator running your own business,
doing your own thing, you have a lot of freedom
to craft your work around only your strengths,
only the part that you are really good
at, that adds a lot of value for other
people where there's market demand. And so,
for me, there was a bit of a shift where
when I realized that I could craft my business,
my work around only the part that I'm best at,
and that can be a narrow-ass slice,
that's actually really, really freeing.
And so I would encourage folks to think about,
what is the thing that you are extremely good
at that people find super valuable, the part
that you love doing most, if you could not do
all the other stuff you don't want to do, and
how can you think about doubling down on that?
That's such an important point. And the
Claude tip you shared of how to say no well
is such an important ingredient into that,
because so many things come at you and are
interesting and enticing that it's hard to
decline, that you realize, why the hell am
I doing this? I can actually control where
I spend time and why did I say yes to this?
I actually credit you with helping me
come to this realization. I mentioned
you on a podcast the other day about this
because, do you remember when Maven was
launching an important feature, I think
it was our marketplace or something,
and I had asked you if you wanted to go
on Clubhouse to be part of the launch?
I remember that, but I am sure I said no.
Okay, yeah. You said no. You said no.
And I was like, "Wow. Out of curiosity,
what's the thought behind it?" And you said, I'm
going to bastardize this, you could correct me,
but you essentially said, "I don't really like
doing live public speaking type things and I've
been fortunate enough to build a career where I
can write, I do my podcasts, and work only on the
part that I love doing. And so I'm okay saying no
to these other really interesting opportunities."
And I remember at that time thinking it was so
groundbreaking that you could say no to something
that was legitimately a cool opportunity and
be really confident about it because it wasn't
your core competency. It wasn't the thing you are
best at. And I've really kept that in mind when
opportunities come my way of, am I excited about
this? Is this what I'm really good at? Can I shine
in this setting? Because when you are solo, you
get to choose the settings that you want to be in.
That's such a cool story. I don't exactly remember
that, but I am zero surprised at what I said.
And the way I put it now, when folks invite me to
stuff like this is I just find the ROI on my time
is so not worth doing a talk, doing a fireside
thing, doing another podcast. It's just like,
if I can spend more time on this newsletter
than the podcast, the leverage is so much
higher than just doing a talk because that takes
so much time. So I just have this template now
that basically says what I sent you, that is,
that it helps. But it's tough. It's so hard
to say no. Sometimes these opportunities are so
interesting and the person is like, "Wait, what?"
Because I don't think the people asking you for
stuff know that I'm getting 10 of them a day,
and they're like, "Oh, he said no to my talk. He
doesn't want to be on my podcast. What a jerk."
That's what I think. I don't know if that's what
they think. But anyway. Okay, that's great. Yes,
and I think I just had a post about reaching
a million subscribers to the newsletter,
and actually had this image of the Ikigai
concept, which is exactly what you just described,
which is you want to try to find the thing
that you love doing, that people value,
and that you can make money doing. That's the
dream. And that's exactly what you have done
as well. So thank you for being here, Wes. I
actually think we delivered on what I thought
we would. I think this is going to be one of the
most highest leverage conversations we've had.
So two final questions. Where can folks find your
course? I know you also do executive coaching.
Where can folks learn more? And final question
is just, how can folks be useful to you, Wes?
You can find out more at weskao.com.
I linked my course to my coaching from
my main page. I also post on LinkedIn
as well, so you can follow me there.
And I'm always looking to meet fellow
operators who out about communication.
So if you put any of these principles into
practice, I would love to hear about it.
Awesome. We'll do that in the comments.
They can DM you. I don't know,
what's the best way to reach
you on the website or Twitter?
Yeah, bunch of platforms.
All the places. Okay, cool.
Website, email, LinkedIn, DM me.
There we go. There we go. Wes,
thank you so much for being here.
Yeah, thank you so much, Lenny.
Very cool.
This was fun.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to the show
on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.