There's rarely a time like this where
so much is possible. Even like five,
seven years ago, it's so hard to start a
company. Everything feels like it's done,
someone else is working on it.
Suddenly, it's a time, right now,
which I've never even experienced,
where everything you try just works.
With people constantly hearing about all
the things happening. Is there any tools
or processes or approaches you've
figured out to help stay focused?
Our engineering goal is every engineer
should ship a marketable product every week.
I love just how wild that sounds. How do you
maintain quality and make it all cohesive?
I actually think as a startup
your job is to take on technical
debt because that is how you operate
faster than a bigger company. Bigger
companies don't take contact technical
debt, they pay it usually right away,
or they're paying back technical debt
from the days when they were a startup.
Is there anything else that in
how you operate and the way you
build product that you think is
really unique and interesting?
We have what we think of as the public roadmap.
This is basically what people have asked us for.
There's all these surface areas where we receive
user feedback, but these are all features that
every competitor knows about. If a user is asking
us for it, they're asking everybody for it.
It's not going to be a game changer
in terms of winning against your
competition. So we have a second roadmap
which we think of as a secret roadmap.
Today my guest is Gaurav Misra. Gaurav was
an early employee at Snap where he led the
design engineering team, which he explains
in the conversation. He's also an engineer
at Microsoft and a couple other companies.
Most recently, he's the co-founder and CEO
of Captions, one of the most successful
and cutting-edge consumer AI products,
which lets you generate and edit talking videos
with AI. They have over 10 million users and
have raised over a hundred million dollars.
In our conversation, we essentially do an
archeology of how a modern AI oriented startup
operates, including how every single engineer
at their company ships a marketable product or
feature every single week. Why they have a secret
roadmap, in addition to a regular roadmap. We
also get in-depth about how Snap as a product team
operated. What he's learned about what it takes
to build a successful consumer and social app,
why they had no PMs and how designers ran the
show, which may or may not have been a great idea.
And also what happens in a world where AI video
is so good that you have no idea if it's real or
not. This episode is for anyone that is building
a product on top of AI. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app. And also, I just launched
an insane deal for subscribers of my newsletter.
Every yearly subscriber now gets a year free of
Notion, Perplexity, Superhuman, Linear and
Granola. Learn more at lennysnewsletter.com.
With that, I bring you Gaurav Misra.
This episode is brought to you by Brex,
the financial stack used by one in every three
US venture-backed startups. Brex knows the nearly
40% of startups fail because they run out of
cash, so they built a banking experience that
focuses on helping founders get more from every
dollar. It's a stark difference from traditional
banking options that leave a startup's cash
sitting idle while chipping away at it with
fees. To help founders protect cash and extend
runway, Brex combined the best things about
checking treasury and FDIC insurance in one
powerhouse account. You can send and receive
money worldwide at lightning speed. You can get
20x the standard FDIC protection through program
banks and you can earn industry-leading yield
from your first dollar while still being able
to access your funds anytime. To learn more,
check out Brex at brex.com/banking-solutions.
That's brex.com/banking-solutions.
This episode is brought to you by
Paragon. The integration infrastructure for
B2B SaaS companies is AI on your 2025 product
roadmap. Whether you need to enable RAG with your
user's external data like Google Drive files,
Gong transcripts, or Jira tickets, or build AI
agents that can automate work across your user's
other tools, integrations are the foundation.
But building all these integrations in-house
will cost you years of engineering, time you
don't have given the fast pace of AI. That's
where Paragon's all-in-one integration platform
comes in. Build scalable workflows to ingest all
of your user's external data into your RAG
pipelines. And leverage, ActionKit, their
latest product to instantly give your AI agents
access to over 100 integrations and thousands
of third-party actions with a single API call.
Leading AI companies like AI21, you.com, 11X,
and Copy.ai are already shipping new integrations
seven times faster with Paragon keeping their
engineers focused on core product development.
Ready to accelerate your AI roadmap this year,
visit useparagon.com/lenny to get a free
MVP of your next product integration.
Gaurav, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you. Thanks for having me. Excited.
I very rarely have early stage founders on
the podcast, but I wanted to chat with you
because you're at the center of so much of what
is top of mind for a lot of builders these days,
AI and video, and just consumer and social apps.
Also going viral and finding new marketing
channels. So I think there's a lot that
people can learn from the way you approach
product, the way you've built product and
the way you just think about where things are
going. So again, thank you for being here.
Appreciate it. Honestly, it's an exciting
time. I got to say like there's rarely a
time like this where so much is possible. In
normal times, if you think about even five,
seven years ago, it's so hard to start a
company. It's so hard to come up with an
idea. It's just like everything feels like it's
done, someone else is working on it. Or it's like,
oh it's been tried three times and failed three
times. And suddenly, it's a time, right now,
which I've never even experienced honestly in
my career, where everything you try just works.
There's so many possibilities. There's not
enough people in the world to work on them.
Honestly. There's more things that can be done
than there's people available to do them. It is
just such a rare thing. And honestly, it's
not going to last forever. We are going to
catch up to this, but just feels lucky to
be part of that movement. It's awesome.
When you said everything is working, I
think what's an important distinction
there is the building of the tool works.
The tech is now there to build all these
things that have not been possible before.
The thing that is increasingly, difficult,
and I want to get your take on this,
is getting anyone to pay attention and
stick with your thing because it's so easy to
build stuff and everything is just awesome and
interesting. It's harder to get people to
pay attention and stick with your product.
So I guess is there anything there, you've
learned that you've built a number of
successful products. We'll talk about Snap and
what you're doing now, about just, I don't know,
what you need to think about these days to get
anyone to pay attention and then stick around.
Yeah, I mean honestly it's a great point and
I think there is a lot of hype obviously,
and part of it, that's what's driving a lot of
this growth for a lot of companies. And I think
from a user acquisition/marketing perspective,
in a world five or seven years ago, if you were
making something novel and you went to users and
it was like, "Oh, we got something better." People
are going to be like, "Well, whatever. Everybody
says they got something better. I don't care."
But today, and this is not probably the way
you should do it, but you can go and just say,
"We've rethought this thing with AI." And
a bunch of people will just be like, "Well,
how?" Or "Maybe I should check this out."
They'll just try it. Obviously, you have to
deliver on the promises. If you don't deliver,
people will come in, they'll play around a bunch
and then just leave. But if you can truly deliver
on the promises, there's great opportunities to
require users at scale. So I think that's slightly
different. And I don't know how long that lasts,
but it is definitely a different time from that
perspective. I do think also at the core of
building products is solving problems. I think a
lot of people sort of get caught up in this, well,
it's cool and people will come for the cool
right now. People will come in and be like,
"Well, let me check it out. It's cool."
But at the end of the day, if you're just
building a playground and people play around in
the playground and then they leave after playing
around, it's not a business. So I think that is
still key. You have to be solving real problems.
As we were talking, I'm
thinking about every day there's
something that would maybe a few years
ago be news for a year. Holy shit,
this is now possible. Now it's like every day
something like that happens and then we're like,
all right, so what I think about is like,
we'll have AGI one of these days or super
intelligence and everyone's going to be, "Oh,
amazing." And then, "Okay, what's for dinner?"
Isn't that already happening? Think about, in a
way, I self-reflect on this sometimes if like,
you've seen Iron Man and stuff, they have the
J.A.R.V.I.S thing and you've seen Interstellar and
they have the TARS machine. They're talking back
and forth with these things like bouncing ideas.
That is science fiction. That's literally
science fiction. Okay, it's not perfect,
but it exists in a way that nobody could
have imagined. That's science fiction has
become reality and I feel like nobody cares.
In a way, you would've expected the world
to be turned upside down, but it feels like
almost in a way so slow and people are like,
yes, adoption is happening, but I feel like
it's almost a shocking development in a way.
It feels like you guys have done a good
job staying top of mind and continuing to
get people excited because to your point,
there's so much happening. How do you get
people to continue to be like, "Oh, okay,
wow, what their building is actually is
interesting and continues to be interesting."
Anything you've learned about just what it takes
to stay top of mind and continue to pull people
back and get people re-excited over and over?
Hundred percent. I mean, I think honestly it
just comes down to not just AI for the sake
of AI or AI for the sake of excitement or hype
or novelty or whatever that is, it's actually
effective AI like AI that solves real problems,
practical problems. And the fundamentals haven't
changed. In a way, there's three steps to
building products. You identify a user problem,
you apply some technology to solve that problem,
but then finally you have some mechanism to find
people who have that problem. If you can do all
three of those things, then in any environment
you can create great products. But I think right
now what's different is so much is changing on the
technology side that you can create products
that could not have been created before and
solve problems that could not have been solved
before. And that's creating the opportunity.
And for us, especially in the video space,
it's truly endless. We've just begun,
our goal specifically for video is not to
build professional tools. We're not building
for professionals at all. We're building for the
person who could not have created video before.
They didn't have the tools, the skills, the
means to be able to create video and now they can
because they're able to jump over that skill gap
or that time gap. Maybe they're business owners,
they don't have time, they want results,
and honestly a lot to solve there just tons.
Solve people's problems. Easier said than done,
but it's a good reminder. In the end that's all
that matters. Something that I always think about
with people in your shoes is just how do you not
get overwhelmed and how do you know what to
pay attention to? How do you stay focused?
Any tips there for folks that are just
reading every day, a new announcement,
and then just like I just, how do
I? What do I do? There's too much.
It is the new problem of product development
in a way. There's too many possible paths you
can go down. There's too many ideas, there's too
many things you could do. And I mean obviously,
prioritization is always an important skill set
and has always been, but it's become an even more
important skill set right now because you have
to figure out what not to pay attention to. Our
general framework for it is to look for user
demand, and actually the easiest way to check
for user demand is to just see what has virality.
Usually, what has virality and what people want to
share and talk about, there's something at the
core of it that actually is interesting. Now,
it may not always be interesting in a
way that's like maybe it's a one-time
use case. Maybe it's not something that people
would do repeatedly. Maybe it's not something
you could build like a subscription business
off of, but oftentimes there's some things,
some core element of it that has resonated with
people. And if you can identify that core and then
mold it into fitting into your business, it's
actually a great way to identify what actually
works. And we have these tools right now. We don't
have to build anything. You can just kind talk
about it and people will share it, share the idea.
And you can measure how well the product might be
received even before you built anything. So it's
a great tool we use for prioritization. We spend
a lot of time on social media. Obviously, our app
is often used for social media, so a lot of our
employees will spend a lot of time on social
media. We look at what the trends are, what's
happening, and based on that we can get a pretty
good read of what might resonate well with people.
So as a leader of a company with people
constantly hearing about all the things happening,
is there any tools or processes or approaches
you've figured out to help people continue,
stay focused, not get excited about every
shiny new object and actually ship things? I
I mean honestly, it's all about incrementality
in a way. I think we do aim to ship every week.
Our engineering goal is every engineer
should ship a marketable product every
week. And so what's a marketable product
is a product that you can show to users
and the user might subscribe or pay
for the app just for that or come
to the app essentially just for that.
And that's why table stakes features,
let's say we're talking about word processor
or something. If you had auto format or just
table stakes stuff like justify alignment or
something, no one's going to come to your word
processor for justify alignment. You can market
that because it's obvious, of course it exists,
but if you did something unique that nobody else
has done, you can go and show that to people and
people will come to your app just for that.
And even if your app doesn't have a lot
of the obvious stuff, maybe it doesn't have
justify alignment, people will jump over that
just to use these new tools and new abilities
that you might be building and marketing. So we
try to do every engineer one marketable feature
per week, and a lot of that stuff may not work,
but a lot of it does work and we can figure
out obviously, where to put in more effort,
things that start to work, we double down on
those things, build more. People often complain
because think about it, in one week where we're
shipping, it's not complete, it's MVP, truly.
And we slice the hell out of it. We take
the design and we cut, cut, cut until we
can really say that it's going to be useless if
we cut anymore. We get that out and people come
in. And if things are going well, people will use
it despite all the problems that it might have,
and now people will complain and we'll have a
list of problems and we know what to do next.
That's a starting point essentially.
As long as we're shipping one a week,
we get a ton of volume of features and products
and directions we're releasing, cut a lot of
that. What remains expand from there. So it
works really well, and it keeps people focused.
I love the simplicity of that. I love
just how wild that sounds for a lot of
companies I imagine. Every engineer ships
a marketable feature or product every week.
Yes.
There's some people listening to this
and are just completely stressed out
by this idea and there's some
people listening who are like,
this is exactly how I want to work.
This is how every company should build.
Yep.
How do you maintain quality and make it
all cohesive? I imagine that's the big
trade-off. Just, any tricks there for folks
that want to maybe start operating this way.
Quality is not something you compromise
on most of the time. I think yes,
there's strategic compromises in quality, but
most of the time what you want to do is have a
bar for quality where people should come in and
if they're using the feature, it should work,
right? Of course. And the way to cut down on time,
and I think this is a mistake people make a lot of
the time, is when time is being pressured
downward, a lot of times engineers, PMS,
designers, they will cut on quality rather
than cutting on scope. And actually you can
cut on scope. It's actually, the method that
we use is we look at every element that's going
to take any time to build and we just say, what
if we remove this? Is the product still useful?
And we keep repeating that until we remove
whatever's left and we say it's going to
be useless at this point. And that becomes the
one-week project, right? It actually really works.
It narrows down to the core of what you're
really trying to ask. So for example, let's
say we wanted to build something to add an image
on your video or something like that, and this is
a really basic idea. I just made it up right now.
And you might imagine a design in which you import
your image from your camera roll, but before it
lands in your video you might want to remove the
background. You might want to change the hue and
saturation or something like that. And you might
expect a designer to design all of those features
and you let it design, but you really quickly
realize that you can cut all of that stuff.
You can cut the background or you can cut the
hue saturation. All you really need is pick.
And then there might be a picker. We need a
picker with a library, with a lot of different
type. What if you want to pull from the cloud?
What if you want to pull from the drive
or something like that? Cut all of that,
right? And essentially come down to the core,
which is just native picker from the camera,
lens, straight in the video, no UI. And that is
already, that should be useful. If that's not
useful, then anything else built on top of that is
also useless. So that's how we might go about it.
That last sentence is so key to
this. It's the core idea of ship
small iterative features before you
invest a lot in something to figure
out is there anything there, is
this worth spending weeks on?
Totally. And I think the coolest part of this
method is the first thing that the users will
come in, they'll use the thing, they'll import
images and the first thing they'll complain
about is what bothers them the most? Is it
human saturation? Is it background removal?
Is it picking from the cloud? You'll just
get the most complaints about that thing.
People will be like, and people will
be honest about it or they'll be like,
"This sucks. It doesn't even have
background removal. What kind of
image thing is this?" And you have
to take that feedback and just next
week you can ship in a single week all the
things that the user's complaining about.
And then they're like, wow, this
team is shipping like crazy.
Yes. Exactly.
Solve all my problems. So responsive. This
connects a common sign of product market fit,
which is when people are complaining about the
thing that means they actually care enough to
complain and that's a really good sign
if they're complaining about something.
It's very true, very true. If nobody
complains, it's almost red flag.
A lot of this is turning into an archeology of a
modern product team and startup. So I want to keep
digging. This is not where I was planning to go,
but this is awesome. I love that this approach of
every engineer shipping something every week
that's marketable connects directly to where
I started this conversation, which
is how do you stay above the noise?
And part of the answer is just ship stuff
constantly, and just continue to impress
people. Like, "Here's a new amazing
video feature." "Look at this thing."
Exactly. Yep. I think it's definitely key,
right? And there's enough area and enough scope
for that to happen. I think truly in normal
times it may not be possible to create that
much roadmap that quickly, but I think because
there's so much innovation underlying all this,
there is that scope available. The roadmap
almost seems unlimited, just truly.
Okay. The other question I imagine people
would be wondering is how do you work on
longer-term projects that take many weeks?
There's also infrastructure, I guess,
back-end stuff. So maybe answer those questions.
How do you think about long-term stuff and then
how do you deal with back-end stuff that
isn't a feature that anyone would care for?
Yep. Usually, we'll dedicate time to that
separately. For example, usually Q4 for us
is infrastructure quarter. We just go and
build all the infrastructure. Q4 is generally,
we've already delivered a ton of products
and stuff. We're feeling pretty good about
the rest of the year. Things are winding down.
Obviously, holidays and stuff coming up. And so
we spend all that time paying the technical debt.
I actually think there's a unique thing to think
here about technical debt in general. And as a
startup, your job is to take on technical debt
because that is how you operate faster than a
bigger company. Bigger companies don't take on
technical debt, they pay it usually right away. Or
they're paying back technical debt from the days
when they were a startup, and they took on a lot
of it. I mean Snaps, I used to work at Snap and
there was a lot of examples of that over there,
and I'm sure it happens at every other company.
And we think about it as like, well, is this
a problem we need to solve today or is this a
problem that the 50th engineer or the hundredth
engineer or the 500th engineer can solve? And
if it is a problem that a future engineer can
solve, we should use that future engineer now.
Essentially, that's what we're doing. And we're
saying we're going to push this to somebody in
the future. And by the way, if the company
fails, that engineer will never be hired and
all this won't matter anyways. So it's like
financial debt in many ways. Financial debt
is taken on to create leverage. It can be a good
thing like if you're buying a house, you take on
debt and you can buy something probably more
than you can afford without taking on debt.
And it's the same thing. You can create products
that you wouldn't be able to build with a small
team that you have by taking on strategic
technical debt. It's very positive actually.
Wow, this is such a cool idea. And where my mind
goes is that future engineer
may be an AI agent engineer.
Exactly, yeah.
Just solving problems, just
on technical debt in you.
Exactly. Some engineer in the future Five-hundred
engineer many years from now will get a promotion
because they solve this big problem that
those really bad early engineers created.
So obviously, there's a line to this.
There's only so much debt you can take
on before you become a big problem.
Is there any thoughts on just that
balance of just how much is too much and how if
it's enough for a net feature engineer or just-
Yeah, I mean I think generally the rule
of thumb is every piece of debt that you
take on you have to pay interest on. So
if there is debt that you've taken on,
there's 1% or 2% of your time that is going
to be taken away every day in maintaining
bugs and issues and restarts and crashes and
things that are happening with that. Because
you did it the fast way, something's going
to go wrong with it. Every day. 1% of your
time will be taken away. If you take on enough
debt, you'll be paying 80 or 90% interest and
you'll not have any time to do anything new.
You'll just be paying interest. That's all.
And that's when you get into the mode of like,
oh, we're just keeping the lights on. We don't
have any engineers to do anything. We're just
keeping the lights on. That's the failure case
for a startup. So in a way, you have a
technical debt runway. Once you run out,
once you've taken on too much debt. And if you
haven't delivered value in that time, enough
value to hire the engineers to pay the interest
or just pay off the debt, you'll get in trouble.
I love that. That's such a nice heuristic of
how to think about when to invest in something.
I don't want to go down this too far, but just a
thought I have is ... because sometimes there's
big technical decisions you got to make that
impact the way everything builds or is built
in the future. I imagine those you spend
more time on and take really seriously.
Definitely. Yeah, I mean I think as long as it's
possible for wherever it's like a two-way door,
you can do whatever you want. I mean this is
a classic methodology. If it's A one-way door,
it's worth thinking about and sort of
doing correctly at least as much as the
one-way door would matter to you in the future.
How much do your engineers use Cursor and tools
like that to build? How much
is AI helping your team move?
A hundred percent, yeah. I mean everybody's
using it. It's super helpful. I mean even I'm
using it honestly. Yeah, it's a huge
multiplier for the team, no doubt.
And is a Cursor specifically. Is there
anything else that you guys found useful?
Yeah, we are using Cursor. Yep. We've tried all
the different tools. We were using Devin as well,
which is another, you know? That's more
advanced, I guess. It's solving bugs for you.
Yeah, Devin's basically, I think it's 500 bucks a
month and it's like an AI engineer
that you just chat within Slack.
Exactly, yeah. In a way, these
are the types of things that us
as a startup can do that bigger
companies can't just, you know,
they can't just pull in Devin. They have to get
30 lawyers in the room first before that happens.
And they're all called Devin, these are
like agents. Everyone's going to have
hundreds of Devins working at their company.
Exactly. You can have multiple Devins. I actually
heard you can have a manager of
Devins who's managing Devins.
I love that managers are all getting layered,
like unlayered and then they're going to have AI
managers. That's the ultimate bait and switch.
Yep.
Okay. Is there anything else that
in how you operate and build the way
you build product or set up the way you
build product that you think is really
unique and interesting that other
people might be able to learn from?
Our process is a bit interesting in that
way. We have a design team, we have a PM
team. We're very early on those teams right now.
And obviously, we have engineering. And we have
all the different surface areas. So iOS, Android,
web. There's backend team, machine learning team,
research team. So generally, when we're
developing products, we may start off with
a PM first approach where we're finding some
sort of overall issue that we want to take on
some new area or pillar we want to take on and
then creating sort of product specs from there.
But a lot of times we'll also start the opposite
way. We'll first design something without even
having any idea of what or why we're doing it,
but we'll design a bunch of different things and
then we'll sit down with the PMs and look at
the designs and just go over one and the next
and the next until we find interesting
things and ideas that pop out of that.
And a lot of times that leads to us discovering
things that we wouldn't have discovered if we were
just too focused on the metrics and the numbers
and things like that. So it's almost reversing
the process a little bit and starting with design
first, but it can often result in finding unique
ideas basically. I also think that we have a
unique setup in how we create our roadmap. So
normally you have a single roadmap and we actually
divide a roadmap into two different roadmaps. So
we have what we think of as the public roadmap.
This is basically what people have asked us for.
So there's all these surface areas where we
receive user feedback and we look at all that
feedback and people will ask for features. They'll
ask for, I want background removal, I want to
undo and redo, I want to upload longer videos,
whatever it is, a bunch of different features.
And we'll just make a list of
that. And just like anything else,
we'll prioritize it and we'll look at how many
people it affects and what the possible markets
are and just get it done basically one at a time.
But these are all features that every competitor
knows about. These are public. If a user's asking
us for it, they're asking everybody for it. And
every team has essentially more or less the same
list and everybody's prioritizing it. And yeah,
sure you can win a little by extra nicely
prioritizing it or winning a little in
prioritization or execution or something,
but it's not going to be a game changer in
terms of winning against your competition. So
we have a second roadmap which we think of as
a secret roadmap. So this is a roadmap
that nobody asked for anything on this
like literally, nobody has ever asked for it.
And if a user were shown something on it, they
might be like, "I don't need this. I don't know
what this is." But given our unique vantage point,
our unique understanding of the problem set, the
user space and the technology, we've come up with
some special ideas that we think will completely
revolutionize how something is used where we can
truly change the behavior of the user. I think
that's what at is at the core of. It's like
people are doing things one way if we're able
to show them another way. And once they try it,
they never go back. That's what a product
is, that's success. And those are the types
of ideas that we put on the secret roadmap.
These are things we never talk about publicly,
never tell anybody about, and we announce them
and just give them to users and see the effects.
A lot of this we come up with through
brainstorming. So we do actually do quarterly
brainstorming, company-wide, everybody's included
like everybody from. It's not just a product team
thing, it's like engineering, recruiting,
everybody's included in. And we all come
up with marketing, obviously, everybody comes up
with ideas, we vote on the ideas, rank the ideas,
and then the product team takes over from there
and thinks about like feasibility and technology
and what the different things could be. So this
is a way where we can take all that noise that
people are getting, everybody's browsing social
media, seeing all these different things that are
blowing up, these models and advancements and we
can get all that information together and provide
a unique internal roadmap where how are we going
to approach and create value out of all of these
different advances that are happening.
So that's our general methodology. And
a lot of times the biggest wins will
come from the secret roadmap. That's
the game-changing stuff. It's not going to be the
user requests usually that are going to do that.
I love just how calling it the secret roadmap
makes it extra interesting. [inaudible 00:30:07]
Exactly, yeah. It's a secret.
It's a secret. I'm not even going
to ask you what's on that secret
roadmap. You can't tell me.
What's an example of feature
that came out of that secret roadmap
that's been a big deal for you guys?
Tons. I mean, I'll give you an example from a
long time ago. One of the first AI features we
added after the app initially took off was this
feature called eye contact. So this was a feature
where if you're recording something, oftentimes
people who are new to recording a video might read
from a script or a teleprompter or something like
that and they might have that off-screen. So it
looks like you're reading and it's not great from
the perspective of the video itself or the viewer
of the video. So we had this feature where it
basically shifts your eyes to look at the camera.
And we were actually the first company to build
this. We worked with Nvidia on this. It's actually
really interesting because when we originally
reached out to Nvidia about this. They were not
sure why we needed this. And they actually gave
it to us pretty openly and were excited about
some sort of partnership of how can we get this
technology into something that could be useful.
But we saw this creator use case which was unique,
and it was one of the ideas that came out of the
brainstorm and we threw it on there, we launched
it. It was a huge success. I mean, I'll be honest,
the video, the ad that we made, a social media
post that demonstrates this was so viral,
it was made in basically every language around
the world. It still till today gets millions of
views. We find reposts and reposts of that thing
that other people have created that get millions
and millions and millions of views because
people are like, "Wow, this is a great idea."
And now it's been copied the hell out of,
I think it's available basically on every
app you can imagine. For good reason of course.
But that's one of the ideas that came out of it.
You talked about how you come up with
these secret roadmap ideas. I'm just
intrigued by this. I'm going to
spend a little more time here.
Does your team ever work with an AI LLM to help
brainstorm? I imagine that's where things will go,
where you're actually jamming. The AI
agent is brainstorming along with you.
Honestly, I would like for it to go there. It
hasn't gone there yet. We haven't done that
exactly, because the problem is context. And I
think just the context of understanding the user,
the use case, it's so abstract. Even right now,
I feel like I understand our users obviously,
but I can't exactly verbalize why that is
or how that is, a little bit abstract. And
I spend a lot of time with RPMs and designers
imparting anything that I understand and I've
learned over the many years I've been working
on this, how do I impart this to them? But then
it's a challenge because I can't even verbalize
it myself. And so it's an extra hard challenge
to figure out how do I put this context? How
do I make it available to an LLM when I can't
even put it into words exactly. And honestly,
this is probably my own feeling but, and I need
to work on this, but there is something to it.
I do remember at Snap for example, I think one
of the most unique things about Snap and the
CEO Evan Spiegel was that he had an unmatched
understanding of the user. I think years and
years and years of the company's existence past,
almost a decade. And nobody understood the user
like he did. He would come up with ideas that
everybody would disagree with and we would
launch them and there would be hits, just
hits after hits. And nobody would understand why.
Everyone would line up and be like, "Great." Round
of applause for everyone, but no one knew why.
A great example of that is a lot of this was
figured out in retrospect too. I think there was a
point at which Snap declared that they're a camera
company and a lot of people laugh at them and
said, "Camera. What are we making digital cameras
or something?" Or, "Why is it a camera company?"
But I think at the core of it was this idea that
Snapchat opens to the camera and that was
actually the differentiator. That actually
that small decision was holding the entire
company against all competition because when
the moment passes where your friend is doing
something funny and you need to capture it,
you're not going to open Instagram or anything
else because it doesn't open to the camera. You're
going to open Snapchat because you can capture
it right away. And Instagram can never copy that
because all their metrics are going to go down
as soon as they do that. So that is a fundamental
understanding. And I figured this out much
later, actually, but it's such a powerful idea.
I'm glad you talked about Snap. That's
where I definitely wanted to go. This is
where I was going to start. So I'm glad we
circled back to your experience at Snap. So
the reason I am interested in this is if
you think about social networks like Snap
is basically the last social network to have
launched and stuck around other than TikTok,
which I don't think is a social network.
I think it's just this content platform.
I don't think you're really interacting
with people really. And that was 2011 when
it launched. So it's been like 15 years since
the last social network launch that has worked.
And I think it's interesting also because there's
rarely been a lot of insight into just how Snap
operates. You were there really early. You're
a big deal at Snap. You built a lot of really
important features. So I wanted to spend a
little time here, and it feels like a lot of
things you learn from Snap you're bringing to your
company now. So let me just ask, I think you may
have answered this, but I'm curious if there's
something else here just broadly maybe other
than Ev's brain, what do you think was core to
Snap being a successful consumer social product?
There were a couple of different things
that went well. I do think for a company
like Snapchat or Social Network, the core product
market fit can be extremely strong. Essentially,
the reason that people are downloading it,
the way that it's spreading, the way that
it's distributing, the way that it's inviting
friends or sending Snaps or whatever it is,
that product market fit can be so strong sometimes
that it can be hard to actually build something
because you actually can't tell if what you're
building is what's responsible for growing the
thing or if it's actually hurting it and it's
growing despite what you're doing basically.
And I think because of that, it actually sometimes
teaches people the wrong things. It teaches people
that the contrarian thing that they were doing
was right when it was actually just wrong and the
company just grew despite it. And I think some
of the things that Snap did well and it needed
to do really was to continue innovating, right?
Because for a company like Snap, it has a ton of
competition. Social networks are monopolies by
nature and there's a lot of reasons for Facebook
or any other social network to stop the growth
of Snapchat. And they tried, they tried really,
really hard. And the way that Snap was avoiding
that was by innovating. I think the core of it was
the setup that they had, which was very unique.
I've never seen anything like it. I've worked
at a bunch of different companies, but obviously
there's a CEO and the CEO was very product-led,
his designer himself, but he surrounded
himself with the design team. That was
sort of the central team in the company. And the
design team was like 10, 12 people. Basically,
pretty small, even at 5, 6,000
employees it was that small still.
Oh wow. At 6 or 6,000 employees. The design
team was, you said how many, five or six people?
10, 12 people.
10, 12. And to add to that, there's no PMs
really for a long time. That was before.
For a long time, yeah.
Big difference.
Initially, there were no PMs at all. PMs were
introduced with monetization. Once monetization
was a big sort of element, that's where PMs
came in. Today, I think there's a ton of,
or there's an adequate number of PMs across the
company, but there was a long period of time,
especially when the innovation was happening, when
there were a much, much smaller number of PMs and
it was very designer led. But at the same time, I
think that's slightly misleading in the way that
these weren't your sort of average designers.
These were designers who were actually PMs as
well. That's what the secret sauce was. They
were able to not just design but also do the
PM part which is a big responsibility. It's a
lot of work, especially for that many employees,
but it gave the CEO a way to have granular
control over what exactly was being launched
in which part of the app at all times.
Because he could meet with a set of 10 or 12
people and know every change that was happening
that was user impacting. A lot of changes were
being worked on that were infrastructure and
types of things that keep going on in the back
end where you're improving ranking and whatever
that might be, performance and things like that.
And those were not usually his concern. He was
concerned with what UI are we adding where? And
if you needed to add UI to the app, you needed
it designed. And if there's no designers in the
company, except for a handful who talk directly
to the CEO, you create a very granular control
over what's being launched in the company. So
everything needed to be approved by Evan. If
you hadn't approved it, it's not going out. So the
design team actually held a lot of power in that.
This is awesome. So what I'm hearing
partly is, I don't know if this is true,
but it feels true that to make a consumer
app that is successful and breaks through,
you almost need a singular mind that continues
to stay in the weeds on everything. And the
way Evan did that is very close to the
design team who basically ran product.
That's very true. Yeah, it's very
true. And he was able to keep the
context of the entire app in
his head at the same time. He
knew the interdependencies and what we're
doing and why we're doing it. And so that
gave him just very granular control
over the company's product roadmap.
It makes me think about Brian Chesky and Airbnb
is a consumer product, it's not a social network,
but I wonder if that's just an interesting
insight just for consumer products. They
will generally do better if there's one
person with a really ... the right sort
of combination of experiences, insights, and
just they continue to run and own every detail.
Definitely. And also the ability to
bring about change, the ability to
truly energize an entire organization to
do something that's not just incremental
but fundamental.
>
Exactly.
Founder mode. That's what
we're getting to, basically.
Yeah, ever heard of it. Okay. And
then you said that these designers,
so I know it's famous that Snap had no PMs for
a long time. Designers were PMs. This point
you made about the designers where PME is really
important. I think a lot of people look at this,
they're like, "Amazing. We're just going to
hire just designers. We don't need all these
PMs. Slow everything down. Just tell us what
not to build." Can you just talk about the
level of these designers? What allowed them to
be as successful as they were without any PMs?
Yeah, I mean I think what was expected from the
designers now was not just the ability to design,
the skill set of designing, which all of them
were IC designers by the way. And there were
no reports, so they weren't allowed to
have reports actually. And so they were
designing everything themselves, but they
also had to have the leadership skills to
go figure out the roadmap, write all the
documents, work with the different teams,
figure out shipping schedules and just know
everything, not just the technical and the
engineering part, but the UX and the UI and
the product needs and why are we doing this.
The roadmap, there's just a ton to keep in mind.
And that means that it was a job that was just
highly ... it was very high workload. No doubt,
very high workload. These people work really
hard and they were paid highly too. For what it's
worth, they were paid way higher than you would
expect designers or PMs or engineers to be paid
with quarterly bonuses and all kinds of things.
That's interesting. And it reminds, people
always say, "Why do you need PMs?" There's
like someone has to do the work that
a PM does. They're not sitting around
doing nothing. And it's important to note
the person that will take on the PME work,
they have to be good at it and enjoy
it. And a lot of designers don't want
to be doing writing docs and organizing
stakeholders and getting alignment and ...
100%, 100%. That's why it was so hard to find
those people who were able to do two things. I
actually think there's an insight in there is
innovation between when you're merging craft
right between two different functions. And I
do think there's something special about one
person doing two different functions or at
least being able to do. And I think a lot of
unique insight and innovation can come from that.
I actually think on my personal side, I eventually
joined the design team. I started at Snap on the
engineering team. I eventually joined the design
team over the last two years that I was at Snap.
And a big part of what I did there was create this
function called design engineering. And that was
actually a different combination. It wasn't the
designer PM. It was the designer engineer. The
person who can think of the UX design it and
also build it and launch it, all of those things.
And we saw both the ability to take designers and
teach them engineering and take engineers and
teach them design as part of that. Obviously,
the reason that we created that function was very
different. It was actually to continue innovating
as the company got bigger. One of the problems
that we identified was that as the company got
bigger and bigger and there's like 500 engineers,
1,000 engineers, 2,000 engineers, 3,000, suddenly
it just becomes very difficult to do everything.
Everything is a six-month project or a one-year
project. Every product is a massive investment of
500 engineers and a lot of time. And so you really
have to pick your bets. If you get it wrong,
if you are innovating and trying to create new
products and you spend 500 engineers for a year
and it doesn't work, it's a big problem. You're
going to be in trouble, especially if we're
coming like Snap where everybody was copying
what they're doing so they had to constantly
innovate, create new stuff and push the bounds.
I think Evan's philosophy was always he didn't
fight the things that were getting copied,
right? Stories got copied pretty much straight
up. A lot of things that Snap created got copied,
but he was more of the mindset of like, "Let's
expand the pie, do something new and push the
boundaries." We'll keep innovating basically.
And so to do that with that scale of a company
becomes really hard. And so we had this idea
of let's create a small team where we can go
and pretest a lot of these ideas because we
had a lot of ideas and we can't go and build
all of these things. So the idea was create a
small team of these design engineers, people
who are able to do the entire product design
engineering process in their head and can put
together early versions of the product, which we
would actually bake into the Snapchat app itself.
And we were able to even test, for example, run
a test in Australia, see how it's performing.
Run a test in a couple of high schools, just a
couple of high schools, see how people behave.
And that way we already have data on how this
might perform in a real world environment,
but we haven't built it to production
level. It's a prototype, essentially.
It's how a startup might build something.
The same idea of what we're doing at our
company now, build fast, get it out there, get
feedback, understand whether it works or not,
and then work with the engineering team to
build it at a scale. Once we understand the
product and the dynamics, then it makes sense to
put on 500 engineers for six months to build it.
So that was a big part of it. I think the nice
thing that came out of it that was completely
unexpected but actually transformational for
me in a way was obviously in big organizations,
alignment is a big issue. How do you get everybody
on the same page? And a big part of a PM's job is
actually to create alignment and it can be a
lot of work because you go talk to all these
stakeholders and get them on the same page.
But one of the insights that we had,
which was unique was as the company gets bigger,
you can actually create alignment by causing
internal virality. If there's enough people in the
company, it actually starts acting like a consumer
base might. If you share something interesting
with someone, they will share it with somebody
else because they think it's interesting and you
can actually create virality inside a company.
So one thing that we would do is we would
create these prototype products. We would
just go into an area, redo a bunch of stuff,
create these prototype products that didn't
exist in Snapchat normally, and then we would
just share the build and it would explode. It
would just go viral inside the company. Day after
day we would hear from engineers, then managers,
then VPs, then eventually from Evan being
like, "Oh my God, everyone's talking about
this. Why am I the last one to hear about it?"
So it would create instant alignment across the
company of this is exciting, this is something
that we want to get behind. And everyone would
be asking, "When are we doing this? When
is this happening? I see someone's already
working on it." So it was a great way to do
that. And once we really understood that the
product actually had good dynamics and we had
tested it, it was a great way to get it out in
front of everybody and create this idea of, "Hey,
we're all working on this. This is the future."
Today's episode is brought to you by Coda.
I personally use Coda every single day to
manage my podcast and also to manage my
community. It's where I put the questions
that I plan to ask every guest that's
coming on the podcast. It's where I put
my community resources. It's how I manage
my workflows. Here's how Coda can help you.
Imagine starting a project at work and your
vision is clear. You know exactly who's doing
what and where to find the data that you need to
do your part. In fact, you don't have to waste
time searching for anything because everything
your team needs from project trackers and OKRs
to documents and spreadsheets lives in one tab
all in Coda. With Coda's collaborative all in
one workspace, you get the flexibility
of docs, the structure of spreadsheets,
the power of applications, and the intelligence
of AI all in one easy to organize tab.
Like I mentioned earlier, I use Coda every single
day. And more than 50,000 teams trust Coda to
keep them more aligned and focused. If you're a
startup team looking to increase alignment and
agility, Coda can help you move from planning to
execution in record time. To try it for yourself,
go to coda.io/lenny today and get six months
free of the team plan for startups. That's
coda.io/lenny to get started for free and get
six months of the team plan. coda.io/lenny.
Another thread I want to follow up on is
prototyping. It feels like that is where
a lot of PM work is going is getting straight
to a prototype versus design or versus PRDs.
And it feels like that's something that
you did and worked super well. Basically,
it's a team to prototype ideas that in theory
now you can just build really quickly with AI.
So I think that's really interesting,
seeing where the feature's going, just ...
100%. Getting things in people's hands, trying
it out. Oftentimes, unless you truly try it out,
in design, it can, in theory, look
good with all the perfect conditions,
but when you actually use it, you realize
it's actually not that useful, for example.
Or when you give it to users. And some of this
is intuition, honestly, just like anything else,
but there's nothing like getting something
in the hands of users at the end of the day.
I love how many of these things you
brought over to your current company,
and I'm trying to think about, one is this
idea of just constantly innovating feels
like that's informed and tell me what
I'm missing, but that feels like that's
informed. The ship market will feature every
single week. This idea of getting design,
starting almost with design versus PM a lot
of times. I'm curious why you don't even go
straight to prototype in those cases. Is
it just the tools aren't there yet or?
I mean, I think our shipping process is
fast enough that within a week we can
get it out anyways. So that way we just
get user feedback, which is even better.
And then the other really interesting thing,
I'm trying to visualize that triangle of
a product team, the triad of PM, engineer,
design. Feels like you guys at Snap took the
corners, not the corners, the line of that
triangle. And you have design engineers. You have
design PMs. I imagine engineers were PME already.
They're very product oriented PMs. Did you have
a function called design PMs? Probably not.
I mean honestly, it's interesting.
Sorry, engineer PMs.
Yeah, engineer PMs should be a thing, I feel like,
or every engineer should strive
to understand the product, right?
Yeah. A lot of companies operate that way. Like
Stripe, I think they had hundreds of engineers
before they hired the first PM because I think
the engineers were doing what they did at Snap to
do the PM work. So it feels like at your company
you don't operate that way. It feels like you have
PMs, engineers, designers. Talk about why
you decided not to approach things that way.
I do think PM is a very valuable
function. I think it may be actually,
and maybe I'll get roasted for this,
but I think at the end of the day,
not hiring PMs at Snap might've been one of
those decisions where it actually succeeded
despite that and because someone needs to do that
work. If you don't have enough people to do it,
then nobody truly owns it and then it doesn't
really happen. Or if it doesn't happen, no one's
responsible, which is not the right structure
you want in an organization. So I think though,
that being said, there was something unique to be
said about what if a designer had the PM mindset.
It's actually the same idea as what if an
engineer had the PM mindset and then you
get even crazier. What if the PM had a design
and engineering mindset? I think all we're
talking about is everybody truly understanding
all the functions that they're working with.
Having a fundamental, broad understanding
of the functions they're working with.
At Captions, we're actually going even one step
further than that. Why shouldn't the PM understand
marketing? I think that's actually the biggest
opportunity for PMs to understand is how do we
actually find the users who have this problem? I
think that's a big part of solving the problem. I
have a unique take on this in terms of I actually
think PMs should own all the way to marketing in a
way. And the reason is that if you think about
marketing, it's expanding the surface area of
the product, right? It's like search marketing is
just placing a button to your product in Google.
Facebook ads is just placing a button to
your app in Facebook. It's almost like you
work at Facebook. You work at Facebook,
you have a button in the app somewhere,
you make a specific thing and people show up.
The funnel begins there and you have all the
metrics all the way from the beginning, all the
way from when the user tapped on the button in
Facebook and then they went down all the steps
and then they landed on some onboarding screen
and they did the thing, they used the application.
That's where the journey begins. And all of that
is, in a way, it's a product. It's the same
skillset. Understanding users from that point
on is I think that's fundamental. How do we not
do that today? We should be. So that's how we
think about stuff. But I think the core idea
is that every function should understand every
other function deeply as much as possible and
maybe even to the level where they can operate
in that function. And that just increases the
likelihood that all decisions being made in the
company at the micro level will be optimized
for all possible parts of the funnel that
different people are essentially looking after.
That's something we think about quite a bit.
I completely agree with that take.
It's interesting that at Airbnb,
Brian was famous for changing the titles of
all product managers to product marketing
manager for exactly this point because he's like-
Makes sense.
... you should be doing the marketing, you
shouldn't just be building the thing. And to me,
I've always assumed as a PM, your job is for this
thing to grow and to get adopted and be loved.
Of course.
So it's interesting people don't
already think of it that way.
I agree.
But obviously, it's hard to learn the
skills of being awesome and paid growth
and SEO and product marketing, messaging,
positioning, but I completely agree. That's
such an important element of building a
product. You're not just building a thing,
hope it works. Goodbye. So I love that that's
how you think about it. And so I guess when
you hire PMs, it sounds like you look for
marketing instinct and some experiences.
100%. And at least the ability and
instinct to be able to learn it.
Yeah. Okay, so I'm going to share one other thing
that I thought as you were talking that I think is
really interesting and it comes up a bunch on this
podcast and this connects back to Ev and what we
can learn from his success. So Patrick Olson once
tweeted this tweet that has really stuck with me,
which is it was around user research and the
way he described it is user research isn't
go to user research that informs what
you build and then you build that. It's
instead you do user research, it informs
the mental model you have as a leader,
a product builder of what your customers need and
what pains they have, and you adjust that model
in your head and then that's how you decide
what to build. And it feels like Ev is very
much that. His head was learning what people
need, teens in particular, and it just worked.
Yeah, I think it's very spot on. I would say
though Snap didn't like user research as a
function for the longest time. I think there
was one user researcher in the company until,
again, 5,000 employees, the post IPO basically.
But I think the people that were making a lot
of the product decisions and the CEO himself, of
course, were very steeped in how the user behaves
and how they operate. They understood that.
I do think Snap also had a unique way of
thinking about how to determine if a product
is within scope or out of scope of what their
mission was. And I think a lot of companies
use the cyber framework and we try to as well,
but essentially, the idea at the core was
that they want to enable private sharing in
a safe way. So I think that makes it clear that
certain things just are out of scope for Snap.
It's actually one of the reasons why Snap wasn't
the company to discover "short form video," TikTok
style stuff because it was just against the
nature of the company to even try something.
It was against the mission of the company. Public
sharing means possibly bullying and bad behaviors,
which is exactly what Snap was trying to avoid.
We don't want those behaviors to develop on the
app. So for example, on Instagram stories,
you can share somebody else's stories to
your followers. I can take your story and share
it to my followers. You can't do that on Snap.
And there was a discussion about should we
do this? No, because it can enable bullying.
Essentially, you're not consenting to your
thing being shared to my followers and that's
essentially bad. So a lot of it was done based on
this type of pillar-based thinking of this is our
mission, this is what we're trying to do, does
it fit within or is it outside? If it's outside,
we don't do it no matter what the cost
of it is, no matter how exciting it is.
And even on Spotlight, the big challenge was
like how do you take something like that and
put that inside the Snap mission? So that
was something we worked on quite a bit. Yeah,
I mean I think there's tons of stories about
earlier versions. I mean Snap almost had
essentially what is TikTok earlier
than TikTok existed and it died out
because it didn't align with the mission
essentially, but happy to get into it.
Yeah, that actually would be really
interesting, because interesting that
these things are important. It's important to
have these clear values in the mission of the
company and to not focus on things that
are outside that. And then you hear these
stories of they had TikTok potentially. So yeah,
whatever you can share there, that'd be awesome.
Yeah, I mean, I don't know if you remember this,
but there was this product called Our Stories,
and essentially it was MyStory, but it
was a public story. And it started off
with this idea of campus stories where you
can post to your campus and other people can
see it. And that actually started creating
a lot of virality because essentially people
would post. There was viral moments truly
where people would post stuff like, "Oh,
I think two people fell in love on it or something
like that." Those types of things really went
viral and it had really good engagement.
But at the end of the day, the problem was
that we were against algorithmic essentially
ranking of those types of things. So there
was a curation team that was looking through
every single one so that there's no negative
behaviors happening essentially on the app.
That was just not scalable. Even though it
had really high engagement and was doing
well, it just wasn't feasible to have a
person looking at every single thing posted
to determine whether it's appropriate or not.
It ended up dying out, but it looked like what
was an early version of TikTok before it had
launched. So I think in a way though it was
a good thing because I think Snap does have
a mission and I think it is solving a problem. I
do think there is a bifurcation of social media
at this point. There is what you traditionally
think of as social networking where you share
things with your friends. And by the way, remember
the days where that used to be the way that apps
would go viral. You would share things with
your friends and then they would share with
their friends and everybody was worried about
friend sharing and how do you send to a friend
and can I text message my friend or whatever.
That time is over. Virality now happens
through a completely different mechanism. It
happens through essentially algorithms that
are deciding whether your piece of content is
worth showing to an arbitrary number of people,
and this is the new age of social media. It's
TikTok, it's YouTube Shorts and Instagram Reels
and so on. And I think actually it's changing
the fundamental nature of how people interact,
fundamental nature of how things go viral. And
I actually think from a regulatory perspective,
we should be thinking these as differently.
On one side, you have something where you're
deciding who sees something and then on
the other side, you have something where
the company is deciding which means that
it's semi curated, right? It's actually
the company's voice. So yeah, I don't know,
should Section 230 apply to that? I have no
idea. Or maybe not. Maybe we're thinking about
this the wrong way, so it should be interesting.
Wow. All right. Well, I'm out of my depth on the
legality decision, so I'm going to not follow
that thread, but I imagine there's something
really interesting there actually. So you've
been talking about just how much things are
changing and I just wanted to follow that
thread and specifically, you guys are at the
cutting edge of what is possible with AI video.
Yes.
It feels like we're approaching and maybe we're
there. This world where you have no idea if it's
real or AI. I'm curious, first of all, just how
far you think we are from that and second of all,
the implications on the world where you
can just generate any video you want.
It's fundamental. At the end of the day,
a time where video images, audio can't be
trusted actually hasn't existed for a while. If
you think about ... I mean there was a world in
the 1800s where there was no video or audio or
images and everything was proven by he said,
she said for the most part. And it's possible
that if everything can be generated and anything
can be created and it looks just as real as
if it were real and there's no way to tell,
then we might actually return to that world
where there's no way to prove anything
besides physical evidence or he said, she said.
And I think that's scary, but also possibly opens
a bunch of new opportunity for someone to figure
out how to solve this problem. I think it's going
to be a big problem. I do think today, we are
almost there in terms of creating absolutely
photorealistic video. I mean the very recent
models, a very cutting edge is just about ... It
feels like a few centimeters away from achieving
it, but I do think to fully get there to the
point where it cannot be differentiated
at all, it's still a couple of years away.
I also think that it is use case driven in a way.
I think thinking about Captions for a second,
we take a unique view on what type of video we
want to focus on. Video generation and text to
video generation. If you look at it today,
it's all silent video. There's no audio and
it's often what you think of as stop video or
B-roll, right? You can actually make a movie
with B-roll. And a lot of a movie or a TV show or
a social media post or an ad actually is dialogue
or monologue. That's actually what it is is people
talking to each other, to the camera, interacting.
That's actually what makes true story.
B-roll is supportive elements that are
showing up to set the scene or something like
maybe before the scene opens, you see a few shots
of New York City or LA or something, and then you
jump into the room and now two people are talking.
So our goal is to solve the talking video problem.
How do we create video where people are delivering
dialogue or monologue or things like that? And
that's what we focus on purely. And there actually
isn't a lot of work happening in that area today
and it's not a solved problem. We're getting
there, we're getting closer and closer, but
today's models actually bifurcate a little bit.
So there's a set of companies today that
are able to create these types of what we're
talking about is avatar videos. They're using this
technology called neural rendering. It's actually
not a technology that's affected by the
transformer and diffusion model revolution
or the large model revolution, essentially.
This is a technology that existed separately
and it doesn't have anything to do with the AI
growth happening right now. It just happens to
produce semi-realistic outputs, but it actually
stops at some point because it's not clear how
it becomes generalizable in every situation.
It has to be trained on people individually. So
you might ingest a little bit of video of you and
then you can generate you. And so it's a different
technology and a different outcome, essentially.
And a bunch of companies using this type of model,
a bunch of companies are doing general text
to video with no audio today. These are large
generative models and they have the capability
to do more, but that frontier just hasn't been
reached yet. I think there's no doubt in
anybody's mind on the research side that
it is 100% solvable. It's just like somebody
has to go do it and we haven't gotten there
yet. Nobody has had the time to go and do that
yet. So that's where we're at, essentially.
We're working purely on large generative models
for talking videos. So that's our core focus. I do
think though, from a safety perspective, we have
a unique framework or how we think about it. So
generally videos divide into two categories.
So for us, we think on one side of what is
documentation, so this is the type of video that
it could be a personal video where you're taking a
video with your friends and you're hanging out,
you're at a restaurant. It's documenting what
happened. You had fun, whatever it was, it's for
your memories. And there's a non-personal version
of this which is like, oh, it's like a reporter
documenting a crime or something that happened or
whatever it is and who was involved, where was it?
Maybe it was a natural disaster or something, and
this is for history. We want to see what happened.
And there's actually no benefit to AI-generated
video in any of this. Actually, all of this,
it's just negative. It's all negative. If we
are generating fake versions of reality to
fool people, there's just nothing good about
that. And we want to stay away from that,
essentially. We want to design products
and build products that make it difficult to use
for that particular use case, for anything that
falls within that. And on the other side,
you have what we think of as storytelling.
Now this could be ads, it could be social media
posts, it could be TV, movies. All of these
things are storytelling. They're designed for
entertainment, they're designed for fun. And
nobody believes if you watch a Geico commercial,
you're not thinking that the gecko is real selling
insurance somewhere out there. You know that
this is fabricated and it's for entertainment.
And same with reality TV even, right? It's called
reality TV. It's definitely not reality and social
media, ads, all this stuff falls in the category.
And if we can enable more people to tell stories
and entertain other people and get their
message out there, that is pure positive.
This is where we want to focus. And a lot of
our effort in the product and design process
goes into how do we design products and build
products that specifically make it really hard
to use on one side and really easy to use on
the other side. And that's the real challenge.
That's really helpful. Something that I'm
really curious about as you're chatting is
ByteDance just released a really amazing
model. I was actually just looking at it
where you put a photo in, I think, and it
just creates a video of this person talking
in all these different ways. Where does that
fall amongst the buckets you just described?
I think that falls exactly in the area that
we're in, which is talking people and that's
what they're going after as well there. So
that's actually one of the first examples of
a large model that a larger company has released
where it's able to do these dialogue or monologue
videos. And I mean you yourself, you've seen it,
so I'm not going to describe it too much, but as
you know, it's highly expressive. It doesn't
look like an avatar video. It looks like ...
Yeah, it's wild.
And that's because of the technology that's
used is fundamentally different. It's just
like this is using a true large diffusion model
is what they use. Whereas most companies that
are working on avatar technology are actually
using something pretty basic in comparison.
How long has it been since that
Will Smith spaghetti video?
Just to give us a reference
of how fast things are moving?
Oh my god, it's been so fast, right?
I think it's a year.
Amazing.
Or is it like two years?
I think it's probably about a
year and a half, two years. Right?
Wow. We'll link to that video and then
you could tell basically that video is
the state of the art of AI video one to
two years ago. And then we'll link to
this other Omni something. I forget what it's
called. I'm just showing what it's like today.
Geez, Louise. Okay, final question and
this is around something that I know
you have a really interesting insight on,
which is that you see marketing using AI video
basically as the final frontier of how people
will experience AI is marketing, is seeing it
in marketing channels. Talk about why you think
that's the case and just what that looks like.
It comes back to what we were talking about
before where the reality is that no matter how
interesting, advanced and amazing a technology
is, science fiction has become reality. We were
talking about this. What was literally science
fiction on TV is real now and most people still
don't even know about it, to be honest.
My parents live in India and they are the
only ones in the neighborhood that know about
ChatGPT and they write these amazing notes to
the community just with all these words.
And people are just like, "How did you get
so good at writing?" And they're not telling
anybody, but there's still a ton of people
who don't even know that these advancements have
happened. And so adaption is actually much slower,
even for the most exciting things. Of course, in
tech circles, everybody's talking about it, but
the reality is it takes a while to get out there.
And I think for companies that are going to
succeed, they're going to have to figure out how
to market these products so that they can be the
ones to reach all these people that have the
problems that they're now able to solve. And
we think about that every day. So on that note,
as a consumer product, we spend a bunch of time
and money on marketing our products, and we often
use performance channels and all kinds of things,
but about a year ago, we would run AI video in
ads and things like that, and we would get all
these comments of people being like, "Oh my
God, this is so fake. Don't show me this."
And around that time, the technology got
just about good enough that suddenly,
those comments stopped happening and suddenly, you
could get performance that was even better than
actually recording with a person because you could
just try more things. You could just generate 30,
40 possibilities and one of them would win and
it would win more than the one creative you can
get from a person. And more interestingly, when
you think about localization, you're going to go
do that in every language. Once you discover
winning creative, now you have to go localize
that in every market and rebuild it from scratch.
It's just a ton. And oftentimes it doesn't perform
as well because it's been rethought essentially.
But we found that just translating it with AI was
able to get performance almost as good as the
original, in the original language. So this is
going to fly to the entire market. I think
wherever there's dollars to be made, saved,
it is inevitable. It will be consumed and it
will very quickly be a lot of social media.
I mean, you could imagine a social network of the
future where, and this is dystopian by the way,
so watch out. You could imagine a social network
of the future where all content is generated. None
of the people are real. I mean, the algorithm
isn't tailoring whose content to show you,
but it's purely generating content
that is completely catered to you,
with people and everything completely
catered to you. I don't think it's out of
the question. It almost seems inevitable
in a way, but that's not too far away,
I think. That's actually very possibly
real in five years or something like that.
What I'm imagining, because it's
hard to imagine a social network
where it's people because usually we
want to know who these people are. I
don't care random sharing status updates,
but I can see a TikTok that is all AI.
Exactly, exactly.
Wow, just content tuned to
your loves and interests.
Exactly.
And just random videos. Wow.
Yep. Because do you know, you see a TikTok feed,
you don't even know who's real or
not today, right? It's not like we-
Right. That's how I would approach
it. I would just join TikTok and
start uploading videos that are AI generated.
Exactly.
And then build a whole network of
that. Oh my god, the future is wild.
Let's go to failure corner. Something that I
try to do with this podcast is share moments
where things didn't go well. There's all
these stories of everything's going great
all the time. All this foundries killing
it, building a billion-dollar company. Oh,
so awesome. But they don't know all the
things that go wrong. So let me ask you,
is there a story you can share of when
things didn't work out? When you failed?
At the beginning of the company, we actually
had a bunch of time where we spent figuring
out what we wanted to do, and I think it's
an unconventional story almost in a way
because we started off the company, the
first thing we did was build the Captions
app. We launched the app. That was the first
thing we did. Took two days to build it. We
put it out there and it immediately took
off. It was absolutely shocking because I
built it on a weekend. We put it out there,
I called my co-founder on Monday. I'm like,
"It's at the top of the app store.
We're getting like 600 videos a day."
Top of the app store, holy shit.
And we didn't do anything to enable that.
It just happened on its own. It was almost
anti-climactic in a way because we thought it
would be a lot more time spent figuring out
the product before that would happen. And
so it felt like, "Wait, this can't be it,
right? It can't be this fast. How did this
happen?" So we got distracted because of that,
because we were like, "Oh, okay. Well, maybe
... This is cool. It'll work. That's great,
but we got to figure out what the product is."
And so we spent at least a year, year and a half
thinking about building social networks and
all kinds of things when we should have been
working on Captions because there was product
market fit there. And how we figured that out
is Captions was sitting on my personal
account, so I wasn't checking that a lot.
About a year and a half into the company, as
we were working on other projects and stuff,
I went back to my personal account, just opened
it, and I saw that there was $500,000 in there.
I looked at a chart and it was just growing.
The revenue was just growing completely on its
own. No employees, no releases, no bug fixes,
no customer support. There was like 2,000 open
support tickets that were unanswered for a year
and a half, and great reviews. It's just going
completely on its own. And so that was a clear
sign to me. It was like, "Oh my God, you should
have been working on that. That product works."
And so we immediately had a meeting. I mean,
it was tough to figure out what the right path
was at that point because we'd invested so
much time in other things as well, but reset,
and we got back on the track with Captions,
and literally as soon as we started releasing
the first features into it, it blew up. What
looked like a vertical line at that time became
a horizontal line, and the new vertical line
was so vertical that the old vertical line
became a horizontal line, essentially. And
it's continued since then, which is crazy. So
we basically wasted about a year and a half.
I love that new way of thinking about a hockey
stick moment where not only is it going vertical,
but the rest of the chart is now just
flat along the bottom of the axis.
Exactly. Yeah.
For people that may not know what Captions is,
I try to describe it at the beginning and
we'll link to it and stuff, but basically,
the reason you thought it was nothing is it
just adds captions to a video that you record.
It does.
Added captions.
Exactly, yep. So I think we wanted ... Our
thought was we're going to build a social network,
but first we got to build a creation tool for
the social network. And we knew that we wanted
to use AI to create video, and it seemed obvious
that, "Oh, speech to text, a solved problem,
we should start with that." So that's why we
decided to start with Captions because it was
a solved problem at the time. What was funny
is that once GPT and stuff started coming out,
a lot of the things that were unsolved became
solved very quickly. So timing was almost perfect.
And that aligns to something you shared
earlier. Just so many of these problems
that were not yet solved are now possible,
and the companies that are in the right
place at the right time benefit greatly
who've been just waiting for this part.
The other thing that I think is interesting about
that story is you try to build a social network.
I think it was around high schools and things
like that. As we've seen, it's very difficult
to build a new social network. So let me just
get your sense. Do you think it's possible
for somebody to come around and build a new, the
next Facebook, the next Snap, the next whatever?
I think it's definitely possible. I do
think ... Let me tell you something crazy,
actually. The social network that we had at the
time, we actually remove it from the app store,
so it's not available anymore.
But til today, there are people,
there are thousands of people that are using
it, posting on it, and all the different things,
which actually speaks to the power of
the social network in a way. It is hard
to create and hard to kill. I mean, I think
X is actually a great example of that too. A
lot of movement happened there and it continues
to work, I guess somehow. So testament to that.
The power of network effects, especially
someone once described this so well,
they're like Twitter/X. They changed the brand,
they changed the team building it. They changed
the URL. Like everything changed about it
except the network effect of the people in it.
It's true. It's true.
I just saw a story that they're
making billions of dollars. He's
actually turned it around. It's actually
becoming a really profitable company.
Wow.
Yeah. It just came out the other
day. So Elon did it. Well, with that,
we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
I'm ready. Let's do it.
What are two or three books that you
have recommended most to other people?
I have to say here that I actually don't
read books. It's actually something that
I decided on purpose where I decided I
don't want to build my skill in reading,
and I want to build it in listening and watching
instead, because I think that's the future.
I love how intentional that is, and I
love how it's a really cool way of saying,
I don't read books. The future isn't reading,
but I love that you have books
behind you, so [inaudible 01:20:58].
I do. Yeah.
[inaudible 01:20:59]
[inaudible 01:21:00] didn't
read, they're back there.
That's funny. Okay, cool. I
want to ask more questions,
but I'm going to keep going. Lightning
around. Speaking of watching and listening,
do you have a favorite recent movie
or TV show you've really enjoyed?
I like Silo and Severance. I mean, obviously,
I think everyone's watching these.
There's a book around Silo too.
I read that. I read all of
them. There's three of them.
There are.
It sucks to watch the show because you know
all the tricks that are about to happen,
and I'm just like, "Why am I watching
this? I know where this will go.
Yeah. I mean, for what it's worth,
it does seem like the show is
going on a slightly different path.
It is. That was also what annoyed me. Just like,
"What the heck? This is made up. All is
made up shit." I don't like that when I
watch the show. So two reasons I'm not
watching it but [inaudible 01:21:40].
Don't worry about it. I didn't actually read
the book. My wife read the book
and then she told me the story.
Okay, okay. I was worried.
I was worried. Okay, cool,
and Severance. Okay, great. I love Severance.
Next question. Do you have a favorite product
you've recently discovered that you really like?
My favorite product, honestly,
is Linear. I'm not going to lie,
just because it's so well-designed and it's so
easy to use. I also like Superhuman. I mean,
these are obvious answers, but I do use
these things every day and it's hard
to create products that you use every
day and don't hate. So props for them.
Cool. I haven't announced this on the
podcast yet, but this is a good time,
whoever's listening right now, is I just launched
a bundle where if you become a paid subscriber
to my newsletter, you get, listen to this, a
year free of Linear and Superhuman and Notion
and Granola, which is incredible AI app for
note-taking and Perplexity, Perplexity Pro.
Ooh. Nice.
$2,000 in value for the price of my
newsletter, 200 bucks, going to that.
Damn, that's real value.
It's an unbelievable deal, and it's
a no-brainer at this point to buy a
subscription, but this isn't an ad
for my newsletter. I'll keep going.
Next question. Do you have a favorite life motto
that you often find yourself coming back to,
sharing with friends and
family in work or in life?
I actually learned this because someone else
told me that I keep repeating this thing,
but I have this framework of how I want to
operate at work, basically. Right? I think I
love to compete and to win at the end of the day.
And I think that to win, you have to be the best.
But I also think the easiest way to be the best
is to be the first, and that actually is key.
And so is the motto the easiest way? Is that the-
That's it. The easiest way to
be the best is to be first.
Be the first. Interesting. Okay. I have to resist
following threads here because I
want to make this lightning round.
Okay. Final question, just for fun. What's
the coolest, most wild AI video you've
seen recently? Is there one that comes to
mind of like, "Wow, that was something"?
I mean, honestly, I got to say the
OmniHuman stuff was pretty cool.
The ByteDance video that we talked about.
Yeah, exactly. I mean, the broccoli
talking. I don't know if you saw that one. There
was a little broccoli delivering a little speech.
Interesting.
Yeah, it looked like it was
animated by an animator.
Just imagine being a kid these days
and just seeing stuff like that.
I think you're probably just used to it,
right? You're just like, this is just normal.
Mm-hmm. It's just like we were saying,
AGI is just going to come around.
Exactly.
All right. Cool. What's for
dinner? Cool. That's great.
Yep.
Amazing. Gaurav, this was incredible.
It was so insightful on so many levels.
Two final questions. Where can folks
find you and what you're building if
they want to learn more? And then
how can listeners be useful to you?
Awesome. Yeah, I mean, definitely find me on
LinkedIn. That's where I live most of the time.
My DMs are open, et cetera, et cetera. So feel
free to send me a message. And I think what'll
be useful, I mean, we're building out our
early product and design team, so if AI video
is interesting, if consumer apps are interesting,
now's the time to join. We're really small, early,
we work together across the team, so there's
going to be no better time to join, basically.
And you get to ship a
marketable feature every week.
Exactly. I mean, that's the PM's
dream. Think about it. Right?
The PM's dream. Yeah, I like that that's a
filter. The people that get excited about that,
great fit. The people that are stressed
out by that, not the place to be.
Exactly.
So awesome. All right. Gaurav,
thank you so much for being here.
No, thank you. Appreciate it.
Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to the show
on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.