You were a product leader at Dropbox,
then Instacart. Now, you're the PM of
the most consequential product in history.
I didn't know what I would do here because it
was a research lab. My first task was I
fix the blinds, or something like that.
When someone offers you a rocket
ship, don't ask which seat.
We set out to build a super assistant. It
was supposed to be a hackathon code base.
What was it called before?
It was going to be Chat with
GPT-3.5 because we really didn't think it
was going to be a successful product.
And then Sam Altman is just like, "Hey,
let me tweet about it."
This is a pattern with AI,
you won't know what to polish until after
you ship. My dream is that we ship daily.
By the time people hear this, they're
going to have their hands on GPT-5.
About 10% of the world population uses every
week. With scale comes responsibility. It just
feels a little bit more alive, a bit
more human. This model has taste.
Kevin Weil, your CPO, said to ask you about this
principle of, "Is it maximally accelerated?"
I just really want to jump to the punchline,
"Why can't we do this now?" I always felt
like part of my role here is to just set
the pace and the resting heartbeat.
Everyone is always wondering, "Is Chat
the future of all of this stuff?"
Chat was the simplest way to ship at that time.
I'm baffled by how much it took off, even more
baffled by how many people have copied.
ChatGPT is now driving more traffic
to my newsletter than Twitter.
That is the type of capability that
has been incredibly retentive. I've been really
excited about what we've been doing in search.
Can you give us a peek into
where this goes long-term?
ChatGPT feels a little bit like
MS-DOS. We haven't built Windows yet,
and it will be obvious once we do.
Today, my guest is Nick Turley. Nick
is Head of ChatGPT at OpenAI. He
joined the company three years ago,
when it was still primarily a research lab. He
helped come up with the idea of ChatGPT and took
it from 0 to over 700 million weekly active
users, billions in revenue, and arguably the
most successful and impactful consumer software
product in human history. Nick is incredible. He's
been very much under the radar. This is the first
major podcast interview that he has ever done,
and you are in for a treat. We talk about all
the things, including the just launched GPT-5.
A huge thank you to Kevin Weil, Claire Vo,
George O'Brien, Joanne Jang, and Peter Deng
for suggesting topics for this conversation. If
you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting app, or
YouTube. And if you become an annual subscriber of
my newsletter, you get a year free of a bunch
of incredible products, including Lovable,
Replit, Bolt, n8n, Linear, Superhuman, Descript,
Wispr Flow, Gamma, Perplexity, Warp, Granola,
Magic Patterns, Raycast, ChatPRD, and Mobbin.
Check it out lennysnewsletter.com and click,
"bundle". With that, I bring you Nick Turley.
This episode is brought to you by Orkes,
the company behind open source Conductor, the
orchestration platform powering modern enterprise
apps and agentic workflows. Legacy automation
tools can't keep pace. Siloed, low-code platforms,
outdated process management, and disconnected
API tooling falls short in today's event-driven,
AI-powered agentic landscape. Orkes changes
this. With Orkes Conductor, you gain an
agentic orchestration layer that seamlessly
connects humans, AI agents, APIs, microservices,
and data pipelines in real time at enterprise
scale, visual and code-first development,
built-in compliance, observability, and rock-solid
reliability, ensure workflows evolve dynamically
with your needs. It's not just about automating
tasks, it's orchestrating autonomous agents and
complex workflows to deliver smarter outcomes
faster. Whether modernizing legacy systems or
scaling next-gen, AI-driven apps, Orkes
accelerates your journey from idea to
production. Learn more and start building
at orkes.io/lenny, that's orkes.io/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta, and
I am very excited to have Christina Cacioppo,
CEO and co-founder of Vanta, joining
me for this very short conversation.
Great to be here. Big fan of the
podcast and the newsletter.
Vanta is a longtime sponsor of the show,
but for some of our newer listeners,
what does Vanta do and who is it for?
Sure. So we started Vanta in 2018,
focused on founders, helping them start to build
out their security programs and get credit for
all of that hard security work with compliance
certifications, like SOC 2 or ISO 27001. Today,
we currently help over 9,000 companies, including
some startup household names, like Atlassian,
Ramp, and LangChain, start and scale their
security programs, and ultimately build
trust by automating compliance, centralizing
GRC, and accelerating security reviews.
That is awesome. I know from experience that these
things take a lot of time and a lot of resources,
and nobody wants to spend time doing this.
That is very much our experience, but before
the company, and some extent, during it,
but the idea is, with automation, with AI,
with software, we are helping customers
build trust with prospects and customers
in an efficient way. And our joke, we started
this compliance company so you don't have to.
We appreciate you for doing that, and you have
a special discount for listeners. They can get
$1,000 off Vanta at vanta.com/lenny, that's
vanta.com/lenny for $1,000 off Vanta. Thanks
for that, Christina.
Thank you!
Nick, thank you so much for joining
me, and welcome to the podcast.
Thanks for having me, Lenny.
I already had a billion questions I wanted
to ask you, and then you guys decided to launch
GPT-5 the week that we're recording this. So, now,
I have at least 2 billion questions for you.
I hope you have a lot of time. First of all,
just congrats on the launch. It's coming tomorrow,
the day after recording this. Just congrats.
How are you feeling? I imagine this is an ungodly
amount of work and stress. How are you doing?
It's a busy week, but we've been
working on this for a while,
so it also feels really good to get it out.
So, by the time people hear this, they're going
to have their hands on GPT-5, the newest
ChatGPT. What's the simplest way to just
understand what this is, what it unlocks, what
people can do with it? Give us the pitch.
I'm so excited about GPT-5. I think for most
people, it's going to feel like a real step
change. If you're the average ChatGPT user, and
we have 700 million of them this week, you've
probably been on GPT-4o for a while. You probably
don't even think about the model that powers the
product. And GPT-5, it just feels categorically
different. I'll talk about a lot of the specifics,
but at the end of the day, the vibes are good,
at least we feel that way. We hope that users
feel the same. And increasingly, that is the thing
that I think most people notice, right? They don't
look at the academic benchmarks. They don't look
at evaluations. They try the model and see what
it feels like. And just on that dimension alone,
I'm so excited. I've been using it for a while,
but it is also the smartest, most useful, and
fastest frontier model that we've ever launched.
On pure SMARTs, one way to look at that is
academic benchmarks on many of the standard ones,
whether or not it's math, or reasoning, or just
raw intelligence. This model is state of the art.
I'm especially excited about its performance
on coding, whether or not that's SWE-bench,
which is a common benchmark, or actually front-end
coding is really, really good as well, and that's
an area where I feel like there's the true step
change improvement in GPT-5. But really, no matter
how you measure the SMARTs, it's quite remarkable,
and I think people are going to feel the upgrade,
especially if they weren't using o3 already.
And the second thing beyond SMARTs is it's just
really useful. Coding is one axis of utility,
whether or not you have coding questions or
you're vibe coding an app, but it's also a
really good writer. I write for a living,
internally, externally. I just wrote a big blog
post that we published Monday, and this thing
is such an incredible editor. And compared to some
of the older models, it's got taste, which I think
is really exciting. And to me, that's something
that is truly useful in my day-to-day. And there's
a bunch of other areas, like it's state of the
art on health, which is useful when you need it,
but again, the thing you can't really express
in use cases or data is the vibe of the model.
And it just feels a little bit more alive, a bit
more human in a way that is hard to articulate
until you try it. So, feel good about that.
And yeah, as mentioned, it's faster. It thinks,
too, just like o3 did, but you don't have
to manually tell it to do that. It'll just
dynamically decide to think when it needs to. And
when it doesn't need to think, it just responds
instantly, and that ends up feeling quite a bit
faster than using o3 did. And then maybe the
thing that's most exciting is that we're making it
available for free, and that's one of those things
that I feel like we can uniquely do at OpenAI.
Because many companies, I think, if they have a
subscription model like us, they would gate it
behind their paid plan. And for us, if we can
scale it, we will, and that just feels awesome.
We did that with 4o as well. So, everyone is going
to be able to try GPT-5 tomorrow, hopefully.
How long does something like this take? I don't
know if there's a simple answer to this, but just
how long have you guys been working on GPT-5?
We've been working on it for a while. You
can view GPT-5 as a culmination of a bunch of
different efforts. We had a reasoning tech, we had
a more classic post-screening methodologies, and
therefore, it's really hard to put a beginning on
it, but it really is the end point of a bunch of
different techniques that we began for a while.
Can you give us a peek into the vision for where
ChatGPT is going, GPT in general is going?
If you look at on the surface, it's been the
same idea with a much smarter brain for a long
time. I'm curious where this goes long-term.
So, to maybe back up a bit, now, you
think of ChatGPT as, "Is this going
to be ubiquitous product?" Again, about 10%
of the world population uses every week.
Holy shit.
I think we have 5 million business customers now.
It's an established category in its own right.
But really, when we started, we set out to build
a super assistant, that's how we talked about
it at the time. In fact, the code base that we
use is called SA Server. It was supposed to be
a hackathon code base, but things always turn
out a little bit differently. So, yeah, in some
ways, that is still the vision. The reason I don't
talk about it more than I do is because I think
assistant is a bit limiting in terms of the mental
model we're trying to create. You think of this
very personified human thing, maybe utilitarian,
maybe a... And frankly, having an assistant is
not particularly relatable to most people, unless
they're in Silicon Valley and they're a manager,
or something like that. So it's imperfect.
But really, what we envision is this entity that
can help you with any task, whether or not that's
at home, or at work, or at school, really any
context, and it's an entity that knows what you're
trying to achieve. So, unlike ChatGPT today, you
don't have to describe your problem in menu to
detail because it already stands your overarching
goals and has context on your life, et cetera. So,
that's one thing that we're really excited about.
The inverse of giving it more inputs on your life
is giving it more action space. So, we're really
excited to allow it to do, over time, what a
smart, empathetic human with a computer could
do for you. And I think the limit of the types
of problems that you can solve for people, once
you give it access to tools like that, is very,
very different than what you might be able to
do in a chatbot today. So, that's more outputs.
And I often think, "Okay, I'm a general
intelligence. What happened if I became
Lenny's intern, or something?" And I wouldn't
be particularly effective despite having both
of those attributes that I just mentioned, and
it's because I think this idea of building a
relationship with this technology is also
incredibly important. So, that's maybe the
third piece that I'm excited about is building
a product that can truly get to know you over
time. And you saw us launch some of those things
with improved memory earlier this year, and that's
just the beginning of what we're hoping to do so
that it really feels like this is your AI. So,
I don't know if supersystem is still the right
exact analogy, but I think people just think
of it as their AI. And I think we can put one
in everyone's pocket and help them solve real
problems, whether or not that's becoming healthy,
whether or not that's starting a business,
whether or not that's just having a second
opinion on anything. There's so many different
problems that you can help with people in their
daily life, and that's what motivates me.
So an interesting between the lines that
I'm reading here is the vision is for it
to be an assistant for people not to replace
people. It feels like a really important piece
of the puzzle. Maybe just talk about that.
AI is really scary to people, and I understand
there's decades of movies on AI that have a
certain mental model baked in. And even if
you just look at the technology today, everyone, I
think, has this moment where the AI does something
that was really deeply personal to them and you're
thought, "Hey, AI can never do that." For me,
it was weird music theory things where I was like,
"Wow, this thing actually understands music better
than I do," and that's something I'm passionate
about. And so it's naturally scary. And I think
the thing that's been really important to us for
a long time is to build something that feels like
it's helpful to you, but you're in the driver's
seat, and that's even more important as the
stuff becomes agentic, the feeling of being
in control, and that can be small things.
We built this way of watching what the AI is doing
when it's in agent mode. And it's not that you
actually are going to watch it the whole time,
but it gives you a mental model and makes you
feel in control in the same way that, when you're
in a Waymo, you get that screen, for those of you
who've tried Waymo. You can see the other cars.
It's not like you're going to actually watch,
but it gives you the sense that you know
how this thing works and what's happening,
or we always check with you to confirm
things. It's a little bit annoying,
but it puts you in the driver's seat, which is
important. And for that reason, we always view
technology and the technology that we build as
something that amplifies what you're capable of,
rather than replacing it, and that becomes
important as the deck gets more powerful.
Okay. So you mentioned the beginnings of ChatGPT.
I was reading in a different interview. So you
joined OpenAI. ChatGPT was just this internal
experimental project that was basically a way
to test GPT-3.5, and then Sam Altman is
just like, "Hey, let me tweet about it,
maybe see if people find this interesting," yada
yada, yada. It's the most successful consumer
product in history, I think both in growth rate
in users and revenue, and just absurd. Can you
give us a glimpse into that early period before
it became something everyone is obsessed with?
Yeah. So we had decided that we wanted to do
something consumer-facing, I think, right around
the time that GPT-4 finished training, and it
was actually mainly for a couple of reasons.
We already had a product out there, which was our
developer product. That's actually what I came in
to help with initially, and that has been amazing
for the mission. In fact, it's grown up. And now,
it's the OpenAI platform with, I don't know, 4
million developers, I think. But at that time,
it was early stage, and we were running
into some constraints with it because
there was two problems. One, you couldn't iterate
very quickly because, every time you would change
the model, you'd break everyone's app.
So, it was really hard to try things.
And then the other thing was that it was really
hard to learn because the feedback we would
get was the feedback from the end user to the
developer to us. So it was very disintermediated,
and we were excited to make fast progress towards
AGI and it just felt like we needed a more direct
relationship with consumers. So we were trying to
figure out where to start. And in classic OpenAI
fashion, especially back then, we put together
a hackathon of enthusiasts of just hacking on
GPT-4 to see what awesome stuff we could create
and maybe ship to users, and everyone's idea was
some flavor of a super assistant. They were more
specific ideas, like we had a meeting bot that
would call into meetings, and the vision was maybe
it would help you run the meeting over time. We
had a coding tool, which full circle now, probably
ahead of its time. And the challenge was that we
tested those things, but every time we tested
these more bespoke ideas, people wanted to use
it for all this other stuff because it's just
a very, very generically powerful technology.
So, after a couple of months of prototyping,
we took that same crew of volunteers,
and it was truly a volunteer group, right? We
had someone from the supercomputing team who
had built an iOS app before. We had someone on the
research team who had written some backend code in
their life. They were all part of this initial
ChatGPT team, and we decided to ship something
open-ended because we just wanted a real use case
distribution. And this is a pattern with AI, I
think, where you really have to ship to understand
what is even possible and what people want,
rather than being able to reason about that a
priori. So, ChatGPT came together at the end
because we just wanted the learnings as soon
as we could, and we shipped it right before
the holiday thinking we would come back and get
the data and then wind it down. And obviously,
that part turned out super differently because
people really liked the product as is.
So I remember going through the motions of
like, "Oh, man, dashboard is broken. Oh, wait,
people are liking it. I'm sure it's just going
viral and stuff is going to die down," to like,
"Oh, wow, people are retaining, but I
don't understand why." And then eventually,
we fell into product development mode,
but it was a little bit by accident.
Wow. I did not know that ChatGPT emerged
out of a hackathon project. Definitely
the most successful hackathon project.
I like to tell this story when we do our
hackathons because I really do want people
to feel like they can ship their idea,
and it's certainly been true in the past,
and we'll continue to make it true.
If you don't want to share these things,
but I wonder who that team was.
The team is largely still around. Some of
the researchers working on GPT-5, actually,
were always part of the ChatGPT team. Engineers
are still around. Designers are still around. I'm
still here, I guess. So, yeah, you've got the team
still running things, but obviously, we've grown
up tremendously, and we've had to because with
scale comes responsibility. And we're going to hit
a billion users soon and you have to begin acting
in a way that is appropriate to that scale.
Okay. So let me spend a little time there. So,
I don't know if this is 100% true, but I believe
it is that ChatGPT is the fastest growing, most
successful consumer product in history. Also,
the most impactful on people's lives. It feels
like it's just part of the ether of society now.
It's just my wife talks to it. Every question
I have, I go to it, voice mode. My wife is just
like, "Let me check with ChatGPT." It's just such
a part of our life now, and I think it's still
early. So many people don't even know what the
hell is going on. Just as someone leading this,
do you ever just take a moment to reflect
and think about just like, "Holy shit"?
I have to. It's quite humbling to get to run a
product like that, and I have to pinch myself very
frequently, and I also have to sometimes sit back
and just think, which is really hard when things
are moving so quickly. I love setting a fast
pace at the company, but in order to do that with
confidence, I need at least one day every week
that I'm entirely unplugged and I'm just thinking
about what to do and process the week, et cetera.
And the other thing is I've never ever worked on
a product that is so empirical in its nature
where, if you don't stop, and watch, and listen
to what people are doing, you're going to miss
so much, both on the utility and on the risks,
actually. Because normally, by the time you ship a
product, you know what it's going to do. You don't
know if people are going to like it, that's always
empirical, but you know what it can do. And with
AI, because I think so much of it is emergent,
you actually really need to stop and listen
after you launch something and then iterate
on the things people are trying to do and on
the things that aren't quite working yet. So, for
that reason alone, I think it's very important to
take a break and just watch what's going on.
Okay. So you take a day off every week... not
off. Okay, that's not the right way to put it.
You take a day of thinking time, deep work.
I need it. Yeah, yeah, yeah. And I
need to hard unplug on a Saturday,
or something like that. Obviously-
On a Saturday [inaudible 00:20:16].
But it's just not possible otherwise.
This has been a giant marathon for
three years now. Yeah.
Like a sprint marathon.
Sprint marathon, that's right, or interval
training, or something. I don't know how to
exactly describe the OpenAI launch cadence,
but you've got to set yourself up in a way
that is sustainable. Even if this wasn't AI and it
didn't have the interesting attributes that I just
mentioned, I think you would need to do that. But
especially with AI, it's important to go watch.
So, along those lines, I talked to a bunch
of people that work with you, that work at
OpenAI. Joanne specifically said that urgency
and pace are a big part of how you operate,
that that's just something you find really
important, to create urgency within the team
constantly, even when you are the fastest
growing product in history, growing like
crazy. Talk about just your philosophy on the
importance of pace and urgency on teams.
Well, it's nice of her to say that. Two things,
with ChatGPT, when we decided to do it, we had
been prototyping for so long and I was just like,
"In 10 days, we're going to ship this thing," and
we did. So, that was maybe a moment in time thing
where I just really wanted to make sure that we go
learn something. Ever since then, I spent so much
time thinking about why ChatGPT became successful
in the first place, and I think there was some
element of just doing things where there was
many other companies that had technology in the
LLM space that just never got shipped. And I just
felt like, of all the things we could optimize
for, learning as fast as possible is incredibly
important. So I just started rallying people
around that, and that took different forms.
For a while, when we were of that size, I just
ran this daily release sync and had everyone
who was required to make a decision in it, and we
would just talk about what to do and to pivot from
yesterday, et cetera. Obviously, at some point,
that doesn't scale, but I always felt like part
of my role here, obviously, was to think about the
direction of the product, but also to just set the
pace and the resting heartbeat for our teams.
And again, this is important anywhere, but it's
especially important when the only way to find out
what people like and what's valuable is to bring
it into the external world. So, for that reason,
I think it's become a superpower of OpenAI, and
I'm glad that Joanne thinks that I had some part
in that, but it really has taken a village.
I love this phrase, "the resting
heart rate of your team".
That's such a perfect metaphor of just the pace
of being equivalent to your resting heart rate.
I actually learned that at Instacart, when
I showed up there, because we were in the
pandemic and it was all hands on deck. For a
while, there was this... I think there was a
company-wide stand-up because we disbanded all
teams. We were just trying to keep the site up.
And for me, I had been used to taking my sweet
time and just thinking really hard about things,
and that's important, but I really
learned to hustle over there, and
I think that's come in handy at OpenAI.
Okay. So, along these same lines, I asked
Kevin Weil, your CPO, what to ask you, and
he said to ask you about this principle of,
"Is it maximally accelerated?" Talk about that.
That's funny, we have a Slack emoji, apparently,
for this now because I used to say that. Now, I
try to paraphrase. Sometimes, I just really want
to jump to the punchline of like, "Okay, why
can't we do this now?" or, "Why can't we do it
tomorrow?" And I think that it's a good way to cut
through a huge number of blockers with the team
and just instill... especially if you come from a
larger company. At some point, we started hiring
people from larger tech companies. I think they're
used to, "Let's check in on this in a week," or,
"Let's circle back next quarter to see if
we can go on the plan." And I just, as a-
... on the plan and I just kind of as a
thought exercise, always like people asking,
"Okay, if this was the most important thing and
you wanted to truly maximally accelerate it,
what would you do?" That doesn't mean that you go
do that, but it's really a good forcing function
for understanding what's critical path versus what
can happen later. And I've just always felt like
execution is incredibly important. These ideas,
they're everywhere. Everyone's talking about a
personal AI, you might've seen news on that and
I really think that execution is one of the most
important things in the space and this is a tool.
So, it's funny that that became a meme. It's like
a little pink Slack emoji that people just put on
whatever they're trying to force the question.
I was going to ask, what theme [inaudible
00:24:47]. So, it's a little pink,
is there something in there like-
It's a Comic Sans emoji that says,
is this maximally accelerated?
Okay. And so, the kind of the culture
there is when someone is working on something,
the push is, is this maximally accelerated? Is
there a way we can do this faster?
Is there anything we can unblock?
Yeah. And we use that sparingly, right? Because
it needs to be appropriate to the context. There's
some things where you don't want to accelerate
as quickly as possible because you kind of want
process. And we're very, very deliberate on that
where your process is a tool. And one of the areas
where we have an immense amount of process is
safety. Because A, the stakes are already really
high, especially with these models, GPT-5 which
is a frontier in so many different ways. But B,
if you believe in the exponential, which I
do and most people who work on this stuff do,
you have to play practice for a time where you
really, really need the process for sure, sure,
sure. And that's why I think it's been really
important to separate out the product development
velocity, which has to be super high from, for
things like frontier models, there actually needs
to be a rigorous process where you red team, you
work on the system card, you get external input,
and then you put things out with confidence
that it's gone through the right safeguards.
So, again, it's a nuanced concept, but I found
it very, very useful when we needed and for
everything product development, you're a dead on
arrival, so it's important to get stuff out.
We got to open source those memes so that
other teams can build on this approach.
Absolutely.
So, interestingly with ChatGPT,
and it's not a surprise, but not only is it the
fastest-growing, most successful consumer product
ever, retention is also incredibly high. People
have shared these stats that one month retention
is something like 90%, six month retention is
something like 80%. First of all, are these
numbers accurate? What can you share there?
I'm obviously limited on what exactly I can share,
but it is true that our retention numbers
are really exciting and that is actually
the thing we look at. We don't care at all how
much time you spend in the product. In fact,
our incentive is just to solve your problem and
if you really like the product, you'll subscribe,
but there's no incentive to keep you in the
product for long. But we are obviously really,
really happy if over the long run, three month
period, et cetera, you're still using this
thing. And for me, this was always the elephant
in the room early on. It's like, "Hey, this may
be a really cool product, but is this really the
type of thing that you come back to?" And it's
been incredible to not just see strong retention
numbers, but just see an improvement in retention
over time even as our cohorts become less of an
early adopter and more the average person, so.
Yeah. So, that note is something that I
don't think people truly understand how
rare this is when a product... The cohort of
users comes, tries it out and then retention
over time goes down and then it comes back up,
people come back to it a few months later and
use it more. It's called a smiling curve, a
smile curve, and that's extremely rare.
Yeah, yeah. Yeah. There's some smiling going
on that's just on the team and I feel like
have technology, some of it is not the product.
I think people are actually just getting used
to this technology in a really interesting way,
where I find, and this is why the product needs
to evolve too, that this idea of delegating to an
AI, it's not natural to most people. It's not like
you're going through life and figuring out what
can I delegate? Certain sphere of Silicon Valley
does that because they're in a self-optimization
mode and they're trying to delegate everything
they can. But I think for most people in the world
it's actually quite unnatural. And you really have
to learn, "Okay, what are my goals actually and
what could another intelligence help me with?"
And I think that just takes time and people
do figure it out once they've had enough time
with the product. But then of course there's been
tons of things that we've done in the product too,
whether or not it's making the core models better,
whether or not it's new capabilities like search
and personalization and all that kind of
stuff, or just standard growth work too,
which we're starting to do. That
stuff matters too, of course.
So, you might be answering this question
already, but let me just ask it directly.
People may look at this and be like,
"Okay, they're building this kind of
layer on top of this God-like intelligence. Of
course it will grow incredibly fast and retention
will be incredible. What do you guys actually
doing that sits on top of the model that makes
it grow so fast and retain so much?" Is there
something that has worked incredibly well that has
moved metrics significantly that you can share?
One thing we've learned, I'll answer that question
in a minute, but one thing we've learned with
ChatGPT is that there really is no distinction
between the model and the product. The model is
the product and therefore you need to iterate on
it like a product. And by that I mean obviously
you typically start by shipping something very
open-ended, at least if you're OpenAI [inaudible
00:29:38] that's kind of a playbook. But then
you really have to look at what are people
trying to do? Okay, they're trying to write,
they're trying to code, they're trying to get
advice, they're trying to get recommendations
and you need to systematically improve on those
use cases. And that is pretty similar to product
development work. Obviously the methodology is a
bit different, but discovery is the same. You got
to talk to people, you got to do data science
and you got to try stuff and get feedback.
So, that's one chunk of work that we've been
very consciously doing is improving the model on
the use cases people care about. And there's also
such thing as vibes because I'm sure you know and
that's one of the things that I'm excited about
in GPT-5 is that the vibes are really good. So,
that too is, we have a model behavior team and
they really focus on what is the personality of
this model and how does it speak and talk. So,
there's that kind of work. I would say that's
maybe a third of the retention improvements
that we see or so just roughly. And then I
think another third is what I would call product
research capabilities. They're research driven
for sure. They have a research component,
but they're really new product features
or capabilities. And search is one example of
that where if you remember in the olden days,
maybe 20 months ago or something, you would talk
to ChatGPT and it'd be like, "As of my knowledge
cut off..." Or, "I can't answer that because that
happened to recently," or something like that.
And that is the type of capability
that has been incredibly retentive and
for good reason. It just allows you to do more
with the product personalization, like this idea
of advanced memory where it can really get to know
you over time is another example of a capability
like that. I think that's another good chunk.
And then the third stuff is the stuff you would
do in any product and those things exist too.
Not having to log in was a huge hit because it
removed a ton of the friction. I think we had
this intuition from the beginning, but we never
got to it because we didn't have enough GPU
or other constraint to really go do that. So,
there's the traditional product work too. So, I
often think about it as roughly a third, a third,
a third, but really we're still learning and we're
planning to evolve the product a ton, which is why
I'm sure there's going to be new levers.
You mentioned something that I want to come
back to real quick. You said that it was
something like 10 days from Hackathon
to Sam tweeting about ChatGPT being live?
The Hackathon happened much earlier and we were
prototyping for a long time, but at some point we
basically ran out of patience on trying to build
something more bespoke. And again, that was mostly
because people always wanted to do all this other
stuff whenever we tested it. So, it was 10 days
from when we decided we were going to ship to when
we shipped. And the research we'd been testing
for a long time, it was kind of an evolution
of what we'd called instruction following, which
was the idea that instead of just completing the
sentence, these models could actually follow you
instructions. So, if you said summarize this, it
would actually do so. And the research had evolved
from that into a chat format where we could do it
multi-turn. So, that research took way longer than
10 days and that kind of baking in the background,
but the productization of this thing was very,
very fast and lots of things didn't make it in.
I remember we didn't have history, which of course
was the first user feedback we got. The model had
a bunch of shortcomings and it was so cool to be
able to iterate on the model. The thing I just
talked about, treating the model as a product was
not a thing before ChatGPT because we would ship
in more hardware where there'd be a release GPT-3
and then we would start working on GPT-4 and these
weird giant big spend R&D projects that would
take a really long time and the spec was whatever
the spec was and then you'd have to wait another
year. And ChatGPT really broke that down because
we were able to make iterative improvements to it
just like software. And really, my dream is that
it would be amazing if we could just ship daily
or even hourly like in software land because you
could just fix stuff, et cetera. But there's
of course all kinds of challenges in how you
do that while keeping the personality intact
while not regressing other capabilities. So,
it's an open field to get there.
That's such a good example of is it
maximally accelerated? Okay, we're
going to ship ChatGPT 10 days.
[inaudible 00:33:48]-
Holy moly. We've been talking about
ChatGPT. Clearly it's kind of a chat interface.
Everyone's always wondering is chat the future
of all of this stuff? Interestingly, Kevin Weil
made this really profound point that has always
stuck with me when he was on the podcast that chat
is actually a genius interface for building on a
super intelligence because it's how we interact
with humans of all variety of intelligence. It
scales from someone at the lower end to a super
smart person. And so, it's really valuable as
a way to scale this spectrum. Maybe just talk
about that and is chat the long-term interface
for ChatGPT, I guess it's called ChatGPT.
I feel like we should either drop the chat
or drop the GPT at some point because it
is a mouthful. We're stuck with the name,
but no matter what we do, the product will
evolve. I think that I agree that there's
something profound about natural language. It just
really is the most natural form of communicating
to humans and therefore it feels important that
you should be communicating with your software
in natural language. I think that's different
from chat though. I think chat was the simplest
way to ship at the time. I'm baffled by how much
it took off as a concept. Even more baffled by
how many people have copied the paradigm rather
than trying out a different way of interacting
with AI. I'm still hoping that will happen.
So, I think natural language is here to stay,
but this idea that it has to be a turn-by-turn
chat interaction I think is really limiting.
And this is one of the reasons I don't love
the super system analogy, even though we
used to always use it is because if you think
that way, then you kind of feel like you're
talking to a person and GPT-5 it's amazing
at making great front-end applications. So,
I don't see a reason why you wouldn't have AIs
that can render their own UI in some way. And
you obviously want to make that predictable and
feel good. But it feels limiting to me to think
of the end-all-be-all interface as a chatbot. It
actually kind of feels dystopian almost where I
don't want to use all my software through the
proxy of some interface. I love being in Figma,
I love being in Google Docs. Those are all
great products to me and they're not chatbots.
So, yes on natural language, but no on chat is
where I would describe my point of view. And I'm
just hoping in general that we see more consumer
innovation on how people interact with AI because
there's so many possibilities and you just got to
try stuff. That's why chat stuck is we just did
it and people liked it. So, I'm hoping that we
see more there and we'll try to do our part.
So, you mentioned that you kind of got
stuck with this name ChatGPT. Maybe this
is part of the answer, but I'm curious just
are there any accidental decisions you guys
made early on that have stuck and have
essentially become history changing?
There's so many and it is funny, because you have
no time to think about them and then they end up
being super consequential. The day was one, we
went from chat with GPT-3.5 to ChatGPT the night
before, slightly better but still really bad.
What was it called before?
It was going to be Chat with GPT-3.5 because we
really didn't think it was going to be successful
product. We were trying to actually be as
nerdy as we could about it because that's
really what it was. It was a research demo, not
a product. So, we didn't think that was bad. But
I think that in the original release, making it
free was a big deal. I don't think we appreciate
that because the GPT-3.5 model was in our API for
at least six months prior to that. I think anyone
could have built something like this. It might not
have been quite as good on the modeling side, but
I think it would've taken off. So, making it free
and putting a nice UI on it, very consequential in
the way that you take for granted now. And this is
why I think that A, distribution and the interface
are continuously important even in 2025.
The paid business, which now it's a giant
business both in the consumer space and in the
enterprise space. The birth of that was just to
turn away demand originally. It was not like we
brainstormed, "Oh, what is the best monetization
model for AI?" It was really what monetization
model or what mechanism would allow us to turn
away people who are less serious than the people
who are really trying to use it? And subscriptions
just happened to have that property and it grew
into a large business. I think shipping really
funky capabilities before they were polished is
another thing where that feels like a tactical
decision, but it became a playbook because we
would learn so much. Remember when we shipped
Code Interpreter, we learned so much after
we shipped it. Now it's known as I think
data analysis in ChatGPT or something like that
just because we actually got real world use cases
back that we could then optimize. So, I think
there's been a lot of decisions over time that
proved pretty consequential, but we made
them very, very quickly as we have to, so.
The $20 a month feels like an
important part of this. Feels
like everybody's just doing that now and-
On that one actually, I remember I had this kind
of panic attack because we really needed to launch
subscriptions because at the time we were taking
the product down every time. It was, I don't know
if you remember, we had this fail whale, there's a
little [inaudible 00:39:09] generated poem on it.
So, they were like, "We had to get this out." And
I remember calling up someone I greatly respect
who's incredible at pricing and I was like,
"What should I do?" And we talked a bunch and I
just ran out of time to incorporate most of that
feedback. So, what I did do is ship a Google Form
to Discord with, I think the four questions you're
supposed to ask on how to price something-
[inaudible 00:39:32]?
Yeah, exactly. It literally had those four
questions and I remember distinctly A, you
[inaudible 00:39:38] a price back and that's kind
of how we got to $20. But B, the next morning,
there was a press article on you won't believe
the four genius questions the ChatGPT team asked
to price their... It was like if only you knew.
So, there's something about building in this
extreme public where people interpret so much
more intentionality into what you're doing than
might've actually existed at the time. But we got
with the $20. We're debating something slightly
higher at the time. I often wonder what would've
happened because so many other companies ended
up copying the $20 price point. So, I'm like, "Did
we erase a bunch of market cap by pressing it this
way?" But ultimately I don't care because the more
accessible we can make this stuff, the better. And
I think this is the price point that in Western
countries has been reasonable to a lot of
people in terms of the value that they get back.
And most importantly, we were able to push things
down to the free tier semi-regularly and we always
do that when we can [inaudible 00:40:35], but-
So, the survey, just to give the official
name, the Van Westendorp survey is how you
guys ended up pricing ChatGPT?
It was the top Google result. This
was before ChatGPT has real-time information.
Otherwise, it could have maybe price itself,
but it was Discord plus Google Form plus a blog
post on that methodology that got us there.
That is incredible. What a fun story. This
is the survey that Rahul Vohra at Superhuman
popularized in his first- round article-
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, that's right. That's right.
Definitely don't bring me on here as
a pricing expert, I think you have
got better people for that.
Whether it was right or wrong,
it is now the fastest-growing, insane
revenue generating business in the world. So,
I wouldn't feel too bad.
No, it worked out. Yeah.
It worked out. And by the way, I'm on the $200
a month tier, so there's clearly a room-
Thank you. Thank you.
... [inaudible 00:41:25]-
The story of that one is interesting too because
originally the purpose of the Plus plan was to be
able to ship first uptime and then be able to ship
capabilities that we couldn't scale to everyone.
And at some point it got so many people in the
Plus tier that had just lost that property. So,
the main reason we came up with the $200 tier is
just we had so much incredible research that's
actually really, really powerful. Like o3 Pro or
tomorrow GPT-5 Pro and just having a vehicle of
shipping that to people who really, really care
is exciting even though it kind of violates the
standard way a SaaS page should look, it's
a little jarring to see the 10X jump. So,
thank you for being a subscriber on that
and thank you everyone else who's watching
you subscribed to any tier, it's great.
I'm just going to throw a fishing line into
this pond of are there any other stories like
this? You shared this incredible story of Chat
with GPT-3.5 being the original name, how you
came up with pricing. Is there anything else?
Enterprise is interesting one too because
we've seen so much incredible adoption in the
Enterprise and it's sort of objectively crazy to
try to take on building a developer business and
a consumer business and an enterprise business
and all at once. But the story there is in like
month one or two, it was very clear that most
of the usage was work usage, actually much more
than today where you've got so many consumers on
the product and it's kind of sort of transcended
into pop culture. But at the time it was writing,
coding, analysis, that kind of stuff. And we were
pretty quickly in organically in 90% of Fortune
500 companies in a way that I had seen maybe at
Dropbox back when that was my two jobs ago where
we had a similar story. And since then there's
been more PLG companies. But the real reason
we did Enterprise, remember we were debating
should we do enterprise or should we launch an
iOS app because that's how small the team was.
The reason we did is we were starting to get
banned in companies because they all felt
rightfully or wrongfully that the privacy and
deployment story, et cetera wasn't there. So,
I was just like, "Man, we have to do something.
We're going to miss out on a generational
opportunity to build a work product." And
we've literally defined AGI as outperforming
most humans at economically valuable work or I'd
probably [inaudible 00:43:45] that, but I think
that's the way we put it. And so, I feel like
we had to be present there and it was a fairly
quick decision at the time, but it's grown into an
immense business. We just hit 5 million business
subscribers up from 3 million, I think a month
or two ago. So, it is kind of the spinoff that
it's taking a life of its own that I'm really,
really excited about for [inaudible 00:44:11]-
That is a lot to be handling the platform
essentially the API, the consumer product,
the fastest-growing, most successful product in
history and also the B2B side, which is clearly
a massive business. Do you have any kind of
heuristics for how to make these trade-offs do all
this at once and stay sane and be successful?