Our whole team is only like 15 engineers a year.
We use a ton of Devin when we're building Devin.
Most folks on the team are definitely working
with up to five Devins at once, and so Devin
merges like several hundred pull requests into
production in the Devin code bases every month.
What percentage of your PRs are
Devin versus humans right now?
It's in the neighborhood of a quarter or so.
Where do you think this will
be at the end of the year?
Honestly, we expect it to be
a decent bit more than half.
You guys are so ahead of how
companies work with AI engineers.
AI is going to be the biggest technology
shift of our lives, so most of the big
tech revolutions that we've had over the last 50
years, like personal computer, and the internet,
and the mobile phone, they all had this big
hardware component that was a big part of the
distribution. Folks who were building for those
industries kind of saw their market grow and grow
and grow basically steadily year over year as the
number of people with mobile phones increased,
right, as the number of people connected to the
internet increase. One of the things which is
already I'd say different in AI, is just how
explosive the technology can be. There's no
weight on hardware distribution. It means that
the space is just growing so exponentially.
How is the act of being an
engineer and building changing?
I think there's going to be way more programmers
and way more engineers a few years from now.
Pretty quickly. The form factor of what it means
to be a programmer obviously is going to change,
but at the end of the day, of course the
discipline is all about just being able
to tell your computer what's do. And so in
that lens, I really think that programming
is only going to become more and more
important as AI gets more powerful.
Today my guest is Scott Wu. Scott is
the co-founder and CEO of Cognition,
which makes a product called Devin, the world's
first autonomous AI software engineer. Unlike
other AI tools that I've highlighted on this
podcast, Devin is designed to act like an
actual remote engineer that you chat with like you
would with any other human engineer through Slack
or through its dedicated website. When Devin
launched about a year ago, it was very much a
junior engineer. Over the past year, they've made
a lot of progress and Devin is now being used by
tons of companies in production. We chatted about
how their engineering team of 15 uses Devins to
build Devin, including how every engineer uses
about five Devins each to help them code and
move faster. How a quarter of their pull requests
today are committed by Devins and that they expect
this to be over 50% by the end of the year.
We also talk about how Scott imagines software
engineering is going to look in the future and how
the role of an engineer changes from a coder to an
architect. We also get into the eight pivots that
they went through before landing on this path,
why Scott believes AI tools like this will lead
to more engineer hiring versus less. Also where
the name Devin comes from and so much more.
This episode is going to blow your mind. I
highly recommend you listen to it if you're
at all interested about where engineering,
product building, and AI is going. A huge
thank you to Claire Voue for suggesting a
bunch of great questions for this conversation.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. Also, if you
become an annual subscriber of my newsletter,
you get a year free of Linear, Superhuman,
Notion, Perplexity, and Granola. Check it out at
lenny'snewsletter.com and click bundle. With that,
I bring you Scott Wu. This episode is brought
to you by Enterpret. Enterpret unifies all your
customer interactions from Gong calls,
to Zendesk tickets, to Twitter threads,
to app store reviews and makes it available for
analysis. It's trusted by leading product orgs
like Canva, Notion, Loom, Linear, monday.com, and
Strava to bring the voice of the customer into
the product development process, helping
you build best in class products faster.
What makes Enterpret special is its ability to
build and update customer specific AI models
that provide the most granular and accurate
insights into your business. Connect customer
insights to revenue and operational data in your
CRM or data warehouse to map the business impact
of each customer need and prioritize confidently
and empower your entire team to easily take action
on use cases like win-loss analysis, critical
bug detection, and identifying drivers of churn
with Enterpret's AI assistant Wisdom. Looking
to automate your feedback loops and prioritize
your roadmap with confidence like Notion, Canva,
and Linear visit E-N-T-E-R-P-R-E-T.com/lenny to
connect with the team and to get two free months
when you sign up for an annual plan. This is a
limited time offer. That's enterpret.com/lenny.
Many of you are building AI products, which
is why I'm very excited to chat with Brandon
Foo, Founder and CEO of Paragon. Hey Brandon.
Hey Lenny. Thanks for having me.
So integrations have become a big
deal for AI products. Why is that?
Integrations are mission-critical
for AI for two reasons. First,
AI products need contacts from their customer's
business data such as Google Drive files,
Slack messages or CRM records. Second, for AI
products to automate work on behalf of users,
AI agents need to be able to take action
across these different third-party tools.
So where does Paragon fit into all this?
Well, these integrations are a pain to
build and that's why Paragon provides
an embedded platform that enables engineers
to ship these product integrations in just
days instead of months across every use case
from RAG data ingestion to agentic actions.
And I know from firsthand experience
that maintenance is even harder than
just building it for the first time.
Exactly. We believe product teams should focus
engineering efforts and competitive advantages,
not integrations. That's
why companies like You.com,
AI21 and hundreds of others use Paragon
to accelerate their integration strategy.
If you want to avoid wasting months of engineering
on integrations that your customers need, check
out paragon@useparagon.com/lenny. Scott, thank you
so much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Thanks so much for having me. Excited to be on.
I'm really excited to have you here because you
are building and you've been building something
that is very different from what a lot of other
AI companies have been doing for a long time,
although they are starting to converge to where
you guys are now. We're going to talk about that
and it's also just such a unique point in the
history of AI and just the journey of AI. And
so it's really cool to be chatting right now.
And I feel like we're going to chat again in a
few years and be like, wow, we were so right
about so much and so wrong about so much.
Yeah.
And so I'm excited to have you here.
Let's start with talking about Devin,
giving people an understanding
of just what the heck Devin is,
is the main product that you guys build. What
is the simplest way to understand what is Devin?
Absolutely. And so Devin is a fully autonomous
software engineer that is going to work on
tasks end to end, and so there are a lot
of great tools for all parts of the stack
of the AI code workflow. What Devin does
is it is a full asynchronous workflow,
and so you can tag Devin on an issue in Slack,
you're talking about an issue and you tag Devin,
you can tag Devin in Linear, you can have Devin
and Devin will make pull requests in your GitHub,
and so it's very much built to work with
engineering teams as your junior engineer.
Amazing, okay. So I remember when you guys
launched this, there was this big pitch of
this is your new AI engineer and it was
really good at a lot of stuff. It wasn't
great at other things. It's been a year now
about since you guys launched, is that right?
Yeah, yeah.
What's the best way to think about the level
of seniority that engineer had back in the day
when you guys launched and then the level
of seniority of engineer today if that's,
I don't know, measure of how to think about Devin?
Yeah, and it's crazy to think about by the way,
because a year ago when we did the initial launch,
I mean people didn't really believe that an
agent was possible. Right. And it was, I mean,
it was a very different time. So like start
of 2024, things with model capabilities were
definitely quite a bit earlier on, reasoning
especially was quite a bit earlier on.
And yeah, I mean, in the time since then it's
obviously developed a lot. I think in terms of
practical skills, there's some comparisons
we make. Sometimes we kind of say, well,
when we got started it was kind of like a high
school CS student and then as time went on,
it became more of a college intern and now it's
like a junior engineer. But I would say though
that those are more rough guidelines because
I really like the phrase jagged intelligence
for example, because obviously there are
certain things that it is much better at
than a human. There are certain things
that it's much worse at than a human.
And I think over the last year we've learned a
lot especially about not just coding agents but
agents in general just really building out how
all of us should be working and interacting with
agents as part of our flow. And so a lot of the
things that we built, I mean, there was no Slack,
there was no GitHub integration, there was no
Linear, there was no interactive planning phase
working back and forth. There was no way to touch
up Devin's code. And so a lot of the features that
we've built on the product side since then have
really been about basically yeah, figuring out how
to make working with Devin and handing off tasks
to Devin as smooth of an experience as possible.
That's so interesting. So a lot of the work has
gone not into how do we just make
Devin the best possible engineer,
but it's how to work with this new type of
entity that we haven't ever worked with.
I think it's a 50/50 of both. I think the
capabilities obviously have improved a ton
and we've seen these get better and get
measurably better. But I think the other
side of it is everything to do with yeah, really
the product interface and the tools and so on.
And I think today folks generally know how
to use chatbots and to with chatbots, right,
and that's an interface that people are familiar
with and obviously with agents it's still like
a real curve, I think to learn how to use them
and how to get the most out of them. And so it's
really exciting to see a lot of others starting
to build and do a lot more in the agent space as
well. But I think this is the kind of thing that
we're all really figuring out together as a space.
What can you share about just
the scale of Devin at this point,
whatever you're comfortable sharing,
and then just where do you think the level of
Devin's coding abilities will be in a year?
So we work with companies of all
stages and sizes. On the smallest end,
it goes to startups of just one or two people who
are using Devin to build out a lot of their kind
of initial prototype or initial product
all the way up to big public companies,
Fortune 100 companies or public banks
or things like that who are using Devin
across their engineering teams. In general, we've
seen a huge range of the use cases there. And
obviously the kinds of engineering work that
you're doing at a one or two person startup,
they're very different from the kind of
work that you're doing at a public bank.
But throughout it's all been basically yeah,
being that junior buddy of yours that makes
you go faster and really multiplies you, I would
say. I think it can multiply you as an engineer
obviously by just letting you work with your own
team of Devins instead of having to be kind of
fully synchronous on a single task. And then
it's also kind of multiplying your team and
multiplying your team's knowledge base because
Devin really accumulates a lot of the knowledge
from working with every member of your team and
is able to bring that into each new session.
Awesome. We're going to show people how it
actually works later in the podcast. We're
going to do a few live demos, but
let's actually go to the beginning
of the journey. What's just the origin
story of Devin? How did this all begin?
The founding team, I mean most of us have known
each other for years and years and years actually.
And for almost everyone, this is our first time
working together, but we've known each other a
long time. And we all actually had our own kind of
journeys in AI for the last decade or so. And so
for myself, I ran a company before this called
Lunchclub, which was an AI for a professional
networking product and I ran that for about five
years. And one of my co-founders, Steven was one
of the first engineers at a company called Scale
AI, which has obviously grown a lot and done very
well. My other co-founder Walden, was an early
engineer at a company called Cursor, which has
also obviously grown a lot and done really well.
And our whole team was kind of like that. Many of
us knew each other from competitive programming
and math competitions, but we had stayed very
closely in touch in the decade since then and
we've all kind of all had our own journeys.
And so we had one person who was running teams at
Neuro, we had one person who was at Waymo, someone
who had their own YC tools startup for machine
learning, and we were really excited to build
something together. And this was around late 2023,
so about a year and a half ago at this point. And
yeah, when we got started, I mean I think there
were a couple of things that we felt really
strongly about and one was that reinforcement
learning was really working and was going to be
the next big paradigm shift in capabilities. Back
then it was the initial ChatGPT launch in 2022,
and those models were, to first order were what
we would call imitation learning in AI, right,
which is basically you have the model read all the
texts that you can find on the internet and then
train it to talk like somebody on the internet
would talk. Right. And there are kind of obviously
a lot more details on top of that, but that's kind
of the first order pass of what was really done.
And it was amazing. Right. I mean, it passed
the churn test, it was able to respond and to
have encyclopedic knowledge about a lot
of things. And I think this new paradigm
which we've gotten into over this last year
or year and a half is really high compute RL,
which is a very different paradigm, right, which
is basically the ability to go and do work on task
and put something together and then be evaluated
on whether that was correct or incorrect and use
that knowledge to decide what to do and to learn
from that. Right. And so we felt very strongly
that that was going to happen. I think for us,
code was the natural thing to work on for a couple
reasons. One, because we're all programmer nerds
ourselves, and so teaching AI to code is about as
cool as it gets for us, but also because code
has this whole automated feedback loop, right,
where you can run the code and that is the kind of
automated feedback that really feeds into the RL,
which makes these models so great at coding.
And then the other thing that we felt very
strongly about was that the product experience was
going to shift from what I'll call text completion
to agents basically. Right. And to first order,
I would kind of say there's been a lot of great
experiences in text completion. It's been used for
marketing, it's been used for customer support,
it's been used for education and in Coda obviously
as well. The GitHub copilot was kind of really the
dominant product of that initial wave. Right.
But I think that the big shift that we really
felt we would see is moving from kind of this text
to text model to an actual autonomous system that
can make decisions, that can interact with the
real world, that can take in feedback, that can
iterate and take multiple steps to solve problems.
And now we call that agents, but that was what we
were really excited about at the time. So it was
always coding, it was always agents. And in some
ways that kind of feels like it should have been
cleared from the start. But even with that, I feel
like we've pivoted eight times or something within
coding agents over the last year and a half, so.
I just noticed recently all the AI,
top AI companies sort of, not all,
but many of them, the product
that is winning is different,
has a different name from the company,
which is not typical, Cursors, Anysphere,
Bolt, StackBlitz, you guys are Cognition Labs,
like V0 is Vercel. And it just tells me these
all emerge later in the company's journey and
they tried a bunch of stuff and like, oh wow,
this thing worked and it's so interesting that
it's so common amongst these top AI companies.
Yeah, and there's even, I mean OpenAI,
ChatGPT, Anthropic and Claude and Google. Yeah,
it's funny. Yeah, yeah, I agree. So when we got
started, it wasn't even really a company. I mean,
it was more like a project or a hackathon almost.
We got a bunch, we booked an Airbnb basically for
a couple of weeks. This was around Thanksgiving
time and just got a bunch of people together who
were just excited to hack on some projects
and build something cool. And it's funny,
actually the first thing that we were building
for actually was more solving these more contest
programming problems and using an agentic loop
to really do better on that. And so obviously
if you run your code on the test cases, you
can evaluate, there's a lot of agentic work
that you can do there to try and do better, and
that we spent some time on that initially. And
then we've kind of gone from, I mean the story
of the whole company for us in some sense has
been going from hacker house to hacker house.
So after that we had another hacker house and
that's where kind of some of the initial ideas
for Devin came and really building a software
engineering agent and not just a coding agent
and having to interact with a lot of these tools,
but even then there were so many iterations. And
even the idea of talking to Devin for example was
like, it was something that we had to come up
with. Right. Initially, it was just like you
hand off a task and then it works and then it
shows you this whole finished code. Right. And
now obviously it's like you can jump in at
any time, you can get feedback on the plan,
you guys can scope out the task together
when you're working with Devin. And a lot
of these things we had to develop obviously, and
certainly we've learned a lot about the use cases,
the form factor. We've made a lot of big
improvements and step function improvements
on the capabilities and Devin's ability to
use tools and to bug and make decisions.
And so it's yeah, it's been a fun journey. I mean,
I think I would say that the grounding question
for us really, which is one that we think about
all the time, is really just what is the future of
software engineering and how should we be working
with AI to write code? Because I think at the end
of the day, of course that's what underlines
all of the product decisions that we make, so.
I like that you're asking the
juicy question I wanted to get
to. Before I ask it just for the
history books, when did you guys
start kind of hacking around and when did
Devin launch? How long was that period?
Yeah, so we started in November of 2023, which
was then yeah, just like hackathon mode. We
officially made it into a company around the
start of 2024, and then our initial launch
was in March. And so it was like nonstop, I mean
it's been nonstop for the entire last 17 months,
but it's getting to the launch and then
obviously working with enterprises and
developing the product a lot more, building it
and getting it to work for a lot of practical
use cases and then making it fully available
self-serve in December of last year. And now
we've rolled out 2.0 obviously just a few weeks
ago. And so it's been a very busy time for us.
Understatement of the century. Let me ask
this question because you touched on it a bit,
this whole idea of Devin as a person and this
idea of creating a personality for Devin. It's
unlike any other, I believe, AI app. No one else
has a name and you don't think of it as a person.
What made you guys decide to go that approach and
just how do you design it to work well that way?
I would say it's a decision we're pretty proud
of, I would say. I mean, I think there's a lot
of different product experiences out there, and
I think the thing that really makes Devin unique
in what it does is that you can really hand off
and more and more what we've seen honestly is
that I think a lot of kind of explaining the Devin
experience to folks is really just explain it as,
yeah, this is your junior buddy. And that goes
for a lot of the parts of the flow where in
the onboarding for example, initially I
would say we've definitely had a lot of
users come in and just kind of see the blank
screen and not really know, or they'd ask,
"Hey, I'm going to do this whole big
re-architecture, the whole code base."
And basically what we've learned over time is
to basically get folks to think more like whoa,
whoa, whoa, let's work on getting the repository
set up first. Let's make sure we hand Devin a
couple one pointer tasks so it can get familiar
with the code base. Let's get it the thing. If
Devin needs to be able to test the code or
run the linter or CI or things like that.
Obviously we want to make sure Devin's got its
own virtual machine set up to be able to do that.
And similarly, I think the usage pattern,
I think often it wasn't clear and obviously
you can sit and just kind of watch Devin
do it action by action and work that way,
but we found that the best workflow really as
a team building a lot of stuff was to work with
multiple Devins and to run them asynchronously
and to kick them off and to only jump in basically
as you needed to provide feedback or steer the
plan or anything like that. And so in many ways,
I think Devin as a name really is our attempt
to kind of capture the soul of that as a product
where it really is treating it like a bit more of
an autonomous entity that you can hand off tasks,
that you can work with, that you should
be teaching and learning with over time.
I want to come back to an area you started
us down and then I took us away from which
is impact on software engineering and how software
engineering is going to change. So there's kind of
two parts to this. Just like when people are
using Devin today, say this year, how is the
act of being an engineer and building changing
for those companies? What does that look like?
By the way, we're all software engineers
ourselves. It's like I'm a programmer
by training and still a programmer at heart
certainly. And I think the way that we've always
thought about it is there's layers of abstraction
and there's tools, and one way I would say it at
a high level is kind of I think of AI in general
as, yeah, I mean computers are obviously getting
more and more intelligence and are able to do
more and more and it's possible there may come
a day where computers truly do everything that we
do and humans are not responsible for any of it.
I don't expect that to come particularly soon, but
I guess what I would say is until that point, for
as long as we're still part of the equation, one
of the most important things to do obviously is
for us as humans is to instruct our computers on
what we want and what we want to build and what we
want to do. Right. And software engineering is, we
think of it today obviously as Python and C++ and
JavaScript and all these things, but at the end
of the day, of course the discipline is all about
just being to tell your computer what to do. And
so in that lens, I really think that programming
is, if anything, is only going to become more and
more important as AI gets more powerful. And I
think the thing that's really exciting for us is
yeah, it's really seeing that kind of iterative
transformation. And so you ask what things look
like today, and I would say, yeah, it really is
like having a junior buddy or really a team of
junior buddies that you can work with. Right.
And so every engineer on our team, we use a
ton of Devin when we're building Devin, and so
Devin merges several hundred pull requests into
production in the Devin code bases every month,
which is, I mean, our whole team is only
15 engineers, and so it's a pretty sizable
fraction of all the code that we write. And the
way that we use it is basically, yeah, everyone's
got their whole team of Devins. If you're going to
be looking through various issues, if you're going
through feature requests, if you're going through
bugs, if you're going through new paradigms that
you want to build, then it is naturally the case
that there's a lot of handoff points where you
just say, "Hey, at Devin, here's what's going
on. Can you please take a pass at this?" Right.
And sometimes Devin will be able to do the task
100% autonomously and just makes the PR and then
you merge the PR and that's great. Sometimes
you want to be able to jump in for the 10 or
20% that really needs your help. Maybe there's
a few details with how exactly you want to scope
it or how you're architecting this feature, or
maybe you want to go and test the front end at
the end yourself to make sure it looks exactly
the way that you want and give your one or two
lines of feedback after that. Right. But a lot
of it is really yeah, is kind of like yeah,
learning to work with Devin to be able to
just do more in parallel and build more.
What percentage of your PRs are
Devin versus humans right now?
Yeah, I'd have to look, but it's in the
neighborhood of a quarter or so of all of our-
Wow.
Yeah. Yeah.
And then what was it like six months ago?
Oh yeah, it's grown a ton for, I mean, we've seen
it grown exponentially internally ourselves as
well. And so it's kind of an interesting one
where again, it's always both the capabilities
and the product interface. And so I think
the intelligence has increased a lot. But
the other thing of course is that we've spent
a lot of time in figuring out how to build and
to really kind of build for an interface where
you can get Devin's value on tasks where Devin
is able to do the 80 or 90%. And so Devin is
obviously not perfect and it'll make mistakes
and so on. And a lot of the question is basically,
yeah, how do you scope out your initial task with
Devin and then just kind of set Devin off and
have it go and do the things that you want do?
How do you come in at the end and review and give
feedback? How do you make sure Devin learns over
time? How are you able to kind of just check
in as needed and course correct if you want to?
Okay, so today about quarter of
your PRs are Devins. Where do you
think this will be at the end of
the year? What would you guess?
I think by the end of this year, we expect it to
be more than half. And I mean, as time goes on,
one of the things that we've seen is just
you're able to do more and more and more work
asynchronously. Right. And you're able to hand off
more and more. I think the soul of programming,
the soul of software engineering has really
been about through all the areas, not just now,
but even when it was assembly, right, and even
when it was Pascal and even when it was punch
cards or whatever, I think the soul of
it has really been basically just about
defining the problem that you're facing
and really thinking through exactly...
... about defining the problem that you're facing
and really thinking through exactly what is the
solution that you want to build. Thinking through
the architecture, thinking through the details,
and really mapping out in your mind exactly what
you want to build basically and what you want to
have your computer do. I think that's what makes
software engineering really great and I think
that's the funnest part of software engineering.
I think, at the same time, that's probably in
the neighborhood of 10% of the average software
engineer's time, right? Because 90% of the time is
you've got this Kubernetes error, then you've got
to debug, and you have to see what went wrong and
the system crash, or you left some port open and
this is messing up, or there's a bug report that
you have to take care of, or you've got to migrate
your code, or you got it upgraded to a new version
or things like that. A lot more implementation.
One of the ways that we've kind of thought
about Devin in building Devin is really allowing
engineers to go from bricklayer to architect, so
to speak. A lot of it is just getting to the point
where you can do the high-level directing and you
can basically specify things exactly how you want.
I think it's very much about still having the
human in control and having the human able to do
the full specification, but just multiplying the
magnitude of what you can do and what you can
build in one day or one hour or however long.
In the future, say someone is trying
to get into software engineering,
thinking about becoming an engineer,
first of all, do you think people
should... Classic question everyone's getting
these days. Should you still learn to code?
Yeah.
I'd love your perspective there. And then
two, for people that are engineers today,
what skills do you think will be
more and more important and then
less important in this discussion of
moving from bricklayer to architect?
Yeah, for sure. I love this question. First of
all, the question of whether you should still
learn to code, my answer would be absolutely
yes. I think, to a large extent, when you take
computer science classes and when you learn these
fundamentals, sure you're learning a little bit
about how a particular language is, syntax works
or something like that. But honestly, most of what
you're learning really is about the ability
to logically break down problems for number
one. And two, I would say is just the model of a
computer and a lot of these decisions and a lot
of the abstractions that we've built over time.
What is a database and how should you think about
a database? What is a garbage collection system
and how do those work and all of these different
pieces? The reason I think that's important
is because it's the same with a lot of these
other... Arguably we've already gone through these
phases in programming and I think this next one is
going to be somewhat faster and somewhat bigger,
but in many ways a similar flavor, which is when
you work with Python today, obviously, a lot
of things are already abstracted away from you.
In some sense, someone from 50 years ago might
already call Python. You just get to explain in
English what you want and now the computer does
it for you. That's great and I think it's really
powerful. It's opened it up. I mean, we have far
more programmers, obviously, than we ever have
before because of that, but I would say certainly
as you're building your skills as an engineer, it
really helps a lot to understand the abstractions
and to be able to peel the layers beneath. Folks
will use assembly for example if they're really
performance optimizing a piece of code, but also
in order to build good systems and to understand
these things, you certainly want to understand
these abstractions of how does networking work.
What is TCP/IP like exactly or what happens with
this Python code when it gets interpreted or all
of these details. Similarly, I think we will get
to a state where, with no experience at all,
you're going to be able to build some pretty
cool stuff and to do some pretty amazing work
just by explaining what it is that you want. But
I think that, for quite some time, you really want
to be able to think precisely about the details,
to peel back the abstractions, to be very precise
about what it is that you want to build and how.
And then for skills that you think are
more and more valuable for engineers,
where should engineers today be
leaning more and more into versus like,
"Forget this. I don't need
to think about this anymore"?
For sure. I think architect... I mean,
we already have a term for architect and
engineering and I think it is directionally the
right term. It's, I think, one thing to just do
a routine implementation and write boilerplate
code and things like that. I would say that,
in many ways, AI coding has already made us
much faster at that, but I think a lot of
the core questions of understanding very complex
systems and working in the context of the whole
company and thinking about the product that
you're building or the work that you're doing
and understanding, "Okay, what are the
problems that we want to solve? How do
we want to solve those problems? What
is exactly the solution that we want
to build? What are all of these key decisions
and trade-offs that we're going to be making?"
Basically, I think folks who are able to do that
really, really well are just going to be able to
leverage themselves more and more. If anything, I
think there's going to be way more programmers and
way more engineers a few years from now than
there are today. I think pretty quickly the
form factor of what it means to be a programmer,
obviously, is going to change. And in some sense,
it already has, but I think there's just going to
be so much more for us to build. Folks talk about
Jevons Paradox all the time. I mean, software
is truly the shining example of Jevons Paradox,
where we have always managed as a society
to find more and more things that we want
to build software for and build more code for. I
really think there's a lot more out there to do.
For people that don't know Jevons
Paradox, can you briefly explain it?
Absolutely. Yeah. Jevons Paradox just says
that as the price of something goes down,
it can still be the case that the total spend
on it actually goes up. You can think about this
with money, you can think about this with time
or resources, but the direct version here is,
I think, as it becomes easier and easier to
program and as programming becomes more and more
effective, I think we're going to have a lot more
programmers. I think in a kind of zero-sum view,
you might say, "Well, we're going to be
10 times faster at software engineering
and it means that we're going to need
10 times fewer software engineers." But
I think in practice, what really is going to
happen is actually we're going to build even
more than 10 times as much code. And because all
of the work that we do is so capped, obviously,
on our ability to actually build and execute
and iterate, we're going to have so many great
ideas out there, we're going to have so many
great products out there. People are going to
build a lot more personalized experiences, for
example, and there's going to be a lot to do.
Going back to the way you guys use Devin, you said
that every engineer has this fleet of Devins. How
many Devins per engineer do you find most people
are working with these days at your company?
Yeah. It's very asynchronous. Obviously,
you can kick them up and start them up and
shut them down basically as you see fit, but
most folks on the team are often working with
up to five Devins at once, I would say. It's a
nice flow where you think through, "All right,
what are the five things that we want to get
done today?" You have Devin one do number one,
you have Devin two do number two, Devin three...
For what it's worth, I think it's taken us some
time to adjust to it and get to the point
where it's really intuitive for us, but I
think it's definitely a different experience where
you're handing off most things asynchronously.
The goal for each of your tasks is to be there
for the parts that really need your expertise,
either you really, really need to define exactly
what it is that you're solving for and what you're
building or maybe some of the more complex
parts where you want to steer Devin towards,
particularly what kinds of changes you want
to make. "I want the class to be set up this
way and we should go and change all the
downstream references to this as well
or whatever." But basically having Devin do
the bulk of the work asynchronously with you.
And then how many engineers
do you guys have roughly?
Yeah, our engineering team
today is about 15 people.
15. 15.
15, yeah.
Holy moly. Okay. And then
each one has five-ish Devins.
Yeah.
So there's five times the number
of Devins as engineers. What I
love about this is just a glimpse
into where the future is going.
You guys are so ahead of how companies work
with AI engineers. Seeing how you operate
is going to be, as a sense, essentially
how most companies will end up operating.
Yeah. For what it's worth, we've already seen this
shift, I would say, ourselves where... In terms of
the team, obviously, folks don't spend that much
of their time just writing out boilerplate or
just doing pure implementation of features. People
get to spend much more of their time focused on
really just thinking about the core questions
of, "How do we make Devin better? What is the
right interface for Devin? What is the right flow
or the right set of features that's really going
to make this as great of an experience
as possible?" That's how we like things.
When is the point you reach, where there's takeoff
of this being the by... Your Devin starts moving
so much further ahead of everyone else. Once
you have enough Devins doing all these things,
they're just like wherever and you're 10
years, 20 years, 30 years, 100 years ahead.
Honestly, as a community, I think all of
us as engineers around the world, I think,
are going to have to think about this and build
for this and adapt to these new technologies.
But what I would say is, I think more and
more... Especially as capabilities get better,
but certainly even in studies say today, I think
more and more things are going to shift towards
this asynchronous flow. And one of the reasons I
would say for that is in the real world, you're
just capped by real world constraints. I think
that one way to put it is kind of like... Don't
take these numbers exactly, but it's kind of like
the first order math of it is, of course, being
able to write files or to complete this function
or complete this line or things like that.
It helps a ton. It's a really great experience.
There's a lot of parts of building software that
obviously are almost not that at all, right? If
you have a bug that you're trying to fix and so
you spin up the local server, you click around
on your own product on the front end and try to
reproduce the bug yourself. Once you have the
error, you take a look at Datadog and you see
what happened and you try to find other errors
in the logs. You look at those files and you see
what went wrong, you make some edits, maybe you
go and rerun the whole process again now that
you make sure your change looks right. That's a
lot of what it means to be a software engineer.
These are processes that take real time. I think
we're going to shift more and more towards this
agentic workflow, because that's in some
ways the way to really get to that 200%,
500%, 1000% gains that we'll be getting to with
software engineering over the next few years.
Enough talk. Let's show people what the heck
this actually looks like. You've got a couple
demos prepped that show a few use cases
that you found helpful. You're going to
pull up your screen and then we'll kick it
off and then we'll talk as it's happening.
Yeah. The whole process obviously of working
with Devin is working asynchronously.
I thought it'd be cool for us to actually just
watch Devin a little bit in action and then we
can go through some other examples of work that
Devin's done or things that Devin does for us,
even on our team for example. But then we can
check back in asynchronously with our Devin after.
Let's do it.
I'll share this real quick. The key thing
that I would just emphasize here is a lot of
it obviously is really just about thinking about
as a software engineer or as engineers ourselves
or engineering teams, PMs, and so on. What are
the things that we would want to build that we
would want to hand off? We have Devin set up with
our own Devin code base, for example, and so I'll
go ahead and kick off with Devin for that. I'll
just say, "Devin, I'm on with my friend, Lenny."
Hi, Devin.
"Can you modify Devin web app two?" Let's feature
your newsletter as part of the Devin website.
Let's do it. On the real Devin website.
"Feature Lenny's site."
Yeah, lose all your features.
We're going to kick this off. As you
can see, Devin gets started instantly
and goes ahead and responds. Again,
you can work with this asynchronously,
you can work with it synchronously as well. For
this, we'll just kind of go in a little bit and
see exactly what's going on. But as you can see
here, Devin's going through files and taking a
look through a lot of stuff. We can follow here
basically as we need to and see what makes sense.
You can see Devin's already called out a few
particular pieces where there's the sidebar,
which we have implemented on the front end, and
there's pieces there. We're going to have a new
component and that component's going to link to
Lenny's website. That all sounds good. Devin's
asking us any questions if there's anything that
we have here. Same story here where you can let
Devin make its own decisions and hand off, or
you can go ahead and give some more thoughts.
Should the button open in a new tab or within an
application? I'll say let's open it in a new tab.
And you could answer these at any
point. Is it waiting for the answer?
You answer these at any point,
you can hand off, hand back off.
It's not going to be like,
"Just god damn it. I just wrote it this
way. Why didn't you tell me earlier?"
That's right. One of the big pieces with
Devin is Devin will always be enthusiastic,
will always be ready to put in the hours.
Thanks for changing scope. Thanks, Scott.
We'll give Devin a chance to work and it's
going to go through these files and it'll
make a pull request for us and we'll see and
go from there. But I thought it'd be fun to
show some other examples of Devin in action as
well. One of the examples actually this morning,
which I just used Devin for, is I asked
Devin to help me brush my own facts up
for this podcast. Obviously, a huge fan of the
podcast and the newsletter. I asked Devin, "Hey,
Devin. I'm to be on the podcast. Could you please
research everything you can about him and make a
nice website quiz for me so that I can make sure
I know my facts?" This was just this morning,
I asked Devin to do this and I'll just show what
Devin did, it looks like. Went to Wikipedia first.
Unfortunately, it's not a page in Wikipedia,
which is... Lenny, we will work on that.
I'm not a big enough deal yet.
They did you dirty. I mean, we need a page list.
And so then it went and found it on Spotify.
So you're watching what it's researching live?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. This was
this morning, obviously.
This is a playback of what Devin did. This is
part of Devin you could just watch what it did.
Yeah, yeah. Especially when you're building
engineering products or something like that, you
can see each of the steps that Devin was doing,
or if Devin tested the code locally, obviously you
want to be able to go and look and see what Devin
was cooking around with and testing or things
like that. It found the newsletter. It's going and
looking at this and it's going and reading all of
this. And then it says, "Okay, let's get started
with putting the code together." It says, "Hey,
I've researched." It's going through and writing
all of this, putting the app together. It plays
its own quiz itself. Actually, we should just play
this quiz actually. Let's see how much I know.
[inaudible 00:39:05]
What is the name?
What is the name of the podcast? Lenny's
Podcast. For people not watching,
so to say, approximately how many
subscribers? A million. Very good.
Yeah. Yeah.
What are three main topics Lenny
is focused on? Oh, product, growth,
and career. Very good. It's a good
quiz [inaudible 00:39:25] of people.
What does [inaudible 00:39:26] besides podcasting?
What does Lenny do besides podcasting?
I'd say writing, investing, and
advising. How often does Lenny-
[inaudible 00:39:35]
Once a week, right?
Once a week.
Yeah. We can go through all these
and do all these. I took this quiz,
by the way, obviously, to make
sure that I was well-prepped,
but this is kind of one of the more fun
examples, obviously, of [inaudible 00:39:46]
Scott, how many subscribers
do I have at my newsletter?
Over a million, actually.
[inaudible 00:39:52]
And then one last one I'll show and then maybe we
can come back to our initial run after. Like I was
saying, a lot of this is really built to work with
all of the existing code workflows out there. For
example, we were doing some exploration with the
DeepSeek repository on GitHub and we imported it
into Devin and we got our own fork of it set up
in Devin. A couple of things I just wanted to
show here. One is Devin sets up its whole wiki
with all of its internal understanding. When
Devin indexes the code base, obviously, building
a representation of the code base and learning
it and improving it over time is one of the big
things that Devin does. Funnily enough, we found
that naturally humans really are interested to
understand this code base representation as well.
Devin Wiki is something that we built
here and you can take a look at all
these different pieces and see each of these
different things. Here are the FP8 operations,
here's an SG [inaudible 00:40:46] integration.
There's diagrams of how the different layers
are built and put together. There's deployment
operations. There's a lot of details about the
architecture as well. You can ask questions
about it as well. For example, you can say,
"How does DeepSeek handle multi-token prediction
designed for spec deck?" It'll go through and it's
able to search through the entire code base and
give you an informed answer based off of that.
We use this a lot. It helps when
you're scoping out a task for Devin
and doing an initial prompt. It also
helps, obviously just in a vacuum,
you often have questions about your
code base that are really nice.
This episode is brought to you by Attio, the
AI-native CRM. Attio is built to scale with
your business from day one. Connect your email
and calendar and Attio instantly builds a CRM
that matches your business model, with all of
your company's Contacts and interactions enriched
with actionable insights. Sync in your product's
usage, billing info, or any other data sources
and Attio's flexible data model will handle it
all without any rigid templates or workarounds.
With Attio, AI isn't just a feature. It's the
foundation. You can do things like instantly
prospect and route leads with research
agents, get real-time insights from AI
using customer conversations, and build powerful
AI automations for your most complex workflows.
Industry leaders like Flatfile, Replicate, and
Modal are already experiencing what's next for
CRM. Go to A-T-T-I-O.com/lenny to get 15% off
your first year. That's A-T-T-I-O.com/lenny.
Something that I've learned as I've been talking
to more and more AI building companies and apps
is there's a big difference in how large of a
code base they could integrate into. That's a
big deal for companies that are existing versus
startups, people that have large existing code
base. How should people think about what
kind of code base Devin can plug into?
Yeah. We go all the way to the biggest code
base as possible. One way I'd kind of put it
is how... The way that we as engineers would
think about a large code base is certainly
when you're making changes or when you're
thinking about a particular task. You're not
bringing in every single line of the code base
at once. You have a high level of traction that
you're able to think about and look into and
then you're obviously able to zoom in and get
to higher resolution on each of these different
things. Devin works in much the same way,
where the first thing it'll do is it's going
to figure out the high level architecture of
what's going on here and what this is built for
and so on. But within each of the components,
it's obviously also going to be able to
zoom in and give some more detail about
each of these. Here's FP8 to be float 16
and how exactly a lot of that is set up.
Here's each of the different parts of the code
base. Similarly, we built this to be scalable.
It's essentially coming back to
the engineer as architect. Now,
it's helping you understand the
architecture, kind of circling back to that.
Yeah. Yeah, exactly. One of the fun use cases that
we've seen actually with folks is they'll often
actually get Devin's help to onboard new engineers
on the team. When you're new and you're joining,
there's obviously a lot of questions that you
have about the code base or about how things are
set up. It also sometimes can be a little bit
awkward to ask your mentor or your manager the
questions and if you're worried that they're going
to be really dumb questions. It's nice to just be
able to ask Devin and to go through Devin's wiki
and to understand these internal representations.
I think that's really interesting, because
it comes back to your point that Devin is
not just a junior engineer. It's
what you call a jagged engineer.
A jagged intelligence.
A jagged intelligence, where it's almost like a
staff engineer at understanding the code base.
Usually, you have to ask an engineer that's
been there a long time, " What does this do?
Where is this thing? How does this work?"
It feels like Devin's very good at that.
Yeah. Yeah. Obviously, the retrieval
and processing a lot of code and a lot
of tokens at once is something that language
models are really great at. Basically being
able to get those gains in the places that you
need them is really great. Yeah. Sweet, cool.
All right. You got a couple more use?
Yeah. One last thought I'll show is just...
We just rolled this out last week actually,
but it's a full Devin automation setup with
Linear. If you have tasks that you're doing
on the DeepSeek repository, for example, and
it's all set up, all you have to do is you
just add the Devin label and Devin will come
through and it'll give you this. It's going
to give you its thoughts on what the tasks
looks like and you can take a look at each
of the particular files that you see, or it'll
point out snippets that it thinks are important.
From there, if you feel good about what was
built or the conclusions that we came to,
then you can just start off the Devin session
that will go and actually do that work.
That is insane. That sounds
like such a simple idea,
but essentially what you're saying
is there are tasks in Linear that
are fixes and features and now Devin just
goes off and can just do them for you.
Yeah. Definitely it's a hands-on process.
You certainly want to be involved when Devin
is scoping out the task or giving you its
thoughts. The nice thing, too, by the way,
is Devin will give you its confidence level.
Here's how likely I am to really understand
this piece or that piece or whatever, but it
helps make things a lot faster. To your point,
a lot of product managers, for example,
obviously love to be able to use Devin
in Linear to understand the code base better
or things like that. Claire Vo, for example,
from LaunchDarkly is a big Devin user and she
loves basically going and scoping out tasks or
asking data questions or asking, "Hey, what's
going on? Or is this merged into production
yet? Or is this a feature flag right now? Or
what percent of people are getting this or
that feature?" It's a clean way basically to
make that intelligence much more accessible.
I love, just with the integration with Linear,
that you can still keep it really simple.
You add a little ticket like, "Hey, this link to
this home page, do this," and Devin will be really
good at understanding what you mean and then show
you, "Here's what I'm thinking." Is this right?
Yeah. Yeah, cool. Okay. Yeah, Devin
did finish working. It seems like
there's something going on with the
CI and it's debugging that right now,
but it went ahead and put up the initial first
pass pull request and we can take a look.
Let's do it.
This is the Devin website, obviously,
in this custom deploy and we have
Lenny's newsletter right here.
Let's ship this to production.
We won't be so confused.
Yeah.
That's amazing. Okay. Show it again real
quick. Just added it to the home page of Devin.
Yeah. Devin, obviously, has access to our Devin
code base. It does a lot here and so it's
super familiar with all the pieces here.
Beautiful.
Yeah, I like how that looks.
We've got Devin search,
we got Devin [inaudible 00:47:33],
and we've got Lenny's newsletter.
[inaudible 00:47:34]. You link to my
site. We'll get some PageRank going.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay. Is that a good example? Oh, there it is.
What a beautiful website for my newsletter. Is
that just a good example of the kind
of thing Devin is very good at like,
"Here's a very specific thing to change on
the website"? How does your people think
about what Devin is very good at and
maybe where it starts to fall apart?
The way that we often describe it is, I
think, Devin is best when it is working
on tasks that are well-defined.
One way to put it, you might...
On tasks that are well-defined. One way to
put it is, you want to be giving Devin tasks,
not problems. And a lot of these things like
what you just saw, which was kind of like a quick
front-end feature request or a bug fix or adding
testing and documentation or things like that.
One of the things that makes a loop really
nice obviously is a quick way to iterate
and test. And so with something like this,
obviously super easy for us, for example,
to just go pull up the preview and see that
the link worked. Obviously it would be easy
for Devin to do as well. Devin will often go
and log in to Devin and start a Devin session
and make sure when it's working on our code
base, which is kind of hilarious. But yeah,
you generally want something that is kind of easy
to verify and easy to test is the main thing. And
you can work on bigger projects or bigger asks
as well, obviously. But in that case you should
certainly expect to need to steer Devin more
to make sure it's going the right direction.
It's interesting because that's very similar to
the way people talk about synthetic
data and reinforcement learning,
creating data that's very easy. There's
a very definitive answer, yes and no.
Yeah.
It's very clear.
Okay. Let me ask you this
question. What's something
that you guys debated a lot as you
were designing and building Devin?
I'll give a couple that comes to mind.
One I would say is a question of,
I'll call it how opinionated we should be. We
had the workflows that we used to Devin for,
which was very much as you can see for basically
integrating to our Slack and GitHub making pull
requests for us in our repos, responding to issue
reports or things like that. And naturally we've
had certainly a lot of other different things
that have come up that folks have tried. I mean,
we have folks who order their DoorDash with Devin,
for example. Even we have folks, certainly a
lot of people who are building cool websites
from scratch or working on things like that.
Yeah, I mean it is been an interesting trade
off for us where I think the way that I would
describe it is in our product, certainly the
large bulk of the features that we build are
for this kind of making pull requests and
engineering teams use case. But I think
basically our kind of general stance with all the
others is obviously if folks want to use Devin for
that, that's great and we want to just make sure
that they're fully aware about the limitations
and about where things can get caught up.
It is funny with AI and especially because I would
say one of, I would say the most common pieces of
advice out there I would say is focus on a really
niche cohort. Do things that don't scale, make
one use case that's really great and then you grow
from there. And I think that's great advice across
the board. But yeah, it's kind of interesting
because I think with generative AI, you naturally
see this where a lot of product experiences can
turn out to be more general. And so it's an
interesting trade-off for us. This is something
that we still always go back and forth on and
how much do we want to do more to support all the
other kind of use cases out there to handle other
things that folks might want to do with Devin.
I think another one that comes to mind is how much
Devin should be, let's say a single comprehensive
project experience versus a suite of tools. And
as you can see here, we have Devin search, we have
Devin Wiki, we have the linear ticket scooping,
and certainly these tools interact with each
other, but I think as time has gone on, we've seen
it more and more as really building this suite of
tools. And I think the core agent experience and
the core kind of agent that will go off and build
each of these build things for you, for example,
is always of course going to be that's Devin,
and that is the core piece. I think that will
always be what's really special about our work.
But I think that all of the other features out
there, there is a complex suite of work that's
required for real-world software sharing and
engineering is just messy at the end of the day.
And so I think there are a lot of different flows
and a lot of different use cases that makes sense.
And an obvious thing to point out is you could ask
the same questions to Devin search as you could to
Devin and Devin will go through and it'll do the
same thing. It'll go through and look through the
files and give you an answer and stuff.
But with that said, on the one hand,
I think on the capability side, there's
certainly a lot you can do to really optimize
things for very specifically question answer
about this repository and that made sense to
really build into a specific kind feature.
And then on the other side, I would say
we found that users actually really, really
like having this access of control. Sometimes
you have a task that you're thinking about, but
you actually don't want Devin to get started on
the task just yet. You want to ask Devin and
understand what parts of the code base might
be relevant. And so you want to be very direct
about saying, "This is just an ask and I just
want to see the snippets of the code base that
relate," or, "I just want to look at the Wiki
and understand the existing representation."
And so it's on both the capabilities and on
the UX side, we've found that that's kind
of what's naturally made sense over time.
Well, let's talk about the landscape then
of just other companies in the space,
which is something a lot of people are always
thinking about. There's all these different
approaches. You guys are going full on AI
engineer, there's obviously ID companies.
There's also just models being built that are
really good at engineering. Everyone's kind of
starting to build agents now. You guys are
ahead on this in a lot of ways. OpenAI just
recently said they're going to build a software
engineering agent. Anthropics got something there.
Cursor and Windsurf have their only agents and
Replit. Thoughts on just where you guys fit in
the landscape and then how do you think you
win long term. How do you think about that?
Yeah, and for what it's worth, I think all
of these are incredible teams. I think really
smart and really forward-thinking folks who are
building a lot of great products out there. And
I think there's a lot to do honestly over the next
few years with the advent of AGI or whatever you
want to call it. I think one of the quotes that
I love is in 2017, if you asked if we had AGI,
the answer is no. And in 2025, if you ask if
we have AGI, the answer is, "Well, you have
to define AGI. And it depends on your subject."
And I think it does get to the point of, I mean
there is a lot of really amazing stuff happening.
I think that it's easy to underrate, I would say
just how big of a shift it is that we're seeing
where I think there are a lot of great products
out there, for example, over the last 10 years,
20 years, 30 years, that have made each of these
different niches of the life cycle of building a
product a little bit easier, for example, right?
There's great products out there for instant
response, there's great products out there for
logging, there's great products out there for
billing, there's all of these different tools.
And the obvious thing is what we're seeing
with AI is all of these spaces are going to
be moving multiple times faster and it's going to
be like an order of magnitude shift, if anything.
And so I think from our perspective, we've
obviously had a very specific lens that we've
bet on this whole time, and that is autonomous
coding agents. And there's a lot of problems to
solve there, to be honest, right? There's still
a ton to do on the core capabilities, certainly,
and we see cases all the time where it's like,
wow, why did Devin make that decision? That seems,
no human engineer would've ever done that.
There's all sorts of spots where, with the product
interface, there's obviously a lot to think about.
And I think it's by the way, not just a single
thing that we're working towards, but
something that will change with every
edition of capabilities. I kind of think of
it as there's 20 generations of agent product,
agent coding experiences to come. I think the one
that we'll get to over the course of several years
is probably something where you don't even look at
the code at all, right? And you're actually just
looking at your own product and you're just able
to look and specify and say, "Hey, this button
should be a little bit rounder. Let's do that. And
by the way, let's add a new tab here and maybe we
should save this information. Let's start up a
database table and let's index it on X, Y, and Z
columns." And you're just basically working with
your products in real time and having your agent
build out those things for you. Obviously there's
going to be a lot of generations in between here
and there, but I think the product experience
itself is going to change every single time.
And then obviously there, there's all of the
practicality of just getting it out there in
the world. And so folks obviously need to learn
how to use the new technology. There's a lot to
do to deploy into all of the messiness of
real world software. There's a lot of COBOL
out there still. There's a lot of FORTRAN
out there still. There's lots of kind of
abstractions and details that folks have done.
And so I think from our perspective, we have
since the beginning have been laser-focused on
agentic coding, and that is the one thing that
we've really believed in. It's the one thing that
we've designed for and that goes all the way to
even the revenue model with ACUs and having the
usage-based setup. It does into obviously all
the product experiences of thinking how,
okay, where do you want to talk to Devin?
You want to be able to talk to Devin in Slack,
you want to be able to spin this up from your
issue. You want to be able to all of these
things and then of course the capabilities.
And so I don't think there's any one easy answer.
I think it's obviously a combination of things,
but this has been the space that we've lived
in and spent all of our time in for the last
year and a half, and it's going to be that
way for the next five or 10 years too.
Along these lines, a big question everyone
always has in AI's moats and defensibility,
it's a question I've been asking
every founder that comes on. How
do you just think about how to build a moat
in this space when it's so much easier to
build and so much is built on these models
that are themselves advancing so quickly?
I'd give one slight tweak on that, which is
I think it's often less about moats and more
about stickiness. And what I mean by that is
moats are in some sense, typically what folks
mean by moats is something that means that a
competitor couldn't even enter the market. And
I agree that at a high level, a lot of different
folks at different layers of the AI spectrum,
the foundation labs or the application layer or so
on, I don't think there's any kind of hard barrier
that would prevent others from entering. I think
what does exist is stickiness, which I would kind
of define as once you have a product experience
that you really like, are you excited to keep
using that experience or is there an effect where
it is just as easy from now on to just switch
on to a new one and learn a new one and so on.
And I think from that perspective, I think there's
a few things that are really great about coding
agents in particular. One I would say is there
is a lot of just inherent stickiness and learning
and buildup over time, which is that as you use
Devin and as your whole team uses Devin, it's the
same thing with an engineer. If you're joining on
day one versus you've been at the company for
five years, you wrote half the code yourself,
you've touched every file you've built every
single piece, you know all the engineers. And
so similarly, it's like Devin will really learn
and build its representation of your code base
and of your stack and of your process over time
and will be able to do a lot more with that.
And then the other piece of it, which I think is
really exciting I'd say is there really is a lot
to do of what I would call a multiplayer aspect
of code, which if you think about it, is how a lot
of things get done in the real world, certainly.
And so it's one thing to have your own experience,
which you use yourself as just an engineer, but
for example, ourselves, we see this all the time
where some engineers are working with Devin
and teaching Devin things and as I mentioned,
folks will have Devin on board their new engineers
and kind of convey that knowledge to them.
Or similarly, it's like I'll start a session
with Devin in Slack and I'll say, "Hey, it'd
be cool if we could do this thing." And some other
engineer will chime in and say, "Oh, by the way,
the reason we did it initially was X and Y." And
so Devin, just make sure when you do this change
that you still support that workflow. And Devin
will say, "Okay, sounds great." Or Devin will
make a PR, I'll be working with Devin, we'll make
pull requests and GitHub and somebody else will
be reviewing that PR or give some comments and
Devin will work on that too. You'll be in linear.
So all these kind of spaces, it really does just
kind of set up for an experience basically where
Devin can just grow in the value that it can
provide for your whole work over time. And
so I think from that perspective, if anything,
we want there to be a lot of innovation and a
lot of new products and so on. I don't think
that the goal is to try to lock other people
out of building. There's a lot of stuff
to build, and I think there's going to be
a lot of different experiences. I think from
our perspective, what we think about is more
like how can we make Devin more and more
and more useful as you're using it more?
It's very similar. We had Michael from Cursor,
the CF Cursor on the podcast, and he had a
similar point of just he thinks moats are just
kind of like consumer, like Google is the way,
he thinks it's like Google where people can
easily switch. You just have to stay the best,
and that's the answer. And it feels like you're
adding to that of just like, but also if you can
create some stickiness where it is very hard to
leave because it's so good at what it's doing
and it's built knowledge and integrated to your
workflows and builds on that on that stickiness.
Yeah, and I think one of the things
that's nice about our space too is,
software engineering for better for worse has a
very clear tie to value. And what it means is,
I guess one way to put it is there
is always kind of a clear next level,
at least for the next while. I think there
could be some point where you're just like,
"All right, just build the entirety of YouTube
for me." And Devin just does the whole,
it's like there's probably been a hundred million
hours of human engineering time building YouTube,
building the algorithm, building all the
infrastructure, all of the, everything,
every little detail. And maybe there's some
time where Devin just does that out of the box.
That's obviously going to be a long time from now.
I think on the interim, on every level in between,
obviously it makes a difference the quality of
software engineering. And I think one of the cool
things with developers obviously is developers
are really willing to learn new experiences and
to put in effort if it means that they're able
to have a higher and higher quality experience.
Awesome. I'm going to spend a little time on
the tech that enables Devin. Without divulging
trade secrets, just what allowed you to
make Devin so good? Was there an unlock
with a certain model? Some folks have
shared three points on a 3.5 was a huge
unlock for a lot of their products.
Just what's kind of the key to the
way you've architected or built
Devin that makes it work so well?
We obviously, we've been betting on agents
for a long time. I think that agents were
doable and workable a lot earlier than most folks
might've thought. But certainly I think as the
community has really rallied around it, I mean
you see the impacts of that in the pre-training,
you see the impacts of that in a lot of the work
that's done with these models. I actually don't
think there's been any, from our perspective, I
don't think there's been any single step function
based model shift or anything that has been kind
of like a night and day difference in Devin,
but I certainly think that the curve of every
point on the chart, I mean there's a new model
that comes out every week now has obviously made
a big difference in terms of what we've been
able to do. And then obviously on top of that,
we work with the research teams at all these
foundation labs to do a lot of our work on top.
And so I think that my hot take here at which I
would give is, I think in terms of base
intelligence, we're honestly basically
already there. And I think a lot of what we
see actually and what we spend our time on
is less so, obviously, we don't our own models
or things like that. It's less so increasing
the base IQ of a model, for example, and more
about teaching it all of the idiosyncrasies of
real-world engineering and thinking about
here's how you use Datadog and do this,
and here's how you might diagnose this error and
here are the different things that you could run
into and here's how you handle each of those. And
when you're ready, here's how you make GitHub PR.
And this is true in engineering. It's
true in every other space as well. I mean,
there's so much detail and idiosyncrasy to the
work that we all do obviously day to day. And a
lot of it is kind of like teaching the model
to mirror the complexity of the real world,
I would say, rather than getting it to some
higher fundamental level of problem solving,
which I think the foundation labs
are doing a really great job.
There's something you shared when we
were chatting before we started recording
around the growth of previous transformative
technologies were very hardware oriented and
there was a limiting factor to their growth and
AI is not that. Can you just share that insight?
For a number of reasons? I think AI is going to
be the biggest technology shift of our lives,
but I think one thing, which is what we were
just talking about before this, which is most
of the big tech revolutions that we've had over
the last 50 years, I mean, I'm thinking about
personal computer and the internet and the mobile
phone and stuff, they all had this big hardware
component that was a big part of the distribution.
And so you had the internet, and initially it was
just these universities that were talking with
one another, but obviously over time we got the
whole world plugged into the internet and it took
years and years and years. Same thing was true
with mobile phones. Same thing was true with PC.
And the thing that's interesting about that in
particular, which is I would say we're
already seeing the effects of that,
is in these hardware distribution machines,
obviously there's a lot that depends on real
time. And so folks who were building for those
industries saw their market grow and grow and
grow basically steadily year over year as the
number of people with mobile phones increased,
as the number of people connected to the internet
increased. And many of those businesses, it's
still crazy to think, but many of those businesses
got started right in the beginning. I mean,
Apple and Microsoft were started right around
the same time. And same is true for a lot of
the great internet businesses or wherever, but
certainly it was something that touched whole
world with time or a large fraction of the whole
world. And it had a really massive impact, but it
took place over several years because of the time
that it took. And I think one of the things which
is already I'd say different in AI, is just how
explosive the technology can be. Once AI could,
and I think we're firmly past the inflection point
in AI code where it's, as an engineer, if you're
not using AI at all to write code, I mean you're
falling behind honestly. And it is a technology
that everyone should have and should be using, and
there's no kind of weight on hardware distribution
that is causing that. It means that the space
is just growing so exponentially, basically.
Michael Ballin has this interesting point
that cliches are cliches because they're
so true and that's why they're cliches.
I heard that a million times and I think
it's like people hear this like, "Yeah,
yeah, I know," but it's actually insane
what is happening. That's why you're
here to help us through this transition.
Yeah, no, I mean, it is a fun time and I think
there will be real investment and real work that
it takes. But I think from the perspective of
us as engineers, for example, I think it just
means it's so important to stay in the loop with
everything that's happening. And as we're seeing
it's not only because of your learning and your
ability to work these technologies, but it's also
about basically teaching the AI what there is
to know about your code base in order to make
it really effective at building with you and doing
more of the things that you would want it to do.
So along those lines, for people
listening that they're like, "Hey,
we should be using Devin at our company," what
are things you've found to be helpful in helping
an engineer at a company get adoption and be able
to use Devin either culturally or logistically?
So a pattern which we often see with
folks is there will be a few folks
at the team who are really excited
and want to try out the new thing,
and they want to put in the investment and are
really excited to get it going. And they'll go
through all the setup. They'll give Devin the
repos, they'll teach Devin how to run the lint
and the CI and all of those details. And they'll
start off by giving it those initial tasks and
help Devin build a foothold basically. And
as time goes on, eventually folks will see,
"Wow, Devin's writing all these PRs,
Devin's doing this [inaudible 01:08:14].
Who's this Devin person that just joined
the company's just knocking out PRs?
Yeah. And they'll see that, and
then naturally they'll get on and
they'll get an account. And one of the cool
things of course is by the time they join,
Devin already knows a good amount of detail about
the repositories that they're already working in
and they're working with that. And so one of the
really cool things which we often see is that the
early adopters themselves can really pave the
way I think, for everyone else on the team.
But yeah, I think the main thing I would just
kind of call out is it really does take, it's
a very different product experience, and I think
for what it's worth, I think there's still a lot
more that we can do to make it as intuitive and as
clear as possible to folks like how to use Devin
and what the right steps are and how to really
maximize value out of Devin. But I think that,
yeah, it's the kind of thing where if you put
in the investment and understand exactly what
it takes to get Devin to be successful, we've
found ourselves that as time has gone on,
we just use Devin more and more
and more with every next update.
So let me follow that thread. There is a
question I ask every AI app building founder,
which is, if you could sit next to every new
user of Devin and whisper something in their
ear to help them be successful with Devin,
one or two tips, what would those tips be?
I think the biggest thing I would say is it really
is just treat Devin like your new junior engineer.
And I think that's the biggest thing. I think
folks come in and they see the blank page and they
think of all sorts of various things that they
want to try out. They think of lots, where I think
typically the flow that we see that works best is
obviously you can try demos and you can do things,
but a lot of it is just like, "Yeah, let's figure
out what tickets we want to get done today or this
week and let's have Devin get started on those
and let's start with the easier ones and then work
with Devin and understand what things Devin needs
to get set up to be able to test its own code and
do this well. And then let's scale up over time."
And then obviously as you work with your engineer,
you understand better how to communicate
with them or what are the right tasks or
projects to bring them in on. But I think
that really is the one-liner for us.
Okay. There's a question I'd be meeting
task. I just want to get back to this
because it's something I think a lot about with
Devins. Everyone's going to have five Devins,
let's say 10 Devins. Everyone's kind of turning
into basically an engine manager with a bunch of
junior engineers, which isn't necessarily the best
job in the world because it's just a bunch of, at
least you don't have to do performance reviews and
one-on-ones, but it's sitting around, checking a
lot of PRs all day. There's a sense of you become
an architect, which is kind of what every engineer
wants to become eventually, right? They're all,
"I just want to think about the architecture. I
don't want to code all these stupid, fix bugs."
So I get that there's a good side to that,
but just I imagine you're thinking a lot about
this, just like how do you make life pleasant
and fun and enjoyable as basically an engine
manager of say, 500 Devins in the future?
Yeah, I can just imagine the performance,
"Devin, you've done a really great job on
your task, but I really would like you to be more
proactive in the team meetings." So what I'd say-
[inaudible 01:11:29].
It's funny actually because something that
in terms of the wording that we thought a
lot about as well is just, we've used
the term manager of Devins in the past,
which of course I think is a big part
of it. But I think that the only thing
I would point out here is I think that the
bricklayer versus architect is closer to the
experience than being a manager. Because I
think a lot of the difficulty of management
or the reason that people shy away from it
is more because of a lot of the various.
... [inaudible 01:12:00] because of a lot of the
various, let's say... There's all of the context,
and the ownership, and the responsibility
and stuff, and then there's also all of the
emotional aspects of it. Where, I think working
with Devin is a little more like just being,
more as having an interface to hand
off tasks and build tasks. And so,
the parallel that I would draw is when we invented
Python, obviously... It's like, in many ways the
description and the outlining of tasks, obviously
it was a different paradigm, but I think certainly
it was nowhere near what folks typically
think of as management bureaucracy today.
And I think that with Devin, a lot of it is just
like, it's more like finding the right levels of
abstraction that you could work with Devin on, and
just finding the workflows that work really well,
and the obvious thing to say here is, it's like
you can always have Devin take a first pass at
things. And so you have Devin take the first
pass, if it's great, you merge it right away,
if it needs some touch up, you can obviously
give that feedback, for example, but a lot of
it is like, it's more about, basically making
Devin part of your flow than it losing control,
which I think is the main thing that
folks are scared of with management.
Are you thinking about a manager Devin?
Like a Devin that manages other Devins?
Yeah, yeah. So, for what it's worth, Devin
can start other Devins through the API,
right? And so, we've seen this happen quite
a bit of times, where naturally if you have
some big tasks that you want to do, Devin will
do this all the time, it'll chunk up and then
[inaudible 01:13:53] into smaller Devins. And
so, it's the kind of thing that you need to give
Devin the credentials to be able to do that, it's
not currently something that is default enabled,
but I can certainly imagine as time goes
on that there's more and more of that
Devins all the way down.
Yeah, yeah. I think the thing that's kind
interesting too is, with humans, the way I almost
say it, in technical terms, it's like there's
this coupling of a context and a thread, and what
I mean by that is basically, each human can only
operate a single threaded on the work that they
do, and they have their set of context, and then
there's other humans obviously who can do other
stuff at the same time, but they have their own
context. With agents, one of the cool things is
you can have an agent that's doing multiple lines
of exploration at once, but is sharing all of the
context of everything that they find, and so I
think that this is very early, and I think we'll
see this, but folks obviously love to talk about
basically systems of agents communicating with
one another, and I think that there will be a lot
of new paradigms to build for, once we get there.
And it's so interesting what you said about the
decision between having one Devin and only one
Devin do all the things, and you just tell them
things and they fire off jobs versus you have
five Devins, and they're each doing individual
things, it's such an interesting decision to make.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, for sure.
Okay, two more questions. Maybe the
most counterintuitive thing you've
learned so far building Devin, that maybe goes
against startup wisdom, common startup wisdom?
Something I've thought about a lot lately as
we've built this is, this is not my first company,
actually for a lot of us, it's not our first
company, I think of our 26 or 27 people total
on the team, I think 18 of us have started our own
company before this. And yeah, one of the things
I think about is, there's actually your point
about cliches I think really spoke to me as well,
which is, there's the really common things
which you hear all the time in startups,
where you're like, you got to move fast, or you
got to hire great people, it's like, okay, well,
obviously you do, I wasn't planning on not hiring
great people, I wasn't planning on going slow. And
similarly it's like, yeah, you really got to build
something that people want. And there's these
three to five things which are always repeated,
and they're always the common wisdom in startups.
And I definitely had this idea as a
founder, when I was starting initially,
that, all right, so those are the three to five
basic things, but as you get really deep into it,
you spend a lot of years into it, you learn
all of the thousands of other things that
you have to learn to build a company. And I
think to some extent that's, of course, true,
and there's lots of little details that you'll get
into with all these different things, including
team building, and product, and strategy, and
engineering decision-making, and fundraising,
and sales, and every other component. But I also
realized that as time has gone on, more and more,
I felt like building companies well sometimes just
comes down to doing those three to five things
just even more than you could possibly expect.
And so, with us, it's like... And everyone says we
go fast, but it's like, yeah, we had a hackathon
in November, we had another hackathon in December,
we started the company officially in January,
we got the prototypes out to initial users in
February, we did a launch in March, we got our
first customers in April... It's just like,
basically truly pushing the pace in every
spot where we possibly could has really made a
difference for us. And similarly, it's like, yeah,
everyone always says you should hire great people,
but I think that the truth within that truth is
basically you should fight to all ends basically,
to get the folks that you really want to bring
in. And one of my favorite stories to share is
we had a candidate who came and interviewed, he
was a junior at MIT, so he was very, very young,
and we gave him an interview, and he did way
better than almost any of the full-time candidates
that we had ever talked to. And so, we said, hey,
what do you think about taking some time off of
school and working with us and building out Devin?
We really think you're just going to be able to
come in and just have a ton of impact already
from day one. And he thought about it for a
while, and he came back and he said, you know
what? I'm down, I want to do it, but my parents
really want me to graduate from school, and I'm
just not sure there's a way to make it work. And
so, we talked him more and just understood the
situation, and then we flew to North Carolina,
went straight from the airport to his parents'
house, had dinner with him and his parents,
we talked a lot, a really nice Gujarati family, we
gave them some gifts and just talked to them about
it, and try to understand what would it take, and
what would we need to make work. And they just
said, it sounds like a great opportunity, but
we really want our son to be able to graduate.
And we talked that through and we figured out
a setup basically, where he could work for us
essentially full time, but then come in for his
required classes, and do what he needed to do to
get the diploma basically, but no more than that.
And we talked that through, and then we got to a
point where everyone was happy with that, and then
went straight back to the airport and flew right
back, basically. And that was the first and only
time that I've ever been in North Carolina, and it
was just a great trip. And it is the kind of thing
where it's like, hiring great people is one thing,
but truly just never giving up, and really giving
it everything that you can to make it work for
people who really makes sense to be on the team.
And he's been with us on the team for over a year
now, and he's been an incredible, incredible
engineer, and we wouldn't be here without him.
And similarly, we had someone else who was
again, really, really talented candidate,
did amazingly well, very young, and had a lot
of great offers at a lot of other companies,
and we were talking to them about, he wanted
to start his own company someday as well,
and we were talking to him about certainly a lot
of the obvious things, which are having him meet
our investors, or get to do work with customers,
or see a lot of these other components so that
when the time came that he would have all the
experience he needed to start his own company.
But one of the other things that was big is he
was talking with a lot of great companies already,
he didn't want to burn any bridges,
and so we actually worked with him and
basically hand wrote all of his rejection
responses to each of the other companies,
and worked with him on it to say, here's how
you should say it in a way that's going to
come off as that you really did appreciate the
time with them, and that obviously you want to
remain close with them and stay in touch. And it
was the kind of thing obviously where it's like,
look, obviously our job is to make sure that he's
happy enough that he doesn't want to leave at any
time in the near future, but I think it's
the kind of thing where the way that you
put together a really, really great team is
by fighting for what's right for them too.
Wow, those are incredible stories. And it
makes so real these, as you say, cliches,
hire the best people, this is what it sounds like
to hire the best people. This is what it takes.
Yeah, no, and I was just saying, a
lot of things we've fought very hard
to just reimagine things from the ground up
because a lot of it really is just thinking
about where do we think the technology
is going over the next five, 10 years,
and what is the place that we
want to have in that future?
I wonder if people are going to be
fighting for the best Devin someday.
They're just going to [inaudible 01:21:19] Devins.
Yeah.
They're [inaudible 01:21:22] so smart.
I'll give you overtime pay,
benefits, free healthcare,
and everything, and then the Devin's like...
Three Devins like Magic: The Gathering cards.
Yeah.
And then just going back to your three to five
things. So, essentially this is incredible advice,
essentially, it's like you always hear hire the
best people, move fast, build things people want.
Yeah, build something people want, stay as
close as possible to your customers, and then
I think the other thing is just always think about
where things are going, not where they are today.
I feel like those are the five things, which is...
Especially in AI, with things moving so fast,
and there's so much great talent, I feel like a
lot of these are even more true, where it's like
it's not just thinking about where things are
going to be in 10 years, it's like thinking
about what's going to happen next week. And
obviously, things are moving very quickly,
and it is very hard to predict, but you really
have to be very rigorous with yourself, I'd say,
about thinking through those things and evaluating
all of the decisions that you make in that lens.
And staying focused is the big takeaway
to me here, is it ends up feeling like
there's 1000 things you should do,
but it's always these five things.
Yeah.
Scott, we covered a lot of ground. We went through
every question I had, which is great, is there
anything else that you want to share? Anything
else you want to leave your listeners with, maybe
a final nugget or something really you want to
double down on that we said before we let you go?
The biggest thing that comes to mind for me is
there's a lot of different perceptions about AI,
right? I think basically every emotion under the
sun right now. There's a lot of fear, for example,
there's also a lot of skepticism, and
we're very skeptical types as well,
and we always wanted to try it ourselves to really
see it and believe it. And I think the main thing
that comes to mind for me, is I'm honestly really
optimistic about what we're building here with AI,
not just with code and with Devin, but the whole
space, and everything that's getting done. And I
think one of the cool things that is really
actively happening is just the ability for
everyone to multiply themselves, and that's how
we've always thought about it, it's how we've
thought about what we're building. And I think
there is a lot more to do out there in the world,
I'm not too worried about us running
out of things to do, and from that lens,
I think that the thing that we've always been
most excited about is, how can we all do more?
I hear you Scott. Well, with that optimism,
we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
Yeah, let's do it.
Okay, here we go. First question,
what are two or three books that you find
yourself recommending most to other people?
In terms of nonfiction, I think for folks in
startups, I think one of the things that I've
really enjoyed is just learning and understanding
the history of Silicon Valley. And it's all
of these things that we think about, somebody
invented them. It's one of the great realizations
I feel like, is somebody invented the idea of
a seed route, somebody invented the idea of
venture capital, somebody invented the idea of
product-market fit, and all of these different
principles that we talk about. And so, for that,
there's a book called The Power Law by Sebastian
Mallaby, which I really like. And basically,
it's just a tour of many of the great businesses
and the great products that have been built
over the last 60, 70 years in Silicon Valley,
which I really love. I think in terms of
fiction, I actually have always really liked
The Great Gatsby by F. Scott Fitzgerald, it's
one of my personal favorites as a fiction book.
Do you have a favorite recent movie
or TV show that you've really enjoyed?
I have to admit, I have not
watched... I can't think of
a single movie or TV show that I
have watched in the last while,
so I'm sure, I'm looking forward to
watching a lot of great ones post-AGI.
That's got to be in the trailer, that's great,
I like that. And that just shows how hard
you're working, just how much shit is going on,
and how fast everything's moving. Do you have
a favorite product you've recently discovered
that you really love? Could be an app, could
be something physical, could be a toothbrush.
One I would say is I got an Aura frame recently,
it's just like a frame that shows photos, and you
can show a new photo every day, or every hour,
or every 15 minutes, or whatever you like.
I've actually, I've really enjoyed it a lot,
I think it's a nice way to basically just have
a picture frame memories that come up. And then,
the other thing I would say as a general purpose
thing, it's not particularly new, but I would say,
I think AirPods are extremely well-built and
well-designed. And I realize now that it's like,
I basically use them for all... I'm taking calls
on a walk and I'm using AirPods, obviously I'm
doing work at my computer, at my desk, I'm
plugged into AirPods, and it works quite well,
honestly, for a lot of different situations, and
they're very comfortable, they're very consistent.
I'm going to double down on the Aura frame,
I also, I got one of these for my mom and my
mother-in-law, and they're so great for just
sharing photos of your kids with your family.
And people have, they've heard of digital picture
frames, but the Aura just does it really well,
and it's really easy to add photos,
and they're just really nice looking.
You can imagine not that long from now,
we'll have the Aura Frame except Studio
Ghiblifies every photo that you
have in it, and then it's... Yeah.
Or just imagines things you've done that are
really cool. Look at my sweet life. Yeah. Cool.
And it's Aura, it's A-U-R-A, I believe is how
you spell it. Folks who want to check it out,
we'll link to it. Not affiliated. Okay, two
more questions. Do you have a favorite life
motto that you often come back to
and find useful in work or in life?
Yeah, something I've thought about a lot is
a lot of the proverbs out there are actually
contradictions, right? It's like birds of a
feather, and then you also have opposites attract,
and you have all... And it's kind of funny,
because you feel that both of them are true,
and often they both are true, and a lot of it is
about understanding why. And one of those that
I feel like, especially in the world of startups
that I think about all the time is, I think it is
very important to be focused and driven, and to
really maximize your potential, and then at the
same time, it's also very important to not let
your own personal emotion get tied up in your
success or failure, and I think especially with
startups, because there's always ups and downs,
honestly, even in the most successful companies
ever, it's just like, it's a rocky road, there's
a lot that happens, and a lot that goes down.
And I think one of the things which I've thought
a lot about is that somehow you really want to
do your best, and put everything you can into it,
and do everything you can to... Basically, you
want to put it all out on the field. But at the
same time, you want to be okay with both wins
and losses, and you want to be able to move on,
and go into the next one each time.
And something, yeah, it's funny,
but what I've found personally is that obviously
it's really important for your own emotional
state and mental state to be able to do that, and
we've had lots of mistakes, and I've had a lot.
I had my first company, which obviously, which was
cool, but there are a lot of tricky spots there,
and then over the course of Cognition, it
feels like it's been already eight years
compressed into one year, and it's still going
at that pace. But somehow it also actually makes
you more successful, I think, too. It's like,
you are just more able to give it your best,
and to do the things that will lead to success if
you're not tying it up in your own personal worth.
That is so interesting, I just had a podcast
recording recently where with an executive coach,
Jerry Kelowna, that I think will come
out before this, might be after this,
that's one of his big pieces of
advice, and it's a very Buddhist
approach of just [inaudible 01:29:33]
and attaching to a certain outcome.
Yeah.
Okay. Final question, I'm curious if there's
a story here, but we could keep it short,
is there a story behind Devin as the name,
or is there another contender for
Devin being the [inaudible 01:29:48]?
Devin was the name from pretty early on, we were
interested, we were working on coding agents from
the beginning, and my co-founders are Steven
and Walden, for example, and we had this idea,
all right, let's get started, and let's try
to expand the box as much as we can. So,
have everyone think out of the box and do their
own thing, and let's have everyone do their own
thing first for a bit, and then we'll consolidate
and take everything that we've learned. And so,
Walden made a virtual developer version
of him, which was called DevWalden,
and then Steven made one of him, which is called
DevSteven, and we had all these... And then we
were kind of combining it all into one thing,
and we're like, okay, you know? It's Devin.
And that was the thing. And so Devin was, yeah,
Devin stuck for us quite early on, I would say.
One thing which we did have a big decision on
though actually is what the image of Devin would
be. And so, as folks know, there's the hexagons
and then people have seen this more recently,
but there's actually also an otter, a
little otter with a laptop in its lap,
and that is Devin as well. And we had this debate
over what to go with, and what not to go with and
stuff, and it's been a while now, but somehow
we still have both the hexagons and the otter.
You skipped over where the Devin, did
you have just have, it just came to you?
Oh, so Devin is, it's a dev. Yeah.
[inaudible 01:31:10].
And so, it was kind of like, when
we were consolidating all the names,
it just seemed clear then that this would be the
universal dev that we all liked to work with.
Wow.
Yeah.
Incredible. Scott, this was so much
fun. Oh my God, I learned a ton,
which is always a really good sign. Two
final questions, where can folks find
you/Devin/anything else you want to point them
to, and how can listeners be useful to you?
Awesome. Yeah, no, we're at App.devin.ai, and
you can find us as well on Twitter or a lot of
other social media. We'd obviously love to hear
any feedback you have about the Devin product,
there's so much to figure out,
and I think the, like I said,
I think we're all still 20 steps away from
really the future of software engineering,
and so it really means a lot to hear what folks
think about the product as they're trying it out.
And so, please let us know anytime if there's
things that we can do to make it better.
Scott, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you so much for having
me. I had a great time.
Me too. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening,
if you found this valuable, you can subscribe
to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app. Also, please
consider giving us a rating or leaving a review,
as that really helps other listeners
find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
LennysPodcast.com. See you in the next episode.