You built and led Facebook news feeds.
You shipped the Messenger app as its
own app. You launched ChatGPT Enterprise.
What's an important lesson you've learned
about what it takes to succeed building
something from idea to one to billions?
You have to plan your chess moves
out in advance. You have to really
think before you act and build systems that
were going to let you go sustainably faster.
What's the most counterintuitive
lesson you've learned?
Sometimes your product actually doesn't matter.
At Uber, I learned this because, really,
the price and the ETA at Uber was the product.
Looking at it from a holistic perspective,
we humans consume the entirety of the product.
It's not to say that you shouldn't fix the bug,
but it doesn't have as much of an impact as
something that is more important to people.
What's one specific thing you
think will change in a big way
with AI that people don't think enough about?
Education is going to change. My son, he was
nine at the time, built a custom GPT that you
can type in any topic and it would give you a
sentence that had every letter of the English
alphabet. Isn't that mind-blowing? I
can already see his brain rewiring.
What's one thing you look for in people you hire?
In 6 months, if I'm telling you what
to do, I've hired the wrong person.
It helps me and the person operate on a
different level where the goal is not,
did you hit this OKR? The Meta goal becomes,
are we calibrating enough? Are we actually
getting into a spot where in 6 months you're
the one telling me what needs to be done?
What's something you've learned about what
it takes to be a great product person?
I think there are five different types
of product managers. Number one is-
Today my guest is Peter Deng. Peter is maybe
the most under the radar impactful Product
Leader that you have never heard of. I often say
that the best product people are not the people
on Twitter and LinkedIn sharing advice, but the
people who don't have time to do that because
they're too busy doing the work. Peter is the
epitome of this. He was VP of product at OpenAI
where he oversaw product design and engineering
for ChatGPT and helped ship ChatGPT Enterprise,
voice, memory, desktop, custom GPTs and more. He
also oversaw and built their first growth team.
He was the first Head of Product at Instagram
where he worked closely with Mike and Kevin,
and oversaw all product development, including on
content sharing, ads, growth, even helped build
out their design and user research functions.
He was also a Head of the Rider product team at
Uber where he oversaw everything in the Rider
app, including big improvements to pickups and
drop-offs at Uber Pool and airports.
He also helped the team launch new
products including Uber Reserve, which is now
approaching a $5 billion a year business. He
also spent nearly 10 years at Facebook as their
4th ever Product Manager where he built and led
the team behind the current Newsfeed product,
the standalone Messenger app, also photos,
and groups, and homepage, and profiles. He was
also Chief Product Officer at Airtable where
he helped the company systemize how they built
products and transitioned to Enterprise. He also
led product management at Oculus. These days
he is General Partner at Felicis where he is
able to bring everything he's learned to more
founders as an investor. He has never done a
podcast before or shared any of these lessons or
stories publicly. So, you are in for a real treat.
A huge thank you to Eric Antonow, Nick Turley,
Lauren Motomati, Joanne Jain, and Sundeep Jain
for contributing questions and topics. This
conversation, if you enjoy this podcast, don't
forget to subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. Also, if you become
an annual subscriber of my newsletter, you get a
year free of a bunch of amazing products including
Bolt, Linear, Superhuman, Notion, Perplexity and
Granola. Check it out at lennysnewsletter.com
and click bundle. With that, I bring you Peter
Deng. Many of you are building AI products, which
is why I am very excited to chat with Brandon
Foo, founder and CEO of Paragon. Hey Brandon.
Hey Lenny. Thanks for having me.
So, integrations have become a big
deal for AI products. Why is that?
Integrations are mission-critical
for AI for two reasons: First,
AI products need contacts from their customer's
business data such as Google Drive files,
Slack messages or CRM records. Second, for AI
products to automate work on behalf of users,
AI agents need to be able to take action
across these different third-party tools.
So, where does Paragon fit into all this?
Well, these integrations are a pain to
build, and that's why Paragon provides
an embedded platform that enables engineers
to ship these product integrations in just
days instead of months across every use case
from RAG data ingestion to a Agentic actions.
And I know from firsthand experience
that maintenance is even harder than
just building it for the first time.
Exactly. And we believe product teams should focus
engineering efforts and competitive advantages,
not integrations. That's why companies like U.COM,
AI21 and hundreds of others use Paragon
to accelerate their integration strategy.
If you want to avoid wasting months of engineering
on integrations that your customers need,
check out Paragon at useparagon.com/lenny. This
episode is brought to you by Pragmatic Institute,
the trusted leader in product expertise. Pragmatic
Institute helps product professionals turn ideas
into impact through proven courses, workshops and
certifications designed for real-world success.
For over 30 years, they've trained more than
250,000 product leaders at companies like Google,
Microsoft and Salesforce. Equipping
them with practical strategies to
build and scale market-winning products.
Pragmatic's full-time instructors each bring
over 25 years of hands-on leadership experience,
teaching strategies proven to deliver real-world
results. And it's not just about what you learn,
it's also about who you learn it with. Completing
a course connects you to an active community of
over 40,000 product professionals. You'll engage
in meaningful conversations, collaborate with
peers and mentors, and gain direct instructor
access to refine your strategies and stay ahead
of trends. Get 20% off with Code LENNY20 at
pragmaticinstitute.com/lenny. Peter, thank you so
much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you. I'm so thrilled to be here,
really honored. Looking forward
to having a great time here.
As we were preparing for this conversation,
we were jamming on what we should focus on.
There's so much that we're going to talk about.
But something that you said was really interesting
and I'm really excited to start with this, which
is that, you've always felt that you haven't been
able to say all the things you really think and
feel because you've been within corporations,
PR people keeping you on message, and this is
the first time that you feel free to share.
First time.
Okay, so first of all, just how
does that feel? Second of all,
tell us something that you've been wanting
to share or that you can finally talk about.
Well, it feels really good. So, let me ask... I
love it that you're starting with a spicy question
here and let me share some more context
behind it. I'm here to speak more freely,
but it's not really what you think.
I'm not here to divulge any secrets
from the companies. But naturally I'm kind of
a storyteller, I'm kind of an introvert. So,
this podcast, I feel like I have the ability to
go deeper with you on any topic and kind of add
the context. Because I think without some of the
context, some of my spicy takes or whatnot might
be taken out of context, and just not having the
time pressure, not feeling like there's some PR
message I have to hit, is just really freeing.
So, it feels awesome, really anything that is on
your mind that you should find interesting to your
listeners, I'm here for it and yeah, I'm excited.
Something I always tell guests, and I don't want
people to take this out of context also, but I
always describe myself as a reverse journalist
where I want the guests to be the best version of
themselves. I never want to catch people off guard
or just say something they never meant to say. So-
That's great.
... it's a safe space. Okay. But still,
is there anything that you want to share
or that might be interesting to
share that you've been wanting to
share that you haven't been able to?
Is there anything along those lines?
I mean, I always get this question around sort of,
AGI, is it coming? Is it
going to solve everything?
What have you seen?
I mean, it's so interesting
because when I was at OpenAI,
it was around the time that people
were really scared of AI and, "Oh,
it's going to get rid of humans or it's going to
do all these things." But with every technology,
I think everyone's been just kind of taking some
time to acclimate to it. And I think with AGI it's
a similar thing, which is it's so far out that
everyone's like, "Well, what's our world going
to be like?" And the real answer is none of us
really know. But in terms of solving problems,
I think some people believe AGI is going to
solve everything, but I don't think so. AGI
is just necessary but not sufficient. A lot of
the value is still going to require a bunch of
hustle from a lot of builders to really turn
that new source of energy and channel it into
something that we humans want to use that solves
some of our problems. And that hustle is going to
be required, that elbow grease is going to be
required to really make AGI something useful.
Your point is that people think AGI
hits, all of a sudden all jobs are gone,
AGI is doing everything. Because I think
this is a optimistic message that things
will be okay if AGI, basically AGI being, and
I'm curious if you have a clear definition,
but AGI being, AI being just
basically as smart as humans-
Look, I won't-
... generally.
... claim to be an expert on this at all, but I
think that with every technology that's come out,
we've been able to harness it and it takes a
lot of harnessing. I think I'm going to use
that word very deliberately. I'll use something
really basic. What seems obvious today is that,
there was a time when databases were all the rage.
It's like, "Oh my goodness, you can store a bunch
of data and you can query it really quickly and
imagine all the possibilities." And I think that
a lot of amazing entrepreneurs and builders built
some really great products on top of databases.
That's right.
In fact, that's kind of the basis of all the
stuff that we're seeing today. And it seems
so obvious today, but I don't know, maybe in 10
years, 15 years when we look back, it's like,
"Of course it made sense that we have this super
intelligent thinking machine." But it requires
the product builders to be able to go
in there and say, "How do we channel
this energy to make it something that we
as humans love to use and want to use?"
I love the optimism around this. It's
just like things will not go crazy once
computers are as generally intelligent as humans.
I think that's exactly what I'm trying to say.
And I think that again, every technology people
have this fear. And I remember watching a
documentary once and they were talking about
how when the bicycle came out, people were
like, "Oh my goodness, this is going to be
the end of all things." And again, it sounds
silly today. Because you're like, "bicycles,
really?" But then if you put yourself in the
context and the mindset of a previous generation,
which the next generation will be looking back
at this podcast in that previous generation,
I think that again, I think optimistically,
things are going to be okay, we're going to
adapt. And this was actually one of the things
that I talked about with my friend Josh Constine
at South by Southwest, is this idea that humans
will always co-evolve with technology. And I
think that that co-evolution is already happening.
If you take a look at, there was a lot of a fear
of AI just when ChatGPT came out, but when
you start to get familiar with it things,
that kind of things change and then you
are able to evolve from being fearful to
familiar and to go all the way to having this
mastery of this thing of like, "Oh my goodness,
look at all the startups that are happening
now. All the things that we can build. And
just over 18 months." I would say we look
back and there's been an attitude shift.
And so I guess part of my optimism comes
from, if you look back 18 months and you
look forward 18 months, might it be the same
thing for something that we're chasing now?
Well, let me follow this AI thread a little bit
more and then we can move on to other things. I
feel like every conversation, there's a time
to AI conversation and then it's like, okay,
there's other things that also matter. So,
let me ask you this, the question, what's
one specific thing you think will change in a big
way with AI that people don't think enough about?
I think education is going to change in a
big way. And I think a lot about this because
I'm involved in my kid's school quite a
bit, and that's something I've done after
I left OpenAI. And what's fascinating to me
is that watching my son who got to dog food,
a bunch of the OpenAI stuff before it was public,
I think I can safely say that, that seems okay.
And when he was playing with ChatGPT and some of
the latest models and he was nine at the time,
I can already see his brain rewiring. He was
starting to ask questions and he never heard
the word prompt before, but he's like, just this
is how awesome the human mind is, because he was
exposed to this technology at an early age,
some things just are unlocked. And I think
that you're able to think differently. And I'll
give you a specific example of what I mean here.
He goes to Python class and he's coding. Now,
I don't actually think he's going to have to
code when he grows up. I think that's going to
be a solved problem. But it's a very valuable
skill because I think learning to program is
learning how to think in a structured way,
in a systematic way. And he was prompting
ChatGPT with some really crazy things that
I never even thought of. And one of the things
was, "Hey, ChatGPT, can you give me a sentence
that has every letter in the alphabet along the
theme of oceans or along the theme of space?"
And the reason this kind of blew my mind is
because in traditional programming you couldn't
write that program. You can't say in Python like,
"Oh, write a function that goes and formulate." I
mean, it's a really difficult function to write.
But for him to be able to think of that prompt,
which is really cool because he built a custom
GPT that you can type in any topic and it would
give you a sentence that had every letter of the
English alphabet, kind of like the quick brown fox
jumped over the lazy dog. Isn't that mind-blowing?
At age nine he could think about that,
whereas being at age nine, I was playing with
Legos and maybe QBasic. And so this idea of
how young human's brains will evolve because of
this new tool we have is going to change the way
I think we're going to do education. And I'll be
very honest, I'm not an expert in education, but I
just thought a lot about it. And one thing I think
is going to be really important in the future is
being able to figure out how to ask the right
questions. We humans are inherently inquisitive.
But being inquisitive and turning that into the
right questions to prompt or ask AI, which is
going to be again, something that everyone's
going to have access to is going to be a
differentiator for what kind of work can be done.
The analogy I'll draw is, when the calculator was
invented people didn't stop doing Math, they just
did higher level Math. And it frees the mind up
to do other things and think more at a higher
level of abstraction. And I think we got to
prepare our kids on thinking about, "Well, how do
you think at a higher level of abstraction?" And
this has happened before. I think Google has
made memory kind of obsolete. You don't have
to memorize facts anymore, you can just Google
it. And the next phase will be something around,
"Well code will just appear if you summon it."
So, what are the things that people will think
about and the skills we have to develop that are
at the next level of abstraction, that tap into
our creativity, that tap into our curiosity?
That's going to be really interesting. So,
I think education is going to change dramatically,
just like how progressive education in the past
switch from memorization of multiplication
tables into something that's a little bit more
kind of higher level, higher level thinking. And
I think that's going to be one of those big areas.
This makes me think about an NPR story I was just
listening to where they were following professors
using ChatGPT to create their curriculum. There
was a lot of talk of students using ChatGPT,
cheating, having ChatGPT write their essays. But
teachers are using ChatGPT in a big way. And then
students are raiding professors
badly because they noticed they're
using ChatGPT for their curriculum.
So, it's kind of this arms race.
But it's also interesting because
then that it goes further, it show
further though. The whole system
has to change. Because again,
I still believe that human brains are inherently
inquisitive and that we still need development
in some way. But how that's going to develop,
I'm fascinated to watch how that plays out.
I want to get back to product, but first
of all, I know something that you think
a lot about along these lines. This came
up in many conversations I had with folks
that you worked with. Is your emphasis
on the power and importance of language,
being really good at thinking about the words
you use both in writing and speaking. Just
talk about how you think about that, just the
importance and power of language as a leader.
I remember taking this class that really stuck
with me in college. It was called Language and
Thought. And it was taught by Herbert Clark. And
he had this thesis that kind of blew my mind,
which is that, "Language actually affects
the way you think." That's one of the parts
of the thesis. And once I heard that and read
that in his book and listened to the lecture,
I couldn't stop thinking about that because it
just rang so true. I grew up speaking Chinese
and I think that there's a lot of things of just
the Chinese language that I feel like I noticed,
I thought differently when I learned English.
And there were some studies around this too,
I think that there's, I think in, I'm
not sure exactly, I just have to go
check up on this. But I think in Russian
there are two different words for blue,
there's a greenish blue and
a bright blue or something.
I speak Russian but it's like... I moved
to the U.S. when I was 6 and so my Russian
is not great. So, I'm trying to think
of this as you say it, but keep going.
Well, so then this is great. So, I need to get a
way to validate this. But from what I remember,
because there were these two different words for
these different shades of blue Russian speakers
who then learned English had an easier time
distinguishing between these two shades of blue
than, and a faster time doing so than people
who had just grown up speaking English. So,
I read some studies over there. And also there's
some other languages that don't actually have a
word for blue, I think. And then that's actually
really hard for them to distinguish over time. So,
that really stuck with me and I think
that it's kind of rings true. So, when I,
how I put it in practice, is that when I make
slide decks, I gave a presentation to a class
a couple of weeks ago and there were probably
a total of 20 words on the entire slide deck.
And I spent hours obsessing over them because
I really wanted to make sure I captured the
right essence of what I was trying to say. And
I think that crafting is really important when
you're working in product, because if you're
sitting down and you're writing a vision doc
or you're writing a PRD, and if you don't pay
attention to the words you use, and you're not
intentional about it, those have downstream
effects. People might misinterpret things,
the connotations may not actually come through.
And so I really am very careful about it because
I think that there's a multiplicative
effect and a downstream effect for using
the wrong word. And I really believe in
that kind of language affecting thought
thesis which is why I've just really,
really paid attention to that.
Mm-hmm. Yeah. And I feel like
AI can help you with that too.
Yes. Exactly.
We had an episode-
Well, actually, speaking of AI, actually
that's a really interesting point.
I think it's really interesting and kind of
poetic and fitting that the breakthrough in
artificial intelligence came from large language
models. It's interesting to me because there is,
with every word in every sentence so much of the
knowledge is encapsulated and shaped. And when
ChatGPT does something really interesting,
I tell people it's oftentimes just writing
Python code and interpreting it. And
Python is a language yet again. So,
I think that there's something really interesting
where like the condensation of human thought in
language is related to the LLMs and the
advancement scenario that we have today.
I think it was Ilya on a Dwarkesh's
podcast where he was talking about,
you may think LLMs are just like, "Oh, just
predicting the next word, what's the big deal?"
But in order to do that, it has to understand
the universe and everything in the world that
has ever happened and existed and everything
anyone's ever written to predict the next word.
Yeah, love it.
Yeah. Okay. So, let me zoom out a little bit and
shift a little bit to just product in general.
Sure.
You've worked at and built some of those iconic
products in history. You worked at OpenAI,
Facebook, Uber a Head of Product at Instagram. So,
let me just ask you this question and see where
this goes. What's the most counterintuitive
lesson you've learned about building products or
leading teams that goes against common wisdom?
I think one thing that, it's a really hard lesson
that I learned at Uber, which is sometimes your
product actually doesn't matter. And by product
I mean the pixels you put on the screen or things
that you build in your mobile app. And at Uber,
I learned this because, it pains me to say this,
but really the price and the ETA at Uber was
the product. And I think a lot of times people
at tech companies think of the product as just
this digital manifestation, but looking at it
from a holistic perspective, we humans consume the
entirety of the product. And I think that was one
of the things that I learned, the lessons that
I learned that was really kind of hard hitting,
that sometimes the pixels don't matter as much as
you think. And you fix a certain bug, it's not to
say that you shouldn't fix the bug, but it doesn't
have as much of an impact as something that is
more important to people like a price or ETA.
And this happens a lot in B2B products where it's
not just about how... It's great that your product
is well-loved by its end users, but does it make
good business sense? Is one of those hard lessons
I learned as a very bright-eyed, bushy tailed sort
of design-based product manager going into Uber.
I think the other insight that I had or other
thought I had the other day was just the idea that
so many of the tech companies today, this is kind
of counterintuitive, so many of the tech companies
that are most valuable today didn't really start
with any technological breakthrough. They were
built on some kind of technological breakthrough
and they ended up building a lot more technology.
But really a lot of these companies, like Facebook
for example, just put in the hard work, the elbow
grease, especially in the early stages, to take
essentially a database of human connections
and build something valuable on top of it.
And that keep on polishing and iterating
that product and coming up with new ones
like newsfeed and photo tagging just kind of came
out of just really paying attention to what people
wanted. And some of the ideas are super simple and
it's not something that came out of the lab. So,
Uber for example, took the fact that everyone
had these GPS devices in their pockets, and they
didn't invent the GPS device, but they were able
to take that and the fact that people had cars,
and people wanted to get around, and there
was a human need, and they just connected
the dots, and put everything together.
And eventually, built a ton of tech to
predict the right marketplace and pricing et
cetera. But largely that's a very valuable
tech company. But it's largely an operations
company. And I want to give a huge shout-out
to my colleagues there who run Uber Eats and Uber
Rides from operations perspective. Because truly
that was one of the biggest business model hacks
that I've seen. And so I think that it's Silicon
Valley it gets lost a lot. It's like, "Oh, this
is a new tech company." Oftentimes some of the
most valuable ones are just the ones that are just
building what people need on top of existing tech.
There's so much to say here. I love it.
And this is coming from someone that led
the Uber Rider product team and worked at
Facebook and a Head of Product at Instagram.
It means a lot coming from someone like you,
not someone that's not in product especially.
Yeah, I mean, just to go further on the Instagram
part, the idea was super simple. It was showing
photos and visual sharing. But the craft that
Mike and Kevin had in putting in the hard work
to get the product just right, that's what made
it really take off. That's a great example. I
had forgotten about Instagram, but how could I?
But it wasn't anything that any other company
couldn't have done, but it was that product
taste that Kevin and Mike had and conviction that
there's a certain sort of vibe, if you will, that
people wanted, and building that and iterating,
and look at it now, it's a core part of our
lives. Visual sharing, they really solved it.
Yeah, I just had Mike Krieger on the podcast.
So, it's interesting, there's two tensions here.
One is just the product doesn't matter in a lot
of really successful companies. It's secondary
to the cars, the drivers, the GPS and the phone.
And then on the other hand, there doesn't need
to be a technological breakthrough to build
a huge business. It's almost like if there's
no technological breakthrough, then the product
matters. Facebook is an example. Basically, it's
like a database of connections, but what allowed
an Instagram, what allowed them to breakthrough,
and there's classically competitors at the time.
Was the experience, was it a lot better? And then
maybe on the flip side, if the experience
doesn't matter, then it's the breakthrough
is on the operations and other... Does that
resonate? Is that kind of what you're saying?
It does resonate. I think both have to
be true. But also I would say that even
if you did found a company that has a huge
technological breakthrough. Very shortly,
I think that the product experience will
start mattering, because how long does that
technological advantage last before humans
wisen up to be like, "Well, this is not the
product I want to use. I use it a little bit
differently and this is more ergonomic for me?"
Et cetera. So, I think that what you said
is a beautiful summary. I also think that a
point in time in a company's history will also
determine what is going to be more important.
This is, especially, interesting for companies
building on top of LLMs and AI infrastructure,
where you're essentially saying,
you don't need to have some kind of
technological breakthrough to build something
valuable if you can create a really special,
unique experience that unlocks the
potential of this super intelligence.
I think that's right. And I have some more
thoughts on just sort of the companies that
are building on top of LLMs that are just...
That's a slightly different thing I would say.
I think that for them, having the right data,
and that right data flywheel's is so important.
Like proprietary data especially.
Exactly. And the flywheel part is just,
you can start with proprietary data,
but the flywheel is really just sort of how
do you continue to maintain that and generate
that. And the second thing is, again, it's the
workflow. So, it's the ergonomics of how does
it actually integrate into people's lives? And
that is going to be more and more important.
Well, let's actually spend more time there
because a lot of people are thinking about
this. It feels like everybody's
trying to start a company these
days with AI enabling so much more. And so
I think a lot of people are just curious,
where should they spend time? And so I think
this is actually really interesting. So,
what I'm hearing here is two things to think about
to create any kind of moat, defensibility against,
say, foundational models coming to your lunch
or in other companies. What sort of data can you
acquire that is proprietary and create a
flywheel to generate more of that data? And then
the other piece is how do you fit into a very
specific, basically, vertical that you understand
really well that fits into their existing
workflow? Is that...? I'm probably right.
Yeah. Well, it's, again, this is something
we can unpack for a long time. Because
with any product that you want
to build, there's going to be
incumbents that have distribution advantages.
But I do have this thesis that there are certain-
... have distribution advantages, but I do have
this thesis that there are certain products that
will be able to break through those advantages
of the distribution of the other companies,
but you have to overcome a pretty
high bar of your product has to be
so much better. I think that's one thing.
But yeah, I think that data flywheel thing
is really interesting because the models will
get really good at whatever data you show it,
and that's one of the things that people just
think that AI is such a magic wand. But no,
it's like if it's been trained on the right
data, it's going to do the thing that it's
been trained on. It's very malleable.
Being very mindful of the data that you
have access to to start your flywheel going
and what you can do to keep on going with
that flywheel is going to be a critical thing
for anyone who's starting a company today.
Let's make that even more specific. When you talk
about this, I think about... The CEO of Windsurf
was on the podcast and we talked a lot about
how they've all this really unique data about
which recommendations of code snippets people
accept and reject and they actually launched
their model I think based on that. Is that
example? Any other examples to make this real?
That's a perfect example.
There's some companies I've invested
in that aren't public yet that have their own take
on that, which is really interesting to be able to
take whatever activity is in their product to
get smarter at the thing that they are doing,
again, which is why I think the data flywheel
and the workflow goes so hand in hand together,
because if you are solving something
actually valuable for businesses, for people,
and there's a lot of that attention that's being
paid to, a lot of work is being done through it,
you're going to have that edge.
This is where I see again startups in
very different markets who have this insight,
who understand this very deeply, and are not
just trying to zero shot everything and be like,
"No, no, no. This is how we're going to build it
to make the product genuinely useful so that
it can get genuinely more useful over time."
That is going to be amazing because as a consumer
of any of these products, we're going to benefit.
What I'm hearing here is also if you don't
have proprietary data or unique data, you
can still have a chance by building this flywheel
where you collect that data through your usage.
For example, Windsurf, if they all
built on Claude 3.5 and then now
they have all this unique data and
now they're launching their models.
That's exactly right.
This goes back to something
I might've mentioned briefly, but you
got to have grit when you're building
anything. You got to be able to have
that vision, have that clear direction,
and be able to really go chase that.
I think that's really important.
To make your example of distribution being
overcomable, a great example I think a lot about,
and we had CPO, turns out there's many CPOs
at Microsoft, I didn't realize how many CPOs
they had, and I asked her about, "Why didn't
Copilot..." The fastest growing companies in
the world, Cursor, Windsurf, Lovable, Bolt,
all these guys. Copilot was so ahead of these
companies and these companies broke through.
While Microsoft has distribution, amazing talent,
infrastructure, all the things, early first mover
advantage and it's to your point, they were just
building products that were much better,
Cursor, Windsurf, all these, Lovable, Bolt.
I do believe there is a level of product
craft that will make it so that it's just
worth it to switch or try something else.
There are a few products out there that I
see with this. I think Granola is one of them.
There's so many distribution advantages that
Google Meet has, that Google, Facebook
started off, Microsoft Teams has,
Zoom has, but they're just these tiny little
product craft delightful things that I really
appreciate myself of like, "Yeah, they got it."
They have these little edges, set it down just
right, and they've really figured out a way to
really make it so delightful that it's like,
"Yeah, I will install this piece of software.
Yes, 100% I will talk to my friends about
this because it is so life-changing."
We're starting to see that now. Again,
before, I would say 18 months ago, it's like,
"Oh, well, who has the best model?" But then
coming forward, it's like really who has the
best workflow and who has the best product,
and we humans are just demanding. We want the
best. And so when someone is going to come out
and produce something that's so well-crafted,
I think people are going to pay attention.
A couple of takeaways here is if
you're trying to build an AI startup,
a few things you should be thinking about that
gives you a better chance of breaking through
and winning is what are your data flywheels
where you collect proprietary unique data,
how do you build something the craft
comes through and people are wowed and
want to tell their friends about it.
Granola is a great example. Clearly,
Cursor, Lovable, Bolt, Rep, all these guys did
that and then it feels like they just understand
a vertical workflow really well and someone's
problem and solve that in a really unique way.
Yeah. I couldn't have put it better myself.
Awesome.
Let me ask you,
this came up in my chat with Mike at
Anthropic and it's along these lines.
I was thinking about just what
is product doing at Anthropic.
They're building this basically a gigabrain
super intelligence thing that's going to know
everything and maybe build its own experience in
the future. And then there's this product team
building this layer on top to interact
with this super intelligence gigabrain.
What is the point? What is
the value of that layer?
You spoke to it a bit here of just there's value
in the experience and feeling native, but I guess
let me just ask you that. Just where do you think
product goes at a company like Anthropic, OpenAI
where there's just the super intelligence that
the team is working on and there's this UX on top?
I think those companies have just such an
advantage because you get to work in the
same building as the researchers. I think that
there's that really symbiotic relationship,
close partnership between post training and
product where, again, more and more it's going
to be less about the raw intelligence, it's
going to be about the fine tuning of what the
model can do that really resonates with people
and what people want and also what the product
trajectory is going to be. I think that
you're going to see that more and more.
I think this is less about Anthropic but more
about OpenAI. I think OpenAI made a great move.
I am a huge Fidji fan. As soon as that news leaked
that she was going to join, I texted her. I was
like, "This is great. Amazing. Congratulations."
I'm thrilled for her, for the company, for all of
my friends still at OpenAI because it's just
going to be this amazing leader coming in.
I'm also thrilled as a consumer because
some great products are going to come out.
I think really that close, tight-knit
relationship at any of these large model
companies between post training and product is
going to produce some really incredible stuff.
First of all, Mike actually said
very similar things that the more-
I promise you I did not watch that podcast.
It hasn't even come out yet so I believe you.
Yeah. He had this interesting finding where
he put product people on UX product experience
front-facing product and then he put PMs on the
research teams and building models, helping models
get better, helping researchers build things,
and he found that all the leverage and wins
came from the PMs working with the researchers,
much less so on the product experience. And
so he puts more and more PMs with that team.
I'm so thrilled to hear that because that's
a little bit... It's very validating because
that's what we did at OpenAI too. We were very
closely tied to the post training team and it was
because of that tight collaboration that you see
some of the advances of ChatGPT getting better at
so many things. It's great. It's awesome that
we independently came to the same conclusion.
Yes. It's a good sign.
Okay, so we're talking
about startups, building new companies. I
want to follow this thread a little bit.
Sure.
I feel like you've built more products from zero
to one to scale than maybe most anyone else across
all the companies that you've worked at. I'm going
to do a quick rundown of some of the things you've
done and I'm going to miss a bunch but let's see.
You built and led the Facebook Newsfeed,
the current version of it. You built the
new groups experience chat and messages.
You shipped the Messenger app as its
own app. That was one of your projects.
You led UberPool low-cost rides. You launched
ChatGPT Enterprise. You shipped voice and vision,
memory, custom GPTs, just refreshing the
whole design of ChatGPT. Many more things.
A lot of work at Airtable obviously. Also, Oculus.
These are just some examples in the intro. I'm
going to try to go through all these things.
All that to say, I feel like you've seen a lot
of what works and doesn't work, building
from idea from zero essentially to one to
scale. So let me just ask you this question,
what's an important lesson you've learned
about what it takes to succeed building
something from idea to one to billions?
Yeah. Thank you. That was a good trip down
memory lane too when you read that off.
I think the first thing I would say, going from
zero to one is different going from one to 100.
When you are in the one to 100 phase, which
is a lot of the time that I spent is the one
to 100 phase, we quadruple Instagram usage in two
years, that was very much a fun ride and there's
a bunch of other examples at other companies.
But when you go to one to 100, I think one of
the things that you really got to take into
account is that you have to plan your chess
moves out in advance. You have to really think
before you act and build systems that are going
to let you go sustainably faster, because
the zero to one is you're trying to find
that product market fit and then when you get
to one to 100, you're trying to make sure you
can get to hyperscale as fast as you can.
I've been very fortunate to be along the
ride of many of these products as they were going
through that hyperscale. And the analogy I always
like to use is that when you do that, you feel the
G-forces. Some people are like, "Oh, yeah, I'm a
pilot, I can fly at 35,000 feet." But feeling the
G-forces of takeoff of a rocket is very different.
One thing that I've learned there doing that
a few times is you got to build the systems
that help you move sustainably faster, and
sometimes, you have to go slow to go fast.
Here's an example.
In building the Newsfeed, the current version
that we have today, it really hasn't changed much
from the time that we built it, I don't even know,
it was like 12 years ago or something, I don't
know the reason why it hasn't changed much.
But I like to think that it's because we
put a lot of time and craft into thinking
about the whole sharing loop and what are the
key pieces of it and how is it architected,
what's the information architecture, and what
does that whole flow look like, how does it go
from posting something at the top of the page to
showing up in the newsfeed to someone clicking
like and then that notifications thing lighting up
red and then that repeating over and over again.
I like to think that Newsfeed has stood the
test of time, the current version of it,
because we thought very carefully about
how people wanted to interact and how
people wanted to consume information and
also, that whole loop. When that happens,
then I think things are built to last. I think
this is a case at a lot of different companies.
When I was at Uber, we had a bit of a spaghetti
string code situation on the writer app,
but taking a step back and re-architecting
things of what are the core components
and how do you actually make it so that the
product selector can scale around the world.
Here's a little known fact. Talk
about grit and elbow grease.
Uber's not just as simple as finding a ride.
If you've ever been to another country,
like in India, sometimes, there are
no street signs, so you have to pick
up in front of this mini mart or whatever it
might be. There's a whole team that worked on
pickup and drop-offs. This was a large effort.
It sounds so boring but it was so critical to
Uber being able to scale because pickup
and drop-offs team thought about, "Well,
how do you do it for venues?" That venues and
finding that right abstraction means that you
can have a scalable way to do pickups at
airports and configure different venues.
Those systems when you take the time to
build them in the one to 100 phase help
you speed up massively and that's
how you get 4x users in two years.
Or on Messenger, we put a lot of thought into
the infrastructure around push notifications,
etc. We grew that product from zero to 4.7
billion messages sent per day in about two
and a half years. I think it really requires
that forethought in building the right systems.
Let me follow that thread real quickly
because that's really interesting.
Essentially, what you're saying is there's
a phase of once you find product market fit,
and I want to actually ask you
this before you start planning,
when you're starting to scale going from one
to a hundred, your advice here is basically
don't move fast and break things. Don't ship
MVPs. This is the time to really think many
chess moves ahead about what you're going to
need to get this to, say, a billion users.
Yeah, yeah. It's building the systems and
then that systems thinking will carry you
really far, or at least that's
been my experience and hopefully,
you can find the same way but your biology
may vary. But yeah, that's exactly right.
What's your guidance on just when to
do that? Because you build something,
okay, well it's working, there's also this
just like, "Okay, let's just keep it going,
let's scale it as far as we can." In
your experience, is it... Just what's
the guidance on when to really step back
and really think years and years ahead?
Great question.
The first thing I'll say is that it's
not a binary switch. It's actually a ramp rate.
When I've led teams, I've always believed strongly
in this portfolio approach. Famously, Google had
the 70-20-10 portfolio approach. That may be the
right thing for a more mature company, maybe
it's 50/50 if you're a startup, but you have
to think about this in a non-binary way and in
a way, that's about scaling up and when do you
need to put more resources behind that.
Every startup is going to be different.
Every product that you're launching is
going to be different. And then thinking
about your portfolio approach and how much you
allocate your time that would be my advice. It's
really dependent on the stage that you're in.
I think that actually is a nice dovetail to my
second thing, if I may, which is when you're going
from that stage of maybe one to five or one to 10,
so not just fully one to 100, one thing I found
to be very helpful is to measure everything.
This sounds, again, very simple but just like how
you wouldn't fly a plane without instruments, why
would you run your products without understanding
the instrumentation and how it's doing.
One of the things I did in pretty much all the
teams that I led, whether it was Instagram, Uber,
Airtable, was all about... ChatGPT too.
One of the first things I did was
always to build a growth team.
Building a growth team is really
interesting because it actually is a simple razor,
it's a simple thing to think about. It's like,
"I'm going to build a growth team," but then
you're going to uncover a lot of things.
You're going to uncover how much stuff you
have not yet logged and how non-rigorous
you've been looking at your entire product.
It's so funny because I've seen this movie so many
times, the same movie so many times that every one
of these companies where I remember walking into
Instagram and I think asking Kevin and Mike,
"So how many users do we have?" It's like,
"Well, we don't really know." And so it's like,
"Well, there are a lot and we don't really know."
When you build a growth team and you hire the
right growth leader, I've had the pleasure
of working with George Lee at Instagram, some of
the early growth folks at Facebook, Andrew Chen
at Uber, Airtable. I had the privilege of working
with Lauryn, who is currently now leading growth
at Notion. I've been very fortunate to work
with some really amazing people on my team.
When you hire the right person, they start asking
all the right questions because when the archetype
of person who is a growth PM will be like,
"Well, wait. Why is this happening? And let's
get the data on X, Y and Z thing." That's when you
realize you don't have X, Y, and Z thing logged
and after you have X, Y, and Z thing logged,
you look at the data, you're like, "Wait. Well,
why is that happening?" And then you're forcing
yourself to go deeper into the analysis of doing
some analysis of like, "Well, what's correlated
with what and what are some hypotheses?"
Because growth leaders, growth product leaders
are so into this experimentation side, it actually
is this really easy thing to do is when you start
building a growth team, it just begets all of the
right questions being asked and then it starts
turning into all the right behaviors of taking
something you've been building, which seems
like it's working into a more rigorous system.
That's zero, sorry, the one to 10 phase I would
say that really sets you up for the 10 to 100.
What I like about this growth team advice is that
a lot of people think of a time to hire a growth
team to we need to drive growth. What you're
saying is there's a lot of second order benefits,
which is they help you figure out what
the hell's going on and inform a lot of
other things that are happening, people just
actually understanding how things are going.
Totally.
I think that the reason why growth team is the
advice I would go with rather than to build
an analytics team is because if you build
an analytics team or a data science team,
it's possible that no one's going to listen to
them. It's like, "Oh, I have these insights."
It's like, "Well, no one really cares."
But if you hire a growth leader,
they are now tied to outcomes of driving growth,
so they're going to be the ones who are listening
and asking more questions and really partnering
with that data science team to make your entire
product and business more rigorous. That
just changes the DNA of your entire team.
I want to talk about hiring, but is
there anything else along these lines
that you want to share of building
new products, scaling products?
I guess the last thing I would say
is I want to make sure that sometimes
in the pursuit of numbers, product folks lose
sight of the importance of taste and craft.
Maybe this is actually the dovetail into building
teams, but you got to have the counterbalances.
It's really important to give two people on
your team different charges. One is like go
grow the product and the other one is wait,
maintain that design, that beautiful aesthetic,
the craft that your product is known
for. That tension is extremely healthy.
I've seen this at Facebook. I've seen this in
Instagram. I helped create this at Instagram,
this healthy tension. Airtable, same thing,
but just having... ChatGPT, same exact thing.
You have to have that push and pull on
both sides to really stretch the gamut.
That begs the question, how do you
actually do that? You could talk about it,
you could be like, "Okay, we need to
make sure the experience is awesome
but also grow this number. Here's your
goal." How do you operationalize that?
Is it a performance review? Attribute
thing? Is it culture or something else?
As a leader, you have to set up your
team the right way. You have to really
think about your team as a product and what are
the various pieces you need to really stretch
the gamut of what you're thinking about.
The teams that I've helped build are...
The most successful ones are a team of
Avengers that are just very different,
have very different superpowers, but together
you as the leader are the one who's helping
adjudicate any differences or any disagreements
but you know you're getting the best outcome
when everyone's pulling and obsessing over
a different thing. And that's important.
It's important to create your balance and
really increase the space that you're looking
at and create those healthy debates.
I think a lot of people overlook that.
I think some people think of people
on a team as warm bodies to do a job,
but my philosophy has always been to think
about, "Well, what does the company need
to be successful and who's the best person who
spikes at that one thing and how do I make sure
that we get that person and how do we make sure
we get the other person and the other person?"
It's almost like you're playing an RPG
where everyone has different sliders
and you have to create this super team where
everyone actually spikes in different ways.
That is something that I've had a lot of
success with in terms of when you create
that environment and you create that vibe, you're
going to get a lot of mileage out of that team.
That is a really interesting answer. It's not
one I've heard before. Essentially, it's not
create the right incentives, it's hire people
that naturally see the world in a certain way
and that creates a balance and a healthy tension
between say a PM and a designer and an engineer.
That is really interesting because that
feels a lot more sustainable than like,
"Here's your goal. But also when your goal is
make sure the experience is great and people
support tickets are down." It's just like
naturally, they need to want this to happen.
Totally.
Actually, I have a framework
around... I think there are five different
types of product managers that has held true.
This is a framework that just came out of a
random jam at Uber when I was talking to some
of my colleagues there. We formulated this
in terms of helping with hiring practices.
Everywhere I've gone, I've also been best
friends with the recruiters because honestly
my whole thing is got to build the right team.
So we have to really partner very deeply.
At Uber, we developed these five
archetypes of a PM. To this day,
I still think it's actually exactly true
and it still holds true to this day,
but is that interesting?
You want me to go into that?
Absolutely. I'm so excited to hear what these are.
These are the five that I've found to be most
enduring and actually the most different.
When you talk about... I love
the way you put this, Lenny,
which is when you hire the right people and
they're naturally motivated by different
things. These are the five that we came up.
Number one is the consumer PM. This is the
person that's half designer, half product
person, really obsessed over the details.
"Is it delightful? Is it crafted enough?
Oh my goodness, this is three pixels off.
I can't stand it. This is driving me nuts. Why
is this so complex?" These are the people that
you think of as sometimes the criticism PM
is the consumer PM, but that's just one type.
Another type, just on the other side we've talked
about before, is the growth PM. These people are
half data scientist, half product person, they are
wired to think numbers first and they have this
air about them that's like the best ones do, which
is like, "I'm really skeptical. Show me the data.
Let's run a test and prove it. I don't believe
you." I start with these two in the framework
because they're actually really different.
One, it's like, "I have vibe, I feel the vibe,
this is better," and the other one's like, "No. I
don't believe you. We should test this and prove
it." That's a really healthy tension.
I love having two people in a room
debating that. I'm like, "Great. We are
going to get some good things done and
we're going to move the product forward."
The third type is what I call the GM PM or
the business PM. These are half MBA, half product
person. These are folks that are naturally wired
to start with the business model and think
about, "What are the margins? What are the
opportunities? Where's the value being created?"
We had a lot of these at Uber and they were the
marketplace PMs and they're just like...
I loved working with them because their
minds just worked differently. They just
thought about problems from like, "Well,
what is the incentive here?" This is a
fascinating type of mind to work with.
Another one I found, it's actually
more nuanced than you think,
is there's a certain archetype that I call the
platform PM, which is someone who's really deeply
wired to build tools for other people.
At Uber, we had internal platforms for
messaging or for building internal tools.
Oftentimes, these folks are overlooked but
it's actually a really deep wiring, because
these are the people that are going to build
the systems that are going to make you go
faster. And that's what they love doing.
The last one, I would say, I used to call it
an algorithms PM, but now in the world of AI,
I'm going to rename this to research PM.
These are half researcher, half engineer,
half product person. These minds are amazing.
Basically, they think traditional Google search
algorithm PM but nowadays, it's like who are the
people who really have that product taste but
deeply understand the tech and the way the models
are trained to go and affect that and build the
most amazing product.
Those are the five.
I still think to this day these hold true,
and we might have been onto something the
day that we brainstormed this at Uber but,
yeah, I'm curious to hear your feedback.
This is great. As you're talking, I'm just like,
"Here's that person, here's that person. Okay,
they fit here." This super resonates.
This episode is brought to you by
Contentsquare, the analytics platform that helps
companies build better digital experiences.
Ever wonder why customers drop
off before converting or why
some pages perform better than others?
Contentsquare takes the guesswork out of
digital experiences, giving you real-time insights
into how users interact with your site or app.
With AI-powered analytics, automatic frustration
detection, and clear visualizations, you'll know
exactly what's working and what's holding your
customers back. Whether you're optimizing an
e-commerce checkout, refining a B2B lead flow, or
improving a mobile app experience, Contentsquare
pinpoints exactly what needs fixing and why.
Contentsquare powers better customer journeys
across 1.3 million websites and
apps. Discover the insights you've
been missing at contentsquare.com/lenny.
Just to summarize, there's consumer PMs,
growth PMs, business/GM PMs,
platform PMs and research PMs.
Yes.
A lot of people call them AI
PMs now. I feel like that's
the term that's really [inaudible 00:55:51] now.
You have to evolve with the times. Yeah.
But also the other part of the framework I find
interesting is that everyone has
a primary one and a secondary one.
It's like one of those personality tests.
Maybe we did this just because it was hard
to pigeonhole people and I myself don't think
I was pigeonholable, but I do think that people
lead with one type of thinking and then also have
the secondary thing that keeps them in balance.
If you believe that and you apply it to your team,
I'm curious to hear from your listeners
if this does resonate or not. Maybe this
framework will help you realize that you're
missing someone that you should be not missing.
What was your archetype when you were a PM?
That's the other thing with personality
types is the ones you hear. You're like,
"This is me. I own this."
There's no doubt about it.
I am a consumer PM and also a growth PM.
That's my primarily consumer... I can't...
This is what I told you about the other
products I've loved. I can see the details
that people put into it and I so appreciate
that. But at the end of the day, it's like,
"We got to measure things." That's what
I am. But again, everyone's different.
I love your point about how a lot of people think
of PM. They hear that first example and like,
"Oh, I guess that's what I need to be, because
that's what everyone talks about when they're
amazing product managers." But you're saying
there's many other ways to be a successful PM.
We did a personality test at Airbnb when I
was there, and one of the biggest takeaways
was it's like this color test and
you get a color green or yellow,
red, and the team was all over the spectrum.
It was a really good reminder just you can
be a different type of person and still
be really successful in this role of PM.
It's probably because of these different
archetypes and different needs and roles of
PMs. There's this word product manager
but there's many things that PMs do.
Also, as an investor now, it's really important to
see the fit of the founder to the market because
if you put a consumer PM into a really boring
regulated industry, they're probably going to
get frustrated and they're probably not going
to see it through. Whereas there's people
that you look at the pitch and you're like,
"Wow. You are really passionate about this-"
... pitch and you're like, "Wow, you are
really passionate about this problem,
and you really care about building tools
for others, and this is exactly," this
is the Twilio PM or whatever it might be.
"You're a perfect fit for this business and
that's awesome," right? So I think, yeah,
I love what you just said in the summary,
because I think there's no one way
to be a PM, and I think this is,
hopefully this framework will give people a little
bit more space to express who they really are.
I'm curious if other functions also have these
sort of archetypes, like designers and engineers,
but we don't need to get into that. How about
if you're listening to this on YouTube, leave
a comment of which of these archetypes you think
you might be. What's your primary and secondary?
I'll read them again. Consumer PM, growth PM,
business/GM PM, platform PM, research/AI PM?
Love it.
Okay. I want to talk about hiring.
So this actually came up a lot when
I was chatting with folks that you've
worked with, especially Nick Turley,
who's head of product at ChatGPT, who we're
trying to get on the podcast. Because-
Yes.
... that's an-
He's awesome.
That's what I've heard. So he told me that the
current head of engineering, the lead product
engineer, the head of design and head of marketing
at ChatGPT are people that you hired. Also,
many of the people you hired have gone on to do
incredible things. You've shared a few of those
names, many of them have been on the podcast,
which is the ultimate measure of success. So let
me just ask you this, what's one thing you look
for in people you hire that you think people sleep
on, that you think people aren't paying enough
attention to, that helps you find amazing stars?
That's really flattering to hear that from Nick.
Nick is one of the best people I've worked with,
period. In fact, I want to just do a quick
shout out. Folks at OpenAI are pretty much
the best people I've ever worked with in my
career. When I took the job, I told the team,
"This is going to be my last operating role,
and I'm going to leave it all on the field,
and I'm just going to go all out.: And basically
I spent probably as much time, if not more time on
recruiting and building the team as I did thinking
about the product. And this is going back to what
I said earlier about, I think you got to bring the
right people together to have a huge impact. And
oftentimes leaders overlook this and they're
like, "Ah, it's just a warm body," but truly,
people who have strengths in certain areas
compliment others with strengths in other areas.
And when you build that team, amazing things
happen. It's the best investment you can
make. It's going to pay off so many dividends.
So I think that's my opening salvo in terms of
you got to get ... Everyone who's listening out
there, you got to make sure you look at everyone
in your team, you look at what you need, and
you have to get the best in each. And truly,
in my farewell dinner at OpenAI, I think I
closed with just, "Look, I don't even know
what I would do after this, because all the best
people I've worked with are here." We have Ian
Silber running design there, Thomas Dimson, Joey
Flynn, Ryan O'Rourke. Nick Turley was an amazing I
met there. Joanne, I mean I have so many people
I'm missing, but Coley on product marketing,
Antonow on the marketing comms side, [inaudible
01:01:07], the list goes on. Product operations
is stellar. I'm so proud of, honestly, the team
that I built there more than the products. So I
just wanted to say that it's a big thing that I
really care about, and I hope more leaders think
about that too, is really be mindful of putting
your team together, and thinking about that as a
product. And you have to really craft that.
You have to really care about the team. So-
Just to double down on that point, actually,
before you get to the next tip here,
I just love this answer, which is, if I were to
ask someone, "What's your hiring vice? What do
you look for that people may not be looking for
enough?" Most of it would be like in that person,
here's what you need to focus on, and
here's the interview question. But
kind of your broad answer so far is
it's not actually about the person,
so much as what is the team going to look
like, and where do we need spikes? Where do
we need to balance out the composition
of this Avengers that we're building?
Totally, totally. That's exactly right. And
so that being said, I guess I have, I guess,
on brand, I have two things I want to share
about hiring the right team. I have this saying,
I actually have this doc that I've taken
around various companies called the PXD API,
which is like, "Here's how to work with me." And
in it, there's a saying that I have, which is what
I really optimize for for everyone that I support
and everyone I hire, which is in six months,
if I'm telling you what to do, I've hired the
wrong person. And it's just kind of served me
really well on three different levels. Number one,
it's a reminder for myself when I'm either hiring,
or looking for the person, is to keep my bar
super high and just not settle. Because if I do,
most likely in six months, it would not be true
that I would be able to let this person run,
and I would still be telling them what to do,
which is not what I want. That is not my desire.
The second sort of effect of that is that it's
... I say that to people when they come on the
team or as we're making the hire, because
it communicates to them that that's my bar,
and that's how they know they'll be successful,
and something to kind of work towards.
And the third thing is kind of a joint thing
for both of us, which is it kind of gives us,
it helps me and the person operate on a different
level, where the goal is not did you hit this OKR,
did you hit this goal? The meta goal becomes,
hey, are we calibrating enough? Are we actually
getting to a spot where in six months,
you're the one telling me what needs to
be done? Are we getting there, right?
Because then, if that's the framing,
every mistake that is made or whatever on either
of our parts becomes a learning opportunity in
terms of like, well, how do we grow from this
to where we want to be in six months? And how
is it possible that I, as a manager, can do the
right things to set this person up for success,
so that I don't have to be involved in six months?
And I think that those three things, and being
able to have that second-order effect of this
simple razor, in six months, if I'm telling you
what to do, I've hired the wrong person, it puts
pressure on me, it puts pressure on the person,
and it creates this really interesting environment
and this kind of safe space to really think about,
are we heading towards that goal?
And again, every place I've been at,
as much as I've loved building the product, I've
taken so much pride in building the team, and
it's just been so much of a pleasure. And I think
this is one of the two secrets that I have here.
This is so good. I have a follow-up
question, but just to point out why I
think this is so genius is that there's
kind a assumption here of this person,
you can trust them. So there's like, do I trust
this person? Do I feel like they're going to be
proactive? Do I feel like they're going to have
correct insights, essentially taste and gut
feeling? It's like the layer below this question,
which is great. And also just this autonomy,
it feels like autonomy almost implies so many
important traits of somebody that you want to
hire. And I love just how simple this question
is for both you and them to [inaudible 01:05:35]-
Thank you. And really with that autonomy, I love
what you said about autonomy. Because truly,
as a leader, as a manager, your goal is to
scale. And if this simple statement is not true,
how are you able to build the
best company, the best product?
So here's the follow-up question. Is this
mostly for leaders, like say a head of product
at ChatGPT, say, someone's not a CPO, they're
just like, I don't know, a manager of a PM team,
is there a version of this that you think might
be useful to them, or is this mostly for leaders?
I think this is for everyone. I think it's for
everyone who is a manager. Because if you're
going to be a successful manager at any company,
or a leader at any company, and if you're starting
as a line manager, or whatnot, and you're kind of
wanting to grow, or even just wanting to ... If
you're early at a company, you have so much
institutional knowledge. And so getting more
leverage in terms of being able to pass on the
wisdom that you've learned is so crucial into
being successful that I think every manager should
approach their reports with this. Because truly,
it's just good for everyone. It's good for the
company to have more kind of leverage and scale.
It's good for the person who is being brought
onto the team, because they know what success
looks like, and it gives them a path to keep
on growing. And it's great for you as a leader,
as a manager, to be able to basically
scale up the entire expertise of your team.
I imagine you don't even need to plan to not
tell them what to do. It's just a good lens into,
are they going to be amazing? Even if you
plan to be telling them sort of what to do.
Yeah, exactly. The other thing is,
again, in your interview process,
you kind of end up looking for these insights,
and you look for the behaviors of like, oh,
are they actually going to be potentially able
to achieve this in six months? And that's going
to give you a really good lens on the picking
side, not just the development side as well.
Peter, what's your second
secret? This is one-for-one.
Yeah. Okay. The second one I'd say is, I feel
really strongly about this, which is the area
that I look for most is growth mindset. And I
actually came to this some point in my management
career at Facebook, where I did make a mistake
and hired someone who just didn't quite have
that growth mindset. And it was really difficult,
because the way I say it's like, "Look, I don't
have time to sugarcoat any feedback," and frankly,
the best people I've worked with are the people
who come into one-on-ones with me and yell at
me and tell me I'm messing up. I love that,
because there's nothing left unsaid, and we're
able to kind of move the ball forward of, "Hey,
how do we get better from this?" And I feel
like growth mindset's one of those things,
Lenny, that it feels really hard to teach at
a certain age. And this is really important
to me and my family, I expect growth mindset
of myself, of my kids, my colleagues at work.
Because I think it just creates this environment
where everyone is open to what's the one thing I
can get better at? And that whole get 1% better
every day can become true. And it's funny,
whenever I go to teams like ChatGPT
or Uber, when I'm always the final
interview for someone in my org, and I
partner with recruiting on developing
the rubric, I always insist on doing the last
interview. And I do ... not product sense,
I don't do design, I don't do execution, I
don't do metrics. I only do growth mindset.
And it's kind of like, well that's crazy. What
about all of these other attributes? I'm like,
"Well, I'm pretty sure I can trust the other
people to assess the other attributes." But I
think the growth mindset thing is so important
to me, that we build a org where people are
self-reflective, and want to get better, and take
that feedback, and give that feedback. And it just
is this meta unlock that I found to be true.
And really, if you don't have growth mindset,
and you're not open to feedback, and you're not
open to learning, then that's the meta blocker.
At that point, it's hard to get feedback, it's
hard to onboard to a new skill. It's hard to
develop in any sort of meaningful way. And so
I found that to be the really critical piece.
That's a big deal what you just said there,
that essentially as the CPO, head of product,
big product leader at a company, your
interview is not like, "Are you an
amazing product manager? Do you have products
taste," things like that. It's a growth mindset.
And I just want to clarify, it's because
all the other things have been interviewed
by the designer, by the engineering lead, et
cetera. And that's where the previous principle
comes into play as well, in terms of, I do
trust my team to go and assess those people,
but the one thing that I care so much about is
growth mindset. And that's kind of the thing.
And to be honest, I do do a little bit of a sweep.
So if we got weak signal on one of those areas,
I'll do it. But the pure focus of my last
interview is going to be on growth mindset.
Okay, well I need to ask you what that looks
like. But before I do, when you talk about
growth mindset, I have this image of Mark Benioff
on the podcast, and I asked him, just like there's
so much changing all the time. It's such a crazy
world to be leading a company in this world,
where just, everyone's disrupting each other, AI's
changing everything. It's just moving so fast,
every day there's a new breakthrough, and
you have to keep track, and just like,
how do you deal with that? And he's like, "You
should be thinking, 'Good. This is amazing. This
is the best time to be building. There's so much
opportunity, so exciting. This is what we want.'"
Exactly.
"Good." I just remember saying like, "Good."
I love that.
And I feel like that's the
epitome of growth mindset.
Yep, absolutely.
Okay, so let me ask you just how do you tease
out a strong growth mindset? What are some ways?
Well, good thing I'm not an operator anymore,
because I'm going to give away my interview
questions, so no one can cheat on this. I feel
like this is another reason why this is such a
great time to do this podcast. The question
I asked has been the same one I've asked for
years. And you can really kind suss it out from
this, which is I asked them, think about one of
the biggest mistakes you've made, truly, the more
painful the better. And tell me what the mistake
was. Describe to me the situation, and tell me
actually how you actually think differently now,
work differently as a result. How has that
turned into a core principle of yours, et cetera.
And I give them a moment to think about it.
Sometimes I even share some of my mistakes,
if need be. And it's interesting, because
I've asked this question so many times,
I can smell the BS if they're not being authentic.
It's kind of like, "oh, I've worked too hard," or,
"I did this thing." And they're really not being
that ... You can tell the vulnerability that
people are willing to express. And I reciprocate
with that, if they ask me what mine is, I will
tell them what it is. And then that's the vibe.
But what ends up happening is there's multiple
reasons why this is really interesting. One, you
get to get a sense of how reflective they are. And
there's one woman, I was chatting with them, we
actually went on for an hour, because she was just
educating me on this amazing problem that she had
made this mistake on, and how it changed the way
that she worked, and the company worked. It was
just incredible. And you can sense the passion,
you can sense what's genuine. And then there are
always, once in a while those things that people
are just very, a little bit more defensive and
not willing to open up. And it's safe. It's a
one-on-one setting, so it's a safe space. And it's
also, I don't think it actually selects for or
against introverts or extroverts. I think at that
point it's really genuine. And the second sort of
order effect there is, if they end up coming on
the team, you've already had that moment. You've
already had that moment where you've just already
said, "Hey, this is where I really messed up." And
guess what? It's all okay. It's not a loss, it's
a lesson. And so it just sets a different tone
for your working relationship. So again, I've
never A-B tested this, so I can't tell you if
this actually, works or not, but I found it to
be very helpful in the style that I work in, to
be able to have that level of connection, whether
it's with a direct report or somebody in New York.
What I love about this answer is it's very much
like Fail Corner, which is a recurring segment
on this podcast, and I might tweak Fail
Corner to be even closer to this question.
Okay, so let me summarize these essentially two
questions that you've found to be really helpful
in finding these superstars that you've hired over
the years. One is you ask people in six months,
"If I'm telling you what to do, I've
hired the wrong person." Or I guess,
how do you say it when you say it to someone? Just
like, "You're probably the wrong person for this?"
Well, it's actually framed a little bit
differently. So there's five different
part of my API, or just how to work best with
me. There's five attributes of people that
are most successful who work with
me and I love working with. And one
of them is framed as that you're telling
me what to do, not the other way around.
Six months after joining.
Right, right. And then I follow up with,
"In six months, if I'm still telling
you to do, I've hired the wrong person."
Got it.
I think, that's how I frame it.
Okay. By the way, you should
open source this PXD API doc.
I would love to. I think now I got nothing to
hide. I'm just like, "Here, I'm an open book." So
maybe we'll do that at some point. You'll make me
brave enough to do that, maybe after this podcast.
So you may find a link in the show
notes for this podcast to the doc.
If I'm brave enough.
Okay. And then the other question you ask is,
"Tell me essentially a story of when you
failed, a product that you launched failed,
and how that changed how you behave, how
you think about product, how you operate."
Yeah.
Amazing. Okay, great. Okay,
let's talk about management.
Sure.
So this came up, so I talked to a bunch of people
that have worked with you, and interestingly,
one of the most recurring themes, it wasn't
about AI, or ... Hiring came up a bit,
but it was actually mostly about how skilled you
are as a manager. And this all has already come
through in a lot of the things we've talked about.
So I want to talk about a couple things here.
Sure.
One is someone that you worked with
at OpenAI, Joanna Jang? Or is it Yang-
Joanne? Joanne.
Joanne. Joanne Jang, or Yang?
Yeah, Jang.
Jang. Okay, cool. You worked with her at OpenAI,
and she shared a couple things that I think are
really interesting. One is that you had a
profound impact on her career by teaching
her how to manage up more effectively. And
you did that by teaching her a really simple
phrase that she just says and uses. First
of all, do you remember what that phrase is?
I've said a lot of stuff, and I've kind
of forgotten. I tend to forget what I say,
so you might have to remind me.
Okay, so she said "Say you'll do the thing, do
the thing, say you did the thing," as a skill
of managing up. So just talk about that, just
the power of that and what that's all about.
I mean, look, I learned this from my time at Uber,
from Jill who runs PR, comms, and policy there,
and she used to have this saying, which is like,
"Repetition doesn't spoil the prayer." It's just
a natural thing where people are busy. So whether
you think about managing up or even managing the
entire org, if you don't repeat what your goals
are, if you don't repeat what your vision is,
if you don't repeat the thing that you feel
strongly about what you're doing, whether it's
maybe to your manager, one, I think you might lose
sight of the thing that's important. And I think
this is where it's a little bit about behavior.
This is another language affecting thought thing.
By giving this phrase to Joanne, maybe it was just
like, "Hey, let's just be very intentional about
what we build." That becomes a constant reminder.
And it also has this other effect, where if
you're saying, "This is what I'm doing," and then
that's a thing that your manager's like, "Wait,
we don't need to do that anymore," you can have a
conversation about that. As opposed to just doing
the thing and not saying that you're doing it.
So let me take a step back. So one, say what
you're going to do. And then in that exercise
you're going to be able to calibrate with your
manager, again, with anyone, what is it that
we're going to do? And I think the words are
really important here, going back to what I said
earlier, so figuring out what is that goal, and
crafting that to really pack the most punch and
the densest of concepts. And then you're telling
them that you're doing it, which that's the second
phase, which is like, in your one-on-ones or in
your team all hands, you're saying, "This is
what we're doing."It's a great time to reaffirm
you're doing or invite the conversation
that this is no longer the thing to do.
And you got to tell them you did it. So just
close the loop, just be like, "Okay, great,
this is now done." And I think that's, again,
it's one of those really pithy phrases that has
so many second-order effects that are behavioral,
almost. And this is a little bit of a hack in
terms of helping people. It's funny that Joanne
thought of it as managing up, which it is, but in
my mind it's almost like this is how we operate,
and this is how we're successful to stay on task,
stay on goal, and be able to revisit the goals
that we've set when they no longer are relevant.
So the phrase again is say you'll do the thing,
do the thing, and then say that you did the thing.
Sorry, one more time. The way I would say
it is, say you're going to do the thing,
say that you're doing the thing,
and then say that you did it.
This also works for presentation advice. So
this came up, I don't if it was Guy Kawasaki
or someone, had a very similar phrase that was
for how to present well, which is tell them
what you're going to tell them, tell them,
and then tell them what you just told them.
It's possible that I might've incepted
it from there. So I take no ownership
over this phrase. I will just
say that yes, I did repeat it.
This is great. And I love that this isn't just
managing up advice, it's just operating advice for
everyone. And there's an implication of, the last
part is just make sure people know what you did,
almost make sure that you get some credit,
and people understand the impact you've had.
Which is important. I think there's a lot
of people who are kind of introverted,
and don't want to draw attention, and don't have
the hero complex. And I think that those people
tend to get lost in organizations. So if that
describes you, just remember to say what you did.
There's another management trait that Joanne
shared that I want to spend a little time on,
which is you're very good at helping people
understand that they can lean into their
strengths, and not feel like they need to fit
into a certain box. She shared that you basically
helped her create almost a new role within OpenAI
that wasn't even a thing before. So just maybe
share that example, and then just talk about
why this is important, how you think about this.
Well, I love that we're talking about things that
Joanne are telling you, because Joanne's really
special. I got to just take a moment to give
her a giant shout out. She is the only person
that I've worked with that has as much technical
depth as she does have product taste. And I just
want to pause there. It's just truly special.
I feel entirely privileged to have the chance
to cross paths with her at OpenAI. I learned so
much from her. Again, talk about not telling you
what to do after six months. She was telling
me what to do from day two, and I loved it,
because she was so technical, and she has this
taste and those two things are very rare to find
together. And with Joanne, because she was
so special in that way, and I spotted that,
I was like, "Wow, I've worked with so many
PMs and just like, this is very unique."
It felt like we had to find a way to craft
this. And sure enough, I was like, "Hey,
can you just write up a job description of what
is this thing? Because there's something magical
here, but I don't fully understand it." I
don't think any other person really thinks
of things this way, and think this might be a
big superpower for OpenAI. Let's codify it."
And again, going back to my language being a
really important thing, I think the exercise
sometimes of writing things down, of things that
you intuitively feel, give you an artifact that
can kind of communicate with somebody else. So
in this case, Joanne writing down some of the
things that she got really excited about, helped
me really understand that. And I was luckily in a
position where I can basically say, "Look, let's
create this role. Let's create this role and
have you lead it. And I think this is going to be
great for the product if we're able to codify it."
So I don't think I did anything special.
I was just following my instincts,
and just following her lead. Again, I'll be clear,
I did not author that document. My recollection,
she did that. So she did all the hard work in all
of this thing, and I don't want to take any credit
for it. The only thing I did was just gave her
a little nudge of, " I think there's something
here. Can you just take a moment to go and write
this down?" And when she did, it was just like,
"Okay, this has got to be a role and you
have to be the leader for this function."
What is the actual role she ended up in? I
think that'd be really interesting to share.
The role was model designer, and it was just
a really interesting way that she framed it.
And I know this role probably exists in some
incarnation in other foundational model companies,
but the way that she described it, and the
things that she found to be the spikes required,
led us to hire our first two model designers
after running a search. And they were just
perfect fits for the team. And that, I think,
is largely a big secret as to why, at least, I'm
biased. I love ChatGPT so much, and the way
the model comes off, and the vibe of the model,
is largely because of this technical plus taste
role that she has created and she's leading.
I love one of the interesting takeaways
from this is as a leader is just pay
attention to what people are
really, really excited about,
and then take the step of, let them try
to describe it very clearly in a doc.
Coming back to your point about the power
of language and words is just like, "Okay,
tell me exactly what you're thinking and let's
jam on it, because maybe there's something here."
Yeah.
Is there anything broader here about
just leaning into strengths that you
find just ... There's a lot of people,
there's all this debate of should I
just work on the things I'm terrible at
and that'll make me better, or should I
find the things I'm amazing at and just get
better at those things? Any thoughts there?
I genuinely believe that fit is a two-way
street. And so what you are passionate about,
what your strengths are, you got to really find
the right company, the right role for you. And I
think there's a lot of force fitting that people
want to do is to fit into a certain archetype. I'm
glad we talked about the PM archetypes. Hopefully
that frees people up to really lean into what they
love. Because life's pretty short. It'd be
great if everyone would find the thing that
they really wanted to do, and be able to lean
in and do that. And I think the optimist to me
is also why I'm so excited about the time and
age that we're in right now, because there's so
many different companies popping up. So there's
something that really resonates with people.
I mean, take a look at just what we're doing
here, it's like, podcasting was not a thing 20
years ago. It was not a thing. But now, we are
able to have these amazing tools and platforms
that allow people to really express themselves,
and really, what really truly brings them joy
and makes them happy, and also brings a ton
of value to the world. So I think that, yeah,
I definitely believe in leaning in strengths,
and I think that as hard as it may be,
sometimes you got to look at where you are right
now, and is this the thing that you really want to
do? Or is there something else that's drawing
your attention and drawing you towards that?
There's another management oriented question I
want to ask you. This came from Eric Antonell,
who apparently has worked with you for
17 years across a bunch of different-
Yeah, off and on for 17 years. One of my
biggest mentors and friends, he's amazing.
Okay. So he's like, "You need to ask this
question." So the way he put it is you've hired,
managed, mentored many, many, many product
people, some junior, some senior, across so
many different cultures, and he's just like, "We
need to learn something from your experience doing
that," in terms of what you've learned about what
it takes to be a really successful product person,
whether it's being successful in building
product or career-wise, what's just a nugget
that you learned from seeing so many different
types of people, and cultures, and seniority.
I think for a product person specifically, it's
really important to obsess over the details of
craft. Because ultimately, you're crafting
a product. It's important to obsess about
the details of craft, while simultaneously
having the perspective and wisdom of which
details don't actually matter. I'm going
to pause there and just kind of try to-
I'm going to pause there and just try to
unpack this a little bit because at the
core of being a product person, you're like,
oh, I want to build something that people love
and that's the job and that's what draws
people to be product people is that you
have this desire to build. And I think that
I've been involved in enough teams where I,
myself, and when I was really young
and coming up as a product person,
I would just get obsessed over these little
details and I realized afterwards that we've
just wasted a bunch of time on something that
didn't actually matter. So I think that dichotomy
is somewhat interesting and beautiful to me
because it capsulates both the core of what
the ethos of a successful product person is, which
is you really have to care and you have to give
a crap about the product that you're building,
but you also have to have the perspective and
business know-how to understand where do you apply
your time and where do you apply the care there?
And I myself feel like I've gone through
cycles. Everything that I've done,
I've gone super deep and really obsessed and
then I take a step back and I'm like, wait,
actually I was missing something and this other
thing was more important, right? I'll give you
an example. I'll use the Uber example here as
what I said that the digital product didn't
really matter and it's all about the price, the
ETA, one of the products that I've built at Uber,
which is Uber Reserve, right? It's the simplest
of things. Going back to what I said before,
sometimes the best products is the simplest of
things. But the problem that we were trying to
solve is that everyone has this. You have a 6 AM
flight, and are you really going to wake up at 4
AM and request an Uber and hope that there's
enough Ubers and the person's going to come?
Because if you do that, you're not going to sleep
well and you're going to wake up every two hours
and you're probably going to miss your flight
anyway because you're going to fall asleep or
whatever. And so there was this insight of like,
okay, there's a whole mismatch between what people
really want, which is the peace of mind that
their car is going to be there and guess what?
I'm willing to pay for that. And so we built
Uber Reserve, which it was the simplest thing,
which is like, oh, just go ahead and say what
time your flight is and we'll work backwards
or even just tell us when you want to get picked
up and everything about that product we crafted
what really mattered for the user, which was
the peace of mind. So if you go there and you
say what time your flight is and your pick-up
time or whatever, I think that the product is...
It hasn't changed that much since I was there.
It would tell you, oh, this is cutting it really
close. You may not make your flight. It's like,
wow. Again, that was put in there because of the
principle of peace of mind. And on the other side
it's like, well, what do drivers need? They need
to know you're not going to cancel and all this
other stuff. So you've got to think about the
driver incentives too. So it was a simple idea,
really proud of the team for figuring out all the
intricate details, did some testing, and last I
heard from folks internally, this is a $5 billion
a year business now and one of the highest margin
ones, and I'm really proud of this because it came
from the idea of let's focus on what actually
matters, which is that peace of mind and how
many people really need it in that moment.
So I think that's the best story I can tell.
That's an awesome story. It connects so many
of the things you've talked about. One is just
it may not be the product that really matters,
and micro-optimizing the experience is not going
to move the needle when there's something
else that's more operationally oriented,
but there's always going to be a product component
if you're building it for freezers. The other
piece that I think is interesting here is...
Well, there's two. One is just it connects back
to your point about the importance of autonomy of
product people is just I feel like you're like,
here's the team, here's what I'm told
to work on. And then you're like, oh,
but this thing is actually the problem we need to
solve and let's just build a new product around
it. And then there's a whole story I imagine
of you getting buy-in and all that stuff.
The other thing this connects to, we just had
the CPO of Uber, the current CPO of Uber on the
podcast, and he had a few episodes before
this one. It was all about dog fooding and
basically exactly discovering these problems.
He's done seven to 800 rides as an Uber driver
to discover these problems. He had this great
quote about, it's one thing to watch, just
build an app for drivers sitting in your office
making it look really pretty. It's another to be
driving 60 miles an hour with this phone a few
feet away from you trying to figure things out.
A hundred percent. Oh, I remember that I took
two weeks off before I joined Uber. And in that
time I've been obsessed with user research for the
longest of times, and this is more relevant back
then when you wanted to really understand how the
wide massive users were using your product. And I
remember I actually leased a car to drive for
Uber those two weeks. So it was a little white
VW something or another. I put an Uber sticker
on it, I turned on the app and it just started
driving and there's no better way to learn than to
dog food, and I'll just build on what... Sachin is
the person you had on the podcast? Yeah, he's an
amazing, amazing guy. And so I'll just build on
what he said there. I think that what really stuck
with me in terms of framework that I learned back
in school because I was brought up with the IDEO
way of design thinking and I was at the design
school at Stanford where before we literally
were in trailers. That's how early it was.
But I remember the framework that really stuck
with me is what IDEO preached, which is there
are five stages to great design thinking. Number
one is empathize, two is to define, three is to
ideate, four is a prototype, and five is to test.
And what I love about this framework, and I really
hope this doesn't get lost because I don't know
how much it's being preached nowadays in design
thinking is that it has the right words associated
with it. The first thing is empathizing. You've
got to really feel the pain of your customers.
It's not just about theoretically understanding
what the problems are. It's really empathizing,
which is why user research was so important to me
is to understand that, or even like Sachin said,
just taking those rides but also flying around the
world. And when I was working at Uber to figure
out, well, what are the various conditions?
And so empathize is a really powerful word. The
define is also a really powerful word because it
forces you to articulate what the problem is.
And this is, again, going back to the language
thing of you have to be very intentional about
defining the problems that you want to solve
and then ideate, we all know it's brainstorming
and prototyping and tests are self-explanatory,
but the first two stages I think are really
insightful and it talks directly to what Sachin
was saying. You've got to dog food because you
really have to empathize and the great products
are when you really feel the pain and you really
empathize with what people are experiencing.
That's a great connection to another podcast
episode that came to mind as you were talking,
the head of product at Linear, Nan, had this
really great concept that's exactly what you're
saying, which is as a product person, you
want to feel the pain of your customer the
same way they do. You shouldn't stop asking
questions to understand what they're telling
you until you feel the pain that they
feel and that'll help you. Basically,
that's like how to operationalize empathizing.
It's just do you feel the suffering?
Yeah, and I really do hope product people
still do this to this day because I think
there's so many shortcuts that if people take,
you're going to miss the point, right? I still
remember distinctly flying down to LA with Kevin
Systrom to go do a user research study, and it was
a one-way glass thing where we listened to people
talk about Instagram and how they use Instagram,
and there's no substitute for that. I think that
to anyone out there who's doing user interviews
and then saying, hey ChatGPT, summarize the
takeaways, you're missing the point. You
can't empathize with the summary. You have to
be in the room fully immersed, no phones, just
actually hearing the words and the intonation.
That's how you're going to get the full color.
It makes me think Jeff Bezos has this great
quote, if you have an anecdote and data and
they're telling you different things, trust
the anecdote. Oh, man. So many lessons. Okay,
so to start to kind of wrap up our
conversation, we covered a lot of ground,
I want to ask you about Facebook real quick. So
you joined Facebook very early. Eric Antonow,
who I've mentioned previously, told me that it was
very strange that you left Google to join Facebook
at that stage. Google was killing it, on top of
the world. You had such a strong career path,
things were going great, but you decided
to take a big leap joining Facebook. What
did you see? Because I think there's
something interesting here that we can
learn about what you saw that may help
other people decide where to go work.
I've always been enamored with this idea
of understanding us as fundamentally human
and how we're wired. And I remember at the time
talking to the folks at Facebook and seeing it,
and this was back when people were like, oh,
this is just a college site, and that was the
vibe back then. But what I saw was that the
team and Mark and others really understood
the fundamental human desires that people
had to connect and feel lonely and to share,
and they really got the right articulation of the
problem they were trying to solve, which was to
make the world more open and connected. And this
really resonated with me because again, I study a
lot in college like psychology, and I was really
enamored with this idea of how are we as humans
fundamentally wired? And it felt to me like a
no-brainer to go work at Facebook because they saw
how people were wired and how to actually build
products that complement how people are wired.
And it wasn't that they were trying to force fit
something into something that was unnatural. It
was almost like how do we build technologies and
products that actually augment our fundamental
desire to stay connected? And this goes back to
why I think the power of wars is so important
is because you take a look at some of the
mission statements for Friendster or MySpace,
I don't even know if they had mission statements
or what they were, they were kind of vapid and
they didn't really speak to the fundamental
humanity of what Facebook was striving to
build and that just deeply resonated with me. And
so I remember spending time with Eric being like,
"Hey, what should I do? Should I take this offer
from Facebook or should I stay at Google?" But
ultimately it was just that deep resonance
with my values of building things that were
fundamentally human. And ultimately I
think that for any startup out there,
anyone building product, the more that you can
get a good impedance match between what you're
building and what humans fundamentally want and
need, the more successful you're going to be.
So that's my big answer. I think the secondary
answer, I've always optimized for learning in my
career, and this is a huge thing that I say to a
lot of people because they look at sort of like,
oh, you've been at all these companies,
what's your secret? I'm like, well,
I've just figured out that I want to go to the
place where I can learn the most. And for me,
that wasn't really Google, but I had so much
I wanted to learn from operating at Facebook.
And at Facebook I would say, yeah, I was there
for nine and a half years, but I always jumped
around every two and a half or so when I feel like
there was something new to learn. And that's it.
I mean, I don't know if it's a secret or not, I
got lucky and I was able to have opportunities to
learn different things and different skills, and
that served me quite well. And regardless of any
outcome, I would say that's just a great way to
live your life personally is just to optimize for
learning and those experiences and for me, moving
to Facebook was that I saw so much learning that
could have happened and it ultimately did happen.
So I feel like that was a good outcome too.
[inaudible 01:39:55] did it. So a couple
takeaways here for folks that are maybe trying
to decide between a couple roles, maybe deciding
if they should leave and do something new is one,
are you feeling like you're learning enough/is the
new place you're thinking about going to help you
learn a lot more? Two, is what they're building
aligned with human behavior? Almost this impedance
match that you described. It feels like there's
another element you shared, which is do they have
a really unique insight about how things work?
And also do you really care about this? Is this
also how you see the world? So you're talking
about a Facebook, they have this really unique
insight about human behavior and that was really
important to you, and so it was a really good fit.
A hundred percent. Yeah. I think the insight
thing, thank you for summarizing that and drawing
that out because it's also what I look for and
what I want to partner with companies and startups
now is do you have that unique insight? Are you
teaching me something that I really don't know?
And that usually is a good indicator of a strong
point of view, and having a strong point of view
is really important because there's a saying
that Mike and Kevin had at Instagram which is
we may not be right, but at least we're not
confused. I think it's a beautiful phrase I
thought because sometimes you've just got to go
and do the thing that you think is right and the
indecision is going to be one of the things that
really gets you and bites you. So that for me is
something as I look for folks who have a strong
conviction, whether it's the founders I support
when I go join and be an operator at the company
or the founders I support in my current role.
That's so interesting. Tomer
Cohen, the CPO of LinkedIn,
that's a famous phrase that he often uses too.
Really?
So I think he borrowed it from
those guys. Yeah. That was one
of his mottos. We may not be
right, but we're not confused.
Wow, I didn't know that. So I did talk
him at one point. I don't remember if
that's something we talked about, but again,
it could just be like great minds think alike,
and we just had different great folks with Mike
and Kevin and Tomer feeling the same vibes.
I love just how many episodes this conversation
has referenced. Okay, so speaking of learning,
final question before we get to our very exciting
lightning round, I'm going to take us to Fail
Corner, which is very aligned with your growth
mindset question. So the idea of this segment is
people come on this podcast, they share all these
amazing stories of everything's working out, I had
so much success, worked at all these incredible
companies, everything worked, but in reality,
things don't often work out. Most people go
through a lot of failed initiatives, projects,
career hits, so the question is just what's a
product that you built and launched that was just
a big failure? And I'll ask it the way you ask it,
how did that change the way you think and operate?
One example is, since we were talking about
Instagram before, we tried to build a kind of
camera first app at Instagram. It was called Bolt
and it didn't work and the great levels of craft
and design and the premise was essentially can
we make it so it reduces the pressure to share,
and you can open to a camera, you can just
send some things to folks and you get some
good feedback and you go from there. And it was
obviously the Instagram design team, so it was
top-notch. The app was designed really well.
It was really fast because it's the Instagram
engineering team and they were just really good at
making performant mobile apps. It had all of the
advantages that we had talked about that we valued
at Instagram, but we launched it and I believe it
was New Zealand or Australia and it didn't work.
And I remember the reason we knew this is as we
were looking at sort of the retention graphs
and retention is the key indicator in any
product that you build, it's not the number of
users, not the volume, it's actually retention
and cohorted retention, you can [inaudible
01:44:00] the line and if it asymptotes,
then you're in a good spot because that means
that people over X period of time will continue
to stay on the app and that just didn't happen.
And I think the learning here was that you can
really have the best team in the world with
the best product taste and you can't really
predict what's going to hit on the first go.
And failure is okay, you're just going to up and
learn from that and nobody wallowed over that. We
actually had some technology that we built there
that we were able to port over to the main app,
which was really helpful, but to quote the great
american poet Sean Carter, "It ain't a loss, it's
a lesson." And I think it's really important that
you see that as a product person is that you
don't see it as failure, you see it as kind
of great. Now I'm that much smarter. And this is
something that I've just collected. There's other
examples as well, but I think this is a good
example of sort of something that's somewhat
counterintuitive, that you have the best team,
you're going to provide those hits over and over,
but sometimes you can't predict those hits and
you just have to have the wisdom to be like,
okay, let's see what we can learn here, see
what we can save here, and then move on.
I absolutely remember that product in launch
or heard about it, but I also don't ever think
about it. And so I think it's a good reminder.
Because Instagram launching a new product that's
trying to rethink the way you do your camera,
that's a big deal. And so I could see that
being a really big deal for it not to work out.
At the same time, nobody remembers that really.
Exactly. Yeah.
Peter, we've gone for two hours at
this point. I feel like we could
do two hours more. We'll save
that for another conversation.
Great.
Before we get to our very exciting
lightning round, is there anything
else you either wanted to share or want to
leave listeners with to maybe double down
on a point you made that you think might be
helpful? Otherwise, we'll just jump right in.
I think we should jump right in because
I feel like you've extracted every little
ounce of what wisdom I had here and you
did a great job here just helping me
remember these stories and recounting
stuff, so I'm ready to jump in.
That's my goal, although I know there is
much more that I haven't even started to tap,
but with that, we reached our very
exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
I'm ready.
Question one. What are two or three books that you
find yourself recommending most to other people?
This is easy for me. Number one is Sapiens. If
you're a product person, you have to understand
our own humanity if you want to build products
for people, straight up. That's a beautiful
book. I read it before it was called Sapiens, it
was called From Animals to Gods, and it was just
republished in a different name, but it has really
stuck with me and I remember, it's a very short,
easy read, so I'd recommend that. The second
book I think for product folks is a classic one,
which is The Design of Everyday Things by
Don Norman. This may seem outdated and old,
but I promise you it's not. It really helps you
understand physical product design, which is
again, things that mold and shape to humanity.
I think it gives you a good sense of that.
Third book is something I'm reading right
now it was recommended by a friend of mine
and I can't put it down. It's called
The Silk Roads by Peter Frankopan. And
basically this is a recounting of history
through the lens of The Silk Road and the
Middle East and how that's evolved. It's so
fascinating because one of the things I love,
Lenny, is seeing things from different
perspectives. This is why travel's fun,
this is why user research is fun for me, and it
really helps you see the events of world history
that we've all been experiencing through a very
western viewpoint in a different way. And it
kind of connects a bunch of things that are like,
there's Western thought, there's Eastern thought,
but if you see the connection between them,
it's super fascinating. I'm only two, three
or maybe four chapters in, but definitely
something I would recommend off the bat.
What is a favorite recent movie or
TV show that you've really enjoyed?
Maybe it's not as recent, but the one
that always comes back to me is The Wire,
HBO's The Wire. And I guess there's just so
many TV shows now that I'm still processing,
do I want to put it in my all-time greats? But
the storytelling there and the various
different sort of consistent characters,
but the fact that there's the beautiful writing
of The Wire is something that's unparalleled.
I'm now curious what's in your all-time greats
list, but I'm not going to go there. We're
going to keep going. What's a favorite product
you've recently discovered that you really love?
I'm just going to go with Granola because
I think that we talked about this before,
but this has been a superpower for me and I
have a lot of commute time now. What I do is
I just do a single player mode. I go up and I
start thinking about and brainstorming about
sort of ideas or theses I have for investing or
whatnot, and I get to where I'm going and boom,
they're organized in a more cogent way and
oftentimes ways that I didn't even think
about articulating them. So it goes
through the process of forming words,
but it also helps with that assistance and I think
it's a beautiful product on many different levels.
Wow. Granola's killing it at this category
recently, and I'll give a shout-out,
you get a year free of Granola if you become
a yearly subscriber of my newsletter, which
is not just for you, but your entire
team, they gave an incredible deal.
Is that true? I didn't know that.
A hundred percent true.
Okay, well I'll tell you, I was not compensated
for that little pitch there,
that's genuine right there.
I'm also not compensated. Yeah. If you go
to lennysnewsletter.com and click bundle,
you'll see a way to get it. Love the
product, use it all the time. I should
be using it for these interviews and then I
could have a whole summary ready to go. Okay,
next question. Do you have a favorite life motto
that you often come back to in work or in life?
Yes. This is actually something that my dad
taught me. It's a saying that is in Chinese.
It actually rhymes in Chinese but kind
of almost rhymes in English. And it goes
something like this in English which is if you
move a tree, it dies, but if you move a person,
he thrives. And I think it's a really interesting
thing I keep on coming back to, and this goes back
to why for me it's just the joy of learning and
trying new experiences and being at different
companies that I've been very fortunate to be at.
I really think that that's how you should live
life is just to kind of experience these different
experiences. And it's kind of poetic to be like,
yeah, unfortunately for trees, you can't
really move them after a while. But for humans,
I think that you move them around and we get
different travel experiences and we get different
life experiences when we go to different jobs,
and I think that makes life really worth living.
I always think about what I would answer to
this question, and there's a few, but one is
something I always come back to when my wife and I
are deciding to do something is choose adventure.
Similar sentiment. Final question. So you've
now moved from product leader to investor,
so I just want to give you a chance
to tell people what kind of stuff
you're looking for. So you moved [inaudible
01:51:11] now, investing in startups. What
sort of startups are you looking for? Who
should reach out if they're interested in-
Well, I appreciate that opportunity. Look, for me,
I think it's been very clear. I just love working
with great people and for me, investing is just
the ability to support more amazing founders. I've
always been drawn to the founder archetype, like
working closely with Zach or with Travis or Howie,
Brendan at Oculus, and folks at Opening Eye,
I think there's this amazing sort of visionary
person that I love supporting in one way or
another. And I've supported them mainly from the
inside as a product leader, but for me it's just
finding those amazing founders. In this current
role, I get to work with many founders at the
same time. And just two days ago I had meaningful
calls, product jams with three different founders
in three different industries, and that kind of
keeps my mind super alive. So that's kind of why
I'm doing what I'm doing now, and I would love to
find some more of those amazing thought partners
and people that I can just help out if I can.
Okay. Stage and market, anything there for
folks of like, okay, he's a fit, not a fit.
Absolutely. So I would say early stage seed, seed
plus and A is where I really get excited. I feel
like I am able to help folks see the next stage.
I've seen a lot of movies in my life in my career,
so it's like, oh, great, I can definitely see
this extrapolating out. You'd have to convince
me of the future, and then it's really
fun to be able to jam and help support
if I can in how you scale from the one to 10
and 10 to a hundred. So that's really big.
And then in terms of what I look for it's the
two things I said before, in this day and age,
there's so many amazing things that's going to be
built. One is do you have unique data and do you
have a data flywheel? Two, do you have a really
crafted workflow that you can really get after?
And I guess third, do you have that insight
of what product things actually matter and
also which ones don't? And then how do you
actually go and expand upon that? So yeah,
really excited to meet a bunch more founders,
whether it comes from here or somewhere else.
Okay, so final question and it's how
do folks reach out if they want to
actually talk to you about this and
how can listeners be useful to you?
Thank you for the question. I am an introvert,
so I'm really kind of silent on a lot of social
media. I have accounts on X and Threads, but
really I think LinkedIn is the network of choice
for me. I want to be able to passively consume
and learn about what's happening. How listeners
can be helpful, I just want to learn. What are
you all thinking about? What are some of the
insights you're seeing? One of the analogies
I have about AI in this day and age is that
it's this really interesting new element that
humanity has discovered. And what's awesome
is that humanity is also very creative. And
so what humanity does with this new element,
I'm fascinated by, and you can tell
the founders who've actually played
with this element because they have this innate
sense of what this thing can do and can't do,
and I'm just looking to be inspired by
the creativity of all you all out there.
Wow, that's such a cool way of thinking about
it. It's going to change my perspective on AI
a little bit. Peter, this was incredible.
I really appreciate you taking the time
to share so much wisdom. I know this is the
first time you've done anything like this.
I feel like this is going to help a lot of
people in a lot of different ways. I feel
like we covered everything I wanted to
cover, so just again, thank you for-
Well, thank you for having me.
This has been a real pleasure
and hopefully some folks out there can get
some learnings from this and find it useful,
but that was my goal is to be able to share some
things and hopefully it'll be helpful to some
folks out there. So thank you.
Thank you for the opportunity.
Thank you, Peter. Bye everyone. Thank you so
much for listening. If you found this valuable,
you can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating or
leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can
find all past episodes or learn more about
the show at lennyspodcast.com.
See you in the next episode.