Your brand name, nothing's going to be used more
often or for longer than that name. Design will
change, messaging will change, products
will change, but that name is there.
What's a name that you came
up with that you had to fight
super hard for, that the client just hated?
When we presented Sonos, it was rejected because
it's not entertainment-like. We argued about
that because I said, "This is outside looking in,
but I don't see you as an entertainment company."
Humans do like to be comfortable. Part of our job
here is to help people to give the confidence
going bigger and being uncomfortable.
There's a quote that I found of yours, "If
your team is comfortable with the name,
chances are you don't have the name yet."
We look for polarization. We look for tension
in a team arguing about these things. Polarization
is a sign of strength in the word. Most clients,
they come to a naming project absolutely
believing with full confidence that they're
going to know it when they see it, and
the truth is it almost never happens.
Most people listening to this are founders,
a lot of PMs on product teams. Let's say they
have a couple of weeks, got to come
up with a name. What should they do?
Today, my guest is David Placek. David is the
founder of Lexicon Branding, which pioneered the
field of brand naming, and invented a few names
that you may have heard of including Powerbook,
Pentium, Blackberry, Swiffer, the Impossible
Burger. Also, Vercel, Windsurf, CapCut,
and Azure. In our conversation, David opens up
about the very specific process that he and his
team go through to find winning names, including a
simple exercise that you can do with you and your
team to help you find the right name in just a
few weeks. We also talk about why a great name is
worth spending your time on, why you won't know
a great name when you see it, and why you need
to feel uncomfortable about the name first. Also,
why big team brainstorms don't ever lead to great
names. The stories behind names like Pentium,
and Sonos, and Vercel, and Windsurf. Also, such
interesting insights about the feeling and energy
of every letter of the alphabet and so much more.
This episode is designed for anyone trying to
figure out a name for their product or company,
and also just for anyone that's interested
in hearing the stories of how some of the
most iconic names came to be. If you enjoy this
podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow it
in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. And
if you become a paid subscriber of my newsletter,
you get a year free of a bunch of amazing
products including Bolt, Linear, Superhuman,
Notion, Perplexity, Granola and more. Check it
out at lennysnewsletter.com and click bundle.
With that, I bring you David Placek.
This episode is brought to you by WorkOS.
If you're building a SaaS app, at some point,
your customers will start asking for enterprise
features like SAML authentication and skim
provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in,
making it fast and painless to add enterprise
features to your app. Their APIs are easy to
understand so that you can ship quickly and get
back to building other features. Today, hundreds
of companies are already powered by WorkOS,
including ones you probably know like Vercel,
Webflow, and Loom. WorkOS also recently acquired
Warrant, the fine-grain authorization service.
Warrant's product is based on a groundbreaking
authorization system called Zanzibar,
which was originally designed for Google to
power Google Docs and YouTube. This enables
fast authorization checks at enormous scale
while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases.
If you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features
like single sign-on, skim, or user management,
you should consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in
replacement for Auth0 and supports up to 1 million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
workos.com to learn more. That's workos.com.
Last year, 1.3% of the global GDP flowed through
Stripe. That's over $1.4 trillion. And driving
that huge number are the millions of businesses
growing more rapidly with Stripe. For industry
leaders like Forbes, Atlassian, OpenAI, and
Toyota, Stripe isn't just financial software.
It's a powerful partner that simplifies how they
move money, making it as seamless and borderless
as the internet itself. For example, Hertz boosted
its online payment authorization rates by 4% after
migrating to Stripe. And imagine seeing a 23% lift
in revenue like Forbes did just six months after
switching to Stripe for subscription management.
Stripe has been leveraging AI for the last decade
to make its product better at growing revenue for
all businesses, from smarter checkouts to fraud
prevention and beyond. Join the ranks of over half
of the Fortune 100 companies that trust Stripe to
drive change. Learn more at stripe.com.
David, thank you so much for being here,
and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you. I'm excited about today
and looking forward to the conversation.
Me, too. These are actually my favorite kinds
of conversations because this topic is so outside
of my wheelhouse, and I know I'm just going to
learn a ton. Also, this is just something that
every founder and product builder has to think
about at some point, and they have no idea what
they're doing. And then, their name becomes so
core to their identity. It's hardly the word they
say more than any other word. And I feel like
I've never heard advice on how to do this well.
So, I'm really excited for this conversation.
I'm going to just dive into a question. And the
question is just what's a name that you came up
with, and your team came up with, that you had to
fight super hard for that the client just hated,
and you ended up winning. And now, it's just such
an obviously awesome name that everyone loves.
The story I like to tell is a story of Sonos.
One, a great client team. I worked with all
the founders. But at the time, they were
stuck on being in a brand name that put
them in the entertainment business. And so when we
presented Sonos, which has many qualities to it,
it was rejected because it doesn't have enough
emotion to it. It's not entertainment-like.
And we argued about that because I said, "This
is outside looking in, but I don't see you as
an entertainment company. You make speakers that
allow for the flow of entertainment through these
things. And Sonos is about sound." But it had
a particular quality. It's called a palindrome,
which really means that you can flip it and
it means the same thing. In the case of Sonos,
you could also turn it upside down
and it was essentially the same.
And so that got them thinking about this, but
they were still has... So I left that meeting
in Santa Barbara, and I came back and they were
still struggling with it. And I got on a plane,
didn't even bill them for this, went back down
to Santa Barbara and met with them again and
said, "I really believe in this name and I think
it's the right for you." And at a certain point,
one of the founders, Bob MacFarlane, who's just
a wonderful client. I could see him thinking,
and he said, "You know? We're trying to name
this for ourselves, and what we really should
be doing is naming it for the marketplace and
the customers. And I think Sonos now is the
right name. And I felt really good about that." He
later wrote me a note about how I help to do that,
and we use it sometimes in credentials
presentations because it's such a nice note.
But Sonos is something I'm so glad that I had this
internal energy to, "I got to go down there and
make a bid for this." I don't do that often, by
the way, but I felt very strongly about Sonos.
I love Sonos. I love the name. I have many Sonos
products. How often does this happen where the
client is just, "No, this is not the name. We
have this bigger vision, we have a whole other
idea of it." And then you convince them.
Well, it happens all of the time. And it's a
little bit bidirectional, right? Most
clients, and I can understand this,
they come to a naming project absolutely
believing, with full confidence, that they're
going to know it when they see it. And the truth
is, it almost never happens. I think this year
we'll hit 4,000 projects that we've completed.
And it's interesting, we'll tell people in a very
polite way, "You're not going to know when you
see it." But I know they don't believe me. And
even when... You could see them thinking that,
"You know what? He was right. I really have to
think about this. I have to process it." And part
of that, part of why clients don't like the bolder
names, the more imaginative names that we present
is they are looking for comfort. And that's the
opposite that what you want to do. And part of our
job here is to help people to give the confidence
that going bolder, and bigger, and being
uncomfortable. I use the expression, "There is
no power in comfort, not in the marketplace."
Wow. There's so much here already. So this idea
of you're not going to know it when you see it is
something that people come in with thinking like,
"Once I see it, it'll be obvious." Just why is
that almost never the case? Is it because the name
has to be something that is uncomfortable?
There's a lot of psychology to this,
which ironically, I never even took a psychology
class in college or graduate school. But the first
element is humans do like to be comfortable.
And one of the mechanisms of comfort is if
something's been successful before, then I feel
like I can approve it or select it. This is why
movies like Harry Potter or even novels like
Jack London's Call of the Wild get rejected
so many times. I think Harry Potter was rejected
16 or 18 times, and Jack London's book even more
than that. I mean, think about it. He's pitching
a book and they say, "What are you talking about
here? You're saying a dog becomes a wolf?
I've never heard of anything like that." So,
we really do have to help people think about,
"It's not about the past. You're actually creating
the future." And we really talk to people and
emphasize the idea, "This isn't a name you're
creating. We're creating an experience
for you. We're going to work together."
And our conversations always start with,
"Talk to us about how you behave now and
how you want to behave in the future," as
opposed to, "Tell me about your positioning,
tell me about your values, tell me about your
mission." That's really kind of old thinking.
It's very traditional, and that did work 25 or
30 years ago. But this is a far more complex,
interconnected world, a digital world now that
stuff just doesn't create... It doesn't create
names like Sonos or some of our other credentials
that we probably will talk about today.
Yeah, we're going to talk about just
the process you guys go through,
so stay tuned for that. But before we get
to that, is there's another story you can
share that shows this idea of being bold?
I'll talk about Microsoft's Azure. So when
Microsoft came to us, they were pretty much stuck.
And Microsoft does... And in many ways, to their
credit, a lot of things don't need to be named.
They don't need trademarks. They don't need brand
names. They need descriptors. And so they came to
us to develop a name that started or ended with
cloud. Made sense to them because it was a cloud
service. And our reaction was, "If you do that,
you're going to be in an ocean of other cloud
this, cloud that. And you have an opportunity
as Microsoft here to really emerge as a leader
in this." And so, there was a discussion about,
"Okay, we'll take a look at those, but we'd like
to see some cloud names." Which is easy to do,
by the way.
Classic.
So, we did that. And along the way,
we came up with this word azure,
which is another word for blue. And so there was a
link to clouds, blue sky clouds, things like that,
but we really presented it based on its
linguistic qualities. It's a noisy word,
that Z in there. It starts with an A, and it ends
in a nice smooth flow. So, we really strive to do
create names that are balanced. And in a very
busy competitive world, having a strong signal,
which is generated by noise is a good thing.
The reaction wasn't good. One of the clients said,
"That's just a dumb idea." Remarks like that.
At this point, after these four decades,
it just rolls off my back like water off a
duck is what my grandmother would say. But
I think along the way, as we talked about it, they
began to warm up to this. And now of course it's,
I don't know, a $100 billion brand or something
like that. But that's an example of, "I haven't
seen that before. I'm very comfortable with cloud.
Cloud is what it is. We're describing it." But
that's a statement. And I think that... Well, I
don't think I know that's what I said in one of
the presentations is, "You don't want to make
a statement here. You want to start a story."
And Azure is going to behave differently in
the marketplace than Cloud Pro, which is I
think one of the names that we presented to
them on the other site at their request.
I'm glad they went with Azure. Let me actually
ask this question. I know you're biased,
but just how important is a great name? If you
had a better name than a product that was better
than you, does that make a big difference?
Just anything you can share there to help
people see this is the power of a great name.
Let's look just at the reality of this. Your brand
name, whether it's a product name or a company
name, nothing's going to be used more often or
for longer than that name. Design will change,
messaging will change, products will change,
but that name is there. So, I like to talk
about this idea of cumulative advantage.
Over time, as people buy more and more
of the product, they see it more often,
that their bond between you and that
brand, or them and the brand I should say,
becomes stronger and stronger. So you want that
name to stick in their mind to be distinctive,
because distinctiveness is what
creates that cumulative advantage.
The second thing is this notion of what I call
asymmetric advantage. It makes perfect sense,
and most clients agree with this when we say
this is that even before you launch this brand,
why not start with an advantage in
the marketplace? And you won't get
an advantage if you're descriptive. If you are
Cloud Pro and there's 10 other cloud services,
you're not going to stand out in the marketplace.
You won't have the ability to create necessarily
that cumulative advantage in the marketplace.
So, those are my two reasons why names are,
I think, done right. And we do talk about
our mission is not creating good names.
A lot of people can do that. Our mission
is to create the right name for clients,
because the right name does deliver asymmetric
advantage and cumulative advantage for you. And
that, for us, has almost unlimited value.
This is a great answer. Essentially what you're
saying is it's not going to necessarily
make or break you, but it gives you an
advantage. A great name gives you an advantage,
especially if you're just getting started.
You need every advantage you can get.
Exactly. And this is maybe a little bit off
a tangent, but one of the best books on marketing
I've ever read, which is not a book on marketing,
and you may have read it along the way
in college if you studied any Greek or
classics. It's called the Melian Dialogues. And
it's a dialogue... It'll take anybody listening
to this maybe 25 minutes to read it. Between
the Athenians and the government of Melos,
the Athenians had decided that they needed that
island. And they went and approached them very
nice way, that, "We want to take over the island.
Nothing will change. You'll be taxed a little bit,
but we'll protect you." And the Athenians had
thought every aspect about how to take that island
before. So by the time they got there, they had
created asymmetric advantage in terms of ships,
and men, and all of this other stuff.
By the way, in the book, there's no
mention of marketing or brand strategy or
any of these things, but if you read it,
you begin to see that it's marketing, really,
is about a symmetric advantage. And so,
why not start from the very beginning with
an advantage? That's the value of a name.
Let's dive into the actual process you
guys go through, and I want to read
a quote that Guillermo Rauch shared when I asked
him about what it was like working with you. He's
the CEO and co-founder of Vercel, which you guys
worked with. I definitely want to hear that story,
by the way. So he said, "Before David, the
ability to name something was like charisma.
You either have it or you don't. It was so surreal
to watch his team distill it down to a science."
So let me just ask you, what does that science
look like? What are the steps to coming up
with an amazing name for your product
or company that you guys go through?
That's very nice of Guillermo. He is a very
impressive innovator in this category and
we greatly enjoyed working with him. Well, our
process is real. I break it down in three steps.
First, we have to identify, then we invent,
and then we implement. It's just three things.
It's not rocket science, but it's a combination
of creativity and discipline. And obviously,
talented people and experience in these things.
So, let's just go through those things. In the
first section of identify, it's really trying
to find out from the client, let's talk about
behavior. So, how are you behaving now and how do
you want to behave in the future? That behavior is
bidirectional. In other words, the marketplace
behaves towards a Vercel, that's the name we
created for Guillermo. And they behave towards
the marketplace. And that's an important point
because everything... Buildings are bidirectional.
Look at a building, you behave differently towards
a temple than you or a church versus a Holiday
Inn in terms of how that architecture states. So,
we focus on that. Behavior is closely
aligned for us with experience. How
do you want the experience of this brand?
Now, when we listen to those things, we begin to
think about rhythm of the name. So something like
Dasani has a lot of rhythm to it, right? It's kind
of calming. And so, we'll begin to extract things
from that discussion on experience. We will then,
also, as part of this first phase, look at the
competition. We call that developing a landscape.
And we're looking for what are the words... What
are the brand names, first, and then what language
are they using in this space? Because we have to
be distinctive. If a brand name isn't distinctive,
you lose. Then, you're imitating. And that's
a form of suicide. That's a famous quote from
some... I think the president of P&G 50 years
ago or something like that. So, that's that first
phase which allows us to create what we call a
creative framework. And we don't even use the word
objectives here because that gets too logical.
Actually, framework for us is a metaphor for a
window for us, and our teams, and our linguists
to travel through. To open things up so that we're
not coming back with a narrow list of names.
We're coming back with names that have depth,
and breadth, and have different experiences
and personalities to them. And clients will
sign off on that. And then, we get going.
So now, we're moved to the invent stage.
And in the invent stage, we do really two things.
You can look at this as two layers of our process.
I think the second layer is probably what makes us
quite unique in the marketplace. It's the result
of millions of dollars of R&D on our part.
So the first thing is, no surprise to anyone,
we work with creative individuals. And we don't
use... This will be contrary. We don't use large
brainstorming sections. I did. When I first
started the company, I used freelancers, I
used large brainstorming groups. And along the way
through some analysis, we really discovered that
that was not really working for us. That actually,
the names were coming from employees and from
small groups. And so we've moved our process to,
at least, two or three small teams of two people.
And each of those teams... So let's say on
significant projects, we always use three teams.
And each team gets a different briefing. One team
knows everything about the project but the other
teams don't. If we're working for Microsoft,
the second team thinks they're working for
Apple. I mean, they know it's disguised. We're not
keeping this from anyone. And then the third team,
we take it out of computers, and they might be
naming a bicycle or a car or something like that.
What we're trying to do is open up the coffers
of creativity for this. And so when people
are working on what they know is not the real
assignment, they are now free to make all kinds of
mistakes. And so, most of our names have come out
of the second or third team because they're-
Wow.
Yeah. I think the process,
at some point, I will hopefully write either a
good article on this or maybe even a book. But
this process would work for, I think, a lot of
things. I know it would. All right now, what's
that second layer that I talked about? Well, we
have made significant investments in this area of
linguistics and cognitive science, and it's in
two ways. One, building proprietary knowledge.
So we know through research that we funded,
an extensive amount about an area in language
called or linguistics called the sound symbolism.
So, what are the sounds of the 26 letters of the
alphabet and what do they do? How do they evoke
things? Well, it turns out that each of those
letters sends out a signal that creates a certain
sort of vibration, if you will, or experience.
Now, there's been research on that over the years
but there were some gaps, and we decided to fill
this. And over the years, we've had a very good
relationship with Stanford University, with their
Department of Linguistics. We've hired linguists
from MIT, from Berkeley. We have a linguistic
internship here. I actually just ran this number,
preparing for this discussion. We have employed,
over four decades now, 253 linguists. Most of
them PhDs, some of them contracts, some of them
actual employees. That's a lot of intellectual
knowledge. So we really have, what I call,
a linguistic engine here. And then we now have
an operating network of... I just checked on
this figure yesterday. We have 108 linguists in 76
countries that help us. Some of them do creative
work, others will do just the analysis of names
for us. So now, we have that creative framework,
we have creative teams working on this.
Now, we're tapping into databases that have
over 18,000 small word units, technically called
morphemes. So, we also can tap in from a sound
standpoint. What are the sounds of reliability?
What are the sounds of aliveness? And so with
Sonos, by the way, we wanted things that are
somewhat noisy. And so S is a noisy letter, like a
Z or even a V. And so, you begin to set priorities
about what letters we're going to use. And that
work from that, we call it an engineering layer
floats up into the creative teams. And so, it's a
mixture of things at a certain point in time.
All right. Now, what happens to all that?
At a certain point, usually 3 to 4 weeks into
this, we might have 2 or 3,000 ideas. I say ideas
because they're not all solutions, they're not
all workable. They may be just beginning ideas,
concepts. And we sift through those. And now
one of the major challenges that we face,
and certainly our clients face, is the need
to clear a trademark for it to be not in
conflict with a marketplace that is... We're
almost reaching a tipping point in terms of
difficulty of clearing names here. And so we have
paralegals here, and we have a trademark attorney,
and we'll analyze those names. That gets us
to a much smaller set. And then, we'll do our
linguistic work with our linguists, and we end
up with a set of names to show our clients.
We'll do this twice with most assignments.
Sometimes, we'll do just one time depending
on timing and budget. But we really try to get
two cycles here, partly because humans love to
compare. If you're looking for a house, you don't
just look at the first house and say, "Okay, let's
sign us up." You look and you learn that we don't
need a swimming pool, but we do need a view. It's
the same with names. And so, we get feedback from
our clients. And sometimes, that's a co-creative
process where a client will come up with a word
or a solution and we'll then run that through our
screening mechanisms for them. And that's really
the process. The final phase is implementing.
Let's actually pause at that because I would, so
much, I want to talk about with the second step,
but we'll get to the step three. They're
just blowing my mind, all the things you
guys do here. This is incredible. There's so many
things here that are so unlike what I expected.
First of all, the creative folks that are actually
coming up with these names, what's the background
of these people? Who are these people?
So, the fundamental quality is they're going to
be curious and they're going to be hardworking.
This is... And hopefully... And this is hard to
screen for, but lower egos. This is unlike the
advertising business which I came from, so I've
six years at a large agency. Where a creative
person or a copywriter can think about something
and come in with 3 or 4 alternatives in terms of
a headline or body copy. And that might be refined
a little bit and maybe sent back to the drawing
boards altogether, but it's a relatively simple
process. And no disrespect intended there.
Here, I can't just sit down and say, "Okay,
we're naming a new car here. And so, I'm going
to generate 100 names and you generate 100 names,
and something will fall out." Those names will
not... There's not enough in that list to clear
through our screens. Of legal screens,
our linguistic screens. And remember,
we start with a creative framework and a
criteria that the names need to meet. So,
we're looking for people who can churn out
a lot of work. And when that's rejected,
they just keep going. So, we look for tenacious
people. Now, we have... And we'll probably get to
this later, but we have software here that
helps people generate names. Not really...
Maybe five years down the road, it'll actually
spit out solutions, but now it's helping us to
generate ideas and directions and what I...
Sound symbolism, ideas, word unit, prefixes,
suffixes, things like that. So, it's relatively
easy for anyone that works here to develop a list
of 2 or 300 names over a 3 or 4-day period.
Where do we find these people? More who are
writers from newspaper reporters because they
have to work fast. Their stories get rejected.
People who might have written a novel. We
have hired people from agencies over the
years. They work a little less effectively than
others who have a speechwriter from... I wrote
speeches in Washington. Those people have
to work hard, crank out a lot of material,
get rejected. Candidate says, "I don't like
this, start over." Those are more resilient
people. That's where they come from. It's not
easy to find these people. It really isn't.
Let me just throw out here. I'm going to
ask you after we go through this process,
what people that don't have the resources and
time to do this, what they should do to come
up with a good name. I'm just going to let
people know as they're listening because-
Sure.
... I imagine many people are wondering,
but let's not go there yet.
Okay.
How long does this process usually take? What's
the ideal length the company should expect when
they want to come up with an amazing name?
For us, the ideal link is pretty short. It's eight
weeks. For larger corporate projects where you
have boards and a little more politicking to do,
and a few more presentations, it's a three-month
churn. And sometimes by the time they approve
things and clear, it's a four-months process.
Okay, cool. So eight weeks mostly if you're
a big company with a lot of red tape.
You have to work through then longer.
Okay, this point you made about three
different teams with different almost
context is so interesting. So say, let's use
Windsurf as an example, which is an amazing name,
killing it, that you guys helped come up with. So
is the idea there, okay, here's we're naming this
AI IDE. One of the team has told, "No, you're
building a bicycle. Here's all the same brief,
but it's a bicycle. And then another team, you're
building a..." I don't know, lap. I don't know,
something non-technical essentially, right?
Yes.
Like, a cup. Say more about that because that is
amazing because. And you're finding that most of
the best names come from the groups that
aren't... Let's name an amazing AI IDE.
This is a good example. So in technology, there
are some things that if someone hands you a new
phone and you look at it and it's tangible and
it's got a shape and color, things like that,
easier to name. But the name of Windsurf,
before it was Windsurf, was Codium. So,
it's all about a type of code or a process for
coding. That's intangible. And even though we
do an awful lot of technology work, it is still
hard for us to really get ahold of what that is.
So our rule here is if there's something that is
intangible like that, we have to make it tangible.
And sometimes we do that not by giving a team,
sometimes it's an individual, the assignment
to create ideas for the brand itself, but
to just dive into a particular context.
And in this case with Windsurf, this is about
flow about giving people that are coding something
much more of a flow process, a smoother process,
a more dynamic process. So in that case,
One team was just given the task of we want
to look at a list of all the things that can
communicate either in a real word like flow or
metaphorically or in a sport about that kind of
dynamics. That kind of movement. And there was
Windsurf sitting on a list. I mean, sometimes,
this is really just that simple. Of course,
you have to have the right framework and you
have to give the right directions to someone.
And Windsurf, for us and particularly for me,
it checks all the boxes. It's a wonderful
image, it's an experience. Literally, a physical
experience. It's a compound, right? Two words put
together. We know from the research we've invested
in that compounds like Powerbook or Facebook are
multipliers of associations because there's wind
and there's circles around that, and then there's
surf images around that. So 1 + 1 = 3, right?
It's interesting that when we present compounds
to clients, we often get the comment, "Well,
it's a little bit long and it's a compound.
I'd rather have a shorter single word." And
then that's why we actually did research
on just how effective our compounds so we
could pass that information along. We passed
that along to the team at that time. Codium,
by the way, could not have been a more
intelligent, nicer, more respectful team
that we've worked with. I'm so glad for their
success. But we explained to them about the
multiplier effect of compounds. We showed
them imagery that they could use. I mean,
it's simple to execute on something like that. And
so, that's how that came about. I'll stop there
and see if you need more information or not.
Let me actually follow this through real quick.
It's going to be kind of a tangent. You guys
have been working with AI companies more and
more recently, which is so interesting.
What's different about naming AI products
from traditional products, not AI, I guess?
First off, we are working mostly with engineers,
and engineers who haven't delved into the
world of creativity and necessarily marketing.
And that's their strength. And what we have to
do is we have to balance their strength with our
strength. So there's a little bit of a challenge
there, but I think we deal pretty well with that.
Secondly, this is the fastest moving progressing
category I have ever experienced. And I have that
perspective, right? I went through the early
days of the internet and the World Wide Web,
and that was moving pretty fast. But the internet
compared to this looks like a daycare school or
something like that. We're challenged by just
keeping up with developments. Third thing,
and this is the creative challenge here, is that
engineers come to us wanting more sophisticated
names where they are likely to end up with
another Codium or an Anduril or an Anthropic.
And when we saw this trend of that AI is going
to take off, and it was an intuitive feeling
on my part. I could have been wrong. I said,
"Let's find out what's going on here." So both,
not only who's developing the products, but how
do people think about AI? And we did a series of
research. I probably invested $20,000 or so. And
we interviewed consumers in Europe, South Korea,
just picked out one country in Asia, and in
America, and developers in those three. And
they really have different views. Developers are
all totally positive on it. They see the future,
they see a big future, not too concerned, some
are, but most aren't. Consumers are skeptical,
worried about it, worried about their jobs,
see the hope in it, those types of things,
but haven't got the handle on it.
So Codium is an example where we said,
"We think what you're doing needs to be much more
tangible, and something that people can grab onto,
and much more natural as opposed to a
Codium." And they listened to us. Very
simple as that. And in this case, we were
right. And by the way also, I have to say,
there's some luck to this. Windsurf happened
to be available and they sought right away,
not exactly right away but it took about a week
going back and forth to select it. So, let me stop
there and see if that answers your question.
Absolutely. And it feels like most AI companies
end up having a different name for
their product than their company.
I've noticed this funny trend cursor was
any sphere bold with stack is StackBlitz,
Windsurf is Codium. Basically, everyone.
When does it make sense to change your name?
Windsurf just officially changed their entire
company name to Windsurf from Codium. It was
just a product. So, let me just ask you that.
When does it make sense? It feels like a huge
deal and a very challenging thing to do.
It is challenging. And the larger you are
and the more customer base you have,
it becomes a significant project.
So the first thing is you have to make an
argument that it's worth the change. That
we're going to be better off by changing our
name. So, there's a couple situations where
you want to change your name. First one is let's
focus first on startups. Startups get going early,
they get into Y Combinator or something like that,
they're raising money. And they just need a name.
And although they know what they're doing,
and that may change by 10 or 15 degrees,
it's almost like, "We just got to have a
name." And that is the absolute expression
I hear from when a startup calls and says, "We
want to change your name. We started off a year
and a half ago. We just needed a name for the
documents, and so we chose X." And it's not a
very good name. So, that's example number one.
Number two is the company actually has pivoted.
And so, the name that they have no longer really
reflects who they are or who they're becoming, and
which makes that name ineffective. And the third
is that a company has merged and it is time now to
create a new start and reflect to the marketplace
that we're... We're new now, maybe bigger,
but certainly we have more capabilities and we
want you to know about it. And because of that,
we're changing our to blank, which reflects
those capabilities at some level.
I'm excited to have Andrew Luo joining us
today. Andrew is CEO of OneSchema, one of
our longtime podcast sponsors. Welcome, Andrew.
Thanks for having me, Lenny. Great to be here.
So, what is new with OneSchema? I know that you
work with some of my favorite companies like Ramp
and Vanta and Watershed. I heard you guys launched
a new data intake product that automates the hours
of manual work that teams spent importing, and
mapping, and integrating CSV in Excel files.
Yes. So, we just launched the 2.0 of OneSchema
FileFeeds. We've rebuilt it from the ground up
with AI. We saw so many customers coming
to us with teams of data engineers that
struggled with the manual work required to
clean messy spreadsheets. FileFeeds 2.0 allows
non-technical teams to automate the process
of transforming CSV in Excel files with just
a simple prompt. We support all of the trickiest
file integrations, SFTP, S3, and even email.
I can tell you that if my team had
to build integrations like this,
how nice would it be to take this off our roadmap
and instead use something like OneSchema.
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many horror
stories of outages from even just a single bad
record in transactions, employee files,
purchase orders, you name it. Debugging
these issues is often like finding a needle in
a haystack. OneSchema stops any bad data from
entering your system and automatically
validates your files, generating error
reports with the exact issues in all bad files.
I know that importing incorrect data can cause all
kinds of pain for your customers and quickly
lose their trust. Andrew, thank you so much
for joining me. If you want to learn more, head
on over to oneschema.co, That's oneschema.co.
I want to come back to this linguist piece,
which I know is really unique to the way you guys
operate, and it's so interesting. So you employed,
you've said, over 250 linguists over the course
of your business career. This linguist step, the
way you described it is they're not coming up with
names, they're more kind of like a filter for,
"Here's all the names we've come up with. Here's
the ones that are good linguistically." Is that
right? Or is that team also suggesting names?
Yeah. Some of the people there, depending on the
assignment, will actually help us create names,
for sure. And so, we have linguists here.
And in the network, we have linguists. And
those linguists are contracts to us, not full-time
employees. So, there's a little bit of both. But
the preponderance of their work in our linguistic
network is to evaluate names. Not only just does
it mean something negative or positive, but are
there cultural implications to it? Political
implications? Or even things that a natural
disaster that would've happened somewhere that no
one here would know about. Even if we had, if.
This was in Italy, and there was a bridge
or a flood that killed a lot of people.
Someone that speaks Italian very well here,
say at Berkeley University, but has lived
here for 20 years, wouldn't know about that.
And we don't want anything linguistically
that would slow our clients down. And so,
that's why we've invested in building this
network. We have a woman that runs the network
for it. So, it's not an insignificant facet of
our business that we have to run and manage.
Is there a name you love that didn't pass the
linguistic filter, that ended up being like,
"Oh, shit. That's a really
bad name in this culture"?
It happens frequently where we will find
something that isn't really terrible but it's
worrisome to us. It's interesting cultures like
Australian or people in Australia, they have a
lot of interesting expressions. And so, we do find
things that this sounds like it's a certain kind
of shrimp and things like that, and we eliminate
those things. And then we find things that have
sort of sexual connotations, we eliminate those.
I would say it happens every third or fourth
project we'll find something that we will
eliminate and never show the client.
And something you love and you're like,
"Okay, I guess we can show that one"?
That's true. That happens. It does.
You also said this really interesting
thing about how every letter of the alphabet
has a vibrance in an experience. Can you give
a few examples of that? I know you're not
the person doing that work specifically,
but just what are some letter feelings?
The work is from the linguist, but at this point,
I'm pretty adept in it. So, let's look at...
I'll start with the letter V because it is so
illustrative of what this is about. V, from our
research that we've done, is the most alive and
vibrant sound in the English alphabet. And
that's whether you were born in Rome or in
Sausalito, California. So if you know that,
if you know that as you go around the world,
there are going to be some exceptions to
it. It's going to have that vibrancy. Look
at Corvette. They probably didn't know about V,
but it's a perfect name for a car that's fast and
has a big engine that roars. Think about Viagra,
same idea. And there's been surprises to us. B,
the sound of the letter B is one of the most
reliable sounds in the English alphabet.
That was one of our rationales, by the way, for
Blackberry. Because that's another example of a
client who thought we were... I mean, the founder
actually said, "I thought the people at Lexicon
were crazy," when they presented Blackberry.
And we said, "Well, let's stop and look at some
of the assets here. First off, black color's
technology. Yes, not everybody knows the word
berry, but we have those two Bs." We talked about
the nature of a compound. And all of a sudden,
people at least lean forward to consider it as
opposed to rejecting it too fast. So, those are
just two examples. I mentioned Z in Azure, that's
noisy letter. X is fast and crisp as a sound. And
of course, there's semantic value to all of these
letters, too. X is about innovation from aircraft
to computers. And so, you have to look at the
semantics of it and the sound symbol of it.
This is so fascinating. I could listen to this
stuff all day. Just thinking about Vercel with the
V, that very aligns with what they're trying to
do. Just very strong, opinionated way of working.
And Guillermo, he feels like a V person.
He is. And there's an example of a group that had
a lot of confidence, and what their product is is
very innovative. And so, we had permission there
to create something new because Vercel is a coin
solution., right? But notice that we put some very
simple, easy to process things together there.
Or ver, in this case. So we have in vino veritas,
truth in wine, things like that. You have verde,
green. So, very familiar. And then their cel, like
accelerate, something which is really what they
do. They accelerate a client's performance. So,
that was a relatively easy name for us to present
and we were excited about for them to grasp.
By the way, that's known as processing
fluency, which is when you think about
how the brain processes information. We're told
by a number of cognitive science that our brains
are a little bit on the lazy side. We don't
like complex things. And so, we really strive
to make all of our solutions relatively easy for
the brain to process. So it wants, it leans in
towards them as opposed to, "I'm too busy. I'm
walking past that." Names that are complicated,
it's a liability. And we really avoid
that. But Vercel, perfect fluency.
Okay, let's go back, actually, to the three
steps. So we covered two, and it took us on a long
tangent to dive into a lot of the stuff you shared
with the second step, which you call invent. So,
it's essentially the three steps are... Was it
create? What would you call it? The step?
Yeah, it's identify. Invent.
Identify.
And I use the word invent with intention because
it's more than creative. And then the final thing
is implement. Now for us, we're not a design
firm. We're really focused on brand names and
the nomenclature that supports the name. But
for us, implement is helping the client team,
if they choose, for us to help them with
the presentations as it goes up the chain.
To help them write a longer rationale for why
these names, if they're presenting three names
to the president of their company or the CMO, why
these names make a lot of sense, and to help them
develop what we call prototypes. So we'll put
the name on a baseball cap, on a T-shirt. We'll
put the name in a mock-up ad in the Wall Street
Journal. Something's very positive. Because of
Procter & Gamble's new blank product. P&G shares,
they gain 10% this year. So that executives can
see that the lift that that name can have.
That's our implementation phase for them.
And we also do consumer research or customer
research at that stage, and we do that probably
about 50% of the time on our projects where
we're going out and we're really talking to
their customers, and putting the names in a series
of drills. Drills that make them not the marketing
person for the day, but we're really making these
customers feel that this is a new brand. And then,
we're asking about expectations. We're seeing
how these names fire their imagination. And
that's the most important thing in research, not
is the name popular, are they comfortable with it,
does it fit to concept. If you're asking people
is this fit to concept, you are inevitably
always going to get a descriptive name.
You make such a good point about how you need
to arm the people working with you with ammo to
win over other folks internally. Because if the
person working with you is on board and the name
is bold and not an obvious winner, I could see
it being important to be like, "Here's what you
should all show them to help them see the story,
and the mock-ups, and all of that."
Yes. And what's really important is to
help their management see this in the context of
the marketplace and their customers. This is a
very human thing, but people want their boss
to be happy. They want to be okay with their
boss. And so they're thinking about, "I don't
know if my boss would like this." He's more
conservative or she's more conservative.
We try in a very diplomatic way to say,
"This has nothing, really, in the end to do with
your boss. It has to do with the marketplace."
Well, that's easy for me to say because I'm not
working at a P&G or an Intel, but we really try
to give that advice for it because it is about
being successful in the marketplace. And so
first of all, we try to separate the clients
that we work with. We really want to work with
clients that play to win, that want to win, not
just want to not lose in a marketplace. And so,
we try to encourage our direct clients to lead
the process to really say, if a manager or a CMO
or a president says, "Look, we're the team that's
going to execute on this and we believe in this.
We can make this work," they usually rally around
it. They usually do. But if you're just taking
names up to a manager and saying, "What do you
think?" There's a different outcome offered.
So, we like to be in that implementation
phase because we have so much experience.
And usually, credibility with people.
And you said that you come up with 3 to
4,000 names. That's the top of the funnel?
Yeah. And just to clarify that, it's ideas,
directions. It's not-
Complete ready-to-ship names.
Yeah, not ready-to-ship names at all.
Got it.
This is a very inefficient process and a
little chaotic. So in that list of 3,000
names is probably 250 potential diamonds
that have to be fractured and examined.
I really want to see just a documentary of this
process at some point. This is the closer we're
going to get for now, but this is so interesting.
I want to ask about how you would approach this if
you're just a startup that doesn't have the time
or resource to do this. But before I do that,
is there anything else around the process
that you guys go through with clients that
you think is important to share or
they think might surprise people?
I think we've covered it. I do.
Okay, great. Awesome. Okay, so most people
listening to this, there's a lot of founders, a
lot of PMs on product teams. They're working on
a new feature, they're about to launch a product,
they got accepted into YC and they're about to
launch a product. Then they have, I don't know,
let's say they have a couple of weeks. We've got
to come up with a name. What should they do?
So the first thing I do is to say, okay, let's
forget about developing the name for right now.
And I will have them, and I think this is a good
exercise for anybody. We do it here internally
when we think about our business. So I say,
just... Because most of this now, because of
COVID, is on video. And I will say, "Just draw
a shape of a diamond on a piece of paper in front
of you." And I said, "On the top of that diamond,
put the word win. How do you define winning
is really it?" I said, "Now on that other
next corner of the diamond, what do you have to
win? Write that down. On the bottom, what do you
need to win? And then on that final angle on the
left-hand side, what do you have to say to win?"
Then I said, "Now, let's go all the way to that
final thing of what do you have to say to win."
And that's where you just get people thinking
about, "Well, what we really have here is...
And we're better than this." And then I'll just
say, "Okay. Now, what you want to take that this
really should be about experience and behavior.
How do you want to behave in the marketplace? How
do you want the marketplace to behave towards you?
And what kind of experience are you creating?" And
then they'll start talking a little bit. I'll
say, "Now, you just need to probe on that. You
need to keep going. You need to look at metaphors
because this is about experience." And I'll just
give them some of our examples that we've talked
about, "Blackberry, it says to the marketplace,
they're not like the other guys." Think
of something like Google versus Infoseek,
right? Google is an experience. Google says,
"I don't know what these guys are going to do,
but it's not this practical mundane
Infoseek." And that's what attracts people.
And so I'll do a little coaching like that,
and then that usually kind of sets them free.
And they're now thinking about it not as
a word, which has maybe limited value,
but as creating an experience which has
the potential for unlimited value.
Okay. So, let me try to reflect this back for
folks. So the advice is draw triangle. So, you're
coming up with a name. Draw triangle. At the top,
win. At the bottom-left, was it how do you win?
Yeah. So, the diamond is two triangles.
Oh, diamond. Okay, I see. I have triangle in my
mind.
I got you.
Okay, got it. Diamond. Great.
And so on that next angle there
on the right side is, what do you have to win
already? Right? Because they wouldn't be either
in a Y Combinator or getting some seed money if
they didn't have something to win. And often,
people, startups don't appreciate how much
they actually do have to win because they're
so busy and so stressed on what they're doing. And
then, what do they need to win? And then finally,
what do you need to say? And then back up
to defining what is winning to us? Which,
by the way, we start with that question
usually on an assignment that we've been
awarded. And if we're in a room with five
people, all five people have a different
definition of what... Their definition of that
company winning. And that's good to sort that
out because we can move down different
avenues from a creative standpoint.
Let's just make sure people have these
phrases because this is awesome. And I
imagine many people are going to be taking
notes and like, "Cool. I'm going to do this."
I hope so say the four points of the diamond
again just so folks can write it all down.
At the top of the diamond is just the word win,
and underneath that is how do we define winning
for us as a company. And that can start off being
simple, like we want to be the dominant player
here. But you really have to work at that. What
does that really mean, right? The second on that
right-hand tip there of the diamond is what do we
have to win? What are we doing now that makes us
a winner? Then we go down to the bottom of the
diamond, and it's what do we need to win? There
could be technical things there. People talk about
talent and resources. Often there, they'll say,
"We need a good name." We always correct that.
It's not the good name, it's the right name.
And then finally is what do we need
to say? And that's where I say,
that's where you want to spend some time in really
thinking about all the things you need to say,
that you can say or you would even like to say,
which maybe right now you can't say. But you
want to a name that actually is going to have
the flexibility as to when you can say that,
it still works. And that gets them into behavior
and experience. And that usually launches a really
a good discussion with founders internally.
When you say you have to win though,
what you're thinking about there is what is it
that you have that will help you win? And then
what is it you need to have this win?
Yes, that's right. And all companies are
in that same situation. They have
a bunch of stuff, but they need...
A P&G might say, "We need a good distributor."
"Okay. All right, we'll put that on the list."
And then you might say, "Well, we need in..."
When it gets to what do we have to say, we have
to say the right things so that a distributor is
interested in us. And then you go down an avenue
there. Well, what is that? And if you work at
it, this is not a one-hour exercise, it may be an
exercise repeated over the next 4 or 5 days.
Okay. So, you have this diamond. And then
the idea is just sit and put names
down in a Google Doc, let's say.
Yeah. And then you start. But there is
this... And maybe, it's naivete. I guess,
that's probably the best word for this is that,
because I do hear this all of the time. "Hey,
we've worked at this, we got a list of 200 names,
but we don't think there's something there."
And I'll say, "Well, 200 names is not enough.
Get to 1,000, 1,500 names and directions.
Don't evaluate them. Just generate names, and
directions, and ideas, and then have a meeting.
And don't evaluate but speculate." What could
we do with this name? What's the potential here?
There's a lot of overevaluation in our industry.
It makes sense. We survive as humans because we
figure out what's wrong with this picture. If I
want to cross the street, is it safe to cross the
street? What's going on? Those kinds of things.
You have to counter that. You have to say, "Let's
just suspend judgment for a while. And let's do
an exercise here where we take these 10 names
that we think might work and what are we going
to do with it." Because it's how you execute.
Going back to windsurf, as we showed them pictures
of people windsurfing and waves and things, if
they said, "Ah, that just doesn't work for us at
all. I'm very uncomfortable with." Well, then it's
not their name. But they leaned into it, "Okay,
I can see this. It's easy for us to execute. It's
dynamic, it's different." So, that's why we build
these prototypes for people. And that's what... I
think the best advice I can give to whether it's a
startup or someone starting a new cookie company,
is it's not just a list of 200 names. It's 10 or
15 lists of 200 names. And it's thinking about
what do we have to say here? What behavior? How
do we want people to feel in the marketplace about
us? I imagine with Google, people felt relief
that it wasn't a descriptive name. That there
was something new out there in the marketplace.
Yeah. Infoseek, that's such a descriptive name now
that I think about it.
Yes.
Okay, so one more question along these lines. So
say, you have a list of let's say 2,000 or 1,000
names. There's this tension between choosing
something... Like, as a person that is doing
them themselves. Your advice is choose something
bold, not something descriptive. You won't know
it when you see it. Very hard to do, obviously,
when you're doing it by yourself. And you just
advise for not losing sight of that piece. Just
throwing out things that feel too scary, finding
a name that's actually bold as you suggest.
First off, we disappear... Human psychology,
humans only pay attention to what is new or what
is different, I should say. So if you're looking
at shoes and they're all black, black, black,
black, and then the next pair of shoes is red,
that's the first thing you focus on. And so, that
usually gives people permission. They'll say,
"Okay, I get that." So, look for what is really
different between the names that you have on your
list, but also what's different from what's out
in the marketplace. Then you get a client like
Microsoft saying, "Azure is different. There's
going to be a lot of cloud stuff and..." There's
a relevant point there, Azure is blue. And so,
there's a slight logical connection that I think
gave them more permission to move forward with it,
frankly. But listen, this is not an easy task. I
mean, that's why we're in this business, and why
I felt we should be specialized because if you
start doing design and/or advertising or other
things, you can't have the intellectual engine.
You can't acquire the intellectual engine that
we have. So I know it's difficult, but it can
be done, and you just have to give yourself some
time. But stop evaluating. Suspend judgment and
speculate. That's my number one advice to people
trying to do this on their own. Now, how can you
get help? You can talk to your employees, but
it's not so much, "What do you think of this
name?" It's, "What do you think this name could
do for us?" That's a much better question. If
you go out and talk to friends who don't work for
your company, there's a fun drill that I suggest.
I said, "Listen, go out to them and say..."
They'll know what you're doing. And say, "You
know what? We just have a new competitor and their
name is blank. What do you think about that?"
What happens there is you're not asking them
to give you an opinion to evaluate a name.
You're asking them then what does that name do for
you? The information you're getting is that name,
they're telling you what that name does for
them, how it helps them to imagine, which is
a fundamental role of any name. Slight tangent,
but I'm going to go to our kind of research. We do
mostly quantitative research now, but for years,
we did qualitative work. And we still do. But what
we found in, we were always looking for the...
I'll set it this way. We were always looking for
this answer from consumers. If a consumer said,
"I don't really know much about that new product,
but I know that they're not like the other
guys." That's when we knew we had a good name
because they were... Now what happened there?
I mean, the technical term that we use is that
name will create a predisposition to consider this
product because they're not like the other guys,
as opposed to, "I already have something
like that. I'm busy. I don't need another
one of those things. I need something new
and different, and hopefully better."
That's awesome. That's a good reminder. There's a
quote that I found of yours that's exactly along
these lines, "If your team is comfortable with the
name, chances are you don't have the name yet."
Yes. And by the way, the opposite of that is we
look for polarization. We look for tension in a
team about arguing about these things, because we
think that polarization is a sign of strength in
the word. And interesting story, the person who
taught me that, honestly, was Andy Grove over the
Pentium name, because... And I learned a lot from
him. I always say this, I just was very fortunate
to work with him on Pentium, and Xeon, and a few
other things. But when we went to an executive
committee to present Pentium... And by the way,
internally, one of the names that... And makes
sense here, descriptive, bunch of engineers,
ProChip. "Hey, it's professional, it's premium,
and it's chipped. So, it should be Prochip."
So Andy had me give a presentation about the
strengths of this thing, and he said, "Now, let
me tell you why I think this is the right name."
He said, "Because I see the polarization here in
it amongst people. There's this ProChip over here,
there's the Pentium thing." He said, "That tells
me there's energy for Pentium here." And he said,
"That's why I think we should go with it."
And I've never forgotten that. And so,
we do look for that. And when we tell that story,
people say, "You're right. There is... I mean,
we are arguing about this, and there is an
intensity with the name." And that's what you
want. You don't want to go out in the marketplace,
into this very competitive marketplace,
regardless of the category, with something that
doesn't have a level of boldness or intensity.
That was an amazing story. Just again, so
kind of a tip here is if half of your team or,
I don't know, some percent of your
team hates it, some percent of your
team loves it, that's a good sign.
Yeah, it is. It is. Look for that
polarization. That's what we look for.
I also love this tip of asking people if,
"Hey, our competitor just launched. They're
called Windsurf." How your team reacts? If
they're just like, "Oh, wow, that's a great name.
I'm interested in that product." That's what you
want to look for?
Yes, exactly.
How important is the .com for the name you
come up with? I imagine it's really hard to
get these days. Just what do you think about
domain name when you think about naming?
I am so glad you asked this question because
at this point, it doesn't really matter at
all. The .com or URL address has become an
area code. And whether you're in 415 or 615,
it doesn't really matter to people. And now with
AI, SEO is going to be less important. And so,
I just think the principle in play here is you
got to get the right name first. And then if
you can get the .com, sure, go ahead. But if
you can't, there's ways around that. You can
put a prefix in front of it or a little word
in front of it or after it, or you go to .ai
or something like that. But the principle
in play is let's get the right name first.
For those who really... And there are
people who really get hung up on the .com,
they tend to older by, the way. And have, in
their mind, sort of the hotness of the internet
and having a .com, which did make a difference
25 years ago. But it's 25 years now or 30,
right? The good news is because they're less
valuable, you can typically buy a URL if you
negotiate the right way and have time for 15, 20,
25, $30,000. And we say, "Hey, if you can do that,
have fun. I'd put the $30,000 into market."
Awesome. That's reassuring. I imagine many
founders are just like, "God dammit,
there's no names available anymore."
Let me zoom out and just ask you this question as
a, maybe, a closing thought to our conversation.
Say you were just in an elevator ride with
someone, and I'm sure this happens to you
of just like, "Hey, David, I got to come up with
that name. What's your biggest tip for coming up
with a great name?" What would your answer be?
I'd go back to forget about the word, think about
behavior and experience. And then the second thing
from just a creative help, I'm a big believer in
synchronicity. And we try to force synchronicity
here, and I'll give you a couple examples of
that. But this idea of connecting dots, two
unrelated ideas together. And so I'll say, "Look,
if someone says we make sailboats and I'm trying
to..." I'm here in Sausalito. I guess, that's why
I thought about that. And I am trying to create
a new name for my company that builds sailboats.
I would say forget about sailboats. I would
go and pick out some magazines about hunting
or flying magazines. And I would just look through
those, get a notepad out, and put out words that
you like. Things, expressions that you like. And
then that synchronicity, I said, "I would bet you
$5 that out of those two magazines, you will
get a word that you never would've thought of,
but somehow it would relate to sailing."
That connects very much to your story of
how you have these different teams, and
the teams that end up coming up with a
winning name are the ones thinking about a
very different version of that product.