You don't have a choice. AI is going to
disrupt in the most aggressive violent
ways. If you're not in it, you're
about to get kicked out of all of it.
You have very successfully shifted late stage
SaaS business to an AI-first agent-based business.
Fin is our AI agent who will pass 100 million
ARR with Fin in less than three quarters.
Let's talk about how you
made this actually happen.
We were about to hit $0 net new ARR, which means
we would've been in negative growth territory.
So, ChatGPT launches. Was it just like this
is it, we got to go all in on this thing?
I said, we need to become a wartime company. If
we don't fight for this, we are dead. I jumped
hard on AI, but I also restarted the culture.
I rewrote the values designed to be a sharp
knife to cut out the parts of the company
that I just knew wouldn't be effective.
If you're trying to make the
shift and it's just not moving,
you may need to go hardcore founder mode.
The way that greatness is created is that you find
a CEO who's willing to make brave
hard decisions and own the results.
What percentage of the employees kind
of turned over during this period?
Ultimately like 40%.
You said there was a soft coup. Is
there more you could share about that?
Today my guest is Eoghan McCabe. This is the first
in a series of conversations that I'm having with
founders who have successfully transformed their
established SaaS or marketplace businesses into an
AI first company that is growing like crazy and
overtaking their decade plus old business. So,
many companies and product teams and founders
are trying to navigate this very tricky time
where every industry is being disrupted by AI,
and my goal here is to help you essentially
disrupt yourself before somebody else does. The
story of Intercom's transformation into Fin is
incredible. Their traditional business was valued
at billions of dollars, was making hundreds of
millions of dollars in ARR, but growth started
to plateau and was even about to go negative.
Six weeks after GPT-3.5 Came out, they had a
working prototype of what is now Fin and Eoghan
and the team decided to go all in on AI.
Today Fin is growing like crazy already
at eight digits in ARR and Intercom is on track
to be growing faster than every public software
company by next year. In our conversation,
Eoghan gets very real and honest about what
it takes to win right now. What do you have to do
to turn the ship around at Intercom in spite of a
lot of pushback and even a soft coup attempt,
what he believes people still don't understand
about what is happening in software and AI
and so much more. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. Also, if you
become an annual subscriber of my newsletter,
you get a year free of a bunch of incredible
products including Lovable, Replit, Bolt n8n,
Linear, Superhuman Descript, Whisper Flow,
Gamma Perplexity, Warp, Granola, Magic Patterns,
Raycast, [inaudible 00:02:42] and Mobbin. Check
it out at lennysnewsletter.com and click
bundle. With that, I bring you Eoghan McCabe.
This episode is brought to you by Great Question
the all-in-one UX research platform. Loved by
teams at Brex, Canva, Intuit and more. One of the
most common things I hear from PMs and founders
that I talked to is I know I should be speaking to
customers more, but I just don't have the time or
the tools. That's exactly the gap Great Question
fills. Great Question makes it easy for anyone
on your team, not just researchers, to recruit
participants, run interviews, send surveys, test
prototypes, and then share it all with powerful
video clips. It's everything you need to put your
customers at the center of your product decisions.
With a prompt as simple as why did users choose us
over competitors, Great question not only reveals
what your customers have already shared, but it
also makes it incredibly easy to ask them in the
moment for fresh insights from the right segment.
Picture this, your roadmap's clear, your team's
aligned, you're shipping with confidence and
you're building exactly what your customers need.
Head to greatquestion.com/lenny to get started.
This episode is brought to you by WorkOS. If
you're building a SaaS app, at some point your
customers will start asking for enterprise
features like SAML authentication and SCIM
provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in, making
it fast and painless to add enterprise features
to your app. Their APIs are easy to understand so
that you can ship quickly and get back to building
other features. Today, hundreds of companies
are already powered by WorkOS, including ones
you probably know like Vercel, Webflow and Loom.
WorkOS also recently acquired Warrant, the fine
grain authorization service. Warrant's product
is based on a groundbreaking authorization system
called Zanzibar, which was originally designed
for Google to power Google Docs and YouTube.
This enables fast authorization checks at enormous
scale while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases.
If you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features
like single sign-on, SCIM or user management,
you should consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in
replacement for Auth0 and supports up to 1 million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
workos.com to learn more. That's workos.com.
Eoghan, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you. Great to be here.
You have done something quite extraordinary
with Intercom, something that a lot of founders
and product teams are trying to do, which
is to navigate this very scary disruption
that's happening as a result of AI to most
businesses. You have very successfully shifted,
as you described, a late-stage SaaS business to
an AI-first agent-based very successful business.
I want to use the time to extract as much
as I can out of your journey so that people
that are trying to navigate this and having a
hard time can have less pain, less suffering
and will hopefully get to something that works.
To give people a sense of just how well things
have gone. Can you share some stats about the
current state of the business, how it's going?
Currently across the business we benchmark
ourselves against all public software companies.
There's like 120 something B2B software companies.
We're like in the 15th percentile for ARR growth,
so we're up there. Fin, which is our AI
agent, which is the future of the business,
the thing that will disrupt the old
business. It's growing north of 300%.
It took off really fast like all these other
AI companies you hear of the first year,
it grew from one to 12 million ARR. We're now
in solid mid eight digit ARR growth there,
we'll pass 100 million ARR with Fin in
less than three quarters. And yeah, Fin,
we're in the customer experience category with
Fin, so it's one of these agents that helps do
all your customer work and they all started
with service and in that category we are the
biggest by customer count, biggest by revenue,
best by performance benchmarks. We win all our
head-to-heads and our direct competitor
bake-offs. We're rated number one on G2,
so I think we're doing pretty well. We're doing
far better than we imagined at this point.
Okay. This sounds like the dream for a lot
of founders, especially ones that are stuck
with their existing business that isn't going
very far. So, let's get to that. Let's talk
about the beginning of this journey. You had
a business that was working, people used it,
loved it, over 100 million ARR I believe.
Talk about just the state of the business at
the point roughly when you decided I really
need to make a big change and go AI first.
It was already in the hundreds of millions,
Intercom is 14 years and change now. Part of
the story is that in 2020 I had been sick for a
couple years. The background is I had mold toxins
and later I found out that I got a tick bite and
that messed me up. And so I left the CEO role in
2020 and a lot of the mistakes I had been making
when I was sick got worse. We became what a lot
of late stage software companies are today,
which is a bit bloated. We lost some energy.
Our strategy was diluted and unfocused. We're
trying to do all the things for all the people.
We didn't know what problems we
were already solving and for who,
and the result was very slow revenue
growth in the low single digit percent
and I was away for two years unsatisfied where the
business was going. We had this post COVID sugar
rush, which a lot of big companies at that stage
did in 2021. Everyone's valuation and revenue was
through the roof and that hit a lot of problems in
a lot of these companies and we had five quarters
of success of sequential decline in our net new
ARR and we were about to hit $0 net new ARR which
means we would've in negative growth territory.
We never got there. I managed to stop it before
we got there, but we were falling each quarter
and I found that I, despite my wishes to go and
have new adventures, still had a lot of pride
for this damn thing and didn't want to see it.
And in a way that was so different from the way it
started, it started with so much hope and optimism
like so many companies do, and it was about to
fade away. So, that was when I felt like I need
to go back and I need to make a change. I went
back and one month later ChatGPT was announced,
so it would be really neat and tidy to be able
to say that the AI transformation came, I knew
I couldn't be on the sidelines, I had to save
this thing from the coming disruption. Actually,
I got whacked across the head by this AI
thing, but it also ended up being a gift.
So, ChatGPT launches, was it just like this is it,
we got to go all in on this thing? Was
it like, hmm, let's watch this thing?
How quickly was it clear that this is the
future, this isn't working what we're doing?
We and I were very lucky and that we had an
AI group already. We were in the customer
communication business, chiefly doing customer
service. We were building bots, but they were
rudimentary AI. We had a bunch of our own machine
learning that did Q&A for customer service, but it
required a phenomenal amount of setup and was kind
of crappy. But we had a number of AI engineers in
the company already, and so when GPT 3.5 came out,
they said, this is different and it didn't take
long for people to start to imagine that this
is going to be pretty disruptive to service.
And it started where we imagined that this was
going to just wreck everyone selling seats,
everyone in the conventional SaaS game.
And we believed that was quite possible for
some couple years after that moment. But we were
only six weeks into the launch of GPT 3.5 when we
actually had a beta version of Fin. I got a text
from Des, my co-founder, a week or so after the
launch of GPT 3.5 and he said, "The AI team have
something interesting and they actually think we
could make a product out of this." And this was
long before there's now no doubt 100 service
agents. We had something very early working and
part of what we had to our advantage also was that
we had this giant base 300, sorry, 30,000 paying
customers, hundreds of thousands of active users,
millions of their users, billions of data points.
So, we had a lot to play with and so we jumped on
it. Now obviously it's fun to tell that once
again to the idea of this brave Maverick move,
and I won't discount the fact that we were brave,
but we were coming from a point of having nothing
to lose. So, we certainly are unique. I don't
know a single company of our size and age that has
pivoted this hard to AI and being as successful
as we have been, but we also previously were
screwed. We were in a really tough spot, so had
no choice. So, I'll take the kudos and credit,
but also have a lot of empathy for companies that
weren't as in as much trouble as we were, and
so try to thread the needle and sustain the old
business while adding to it with the new AI stuff.
Something I heard from someone that worked at
Intercom, correct me if this is not correct,
you've always been very anti-bot in the
customer support business because you
didn't like how impersonal it was. It just didn't
feel like the way you wanted to build a business,
and then now that's what you do.
Talk about just that transition.
Yeah, I know it's a fun and ironic twist. Our
mission from the early days was make internet
business personal. And when I came back and we
started to lean into AI, I started to wonder,
does that mission make any sense anymore?
Now, part of our lean into AI is that we had
no choice not only for the business, we needed
something new, but also we saw that this is the
future and you can't fight the future. You must
be part of it. And so okay, fuck, we're going
to be part of it. And ultimately, and it's very
easy to tell yourself these little stories. So,
I'm open to anyone telling me this is bullshit,
but when I interrogate myself, my soul and my
mind, I don't think it is, when I interrogate
my heart and my mind, I don't think it is.
But I'm now of the belief that providing a
customer with a highly engaged, instantly
available expert, consistent, fast, charismatic,
funny, friendly, personal agent available for
literally every single customer every minute of
the day around the clock is so much more personal
than making them wait 2, 3, 4 days for a crappy
canned response. And so that's the irony and
the magic and the wonder of AI, even if it does
make us ask some hard questions of ourselves and
think carefully about its impact on humanity, it
actually is superior at the things we describe as
personal and human, relative to humans themselves.
And so that's where I'm at today. Yeah, maybe
it's a bunch of fancy post rationalization,
but honestly that's really where I stand.
I think data has shown people often
prefer not to talk to humans just to
solve problems that can just be solved.
It's a lot of stress to try to figure
out how to talk to some support agent that
doesn't know anything about what's going on.
Yes, and the AI is just better. Look at
Waymo. So, Waymo doesn't crash. It has 3.5
times less crashes than humans. It doesn't bother
you or bug you. I like to chat with an Uber driver
as much as the next guy, but not always. It
doesn't have hygiene problems. It doesn't
take wrong turns. I mean it just doesn't
do all these things that really bug people.
And it's really interesting to see Uber now offer
women the option to call only female drivers,
and I guarantee the reason they're doing that is
because women love Waymo because they feel safer.
AI is so often superior and humans are going to
be far better at other things. I'm pro-human,
I love humans. I really want humans
in the mix for all things in the rest
of my life, but when it comes to practical,
productive, efficient, and effective value,
the glue in between the human parts of our
lives, I actually want AI and robotics.
Before we start talking about how you actually
made this transformation a success, one other
piece of history is just your pricing strategy
historically has been not liked by people.
For example, I once had a Twitter poll
or a survey on my newsletter just like
what products do you pay the most for of all
your SaaS products? And Intercom's by far the
most. I know people constantly complain about
just how unclear it was and how high it was,
and now you guys are at the forefront of how to
price AI products. So, we're going to get to that,
but just talk about the lessons and what
happened there with pricing back in the day.
Yeah, so I want to just validate your survey
data. Yes, people abhorred our pricing.
It was a meme. There were actual funny popular
viral memes on Twitter that were making fun of
our pricing. Part of the problem, if not all of
the problem, well, there's two problems. One was
our strategy, super unfocused. As you said, we're
trying to do all the things for all the people,
and when you're trying to do all
the things for all the people,
your efforts to capture all that different types
of value are going to necessitate pretty complex
pricing. If you're like customer service
and you're selling seats and you're doing
outbound messaging and you need to charge for
messages and you're doing like SD or Messenger
on a website and you need to charge for leads,
already that's just metrics in every direction.
And then if you're trying to sell to many
different sizes of customers, you need tiers
and gates and it just became a behemoth. So,
part of the problem was the unfocused strategy,
and then the other part of the problem was an
unwillingness to frankly make bold decisions,
say no, pick a lane and actually take pain
in the short term for the long term. We
rolled out this new pricing, and this is even
before the Fin pricing you're talking about.
When I came back and I said, "Yes, we're going to
lose a lot of revenue here." I can't remember how
much we wrote down, but we actually have already
given away something like $50 million in ARR.
We've reduced the prices for a lot of customers
just to give them way simpler pricing because
surprise, surprise, when people feel like
they have far simpler, more predictable,
fairer pricing, they'll stick around longer and
it creates so much more ease in the company and
promotes a healthier relationship with the
customer too. When our people saw that we
were screwing customers effectively in every
direction, it starts to erode the idea that
we care about our customers and then they
make other customer-unfriendly decisions.
And so one of the values I promoted when I came
back was that we would be customer-obsessed,
and so we had to kill our old pricing
and give away a lot of revenue. So,
that was the spirit behind the changes. But we can
talk about the Fin pricing if you want to also.
Let's save that because that's a really
important topic that I think people need
to hear. Let's talk about the shift and how you
made this actually happen. You make it sound like,
oh, not fully, but it's oh, we have to
do, it wasn't working anyway. There's
no risk to go all in on this AI thing.
You're making $150 million a year ARR,
you're worth at least a billion dollars
at that point as a business. Yeah.
I mean multiple billions.
Multiple billions.
We were making more money than that, so we
were like multiple hundreds of millions.
Yeah, okay. Very difficult to actually
do even if things don't feel like they're
growing anymore. So, first of all, just
what was the moment, if there was one,
of just like, okay, the six-week experiment
of someone building a Fin internally,
was that being like, this is it, or was there
another moment of like, let's go all in on this?
It was the combination of the company being older,
us all, me and the founders being impatient like,
are we going to make something out of
this? We went through a time when the
company was worth a lot. We're private
so we don't have a daily mark to market,
but all the other public software companies
dropped 80%, 85, 90%. We saw our revenue growth
crater. We were used to nice double digits. We
were in low single digits. And so part of it was,
let's do something here. Another part of it was my
own anger and dissatisfaction with how the company
was being run and the mistakes that I made myself.
I made a lot of compromises as a lot of founders
and founding CEOs do to placate employees or do
it out fear to bring investors along, following
advice in the industry and best practices.
You betray your intuition in little bits and
pieces over the years when the bright spark
of your original idea turns into this big,
unstoppable, scary corporate beast and a little
bit of you dies every single time you go and
betray yourself in that way. If you could pick
in your mind three or four tech darlings from 10
years ago when you meet the CEO and talk to them
privately, very few of them feel outstanding about
the state of their culture and the decisions that
they make and the way in which they have to work.
All of them have betrayed themselves in little
ways, and I had left the business, I was super
sick, I was burned out frankly from the revenue
even having started to slow down before I left.
I had been attacked unfairly in the press, just
all of me was just fed up and I decided to take
a very authoritarian, top-down, aggressive
founder-first approach to all the things,
and I found that deeply cathartic and that was
the thing that led to me in part. The other was
just good old-fashioned logic and the other was
desperation saying, we're doing the AI thing,
the AI thing, exciting and sexy. We need some
new energy thing here. The new AI thing makes
sense. And also just my intuition says, go
for it. And so when people tell these stories,
they rewrite history in their minds for
the stories to be elegant and also so
that they support their own self-aggrandized
narratives about their brilliance. Actually,
it's a big messy cocktail of things. And anyway,
that's my attempt at explaining the cocktail.
I saw a stat that when you first launched,
when you first had this kind of prototype,
you were losing money on every transaction
that you're charging like a dollar,
it cost you $120, something like that.
That's right. 120 cents. Yeah, yeah.
120 cents. Okay. So, there's
a lot of vision here if this
is going to get to a place where this
actually will be great and affordable.
It's really funny. We charge 99 cents to resolve
tickets, customer problems, and we have a higher
resolution rate than anyone else, and we are proud
of that and we obsess over that. It is the metric
by which these agents are assessed, and we wanted
our revenue to be 100% aligned with the value that
they attained because we had all this scar tissue
from pricing prior that felt unfair to customers.
So, we said, what's the most fair that we can
possibly find? Now, when we did all our research,
we found that many SaaS businesses were spending
between 20 and $30 per ticket resolved. We
were spending 22. Now, consumer businesses,
maybe they go down to $5. We were thinking,
can we charge $10? That seems fair. It's half
price. Can we charge $5? Can we even charge
two and a half dollars? But early on we started to
sense that people just wouldn't value the digital
work as much as the human work, even though
the digital work is better, more consistent,
always available, makes the customer far happier.
And so we actually started to lean into a price
that we thought would be was the nexus between us
earning the most and it being the most palatable.
We basically said that if someone is not prepared
to pay 99 cent for us to rapidly and elegantly
perfectly and excellently solve their customer's
problem, we need to wrap this up. We don't have a
business here. So, that was where the 99 cent came
from. I always believe that that pricing should
come from value and not from costs. The cost is
our problem. We just had this sense and intuition
early on that this thing will get cheaper and it
got a lot cheaper. The margin moves around, but we
make a margin that makes this more than worth our
while, and we know our customers get an excellent
deal and are able to deliver to their customers
a level of service that they never could before.
It's a very clear pitch. We just had
Madhavan the podcast and the pricing expert,
and he has this phrase, beautifully simple
pricing is where you want to get to. Also,
he's a huge fan of outcome-based pricing,
which is what you're describing here,
where you pay for an outcome. So, you guys are
in the magic quadrant of his pricing advice.
Yes, thank God our pricing wars are over.
Finally.
Yeah.
Okay, so going back to how you
actually did this thing. So,
basically you described what many people think of
now as founder mode, just top down, as you said,
the third area, and just here's what we're
doing. We're not going to sit around waiting
for you to give me ideas. What did you
do? What did that look like internally?
There was a couple of things. One was we
were burning a lot of money, so I cut a
lot of costs aggressively. Canned a bunch of
different projects. We had this big glorious
office we were about to fit out and I'm like,
we're about to hit negative growth territory,
stop it. And a lot of companies were really
stuck in the prior world where they just
were used to being super successful, rich and
wealthy and spent like drunken sailors. So,
I stopped all of that, got really frugal in
ways I never thought I would. I still haven't
touched the interior design of this office. I'm
in here, even though I call it the hotel Marriott,
I'm sick of it. Anyway, that was one. Another
was picked a lane. Strategically we were all
over the place and I said, "We're doing service."
Zendesk had been acquired a couple years prior.
They were strategically, energetically, culturally
dead. They were upsetting customers in the
market. There's an opportunity there. We're
doing service, forget all the other stuff,
even though there was a lot of people in the
company saying, well, shit, we still have $80
million of ARR that we're getting from the other
thing and we're really good at that, and there's
a big opportunity. There's other companies in this
space worth billions. It was the type of decision
that where I had to practice the professional
CEO approach, which is, "Hey folks, what do you
all think? Let's take everyone's input. Let's
put it all down on a spreadsheet." Everyone
had color beside all of the different options that
we may take. Let's make a group decision. I said,
"Sorry, this is what we're doing." So,
I was very dictatorial in that respect.
We had no one making decisions, so somebody
needed to, even if I had some qualms about
the decisions myself, I couldn't predict
the future, but someone had to make a call.
Obviously as soon as AI came around, I jumped
hard on AI and announced that we were going to
spend nearly $100 million of our own cash
on that. We allocated a lot of capital,
but I also restarted the culture. We had just a
very comfortable culture as a lot of companies
did. There was a lot of focus on social issues
and a lot of complaining and dissatisfaction,
and I rewrote the values designed to be a sharp
knife to cut out the parts of the company that
I just knew wouldn't be effective. So,
I said that people must be resilient,
that we had very high standards, that we'd work
incredibly hard, that shareholder value was the
most important thing that we'd optimize for. A
lot of things that were controversial for this
prior crowd. And then I designed these quarterly
performance processes where not only would you get
a mark or a grade for your performance against
your goals that quarter, but you'd also get a
score for your behavior against the values.
And I hard coded a formula myself, and so I
took it out of the manager's hands to say, if
people got below a certain mark, respectfully
and lovingly, we would say, thank you for your
service. We're going to go forward without you.
And so you do that just a small number of quarters
and you can start to shape an organization that's
design and the image of the values you want to
create. And obviously there was a lot of pain,
a lot of satisfaction. There was attempts at
soft coup, there was letters sent to the board,
people really unhappy, but on the other side
of it, the people left were the most incredible
entrepreneurial, brave, inspiring, happy
individuals you could possibly imagine. And
then you hire in their image. We ran an anonymous
employee survey, I think 15 or 16 months after I
started aggressively working through the org and
rebuilding the org and rebuilding the culture,
and we had a 98 to 99% approval of
management, leadership and new strategy.
And this is coming from me having the lowest
Glassdoor rating for a CEO I had ever seen when
I came back. So, I just want to explain that being
that deliberate about your culture and upsetting a
lot of people is the path through which you can
create a culture where people are super happy,
super engaged, super aligned, and now we have
just this highly performant organization. Yes,
we're messy in many ways. So, that was a big
part of it too. So, it was kind of strategically
picking a lane. Remaking how we go to market,
the pricing was a really, really big piece that
had a big effect. Betting on AI and then culture.
And I kind of buried the AI thing because frankly
none of this would matter if we didn't bet on AI.
So, the story could all be summed up by saying,
when you ask what did I do, it was that
we built Fin and that changed everything.
You said that this was very unpopular. I imagine
many people were not happy with all
the change and how top-down this was,
you said there was a soft coup. Is there more you
could share about that? I never heard that story.
When you make that degree of change and you
tell people that they're in control like we
did in the previous generation of late-stage
businesses, there's going to be some friction
when you change the rules. And it's my strong
belief that great employees and great companies
want and are constructed out of a very clear and
strong hierarchy where it is the responsibility
of the CEO to make brave and hard decisions
unilaterally, yes, using their experts as inputs
and be responsible for the outcome. If I make
decisions that propel the company in the way that
thankfully my decisions have, I get rewards and
kudos and I get to go back to the board and say,
I want a bigger grant. If I don't, I get
fired and I should get fired. If my big,
brave, unilateral decisions put us in the toilet,
then I have to take responsibility for that also.
So, that's how in my humble opinion, it should
work. And I, for one, don't know of a great
company that doesn't work that way. You'll see
from time to time, I did this a couple of years
ago, people will construct these indexes of the
performance of companies that are founder led,
and of course this is a self-serving statement,
but it's also true. And surprise, surprise,
the founder led companies perform substantially
better because they have the moral authority and
the willingness to take the risks that the
professional CEOs don't have the remit for.
The professional CEOs are typically told, don't
mess things up, and the founders are bored if
they're not taking the risk of messing things up
from time to time. And so that's in my opinion,
what creates greatness and great innovation.
But like I said, there will be friction
changing a company that's configured for
democracy and committee decisions and soft
and gentle interactions and communication
to be properly founder led and top down.
So, a big lesson here is if you're trying
to make the shift and it's just not moving,
there's a lot of resistance. You may need to go
hardcore founder mode and make some significant
change. What percentage of the employees
kind of turned over during this period?
Could be something ultimately like 40%. So,
it was a big, big turnover over some couple
number of years. Often the culture is set by a
very small number of people, so it only took a
quarter to really start to change the tenor of
the conversations that were happening, but to
bring in the people that were that new level of
ambition and wanted to work as hard as the rest
of us and work in a mature and engaged in excited
way, that took a little longer time. There's such
a thing as product market fit. There's a thing as
founder market fit, there's a thing as founder,
product market fit. That's how you're doing it
right, but there's also such a thing as employee,
founder, product market fit. You have to have the
right employees for the type of business you're
creating, and there are companies that want
the need to be more stable and they're going
to want the need to hire more stable individuals.
There's going to be companies that want to do the
highly collaborative, more democratic thing. I
wouldn't invest in them, but there's companies
that want to do it. If you're an employee that
enjoys that, there are a lot of positions out
there. There are big companies like Google that
do that. There are startups that hire the crazy,
young, wild, messy, early startup people, and
that's great for them and the company too. So,
it's really all about having the right individuals
and when you create that, not only do you create
great success, but you just create a lot more
happiness and balance and harmony. Ultimately,
the employees who wanted a more gentle democratic
environment, they're not going to be happy in a
company like Intercom or Coinbase or any of
these strong organizations. They'll be more
happy somewhere else. So, even if it requires
a little bit of a loving push out the door,
I know that you're actually doing them
a favor in the medium to long run.
I was going to say that a lot of these people
will be happier working in a different company.
Absolutely. Who wants to go to war every
day with your organization and in Slack?
That's just not fun. That's not good
for the nervous system or the soul.
Yeah, so this whole period sounds very
stressful for you. Did you ever regret
coming back and just like, what the hell did
I get myself into? What am I doing to myself?
I never regretted coming back, but I have
many moments where I don't enjoy the job. I
didn't regret coming back because it was deeply
cathartic for me. When a founder runs away from
their business, it is the ultimate betrayal of
their heart and the dream that they have. Now,
it's okay to wrap things up and quit, but when you
kind of run away, like I kind of had to because I
was sick and burned out and kind of disenchanted,
I don't know, it didn't feel good. So, especially
when I had done that, having betrayed in a
million or a thousand small ways, my intuition,
there was something I needed to exercise. So, it
has been deeply meaningful in that respect. And
then of course, I'm fortunate that it worked out.
I get to be on the second most popular podcast in
tech. I get to pat myself on the back in front
of all these people. Who wouldn't want that?
That said, the reality is that for particularly
people like me who like the adventure and the
high agency being unilateral, day-to-day
movement where you're trying to make big,
wild, bold decisions, the reality is that if
you're successful, most of your days will not
be that. It'll be reviewing the bonus policy for
next year and reviewing the comp proposal for your
execs for the next year. It will be showing up
for accountability meetings and stepping through
the status of different work streams. It'll
be rushing from meeting to meeting, having 8,
9, 10 meetings a day. I don't happen to believe
that that's a great way to live your life. It'll
be trying to get to all the emails you need
to get to such that all those people aren't
offended and hurt and trying to communicate in
the ways with your staff and your team that is
empathetic and thoughtful and keeps in mind that
they may be having as shit a day as you are.
You're giving me an opportunity to paint
story of this maverick led adventure that
you might imagine in a comic. I'm for some reason
picturing TinTin sail the seas, this swashbuckling
adventure. It's not. It's corporate life kind
of sucks particularly for people like me. So,
I have many of those days, and so the only reason
I'm still around is that I have a broader mission
that makes it worthwhile for now, but that's why
you see so many of our best founders get to a
point where they're like, okay, I've had enough
corporate fun. So, that's the most authentic
answer I could give you. No regrets coming
back, but plenty of pain on a day-to-day basis.
Today's episode is brought to you by DX, the
developer intelligence platform designed by
leading researchers. To thrive in the AI
era organizations need to adapt quickly,
but many organization leaders struggle to answer
pressing questions like which tools are working,
how are they being used, what's actually driving
value? DX provides the data and insights that
leaders need to navigate this shift. With
DX, companies like Dropbox, Booking.com,
Adyen and Intercom get a deep understanding of
how AI is providing value to their developers
and what impact AI is having on engineering
productivity. To learn more, visit DX's website
at getdx.com/lenny, that's getdx.com/lenny.
One of the interesting things about this
space of agents, there's all this talk,
agents are taking over. It's the future
of software. SaaS is going to be replaced with
agents. CX is a classic. It just feels like,
I imagine looking forward, it was not obvious.
Now looking back, it's like obviously this is an
amazing place for agents to take over work,
but there's always this talk of agents will
do everything and all the SaaS software is going
to be replaced by agents. Do you have a sense of
just how far this disruption will go outside of CX
because it's already happening in your businesses?
The first thing I'll say is that CX is deceptively
large given it's hidden behind just two words,
two letters. Customer experience really
is service success, sales and marketing,
in my opinion. It's all engagement with all
customers. It's the biggest part by headcount
of any business. Any consumer business and any
B2B business the biggest organizations are sales,
service, success. So, I'll talk about things other
than CX in a moment, but I want to emphasize that
CX is the majority of business operations.
Of course, it'll go beyond CX. Any function
that requires a lot repetitive operational
mechanical work will be automated, whether
it's chasing or collecting or issuing invoices,
it could be onboarding or offboarding employees.
There are so many repetitive jobs in an
organization that it'll start to replace.
One of the interesting questions is how much
will be generic operations bots, how much will
be expert agents? There are expert agents for
law and contract review. There will probably
be expert agents for accounting, but you'll need
the glue in between all of these agents too. But
future organizations will be agents everywhere.
I've spent quite a bit of time thinking about
what does it all look like in the future, and
I imagine it as a medley of humans and agents,
and I don't think it's obviously going to be
humans on the top and the agents all in the IC
roles. I think that'll be more of a complex mix
where you're going to have people that are like
managers and leaders, but they'll be in IC roles,
working with agents to configure them for success
and monitor and manage their progress, kind of add
that oversight and cover for edge cases. And so I
think we're going to be surprised in which the way
that these organizations go, they'll definitely
be smaller, they'll be flatter because of that.
I won't be surprised if there are agents at the
highest level too. I mean, I've been thinking
about how, and we do have a great human chief
of staff here, but imagine a future human chief
of staff that understands your priorities and
actually talks to you and does a check in each
day and reaches out to different people and ask
for updates and helps organize your priorities
and helps you remember who you need to keep
accountable. Clearly there's an opportunity for
that. And so you can imagine agents in specific
roles like customer service in operational roles
being glue and in being kind of like co-pilot or
assistant roles like that, which I mentioned.
But what I think that all brings is just epic
levels of efficiency. It's going to be super
deflationary. There'll be a lot more competition.
AI itself is insanely competitive right now.
It's so intense in a way that was never before
that's going to come to all industries when so
much of their inner workings becomes automated.
And ultimately I think it's going to be great
for the consumer. They'll have more options,
cheaper options, and I can't but
see that be great for the economy,
a lot of economic lubricant as it were, and a lot
of new movement and activity. And if we were to
really go off the reservation, but I'll stop
here, that means that we need more humans too.
We need population growth to show up for this
big growth economically. And yeah, I just see
the future as just a beautiful collaboration
between humans and agents in every direction.
I love the optimism. Someone described
this once as a society ... What is it?
Agentic society where it's us
and agents living together.
Right.
This begs the question around just jobs. We had
Marc Benioff on the podcast. He's all agent force,
agent force, agent force, and asked him just
like, what jobs do you think are going away?
He's just like, "CX, going away, gone. Sales not
going away. We need sales people." Just what's
your sense? I know it's like touchy subject.
No one ever wants to say jobs are going away,
but just what's your sense of where
jobs might be disappearing more, most?
Yeah. Well, I don't find it to be particularly
touchy because jobs have always gone away
and technology has done a really good job at
stealing jobs that we're repetitive, demeaning,
dangerous. We have less people losing limbs and
dangerous factories or dying and suffocating down
mines because of the technology that we now have
available to us. People breaking their backs on
farms or just doing things that's highly demeaning
to the great, beautiful creative potential of each
human individual life. So, I won't apologize for
competing with or competing for shit work because
all the while technology has done that in the
past, population has increased. GDP has increased,
longevity, crime rates have diminished in the
western world, the world that has enjoyed the
most technology. So, we have no good reason to not
believe that that won't continue. Even while there
is difficulty and there has been in the past,
no doubt, people who were gainfully employed
in dangerous work in mines had to find new work.
And so I don't take that for granted, but I think
that this is part of the long arc of humanity
flourishing and getting healthier and happier.
What are the types of work that will go away? It's
all the demeaning, crappy stuff, and that exists
in digital businesses. You ask a human to sit at
a keyboard answering the same question day in,
day out, and you get to a point where you don't
even ask them to answer the question manually. You
ask them to click the button that brings up the
macro. Like what a horrible use of a human life.
I've met thousands of people that have worked at
Intercom, a broad range of talents. People who
they might not describe themselves as particularly
high IQ. Maybe they were suited at that point in
their life for this highly repetitive work. You
talk to them for two or three minutes, you'll see
the bright spark of a beautiful human that if they
got to do the right thing, they would light up and
bring so much happiness and joy to the world.
And so that's the mission we're all on. I'm not
pollyannaish here, like I said, and I'm
suggesting that there won't be friction,
but for the most part, we're doing good. And
to get specific, they will be CX roles and
a lot of basic repetitive roles. There
is a lot of repetitive stuff in sales,
and so you'll do more sales with less people.
There are SD or roles qualifying basic questions.
You're not going to need as many people in sales
organizations. So, I'm a little misaligned with
Marc in that respect. But what he's getting at
is that what sales people bring to the table is
human connection and trust, and that is not about
to go away anytime soon. And thank God for that.
I had Ben Mann, the co-founder of Anthropic on
the podcast recently, and he said that he's like,
"Even my job is probably going to go at some
point." He was like, "Lenny, your job is going
to be replaced by AI at some point." That was
pretty compelling. Did not expect him to say that.
Yeah, I don't know. It will in many ways.
We're going to have agents in AI to aggregate
content and create content, but humans,
as much as when it comes to productivity,
value, efficiency, efficiency is not
the number one thing that we value.
If efficiency was the number one thing we value,
I'd always buy the cheapest clothes, furniture,
computers, even paper for my printer. But I think
humans value things like beauty and human stories
and human heart and connection. And not only
will they still want those and they'll still
want a Lenny that has his own story and his own
take and opinions and is a little imperfect,
but they'll pay more for it. The abundance
of AI is going to make automated things worth
zero. Just like the value of cheap content
on YouTube. Why do people subscribe to some
channels and pay more? Why do people pay to rent
movies? Because some things have more quality,
more beauty, more craft, more art, more humanity.
So, I think there'll always be a place for that.
Phew. All right. I've got a
couple more years at least.
Yeah.
Before I move on to a different topic. Just
kind of reflecting back on this shift to Fin
and the success that you've had, are there any
other just lessons that we haven't touched on
that you think might be helpful for folks
that are trying to go through this journey?
I think it's ultimately that you don't have
a choice. My co-founder Des is writing a
book at the moment, and that's core to
the idea here. You don't have a choice.
The story of the technology industry or digital
technology is really short and it's punctuated
by a small number of things, microprocessors,
personal computers, the internet, maybe mobile.
Now there's AI. I think AI is bigger than all
these things. And all of these things disrupted
essentially all categories. So, not only is
this likely to disrupt all the categories,
it's going to disrupt it in the most aggressive
violent ways. And if you're not in it,
you're about to get kicked out of all of it. And
so my strongest advice is roll your sleeves up,
figure out what's going to disrupt you, have
fun with it. You need to bring in actual talent.
We and I will be nothing if we didn't
have actual AI scientists and leaders.
It's the only way we can be successful here.
We have an incredible person who by the time
this is out will have received a promotion to
chief AI officer. I keep announcing all these
things and that's great confidence to you.
Fergal Reid, and he's just one of the very
best in AI applications, and we happened
to be working with him for many years.
So, part of it is finding the talent and part of
it is bringing in the young talent too. AI is kind
of a young man's game, and I'm young, but I'm not
as young as a lot of the kids building AI. And so
learning to empower and enable them and learn from
them too is a really big deal. And unfortunately,
part of what you learn from them is the only way
you're going to win right now is if you work your
ass off, because all these little AI companies
run by kids in their twenties are literally
working 12 hours a day, literally 365 days a year.
No joke, all of them. And that's not a fun idea
for many of us, especially those who've grown
up. Some people in our generation have kids or
a lot of them do. There's comfort and stability
in your life. You don't want to work like that,
but if you want in, that's part of the price
and that's how so many of these young new AI
are going to win because very few of the previous
generation companies are willing to make all of
those changes and go all the way in. And so my
actual advice, which is not that helpful, is that
if founders of previous generation companies are
themselves not willing to roll up their sleeves
and get into it and work as hard as the kids,
hire a kid. You can be a chairperson like I was,
have a lot of fun. You can mentor the kid, hire
a kid because you're in the wrong job, buddy.
I love how pragmatic this advice is and what's
interesting as you talk about 12 hours a day
every day, it's like we're trying to
get close to what agents are doing,
which is half, that's basically 50% of agents.
But that's not just a poetic cute thing to
say, that comes from something very real,
which is these younger companies know how
to use AI in ways that the older companies
don't. The younger companies are vibe coding
and using AI for their creative work and for
their job descriptions. I guarantee you go to
companies of our generation and even we have
had to push people, you go to companies of our
generation, most people in most organizations,
particularly non-technical organizations, they're
not using any AI. Maybe they're starting to use
ChatGPT to write a job description, but
they're not doing it by default. And so
that's more than a joke. You're competing
with young companies that are in part AI.
This reminds me, I did an interview with the
Perplexity founders. It was, I just checked,
April 2024, so just over a year ago. And they
were saying that the way they operated, and this
sounded it's so crazy at the time, is anytime they
had a question for anyone else on the team, they
first asked ChatGPT about it, and then they go ask
the person as like, that is insane. And now this
is just obvious. That's what we all do now.
Just like, hey, I'm just going to talk voice.
It's a prime example. They're doing many
such things. When I say 365 days a year,
they're the company I think of because they're
doing exactly that. All these young companies are
doing wild, weird and ridiculous things that
people you are in my age kind of chuckle at,
but it's business as usual for them. So,
there's just a big mind shift, cultural shift,
and there's a culture clash of the previous
generation versus the new generation. And the
sooner you kind of wrap your head around that, the
sooner you can start to unstake yourself, I think.
And just to build on that, the sounds crazy
to work this hard, it sounds very stressful,
not fun. Why would I do this? This sucks.
But at the same time, this is, as you said,
such an unusual rare opportunity.
There's so much opportunity. There's
so much wealth being created. There's so many
businesses being created. This is the time,
if you were to ever work really
hard, this is a good time to do it.
I think so. I don't actually generally promote
working that hard. I try to not fetishize it.
I actually think a life well-lived includes
taking slow walks in nature where you're not
thinking about ARR growth or hiring your chief
revenue officer, not going to eight meetings a
day. Maybe you should go to no meetings a
day, certainly not working 12 hours a day.
I don't actually promote that in general
as a thing one should do with their life.
I'm simply saying that if you want to compete
and enjoy success in this age, which means
you need to be doing AI, that is the price.
So, you either decide to pay the price or get out.
Don't half-ass it. You see all these companies
saying, we do AI and they've just sprinkle a
little bit of crappy AI and they've got the same
cultures. It won't work. The one thing I will say,
the one little asterisk to my first point is
that all great people and great things have
been achieved through hard work. And so I'm
speaking out of both sides of my mouth here,
to younger people to let them know that every way
of living is valid, but people who have achieved
things have always worked hard and they find a way
to enjoy it too. And particularly in 2025 in AI.
I want to follow this thread. I was going
to ask you this earlier, but I didn't,
and I want to see if this takes us somewhere
interesting, just watching you speak and talk.
You're very self-reflective, very centered.
You have these really good breaths you take
when you think about something. I met you a
long time ago, randomly at a party when you
were just starting Intercom. I don't think you
were like that. During this kind of two-year
period was there kind a transformation that
you went through to kind of become this?
Absolutely. Yeah. There's a couple things.
First, I mean, there's three things that
come to mind. Working in a startup for 14
years has a certain way of kicking you in
the head many times a day that either kills you
or makes you far stronger. So, that's one piece.
There's no elegance to that point, but I think
we can all intuit that that level of experience
teaches you something, you grow up very fast.
Point two is I did a lot of therapy. I found
this amazing guy 12 years ago. He started a
couple of his own tech companies and talked
in public. He only coached and was a therapist
to CEOs. He's now kind of in a later stage of
his career. But this amazing guy, his name is
Yosi Amram, amazing guy. I just landed on my
feet. I just didn't know who I was dealing with.
But one of the greatest minds and teachers of the
last, I don't know, many decades, people don't
even know him, but he's taught and worked with
many CEOs and he just helped me get to know me and
take time for myself. And people like to hate on
therapy right now. I think a lot of therapy sucks
and a lot of therapists are not good. And they
fear that actually therapy will lobotomize them
and turn them into thumb sucking, navel-gazing,
soft, irrelevant losers that won't have that
edge anymore. And the interesting thing about
12 years of weekly therapy and spiritual work
is that it takes your edges off, but they're
all edges that are super counterproductive.
All the edges that made you an asshole,
got you triggered, miscommunicated or fought
back when you were insecure, they take all
the edges away then help you see yourself and
love yourself so much more for who you are.
Be completely unafraid to acknowledge the
things you're not good at, but own the things
you are. And in understanding yourself, you
understand others better and can communicate
in a substantially more connected and authentic
way. Great, great therapy and it has to be great,
is a recipe for brilliant leadership in my
opinion. And then the third part is two years
away where I ran away, where I was sick, revenue
growth wasn't doing so hot. I unsuccessfully tried
to defend myself from a bunch of fake bullshit
in the newspapers. I mean I was beat up. And
in a moment like that, your ego, any sense
you have of your greatness is eviscerated.
And that's painful. It can be so painful that many
people don't come back from it, and I credit the
10 years at that point, or nine years of therapy
I did at that point, plus the support of this
therapist, the coach that I had, to surviving it.
But if you can survive it, what you end up with
on the other side is all of those insecure, a lot
of the insecurities and all that ego bullshit that
made you super ineffective, jealous, or triggered
for all sorts of different reasons, it's gone. And
your image that you are this perfect, brilliant
leader that all successful founders form when they
are successful had to die. And the reason that's
so good is that that's so limiting. When you have
this ego identity of yourself about how fucking
amazing you are, then any moment that challenges
that is super scary. Anyone who questions it is
offensive. And so I credit wherever I am today and
I have decades of learning still to go to those
three components. And I feel super fortunate to
have had all of them, even though the last one
sucked, I can finally say, wow, it really helped.
Thank you for sharing all that. I'm glad I
went there. I want to show you something that
I randomly have in my office, my wife
just got me that I think you're going
to love. It's a piece of art that I think
will resonate with [inaudible 01:03:02].
Yeah. What am I looking at here? So, it's a hand?
It's a hand with a snap and then let
me see if you can see what it says.
I can't see what it says.
It says ego death now.
Right. Look at this. Good. Exactly.
There it is.
May all our egos peacefully become smaller
and leave this mortal coil. The reality is
none of our egos ever die. And even great ...
Ram Dass is this great spiritual teacher who
died a few years ago and someone asked him
on his deathbed something like, "How did
you get over your bullshit or your ego?" And he
said, "I never did. Just the edges got smoothed
away." And this is a guy who had 70 years of the
deepest, wildest spiritual work, he acknowledged,
no, still my same self. So, the ego is still
there and we actually need to acknowledge
it and love it. And when you acknowledge
it, then it's not a surprise when you're
like a little jealous and you're like, huh, I'm
jealous. That's funny. Okay. And it's all good.
Reminds me Daniel Kahneman who wrote all these
books about biases that we have and here's all
the ways we're flawed. If people ask him, "Have
you learned to live more rationally?" He's like,
"Not at all." Knowing all these things
about how we're flawed in the way we
think all these biases doesn't
actually, I can't use it in life.
We're human. We should let ourselves be human.
I think it's beautiful. We're logic systems,
but we're also heart systems and body systems
and soul systems. So, all of it is good.
Okay, I want to go in a completely different
direction. The last thing I want to talk about,
I needed to mention this. I don't know if you've
seen this, but I've been doing research on which
companies produce the best product leaders. And
I've been doing this by looking at which alumni
of companies go on to become CPOs at the highest
rate, get promoted the most at their next job,
become the first product manager at a future
startup, start their own companies. Intercom
is coming number one across this research
next to Palantir and Stripe, Revolut.
So, the question this begs is, what are you
guys doing that produces such great product
leaders? There's the hiring piece and then
there's what they do at Intercom piece. So,
what do you think is creating these sort of
really big successes from your alumni group?
Yeah, I don't have a really succinct answer
unfortunately. I can say in the abstract,
our culture is a very producty culture. So,
myself and Des, there was four founders and
me and Des Traynor drove a lot, like all the
strategy. We're product guys. I was a software
designer. I studied computer science, so I'm
technical, but never did it professionally. So,
the first part is that just product innovation,
design just was just core to our culture and
people always picked up on that. So, I think good
people wanted to work here and we were good at
finding good people. The other part was
that because we had this sprawling strategy,
we had all these products that we needed a complex
structure for it and that included lots of PMs and
PM groups that we gave a lot of autonomy to. And
so the product of our big messy strategy was that
we had PMs that got to act like mini CEOs.
And so I think that they got to learn the
broader skill sets beyond designing wireframes
and interviewing some customers. They really own
it like a mini CEO to some degree. I think there's
one other thing which is part to our approach was
this deeply first principles thinking methodology
almost to a fault, although I don't think it's a
fault. I and we would create frameworks for
everything. It's like, okay, we want to do
these events. Who are the events for? What is the
ultimate goal of the event? What's the mechanism
by which events work? What are other mechanisms
that can achieve that same goal? How do we define
success for an event like that? How does the user
or the attendee define value? What other things
do those people find valuable? We create these
complex systems to try and approach everything,
but the net effect was we'd have really joined
up considered strategy and it's everywhere.
Like Paul Adams, our chief product officer,
I didn't even plan to show this. He made this
book recently, The AI Age and the Transformation
of Customer Service and it's a bunch of frameworks
for how to think about AI, et cetera. So, it's
part of what we do. And so we would hire people
who are good at that, but we teach that. That's
teachable and not everyone does that. And so the
conversations that Des and I would have, we still
love being on whiteboards. Our very first office,
our own office in Dublin, it was a tiny office.
One wall was four, five computers, the other wall
was just all whiteboards. We loved that we had a
whiteboard wall. In our next office we had a room,
square room and all walls were whiteboards.
So, we just love to draw diagrams so you can teach
all that stuff. So, yeah, it's just all that good
energy product, product energy, first principles,
the people we chose. And on the founders
side, I was talking to Des about this morning,
why have so many Intercom people gone on to be
founders? I think it's because we hired founder
types and my pitch to people was always come
to Intercom, figure out how great companies are
built and build it with us and then go on to
start your own. I would say that often at all
hands. But the irony is that the people we hired
back then, the founder types were probably not
great employees. They were better founders. I'm
not a good employee. And so it'll be interesting
to see if this current cohort, we'll get
many founders out of this current cohort,
but will they convert as well as they did before?
Because we're now hiring people who want to be
part of something bigger. They're more mature and
grown up, more stable and consistent. They're part
of, they have a certain expertise and a certain
lane they want to work in. And maybe they're not
the crazy types that went on to start companies,
but it's wild. I did see some of that research
by you, particularly the one where you show the
companies ranked by the number of founders that
they have. And I'm like, what is happening?
I was as surprised that we were that high
as you were because there are many other great
companies on that list. So, surprised and proud.
I love when people say, I don't really
have a clear answer. And then you have
exactly a clear answer and it resonates a lot
with other companies on this list that I've
had on of what the themes are, and I'll just
reflect back a few of them. One is complexity.
That comes up a lot. And interestingly,
most of the other companies in the list,
I'll read them real quick. Intercom,
Palantir, Revolut, N26, Dropbox, Chime,
Stripe, and then Coinbase and Notion is down
there. So many are FinTech. Almost all are
FinTech. And the complexity there is really
high. So, there's a really interesting trend
there. Just complexity. Ownership is another one
that comes up a lot. Many CEOs, GMs kind of roles,
first principles thinking and just going to the
bare metal comes up a lot in these conversations.
Yes.
And then hiring senior
people, hiring founder types.
Yes. Like Stripe did a lot
of that. I think Stripe did
a lot of first principle stuff and founder types.
The other thing, we didn't even talk about this,
but you guys invented RICE. You guys popularize
jobs to be done. Like speaking of frameworks, you
guys are a wealth of frameworks that we all use.
Drowning and frameworks, yeah.
Drowning slash changing the way everyone
builds product in a really positive way. Okay,
is there anything else that you wanted to touch on
or leave listeners with before we get
to a very exciting lightning round?
When someone like me comes on a podcast like this,
they always have an ulterior motive and that's
healthy and good. It's part of the transaction.
Some of it is to enjoy feeling like an expert.
But my ulterior motive today is to make sure that
people understand that Intercom is a fundamentally
different type of late stage company. We are a
large old startup. Every single way in which we
work is as a startup and are competing with and
crushing the actual startup competition in our
agent categories. And the reason that that's
important for people to know is just like I
said earlier, that the handicap that good but late
stage companies have is that their late stage and
people don't mentally put them in the same box.
They just don't imagine these older companies.
If I told you that IBM had made the
most wildly innovative coding assistant,
you'd find it hard to believe, most people
would. It's maybe so interesting such that it
would stick in your mind, you need to go look at
it. But by default people aren't going to look at
IBM. And so I want people to take a new look
at Intercom because it's a brand new company
and our mission is to help every single type
of business deliver impeccable, incredible,
beautiful personal service to every
single one of their users and people,
many thousands of people are using Fin for that
today. So, go check out Fin please, fin.ai.
And I don't know if you mentioned this
at the beginning, but let's mention that
you predict that you'll be the fastest
growing company across if you were to
look at all public software companies next year.
So, two years ago we were in the low single
digits growth rate. We doubled our growth
rate and last year we were in the low double
digits. This year we're in the 15th percentile
of all public software companies. So, you take
the 120 something public software companies,
we're in the 15th percentile. So, we're getting
up there fast and if we sustain this trajectory,
and it's obviously dangerous to put
these types of things out publicly,
but I'll tell you, I look at the charts
and it's hard not to imagine where this
goes. I think we're going to find ourselves
being the fastest growing out of all,
relative to all public software companies.
So, let's see. But that's the level of shock,
surprise and transformation that has actually
happened here all because of Fin. So, check in
with me in a year and maybe I'll be embarrassed
or maybe I'll be feeling like a genius.
Or underselling it. This just
reflects back on exactly how I
started our conversation. You've
done something extraordinary at
Intercom. I'm really happy that we're
here and we're sharing this story.
Thank you.
With that, we've reached our
very exciting lightning round.
I've got five questions for you. Are you ready?
Please. Ready.
What are two or three books that you find
yourself recommending most to other people?
So, I found I lost the habit of reading
as I started to get more and more stressed
with my startup. And so I would listen to
audiobooks here and there, but the most recent
book I read is a book called Nuclear War: A
Scenario, and it's a very much a nonfiction
and scared the shit out of me. So, if you like
nightmares, it'll be beautiful bedtime reading.
Excellent.
Yeah.
What's a recent movie or TV
show you've really enjoyed?
I love movies. I want TV to be better, but I very
rarely find TV to be great. The first and last TV
show I loved was True Detective one that was just
incredible. But the last movie I watched was 28
Years Later, and that's by Danny Boyle. I was born
in the eighties, grew up as a kid in the nineties,
and so grew up with Trainspotting. It was 28 Days
Later. Then he made a movie called Sunshine. So,
28 Years Later is a type of movie that's just
not made anymore. It's the most nineties movie
made since the nineties. It's like very
rock and roll and also deeply touching. So,
I was really surprised by that. I bet I would
love to know that younger generations that are
watching this, what they may think, they
may hate it, but I love 28 Years Later.
So, this is the same person that made 28 Days
Later, then 29 years later [inaudible 01:15:51].
Yeah, Danny Boyle.
Wow. Okay. Very cool. I didn't know about
that. Do you have a favorite product you've
recently discovered that you really love? Could
be a gadget, could be an app, could be clothes.
I very rarely like products, I'm such a
perfectionist that it has to be really simple
with very little moving parts, like a bowl, to
actually be like, good. I've started to get more
into coffee. I've been buying products by Fellow.
They're remarkably good for consumer products,
different, it's on a different level. So,
there's some sort of level of taste and craft
happening there that I don't see in basically
any other consumer hardware type products. And
of all things, I'd bought a Porsche 911 recently
and that is a beautiful product. The interiors
are exquisite and there's still a bunch of shit
that is going to annoy you. And so it's far from
perfect. So, yeah, perfectionism is sometimes
a gift if you're in the business of creating
products, but also quite the curse. You're
never happy, including with the Porsche 911.
I think that's the third time someone
recommended a car. Someone recommended,
I think Boz at Facebook recommended a fancy
Mercedes, and then someone once suggested a
Rivian, so now we got Porsche on the list. I
always thought maybe one day I'll give someone
all the prizes, all the products people have
ever mentioned in this. And those are getting,
Porsche might be a little high. Okay, two
more questions. Do you have a favorite life
motto that you find yourself repeating, coming
back to in work or life sharing with friends?
It's trite. It's not sophisticated and
it's more of a concept than a phrase,
but it's something around the idea that life is
short. I'm just so aware that time ticks by and
we all live on autopilot. So much of what we
do is inspired by either our insecurities or
things that other people we look up to or
envy do. Very rarely making contact with
what we really want and following our hearts
and our heads. And we just kind of get stuck
in these lanes and just live out our days. And
certainly when you get 41 now, you get to 41
and thankfully still very young, anyone in their
forties, congrats, should feel good about that.
But I know if you're in your twenties or thirties,
40 feels old. But when you're in your forties,
my experience is that the weeks and the
months and then the years go by. It's not
a big deal. I'm back at Intercom two and
a half years now to any of these kids in
AI in their twenties. If they don't get
something done or achieved by next month,
they'll be so disappointed themselves
and so impatient. And in some ways,
at least when it comes to productivity, they're
better at getting more out of the time. But I'm
now trying to get more life out of the time
too. So, just, if there is a motto, it's like
life is short or memento mori, we're all on the
way out. So, make the use of what you've got.
Fun fact, I built an app once called Savorable
that helped you savor the moment, it was called
Savorable and it sent you a text every few hours,
I don't know, maybe once a day with a little
reminder of way to savor the moment. And one of
the texts was just like, remember, you will die.
Yeah. And the problem is that even that
idea, we forget it instantly. And if you
start getting text every day, you'll
ignore the text. Try to fault. We just
don't want to acknowledge that reality on
a day-to-day basis. Maybe that's important.
Yeah, maybe for the best.
Yeah.
Okay, Final question. Speaking of apps, I was
doing research on you in preparation for this
and I didn't realize you built Quitter
back in the day. I love Quitter. I found
it so fun. It basically told you anytime
someone unfollowed you on Twitter. So,
the question just what happened to that app?
I think we eventually sold it for 14K.
Wow, that's cool.
On one of these, I think there's a website called
Flipper where you could sell websites. It really
blew up. It was like a little experiment, kind of
a social experiment. It was the first time that I
had this feeling that there's no reason someone
wouldn't want to use this. Obviously people
are going to want to use this. And it was really
instructive for me because it taught me that that
feeling is possible. You meet so many founders,
young founders particularly, and they don't have
a sense within themselves about the value of the
stuff they're building. Will this be good? Let's
get customer feedback. And it is possible
to build things that you deeply know makes
sense. And that's why my formula for building
things was to always build things for myself.
And that was what Quitter was like. Followers
go up, followers go down. At that point in time,
people had 100 followers or 200 followers, and
you'd want to know who's not my friend anymore.
Oh man, I love that that was your
bar that led you to the success
later if it's as good as Quitter
in terms of product market fit.
I mean, it had the best fit ever. About everyone
on Twitter tried to sign up for it and it broke.
Well, I loved it. Eoghan, thank you
so much for doing this. I love just
how real and open you are about everything
and just how much insight you have to share.
I also just love the vibe. I feel like I
just am more centered just watching you-
Oh, thank you.
... speak. Two Final questions.
Where can folks check out Fin,
follow you if they want to follow up on anything?
And then how can listeners be useful to you?
Check out Fin, fin.ai. If they want to follow me.
I'm E-O-G-H-A-N on Twitter, so it's Irish spelling
of Owen. But if they want to be helpful to me, I'd
love them to try Fin. I'd love them to have their
friends that run any kind of customer operations,
try it too. This AI thing is noisy. There's so
much hype, but it's also really real. And the
weird thing about Fin, even relative to the coding
apps, the coding apps are blowing up, and yet
there's a lot of people experimenting and kicking
tires. You can't kick tires with Fin. We only
deliver value when you expose it to your customers
and it closes tickets and makes them happy. And so
AI is really, really happening. And so if you know
anyone out there that has customers, they should
be using Fin. It's the smartest, cheapest, easiest
way to dramatically enhance their business. So,
if they do that, they'll be helping me sincerely.
I'm sold. Eoghan, thank
you so much for being here.
Thank you, sir. Pretty fun.
This was amazing.
Yeah, thank you.
Bye everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.