Your podcast is a podcast by a builder for
other builders. Here's the most interesting
question I think people can ask builders,
what is your energy source? My energy source
is dissatisfaction with status quo. There are
so many books are about this ... Technology
leading to dystopia. Like no one who
really thinks about this would want to
be born into a world 20 years before today.
I think today is the dystopia of the future.
It behooves us to try to build the kinds of
products that leads in ... Towards progress.
There's a couple quotes along these lines I've
seen that describe the way you think about this
stuff. "If most people are doing it a certain
way I by default don't want to do it that way."
There's an aesthetic in the world that
exists which is that business people dress
in suit and tie, they are speaking
much more sophisticated than I do,
usually without an accent. They usually have a
stick and show dramatically at the chart that
is behind them. How much is that aesthetic
overlapped with outperformance? Pessimism
sounds extremely sophisticated. Optimism always
sounds dumb or at least naive. The most powerful
unquantifiable things in the word
of business are fun and delight.
I don't know of any other company
that operates where the founder
has this 100-year vision of where the product
needs to go and working backwards from that.
I talk about look in the future and then think
backwards a lot, right? It's like what would
we want to have done 20 years ago on this?
We have very long-term plans. At 100 years
you can't talk about this software project
but you can talk about the mission itself,
whatever things that will survive for 80 years
that are left on this particular timeframe.
Entrepreneurship is just precious. Shopify exists,
basically, to make entrepreneurship more common.
Is there anything you want
to leave listeners with?
I really, really, really think that
there is not a single person on this
planet who is even close to being at
their maximum potential. Reminding
people of their own potential constantly
is actually a wonderful thing to do.
Today my guest is Tobi Lütke. Toby is a man who
needs no introduction so I'm going to keep this
very short and get you right to this jam-packed
conversation. If you enjoy this podcast don't
forget to subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube, it's the best way to
avoid missing future episodes and it helps the
podcast tremendously. With that I bring you Tobi
Lütke. This episode is brought to you by Sinch,
the customer communications cloud. Here's the
thing about digital customer communications.
Whether you're sending marketing campaigns,
verification codes, or account alerts
you need them to reach users reliably,
that's where Sinch comes in. Over 150,000
businesses including eight of the top 10 largest
tech companies globally use Sinch's API to build
messaging, email, and calling into their products.
And there's something big happening in
messaging that product teams need to know about,
Rich Communication Services or RCS. Think
of RCS as SMS 2.0. Instead of getting texts
from a random number your users will see your
verified company name and logo without needing
to download anything new. It's a more secure and
branded experience. Plus, you get features like
interactive carousels and suggested replies.
And here's why this matters. US carriers are
starting to adopt RCS. Sinch is already helping
major brands send RCS messages around the world.
And they're helping Lenny's Podcast listeners
get registered first before the rush hits the US
market. Learn more at getstarted@sinch.com/Lenny.
That's S-I-N-C-H.com/Lenny. Today's episode is
brought to you by Liveblocks, the platform that
turns your product into a place that users want
to be. With ready-made collaborative features
you can supercharge your product with experiences
that only top=tier companies have been able to
perfect until now. Think AI copilots like Notion,
multiplayer like Figma, comments and notifications
like Linear, and even collaborative editing like
Google Docs. And all of that with minimal
configuration or maintenance required.
Companies from all kinds of industries and stages
count on Liveblocks to drive engagement and
growth in their products. Join them today and
give your users an experience that turns them
into daily active users. Sign up for a free
account today at Liveblocks.io/Lenny. Tobi,
thank you so much for being
here. Welcome to the podcast.
I'm glad to be here. I'm
excited for our conversation.
I've listened to so many of your other
interviews, I've talked to a bunch of
people that work for you. I want to try to do
something a little different. There's basically
two themes that emerged over and over and
over as I've listened to you share advice,
and interview, and in talking to people that work
for you. One is thinking from first principles,
the other is maximizing human potential. I'm just
going to plant these seeds for now. I'm going to
not ask about these directly, I'm going to come at
these from the side with the many questions that I
have for you. Something that I've heard people
describe at Shopify called the Tobi tornado.
Oh, wow. Okay, that's a start. I like it.
What is the Tobi tornado?
A Tobi tornado, I would say, is a whole lot of
change management or a conversation or conflict or
real talk compressed into a very short timeframe.
I see something it doesn't ... It's not good, I
have a conversation. I have learned something very
quickly about hey, I need to update my priors,
or cool, let's do it differently. At which point a
project might be stopped and we get back together
in a room and then we start a new version of a
product. And everyone who's currently on the team,
of that particular project, is no longer on the
project but they are the founders of the next
version which is built differently. And that
might be a bit whiplashy for people. I mean,
I certainly hope that's true, it's certainly
what people tell me. It's also what they
appreciate about the company. It's like
what is best ends up mattering a lot.
Basically, it's you going into a chat room
being like "Hey, this" ... "We're going
to end this project we're" ... "Let's try
something else" because you've discovered
or realized this is a bad idea. Some people
complain about this practice of like "Oh,
Tobi kills the we've been working on." My lens
is, you realize we're just wasting time on this
thing that is not going to work and we shouldn't
do it. Is there anything there along those lines?
No. This is everything. Again, once I imagine
something might be not the right thing to work
on I'm either incorrect at which point this
is super important that I understand why or
I'm correct at which point it's super unfair for
letting people work on something that isn't going
to make it. There's a third wave which is I could
also ignore it but that's an abjection of my CEO
and founder responsibility that I'm absolutely
not willing to make so that's just not a path
forward that I see valid. I understand that's
what a lot of people choose to do. So yeah,
compressing time is important. We have a fairly
limited time in our careers, right? Our careers
are not that long. If you're lucky you have 40
years in the industry. Most people spent more time
in school and then maybe leave later if they're
so lucky that they can. So it's not even that.
I think you want to do the maximum amount of
things you can be proud of at the end of your
career. When you look back you want to be saying,
"Hey, holy shit, we shipped this thing which was
absolutely an incredible contribution to a mission
I cared about at a company that was full of other
people who cared as much as I did." And also are
very proud of working. And maybe even thinking of
working with me and being really, really glad
that we spent time on projects together. Yeah,
none of this happens if everyone's sort of
optimizing a thing that probably shouldn't
be there, right? And, therefore, I
think it's the better thing to do.
And, by the way, I love this way of describing ...
Of compressing it in time to just make a decision,
not focus on making it come across the most
kind, nicest, sweetest way. When you give
feedback to people when something is not
the way that you think it could be or as
good as you could be it's often very direct and
often hard to hear. To me this comes across as
you're trying to maximize their potential,
you're trying to push them to do something
better. Is there anything there that you
think is a way of approaching feedback?
I really, really, really think that there
is not a single person on this planet who
is even close to being at their maximum
potential. I just think everyone is way,
way, way, way, way better than they think.
And the reason why we're not performing at
this level is a series of ideas, maybe certain
approaches for cultivating our skills and our
crafts that have not yet been discovered and,
therefore, we could not take advantage of them.
It's an environment that just narrows the focus on
fairly unambitious things at which point you get
stuck competing with literally everyone else
in the world because everyone's unambitious.
I have found that reminding people of their own
potential constantly is actually a wonderful
thing to do. And I have a history of being
right about people's potential more than they
are themselves. Now, in a way, this dooms
me fairly often to be disappointed, right,
in myself. By the way, I'm talking about myself
here too. I think I have way more potential than
what I bring to bear and I hate that so I'm trying
to cultivate the skills that I need for tomorrow
and constantly challenge myself. I'm harder on
myself than on anyone else. By some discount rate
act equally to the people around me, especially
the ones who just so, obviously, are brilliant.
Spending time and longer time in careers with
people and then holding them to a high standard
means that they accomplish very often things
that just they didn't imagine they could. To
me this is the most wonderful thing to see. And
frankly this is a throughline for all of my career
because this ... My product is that. I want my
product to cause people to be more successful
than they thought they could. And, in fact, become
more ambitious about what they are building with
their online stores and their businesses than
they are actually initially set out to do.
Because something like this happened to
me, right? I started a snowboard store at
some point. I didn't set out to build Shopify.
If you are committed to following your curiosity
as to the next step, and optimize for maximum
amount of learning when you choose these steps,
it takes you from one place to another and you
actually realize the world's full of lies about
human potential and progress. Maybe people are not
malicious about it but they're definitely confused
about it. School teaches you that you have to
learn this particular piece of math in this
12 month period, and it doesn't matter how much
you understand it. It's like the outcome can be
variable and will grade you on a variable outcome
for a fixed amount of time which has nothing to do
with anything I've ever seen or learned or
see ... Or witnessed about how to actually
learn things. You follow that thread and you just
find that there is no speed limit for personal
growth. In a way Shopify has been a wonderful
experimental lab for this sort of conviction. I've
just seen this to come to be true. And, of course,
hearing from someone that you respect that "Hey,
I think you had it in you to do this thing
significantly better because I think you probably
saw fairly early in the project this sort of
path A path B. You chose path B potentially
out of convenience even though you knew that
wasn't the right thing. And I actually expected
better of you and I expected" ... "I think
the next time this happens in your career
you should go path A because" ... "Based on your
conviction." And, therefore, that's hard to hear,
right, because it's right. But it's also
extremely valuable, right? What I love
is an environment of people who are holding each
other accountable to the actual potential rather
than sort of their current level plus or ...
Plus some, I don't know, a little bit extra.
There's so many threads I want to follow
here. The example of the school is such
a pertinent one. To me right now we're looking
at preschools for our son and I'm ... They're
describing their education philosophy I'm
like, I don't know why I should believe
this is the right approach. And it makes me
just want to spend all this time researching
what education approach works. I know it's
just preschool and maybe not as critical yet.
Did you have a bet yet? I have three kids too
and this is sort of a decision that every parent
faces, right? So many of your listeners are
probably product managers of machine learning
products that maybe this resonates. So there's a
funny thing about machine learning which you're
just like ... You train on a lot of data, and,
hopefully, you get something that predicts the
thing you want it to predict correctly out of
it. The biggest problem of this is overfitting,
right? What does good look like, a loss function?
Which is a heuristic because it's not the actual
task that the thing will do in the future it's
something that proxies to the task that you want
the thing to do in the future. Predict fraud,
predict the next word, whatever. So overfitting
is basically model learning how to cheat on
the benchmark or on the fitness function.
So there's a business analogy of this which
is that ... It's called Goodhart's law. It's
literally the same thing as overfitting just
for businesses. Goodhart's law just says,
"Any metric that becomes a goal ceases
to be a good metric." Same exact thing.
The universal truths are things that almost
any competitive field will invent for itself by
different terminology often. And I think this is
also, by the way, why it's so interesting to focus
on personal growth and learning a lot about a lot
because you end up finding these sort of hidden
harmonies behind things, the things that are
clearly enduring correct insights. So overfitting,
Goodhart's law are the same thing. School
optimizes for what? Marks supposedly, right?
In fact, overfitting in school is literally the
kids cheating to get marks, right? You get another
analogy. What is however the right loss function
for children? Have you made a decision yet?
No, I have not we just started
down this path. You told me-
It's the kind of thing [inaudible 00:15:57]. You
have to actually go fairly deep in philosophy to
figure this out. And then again afterwards you can
build, you can find the schools that you like. For
us it was just maintaining curiosity. This is
a completely different goal from being good at
marks. But I just think everyone's born extremely
curious and school has a habit of getting it out
of kids. Literally, there's a foundation model of
a child, and you fine-tune it at school, and it
just loses the neurons of curiosity because it's
actually discouraged to meander into other topics
and explore them just because they're interesting.
I don't know. This is sort of not the beat of a
podcast but I just think about this a lot. It's
funny how these things just recur constantly.
So when Archie was on the podcast, he's the head
of growth at Shopify ... I don't know if that's
his official role. Basically drives a lot of the
growth. He talked about how the core product team,
outside of the growth team, operates without
KPIs, without specific goals. And decisions
are driven by taste and intuition primarily
you, and Glen, and some other leaders. And
a lot of people heard that and they're like "I"
... "First, I don't believe that. Second of all,
how does one operate that way when there's
no data to tell us exactly what is right
and good?" So the question I have is just how
does one operate in that way successfully? What
does it take for a company to work that way
because a lot of people will try it and fail?
This is very close to what I just talked
about before with [inaudible 00:17:28].
Goodhart's law is real. The moment a metric
becomes a goal it's no longer a useful metric,
right? I think that's more or less a precise
wording. Why? Because no metric by itself is
a complete heuristic for a complex business
because business are complex. There's a million
of different tensions in a company and you can't
all keep them in harmony by optimizing for one
fix. It's true that we don't have KPIs and we
don't have at least OKRs in the Silicon Valley
sense but we are extremely data-informed. We have
invested enormous amounts of money and time into
systems that give us basically everything at our
fingertips. I sent this demo to other founders
and they're completely bowled over by the way we
can dig into basically every constituent atomic
bit part that makes up the cohort that just got
formed 15 minutes ago by the end of a ... At
the end of a quarter or month or week.
In a lot of different places, this is
one of them but also in its products, it's just
not overfitting for the quantifiable. Everyone
competes for everything but it's highly
quantifiable because it's ... It's fun,
it's like a game. You tweak a number and 0.1
more is better than 0.1 less. That's an immediate
gratification thing. But I just think the overlap
of most valuable things you can do with a product,
and for things that happen to be fully
quantifiable, it's like maybe 20% which leaves
80% of a value space unaddressable by the people
who will only look at quantifiable things. Shopify
is comfortable with the unquantifiable things
such as tastes, quality, passion, love, hate.
It's with the strong emotions that people have.
The sort of deep satisfaction that a craftsperson
feels when they've done a job well is actually
better proxy if you allow it to be then the ... Do
a unit test pass. A unit tests might not pass.
And the unit tests will pass 15 minutes later
because we already fix them or adjust the one or
two things so they support us. We have systems
that tell us exactly if something goes the wrong
way. There's an extremely sophisticated rollout
system in Shopify that forever holdouts and
correlates everything with everything for ... In
every experiment and so on and so on and so on.
But if you think about it as a cockpit for a
pilot. The decisions are still made by pilots and
we think this leads to better results. It's just
the same with our product. There's plenty of A/B
testing tools and all these things for commerce,
and it's, of course, really important to figure
out what your conversion rates are. But are you
representing your brand is an unquantifiable
question? Are you proud of the thing that you
have built? Do you feel it's your own, right?
And so I think there needs to be more acceptance
in businesses or for unquantifiable things. The
most powerful, not unquantifiable things in the
world of business are fun and delight. If people
have fun when they're doing something that is just
upstream from so ... Sorry, downstream from
so many other things. I think that if all the
metrics are pointing down but everyone says, "My
God, I'm having so much more fun," I think that
the very next thing that will happen with some
time delay is all metrics will start going up.
And if that doesn't happen then we adjust course.
The reason why we specifically don't have OKRs and
these things is because ... If you want to hold
the unquantifiable as things that are stable and
exist ... That people actually do really defer
to them and really actually learn to be okay
with someone just saying, "Hey, this is actually
just really great and they're shipping this" then
you need to make certain edits to a business that
don't remind everyone too much of the companies
they might have come from which the only way to
get promoted is by driving the metric up. It's a
bit of a [inaudible 00:22:24] conversation I
suppose. Good on the fortune cookies saying,
"Shopify doesn't do OKRs or doesn't do metrics"
and so on. But it's actually just because the
metrics take us [inaudible 00:22:37]
function where we often defer to just
more ... Sometimes a little bit emotional
but generally less quantifiable things.
I imagine if someone were to hear you
describe this of focus on joy, and fun,
and love, and delight, maybe
... It's easy to dismiss that.
It sounds completely idiotic, right? Again,
there's an aesthetic in the world that exists
which is that business people dress in suit and
tie, they are speaking much more sophisticated
than I do usually without an accent, have a
full head of hair. They talk about metrics,
they are in front of PowerPoint presentations,
they usually have a stick and show dramatically
at the pie chart that is behind them. And highly
charismatic, highly ... So that's our aesthetic.
How much is that aesthetic overlapped with
our performance? I don't know but some of
them ... Some people pull it off who are like
this. I think the world is sort of stacked to lead
us astray based on our stories about what optimal
looks like are just so incorrect in so many ways.
Optimism always sounds dumb, or at least naive.
Pessimism sounds extremely sophisticated. Metrics
driven sounds extremely sophisticated.
Talking about fun sounds like naive.
Well, first of all, I've always ignored
what people think generally. That came
pretty natively to me somehow which I'm very
lucky about. But I've now actually learned
that almost all of the alpha in the world is now
in the ... Exactly the things that are unobvious
but true. And the things that people dismiss
as naive or so. The most successful business
person on planet Earth is Elon and he conforms to
no idea of what the most sophisticated business
person ought to be like in any which way you
can imagine. I think we live in a world where
the counterfactuals are winning because our ...
Because aesthetics are just leading us astray.
This is an awesome segue to the other theme
that I wanted to spend some time on which is
thinking from first principles, Elon is
the classic example of that. Honestly,
I think you're the other most classic example of
that these days. And we'll keep talking about all
the ways you operate very differently from other
companies which are examples of this. But I want
to read a quote from Glen Coates, he shared with
me, of how he sees you that gives an interesting
lens into your first principles thinking.
So here's what he said about you. "Tobi
is at his heart a true futurist, he's obsessed
with the way things should be in the future.
Being data-driven is innately being anchored
in the way users and technology are behaving
today. He's never really said this to me
explicitly, but knowing him I think any design
that is drawn primarily from the way things
are or were is one that he sees as inferior
to one that is skating to the puck of the way
things could or should be." Does that resonate?
Yeah. I mean, I think that's correct. That's
actually really interesting.
Your podcast is a podcast by a-
Your podcast is a podcast by a builder for other
builders. Here's the most interesting question I
think people can ask builders is like, "What is
your energy source? Where are you getting energy
from?" I think fundamentally the world exists at
room temperature. Almost all companies are running
at that, humming along, doesn't do anything. There
are certain individuals who can inject heat into
businesses. Founders do this very well. All the
startups anyone's ever heard of have people who
are injecting heat because if no one would inject
heat into the business, at room temperature,
you cannot outperform anyone else. You can't be
hotter than everyone else if no one's injecting
heat into the concern. So fundamentally, there
is a injection of energy into companies that
comes from founders and the best leaders, like
all the people you've had on the podcast from
Shopify have a perfect set of cast of characters
of people who are just exothermic. They are just
like wellsprings of energy that leads to all
the amazing results that we get to enjoy.
So the question is where does energy comes from?
And that's another one of our discussions which
very quickly goes into the emotions. Actually,
there's a really... So I watched The Last Dance,
the Netflix special of Michael Jordan a while ago,
of course, but there was one scene where he just,
I'm sure this is a super famous story and he just
made up an insight that someone told him so that
he would then go and just want to destroy them
afterwards, which he then of course proceeded
to do because it's hard to imagine anyone more
exothermic than him. So we know what his energy
source is. It's rivalry. It's potentially it's
insight or it's anger, something like this.
I am not... My energy source is dissatisfaction
with status quo. My fundamental belief is all this
talk about technology where all... So many books
are about just technology leading to dystopia. You
know what dystopia is? Today, compared to what it
will be in 20 years ago or any. And you can play
this for any part of human history. I'm not making
a future statement. I'm making a almost totalical
statement about the experience on planet Earth.
No one who really thinks about this would want
to be born into a world 20 years before today
rather than today. And so I think today is the
dystopia of future, and I think it behooves us
to try to build the kinds of products that lead
in towards progress in a small way or a big way.
But yes, I think if someone comes to me and says,
"Hey, let's go do this thing. And we've looked
around and here's how people solve this problem,
let's make a good version of that," I'm like,
"That was not the job." Because everything
that you encounter, that every solution, every
product, everything that exists is path-dependent,
highly, highly, highly path-dependent, and
often path-dependent based on having to make
compromises, based on things that were true at the
time a decision was made but are no longer true.
The entire field of... What was it? I
forgot the name of a field. Chomsky's field,
the linguistic research field. It's cool. We now
have autoregressive models that are just like,
we don't actually need to set up a complete... We
don't need to research the structure of grammar to
be able to make machines also engage in the spoken
word. We actually can just train on the internet,
it turns out. So that was not possible
back then because you didn't have the
right architecture for this, but now it is. So
I think what you have to do is to actually have,
when you come up with a new product or you discuss
a new product, you have to derive it from first
principles. You have to say, "How would we solve
this problem given every fundamental building
block that we have available right now?"
For that, to do that, you actually have to
understand the power and the composability of all
the building blocks that exist right now, which is
a tall order and no one is perfect at this. But
so this way, you go ahead and say, "Okay, cool,
so this is how we are implementing this thing.
This is how it will be implemented today." And now
we can talk ourselves in taking shortcuts. "Maybe
we should actually start up doing it the way
everyone else does. Maybe we derived exactly what
everyone else does as the correct thing to do."
Sometimes there was a lot more wisdom
encoded in the status quo than you expect,
which is I think is super delightful. Then you
figure that out and so when you act on it. But
what isn't okay is skipping the exercise
and doing the same thing everyone else does
because that is again a abdication of product
leadership. And so yeah, I would say I become
extremely suspicious if I get a pitch to do
a good version of the same thing everyone
else does because I just find that in our space
specifically very rarely to be the best solution.
There's a couple quotes along these lines
I've seen that describe the way you think
about this stuff. "If most people are doing
it a certain way, I, by default, don't want
to do it that way. And if you want to do something
world-class, you can't do it like everyone else."
Yeah. I don't even think that's an opinion
that I hold. I think that's actually... We are
basically in axiom territory here. If you want to
do something better than what exists, you have to
do it differently. That does not make a statement
about if it will be better in the end after you
do it. It could also be worse. But you can't get
something better done if you do the same thing.
It's like axiomatically not possible to do. It's
fails Archimedean logic, yet it's something...
You would be amazed how many business plans
are actually failing Archimedean logic in this
way like, "Let's do a good version of this thing
that we've already been doing and we will capture
1% of the market," and just like this stuff.
It's like, "Trust me." I find it kind of cute.
Is there an example that you can share
of you approaching the problem this way?
I imagine it's constantly happening. You
also mentioned you're born this way. So I
think it's hard for someone to just sit
down, learn, think the way Tobi thinks,
but I'd love to help people start to approach
problems this way, so maybe an example might help.
I think this is entirely learnable, I think. And
so I encourage people to just have a practice
of think step by step essentially and just
do it. It'll become a habit pretty quickly
because it just, it also just outperforms.
Examples. The very first example is Shopify
itself. It's cool. So there was lots of e-commerce
software and it was all the way it was because
of path dependence because everyone who want
it in 2004, 2005, e-commerce was an existing
retailer and therefore they had complex
businesses that needed to be ported online,
including all of their somewhat Byzantine business
logic. "I wanted to make e-commerce software that
would do very well on the internet of the future
and I believe that we can make it easier to start
new businesses online than it is in a physical
world because the physical world is encumbered
by a lot of regulations and also upfront costs
for leases and so on. So let's optimize for that
case and build something that is so intuitive to
use that frustrated people in dead-end careers can
spend their lunch breaks making progress towards
building their own business, which then eventually
allows them to do it on their own way."
And so being fortune was biased,
eventually it turns out to be a much better prep
for also solving all the enterprise cases because
no one had to... Enterprise software is overfit
to the sales process, which is that it wins the
RFPs because it has every feature ever or at least
a way of putting a checkbox next to every RFP line
ever. But they're not good, right? An RFP is
a great example of overfitting in the world of
procurement because it tells you nothing about the
quality of software behind it. But honestly, this
happens all the time. It is just like here, we
are setting the stage for much more, much higher
quality retrieval for the products on Shopify
and across Shopify. I think we've been in a local
maxima on search and we think that, especially
with the advances of the new models, certain
things are now possible to do that could not have
been done yet because again of these layers and
layers of path dependence and no one coming and
saying, "Is that the best way to do and maybe we
should rebuild this component periodically?" We
can now do a better job if search that will leads
to much more delightful experiences. And so this
is a fun project that this happening right now in.
I think this is really interesting because what
I'm looking for is like the Tobi algorithm of
first principles thinking. Elon's got these
famous ways of thinking he shared. One is start
with the cost of metal to help you understand
how much a rocket should cost. And then he's
got this five-step. First, decide, do we need
this thing? Then figure out how to optimize it,
then automate it. What I'm hearing so far, and I'm
curious if you've thought about this? And if not,
this feels like a really good blog post in your
futures, the Tobi first principles algorithm,
but I'll share a couple of things I've
heard so far as you've described it.
One is analyze the path that existing solution
has relied on, almost like the assumptions that
were true for it to be built back and it
was built. And the other is this overfit,
what is it overfit for? What is
it over solving that maybe isn't
necessary? Is there anything along those
lines of just how you approach problems?
This is probably too nerdy technical. You are
right, but I should figure myself out a little
bit. My brain runs on a meter language but isn't
directly something I can translate into words,
I suppose. I think more about things like this in
terms of programming constructs, pure functions,
overstate. And I think in any moment, the best
decision to do is I think the perfect product
lead is almost like a thermostat for high
quality product. It's like you're setting,
saying, "I would like to build something really,
really great and I'm going to go through a series
which is much, much more complex than what a
thermostat does," which basically checks the
temperature and then makes a decision of air con
or heating. You make you re-derive literally every
decision that is valuable, every foundational
assumption, every foundational ABC direction.
And you want to see the observation you've made in
the meantime since you last derived the next step.
Re-running the entire function over the state that
is now updated, the higher fidelity information,
would you come to the very same thing?
Sometimes fairly early in the construct
in the tree of foundational assumptions, change is
made. An example we all had was beginning of COVID
when we suddenly had shelter in place. So Shopify
has that incredibly good office spaces and we were
very in-person company and we've... Our floor
plans because I think we really added something
to the understanding of how to put great... I
got a lot of founder energy from my co-founder,
Daniel, to build great collaborative spaces
for creative work with lots of happy accidents,
people running into each other and so on.
Anyway, we were very, very, very,
very determined on doing that. But somewhere
in this construct of nesting functions,
you have to rerun and foundational assumptions.
It's in the stack is the fairly basic Boolean
of are people allowed to leave a house?
Which was yes. The moment that flips,
it's not that just like, "Okay, over here let's do
the best what we can do." It's actually that the
entire tree now moves into a different place.
And it can be a very far place, different,
that you land because you will make the same
quality of decision on every step, but you need
to rerun something that takes you to a completely
different landing zone. And so then this is also
easy for us to say, "Cool, we are going to be
remote only forever? Let's go." And because we
realized that the temporal shelter in place would
cause a series of events that would make that for
optimal best set of trade-offs for the company.
And so I think this is... Can I put this into a
piffy five-step? I wouldn't know, but maybe it
resonates with someone who can help me figure
out the coded English language for this because it
has been nerdy way the I explained it, even to me.
This remote work example is something I definitely
wanted to touch on, which is I'm glad you got
there. So in this decision, is there anything more
you could share about how you got to that place
of like, "Oh this Boolean changed so we should
rethink this?" Because I know you probably, you
weren't... I don't know. Were you in the shower
and just like, "Oh wow, we should really go remote
because of this"? How did that actually come
about? And then I wanted to ask on another part-
Yeah, pretty much actually yes because again,
I rerun over all the inputs and figure out
what happens. And here's a couple of other things
that were starting to fray on the decision to be
in person as well. We started in Ottawa, Canada,
which is a city of a million people, and it has
some tech heritage and good universities. But at
a million people, it's just not population dense
enough and has a depth of talent pool that it can
support a company that is going to 10,000 people.
So anyone who runs this optimization function
I'm talking about here about location strategy
for a new startup will come to the conclusion if
they do it right that everyone should be sitting
around the same table. Only if you can't do that,
do you say, "Okay, let's be all in the same couple
of rooms." Only if that doesn't work anymore, you
say, "Okay, let's be spread over one floor." If
that doesn't work, in the same building. If that
doesn't work, in the same city. If that doesn't
work, at least stay in the same time zones or make
sure that there's good hub connections between.
This is how it works. It's just like some
assumption somewhere along the line is
invalidated. You end up in a different side of a
decision tree. But what was happening to us was
we already were in four or five cities. We were
adhering to the same time zone at this point. But
my experience was I went through, sometimes at the
Ottawa office, through an entire day where I had
10 hours of meetings, which is fairly normal, but
I do every single... I don't think I had a single
other person sometimes with me because every
one of them was with people in another office.
Some people are dialing in remote and so on. So
there was an awkward hybrid-ness which we ended
up in making only good decisions along the way.
This is actually the most dangerous thing. Most
of the time you end up in a bad part of a tree,
in a local maxima of a path-dependent environment,
by only making good choices. People think that
making a good choice inoculates you from making
mistakes or that the presence of a downside of an
idea ends up disqualifying the idea. Both of those
things are incorrect. So what you need to do
then is... So that was an overlay to decision.
The moment COVID started, then we also had
this thing of shoppers exploding because
we were actually an asset to people during
COVID, e-commerce for the local businesses.
And we took that very, very seriously trying
to make more businesses survive COVID, small
businesses survive this particular calamity than
otherwise won't which is important because small
businesses tend to be wiped out first anytime
the times turn fragile. And so we needed to
staff up. And so there's a very weird question
about where to staff up. So clearly the better
input there would be if you could hire people
everywhere. And so once that decision flipped,
you can see how this is actually now super easy
to say, "We are going to remote," because there
is no turning back. There is no... Even with this
decision, it's a better set of trade-offs for the
future is to accept the vast additional difficulty
of building a remote company. It's way harder.
It's not something you should recommend to anyone
to do this because it's the same as trying to run
a world record marathon run in Aspen, Colorado.
It's like there's not enough oxygen up there to
do that. But if you end up pulling it off,
you're a real Chad. That's very cool. So
I find difficulty itself interesting. And again,
I spent enough of my teenage years on the internet
to know that there's amazing cultures that can
be put together purely remote like, I don't know,
Wikipedia, World of Warcraft, Raiding Guilds
can at least have excellent cultures. And so
we are like, "Okay, cool. Let's come to a new
stable part." That stable part was don't port
the office online. Let's port the internet into
a company and then we are like, "Let's go."
This episode is brought to you by Loom. Loom
lets you record your screen, your camera,
and your voice to share video messages easily.
Record a Loom and send it out with just a link to
gather feedback, add context, or share an update.
So now you can delete that novel-length email
that you are writing. Instead, you can record
your screen and share your message faster. Loom
can help you have fewer meetings and make the
meetings that you do have much more productive.
Meetings start with everyone on the same page
and end early. Problem solved, time saved. We
know that everyone is in a one-take wonder when it
comes to recording videos. So Loom comes with easy
editing and AI features to help you record once
and get back to the work that counts. Save time,
align your team, stay connected, and get
more done with Loom. Now, part of Atlassian,
the makers of Jira. Try Loom for free today
at loom.com/lenny. That's L-O-O-M.com/lenny.
I want to talk about this talent stack concept
that you've touched on a couple of times that
I think so much. But before we get there,
I want to go in a different direction,
which I think is an interesting foundational
element to your ability to be successful in your
first principles thinking, which is you getting
to the metal, to the core of the problems you're
solving by actually spending a lot of time
coding. And I actually heard a story about
how you all had this huge all-hands summit. You
flew everyone in. You're all together. There was a
three-day hackathon. And the way it was described
is you're sitting at a table with headphones in,
coding, just like any IC engineer. No one
would've known you're the CEO of this company,
the founder of this company. Why is coding and
working in the code to you still so important?
It's so funny that that's the way the story
goes. It's right, but I don't know why that
is surprising. That's my happy place, being able
to clear out free days of my calendar and being
there till midnight with all these remarkable
people who join us on journey, just building
stuff. It's like, I do my job so that that is the
jobs that exist for other people. That's a job
I actually want. That's the one I couldn't find
because no one did a company for me. But at least
back in most days, I think still not really.
And so I just love coding. It's one of the
greatest, I don't know, hobbies and pursuits.
I've done it for a very long time. I came across
it very, very early. It fits my brain like a
glove. I appreciate so much of the craft behind
coding. I am a trained apprentice in... Sorry,
I've apprenticed as a programmer in Germany,
which has a dual education system that you can
do such things. So I've been professionally in
companies spending all day. And I really
mean it, programming ever since I just
turned 16. I think first day was just before
I turned 16 when I started my apprenticeship.
And so I love it. I have a view on my
screen left of you is a cursor right now,
which is opened to a Juniper notebook where
I'm working on some projection stuff that
I'm playing with. I try to sanity-check as much
as I can of what I get. I try to find... It's a
game for me to find new insights in data. And
I just think, I don't know, it was cool. Maybe
this is the picture you talk about. There is a
picture that someone captured, which is really
fun where I'm on my laptop with a bunch of
engineers and then Harley, so president,
is on stage DJing. This was taken at 1:00 AM
or something like this. It's a picture which
actually really precious to two of us because
it perfectly summarizes our relationship in a
way which these happy accidents are
wonderful and these long journeys,
I've been doing Shopify for 20 years now, so
I appreciate these artifacts. But yeah, so...
To be clear, the reason this is unusual is, and
why someone told me this story, is most CEOs do
not do this, don't just sit there and code along
with the team. And the reason I thought this story
was important is and the reason I think your first
principle approach works is you're actually in the
engineering details, similar to Elon if you think
about it, of just in the weeds doing the thing,
understanding how the thing works, not just
coming up with ideas out of pontifications.
And so I guess is there anything there of just
how important it is, if you want to approach
thinking from first principles, it is to be
really close to the metal, to the bare metal?
Well, yeah. First principles thinking starts
from, I think Elon puts it as physics,
which I think is a little bit atoms-coded.
I think just from the atomic building blocks
really is a right starting point. Atomic building
blocks are the computers we are using. Computers
are our instruments. We use them to create the
music that when people appreciate to receive in
the form of software. So you've got to understand
how they work, at least to work the way I do.
Now, is the way I work optimal? Of course not.
This is my point about the aesthetics of how to
behave, how to work. I probably don't conform to
the traditional view of what the most of public
companies should be like or even should spend
their time, but I think I'm successful because
I don't try to conform to anything other than
what I've learned works. And so what I learned
works is be in as many details as you can.
Really, really, really just understand the
stuff that we are making decisions about and be
willing to don't put too much stake into the sunk
cost fallacy. Try to inoculate business or your
parts of a company from a sunk cost fallacy as
much as possible because that allows you
to just see better solutions and so on.
And I think what we were doing, if I
remember right, is at hack dates is
we were working through pros or cons of just
merging all of Shopify into one huge monorepo
and we are sketching out directory structures
and tooling that we would need, and...
... tooling that we would need and... Again,
monorepo, now for companies, it's a very much
one of those door A, door B kind of things. It's
a very consequential choice that is incorrect to
go say yes to at a certain size, and then it
becomes very correct in my mind to say yes to,
but at that point it's an enormous amount
of effort. So, it's a kind of thing that
actually is something I'm uniquely positioned
to be involved with because it's actually a
business strategy thing as well. That's an
investment, a very real investment to say,
"Hey, let's change the way we are building
system. Let's figure out what the best way is."
There's going to be change management. There's
going to be some people that have very strong
opinions on yes or no. And frankly, "Tobi said
so.", helps. It also compresses a lot of time,
because everyone knows the way I book. Everyone
can come to me with better ideas about anything,
and if you're right, I will change my mind. But
I will hold my opinions very strongly until the
point of being convinced that they're not
the correct ideas. Maybe that's another
aspect of this Tobi Tornado thing you
talked about earlier, people do fight.
Again, the aesthetics of our times put a
lot of stake into consistency. I remember
various politicians losing campaigns because
they were called flip-floppers at times,
which I... Although, I'm more of a Maynard
Keynes school of... "When the facts change,
I change my opinion. What do you do,
sir?" It sounds like a better OS to go by.
It's awesome, because I'm extracting more of
your algorithm of how you think about stuff.
A few things you just shared are, ( 1.), you need
to be in the details. This is thinking about to be
successful as a first principles thinker is (B.),
you need to be in the details in your case code.
In Elon's case, it's like, build the thing and
be at the factory, sleeping on the floor. As you
said, he's very Adams based. You're more digitally
native. And then also, don't be so reliant on some
costs. Like you said in this Tobi Tornado case,
"I know you've been working on this project,
we're going to kill it, because it's not going
to work better if we do that now versus this.
Just keep going, because we've been going." And
then, coming back to the stuff you've shared
previously is, analyze the path that you've been
on, that the previous products and solutions have
assumed the path dependence of them, and then
don't look at what they've overfit potentially,
that isn't correct. Love it. Okay. This actually
is a good segue to something else that someone
that you work with suggested I ask you,
Farhan, your head of engineering. I asked him,
"What's the best way to get a glimpse into Tobi's
mind?" And it's actually along the lines of what
you just described, which is, the question is
just, what's the best way to disagree with you?
I think just disagree with me. I immediately love
it, honestly. I really crave it. It's very funny.
I know how this really surprises people. And
I actually appreciate it even more because it
requires courage, and frankly, I actually do find
that... But it also makes me immediately trust the
person more, partly because I, first of all, think
they will do what they think is right rather than
what is convenient. Agreeing with a group tends
to be much more convenient. But more than that
actually, that they're courageous enough to do
it right then. I think courage is really, really
rare. I found a lot more high IQ in industry than
courage. I found a lot more maybe even genius than
courage. I like that. I wish it wouldn't require
that. This is why I try to be very inviting of it.
When someone disagrees with me, I tend
to immediately stop and say, "Cool,
let's figure out why there's disagreement."
And it's almost never, I find, in the, "I just
feel like we should do this differently." What
I'm looking for is offer unstated foundational
assumptions. What is our divergence point? Because
you might be right. In fact, people often are,
when it gets to this point, I found. Sometimes
it's an unstated foundational assumption that I
hold that is incorrect. People tell me and then
I'm so glad we talked about it, because I will
stop forever nagging on this thing because now
I know we can't do it because of Sarbanes-Oxley
or something like this. It's just like, "Well,
cool." My mental model of Sarbanes-Oxley, which is
regulation for public companies, is not perfect. I
have not in-depth studied all the details for it,
so I will not consult this in my mind when I
am saying, hey, we should solve the task at
hand in a certain way. So, this is very good.
How to disagree? I really like debate. I will
play devil's advocate actively if everyone
agrees on something. Again, especially if a
proposal is something that feels like I could
have predicted would be a proposal before it
got into the meeting and there was nothing
surprising in it, I will make myself an end
boss of a level and just say, "I'm going to say
this is just not that good. I think we could do
way better." I want people to then argue more
in-depth for the veracity of the decisions,
and that leads to a form of disagreement. I
think all these things end up building trust.
I like that that touches also on this
idea of, again, maximizing potential,
the potential of the teams,
the potential of the employees
Because of course, the really important decisions,
we don't talk about. This is the most important
thing. Shopify probably makes... What?... millions
of decisions every day, like, write this code this
way, yes, I'm going to add this unit test, maybe
I'm skipping a unit test. Might be the difference
between a future production audit. Millions and
millions of these tiny decisions. So, you're
not hiring engineers primarily or accountants,
you're hiring people who make excellent decisions,
given their specialization and areas they're
overseeing. And given that, decision making as
a concept is actually really understudied, I find.
I think these are instances where we can just
learn to make decision making together.
Because I think while a lot of decisions
are made independently, we are a product company,
we are on a mission, and we want our product to
feel like something that a single person made,
in the same way how any author tries to write a
book that clearly reads that it came from one
mind. Because people can see and spot this,
if this doesn't happen. You end up with
something that looks like a television remote,
where there's a Netflix button over here... It's
like you can reverse [inaudible 00:59:41] from
the remote control. That's important.
Using these moments and also bringing
decision making inwards to go and
say, hey, let's have very efficient
opportunities for as many people that can
possibly get together, make decisions together,
not as a democracy but with clear who needs to
convince who. That because otherwise this ends up
just taking way too long. Give a opportunity for
everyone to change my mind over Glenn's mind, and
so on, is an excellent practice, I find. I think
this is a more optimal way of going about it.
Speaking of disagreeing, it reminded me of a
story I heard, about the Tobi Tornado actually,
the way you operate that. I love it. It ends
up being this interesting microcosm of your
first principle's way of thinking. The story
is, I think you've said at one point that the
best way to get people to give you insights is to
say something they disagree with on the internet.
Yeah.
That's often the way you approach this
is, you post in a Slack group, "Hey,
I don't think this product is going to work, and
here's why." And that ends up creating the most
information for you. Is there anything along
those lines that might be helpful to share?
I don't think that's one of my
better ways of doing that. I have
to be somewhat careful. The people
I worked with a lot, I will do this,
just because it's funny. But even I can see that
that would seriously stress out the interns.
You guys have a lot of interns. I think
you have 1,000 interns this coming year,
is what Farhan shared.
Yeah, we just started. I was
in the office yesterday and
it's absolutely full of interns. It's great.
Oh, man. Love interns, so much energy. This
idea that you shared about building one product,
building towards one vision, this actually
reminds me of something that came up basically
every time I had someone from Shopify
on, which is this idea of a 100-year
vision that you keep. I don't know of any
other company that operates in this way,
where the founder has this 100-year
vision of where the product needs to go
and working backwards from that.
Can you just speak to that,
of that way of operating, why you find
that helpful, how that actually works?
I talk about look in the future and then think
backwards a lot. What would we want to have done
20 years ago on this, or 10 or 5 years ago?
What's the decision our future selves would
want us to make, is useful. I find future
casting to be generally extremely valuable.
I definitely did not build Shopify to flip. I had
lots of opportunities to sell Shopify to various
people. I didn't consider it, because it's just
too interesting of a journey and I think that's
too... If a endpoint [inaudible 01:02:34] all
companies is a convergence on a set of four or
five people who can afford them, that just creates
too much of a monoculture, I think, in thinking.
I like that Shopify is different. I think this
is good. I think it's a terrible place to work
for many, many, many people. It's the best
place in the world to work for some people.
That's so good. That's what we want, I think.
We want more of this. We want people to be
able to window-shop for a place where they can
be enormously successful, because the place's
set of beliefs just fits you like a glove.
100 years. We have very long-term plans. 100
years, you can't talk about this software product,
but you can talk about the mission itself,
whatever things that will survive for 80 years
that are left on this particular timeframe.
Entrepreneurship is just precious. Shopify exists,
basically you make entrepreneurship more common.
That is the thing we wanted to cause in the world.
We have had, I think, success doing this already,
but again, there's no speed limit and no stopping
point for this. As I keep saying, the word's
unbelievably path dependent. And therefore, if we
are part of a path, we can cause it to be more in
adherence to the things that we value and would
like to see. This is the wonderful thing about
company building. They can have lasting impact.
We are making decisions based on all the things
that we can do. What are the things that will
be most long-term valuable for the long-term
pursuits we are on, and how can we normalize
entrepreneurship? It's a thing that's really
important to me, just because people don't
spend enough time on it. It's all economics.
Our [inaudible 01:04:44] living entirely depends
on businesses. We are all part and tag of an
environment that is extremely entrepreneurial
and actually celebrates entrepreneurship as
a courageous act and a glorious act even.
But that's not true in most of the world. In fact,
most people never encounter anyone who engages
in doing that. It's not something people see
as one of their options. I want us to make
these choices. And I think the long-term
focus matters. It's also really powerful for
decision making. And I know this is potentially
intuitive to most, but also rarely practiced.
You've had a lot of people from Stripe on here.
Stripe and Shopify have had a very long-term
partnership. Stripe and Shopify had potentially
the most valuable partnership, or at least one of
the top ones in history, of technology, because
we were both very small companies and we decided,
hey, let's work on an assumption that both of us
are going to win our markets, and work together.
So, Stripe's [inaudible 01:06:02] for payments and
we're allowed a part of Stripe and so on.
When you're in a partnership like this,
you play basically iterated prisoner's dilemma.
Every instance, every turn you can make a choice:
coordinate or defect, defecting if the other
person collaborates, collaborator effect. If both
collaborate, everyone gets a point. If one defects
and the other one collaborates, you get a lot of
points, all at one moment. Being a good partner in
business is like this corporate marshmallow test
that companies tend to fail in a very funny way.
If you see the videos of kids doing actual actual
marshmallow tests, the smart ones actually turn
the chair around, look away from the marshmallow,
and sit on their hands, and just go vibrating.
Because they know it's the right thing to wait
for getting two marshmallows in the future,
but man, if they just look at a marshmallow,
they'll just eat it. Most CEOs, most companies
can't even successfully do that and just engage
in pulling future profits forward at a
discount or even defecting on partnerships
that would be much more long-term valuable.
If you're talking about long timeframes, like
100 years, there is no question. But clearly, the
correct way to play iterated prisoner's dilemma is
coordinate for both sides. It's way more valuable
[inaudible 01:07:27] doing that over long periods
of time than any momentary defection could
possibly be convenient at a moment. It's a huge
amount of product decisions. When we are deciding
roadmap, end up being very influenced by this,
because I get pitches for things we should do and
why don't we do this kind of change to the system,
there's so much money in it, and all
these kind of things. I'm like, cool,
but almost always come in a form of putting
future profits forward at a discount.
But we have a long time horizon. Let's not take
the discount, let's... Also, you often compromise
the entire business after a while because you
end up just... Your customers notice if you're
going into value extraction. The best companies, I
believe, at least from a perspective of a leader,
resemble some kind of cockpit, or maybe a room
full of dials or levers for monetization. My job
is adding as many of these levers as possible
to the room, and then not pulling any of them.
Because I think we do best if we are on the same
side of a table of our customers and we had them
become entrepreneurs, which is a mission, and we
want to support them to be more successful, which
is the business model we are in. We get a very,
very small stake of the sales in our monetization
system. And therefore, we are incentivized
to make everyone as successful as possible.
Again, when I get a PowerPoint from investment
bankers or so, where they tell me I have enormous
pricing power and I could massively change the
prices, I'm like, "Yeah, but I'd leave Shopify
if that happens to me, so how is that good?"
He's just like, "Why?" It just goes like that.
There's a quote that you wrote somewhere that,
to me, identifies this point so
succinctly, "On a long enough timeline,
playing positive-sum games with your customers
is the ultimate growth hack." Yeah, beautiful.
I think that's pretty piffy and it's
also just... Try to argue with it.
That's true.
Positive-sum games have incredible returns,
especially in the worlds of software,
where you can experience exponentials very
easily. I see company building as... I
wish there would be better analogy than chess,
because chess is a game of perfect information,
which is totally incorrect. But one thing which
I like about chess as an analogy for business is
that it basically is two games, that you have to
be good at at both. There's a positional game that
you learn: Develop your pieces, gain influence
by your pieces over the board. That's really,
really important. And then there's tactics, which
you learn tactic training. You go get a puzzle
trainer and you drill tactics and you learn the
intuition to sports tactics, sense them. Both of
them are actually super independent of each other.
The business world only talks about tactics.
It only talks about the conversion of we did this
thing. We did an A/B test and we changed the color
of blue, and conversion red went up. We lionize
the easy hack. I don't think that's important,
honestly. You need to be good enough at tactics to
not go out of business. You can't get margin code,
sure. But the sum total of all the
value of a potential tactics that you
could employ stays with you if you are
actually are doing the positional game.
The positional game is like, what is the territory
on the map that you are taking? What role do you
play? How much trust do you have of merchants? Do
merchants want more from you or less? Are you the
kind of thing they're trying to optimize out of
their software spend, or the one that they ask to
subsume all other software spend? Do they rely on
you? Are you part of a team, or are you used as a
tool in the toolbox, usually forgotten, sometimes
coming out when certain task is being done? What
does your product cover? What industries are you
addressing? And so on, so on, so on. This is the
positional game. How well do pieces fit together?
Do people like relying even deeper on you?
If you do that well, the tactics are yours
and you can hire a lot of people who are
extraordinarily good at spotting tactics
and using them. But if you do it too much,
you end up extracting through tactics the
entirety of the value that you have created
and that is yours to take through a positional
game. And if you do that, you have nothing left
in the tank. That's for companies that we all
see, that just got to a point and then just
fade. Those are the companies that
got tacticked out of their position.
The skill, obviously, is finding the balance
between these two things of short-term,
not get margin calls, as you
described, but also think ahead.
Is there any kind of heuristic for
founders listening to this who are like,
"How do I do this? How much should I be
thinking about the future versus now?",
I guess? How do you try to create this
pie chart of driving goals immediately
and show investors we're killing
it, while also thinking ahead?
Is there a good heuristic? Objective number one
is: Don't die. Again, in the end, for companies
that become historic companies are the ones
which did not die. It also sounds very basic,
but actually it's more actionable than it
might seem. Past that point, I would argue:
Just focus on the positional game. I think this
is where a bit of a discrepancy of the founder and
the rest of the company sometimes lies. I think
the founders create finite, winnable games for
people, that are very much serving the infinite
game of developing, that the mission implies,
the quality of position on the board.
By the way, it's an infinite board. Just
picture the chess board as the initial
terrain, but there's, I don't know,
fog on the board and it's a terrain that's much
larger that you will explore over time. I think
that's the most prettiest way of mentally thinking
about the experience of building a company. It's
an exploration and a collaborative inquiry into a
question that is implied by the mission. And you
will get to explore how correct your mission
is and how good your decision making is along
the way. And you get to learn a lot, and this
is why I think it's a valuable thing to do.
But they often, the founders, and the mission
of a company are in alignment, but they are,
again, non-quantifiable things. They are
pursuits. Maybe as time horizons that go past,
all of our time horizons of our careers, therefore
that makes it hard for people to care deeply yet.
But they do care about the instances, the games
along the way, the [inaudible 01:15:24] that have
to be done to explore a part of a map,
the tactics that have to be executed.
I'm not going to take us here, but I know you're a
big fan of this book, Finite and Infinite Games. I
actually had it once at a book club and it blew my
mind open. I'm going to link to it. People should
check it out. You've talked about this on another
podcast. I'm not going to [inaudible 01:15:40].
Yeah, it's a lovely book. James Carse did
an incredible, underappreciated... I think
they essentially wrote one of the best
business books. They is trying to write
a hard philosophy book. I don't know
if it works for its intended purpose,
but I think there's more value in what
he actually accomplished. Maybe, sadly,
it may be that he didn't know before
he died, which would be very sad.
It's a little hard to read for people...
Yes.
... so just stick with it
and just try to wrap your
head around what he's trying to say, is my advice.
I think reading... I don't know how many it is,
but... the first couple of chapters really helps
you get your arms around the story, his insight.
The rest of the book are examples of his ideas
applied. My takeaway from reading his examples
is that he did not fully appreciate the insight of
his own idea. It just ends up being very locally
limited and very narrow-focused. It's a much
grander idea than I think he really... This
is why I say I don't think he fully
appreciated quality of his own idea, which...
I think we need a Tobi version of
this book, with a foreword, and...
I heard Simon Sinek...
Uh-huh.
... wrote a book of a similar title. I've
actually never gotten around to read it,
but I think he would be very good at
interpreting this if that's what he did.
That's what it sounds like. I feel like his
book is that book, written in a different way.
I want to come back to something you talked
about, which is focusing on entrepreneurship and
the merchants that you all work with. To me, this
is another example of maximizing human potential.
The way I think about this, people always talk
about Y Combinator and Stanford and all these
places that create all these companies
and founders. If you think about it,
Shopify does this orders of magnitude beyond,
and I don't think you guys get enough credit
for that, the amount of businesses you
create, the amount of lives you change.
That's because we don't want
the credit. That's the point.
Is there a platform?
We don't want the credit.
No.
I mean, maybe if you wanted it, you could also
not get it, but we don't need to explore that
because we actually, literally don't
want the credit. Shopify is a company
that pushes from behind. We don't want to be
written into the story. We want to just...
... want to be written into the story, we
want to just kind of have you do your thing.
There's just too much grandeur in wanting to
front it all. This is also what caused us to
go and help people build their own things rather
than start with a marketplace that everyone gets
to lease a little component of at prices that
corresponds to magically exactly your margin,
as this usually goes in marketplaces. And so
yeah, I think we don't want it. I'm proud of it,
but that's intrinsic. I don't need very extrinsic
appreciation for it, I suppose. There's millions,
millions and millions of people that use Shopify
daily and that represents the business and
it causes major amount of employment around
the world actually, definitely in North America
specifically and Europe. And so I think that's
really gratifying. I'm sure there's a way of
saying that many of us businesses might
actually have existed without Shopify.
I also think you can make a case that a good
number exists because of Shopify, because what
we've observed is that this was actually, it's my
favorite thing in the entire Shopify journey that
we sort of rigorously determined, which is that
because I really, really, really prioritize good
UX, legible interfaces. You can tame enormous
complexity with great UX in a way that makes
sense to people. I think this is actually almost
a moral obligation to do for software because when
software goes bad, it makes people feel dumb and
machines do not get to negatively influence people
in my mind. That is the inversion of the priority
of the hierarchy of how machines are tools wielded
by people to be more powerful at the things that
they're already great at than they might imagine.
That's when this all needs to fit together,
but beyond the moral point, which is 10 years,
and you could definitely take the other side of
what we have determined is that every single time
we make a complex thing simpler. It is actually
that more businesses will exist on a platform.
So I think this is intuitive or at least
directional, but sometimes people are not like,
"Well, don't you just need to have all these
features?" This is the RFP view of a world
of software, right? "Don't you need to just have
all the features then people can implement their
plan?" Well, no. Think about the mental state
and entrepreneurship entrepreneurs, they are,
I mean especially if you're first entrepreneurs,
they're unsophisticated. They don't know what to
do. They're kind of scared. By the way, engaging
in building something again is an act of pure
courage and usually one which is very hard
to hide from others. The people around you
will know that you're doing this thing. Ask any
entrepreneur. The amount of people who tell you
to not do this is actually stunning. People do
not want people to just step out of a box that
exists that they sort of explain to themselves
around them and have a chance of reaching
higher because that would sort of invalidate
their own life story in some meaningful way.
So there's actually a whole lot of nay saying
that discourages people already, which is not
super helpful. So now you have a situation where
people are telling you to quit potentially,
you don't have a lot of money presumably,
you're asking yourself, are you even doing
the right thing? Hopefully there's some elements
of encouragement. Hopefully there's a passion.
Hopefully you're trying to create a thing. Then
comes to a situation that stuns you in some way,
somewhere where suddenly the software starts
talking about APIs where this is something you've
never encountered in your life before or that
just the option that you think it should have on
the text configuration screen doesn't make sense
given what we know about local taxes and so on.
Here's the thing that happens. So the beautiful
thing with Shopify is there's basically no tax
configuration screen. It's just correct. The
amazing thing about software is we can actually
just overtake this piece of complexity.
We know what the taxes are everywhere and
we are just doing it for you. You don't have to
think about taxes. In this case we have someone
encountered something that stunned them, that
stopped them in their tracks. On the wrong day,
what that means, it's like they are
going to close a browser and they say,
"You know what? Fuck it. I'm not cut out for
this." Or, "This piece of software I use sucks and
it's too dumb for understanding the thing I
have in my head," or something else. Everyone
has a different rendering of the same thing,
but just like progress stops. It is not just
the businesses that shouldn't exist anyway
that stop in this way. In fact, it's actually,
and this is again what the data says, so many
businesses get very close to this point many,
many times. I can tell you Shopify did many times
and I have more tools on entrepreneurial journey
than most. I'm a computer programmer and I
love those things. You tell me I can spend
14 hours programming for the next couple
of years. I'm like, "Holy shit, let's go."
Most people aren't like that. So I've had
unfair advantages that allowed me to overcome
very technical climbs on this learning curve,
but I know that's like most people can't have
these advantages and therefore will churn out of a
test. And so in other words, lowering complexity,
making good UX, creating software that just
autopilots taxes or payments or any of these
kinds of things, fraud, actually causes more
entrepreneurship. That is the best thing,
the best answer to the most important question
of my life that I've encountered because up
to this point it was an intuition that doing the
Shopify thing would be valuable in absolute sense,
in a hundred-year sense. Afterwards I knew, right?
And so that also just means now seeing things that
are overly complex or shouldn't even be there,
it's just physically painful because I know,
it's like all these business that are trying
to get somewhere and could exist and could
now employ people and delight customers just
died along the way because of something we
did wrong or poorly and so on. And so this is
a great source of energy for me to keep going.
I feel that, I feel that pain of the idea of
anytime a button's broken or it's not as...
the button's wrong color and more people would be
converting means that you're not creating as many
businesses, many entrepreneurs. The feeling you
described of being scared to launch something,
I exactly felt that when I started the newsletter.
And my solution to that as I launched it is,
"I'm just launching this as an experiment. We'll
see where it goes, just don't worry about it. I
might blog once in a while." And that really
helped just lowering the stakes and I could
see how just things like that and advice
that can help someone get over that hump.
Yes, and I think this is an under explored
thing in the word of UX. Random example,
I was absolutely delighted by, maybe TikTok has
the same thing, I don't know, but I was posting a
video to Instagram and it allowed me to run a try
run of the reel. It just seems like a new feature
and just saying it shows it to a couple hundred
people out of network and if they like it then
it's going to post to my profile. I'm like, "I
don't need that." But I thought that was one of
the more... I honestly just closed Instagram and
was like, "Holy shit, this is probably one of the
most profound insightful pieces of software I've
encountered. And as a connoisseur of good ideas,
I've never had this as a valuable thing."
It feels like a step function upgrade to the
traditional A-B test as a concept because it's
so understandable and I'm like, "What else in
the world should have try runs that run out
of network?" Basically everything, isn't it?
This is an amazing thing. Like I said, the rarest
thing in the world, it's not even creativity or
genius, it's courage. So let's lower the
net amount of courage needed. Honestly,
that's one of those things you can probably
run an entire career or reinvent an industry
on. These things unfurl into incredible
amounts of value if you really pursue
them and come at them from first principles
rather than how can I do the things I want to
do anyway slightly better because of insight.
That's good and people should always do it,
but not usually where most of the value ends
up becoming, like manifests when a new idea
comes around. So I talk radically about an
Instagram feature. That's a weird thing to do,
but I was actually just really to delighted
because again, it just came up a few days ago.
I love this thread of courage. The
example you gave reminds me also of
I feel like going on a dating app at
a different city for the first time
is another example of this where
it's a dry run, nobody knows you.
But even then, shouldn't there be like, "Hey,
post my profile to a different city
for telling me if it's any good."
SO people like it.
I mean I've never dated basically so I
mean at least not in the last 25 years.
Yeah, of the podcast.
So I'm pre swipe left and right dating, so
my conception is very low of this. Maybe I
should look more at dating apps. I'm pretty
sure there's some amazing UX in most things.
I imagine. I feel like dating is going offline
more and more. I'm feeling like that's what people
are trying to do. They're tired of the swipe, but
anyway, going to go in that direction. Maybe a
couple more questions while I have you here. One
is this idea of the talent stack. You've mentioned
this concept before and this is the term that I've
seen you describe it as of this idea of the power
of focusing on your unique talents and curiosity
and that leading you to the biggest opportunities,
especially early in your career. Can you
just talk about what your insight there.
Yeah, again, I only lived one life, so I can't
Monte Carlo all the decisions I make and just
figure out which ones ended up being load baring,
right? I'm at this point pretty amused by the
following thing which keeps happening. But I am
getting curious about some absolutely random thing
and it really is fairly far-flung stuff and like
magic it becomes the way that ends up allowing me
to make a very important choice a year later. It's
ends up being a better analogy that I've learned
or a different way to see something or another
idea that I found being represented in this
area of expertise that is actually just again,
another repackaging of another foundational idea,
which allows me to go and look for more examples.
And it's just funny this way. So even early in
career just I followed my curiosity. I love
programming and I love computers and I loved
the internet when it came along and I just
like, "Cool, I'm going to find a task that
I find valuable," which I was always engaged in
retail and I have a lot to say about how retail
should be brought by the internet to people. But
this is a beautiful intersection of all the things
that I find interesting. And then on top of it,
I found Ruby, which I loved as a technology and
then just now I was highly motivated to tinker,
explore a space that was clearly emerging but
just felt very obviously of value in the future.
But I didn't do it because I was following money.
I did it because I like learning by doing
stuff and I like tinkering the things and
so this was a way of financing my tinkering
by selling snowboards and then it led to other
things. And I've kind of been doing that thing
all along. It's great fun, great fun for me.
I don't know how much of a advice that is, but
maybe a proof point that can work really well.
I sometimes worry though that things like this
end up being a little bit like all you need to
do is buy a lottery ticket, set for lottery
ticket winner, right? So it's, who knows?
It does resonate. It reminds me of
something Brian Armstrong once shared,
which is the reason that he-
He's also, by the way, you have to add him
to the set of first principle thinkers if
you're starting to cultivate one. And I
think there's plenty of startup success,
successful founders, CEOs, especially for
public companies are surprisingly alike
in this projecting slightly different,
maybe coming from different backgrounds,
but Brian is extraordinarily strong at
this [inaudible 01:32:06] by the way.
Okay, here's to the next nominated for
the podcast, Brian. We'll get on it. But
interestingly, he had basically exact same advice
for what allowed him to create Coinbase is his
background was economics, coding and cryptography
or something along those lines. And it's the Venn
diagram, is like, "This is the thing I'm uniquely
strong at and have an opportunity to win it."
Yeah. So this is what we very actively tell our
customers, right? There's a 2005 essay by Kevin
Kelly saying, "In the future on the internet you
just need a thousand true fans." It's what the
internet and I think what Shopify celebrates,
that instead of trying to create toothpaste,
which is of course a huge term but hard to
differentiate. It's much better to figure out
a triplicate intersection of three different
things and nail it. We took a winter vacation
with my boys and my family in the Caribbean and I
like playing poker with them. I like playing poker
and it's great limited information game. I think
this were valuable for kids and so I found this,
I might have mentioned this in some place, but
I found this pirate gold I think it's called.
It's just amazing poker set, poker chips that look
like they come right out of the treasure chest or
in Pirates of the Caribbean. Think about just the
intersection, so this is online Texas Hold'em,
quality poker set instead of... because you can
play with just anything, right? People were in
the market for spending money on something like
this and pirate themed. You're like, " But I'm
such a big fan, I'm telling you about it and
people might actually purchase it because I'm
enthusiastic about it." And because enthusiasm
is actually the best marketing and they have
at least a thousand true fans, and it's just
better to make amazing things for some people
than make something that everyone wants maybe
or would tolerate. And I think that's really,
really good. So I think that works for your career
too because by the way, we are all entrepreneurs
so we're ready to think about any career.
If you actually ask me for career advice is we are
products, we are engaged in entrepreneurship, we
are basically software as a service if you want,
or talent as a service. We are selling a
subscription in the form of our employment
we call it, but it's actually just rebranded the
subscription frankly because it comes some extra
protection, which is very good, but it's still
the same thing, it's a double opt-in company.
Like you would say, I can do these things and I
will be of significantly more value to the company
than you will have to spend on me. There's like a
positive ROI ideally for a company and a company
either says, "I agree or I don't agree with
you." And that's actually what employment is.
So I think people should think about themselves
as a product. Your career is not based on
mentors you find or getting a promotion or not.
It's about what are you too good to ignore in?
How good can you be? Can you be absolutely work?
Can you be excellent? I mean you don't have to be
work class and stuff, but you have to... Ideally
you find a thing where you are just in this sort
of tiny space of five intersections or so versus
we just know more than everyone else and then
everyone calls you. Like I said, we use Ruby. Ruby
was not that fast. Shopify would rather have it
very fast. We found people who got PhDs in dynamic
language, garbage collection dynamic language,
just in time compilation to make Ruby fast.
And they're having delightful time at Shopify
and Shopify is now very fast and it's very good.
And everyone gets to profit from us needing this
because we merged it back into Ruby Core and now
everyone can have a JIT compiler. So it's great.
I feel like every story is a fractal into other
hours of other podcast conversation we can have.
I know you have to go run this nine, 10,
10,000 person company and do real work.
So I'm going to end it there. We got through
almost everything I was hoping to get through,
but there's infinitely more questions
I still have. Just to maybe end it, is
there anything you want to leave listeners with?
Any last nugget that maybe you didn't mention?
If I get to talk to again people who
look at product and product management,
here's my thing that I think maybe
only implicitly came through in all
this. Every product in the world, the
quality at the end of the day is simply
a reflection of how much the people who
created it gave a shit about the product.
And it is not possible to make great products if
the people work on it do not give a shit about
the product. And I actually think this is a very
important role for product leaders to make sure
that the team gives a shit. And I think this is
something that can be done with building empathy
for people using it, but also it can be done
infectiously by the product leader. The product
leader has to give a shit. Do not engage in
product work on product that you don't care
about because you cannot produce the thing that
the person will give you a task is looking for.
And I think again, so much goes into this
unquantifiable conversation which we already had,
but boy is that important because it just isn't
about the brief document, it isn't about the
aligning stakeholders. Sometimes in some places
some of those things are aspects of it and I think
they correlate sometimes with people. But I think
the higher order bit is if you are in product,
you have basically free roads. You have to
have the team sits, look around corners that
they don't see. You just have to understand this
thing that's being done better than everyone else
because that's a role. Now, you don't have to do
this by yourself. Everyone on the team is of a
resource to you and you can query them and
therefore determine what is around the corners
and so on. But in engineering and UX and so on,
but that's very important. Second is you've got
to be exothermically infectious with actually
caring about this thing because just that one
thing alone will make a 10 times better product.
It's crazy how much of a change this makes.
I feel like honestly what you're
describing here is like founder mode,
what the outputs are. Giving a shit,
being exothermic excited and looking
around corners. I feel like this
is its own conversation here.
Yeah, I agree. I don't think founder mode, so
I mean I think, yeah, founder mode is a super
valuable term, but I actually do think that I
answered the question about what I think about
founder mode in the discussion about pumping
heat into systems. That's what I do. It's just
that founder mode in a founder run company, I
think this has an easier time existing because
people dislike the people who are pumping heat
into a thing. People fight them, people probably
take them out, and if the boss is like this,
boss can protect the other people like this.
And therefore I think founder run companies can be
innovative longer because there's a substrate by
which this can stay a thing for a long time. So
anyway, that's my tear down on the founder mode
discussion, which I think is a really fascinating
recent discussion. I find it's very valuable. I'm
sure it's misunderstood in all sorts of ways, but
I think it's more actionable than people think.
Tobi, I appreciate you continuing to drop
nuggets, even though I know you have to go,
by the way, your video looks incredible
right now. This is amazing editing,
we're doing like a rainbow
streaming across your body.
Yeah, we really hit the rainbows here like,
"Let's go and invent." I hope you've
got to gold that you were hoping and-
So much gold.
... I was sufficient leprechaun here to deliver.
What a metaphor. Okay, Tobi, thank you so much
for doing this. This was incredible. I feel like
this is going to help so many people build great
companies and thank you from first principles.
Okay, I got to run. Bye-bye.
Okay, bye.
Thank you so
much for listening. If you found this valuable,
you can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.