One of our users yesterday submitted feedback.
(instrumental music)
They were saying, "v0 is like a super genius
five-year-old PhD with ADHD." I'm not going
to oversell this. It knows everything about
everything, but it has these sparks of brilliance.
How do you think things are going to change
for product managers, for product teams?
People could be more full stack. Imagine a
designer that can ship a fully baked product,
a product manager that can prototype
and ship to production. We shouldn't
put limits on ourselves and what
we can build, and what we can ship,
and what we can dream about making
possible on these web surfaces.
A lot of people are wondering, "What happens
to engineers? Should I learn how to code?"
A lot of the programming jobs to be
done that used to be specializations,
I think, are going away, in a
way. They're translation tasks,
but knowing how things work under the hood
is going to be very important for you because
you're going to be able to influence the model
and make it follow your intention a lot better.
We hear this word taste all the
time, in terms of building taste,
people are always like,
"How the hell do I do that?"
Taste, sometimes I think we think
of as this inaccessible thing that,
"Oh, that person was born with taste." I
see it as a skill that it can develop. I
think is extremely important to try lots
of products. We have one of our internal
operating principles as increasing exposure
hours. Try to quantify how much time you expose
yourself to watching how people use your
products and you'll develop that muscle.
Where do you think the biggest
change is going to happen?
We need to stop talking about AI at
some point. I just see a future where
AI becomes synonymous with software. We build
software and we use software to build software.
Today my guest is Guillermo Rauch. Guillermo is
the founder and CEO of Vercel, which, amongst
other things, makes a product called v0, which has
become one of the most popular AI website building
tools in the world. He's also a legendary engineer
and contributor to open source. He's created some
of those popular JavaScript frameworks in the
world like Next.js and Socket.IO. He's both a
builder and is building a product that's going
to change the way we all build products in the
future. This episode is incredible. If you want
to really understand how product development is
going to change with the rise of AI and what
skills you should be focusing on right now,
I highly recommend you keep listening.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't
forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. Also,
if you become a yearly subscriber of my
newsletter, you get a year free of Linear,
Notion, Superhuman, Perplexity Pro, and
Granola. Check it out at lennysnewsletter.com.
With that, I bring you Guillermo Rauch.
This episode is brought to you by WorkOS.
If you're building a SaaS app, at some point
your customers will start asking for enterprise
features like SAML authentication and SCIM
provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in, making
it fast and painless to add enterprise features
to your app. Their APIs are easy to understand so
that you can ship quickly and get back to building
other features. Today, hundreds of companies are
already by WorkOS, including ones you probably
know like Vercel, Webflow and Loom. WorkoOs also
recently acquired Warrant, the fine-grained
authorization service Warrant's product is
based on a groundbreaking authorization system
called Zanzibar, which was originally designed
for Google to power Google Docs and YouTube. This
enables fast authorization checks at enormous
scale while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases. If
you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features
like single sign-on, SCIM, or user management, you
should consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in replacement
for Auth0 and supports up to one million
monthly active users for free. Check it out
at WorkOS.com to learn more. That's workos.com.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta. When it
comes to ensuring your company has top-notch
security practices, things get complicated
fast. Now you can assess risk, secure the trust of
your customers, and automate compliance for SOC 2,
ISO 27001, HIPAA, and more with a single platform,
Vanta. Vanta's market-leading trust management
platform helps you continuously monitor compliance
alongside reporting and tracking risk. Plus,
you can save hours by completing security
questionnaires with Vanta AI. Join thousands
of global companies that use Vanta to automate
evidence collection, unify risk management,
and streamline security reviews. Get $1,000 off
Vanta when you go to vanta.com/lenny. That's
V-A-N-T-A.com/lenny. Guillermo, thank you so
much for being here. Welcome to the podcast.
Thanks for having me. Longtime listener,
first time, I guess participating
in the podcast, and love being here.
Oh, I appreciate that. Okay, I know you saw
this, I did this survey recently where I
asked my readers, "What tools do you use most
in your day-to-day work as a product builder,
as or product manager?" And in the category of
engineering tools, v0 came in right below Cursor
and GitHub for people's most used AI building
tools. So clearly people love what you're doing.
Yeah, we're very happy to see that. And for us,
we're at the very beginning of the journey in some
ways, because v0 is a relatively new tool, but for
Vercel, our company has been around for a while.
The way that I explain to people is, "Anytime
you're using the internet, if there's a website
or web application that's really fast, innovative,
hopefully it's running on our platform." We're
out there. We are running a lot of websites at
scale. If you watched the Super Bowl recently,
three different companies were promoting digital
products that were built and delivered on Vercel.
So not only can you deploy your ideas
and build them on Vercel, they can scale
to huge volumes of traffic and huge audiences.
So a lot of people know us because of a framework
called Next.js. It's an open source framework
based on the React technology, open source by
Meta, and it powers some of the most innovative
products on the internet. So when you use Claude,
or Grok, or Midjourney, you're using Next.js.
You're using Vercel's technologies. So with v0,
what we're trying to do is, and it's funny,
because you put us rightfully, I think,
in the building or development category in that
survey, but what we're trying to do with v0 is
help more people participate in building software,
increase the total addressable market of people
that are actually shipping things, shipping
real products. And at the same time, just
like you would with ChatGPT, we want v0 to be just
extremely, extremely easy, and the outputs that it
generates, make them as refined and realistic
as possible. The things that you created with
v0 hopefully live up to that standard set by some
of the best and largest websites on the internet.
I was going to ask you how v0 came out of Vercel,
and my theory was it was like you guys are sitting
around being like, "How do we get more people
building websites?" And it's like, "Okay,
let's just help them do it really easily."
It's like TAM expansion for Vercel. Is that?
Yeah.
Or it-
In some ways what I've been doing for not only
10 years that I've been almost working on Vercel,
but maybe my entire life because my strength
as a developer is kind of meta. It's been to
create developer tools. So I've created a bunch of
open source frameworks that are really popular. So
Next.js is one, but before that in a previous
life, I created another tool called Socket.IO,
which is a real-time communication mechanism that
powers, for example, every time you use Notion,
I think you interviewed Ivan, when
Notion is to broadcast messages in
real time to other collaborators, they use a
real-time engine that I built for Socket.IO.
So the reason that startups and companies have
used my products in the past is because I took
something that was very difficult to do, but very
compelling. It was with real-time in the past.
It's building cutting-edge applications on the
web with Next.js. And I try to make it as easy as
possible. But you still needed to know development
skills. For us and the opportunity was if there
is maybe five million React developers, which is
the the library engine that we use, and there's
maybe 20 million JavaScript developers, how many
product builders are people with aspirations of
building products exist? My back of the napkin,
minimum calculation is a hundred million.
And I'll tell you, it's funny where I get that
number from. Slack has about a hundred million
monthly active users. And what you do on Slack
is you go in IT and you talk to people. A lot
of those people are building digital products.
And they talk to one another about what they
would want to see in the world. They talk
to customers through shared channels. I
love that feature. We talk to a lot of the
Vercel customers and they tell us, like,
"I want to build this, I want to see that.
I want this feature, I want that thing."
So the opportunity with v0 was, it's not that
you're going to stop talking to other people,
but what if you could yap into the computer and
see something happen, build a prototype, build
your first version of a product, build a demo,
build a full stack product, build it and ship it?
And so the inspiration for it was very natural
to the mission of Vercel. But concretely, the
genesis, the story was when ChatGPT came out, we
noticed that it was very good at writing the code
that our tools used. So ChatGPT, right out of the
bat, was good at JavaScript, was good at Tailwind,
which is a CSS styling technology, was good at
Next.js, and again, the power of open source. Our
tools were already in the training data of the
internet. And so that long-term bet and vision
in open source really paid off. So because the
models were so good at writing this kind of code,
the idea for v0 came naturally from, "What if we
could build a ChatGPT for building web products?"
Speaking of that, I didn't actually know. So I had
Bolt's CEO on the podcast and he talked about how
Claude kind of unlocked what they're doing and
do you guys sit on ChatGPT and OpenAI's stuff?
We started out on OpenAI. And we've always
used a combination of models. It's funny,
right now on Twitter there's
thread with a million views
of people trying to reverse engineer
the prompt and the models they used.
I saw that on Reddit. Yeah.
And they're all finding that there is all these
kinds of different models that are specialists
in different tasks. And there's a pipeline of
models where a model could hand off work to
another model. And so OpenAI, Gemini, Claude,
but we predate Anthropic because I'll give
credit to ChatGPT that the utility of it was so
general purpose, but from the very first release,
it was very good. In fact, by the way, if I'm
not mistaken, the first prototype of v0 might
have even predated ChatGPT, or at the very
least I think we were running on GPT 3.5. So
we've always had this vision of unlocking more
power for the web through LLMs, and there's a
lot of very interesting technical details of why,
by the way, LMs happen to be so good at the task
of web design and web development that we could
get into. But it was the perfect timing for us.
I want to come back to that. That's actually a
really good question. But let me ask a couple
other questions here. In terms of v0, what's
the scale at this point? We hear all these
numbers about all the folks in the space. What
can you share about what's happening with v0?
I can share that it's growing exponentially,
and that over 1.3 million users have interacted
with v0 so far. We had our largest day ever
yesterday and today, again, we're one of the
largest customers of most of cloud providers at
this point. We're hitting the limits of every GPU,
LLM infrastructure out there in the planet.
And the most exciting thing for me is what
I'm seeing people build with v0. So we launched a
feature about a month ago, maybe even less than a
month ago, called v0 Community. It already has
20,000 submissions. I am sure people in your
audience have used Figma, one of the things that
I love about Figma is Figma files, that I can go
and grab a starting point for something. It
could be a logo, could be a menu, and you can
start with something that someone has already
contributed, like that spirit of open source.
And so in less than a month, I think we've done
over 20,000 community submissions. So we've
learned so much about building AI products with
this and we continue to open source and share our
best practices. But one of the things that I've
definitely learned is prompting it seems like
the easiest interface in the world because it's
just an input and you put text in it. But there's
a little bit of a writer's block sometimes.
So one of my favorite things that I've seen,
and I'm even looking at the home page right now,
and you can see a random assortment of community
submissions. And they have 1,200 forks, and 1,500
forks, and 6,000 forks, and this is every time
people saying like, "Oh, instead of starting
from scratch, I'll start from this application
that someone else has built and I'm going to
prompt it to modify it and make it my own."
So the community submissions are people
building apps on v0 and sharing what they built?
Correct.
You can look at the code and fork it?
It is becoming like a compounding investment.
People share something, someone else grabs it,
makes it better. Maybe you used it at that point.
In many ways, I see this as the next evolution of
GitHub, whereas GitHub, it was a marvel for
software development because I don't know
if you remember this, but the initial, little
tagline underneath the GitHub logo was social
coding. And it had this democratization effect
of building software. But you still needed to
know how to code. And so what we're after
is social product building in many ways,
everybody should be able to cook
and share what they're building.
I hadn't thought of it this way, but I love that
it connects so much to your open source roots,
where people are building on v0, and then
sharing what they're building and then
people can build off those things. It's kind
like an open source AI building experience.
It's fascinating, right? In many ways,
if you think about the Git commit,
the Git commit is super interesting.
If you watch how an engineer works,
they look at a problem, they spend a lot of time
in their code editor, and at the end they say,
"I think I got it. I think I've fixed it." And
then they produce a Git commit. They summarize
their intent and what they try to do after they've
done the work. v0 inverts that. The Git commit is
you go into the chat and say, "Please change the
color of this button. And when I click it, save
this form to a database." And so you're starting
with the intent and the output is the code.
And as a side effect, we can also produce a Git
commit for you. That feature's not online yet, but
it's coming in the next couple of days. Spoiler
alert for the group. And so I like this idea of
we can create this super set of all software
building with this platform. And that is true
to my initial intention with Vercel. Our mission
is to enable the world to build and ship the best
products. And so enabling that for the largest
possible group of people is very exciting to me.
So let's go to this question of just
the elephant in the room for a lot of
people seeing these things happening, product
builders that have been doing things a certain
way for a long time with apps like this coming
around, whether you could just type a thing in,
and build it for you, and it's beautiful. How
do you think things are going to change for
product managers, for product teams? Where
do you think the biggest change is going
to happen? How do you think product
will be built in the next few years?
The most profound one that I alluded to is
that conversations between product builders
and their customers will be mediated
by these zero links, these artifacts.
I think when Claude came up with the name
artifacts, I found it phenomenal, because
we're all in this world, especially in this group
of people, we're here to build awesome things and
share them with the world. Steve Jobs said this
awesome speech about, "It's like our form of
giving back to the world is to try and do the best
possible job we can and share it with the world."
And so the idea that when we talk, we would not
have the power to make those ideas a reality,
it seems like an L to me. I would love to
see people constantly live in the product,
be in the design, spend time tuning and trying
out new ideas. And that's what the ideal work of
the future should look like, and less about
again, that abstraction, that being removed
from the product or even sometimes I can feel
powerless to not be able to change something.
This happens a lot when departments collaborate
within an organization. Marketing wants design
to do something, marketing wants engineering,
engineering needs a design. It cuts always. One
of the things that people got excited about that
we published on the Vercel blog was about design
engineering, because a lot of the people that
we were noticing were being very successful at
Vercel were people that had both the design and
engineering skills. And that was actually another
huge motivator and inspiration for v0, because we
realized that people could be more full stack. We
shouldn't put limits on ourselves, and what we can
build, and what we can ship, and what we can dream
about making possible on these web surfaces.
And so you could imagine removing all those
limitations, a designer that can ship a
fully-baked product, a product manager
that can prototype and shift to production. A lot
of people that use v0 are back-end engineers that
never had the ability to, they could ship an API,
they could build a great low-level infrastructure
system, but to actually bring their end-to-end
vision to life, v0's completing that for them.
Let me follow the thread on engineers. A lot of
people are wondering, "Do we need engineers in
the future? What happens to engineers? Should
I learn how to code?" Your long-time engineer
thoughts for folks that are trying
to decide the career for themselves?
Yeah, I think knowing how things work is the
most important skill in the world. I foresee
a lot of people becoming incredibly impactful
in building and shipping amazing products,
and building gigantic companies, and everything
you could imagine, where a single person can do
the job of a hundred different people in a hundred
different specializations. Take the example of
one skill set that's really important to build a
front-end product is you need to know how to use
CSS or Tailwind to style it. And once upon a time,
I would hire people that were truly specialists in
this task, the task of there's a Figma design or
there is some kind of sketch, and translating that
into reality because they knew really well how to
manipulate layouts, layout code, box model code,
we call it, and borders, paddings, margins,
flex box, all these technologies for styling.
And notice, I actually use the word
translation very intentionally,
because the origin of the LLM or the transform
architecture at least, goes as far back as the
architecture for systems like Google Translate.
They were generative LLM techniques, basically.
That's how they cross that chasm of, remember
when translating tools were horrible and then
one day the problem was just solved? And I look
at a lot of the programming jobs to be done that
used to be specializations, that I think are
going away, in a way, or the tasks to be done,
they're translation tasks. We were translating
from a screenshot, or intent, or a design into
a React, and Tailwind, and CSS implementation.
And right now, v0 is incredibly good at doing
that. It's so good that every time we
put a new generation of the model out,
I run this test of converting my own website and
try to generate it with v0. Last time I did it,
it had taken me like 10 prompts to replicate it.
Keep in mind I'm an expert front-end engineer
that's been in the arena since I'm like 10 years
old and I'm 35 now. And so I do that test because
it's almost like a test of self-imposed humility
of, like, "I remember exactly how long it took me
to build my website with Next.js, the framework
that I created, and ship it." And so with the
last model, it took me maybe 10, 15 prompts? With
the most recent model, it took me two prompts.
And so that translation from the design
intent into working implementation,
another anecdote that I like to share with people
is the model, because v0 tries to embed all of the
best practices of the web, the model output
more accessible code than what I wrote. It
follows the accessibility guidelines that the web
standards consortiums put out better than I did,
because it just knows everything. And so
those tasks where you can almost model it
to a translation task, definitely going away.
But knowing how things work under the hood,
notice all the ... I'm using specific tokens in
this conversation. I'm saying, "CSS," I'm saying,
"Layout." I'm naming styles. Knowing those tokens
is going to be very important for you because
you're going to be able to influence the model
and make it follow your intention a lot better.
And so the TLDR would be knowing how
things work, the symbolic systems,
and that will mean that you have to probably
go into each subject with less depth.
I have engineers at Vercel that know every single
CSS property by heart. They know when they became
available in a certain web browser, they've
been tracking this specification. It's almost
like you're an encyclopedia of knowledge of each
CSS property. You probably won't need that in the
future, and probably that's good, because you'll
free up your mind for more ambitious things.
No, that's fascinating. So what I'm
hearing is a skill that will continue
to be valuable in the future, but I
want to push on this a little bit,
no matter how far AI gets, is understanding
conceptually how software works, end-to-end-
Yes. Absolutely.
... systems, databases, CSS is a thing. So I
don't know if you have kids, whether you have
kids or not, just say they were trying to decide,
"What should I learn to be, to thrive in this
future?" Well, how would you summarize it? How
far? Should they get into software engineering?
Great question, because I have five kids, and I've
already enrolled them in this school of G, myself,
in the sense that I'm already guiding them towards
the things I think are going to be very useful to
them. So understanding how things work needs, I
think the ability to understand the fundamental
logic behind things, incredibly valuable. So I
push them really hard on math. "If you don't know
math really well, you're out of my house." Just
kidding. But it's a fundamental skill that I want
them to know. Eloquence. I joke sometimes.
Have you heard a meme of word cells versus-
Yeah- [inaudible 00:25:13]
... shape rotators?
Yeah.
So a shape rotator is someone
that only has a math brain.
You could argue the kings and queens of Silicon
Valley have been the shape rotators, because
those have been the jobs that have historically
commanded the most status, respect, net worth,
whatever. And then there's the word cells, which
is communicating, more of the liberal arts.
There's also the funny and awesome slide of Apple
saying that they're at the intersection of liberal
arts and technology. I've always had immense
amounts of respect for both sides of the brain,
so to speak. But I think developing great
eloquence, and knowing and memorizing those
tokens that I talked about, knowing how to
refer to things in that global mental map
of symbolic systems will be highly valuable. And
we have some tools to help people prompt better,
but prompt enhancement and embellishment cannot
replace thinking and cannot replace your own
creativity that you want to infuse into the world.
So one of the things that v0 does is it tries and
it succeeds, I think, at creating very nice
designs out of the box. We try to infuse what
we've learned about what do people think is
typically good web design? We've influenced
the model in that direction. But still we also
don't want the whole internet to look the same
way. So your ability to steer the model with
your words into those references, into those
inspirations, is going to be very important.
I actually have an amazing anecdote. We hosted
a design demo night at the Vercel HQ in San
Francisco last night. And we were showing off how
Vercel uses v0 to build v0 and to build Vercel.
And one of our designers showed this amazing
animation that he built, actually two amazing
animations that he built. And in one of them it
was this amazing triangle that had an animation
that I didn't think was possible to make, in that
it was all built with v0. And he used the word
turbulence to describe the effect that he wanted.
So I just want to call out that to people because
the difference between knowing that word and not
knowing it is getting that style into that
beautiful triangle that he created that was
interactive, and it's probably going to end up
in some landing page soon that you're going to
visit on vercel.com. And so developing eloquence
and your linguistic ability I think is going to
be very important. So I love my kids to know
that. And I think that idea of sharing things,
and putting yourself out there, and broadcasting
to the world, so another thing that I do is I
take my kids to hackathons, which just went to an
awesome hackathon at University of San Francisco,
USF. It was called the BLOOM Hackathon. And
I took two of my kids and I wanted them to
watch how people presented their ideas and
we had a lot of fun. We also ate waffles and
grilled sandwiches, which is a bonus.
So presenting and putting yourself out
there. I mentioned in the beginning of the podcast
when we were chatting, I've learned so much from
you and your guests because you put out all these
awesome little posts on X in these videos and
these snippets of your interviews. And so the
ability to present what you've built and put
yourself out there, incredibly important skill
in the future. Especially in a world where the
marginal cost of producing software and new things
are going down, you need to build an audience,
you need to know how to talk to people, you need
to build your own signature brand and style. And
so maybe they're a little too young for that
one, but I guess taking them into hackathons
probably back, is influencing their neural
networks or pre-training data for the future.
I love it. They're going to tell their friends,
"My dad took me to a hackathon." "What's that?"
So are you encouraging to learn to code?
Because it's interesting you mentioned-
Yes.
... math, eloquence, presenting, and
then, okay, so also learn to code.
Yeah, I think again, learning how to
prompt, learning how to code. With v0,
we show you the code when we build things.
So if you can build that mapping of maybe
not learning how to code necessarily as an
abstraction, if you do have a knack for it,
I'm a big believer also that my five kids have
super diverse personalities and inclinations,
and I don't want to be pushing for something
that they wouldn't want to do or whatever.
And so learning to code in the abstract might
be good for some people, but it may not be the
fun thing to do for other people. And so what I
would recommend is try to understand how things
work. So if you prompt v0 or any other tool and it
generates some code, try to build an understanding
of what that does at a high level. It's like
actually maybe an extension even of eloquence.
One of the bets that I made early on with
Vercel that really paid off is Vercel, maybe as
a metaphor is like AWS in easy mode for a lot of
people. We have a very large user base of people
that would have otherwise not have been able to
configure all of the ins and outs of the cloud,
but do want the scale, flexibility, speed, et
cetera. They want to create very high quality
products and services. So I like to give the Super
Bowl example because one of our customers, Ramp,
had a 43X increase in traffic when their
ad went live. The engineer that worked on
that only needed to learn Next.js. Then
they pushed their code to Vercel and now
they can reach an audience of a hundred million
people without a blip, a hundred percent uptime.
That superpower comes from, we made it as easy as
possible to get started, and the language that we
choose is actually very relevant in this story.
JavaScript, in my mind, has always been almost
like the English of programming languages. It's a
language that, if you learn it, you reach billions
of devices. So it's not a coincidence that
when you ask ChatGPT, or Anthropic, or Gemini
to build you web app, it uses these tools. It
uses JavaScript, it uses React. It's become the
lingua franca of building products on the web.
So I would say to my kids, "Look, if you do want
to go deeper into programming, start learning
there." You can reach huge numbers of people.
If you have a passion, I would say there's going
to be a fundamental engineering skill that's going
to be useful for decades or centuries to come,
which is creating foundational infrastructure.
Think about LLMs in terms of, they're like
Oracles that can go and write software for you,
but there's a limit to how much software they can
write. There's context windows, there is time and
computational constraints. So it's very hard
for an agent today to go and say, "I'm going
to write a cloud from scratch. I'm going to write
all the foundational services. I'm going to write
the framework from scratch. I'm going to write
the compiler." No, the LM is orchestrating those
tools and infrastructure. It's not writing the
compiler from scratch. Otherwise, you get into
the Newton thing, in order to create an Apple, you
have to create the entire underlying universe. No,
the elements are interoperating with the universe
as it exists. And so the engineers that learn
foundational infrastructure are probably going to
be extremely empowered still, for years to come.
There's a world where you could argue
ChatGPT will build the next version
of ChatGPT. What I'm hearing from you
is that's a long ways away, if ever.
Absolutely. This is why the
common, the running joke is
that all of these companies have, you
go to their careers page. It's like-
Engineers.
... "Engineer, engineer, engineer." The
counterpoint of that is that at Vercel had,
we have 150 engineers that can write code and
600 total headcount. Now we have 600 engineers.
Some of the best things that I've seen created
with v0 have not come from our engineering team.
They've come from the marketing team, they've come
from the sales team, they've come from the product
management team. The product management team is
fascinating, because now they're actually building
the product. So last night I saw how we've
specced out in v0, think of it as like a live PRD,
we've specced out how the new functionality
for deploying a v0 to Vercel is going to work.
The amount of detail that was contained
in that v0, I mean, we're all just saying,
"Well, just ship it. There's nothing
else to discuss." It was animated,
it was interactive. We were demonstrating
the error state, the success state,
the slow stream state. So it really empowers
product builders not only with technical skills,
I think that does a disservice to the tool.
It empowers them to explore and augment their
thinking with a lot of things that perhaps
they wouldn't have considered otherwise,
a lot of states of the product they
wouldn't have considered otherwise.
The name v0 implies the product is for
prototypes for the first attempt at stuff.
And that's definitely where all these tools
are finding product market fit prototypes,
PMs showing a thing working versus just design.
Do you expect v0 and other tools to get to
a place where you can build salesforce.com
and scale it to billions of dollars? Do you-
Absolutely.
You do? Okay.
We already have an enterprise customer of v0
that only works with v0. All of their products,
all of their features, all of their
client communications are v0 native.
Two days ago, I just heard anecdotally on X,
someone tells me, "My brother just sold his
first website to a client completely built in v0."
Yesterday at an investor conference, an investor
walks up to me and says, "Two of my friends
just got engaged on v0." I was like, "Okay, v0
is a dating app now." So the engagement website,
the proposal, the wedding, it's all v0 native.
So because we've integrated v0, the Vercel
infrastructure, we can do that whole story that I
just told you of like, "I have a website to build
and I can get it in front of a hundred million
people." We can enable that for everybody now.
And so the end-to-end full stack, v0 native,
and built on this awesome fluid serverless
infrastructure that scales to billions of people,
all just from prompts, or screenshots, or just
copying and pasting your PRDs into the tool.
Let's help people be successful with v0. And then
let's also do a demo. But before we get there,
let me ask you this. Imagine you could magically
sit next to someone who's about to use v0 for the
first time and whisper a tip in their ear to be
successful with v0. What would a couple tips be?
Number one is you can be as ambitious as
you want in terms of what you ask the tool.
If you can steer the tool towards some kind of
inspiration that you have, you're always going
to get better results. If you don't have
ideas on what to build or what to prompt,
I would recommend using the v0 community
so that you can find something to fork to
get started. I would say in some ways, if you
have technical skills, this one is interesting,
have some suspension of disbelief. It humbled
me, I was saying about accessibility. So be
open-minded about whether the tool actually
knows some things that you might not know,
and so focus more on the product description,
focus more on what do you want the end user to
experience? What do you want the product to do?
And try to be open-minded about how well the tool
can implement it. Those would be my main wants.
You also have to have a sense of iteration,
I guess. Think of it this way, if you were working
with a design firm or an agency that you've hired,
you will go back and forth and say, "Try
something else." If you were coaching an
engineer that's getting stuck in something,
you would say, "Try something else." It's
amazing how many times I've gotten unstuck in
v0 by just saying, "Just try something else."
Just saying that as the
prompt, not even giving direct-
Just saying that. I mean, the chat is like-
Wow.
"v0, we need to have ... " It's like, "Yeah."
Like you have a one-on-one performance review
with a tool. "Hey, way to talk, try something
else. What you're doing so far is not working.
And it's amazing." One fitness function that I'm
keeping in my head is I really want to find the
thing that it cannot build with v0. So as part
of the v0 community, I have my own profile. We'll
share the link with people. You can see six or
seven things that I've built that I consider
to be pretty impressive. So for example, I
was flying from Tokyo to San Francisco. The
internet was horrible. What I like to do during
flights is I like to monitor our own flight while
I'm on the flight. So I open Flightradar or
whatever, and I was extremely bored as well.
And I noticed that Flightradar, I don't know
which one it was, Flightradar, there's like
four or five of them. They were very bloated. They
had ads. They were not what I wanted the flight
radar to look like. So I built my own during
the flight with the worst internet connection
that you could imagine in the world, integrated
into a flight data API called Edge Aviation.
So this is what I told v0, "You're going to build
the best flight radar on the planet." I wasn't
prescriptive at how, so it used a tool
called Mapbox and a JavaScript library
called Leaflet. I didn't tell him that, or her,
I don't know, v0, what it is. And subsequently,
once we cooked on the design, which looks, I
would say beautiful, I then got more ambitious
and I said, "All right, let's make it real now."
And by the way, that's actually how I would work.
So it's how I like to work. I like to work
experience first, and that's also how Vercel
was built. "Let's start with the front end. Let's
start with the planes on the screen." And by the
way, there's a lot of subtleties, here. For
example, there's so many flights going on at
any given time that there's just too many. So
I had to work with v0 on improving performance.
And once again, I wasn't prescriptive. I just
said, "We have a lot of flights, chief. Let's- "
Did you say, "Chief?"
Yeah, I do say that a lot. And this is, I think
when I shared it on X, it blew a lot of engineers'
minds, because it created a canvas-based, canvas
is the sort of underlying rendering surface that
very sophisticated products use like Figma.
And it created this awesome overlay on top
of the map that can render tens of thousands of
flights at any given time. And then I told it,
"Let's make it a full stack application. Okay,
plug into the flights' API." So that's an example
of we cooked and there was no limit. And so
I'm always in the lookout. The service that I'm
providing to the v0 community is I'm part of the
team that is really trying to break this and say,
"Can it not build something?" And even
when it does build it, we're very obsessed
with quality and performance. It has to be
real. That's our commitment to our users.
And how much did this cost, how much time
does this take to make something like this?
So the flight radar example or v0?
Yeah, the flight radar example
specifically just like very-
I mean, that one probably
took less than two hours-
Less than two hours?
... with the worst internet.
Yeah, what-
Sorry, Japan Airlines, I love
you, but you give me a hard time.
And what did that cost? Like 10
bucks? What would you estimate?
I mean, I pay for the $20 v0 subscription.
20 bucks, okay, for a month. So it's like a
month, but you used it for two hours, 20 bucks.
Yeah.
If you had engineers building this,
how much do you think that would cost?
How long do you think that would take?
I mean, weeks, easily. Easily.
And that's like tens of thousands of dollars.
Maybe the most cracked engineer at Vercel
could knock it out in ... without using any AI,
could knock it out in a couple days. But then
what about the design? What about me? Because
I'm the bottleneck, not the engineer. And this
is what's amazing about this collaboration
because I'm providing the product guidance. I'm
saying, "Draw a dashed line between the ... " And
by the way, v0 just blew my mind so hard. I said,
"Draw a dashed line between the two destination
airports." And v0 said, "Well, I have to
account for the spherical, or what is it,
it's a pseudosphere, for the curvature of the
earth." It's like, "Okay, v0, super genius,
whatever." And so that's what I mentioned about
how you can go back and forth. It's like a
product copilot, it's like an all-knowing being.
One of our users yesterday submitted feedback to
the tool and it was positive feedback. They were
very happy, what they were saying, "v0 is a super
genius five-year old PhD with ADHD." So you still
have to, I'm not going to oversell this like,
"It knows everything about everything. It
gives everything perfect," of course. But
it has these sparks of brilliance.
Really, truly, I think, I've been
a big believer that AGI undersells what we are
collectively building because we already have,
all of this sparks of super intelligence. I
don't believe that v0 is an AGI if it knows
everything about how to draw a dashed line
according to the curvature of the earth and
this high-performance map of airplanes. That's
just superhuman. And yeah, it's a joy to use.
(instrumental music)
Today's episode is brought to you by LinkedIn ads.
One of the hardest and also most important parts
of B2B marketing is reaching the right people.
I'm constantly getting ads for products that I
will never buy. And I almost feel sorry for the
money that these companies are spending, pitching
me on their spend management software or some
kind of cybersecurity solution that my one-man
business just does not need. When you're ready to
reach the right professionals use LinkedIn ads.
LinkedIn has grown to a network of over one
billion professionals, including 130 million
decision makers. And that's where it stands apart
from other ad platforms. You can target your ad
buyers by job title, industry, company, role,
seniority, skills, even company revenue, all
the professionals that you need to reach in one
place. Stop wasting budget on the wrong audience
and start targeting the right professionals only
on LinkedIn ads. LinkedIn will even give you $100
credit on your next campaign so that you can try
it for yourself. Just go to linkedin.com/podlenny,
that's linkedin.com/podlenny. Terms and
conditions apply only on LinkedIn ads.
As you talk, it's interesting, the
way I'm thinking about this now,
there's almost like three core skills in building
apps with AI. There's figuring out what to build,
there's making it look good, like design,
and then there's getting it unstuck.
Yeah,
And it's interesting how these are going to move.
And coaching.
Coaching it. Yeah. Or just like, "Oh,
here's the database error. I don't
know. It's not figuring it out."
Yeah.
I guess does that resonate? I've never
thought about [inaudible 00:46:16] before.
Oh, absolutely. In fact, I'll tell you a little
bit of a story of something. So even going way
back in time, Next.js builds on React. React was
this UI component library that Facebook created,
actually with very similar goals. They had
so many cracked engineers, and they had to
help them collaborate on an enormous product
surface. So they invented or at least pioneered,
I would say the concept of this component as
a unit of reusability, as a building block,
as a Lego brick of how you build software.
It's no coincidence that LLMs love to work
with React components, by the way. And one of the
things that always has stood out to me about that
model is it basically enables people to scale
in how they work together. And one of the key
design principles that they embedded into
this thing, is they called it escape hatch.
The API, when when React doesn't perfectly
model your problem with its component system,
they give you escape hatch. They say, "Okay,
engineer. You are on your own now. There's
no guardrails." And in fact, one of these
escape hatches is called dangerously set
inner HTML. They want the developer to know
uncharted territory. But they did give people
the API. That is a profound systems design
engineering principle. And throughout my life,
I've always thought about escape hatches.
One amazing escape hatch that v0 has is
that you're looking at the code that we're
generating with Next.js. You can edit it,
you can even have other experts look at it. One
thing that one of our demos last night came from
this awesome company, Lumalabs. They're creating
one of the most amazing video models in the world,
and they use v0 and Vercel extensively to
build their application, their websites,
et cetera. And the design engineer was
talking about how he was on a v0 that
had 120 or so iterations. So he was knee-deep
into the latent space. He was in the matrix.
And at one point he got stuck. But you know
what he did? He copied and pasted the code
that we generated and he gave it to ChatGPT
o1 and ChatGPT o1 thought about the solution.
Honestly, I'd never even thought about this
myself. I was so blown away. And it does speak to,
I love that your third point of, "You need to
learn a skill of how to get unstuck." It's like
a profound life lesson. It's just more a generic
life advice you need to get. Facebook actually
had a principle, "Don't get blocked. Seek to
get unblocked, seek help from other people."
What's fascinating is that you can seek help from
other AIs to get unstuck. And those escape hatches
of actually understanding and seeing the code
underneath, and even being able to say, "Okay,
now let's use Git. Let's turn this into more
of a hybrid project, not just prompts, but also
traditional software engineering." The fact that
that door is open to you is extremely valuable.
Let's actually make the super
concrete and show people what
this actually looks like in v0.
So pull up, we'll share screen,
and then we'll do a little live demo. We'll
keep it brief. I find people are like, "Okay,
I get it." But we'll make it fun and brief
at the same time. There it is. I see it.
Beautiful. Okay.
How can I help you ship?
Yeah, of course. We're all about shipping. Okay,
so as I mentioned, you write in English, you yap
into the tool. I'll say for a demo, let's create a
contact sales form in the style of ... By the way,
I had a typo. I don't care. Let's get it. It's Elf
Supreme, the clothing company for an online store.
Now, I mentioned that sometimes people get
blocked, there is a writer paralysis at this
step. So we added enhanced prompt. So now you're
tapping into the latent space of the model,
which has a random component to it.
And by the way, this is still not a
substitute. It doesn't contradict what I said
earlier, knowing the meaningful tokens, knowing
what the right style is, and what it's called,
and whatever is still highly valuable. So the
first thing you're going to notice is that as the
model thinks, you can introspect its thinking. So
we added this recently. It's been mostly inspired
actually by the Deepseek revolution. I would say.
So the fact that when you tell it, "Develop a
contact sales form," what is it going to do?
We talked about escape hatches. Okay, it's going
to use shadcn/ui, it's going to use Tailwind CSS,
it's going to use React. And this is your
opportunity that if v0 is not doing exactly what
you wanted, this is your opportunity to actually
go and correct, or influence, or give feedback and
so on. So you're going to notice it spits out a
bunch of files, and it gives me the thing that I
wanted. I'm going to zoom out a little bit, here.
A couple of things that stand out here that again,
as an experienced engineer, I can point out.
The underlying component system that it uses is
the same component system that the best tools
on the planet are built with. This is called
shadcn. If you go to grok.com today, they're
using shadcn to build their UI. They're using
Next.js. You're getting that caliber of code.
The other thing that it did is people on social
media talk about this a lot. When you use a
global shared component system with the world,
you don't want everything to look the same. So
the fact that he was able to apply the style
and he kind of knew what supreme looked like was
kind of cool. But now I'm going to say, "Actually,
because I am building a financial institution,
make it more serious, make it in the style of
let's say Charles Schwab. Change typefaces.'
So this is the iteration process of like,
"I'm going to go and give feedback to the model.
I'm going to make it try different things."
So once that initial generation was already
created, now the model is actually acting
more as an editor. It's going and making
tweaks to what's already been built.
And this actually scales to very large
projects. You could have started with
something much bigger. So in the meantime, I'm
going to show you what Lumalabs created with v0,
which is absolutely phenomenal. I learned about
this last night. It already has 2,000 forks. I was
telling you about the power of our community. So
by the way, you can just click community here on
the v0 sidebar. I'm going to fork it, because they
generously shared it with the world. Notice all
the incredible animations here? By the way, they
shipped this to hire and attract talent to their
company. I recommend them, by the way, you should,
if you want to be a brand designer, take them into
consideration. Notice that it's an interactive,
everything is AI generated, they used their own AI
image generation tool to create these beautiful
frames. These are all AI generated as well.
Wow.
And it's interactive. So there is the autoplaying
functionality. This is actually a complex layout
in animation system that they built entirely
in v0. I was telling you that at one point they
even got some advice from O-Wan, so shout out to
OpenAI. I'm going to say, "Make it sepia style
colors." So this is an example of like, "Okay,
I forked something. I already have a starting
point." My bank grade contact form is ready.
In the meantime, another fun thing to do is you
can start with a screenshot. So I'll use another
Next.js user as an example, which is fortune.com.
Shout out to them. They built a slick website.
But let's say that I'm actually wanting to break
into the news business, so I'm just going
to paste a screenshot. I could have also
attached the Figma file. And I'm going to have,
v0 already knows, v0 can answer questions as well
about the engineering design product world. So I
can ask v0, "What is a newsletter? Explain with
a diagram. Use Lenny as an example." So v0 is also
a knowledge seeking tool. But we do strongly like,
"Steer the tool to create things." So if I paste
a screenshot, as you can see, it's cooking on
creating a hopefully awesome news website. I
specifically asked, because I think it's funny,
to explain a newsletter with a diagram, so
v0 can create again, explanations, content,
knowledge. The creator is Lenny, you were a
former Airbnb product lead. I guess I should-
It's all- [inaudible 00:55:55]
... have used some examples from Airbnb,
by the way. But let's look at here-
It's all good.
... what it created with Fortune.
Wow.
So notice that, I'm just noticing now
the cyber should have been on the center.
I'm going to zoom out a little bit. Let's use
the refinement tool to center this. I call this,
by the way, one of the hardest problems in
computer science is actually centering things.
With CSS.
That's right, centering a div. And in fact,
look at it. It was a div. So notice that I
did a precise inline prompt? And the difference
between v0 and a lot of other tools is that yes,
you do have the code and code is very
important, but I call it code last rather
than code first. You're living in the product.
So center that. Another website that I love
also built with Next.js is Semaphore.
So I really like their sepia style.
So I'm going to say, "Apply
this style instead, including- "
So you're sharing a screen. So you used
a screenshot to design, to build a site,
and now you're using a different screenshot
to tell it, "Make it look like this."
Yes.
Very cool.
And so the idea is that v0 can Grok different
aspects of what it needs to build. It can be
functional aspects, it can be layout aspects. And
one of the things that's also very important to
know is we influence the model. So a lot of
the things that you would have had to prompt
you might get for free. One that's important to
call out is responsiveness. So as an example,
if I notice that if I do this, it's going
to make it work quite well on mobile, it's
going to give me that hamburger menu. I can now
tell it like, "Apply that style to everything."
In the meantime, I'll show you, this is actually
to me very, very impressive. And I don't know why
today I'm so fixated on the theme of sepia. But
notice that not only did it change the background,
I hope people can notice this. It applied
it to the checkboxes and it applied a CSS.
I'm assuming this is a CSS filter. Yeah, it
applied a CSS filter. Just for the sake of it,
because I'm a nerd, I'm going to look at it. But
yes, it applied a CSS filter. Confession time,
I actually didn't know that there was
a sepia function in the filter property
of CSS. There were many ways to accomplish
this. You could have also written the images
or the videos to a canvas, and apply
all kinds of algorithms, and whatever.
I like that it did more
elegantly than you would have.
Yeah, exactly. So that's why you can't
be too opinionated with the tool.
So another cool thing is I do like showing
screenshots, but I do want to remind
people that the idea is not to clone other
people's websites, necessarily. Right? It's-
It's just a cool demo. It's a simple
way to show off what it can do.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Take screenshots of your own things.
Take screenshots of your art boards,
take screenshots of things that people post in
Slack, and also don't hesitate add functionality.
Incredible. Thank you for doing
the demo. I'm just trying to
imagine having an engineer I'm working
with, asking them to do these things,
and not only just how annoying that
would be, like, "Make it sepia."
Yeah.
But just how much time it would take from, "Okay,
do this thing, copy fortune.com." It'd
be like days, weeks. Here, it's just-
Months.
... check it out here. Months.
If ever.
Yeah.
Maybe it never ships.
That's right. Well, something that I noticed
that I loved at the beginning when you were
doing the prompting and that prompt improvement
feature is it basically is best practices
to make it look good and look better. Which
I think is one of the more interesting,
I don't know, levers to working with AI is it
just has best practices to help you build things
that are beautiful and also feels like there's
this opportunity of just helping you figure out
if what you're building is at all a good idea.
"What is the problem you're trying to solve?" It
feels like there's a PM1 pager step that should
exist. Like, "How do you know this is a problem?
What have users told you? How many people
have told you this?" Things like that.
Yeah. There's something to be said about the fact
that over time we're more and more peeking into
the mind of the AI. That in itself is becoming
a killer feature. So the Deepseek stream, the
thinking tokens moment was a very big moment for
our industry, I think. Because OpenAI did have the
technology, but they decided that for competitive
reasons, which, it's a reasonable think to think,
no pun intended, they were going to withhold it.
And also it wasn't clear that there was going to
be product end user and product utility. But when
Deepseek hit, it was very obvious that people
really liked the idea of understanding how the AI
thinks and influencing where it should go. We've
gotten actually amazing feedback and bug reports
where people actually specifically point out,
"Look, this is where the AI went wrong. Please fix
it." So the more people we get on this product,
the more thumbs up, thumbs down,
the more user feedback we get.
And by the way, I'll tell you for people out there
building products, my number one guidance or piece
of advice I would give to any startup founder
was, "Create a lot of opportunities for people
to give you feedback inside the product." I
drew inspiration from Stripe. And this was
amazing for the early days of Vercel, there was
a feedback button with a very slick inline form,
with four emojis that would allow you to
decide how you were feeling about the feature,
the product at that very moment. And that
would go straight into Slack. And we were
building day in and day out, just streaming
users' thoughts right into our consciousness.
And maybe we would get, I don't know, tens,
hundreds a day, especially the early days,
maybe a couple a day and whatever. When you're
building AI products, it's a constant stream
of user feedback. So for people that are
thinking about not building AI products,
it's going to be hard to compete with something
that has such a tight feedback loop with users.
The whole idea is to capture users' feedback
so the next iteration of the model, the prompt,
the fine-tuning, the examples, the rag is better.
And one of the things that Vercel has done as a
result of this insight is we've open-sourced
a lot of what makes v0 work. So let's say that
you wanted to create the v0 for doctors as an
example. You can go to vercel.com/templates,
and you can clone a ChatGPT template that
basically follows all of the best practices
in the world for really high-performance, awesome
UIs, and now you can go out and build your own AI
products. We've also open-sourced the AISDK, which
is the foundational plumbing of v0. It allows you
to connect any model and generate UI from its
responses, not just output text, but actually
generate UI. So maybe because I love showing
stuff, I'll just really quickly show you this.
Okay, cool.
Because I'm excited about it.
Let's do it.
So if you go to chat.vercel@ai super quick,
you're going to see this is the open-source
ChatGPT demo that we've built. You can ask
questions like old-school LLM. But also,
you can ask, let's actually finish this, let's
ask, "What is the weather in San Francisco?"
We call this generative UI. It's responding not
with just plain text, it's creating components
as a result. Last but not least, and this is a
v0 style opportunity, let's ask it to help me
write an essay about Silicon Valley. It's going
to create a canvas or artifacts style experience,
and everything is generative, but also users can
edit, refine, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
This actually reminds me of something
I've been thinking about. There's all
these startups that are building vertical
AI tools. This is a little bit of a tangent,
and there's always this AI stuff for lawyers,
AI stuff for doctors, nurses, and the pitch
there is that these are going to be founders that
know a lot about the specific problem in this-
Totally.
... useless market, and so they'll build
the tools that are very specific to them.
Yeah, I'm absolutely convinced that expert AI
tools are the future. There's an amazing product
being built on Vercel called chatprd.com. It's
the v0 for writing PRDs and it's going to get
a v0 integration soon so that you can write your
PRD with AI and then you can create it with AI.
That's just an example of a vertical that you
can go after. There's also OpenEvidence. It's
like the ChatGPT for doctors, actually. There
is an amazing startup building x-ray AI tooling.
So the ideas I think are infinite, and what I've
seen from users of AI at Vercel, for example,
our legal team loves this tool called Get
GC.AI. They could in theory go to ChatGPT
to ask legal questions, but someone out there
decided, "I'm going to build the best legal
AI tool in the world." It's going to be up to
date. I'm going to obsess about this problem."
The CEO herself is a lawyer, so it's going
to be hard to compete with that, I think.
But here's what I'm thinking. This is almost
the opposite and I'm curious to get your take,
but let's not spend too much time on this,
because this is a complete change in-
No, I love it.
So you showed me the weather widget that you
just built, basically it's like a little mini
app that the AI built as you're talking to it.
Is there a world where when AI, when AGI is far
enough and approaching super intelligence?
Can it just build you a Harvey, for example,
in real time? "Here's the best experience
for a lawyer. Here we go. We got it for you."
Totally, totally. I believe that eventually,
yes, but humans will always want to have some
guardrails. The reality is that Get GC
is taking a double job. One is making the
best tools for lawyers possible, but also
putting their weight behind it, saying,
"We've actually used this and we believe that
this is what the future should look like."
There is a sense of direction and opinion about
things and I think left to its own devices, AI,
I don't know, this is the double-edged like
prompt embellishment. AI doesn't always know
exactly what we want or what we need. It's still
very much a copilot, a partner, an assistant.
It's not really running our lives, and I don't
know that we even would want that, ultimately.
Okay, I'm going to go in a whole different
direction, which is taste. We hear this word
taste all the time. It feels like a thing that
people are always suggesting. This will continue
to be an important skill, to know what is good,
basically to know what people are likely to find
valuable and good. And I know clearly you
have great taste. You're building incredibly
beautiful products, v0's clearly, it's like the
most beautiful by default builder out there,
as we've seen. So in terms of building taste,
people are always like, "How the hell do I do
that? I have great taste. I know I do. I
don't need to." How have you built taste?
How do you think you build taste and any advice
for folks that are trying to improve their taste?
Yes, I think it's extremely important to try
lots of products. You need to get yourself out
there. I think it's very important to go back to
that, get into the world, ship things. Don't be
hesitant of self-promotion in a way. So being
very honest with yourself, building something,
getting it out there, see how people react. Go
back to the drawing board. I think it's about
exposure. At Vercel we have one of our internal
operating principles as increasing exposure
hours. Try to quantify how much time you expose
yourself to watching how people use your products,
even to watch how people use other products,
and you'll develop that muscle. Taste,
sometimes I think we think of as this inaccessible
thing that, "Oh, that person was born with taste."
I see it as a skill that it can develop.
And again, the AI will help you a lot here
because we try and capture some of the universal
principles of it. But there's also trends in the
world. I'm not a super couture guy, but you can
see that every year Paris Fashion Week has a
theme to it and there is some innovations, there
have some breakthroughs, whatever. And so trying
to stay at the frontier or even try and define
the frontier as well is certainly very exciting.
I love how doable this is,
increasing your exposure hours. Basically
what I'm hearing is, "Use the best apps."
Yes.
There's a feedback cycle component to
it. Just like, "Show people the thing."
And understand these nuances. Right?
Mm-hmm.
So I actually recently created, I published
it to my community, [inaudible 01:10:01] v0.
I created a ChatGPT style interface inspired by
Grok. And I captured a few things that Grok does
that are just so smart. So on mobile web, when
you press enter on their input, they default to
creating a new line. Because they know that
the way that people are used to submitting
things on mobile is not by hitting enter, like
we would do on a desktop computer. You can tap
the little icon and your message goes out. On
desktop, they inverted it. When you press enter,
you're expected to submit. And I think if you
got a new line, I think a lot of people would get
frustrated that most people don't know that they
can press command, enter to submit and whatever,
and it slows everything down. And you
can basically prompt for those things.
But you have to pay attention to the details and
you have to decide what you want to see in the
world. And sometimes that means either defining
best practices, or seeking the best practices,
and learning from others. Another aspect of
exposure hours is that you tend to overrate
how well your products work. It's very important
to give your product to another person and watch
them interact with it, expose yourself to the pain
of reality. And the more you submerge yourself in
the real deal, nitty-gritty of what happens
when people use your interfaces and whatnot,
I think you you'll come out stronger,
more grounded, hopefully more humbled.
We don't like pain, though, and I like that this
is a push, "Create some more pain in your life.
Show people the thing you're building." Do you
have a heuristic or number of how many exposure
hours per week, per month you want your team
to have or is it just more is always better?
Yeah, I'm more is always better. I mean, because
the inertia is to get inside your head, and the
inertia is to think that you know everything,
and assume that everything is going good, and,
"There are no errors. Of course it's fast. It
worked on my machine." I think it's always a
push for more. I do sometimes little things like
I asked my team to color my calendar. So I say I
have to have a certain amount of one-on-ones
with my team represented on my calendar,
kind of like meetings so that I can sync
with people and see how the company's doing.
Then I want to have customer meetings. And
during those customer meetings I push myself
to use the products. In fact, with our enterprise
customers, something that I do is I try to forget
how things are built, what feature of [inaudible
01:12:41] or Vercel they use and whatever.
I just frequently use their products. And
I want the product to be great, that's
all. And then I could try to work backwards.
So a form of exposure hours for me is seeing
what kind of success our customers are having in
the real world. But again, it's just heuristic.
Maybe one third of my meetings this week where
customer meetings I tried and watched them
do. Another really quick one is we invite people
frequently to demo how they use the product live,
sometimes to the executive team, sometimes to
the whole company. And we always inevitably
discover something interesting from the customer
about maybe there is something that they're in
pain about that we didn't know about, or maybe
something was not as intuitive as we thought.
And I find with these sorts of things, when
you do them, when you talk to customers,
you have them show how they use
the product. You always like,
"Why have I not done this more often? What am
I thinking?" It's just so mind-blowing usually.
Yes.
I want to talk about limitations of v0 at this
point. So what should people know about just what
v0 can't do? If you have an existing code base,
can you plug it in and start doing stuff? Or is
that coming? What else should people know? Just
like, "Okay, it's not going to do this yet. But- "
Yeah, you can import code bases through zip files
and Git is coming very soon. It can do full stack
development, it can connect to APIs. In the next
couple of days, maybe even before this podcast is
out, we'll have these very tight integrations
so that if you need a database, or if you need
an AI model, or if the AI decides it needs that,
it'll just seamlessly install it from the Vercel
marketplace. And the Vercel marketplace has
already curated some of the best infrastructure
products in the world to store data, to search
data, et cetera. So it's going to make the product
even more powerful. I'll say again, I did that
exercise, and I do that exercise every day of
I have a wild idea and try to see if it can
come to life. It's very powerful so far. AIs
are still very much a work in progress. They can
make mistakes. We have it as a little disclaimer
underneath the input. You will find errors, our
fitness function. And we've seen such a strong
correlation between user love and retention.
v0's actually their retentive product compared to
other AI products that I've built in the past, or
little demos that we've done, or whatever. People
subscribe and use it every single day, and are
very, if they notice a bug, they're very, very
jittery about it because they're depending on it
day in and day out. But I'll say errors are still
possible. Every once in a while you might get
a runtime error or whatever, but a lot of the
technology that we've added is so that v0 is very
agentic. It has a lot of agency in how to act. So
you're going to see very frequently that if it
runs into errors, v0 tries to solve them itself.
And then last I will say, when products get
really big, AI today is just not as good at
dealing with massive code bases. But going
back to that idea of the React component,
because we break down things into files and
components, we tend to do quite well in that
dimension. In fact, one thing that Next.js was
known for is that in order to start a project,
you just create a file, and Next.js will route
to that page. If anyone is familiar with PHP,
it's like how PHP worked. And so it's so good that
LLMs are good at working with files now, because
it fits very naturally into our world. And if you
can scope down when things get really big, if you
can give it a smaller task, to work on a specific
component or a specific file, you decrease that
likelihood of the LLM not being able to reason
over very, very, very long context windows.
I want to go back to design. We talked about
how v0 is really good at just great design
by default. To lean into that more, if someone
wants to improve the design of their product,
most people are not designers, they don't really
know how to make it look good. They don't know
what to ask for. Any just tips and best practices
for making their app even better, look even nicer?
Yeah, it was really interesting. The other
day I met with a CIO of a large bank who,
on the side does a lot of coding, or tries out
new technologies and whatnot. And I showed him
v0. And he immediately became a v0 addict. He
texts me every day with feedback. He moved two
websites of his own from another website
builder type provider to v0 and Vercel,
deployed them, gave them a domain name, they're
live in production. And then he said, "Look,
I have this challenge. I have this music festival
that I organize with a couple of friends and this
is what the designer gave us." And he had
this brochure. It looked very much like a
print style design. And so he gave that to
v0 and the first result, he was dinging me
for it. He's like, "Look, this doesn't look good."
And then, because I have experience with the tool,
I said, "Why don't I just give it the feedback?"
Literally you were asking me yesterday, earlier,
some of the things that I've learned
with the product or the best practice,
what would I recommend if it were
sitting next to someone? Not only,
you should not hesitate to give the AI feedback,
it's so interesting, dude. Sometimes people will
press a feedback button to tell us what they
wanted v0 to do, and literally all we had to do,
in many cases is just, "Can you just tell v0
that?" And so he sent me this message saying,
"Yeah, I just don't like the design." And I gave
him back a prompt that I would've given. I don't
know what I said specifically, but it's like,
"Make it more jazzy, make it more, make it pop."
And so trying, and again, it goes back to try to
draw inspiration from variety that the AI already
knows about. So in a couple of prompts, we ended
up something that was in his mind, better than the
original print design of that brochure, that
concert lineup. And at that time, and again,
I'm even learning about what v0 is capable of and
the best ways to use it. But with design, I think
unleashing its creativity, and seeing things,
and playing with it is definitely super helpful.
So one thing I'm hearing here is just tell it,
"Make this look better." Or, "I don't like- "
"Make it pop."
You can, totally. And if you can
use tokens that are relevant, so,
"Neobrutalist, minimalist, newspaper-like,
vintage, make it look like a telegram." You
can try and reach for things that
maybe would not naturally come to
mind and you'll be surprised about how well
it can transfer those ideas into reality.
Incredible. Too easy. Maybe
to close out our conversation,
we'll see where this topic goes. I had this
tweet that I loved, that I super resonate with,
"The secrets of product quality is blood, sweat,
and tears." I completely agree. I think that's
why I think my newsletter's been successful.
I spend so much time on every newsletter post,
more than I think anyone spends
on a newsletter post, like 10, 20,
30 hours. And that's why I think it works.
Is there anything more behind that tweet,
anything you've learned in just the importance
of working hard, I guess to great, great stuff?
Yeah, I mentioned exposure hours
is a good example of like, "Look,
it can be painful. It can be painful to see your
baby break in front of everyone and noticing all
the ... " The other thing is that a great
product is made up of a thousand little
details and so you're never really done. There's
a humility that comes from the process also of
why the best product builders will say nine
nos for every yes. Because when you say yes,
it's like adopting a puppy. A feature is
like adopting a puppy. It grows into a beast
that you have to take care of, and it's very
demanding and loving. But also it's a lot, and
poops everywhere. So you have to have a creative
restraint. And while you also have to have a give,
you have to withhold, sometimes with the respect
of the real world complexity that emerges.
A little thing that I kind of obsess about.
I'll give kudos to the Midjourney team. I really
love how Midjourney works on mobile web. I don't
know if they have an app yet, like a native app,
but their mobile website is phenomenal. And to
get it to be that good, by the way, it's possible.
It's actually possible to make great things on
mobile web. But it needs that sense of love,
and restraint, and obsession, and testing a lot,
and using your own products a lot. Dogfooding is
a great mechanism, obviously. So we use the heck
out of Vercel and v0 to make Vercel and v0, and
hopefully that helps us do better. But there is
a lot of blood, sweat, and tears in the process.
Yeah. You can tell how much you use the
product. It comes through in everything
you say. Let me actually ask about this. You
talked about how you said you have 600 engineers?
No, 600 people, total and a hundred-
600 people total?
... 150.
How is AI changing the way they work?
Is there anything there? Because I feel
like you guys are the cutting edge
of how products are built. What's
happening? Is it just everyone's
on Cursor and v0 to build stuff?
Yeah. Yes, but actually it's more profound. I
think it's the, everybody can ship, it's the,
we build with AI principles in mind. I actually
give a shout-out to the Lumalabs engineer who
said, "Well, I'll use AI for everything. I'll use
AI also to generate the images for the website."
And I'm seeing, for example, our designers that
are working on our next conference generate all of
the animations with video models. I'm looking at,
our marketing team are creating demos of how the
infrastructure works with v0 that are better than
any static diagram or landing page that I've ever
seen. One of my most viral xeets or X posts is
something that one of our designers created, which
explains how our compute infrastructure works with
an interactive demo. And until he created that,
by the way he designed, it and created, and
we shipped it all in the tool, first of all,
it wasn't part of his day-to-day job to do that.
v0 is making you such a powerful generalist that
you can step out of your comfort zone of like,
"Well, my job was to do only this." You can just
create. We have a ritual every Friday, we had
it this morning, called Demo Fridays. And so
it's very important to create the space for
people to step out of that comfort zone and
use AI. So us giving permission to people to
build and ship things is part of that cultural
backdrop that makes these things possible.
We had a demo today as part of the Demo Friday
of our VP of sales engineering also creating
an amazing tool that he's going to use to help
prospects understand Vercel with v0. So I've
heard from DevOps and infrastructure engineers
how much they use tools like Cursor to work on
the low levels of the Vercel infrastructure.
So I think very quickly we're seeing AI being
embedded everywhere. I just heard a product
request from a customer that was saying, "Okay,
Vercel, you sell domain names. Let me come up with
new domain ideas with AI." So I just see a future
where AI becomes synonymous with software. I do
look forward to it because we need to stop
talking about AI at some point. I foresee,
it's probably not going to happen, but it is
useful to remind people that AI equals software
now, and we are a software company. We build
software, and we use software to build software.
And AI is just a part of that.
Yeah.
Guillermo, what a beautiful way to end
it. Is there anything else you wanted
to mention? Anything else that you want to
leave listeners with before I let you go?
I'll leave you with my vision of the future,
which is we have this billboard in San Francisco,
which is, "Everybody Can Cook." It is also part of
the Ratatouille film, one of my favorite movies.
I look forward to a future where everybody can
get their ideas out there. If you can dream it,
you can ship it. And also that when you use
products and when you see the creations of
other people and the things that they put out
into the world, that we are collectively making
the world better. So anything you experience
hopefully gets faster, higher quality,
fewer bugs as we go along. And I think we're
all contributing to that. And I look forward to
that and I look forward to everyone's feedback
on how Vercel can play a part in that future.
So to build on that, where
can folks find you online?
Should they just go to vercel.com, visit v0.com?
Yeah. And go to v0.dev-
.dev.
... to get started. I did mention
if you want to build your own v0,
this is more advanced, but check out our
templates on vercel.com/templates. And
also I'm BrouchG on X, so you can
DM me or tweet at me at any time.
Amazing. Guillermo, thank
you so much for being here.
Thank you, Lenny. It was so fun.
Bye, everyone.
(instrumental music)
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to the show
on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcasts.com. See you in the next episode.