Growth is a fairly new field. You have a
lot of renowned interest in growth hacks,
like what is the sure things to get growth. In
the age of social media everybody and anybody
tries to share their tips and tricks.
Oftentimes things that are completely
out of context or they are very specific to one
example and actually do not apply as a pattern.
We're going to start with growth
tactics that never work. If you see
these items on your roadmap, you should
probably not do them. What's number one?
We live in tech. There's always lots of
startups and startups obviously looking
to grow. There is a huge misconception in
the field that in order to get growth going,
you need a growth team. To figure out your
product market fit and how to distribute it,
it's not something that you
can outsource to somebody.
Powerful words. I'm loving this list already.
Number two, this was my favorite and
it might be a little spicy. Never ever
once have I seen a rebrand or redesign,
especially of UK marketing site produce
good performance results. New CMO comes
in designing their website or designing
the brand as if it was reflection of their
personal taste, and oftentimes it's promised
with our acquisition is going to go up and it
never materializes into anything meaningful.
A lot of contrary intakes here, I love this.
Number three, if every single one of your
initiatives that you're doing on growth is
an experiment that's a problem. It's almost
like a disease, like a paralyzing disease.
Today my guest is Elena Verna, my first ever third
time repeat guest. Elena is the smartest person
that I know on B2B Growth. She's also hilarious.
She's led growth at companies like Miro Amplitude,
Dropbox, and SurveyMonkey. She's advised dozens
of companies on growth including Superhuman,
MongoDB, Netlify, Similarweb, Sanity,
Maze, so many more. In our conversation,
Elena shares 10 growth strategies and tactics that
never work yet that she keeps seeing people and
companies invest lots of resources into. She also
covers her three favorite growth frameworks that
help you wrap your head around how to think about
growth, and she also does a short dive into the
non-traditional career paths that we both went
down. If you spend any time working on product
growth or lead people or work with people working
on growth, this episode is for you. If you enjoy
this podcast, don't forget to subscribe and
follow it in your favorite podcasting app or
YouTube. It's the best way to avoid missing
feature episodes and it helps the podcast
tremendously. With that, I bring you Elena Verna.
This episode is brought to you by Sinch the
customer communications cloud. Here's the thing
about digital customer communications, whether
you're sending marketing campaigns, verification
codes or account alerts, you need them to reach
users reliably. That's where Sinch comes in. Over
150,000 businesses, including eight of the top 10
largest tech companies globally use Sinch's API
to build messaging, email and calling into their
products. And there's something big happening in
messaging that product teams need to know about,
Rich Communication Services or RCS, think
of RCS as SMS 2.0. Instead of getting texts
from a random number, your users will see your
verified company name and logo without needing
to download anything new. It's a more secure and
branded experience, plus you get features like
interactive carousels and suggested replies.
And here's why this matters. US carriers are
starting to adopt RCS. Sinch is already helping
major brands send RCS messages around the world
and they're helping Lenny's podcast listeners
get registered first before the rush hits
the US market. Learn more and get started at
sinch.com/Lenny. That's S-I-N-C-H.com/Lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta.
When it comes to ensuring your company has
top-notch security practices, things get
complicated fast, now you can assess risk,
secure the trust of your customers, and automate
compliance for SOC 2, ISO 27001, HIPAA and
more with a single platform, Vanta. Vanta's
market-leading trust management platform helps
you continuously monitor compliance alongside
reporting and tracking risks. Plus, you can
save hours by completing security questionnaires
with Vanta AI. Join thousands of global companies
that use Vanta to automate evidence collection,
unify risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go to
Vanta.com/Lenny. That's V-A-N-T-A.com/Lenny.
Elena, thank you so much for being here. Welcome
back to the podcast, our first ever third-time
repeat guest. What an honor Dancing if you're not
watching on video. Thank you for being here. I was
actually just looking at our first episode,
which we recorded almost over two years ago,
September of 2022, and someone just today left a
comment. People are still finding and watching it,
and this comment encapsulates why I love
having you on this podcast. This person said,
"Wow, every word from Elena encapsulates
years of knowledge. This is one to digest,
slowly go back to and put on repeat. Thanks
for sharing your experience with the world"
Thank you for having me. And my
north star metric is insights per
minute. That's what I try to use
whenever I have any live meetings
with people so it squarely fits within
what I'm optimizing for. That's great.
That needs to be my KPI on this
podcast, "Insights per minute."
I think you have it. I think your
insights per minute is pretty high.
That is. I do shoot for that, although I have
learned you also needed to feel good and feel
their story. There's an interesting combo stuff.
You can't just be insight, insight, insight.
It's all about how you present
them too. Storytelling is a big
portion of it actually to stick.
Already insight. That's an insight right there.
There's two areas that I want to spend time on
with you, and these are areas I know you've been
thinking a lot about. One is growth tactics that
never work, that people keep spending time
on and waste their time on. And I know you
have a nice list of things you've seen that
just don't work that people keep trying. And
then two is growth frameworks, your favorite
growth frameworks to help people wrap their
mind around how to think about growth and
grow their product. We're going to start
with growth tactics that never works. Maybe
just frame what we're going to talk about,
talk about what this list and collection of
tactics that we're going to talk about is.
Growth is a fairly new field compared to marketing
or product management or engineering. There's a
lot of people that are now accumulated that have
10 years or so experience, but there's also a lot
of newcomers and because there's ratio of actually
newcomers, it's much higher than those people that
have five, 10 years of experience of doing growth.
You have a lot of renowned interest in growth
hacks. What is the sure things to get growth? What
is the sure thing to get that metric up? How can I
contribute to success with the company the fastest
way possible? All of these shortcuts and obviously
in the age of social media where everybody and
anybody tries to share their tips and tricks and
this and that, people are grasping for oftentimes
things that are completely out of context or they
are very specific to one example and actually
do not apply as a pattern or simply not even
applicable to their type of business whatsoever.
There's just a lot of failure happening in growth
teams. Actually, I think growth teams are becoming
one of those departments that has a higher head of
growth firing rate than even CMOs because people
are coming in, there's a bunch of expectations,
"Hey, you're ahead of growth or you are a growth
pm or you're a growth marketer, you're supposed
to drive growth." And when that growth does not
happen, here comes the axe and people off they go
and the recycle and cycle starts all over in order
to populate those positions. I think that there's
just a lot of misinformation I would say probably
out there in terms of what growth actually is and
how it should be done in the companies. And
today I just want to cover some of the biggest
ones that I see as a patterns as I'm advising
companies, as I'm operating in companies because
it's just so blatant yet there's very few pieces
of information on this for people to learn from.
Amazing. What's number one?
Number one, I have to start with hiring.
There's lots of positions open all the
time. There's so many from head of growth
to growth PM there's a lot of rotation,
as I said that is happening in the field. Very few
growth people actually stay in the job for over a
year or two years. There's a lot of constant churn
and constant rehiring. And when you doing hiring,
there's a lot of mistakes that are actually
happening in hiring that I just want to start
off on the list. It's not a roadmap item, but
oh my gosh, there's just so much fault that is
happening here. And I did write about it on your
blog of hiring for growth. There's a little bit of
a reference to that and one of the biggest latent
issues that I see is hiring too soon for growth.
We live in tech, there's always lots of startups.
Startups are obviously looking to grow and there
is a huge misconception in the shield that in
order to get growth going, you need a growth team,
absolutely not true. In order to get the growth
going in the company, a founder and the founding
team have to figure out how to make it grow
to the first, let's say a million, 5 million,
10 million in ARR. Some of the companies
don't even create growth teams until they're
a hundred, 200 million in ARR because to figure
out your product market fit and how to distribute
it's not something that you can outsource to
somebody. It's not somebody that with a shiny
resume can come over and all of a sudden wave
a magic wand and all of a sudden you have viral
campaigns and a bunch of signups coming through
and everybody's paying and everybody's retaining.
That just doesn't happen. I see that mistake
happening a lot. I really believe that the founder
led growth is not being popularized enough that
you do not need growth teams until you actually
can start running experiments on your user base,
which means that you have volume of users that you
can learn from and optimize and innovate on, and
that first wave of growth has to be founder led.
And there's two specific reasons that I incur
on, which is before you have growth team,
before you would think about growth team first
you need to have solid PMF, product market fit,
means that you have a solution to a problem
and you have customers not only coming in and
solving that problem with your solution, but
they're also retaining and staying with you.
There is a good retention. You can use channel
score of how many people would say that they
cannot live without your product as well, but
there's some sort of PMF. And then number two,
you have data growth cannot function without
data. If you have 10 users or 10 customers,
that's not data, that's a G-sheet with your
customers and you don't need a growth team for
that. Until you have data that you can actually do
an analysis and you can create hypotheses on and
you can start applying experimentation,
don't even think about growth team.
Just to summarize a few of the things you just
said, just for folks, you basically have seen
startups look for a head of growth to join and
solve their growth problem and your insight there
is just almost always that is not going to be the
solution to your problem until you have strong
retention already, have a really high score on the
channel score if don't have a ton of data yet and
party advice is just the founder should continue
to do this for as long as possible. A million ARR
is one milestone a lot of people recommend. To
your point, a lot of companies wait lot longer.
Yes. And honestly, the longer you wait,
the better it is because that way your
entire company will be trained to be
responsible for growth as opposed to
putting this one island with a growth team
and saying, "They're going to be growing,"
and what is the rest of the company doing?
Honestly, the longer you wait, the better.
As you talk about this, sales is
a part of what you described here,
like hiring your first sales person. And I
guess how do you think about your first head
of growth versus salesperson? Is there anything
advice there is? Like for B2B SaaS, you probably
don't hire head of growth for even longer,
you hire sales first or what's your advice?
It depends on how you're actually going to collect
the monies. If your money collection is going to
happen through sales team primarily, then you
absolutely should be hiring sales way before
growth. In fact, in the sales led companies,
growth teams are not necessarily needed even
that much. You might have a growth marketing
team, which is really a demand gen team that is
rebranded for growth marketing so they can charge
you 20 to 30% more in their salaries, but at the
end of the day, sales is doing your monetization.
They are doing your activation, they are doing
your retention and success efforts. For sales like
companies, yeah, higher sales, absolutely. Unless
you're starting to do self-serve revenue.
You're trying to have product sell itself
through potentially freemium acquisition, trial
acquisition or you actually having product led
activation, monetization, that's when you would
need a growth person. If you're starting with
self-serve monetization, growth hire should
be frankly first before sales. Your sales are
going to be more opportunistic in nature versus
if you sales led company, go ahead, hire sales,
wait for growth until you are ready to overlay
product-led growth on top of your sales motion.
That's an excellent clarification.
Basically what I'm hearing,
the advice is hire your ahead of growth
only when you have clear product market
fit and you're a product-led company and beyond
a millionaire ARR ideally something like that.
Right. And I won't say you're product-led
company. You are relying on product-led
motion to resolve a lot of the growth levers
within you because you don't have to be fully
product-led company. But if product, let's
say acquires people, let's say with the SEO
or SEM, and then its product is meant to
activate them and then sales closes them,
sales would be obviously important as well,
but growth would have to come in a little bit
sooner as well. If you have any product-led
components where product is responsible for
acquisition, activation, monetization or
retention, that's where growth comes in.
We talked deeply about that specific
topic in our first conversation,
just for folks, want to go
deeper there. There's lot there.
I need to bring it back. This is keeps happening.
I love that.
I need to repeat it. You need to repeat it
three times right before it sticks to people.
Hopefully this is the third time.
Absolutely. I'm only saying that because
people may be wanting more of what you're
describing and I will point them to our first
episode, which gives deep on that one topic.
Amazing.
Excellent. Anything else before
we move on to number two?
No, let's move on to number two.
Let's do it.
Number two, this is on the other side on the
matured company where I see a trend over and over,
and it's becoming even more prominent right
now of when companies growth slows down,
which inevitably happens for a lot of
businesses, it happens for a variety
of reasons. We're not going to go into the
reasons as to why growth can be slowing down
and then they hire a shiny growth head to fix
the problem, to basically saying, "Our business
is slowing down. We are on the decline. We're
going to bring this person, or we're going to
put this team together and our growth is
going to accelerate." That just does not
happen. If you have the overall business slowing
down, your head of growth is destined to fail
because the reason business is slowing down
is much deeper than not having a growth team.
Growth team can optimize, growth can maybe lift
it by 10, 15%. Maybe that's enough for you. Even
that is on the upper end of what growth team
will be able to do if there is a slow-down
trajectory. But what's important is that if you
have core product and core marketing issues,
growth team will not be able to fix them for you.
You're going to have to address the big elephant
in the room as to why business is slowing down
in the first place as opposed to just plopping
a growth team on the issue and expecting them
to do miracles while the rest of the business
continues chugging on the same trajectory
that caused the slowdown in the first place.
Wow, I've never heard this point before and it's
such an important one and it's very related to
your first point. Growth isn't going to build a
product people want, they will help you grow it
Exactly.
If your business is slowing, your
product market fit basically might
be disappearing and growth
isn't solving that problem.
Disappearing, it may be degrading, it may be
being eaten by a competitor because there's
somebody that is stomping on your territory.
The point is growth can amplify great product
market fit and growth can help you grow faster
once you are already growing. But if you are
slowing down and you have issues with either
your go-to-market strategy or your core product
strategy with your core product market fit,
growth is going to be absolutely helpless to
do anything. And it's honestly, it's a huge waste
of money because at those size of the companies,
you would make fairly large growth teams in order
to tackle every single product flow and interface
that is already out there and invented.
It's a huge expense. ROI on it, maybe
at least one to one. What you put into
it, you might get that much out of it,
but it's not going to be enough to create a J
curve of the reacceleration by just relying on
growth team. I think it's just like this is where
the name growth team plays against it because,
"We're looking for growth. Do you have a growth
team?" No. I don't have a better idea by the way
how to name it, but this is where I think it's
misunderstood that there's the silver bullet
of a perfect head of growth, perfect growth team
that can reverse the trajectory of the business.
Then for folks that are thinking about, "Wow,
maybe I should be hiring head of growth,"
when should you hire head of growth?
When you're an established company,
If you are declining in your revenue growth or
whatever other metric that you're looking at,
your weekly active users or whatnot, see at least
that you're able to plateau it so you can stop the
decline. There is already a visible trajectory
that your core product and your core marketing
teams are able to at least reverse the degradation
of the metrics. Ideally, you would even start to
see some immediate signs of life that there
is potential in the business, in the pockets,
and then you can put growth into it to really
blow it up to the full extent. But if you are on a
decline, just don't do it because there's going to
be very disappointing results in the year or so.
Awesome. Great one, let's move on. Number three.
Number three, this is my favorite, and it
might be a little spicy because if there's any
marketers listening out here, but doing rebrand
more specifically, homepage redesign to drive
growth. This is what hurts me so much and I've
lived through so many of these and never ever once
have I seen a rebrand or redesign, especially
a UK marketing site, produce good performance
results. Now, there's many reasons as to why you
might want to do a rebrand, why you might want to
design your marketing site because you're trying
to enter a new market, new category, your product
has evolved and you need to do a full update. But
those are almost like it's a logging indicator
that something needs to change and you're changing
it and then you know that you're going to have to
optimize the hell out of it in order to actually
bring it even to the previous performance results.
It's like a stepping stone back, but there is a
much bigger room for upside that you can get to,
but you are going to have to work to get
to that upside. But yet so many companies,
there's a story that happens all the time. I
hire a new CMO, new CMO comes in, they're like,
"What's inside my house here? My house is not
designed to my liking. Let me repaint these walls.
I want this shade of blue. Let me put the couches
over here." And they start almost designing
their website or designing the brand as if it was
reflection of their personal taste. And oftentimes
it's promised with our acquisition is going to go
up, our category penetration is going to go up,
our education or awareness is going to go up.
And it never materializes into anything meaningful
because again, if you're doing it as a step
towards unlocking new global maxima, sure,
I love that. Do it. Go after it. Know that
you have a ton of work ahead of you in order
to actually unlock that global maxima.
But to ever promise a homepage redesign
or marketing site redesign in order to drive
more acquisition is a failed promise that is
going to be led by lots of agency money
spending, often a million dollars plus,
lots of arguing about which shade of blue
your brand color is going to be, and eight
to 10 months at the minimum of development
and very lackluster results afterwards.
Oh man, I'm loving this list already. This is
great. To your point, it may still be worth doing
if you're coming into it eyes wide open, this
isn't going to drive growth, but we're setting
ourselves up for a future brand that's world-class
and we know our current brand stinks and our
homepage needs to be refreshed. If you're aware,
it's not going to drive growth, it might be okay.
Every single time I've seen a marketing site
at least rebrand, it's been a step back in
performance that then is being treated as a
fire drill to fix. Just don't do it if you
expect immediate results out of it, or at least
educate the team on how long it's going to take
to get to the point where you think that there's
going to be upside away from your original brand.
I've experienced this not
just with marketing sites,
but most redesigns. Redesign of the product.
Product redesign. How much product and
engineering work comes into just changing
a logo in your product or changing colors? It's
insane. With no results ever, there's no results.
And to your point, it's like, "We've
spent six months redoing onboarding.
Everything we've built builds on this new
design and experience, we can't not launch
it. Every team is working on this new world,
we're just going to launch it and then we're
going to claw back. We're going to figure
out how to get it back." That's how it goes.
It's a new starting point and that starting
point is going to be much lower than your
current optimized experience that you have.
Whether it's well optimized or not optimized,
it doesn't matter. It's gone through some level
of optimization versus rebrand is always a shot
in the dark. It might be prettier, sure, but
that doesn't mean it's going to perform well.
Obviously never say never. Sometimes it
might work, and if it worked for you,
I am so glad. But that's an outlier
and don't treat it as a pattern.
And I was just going to say, I think everyone
listening to this that is working on something
like this is probably thinking, "No,
I think we have a good shot at this."
... is working on something like this is probably
thinking, "No, I think we have a good shot at
this. We've really thought deeply about this
and it might actually be really positive." In
your experience, it sounds like you've seen
it work occasionally, or is it just never?
The best I've ever seen is that it produced net
neutral results and it produced us better ability
to optimize towards something bigger. That's the
best case scenario. So if you're working on it,
my biggest advice is not to say you stop.
Just understand that the goal here is not
to drive at launch, in the seven-day readout
after launch, some increased performance.
The goal here should be, we will
launch, we will probably see a hit,
model out and forecast for a hit, and then give
yourself two to three months at the minimum,
ideally more like six months, to really
optimize it back to a good standing where
it can potentially outperform. But you need
to bake in that three to six months of work
after the launch, which is what a lot of companies
and teams forget to do because they just move on.
Because it's like big initiative, big
pop, and off we go to our next project.
I love that we're only at number three.
This is amazing. Let's do number four.
Okay. Number four is obsessing over your
competition. Okay, so there's a little bit
of a gotcha here. I tear down companies all
the time. I have thousands of Gmail accounts
that I sign up for any and every product. I
go through their entire experience. I look at
their monetization strategies. I look at their
activation. I do it across direct competition of
the company that I'm working with as well.
I want to know what I'm playing against.
So knowing what your competition is doing is
extremely important. Being inspired by some
aspects of what your competition is doing in their
experience is a wonderful place to originate an
ideation or potentially try to implement into your
product as well. But blatantly saying, "Hey, we're
going to copy all of these best tactics or all
of these flows because, hey, they're doing better
than us. Let's just rip them and do exactly the
same. Why isn't our onboarding looks the same as
this onboarding? This company is so successful."
That's where things really go wrong because
every single experience is very unique
to their customer, to their channel.
You don't even know if you're getting their
actual experience or you use some tester cell
or you're getting some personalized thing based
on where you signed up from, who you said that you
are. So you don't even know what actually the
overall thing looks like most of the time and
putting that into your product, it just leads to
very subpar results. And there's a lot of drive,
especially to have it as a shortcut. "Okay, we
don't want to go through this ideation or user
research. We don't want to do user interviews,
but we don't want to do A/B testing. It works
for them. It must work for us. Let's just
go and do it." And it fails 95% of the time.
Now, there are certain pieces that I would rightly
recommend. I already said inspiration. I use it
for inspiration all the time. I'm like, "Okay,
what's cool? What is everybody doing?" So because
I want to just stay in the know on what other
people are implementing and hopefully if it's
in the control experience, it works and it worked
better. I use web archives a ton for locked out
pages too. I'm like, okay, how did it look last
year? Why does their whole page look this way,
or the pricing page? And I analyze that
and I try to extrapolate some results.
I also think that there is a lot of patterns
you start to notice as you start tearing down
all of these companies. You're like, "Oh,
these elements are always the same." That
means all of these companies are arriving
to these things and they seem to be winning
elements. And you can take those elements and
put them into your product, but you can never
skip the ideation, the design, the user research,
the customer interview, the experimentation step.
And you should always balance it with actually
innovating yourself in your product. Because
copying competition is like the fastest way to
mediocrity because you'll never be a leader if
you copied somebody else. Leader is by default is
somebody that is able to separate themselves from
the pack in something else. And if you are trying
to just be, I don't know who is ever trying to be
the mediocre middle of the pack, but maybe it's
a good starting point, but never the end goal.
The only other thing that I'll say before I'll
stop talking is benchmarks. Benchmarks are also
very dangerous here to use because benchmarks
are usually done on all of the competition,
on all of the softwares out there. And the way
people define numbers is so different from company
to company. Even if you look as something as
simple as signups. Okay, how many signups should
you be on average getting? Or your conversion from
prospecting visitor to a signup? Or from a signup
to activated user? It's so depends on how do you
define prospect visitor? Some companies define it
as all traffic. Some define it as new traffic.
Some of them define it on the new IP address,
new persistent id. How Google analytics
defines it. How Amplitude defines it.
So all of these definitions are so different. So
taking also any benchmark that is derived from
competition and saying, "This is where we should
be," is also so dangerous because it might not
even be applicable depending on how you define the
metric. And one of the things that all of those
benchmarking data fails is to actually look at
specific definitions. And that's not to say that
benchmarks are not extremely valuable data point
in your decision making because it's an input
that you should leverage to say what it could
be possible. But to just blindly it and set it
is just a sure way to fail any
of your initiatives and efforts.
You're telling me that there's no shortcuts?
I wish there were. I mean, I've been doing this
for over 15 years. If there were any shortcuts,
I'd be all over them. There are patterns and
there are frameworks, but there's no shortcuts.
So people hearing this, they're like,
"Okay, don't copy the competition. Use
it for inspiration." It's a little hard to
know exactly the line between those two.
Is there an example that you can think
of where you took really interesting
inspiration from someone and it worked
for a company you're working with? Or
you copied someone and it's just like,
"Oh, that failed. That was a bad idea."
I use competition to understand the general
framework of how people collect some information
or resolve certain steps. So, for example,
a sharing model so many products like, "Hey,
can you share this with somebody?" Well, you can
go and spend so much time of figuring out how it
should look. Or you can go to Slack, you can go to
Figma, you can go to Nero, you can go to Notion.
Like, okay, Google, how are they doing sharing
model? You can look at all of that and say,
"Okay, here's all of the common elements that all
of them have. Here's the pieces that I think will
apply to my product. Here's things that do
not, and here's what I can derive from it."
I use it as an input into ideation, but I
never use it as a destination for the result,
if that makes sense. Because it's very helpful to
not start from scratch. The empty start problem
is real and competition is a wonderful way
to not have that and to have input into it,
but never to just say, "Oh, we can skip the design
cycle off we go," or, "Just slap our colors on it.
If it works for them, it's going to work for us."
So I have extensive Nero boards with everybody's
onboarding flows, with everybody's pricing pages,
their sharing model, their invite colleagues
models that I reference all the time.
But they've never been the exact thing
that I would use for any company as opposed
to say, "Hey, I think this is a great starting
point for you. Here are the things that I
think will work very well for your company
and for your product and take these elements.
The rest you need to go and do themselves,
so at least that way there's a starting point."
And this is why I also started doing a lot more
of my own, almost, prototypes, like skeletons
of here's the elements that you should do in
these flows. I have one for pricing page, I
have one for homepage, but you need to put
in your own [inaudible 00:32:36] into
it, in order for it to actually work.
What made me realize this back in the day was
thinking at Airbnb, especially, thinking about
people looking at our flow and being like, they've
got it all figured out. We're just going to copy
what they've done, so thoughtful and have tested
everything. And knowing how that has not happened
and how so much of this was guesswork and we hate
so much of it. Just thinking about people trying
to copy this thinking we know what we're doing.
It's like, "What are you guys even thinking?"
Oh my God, I actually had that happen to me. At
Dropbox not so long ago, somebody reached out
and they're like, "Oh, I looked." It was like
some page on activation flow and they're like,
"Oh, I love this page. This is so cool. I love
what you've done here. I'm going to go take it
to my company." I'm like, "We haven't touched
it in 10 years. This page is only visible for
small cohort of people. Please don't do
it. Please don't copy it. It performs like
shit. I know it's out there, but it's not
meant to be out there. Nobody thoughtfully
put it out there." So that's definitely a
huge failure point that you can run into.
Right, if it's like a fancy company,
assume they're just so smart and diligent
about every little pixel and decision.
If people only knew of how much
craziness is happening in those
big companies and how much chaos there is.
Oh man, that's a whole other podcast episode.
Whole other podcasts, yes.
Okay, number five.
Okay, I have this one. It's a little bit Meta, but
I see it happening all the time. We love to think
that our problems are unique. I'm working in this
company and we have this gross problem and we need
to go and figure out the solution from the grounds
up. Maybe this is a little bit related to the
competition point, but I'm very sorry to break it
to all of you, but your problem is not unique. I
am 99% sure of that. Your problem has been felt by
somebody somewhere in probably many, many places
and you trying to re-engineer solution is time
lost to market and has a huge opportunity cost.
So my biggest thing that I try to get people is
don't think that you have unique problems. You
don't. I know we love to. It'd be fun to have
something unique to learn, but with so many
startups, with so many people in our industry,
in your industry, whichever industry that is,
your problem has been solved by somebody. Or
at least that there's a lot of failures on
the problem that you should be learning from.
And number one thing that whenever you have an
initiative or whenever you have a metric that you
need to go and move, to not start from scratch,
ever. Do not start from scratch. It's the worst
thing that you can do because you can waste so
many cycles on trying to do something
that probably has already been solved,
which means how do you approach this as a result?
Well, you can look at competition and how they're
solving the problem. That's one input, for sure.
You should go find people that have solved this
problem because there are people there and people
love to talk about what they do. So take advantage
of that human psychology and go find those people
and just ask them, "How did you do it? What did
you do? What happened?" Obviously, not all the
time everybody's going to respond, but we have
LinkedIn, we have X. Go out there, find the people
that you think or ask around in your network of
who you think might have similar solutions and
just go talk to people. It would be incredible
shortcut if you're talking about an actual hack
that is a hack to get to an optimal solution.
And then the last thing that I would
also say is that solving any one problem
uniquely is extremely inefficient. We
are evolving so fast in our market,
you need to be able to patternize your
solutions. Patternize, is that a word?
Let's make it a word.
Make patterns. Make patterns out of your
solutions. So more you can stop looking at as
a unique data point or unique problem and more as
there is, I need to fit it into existing pattern
or I need to figure out the framework on how to
solve not only this problem but other problems.
The faster you'll be able to get at least to like
60% of the solution there. And then you can do
very authentic implementation of whatever you want
to do. But to go from zero to 60 manually, as a
one-off, we do not have time in the industry right
now to do it, unless you want to be left behind.
Bam. Powerful words. Is there an
example that comes to mind of you
doing this either the wrong way of just
thinking this was unique and realizing I
should have talked to people, or where you
actually realized something was not unique?
I'll give you actually an example that
I had when I was at Nero. At Nero,
we were first trying to stand up community, and
I was tasked to do it, and I've never done it
before. So I was banging my head around against
the wall and I'm like, "Okay, how do I do it? What
software do we use? Where do we acquire users?
What kind of content is going to go in there?"
So I was approaching it almost like a finding
product market fit, and I will fail so much doing
it. And I honestly only have a year to get to some
sort of traction before this is going to get shut
down because company is impatient, company
is moving fast. So if this is going to be a
failure point, it's either going to be taken away
from me, which is fair, or we is going to close
the door on it, which would be a huge failure
both on my point and for company as a whole.
So I went and I started talking to a bunch
of people that have done communities, and I
remember talking to Caroline from Atlassian who
has stood up community. I actually hired her as
an advisor afterwards and she's like, "Well, are
you talking about a user community or an agency
community or a partner community?" And I'm like,
my mind was blown. I'm like, "I even considering
all of these angles because I was just literally
thinking about users only." And she's like, "Well,
you shouldn't necessarily start with the user
community. If you want some results out of it,
go to agency or partner communities first." She
would applying it to me in a structural way for
me to grasp my head around it and then implement
something that had much better results at the
end that I wouldn't even gotten to probably until
six, eight months later, if I didn't talk to her.
So I think it has to come with a place
of knowing that you don't know everything
and humility to say, "Hey, I need help," and I
might have a already fancy title. At that point,
I was an interim CMO at Nero and I'm like, "I
don't know how to do this." And it actually earns
you a lot more credit than you think. And a lot
of people are afraid to admit that they don't know
how to solve a problem and that's why they start
from scratch. But you need to really put your ego
aside and get some help faster than trying to
hit every single failure point along the way.
And the thing that'll really hurt your ego
is failing. And so the more you could do
to avoid failing and being successful with this
initiative by talking to people, doing research.
And to be fair, failure is going to be
unavoidable. If you talk about growth,
growth is about failure. My big motto, life
motto on growth is that you have to fail to
learn. You can't just constantly succeed.
Success is an output of a lot of failures,
but the question is, how much time do you
have to fail? And a lot of times we don't
realize how many failure cycles we're going
to have to go through before we get a success,
and that company, or even market, has no
time for that. So still expect to fail,
sure, but the timeline for failures
is going to be shortened quite a bit.
Okay, so we've gone halfway through your
list. There's 10 items on this list, right?
Yes, yes. There's 10 items.
Next one is a good one.
I'm excited to chat with Christina Gilbert,
the founder of OneSchema, one of our
longtime podcast sponsors. Hi, Christina.
Yes. Thank you for having me on, Lenny.
What is the latest with OneSchema? I know you now
work with some of my favorite companies like Ramp,
Vanta, Scale, and Watershed. I heard
that you just launched a new product
to help product teams import CSVs from
especially tricky systems like ERPs.
Yes, so we just launched OneSchema file feeds,
which allows you to build an integration with
any system in 15 minutes as long as you can export
a CSV to an SFTP folder. We see our customers all
the time getting stuck with hacks and workarounds
and the product teams that we work with don't have
to turn down prospects because their systems
are too hard to integrate with. We allow our
customers to offer thousands of integrations
without involving their engineering team at all.
I can tell you that if team had
to build integrations like this,
how nice would it be to be able to
take this off my roadmap and instead
use something like OneSchema and not just to
build it, but also to maintain it forever?
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many
horror stories of multi-day outages from
even just a handful of ad records. We are
laser-focused on integration reliability to
help teams end all of those distractions
that come up with integrations. We have
a built-in validation layer that stops
any bad data from entering your system,
and OneSchema will notify your team
immediately of any data that looks incorrect.
I know that importing incorrect data can cause
all kinds of pain for your customers and quickly
lose their trust. Christina, thank you for
joining us and if you want to learn more,
head on over to oneschema.co. That's oneschema.co.
Let me summarize the first five real quick
and then we'll keep going. So the first is,
wait longer than you think to hire a head of
growth. Wait until you have product market fit,
maybe a million, or especially
if you're self-serve oriented.
Number two is if your growth is declining, the
head of growth won't solve that problem. First,
stop the decline at least. Third is redesigning
your homepage, marketing page. Rebranding is not
only not going to help you grow, it's going
to probably hurt growth and slow things down.
And so just go into that wide eyes wide open.
Four is don't just copy the competition and
assume they know what they're doing and assume
that what they do is going to work for you.
Use it as inspiration. On the other hand, look
at get inspiration from experts, competition,
trends, things like that to help you solve your
problem, which you think is no one solved before.
It turns out every problem you're solving
someone has solved in some way, most likely.
Yes, especially in growth. I
mean, I know this can apply to
a lot of product management and to
marketing as well, but in growth,
when you're talking about how do I lift activation
or have a really big drop off between activation
and monetization? These things are a lot more
patternized than you would expect them to be,
so go and find those patterns as
opposed to trying to re-engineer it.
Awesome. Okay, let's keep going. Number six.
So next one. Next one is a little spicy one
too, and that is part of growth you owning some
channels. A lot of growth teams own acquisition.
So owning channels and growth prioritizing SEO,
SEM, social, is one of the biggest mistakes
I think a growth team can do. Now, obviously,
I'm not saying don't do SEO, or don't do
SEM, so organic search or paid search. I'm
not saying that. However, as a growth team, your
number one priority is to create your own or your
earned channel. So channel that you've earned
and that nobody else can compete in but you.
What do I mean by that? When you're doing organic
search or paid search, you're making Google
richer. Great for Google. Google is an incredible
company, but by dumping money into paid marketing,
you are paying them and you're paying for their
distribution and access to their distribution. If
you're doing social too, like you're doing, let's
say, Instagram or whatnot, paid advertising in
Instagram, that's great, but all of that works on
algorithm. An algorithm can giveth, but algorithm
can also taketh away at any point. And you have
no control because you don't own those channels.
You are playing with other players and you're
competing against them in somebody else's channel.
Now, on the other side, there can
be your own earned channel. What
is earned channel? It really goes into the
concept of product-led growth acquisition,
which means you're relying on virality, on word
of mouth, on user-generated content in order to
attract new acquisition through top of the
funnel. So why is that earned and why do I
put that above, let's say organic search, which
is SEO, obviously, is wonderful? But again,
search just goes to Google. That's great.
Versus if you build your own user-generated
content in your own community, nobody else can
compete with you in that. That is yours. Your
competitors cannot buy their eyeballs. Their
people are going to be attracting other people.
Referrals from people to people are everything.
So, Lenny, if I, let's say I sign up for,
say, Superhuman and I invite you into it. That
is much stronger acquisition tactic versus you
looking for and finding Superhuman, let's
say on paid marketing advertisements. And
especially with our age right now where search as
an interface is changing towards AI interface and
the AI interface is giving a lot less credit to
all of the content. Content is almost becoming
a database and there's a new UI that is being
developed on it. Before it was Google was the UI,
and now AI is coming in with a new UI, and
there's not as much control that you have
over this new UI that is being developed.
Focusing on these earned channels that you
own becomes the outmost priority. And if you don't
have them on your growth roadmap, you are going to
be in some really big trouble over the next year
to two years because your cost of acquisition is
only going to go up. Your competition and those
channel is only going to go up. You're constantly
going to be praying to algorithm Gods to giveth
your way, but again, they can taketh at any point.
And it's really one of those fundamental
growth team failure points if they don't
spend enough time on virality and user generated
content to create their own earned acquisition.
Wow. Okay. This is incredible. This is its own
podcast episode in theory that we could do of how
to actually do this. We're not going to cover
the strategy. Also, this may not necessarily
work for every company. Your point is, you
can grow other ways, but this is by far ...
Your point is you can grow other ways,
but this is by far the most powerful,
most effective, cheapest, most likely
to succeed. If you can figure this out.
It's not cheapest. It's actually cost a lot
of product and engineering and even marketing
resources to stand up. So it's not the cost of
a budget, but it's cost of people that will have
to work to create your own channel, so to
speak, for acquisition. And you're right,
maybe that's not for everybody, but it's
actually applicable to more products than
people realize. Because, every single product
has some sort of team functionality, some sort
of roles that they need to do. Every product
can drive word of mouth loop... Well, actually,
that's not true. Not every product can drive word
of mouth loop, but they can drive recommendations
and they can create user generated content.
One of those tactics usually applies to at
least one product. So there is an opportunity
to create some sort of earned channel, even
though it might feel unnatural at the beginning
depending on how you reach PMF and how you've
scaled in the first couple of stages of it. But
if you are not exploring it and if you are not
investing into it or at least trying and failing
within it, I think that you are really leaving too
much of your growth future into the hands of
somebody else that you have low control over.
So the advice here is your growth
team. It's okay if they work on SEM,
pay growth basically and SEO, but most
of your effort and investment should
be in earned channel, owned channels,
specifically virality generated content?
Diversify. Just diversify your strategy.
So not all of it is reliant on somebody
else giving you access to their
distribution. Now, for example,
a Dropbox, over 50% of acquisition comes through
sharing. So I load something into my Dropbox,
maybe I need to send it out for signature. Maybe
I need to just share this file to transfer it to
somebody. Maybe I just need to share this file as
a final delivery to my clients that I was working
with. Well, that recipient then is now aware
of Dropbox, so it solved the brand awareness.
By that action of sharing, you actually
almost activated that recipient too,
so you don't need to educate them anymore on how
the product works and whatnot. And the percentage
of those recipients sign up to become Dropbox
users, and that accounts for 50% of acquisition.
That is a stable earned channel that nobody can
compete with, and it's only for Dropbox to lose,
so to speak. And we actually had our own growth
pod focused on it. Because to optimize both sender
experience and the recipient experience,
because it was such a powerful growth and
growth engine that driven the company, and every
business should have an attempt at one of these.
I think this is going to be a really
good push for a lot of growth teams
to think about what could we do
here? Number seven. Four to go
Number seven. We've talked about this at least
a little bit in our last podcast too. But I see
this as a question that comes up all the time and
something that people are afraid of to invest,
which is a mistake. Every single company
starts with their growth efforts focused
either on product-led growth. Hey, I'm going
to have everything being done self-serve or
on sales in marketing. I'm going to have sales
team and then I'm going to have marketing team
and they're going to do all of the work and my
product is just going to create the functionality.
And that's good and fine for a while depending
on how long that while is. But not overlaying
every single way that you can grow through
product, through marketing and through sales
as an evolution. Is a huge mistake that a lot of
growth teams fail to iterate on and innovate on.
The way that I best be comparing it is if
product has a product-market fit, which is great,
that product-market fit is not going to last that
product forever. They're always going to have
to have a second horizon. They're always going
to have to have a product-market fit expansion
efforts in order to continue to grab as many
people and solve as many people's problems as
possible and increasing their team. Well, the
same comes with growth. If you have a growth
model that works for you, that's wonderful,
good for you. Optimize it, grow it, scale it,
create a team that will be nurturing it and that
will be amplifying it, but you're going to need
to evolve it, and that evolution needs to come
through overlaying other growth models on top
of it. So, A, you are diversified away from just
one growth model failing, because a lot of times
you're going to get into a situation of law.
I love Andrew Chen's article here. It's called
a Law of Shitty Clickthroughs. Where if you
over-optimize the same thing over and over again,
it has minimal returns, and some growth models
have very limited time spans. Some of them are
huge, some can grow for sharing loop at Dropbox.
It's 17 years in the making and it's still firing.
Good for it. That's amazing. But that's very
much an anomaly. Most of growth loops spin out
their ability to produce meaningful results for
you within the first five to six to seven years.
So continuously overlaying those different
growth models, and what I'm specifically talking
about is product-led growth, marketing- led
growth, sales-led growth, and introducing
it into this ecosystem constantly is what really
separates companies that can continue growing for
a long periods of times versus the ones that can
see a really big blip, potentially even unicorn
type of growth rates of 70, 80, whatever plus
percent, and then it starts to slow down. And
don't wait until that slowdown happens. You need
to really start thinking about different ways
that you can attract people to grow so you are not
leaving a gap in the market that somebody else can
enter and own. As opposed to you playing in every
way in where you can interact with your customer.
The way I think about this is the S-curves
of every growth model and growth lever,
right? Eventually it'll help and then
slow down and see you want to find the
next S-curve on things that'll grow your business.
Yes, absolutely. The way that I see it often
is that especially when growth teams, they hit
a really big result out of some initiative, they
just keep trying to focus on that over and over
again. And sometimes that focus is warranted.
Like I said, our sharing loop at Dropbox has
its own growth team against it. Great, but at
the same time, a lot that's not warranted for
all of the... Or you need to realize that there's
not more choose to squeeze out of this thing and
then you need to go and you need to move on.
Which actually brings me to a little bit of
a next thing too, is you need to do it every
18 months. Because a lot of them are going to
fail. And every five years or so, you for sure
need new channel, new growth loops, new tactics,
new engines so to speak, to power your growth
engine. Whether it's overlaying sales on top of
self-serve, whether you're doing a lot of, let's
say virality right now in terms of acquisition
and you're going into marketing a lot heavier.
But every five years something big has to start
taking a big portion of your volume. And for that
every 18 years you need to introduce something-
18 months.
Sorry. Yeah. Every 18 months you need to introduce
something new in order for
it to continue evolving.
And was that number eight of the list we're going
through or that's like a bonus piece of advice?
No, that's just a bonus piece of advice.
Okay, cool. Okay, got it. And so the
advice here essentially is you'll
find something that is helping you grow,
assume that will slow down at some point,
start thinking about other levers and
growth models to layer on top of that.
Yeah.
Something I've seen, let me know if you agree,
is usually there's going to be one lever that
has most of your growth for a long, long time,
and so all other things are not going to
be as big, but they are still important.
So the way I think about it is I try to focus
20 to 25% of growth teams time annually. Not
every given sprint or not every given quarter,
but annually to introduce a new growth loop,
or to introduce a new channel, or to introduce
something new that can potentially bring us
additional umpth to our growth engine. I
know that a lot of it is going to fail.
None of it is gold on any growth metrics
because you cannot goal it immediately,
let's say on monetization or immediately
acquisition. You're just going to cut it at
its knees immediately if you're not going to let
it evolve into something that can be monetized,
that can be responsible for acquisition. So
example on Mirrorverse, which is a user-generated
content library of all of the mirror boards that
people create, it took us probably 18 months until
we started putting metrics expectations on it.
Before that, it was a thing that we were testing.
And it was being used by a lot of people, but
we're like, we don't even know exactly quite
how this is going to fit all together. And
then it started taking off as both engagement
engine as well as acquisition engine. But it's
important to constantly give your team room to
try those new ideas. Otherwise, you're going to
find yourself that your growth loops and your
growth engine is slowing down and you don't have
time to find that second horizon. And that is the
worst situation to be in. That's where growth
starts to slow down. And to recover out of that
is impossible because you need revenue. You need
revenue, you need revenue, you need revenue. And
these growth loops on average take six months,
a year, a year and a half to start producing
even visible revenue. So that's why you need to
start layering it very soon into your initiatives.
To make this even more concrete for
people that are starting to like, oh,
shit I got to do this. Can you just give us
a list that doesn't have to be exhaustive
of potential growth loops, levers, methods,
engines for folks to consider? You've mentioned
a few, but just give a list of people like,
okay, got it. Maybe we'll try one of these.
I'm really big on creating a growth loop
out of user generated content. I think with
everything that is happening with AI and SEO
at the moment, your biggest claim to fame on
content strategy will be harnessing user generated
content. Whether it's user generated templates,
whether it's user generated case studies,
review, whatever it is you need to start
investing into it now, creating a library
out of it, using it for activation purposes,
using it then for acquisition purposes, using
community to spark the conversations around
it. That can be a really wonderful strategy
that everybody should consider of whether
there's juice in it within your product.
Other ones can be, hey, we're a very,
let's say individualistic product, but can we
actually create a referral mechanism for it?
For B2C, that's actually very straightforward. A
lot of B2C products thrive on referrals. For B2B,
It can be more of invitation of other team
members into the product to complete other
jobs to be done. Hey, I've done this. I need
my manager to see it. Can I create a report
to share with my manager? And all of a sudden it
starts to spread within the company. So creating
additional almost product functionality that then
creates these loops potentially for you. So it can
be a slew of things. Obviously, I would highly
recommend just understanding all of the menus of
these earned tactics. I should do a blog post on
it actually. And then just see what works for you
or not. Because at least ideation step a bit has
to happen. If especially you're relying on search
engines for your acquisition, start thinking about
some of the earned channels as soon as possible.
And even though you recommend
spend more time on earned channels,
owned channels, there's also explore
SEO, explore paid growth, right? Sales?
Absolutely. I mean, almost everybody that's
paid, arguably almost too soon potentially.
There's a point to make that shouldn't be. A
company should not be doing paid right now,
but SEO, social resellers, all of those
are wonderful tactics. Obviously, I skew
very heavily towards earned channels
just because once you stand that up,
that's a gift that just keeps on giving and
nobody can take that away from you. But that
doesn't mean that other tactics and other
channels should not be explored as well.
Amazing. Let's keep going. So we
have three to go. Number eight.
So number eight, this one's kind of a doozy
and I think a lot of people don't do it. I
don't know why they don't do it. I think it's
such an incredible ability to propel forward.
And that is, what doesn't work, as I said in the
previous growth tactics, is trying to think that
each problem is unique and you need to solve it on
your own. Maybe this is not so much does it work,
but not hiring advisors is something that I do
not recommend for you to do. You can get access
to anybody for one hour a week. Yeah, you'll have
to pay them. So nobody's going to volunteer their
hour. We're all very, very busy. But hiring
advisors is the biggest career amplification
and your business amplification can possibly
do. Because to create a network of people that
have all of these data points and those all of
the other patterns that you can do is something
that can just propel you so far forward.
That doesn't mean you have to do everything
advisor says. That's not the point. They're not
the strategy setter. But they are additional input
into your decision-making that you otherwise
wouldn't have. You can go and hire somebody
from Atlassian. You can go and hire somebody
from Airbnb that have been and lived through
all of this and they can help you solving
your problem. So I think any growth team that
does not have an advisor is a growth team that is
underperforming. Because even me who I've advised
so many companies, I've operated at so many
companies, I don't know everything. Every time I
take an operator role, I hire advisors for myself.
Because that is the fastest way to learn anything,
and I often see these teams that just try to
figure out everything on their own and not
have any advisors on their boards, so to speak.
I'm not even talking like an official board. I'm
talking not even an advisory board. But you can
hire somebody as a contractor that will be your
advisor, I think is a huge mistake, especially in
this day and age. Because we have a big asymmetry
of information. In our field, there's very little
available to learn because we're all very cagey
because of competition. But at the end of the
day, people know a lot of the stuff and how it
worked for them internally, and I highly, highly
encourage you to not try to wing it on your own.
Along those lines, there's
also advice of just like,
don't worry about advisors. You never know
if they're going to be useful. There's all
these hanger-ons that join your startup
and want to help, but they're not helpful.
If you give one tip for a founder or team
that's interviewing advisors, looking for
an advisor to vet them to help them find people
that are actually great, what would your tip be?
I have actually a good one. Many advisors
might not like it though. I think that you
should not hire an advisor until you do some sort
of workshop with them on the problem that you're
experiencing. See them in action. See what
kind of information they can provide to you,
because any advisor that is cagey about
what they know is not the type of advisor
that you're going to want to have on your team.
You want to have somebody that has lived through
it that can talk to you, to your face about
it, that is able to have hard conversations.
That is able to provide you necessary examples.
That is able to give you and connect dots for
you for necessary patterns. So instead of
just saying, "Oh, this person looks good,
let me hire them as an advisor." Say, "Hey,
let's have a workshop first. I have this
problem. I think that you can help me fix it."
Pay them for it, whatever their rate is for
that workshop, for sure. See how they actually
interact with your team and then hire them on
ongoing retainer bases. Because that creates
an interview loop that is very practical,
that is very quick to understand whether you
can work with them, they can work with you,
and whether they have anything to contribute to
you. And then every single month evaluate whether
that advisor should stay with you. Some advisors,
they only need to be with the company for three
months and off they go, that's fine. Some of
them might stick with you for four or five years,
but every single month you should go and say, did
they add any value? I'm not saying that advisors
should have any monetary expectations like
revenue attribution, so to speak to them. But
did you find value in having conversations with
them? Did they offer anything valuable to you?
That was an awesome tip. And I could see
why people would be like, "God damn. Elena,
don't say that." It makes so much sense.
Here we go. Number nine. Here we go.
My last one is also that I see something
way too often nowadays on growth teams
specifically. This is very, very gross problem.
And that is too much risk averseness on growth,
where you're starting to test everything. If every
single one of your initiatives that you're doing
on growth is an experiment, that's a problem
and that is something that you should take a
look at and say, what am I doing and why do
I need a precise scientific measurement for
every single thing that I touch in order for
it to go to production or to hit the market?
It's almost like a disease, like a paralyzing
disease, that slows down progress, that slows
down velocity, that slows down learnings,
that creates very terrible consequences
to the output that growth teams produce.
And it's a little bit counterintuitive,
because experimentation is a way to do growth for
growth teams and it's their process. Growth teams
are meant to experiment, but I also think that
experimenting on everything is something that
is quite terrible once the team starts to get
locked into that state, and it's really hard
to get out of because they're then afraid to
do any change until or unless that they test.
So where do you find that balance? I
imagine people hearing this are like,
oh, yes, this makes sense to me, and then
they continue to test basically everything.
What's kind of some heuristics
you'd recommend for knowing, okay,
just don't test that. Don't worry about
it. You don't need credit for that win.
First of all, I think that people should trust
their intuition a little bit more. Data is good,
but data is only good if you have enough of
it. So if you have low volume real estate,
that is going to take you eight months
to reach some sort of answer. Do you
really want to test it for eight months?
What's the point of it? My rule of thumb,
if we cannot collect the sample size
in the month, we shouldn't test it,
period. Because it's just then it's not fast
enough. We should just go and do pre versus post.
Pre versus post is pretty powerful. It's also a
way to assess your impact and you can still roll
back if it doesn't work. But don't think that
everything needs a scientific explanation to
whether it needs to be moved forward or not.
Also, experimentation cannot be the way that
people make decisions in the company. There's
still so much about knowing your user,
understanding the market for your brain to
connect all of those dots and to know what
needs to be an experience that your customers
are going to want. That if scientific data,
like a very tight determination of the probability
that this is a success, it's important,
absolutely do it because it might be a really
big strategical pivot that you're planning to
do. So it's a data point to validate that all
of this extra work will be needed. It might
be a very high traffic real estate that even 0.1%
difference will mean millions of dollars for you.
But other than that, it should be just go,
go, go. Do pre versus post. By the way,
I'm not saying just release and move on. Release,
do seven day, 24 hour readout, seven day readout,
28 day readout, even come back to it a year
later and measure some of the retention or
extension data that is associated with it.
But to test everything is debilitating to
growth teams and app paralyzes them in its place.
So kind of look at your initiatives and say,
where do I need precision? And it's important
and I can get it best in that versus where we
should just go for it. And yeah, we will fail
there too, and that's okay. And we can roll back
and we can figure out how to make it better.
But failure is going to happen regardless.
In statistics, six is tricky. Many people
take it for face value versus it's just like
a directional data point to say there's likely
new distribution that has maybe a different mean,
and 5% of the chances. If you measure in 95%
statistical significance, you might not even be
there, and yet really take it for so granted.
Oh, it's going to drive this much lift. So I
just think that people stop in this age of data,
almost rely enough on their element intuition.
A lot of contrary intakes here. I love
this. Elena, we've reached number 10. And
I know number 10 is like a special one
where it's more than one. Quick. Fire.
So number 10 is going to be my little fire
round. My fire round on little things that I
just see people spending way too much time on
it. It hurts my heart, because it's not going
to drive any results on them. So number one.
Color optimizations. Because the love of God,
a blue is a blue is a blue. As long as it's
accessible and as long as it's bright enough,
off you go. You do not need to test the shades
of blue or test it against green or so on. Pick
a color, move on, please don't spend time on
it. That's an early 2000s tactic. It doesn't
work anymore. We pass that in technology sector.
Number two. Third party signups. A lot of times
we think, oh, we're going to get so much more
acquisition if we add Google Auth or if we add
Facebook Auth or Slack Auth or Microsoft Auth,
whichever auth you want to add to it. In some
cases, it's very important to have third party
auth. So for example, if you are a developer
product, please have a GitHub auth. It's kind
of unnecessary. The developers already have
the account there, have them connect with it as
opposed to create a new one. However, if you're
a productivity product, email is fine for the
longest time. Gmail is nice. It's not going
to drive more acquisition for you. You're just
going to do a makeshift, and two more people...
... more acquisition for you. You're just going
to do a makeshift and two more people using it.
It's not going to create incrementality, it's
not going to improve your activation, it's not
going to improve your retention. It's not a growth
tactic. It's part of you just customer experience
that you want to invest into. Number three, on the
fire round, one email wonders. We stress too much
about this one email that we're going to send to
this one customer group. And we're like, oh gosh,
how much lift is it going to cost? It'll never
cause any lift. You will never work as a one-off
email. Too few people open it on average, 25%
open rate. At best you'll get 40 to 50% open rate.
Too few people click it. One email will never do
anything. If you're going to go into email, please
think about it as a series about communication,
about how it interacts with product communication.
It's a whole strategy. It's a whole thing.
Please don't stress about one-off email.
Never test a change in one email. It'll never
work. You're going to have to do the whole
god damn thing and see how it's going to do.
Not just one email, just never going to work.
I'm definitely guilty of this one.
That is a really good one for sure.
And it's so obvious in hindsight,
so I love that you share that.
Yes. And then the last one, growth teams are often
too obsessed about removing friction. Because if
we remove the steps, then more people are going
to get to the destination. And to an extent, if
you cause horrible friction in your product where
it's just confusing about what the next step is,
I agree, go fix the friction of the cognitive
load that it takes to complete a step. That is the
friction that you should be working on. However,
just removing steps or yanking or simplifying
things to an oblivion where you lose an identity
of what you even do or what you're capable of
doing is a completely failed growth tactic. So
simplifying may be an initiative of a different
problem that you're solving, but if you ever have
a line item on your roadmap that says simplified
onboarding, please cross it out. It's not going to
work because simplifying onboarding is an action.
What is the problem that you're solving? You're
never trying to solve a problem of simplifying.
You always have a problem of people are confused
in it, but people don't know where to go or they
get lost in it or they're not educated enough.
That is the problem. And simplifying might be
a solution, but it can never be a problem
on its own. And too many growth teams are
just obsessed with this notion that came
out I think in early 2000s, like, oh,
simplifying is the biggest growth
hack that you can do. Do it. It's
only a solution to a very specific
problem set of too much complexity.
Wow, that was a big one to end on.
That I think will help a lot of people
avoid wasting time. Again, a whole other
podcast conversation probably focus just
on onboarding advice that you probably have,
that I know you have. We've reached the last
item. Is there anything else you want to
share about this list before we move on?
No, I think we've spent too
much time. We're ready to go.
Not too much. Just enough time. And kind
of on a note, I want to call an audible,
and so we were going to talk through
all of your favorite frameworks. I
like the way this conversation has gone.
I don't want people to get overwhelmed
with information. So one idea is just list
maybe your favorite growth frameworks just
for folks to go check these out and
not spend too much time on each one.
Yep, let's do that.
Okay.
Great. So the list of my favorite growth
frameworks. And to me framework by the way,
it's not a solution, it's a pattern. It's
a pattern that exists across almost every
single company out there and it's a starting
point for your ideation and to figure out how
you can almost shortcut to possible list of
solutions as opposed to trying to figure out
too hard of how to even define a problem on its
own. So number one, it's probably expected if
anybody has read anything or listened to me talk
is growth loops. I think anybody who thinks about
growth and anybody who thinks about growth in
the funnel fashion versus understanding what
the growth loops are is missing out on the ability
to create sustainable growth engine. So it's very
important to think about action, reaction that
generates another action and it's a self-contained
flywheel they can spin. A lot of resources on
it at Reforge, Brian Balfour and Casey Winters
and Andrew Chen wrote a lot about this.
Highly recommend anybody looking into.
My next favorite growth framework's actually
written by you, Lenny, and Dan, which is a race
car framework. Everybody has a really hard time
often thinking about what are all of them parts
of growth initiatives and which are long-term,
short-term, how much are they going to actually
produce in results? And race car framework
is wonderful because it separates different
initiatives into, hey, there's some engines,
loops that are just going to keep on spinning.
There's some fuel that you're going to need to add
into it, potentially like paid marketing dollars.
There are some turbo boosts that you may have in
your race car that are going to be, let's say big
user conferences that you're going to hold as
a product or there's [inaudible 01:17:22] and
optimizations that you're going to need
to do pouring oil into that engine so that
actually performs correctly. It's beautiful.
I talk about it all the time with everybody.
The next favorite growth framework for me comes
from Bengali and that's adjacent to user theory.
I think that was very powerful in terms of
thinking about growth evolution. And as we
talked about adding different growth models to
your growth ecosystem, different growth loops,
but also adjacent users which are outside
of your ideal customer profiles or ICP,
outside of your core user and how growth team can
really bring them in and add additional oomph to
your product without even expansion of product
market fit by just optimizing their experiences.
I'm going to stop at these three because
I think those are the most powerful ones.
Cool. On that last one, [inaudible 01:18:11]
Bengali was on the podcast. We'll link to
that episode if you want to go deeper on the
adjacent using user theory. I love how that
was a few minutes on things that could
change people's life if they adopt one
of these frameworks and learn how to think about
growth in this way. It's such a powerful mental
model for thinking about all this stuff you've
been talking about this entire conversation.
Yes, those frameworks are like
my church in my mind of my system
of beliefs of how I think about growth
and how I think about it on a strategic
level of owning it as a strategy, not
just like a tactic or an initiative.
The church of Elena Verna. Amazing. Okay, so
before we wrap up, I want to bring us over to
Contrarian Corner, recurring segment
on this podcast where I like to ask the
guest if there's something they believe
that most other people don't believe.
Contrarian opinion you might say. Is
there anything that comes to mind?
I do have a very contrarian opinion,
although it's not so much related to
growth as opposed to maybe your personal
growth and my contrarian opinion is that
full-time jobs are not the best way to
monetize the skill that you have. It's
one of the packages that everybody should
evaluate and take advantage of, but too many
people blindly default to that package and don't
explore other options that are both available on
the market as well as best suited for their
personalities, for their interests, and for
their skill set. It's like a default plan that
everybody subscribes to that is faulty in itself.
Wow. Okay. Wait, we got to hear more. So
what are some other packages? I think we're
buying some of these packages, these other
options, but I guess what should people be
thinking about when you say this in terms
of what can they actually do and explore?
I'll premise it to saying I don't want to rain
parade on full-time roles. They're wonderful
on video ability, to learn to get the expertise
and depending on which career stage you are at
full-time roles might be the absolute necessity
for you to move on to and unlock the next level.
However, full-time roles boxes into one company
that may not be a great fit for us culturally,
for our skills, for our ambitions, for our
interests. Life is too short for that and
ability to really go and figure out your own
best monetization model, just like you work
on that for your business, you should work for
that on yourself without an assumption oftentimes
is the only option that you should have.
So what are the other options? There's so many,
obviously the couple known ones. Freelancing,
you can be a contractor. I do a lot of advising
and consulting because for my brain of how I work
and how I like to puzzle solve and pattern match,
it works much better to be horizontal across many
companies versus vertical on one specific one. But
that doesn't mean I still don't take those
vertical engagements to deepen my knowledge
into any specific topic. But overall it's a
lot more interesting for me to pattern match
across multiple companies and help them
grow as opposed to just focusing on one.
There's interim engagements where there's
a predetermined end date to your agreement.
There's fractional engagements where you're
working part-time on something as opposed
to engulfing yourself completely.
There's other ways to create courses,
there's a way to create newsletters and monetize
them like you're doing such a fantastic job. So
there's just so many options and people are
sometimes paralyzed by fear of instability,
that it creates when you start to explore other
options because you don't have that contract with
that one company that provides you that paycheck
every two weeks to rely on. But at the same time
you can create diversification for your career
and you depend on when you need to pull that
trigger and when is the right time for you to
explore. But to spend your entire career only
assuming full-time is the only way I think is a
complete mistake that a lot of people are doing.
One of my favorite posts
of yours along these lines,
which is around increasing... What you
want to do is increase optionality and
I guess talk about that because I think
it's a really powerful piece of advice.
So this advice of career optionality, being
the ultimate north star for anybody in their
professional journey is something that I'm
very strong on because a lot of people have
the goal of, I don't know, maybe I want to be a
VP or I want to become a CEO. Or I don't know,
I want to be a manager and I want to people
manage. And this becomes their north star
and they start working towards it. But a lot of
people when they get to their perceived corporate
ladder north stars find themselves extremely
dissatisfied, depressed even by how terrible that
job is. Could people manage your job? I wouldn't
wish it on my worst enemy because it's a terrible
job if you don't enjoy it and you don't know if
you're going to like it until you actually do it.
So I think setting a title as your goal,
which so many of us have titles as goals,
is very wrong way to think about it as opposed
to saying, "Hey, my goal professional is actually
to have options so I can choose what I want to
do. So I can choose what fits my life right now
that I can choose what fits my skills and that
fits my personality and that makes me happy."
And to get career optionality, if that's your
goal, you start thinking about your progression
a lot differently. You're not starting to think
about it of what will get me to the next title.
You start thinking about what will can I do next
year that will increase my option pool? And that's
very different than just getting to a higher
title. And if you start thinking about evaluating
opportunities or whether you should stay at the
company, whether you should move at the company
from the lens of does it increase my options
if I stay at this company for one more year or
does it keep it the same or does it actually
potentially decrease? That is the right way
to find your ultimate happy place and happy job
that brings you energy, that brings you happiness
versus just going for a title and then being very
disappointed with what that brings along with it.
Amazing advice. So important and something I'll
add that I think is a balance to what people may
be feeling here is like, oh, I'll just bounce
around all the best logo companies and create
this killer resume. I think you also need to build
depth and actual experience that you can tap into
if you do any of these things. For example, a lot
of people want to jump to like I'm going to be a
newsletter person, I'm going to start a podcast,
be an advisor before they've done anything real
and you have nothing to actually base your
advice on and that part is very important.
You have to earn your right to unlock
optionality and earning that right does
usually lie within full-time jobs. That is a
universal truth. But then at some point you
should start not just looking at full- time
jobs as the only option that you have. You
should start to think about when can you start
unlocking new ones and testing the market on it.
The other point is that you've been a
great example of is it's not a one-way
door. You can have full-time job, go to
something else, go back to full-time job,
be an advisor, be an intern person, be a
newsletter person. You do that really well.
You should have to do it all. It's
all a menu of options and you pick
a menu item that fits your best
in any given point of your life.
It's never say never and never shut
the door on anything. Absolutely.
Oh my god, Elena, this was incredible. Before
we get to our very exciting lighting round,
is there anything else you want
to share or leave listeners with,
maybe a last nugget or thought or
not because covered a lot already.
No, I think we've covered so
much. I don't want to overwhelm.
Let's do it. With that, we've reached our
very exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
Yes, I'm ready.
First question, surprise,
surprise. What are two or three books
you've recommended most to other people?
Okay, so I just finished this book that I
love so much, it's not a professional book,
but it's Project Hail Mary by Andy Weir.
It's the same author that wrote Martian.
Martian also was made into a movie. So good, so
good. Can't put it down. I think I read it like
two days straight. So highly recommend that.
And the next one that I also started reading
right now is Body Burst. Body Burst is so
good. It's actually takes into account AI
and how we can upload our consciousness
in AI and what can happen with that. So
highly recommend that, I think it's actually
closer to what potentially can be in the truth
for us in the future than not. But I'm a big
sci-fi geek, so I read mostly sci-fi books.
I have a sci-fi recommendation for
you that comes from Noah Smith. I
love his newsletters called Noah
Opinion and he has a list of his
favorite sci-fi books that I've been
working my way through. It's called,
you may have read it by Werner Vogel, Fire
Upon The Deep. Have you heard of this?
No, I have not.
Okay. It's described as not a sci-fi but space,
like a space opera where it's epic,
the most epic scale of universe story.
I'll download it tonight, it'll be on my list.
It takes a little bit to
get into. It's quite unique,
but you just keep going and it's incredible
and AI plays a big role in it actually.
That's awesome. I'll download it.
There you go. Okay, question number two. Favorite
recent movie or TV show you've really enjoyed?
Yes. I just got to watching Beef on Netflix. It's
so good. I'm not going to spoil it for anybody,
Beef. You should watch it. It's a limited
series. It's so good. It will run through.
I love Veep on HBO. So funny. I've probably
watched it two times already the entire series
and I'll probably watch it more because it
just cracks me up every time. I think this
is actually how our government works, so I'm
very intrigued by that. And then the last one
that I really liked that is coming up with
the season two now. So you should catch up
with season one is Last One of Us. If you
don't like zombie movies or zombie shows,
don't watch it. But if zombie and apocalypse
is your cup of tea, Last One of Us is so good.
Or the Last of Us? Or Last One of Us? Last of Us.
Is it Last of Us?
I'm Googling while we talk, Last of Us. I
think it's Last of Us. Yeah, the Last of Us.
Oh, Last of Us. Okay, Last of Us.
You're saying there's a third season coming
soon. That's exciting. I didn't know that.
Yeah, it's so good.
Okay, I love it as well. Great pick. Okay. Your
favorite product you recently
discovered that you really like?
I recently discovered that they make heated
shoes and that changed my life. My feet are
always cold and they are boots that actually
have heated wires through them and I'm obsessed.
And are you like charging it,
like USB plugin kind of thing?
Yeah, I just come in, I plug them in and then I
go outside and I'm warm and I think it's magical.
I have a jacket, also heated jacket, now I have
shoes. I just need my gloves and I'll be all set.
I love the USB powered clothing. And we
should know you live not in Silicon Valley,
you live on the East Coast sort of?
Central. In Central. The coldest it
gets is 30s here, but I'm always cold,
so this is just my love language is
something heated that I can sit on. I'm
that cat sits underneath the light all the
time. And then I also just got AirPod Max,
my headphones. I couldn't connect it to my
computer. Still technical issues on that,
but I love them. The sound is amazing. That's
my new favorite gadget that I'm obsessed about.
What a cool combination, heated shoes and AirPods.
Two more questions. Do you have a favorite
life motto that you often come back to
that you find useful in work and life?
Yeah, it's really one, progress over perfection.
I think that you just need to... The velocity of
information is far more important than
something that I think is perfect and
perfection is an outcome that you get to. But
progress over perfection all day, any day.
Very appropriate for a head of growth person.
Yes.
Final question. You're not only one of
the smartest people I've met on growth,
you're also one of the funniest people on
social media, especially on LinkedIn. If
people aren't following you, they
should. They will not only learn,
they'll also be highly entertained. Is
there a favorite meme that you created
that you are very proud of that you can
describe that we might want to link to?
Yeah, so I also want to say a lot of
people hate me for doing so much memes
as well because they think it's not serious.
And I actually, I want to rebuttal that really
quickly because I think humor is the best
way to disarm people and to point out very
painful situations that we're facing with every
single day or conundrums without putting anybody
on defense. Because we can all laugh at the
absurdity of the lives that we live in every
single day. And a picture's worth a thousand
words. And sometimes memes are just the best
way to communicate the most complex situations
that we are facing within our corporate world.
And they help us understand how common all of
those situations are. We're not unique. You're
not feeling alone by feeling down about what
happened. Everybody's going through the same
thing. So that's why I love memes because
they help connect people on both sides.
Even if you're making fun of one
side because they're like, yeah,
that is true and this is so funny. So I'm a
big proponent of that just because I think
it's actually a better way to both unite people
and just talk about hard problems that otherwise
would be not read if you put it in words.
But my favorite meme is actually one of the
first ones that I've created and I think it's
from Family Guy where they have an elephant and
the penguin standing and then there's Moses
I think, or some biblical character saying,
"What the hell is this?" Looking at the elephant
and the penguin. And the result of it is a child
that has a penguin body and an elephant head. And
if you think about elephant as product and penguin
as marketing, what the hell is this is gross.
Which is a byproduct, a weird, weird byproduct,
product and marketing merged together that doesn't
really fit with either, yet it's its own entity.
I don't know. I think that that's the best to
describe to people what [inaudible 01:33:14] is.
So appropriate. Also, it's hard to describe a
meme and make it feel funny. So good job. Thank
you for doing that. We'll link to this meme in our
show notes. Elena, this was incredible. Thank you
again. Thank you for being our first ever
third return guest. Hopefully there will
be many more episodes of Elena Verna. Two
final questions. Where can folks find you
online if they want to reach out and learn
more and how can listeners be useful to you?
Find me on LinkedIn or my Substack. I'm not
competing with you Lenny, but I share a lot
of my thoughts and everything that I learned on my
own Substack. It's just elenaverna.com. LinkedIn
is for all of my memes, so go there if you want
to laugh, but if you want to learn from what I'm
learning, go to my Substack. And how you can be
useful? Tell me what problems you're facing now.
Don't tell me, oh, how growth is slowing down,
what should I do? I can't help you with that,
too broad, but if you're having a situation,
there's often really good [inaudible 01:34:09] for
me to go and write about it or to do more research
about it. So I just love to hear what some
people's minds, so I can both help them connect
their dots as well as learn about it myself.
And what's the best way for them to do that?
Is it like DM me on LinkedIn, any other-
DM me on LinkedIn or just reply to
my Substack newsletter email. It
goes directly into my personal inbox,
so I read every single one of them.
That's a really good tip. People don't know
that when you get an email on Substack,
if you reply, just goes straight to the author.
Exactly.
Elena, thank you so much for being here.
Okay, thank you for having me, Lenny.
Bye everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
LennysPodcast.com. See you in the next episode.