People just don't realize the
wild journey that you have been
on over the past 18 years building this
company. It feels like there's almost
been these three eras of Dropbox.
The first era of you're killing it.
For the first several years, it was doubling,
10-xing every year. Taping user counts that we
printed out to the wall, and then running out of
space on the wall. Having to put 100,000 users,
200,000, 500,000, 1,000,000,
10,000,000 on the ceiling.
And there's the second era, which I'll
just say, everyone's trying to kill you.
We started getting all the
incumbents. Apple, Microsoft,
Google. All of them launched
competing products, but weirdly,
it was sort of like you see the videos where
there's the mushroom cloud in the distance. You
see it. But you don't hear, or notice it.
It was also clear that winter was coming.
It feels like the year 2015 was a pivotal
year where things started to shift.
I'd start to hear a louder set of critics inside,
and outside the company. Less than a year later,
Google Photos launches. And not only does it
provide a lot of the same value, but they also
gave you free unlimited storage for life. And
so, they just totally nuked our business model.
You end up fighting wars on
three or four fronts against
the big kahunas that have infinite
cash, and can do whatever they want.
So it killed Carousel, killed Mailbox, went all-in
on productivity. And I wish I could say, "Then,
everything got better." It was the opposite,
actually. The narrative completely flipped
on the company. Suddenly, your employees don't
want to wear your T-shirt anymore. Everybody's
looking to you, and is wondering, "How the
hell did you get us in this situation?"
Today, my guest is Drew Houston. This may be the
most interesting, and most useful episode of my
podcast so far. Especially if you're a founder, or
if you someday want to be a founder. Drew shares
the very real talk story of what it's been
like to build Dropbox over the past 18 years.
Including the ups, and especially the downs. He
shares stories that he's never shared before,
the struggles he's been through that very few
people know about, what it's like to compete
with big tech, how he's thinking about the
future of the company. And also, what he's
learned about himself throughout the journey.
This is a very special episode that I suspect
founders will be studying for years to come.A
big thank you to Drew for sharing these stories
and lessons with us. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app, or YouTube. It's the
best way to avoid missing feature episodes,
and it helps the podcast tremendously. With
that, I bring you Drew Houston. This episode is
brought to you by Paragon. The integration
infrastructure for B2B SaaS companies.
Is AI on your 2025 product roadmap? Whether you
need to enable RAG with your user's external data
like Google Drive files, Gong transcripts,
or Jira tickets, or build AI agents that can
automate work across your users' other
tools. Integrations are the foundation,
but building all these integrations in-house
will cost you years of engineering. Time you
don't have given the fast pace of AI. That's where
Paragon's all-in-one integration platform comes
in. Build scalable workflows to ingest all of
your users' external data into your RAG pipelines.
And leverage ActionKit, their latest product, to
instantly give your AI agents access to over 100
integrations, and 1,000s of third-party actions
with a single API call. Leading AI companies
like AI21, You.com, 11x, and Coffee.ai are already
shipping new integrations seven times faster with
Paragon. Keeping their engineers focused on core
product development. Ready to accelerate your AI
roadmap this year? Visit useparagon.com/Lenny to
get a free MVP of your next product integration.
This episode is brought to you by Explo. A
game changer for customer-facing analytics,
and data reporting. Are your users craving more
dashboards, reports, and analytics within your
product? Are you tired of trying to build it
yourself? As a product leader, you probably have
these requests in your roadmap, but the struggle
to prioritize them is real. Building analytics
from scratch can be time-consuming, expensive,
and a really challenging process. Enter,
Explo. Explo is a fully white-labeled embedded
analytics solution designed entirely with your
user in mind. Getting started is easy.
Explo connects to any relational database,
or warehouse. And with its low-code functionality,
you can build and style dashboards in minutes.
Once you're ready, simply embed the dashboard,
or report into your application with a tiny
code snippet. The best part? Your end users can
use Explo's AI features for their own report,
and dashboard generation. Eliminating customer
data requests for your support team. Build, and
embed a fully white-labeled analytics experience
in days. Try it for free at explo.co/Lenny. That's
E-X-P-L-O dot C-O slash Lenny. Drew, thank you
so much for being here. Welcome to the podcast.
Oh, thank you, Lenny. It's great to be here.
I have been so looking forward to this
conversation for so many reasons. One,
is I feel like people just don't realize the wild
journey that you have been on over the past 18
years building this company. You told me a few
of these stories when we had dinner recently,
and I was just like, "You need to come on
the podcast, and tell this stuff. I think
it'll be really useful to a lot of people."
And then also, I feel like you're just a
very real talk founder that isn't afraid to
share what's really going on. I think a lot
of founders don't actually tell you the things
they're going through. It's always, "Killing it.
We're killing it all the time." So for all those
reasons, I'm really excited to have this chat,
and this opportunity to stand with you and hear
these stories. So thank you again for doing this.
Me too, and I've been a big fan of the podcast.
Oh.
I learned a lot.
Oh, wow. I appreciate that. The way I'm thinking
we structure this conversation is, as an outsider,
it feels like there's almost been these three eras
of Dropbox. And tell me if I am missing something,
but essentially, it feels like there's the
first era of you're killing it. Just up and
to the right killing it. Dropbox is on fire.
And then, there's the second era that I think
fewer people know about, which I'll just
say, everyone was trying to kill you. All
the incumbents are coming after you. I like
that it leads you to sigh. This is going to be
good. And then, there's the current era.
I'll say the third era of just rethinking
what Dropbox could be. Does that sound roughly
right? That's a good way to think about that?
I think that's right. Yep.
Okay, awesome. So let's start with this first
era, and spend some time here. Which is, I think,
the era most people know you for. There's the
big Hacker News launch, the demo video of the
thumb drive you're always losing, the referral
program everyone's always studying. You're almost
the epitome of viral growth. And so, let's just
talk about just things here that maybe people
don't know about. Maybe some moments that are
really important to you, memories that stand out
to you. So maybe just start wherever you want to
start about this time of the history of Dropbox.
I mean, I started Dropbox more out of just
personal frustration, and it really felt like
something that only I was super interested in as
far as file syncing. And focusing on one customer,
which is myself. And then there's the story of me
forgetting my thumb drive on a trip to New York,
and things like that, and coding.
I won't get into all that. I had a
lot of friends who were in Y Combinator, and
many friends who had moved from Boston where
I was living out to California.
And doing that whole pilgrimage,
or kind of maybe one-way pilgrimage.
And feeling a little bit left out,
but then also having this idea for Dropbox.
And then I think some of the most memorable
things were the moments where Dropbox really
felt like it was taking on a life of its own,
or maybe it belonged to the internet, and
not so much to me anymore. So for example,
we had a lot of success with these demo videos.
First, was just getting into Y Combinator. It sort
of worked backwards from thinking about, "What
does Paul Graham do all day?" And my hypothesis
was that he just hits refresh on Hacker News
like everyone else. Like me, like everyone else.
This was you trying to figure out
how to get Paul Graham's attention?
Yeah.
I love that. "What does Paul
Graham do all day?" Okay.
Yeah. Well, my first company was doing online
SAT prep, and I was 21 when I started that.
But in the world, there's a lot that Y Combinator
has in common with college admissions. You have
1,000,000 people applying for very few spots.
And the more you can get some kind of hook,
or find some kind of side door. That
was the thinking, and I was like,
"All right. Well, if I can create some
kind of viral video, put it on Hacker News,
get Paul's attention, that'd be one way to do it."
And that was inspired by a book called Guerrilla
Marketing that I had read, which is basically
how to do marketing if you have no money.
Which was a good fit for where we were. I say,
"We." It was just me at the time. And sure enough,
I made this video that was basically a pretty
straightforward screencast of Dropbox. Showing
it working on my computer, and then it hit
the top of Hacker News for two days. I don't
think it can really happen anymore, but sure
enough, we got a note from Paul saying, "Hey,
this is interesting, but you need a co-founder."
Which was a problem because it's clear that the
YC application deadline for the next cycle was
maybe a week or two away. So Paul was basically
sending me a helpful note that, "I know you're
not dating anyone, but you need to be married
in the next two weeks if you want to get into
YC." So I ended up finding my co-founder, Arash,
and there's just story after story like that in
the early days. So I'd say the first chapter was
characterized by just feels like one moment I'm
sort of paddling in the ocean alone on a little
board. The next, I'm just like a hundred feet off
the ground on this tidal wave trying to stay on.
How long does this period last of just Hacker
News to something starts to change? How
long is this up and to the right period?
It was the first several years. So I started
the company back in 2007. I might have been
24 at the time, moved to California. And so, I'd
say it was first probably seven years from 2007
to 2014 were really that crazy fever dream .com
experience where it's a blur. I mean, basically,
get into Y Combinator. After we finish Y
Combinator, that culminates in Demo Day,
and getting your first investors. At Demo
Day was this guy named Pejman Nozad who is
an angel investor who also owned a rug
store in Palo Alto. He runs Pear there.
Oh, and he runs Pear. [inaudible 00:10:25].
Yeah, and he runs Pear now. He introduced
us to Sequoia. He came with us to the pitch,
which I learned later it was unusual. And
that was on a Friday, and then Saturday
Mike Moritz is in our apartment. But
anyway, so we raised money from Sequoia,
and that was a seed round in 2007. So right
after we finished Y Combinator. And then,
basically, you start with a pretty
narrow circle of what you're working on.
I mean, right in the beginning it's just really
just coding, and talking to customers. But that
circle kept expanding pretty rapidly. So in 2007,
we were just building the first prototype of the
product. It was in closed beta for about a year.
And in end of 2008, we launched at what's now
TechCrunch Disrupt. Our demo totally failed. The
wifi wasn't working on stage, so a live demo is
quite underwhelming. So that took a few years off
my life, but fortunately, we had accumulated this
big beta waiting list from basically doing
another version of that Hacker News video.
Engineered to be even more viral, and have all
these memes, and things in it. But similarly,
a few minute demo video of, "What's Dropbox?
And here's moving stuff between a Windows PC,
and a Mac. And here's all these little
Easter eggs about the HD DVD encryption key,
or [inaudible 00:11:50] who was one of the first
YouTubers. Tom Cruise jumping on a couch in
Scientology." This was a long time ago. 15 years
ago, or something. But we put this video on Dig,
and Reddit. And our beta waiting list went
from 5,000 to 85,000 people overnight.
So we got this initial seed audience by chasing
that early adopter set. And then, we also figured
out these viral motions around our referral
program, and shared folders. And so Dropbox
started expanding virally for the first several
years. And then a lot of the engineering that we
applied to the product of Dropbox can't have a bad
day when it comes to your wedding photos, and tax
returns, and all the things people put in Dropbox.
So we took a while to get the beta right before we
felt comfortable opening up to the broader public.
But then, we applied that same engineering
mentality to these viral loops. And this was
all the era when social media was exploding,
and Facebook, and Facebook platform. All these
startups were setting new land speed records for
fastest to 1,000,000 users, or 10,000,000 users.
Things like Zynga. And all of this was built on
this emerging playbook of virality, which in turn
came from epidemiology. The study of the spread
of viruses turned out to be a good parallel for
the consumer internet. Draw your own conclusions.
And then we were like, "Oh, there's no reason
this wouldn't work for Dropbox." And some of
our early investors, Hadi and Ali Partovi, talked
to us about how Facebook thought about growth. And
then there were a lot of great people in the early
days who had really fine-tuned, and mastered a lot
of that. We tried many things. Conventional, and
unconventional. But the things around virality,
and the referral program really worked.
And so for the first several years, it was just
doubling, 10-xing every year. Taping user counts
that we printed out to the wall, and then running
out of space on the wall. Having to put a 100,000,
200,000, 500,000, 1,000,000, 10,000,000 on the
ceiling. So it was wild. And it was super fun, but
it was also super stressful. But going from maybe
$6,000,000 valuation in 2007, to $27,000,000 in
2008, to then $4,000,000,000 valuation in 2011,
being on magazine covers. Just
that whole experience was wild.
The visual of the user numbers extending onto the
ceiling is such a good one. Of just how quickly
things grew. Okay. So let's transition to the
second era. So things have been going great, keeps
growing. Obviously, challenges along the way,
but it feels like it's just grow, grow, grow. It
feels like the year 2015 was a pivotal year where
things started to shift. Does that sound right?
Yeah.
Okay. Yeah. Let's talk about that.
Yeah. Maybe the end of the first era, the start
of our teenage years, would've been around 2013,
or 2014. And maybe before that. 2011, 2012,
we started getting all the incumbents,
or all the big platform companies. Apple,
Microsoft, Google. All of them launched
competing products in one form, or another. But
weirdly, it was like you see the videos where
there's the mushroom cloud in the distance.
You see it. But you don't hear, or notice it.
So it mostly just seemed like nothing happened.
When Steve Jobs was on stage in 2011 announcing
iCloud, calling out Dropbox by name as something
that will be viewed as archaic. And similarly,
we always felt like we were in the shadow of
the hammer of Google launching Google Drive,
which had been rumored long before we even started
the company. For the first several years, we
were just sort of quivering, waiting for the shoe
to drop. And the product's launched, but you would
never be able to look at our numbers and see when
that happened. And the press often writes about
competition like, "Oh, it's a shotgun blast."
When, later, I would learn it's more of a boa
constrictor. But the end of that first chapter
really culminated in us recognizing that we
experienced a lot of benefits of being this
kind of product for everyone. And in fact,
it would be kind of hard for me to describe in the
early days who Dropbox is for, or what it does. It
was similar to what's a phone for, or what's a
computer for? And in the beginning, that was a
blessing. It meant that those viral loops would
really work. Pretty much everybody you would
hit would have a need for something like Dropbox.
Either a personal need, or a work need, or both.
But we recognized even back then before
competition that, "Hey, people are using us
primarily for things like backup, backing up their
devices, or storage. People are using us for photo
sharing. People are using us as a collaborative
space at work, and often, in huge companies."
And then, we felt that there was a lot of tension
between these use cases. So for example, the ideal
file server replacement for an IT admin is going
to look quite different from the ideal consumer
photo sharing app. And we also recognize things
like, "Well, we're going to be competing in many
cases with the device, or the operating system."
When you look at something like iCloud, it's like,
"Yeah. When you turn on your iPhone for the first
time, it's probably not going to give you an ad
for Dropbox." So we're like, "Hey, we need to
address some of these issues," and expanded to
some new areas to diversify. The first two
things we did were, after getting enough
complaints from IT administrators asking us what
the hell these photo sharing features were for,
we pulled all the photo sharing functionality out
into a separate and new app we called Carousel.
Where the basic value prop was phones, to that
point, were limited in their storage by the
amount of physical storage on the device.
We're like, "This is silly. You should be
able to have your whole life in your pocket."
So be able to store everything in the cloud,
but have the experience be as if everything
were locally there through a lot of caching,
and sleight of hand, and thumbnails, and things
like that. So there's much engineering there.
And then, secondly, we saw people were
using us at work, and we're like, "Well,
there's a lot of different adjacent workflows."
And there was a startup called Mailbox that built
the first great mobile email client. Had a lot of
funny parallels. They had a [inaudible 00:18:26]-
Oh, that's right. They're
famous for that waitlist.
Yeah.
That's a really good point.
Which was crazy.
Yeah.
And so we're like, "I don't know. Maybe this is
going to be our Instagram," and so we bought those
guys. And then 2014, I'm on stage painting
this picture of Dropbox's future. I'm like,
"We're going to help be the way that you remember
your life. We're going to be your productivity.
The new productivity suite on your phone," and
all these things. But then it was this dissonance
where there were so many things that were going
right, and certainly the numbers, user numbers,
revenue numbers. We were sort of accidentally
cash flow positive maybe a year after launching.
It was also clear that winter was coming, or
that things weren't exactly as they seemed.
Then the start of the second chapter, 2015, I'd
start to hear a louder set of critics inside,
and outside the company. And I'd been
thinking for a long time like, "All right,
man, we're really fighting wars on all these
very disparate fronts." We're with storage.
We're competing with the device to back up
the device with photo sharing, or competing
with Facebook, Snap, Instagram, Google, Apple.
On productivity, we're competing with Microsoft,
and Google. And then, there's a whole new
cohort of companies like Slack. And then,
there's this experience of one day I am standing
on stage talking about how Carousel, and Mailbox,
and everything are the future of the company.
Less than a year later, Google Photos launches.
And not only does it provide a lot of the same
value, and in many ways very inspired by what we
had done, but they also gave you free unlimited
storage for life. Not just photos, but video.
And so they just totally nuked our business
model in ways that were bad enough in terms
of just their obvious impact, but even worse
because it was so easily anticipated. So this
became a very public, and personal embarrassment
for me. How could we not have predicted that,
or been out in front of that? And then,
that started this period. I'd say that was
the beginning of chapter two where it was we
went from the company that could do no wrong
to the company that could do no right, which
was a big flip. It was probably early summer,
maybe late spring, when Google Photos launched.
At first, I'm just thinking like, "Okay. This
was a big miss on my part. How do we get out of
this? We need to tackle some of these competitive
issues much more ahead on." And then, what's the
problem? Well, the problem is that every incumbent
is going to copy your product. They're
going to bundle it with our platforms,
and then they're going to kill the economics.
And that was clear what was going to happen
with Google Photos. It was very similar product
experience bundled with Android, bundled with all
of Google's different touch points, and then free.
So that was problematic enough for Carousel,
but I'm like, "Wait, this is going to happen
with everything that we're doing. Same thing
with Mailbox." I had even pitch the founders to
join Dropbox by saying, "Look, you're going to
wake up tomorrow, and Gmail, and Apple Mail, and
everything is just going to have these swipes and
snoozes. The UI, it's not a durable source of
advantage. We'll buy that problem from you."
And that's exactly what happened. So I'm
like, "All right. Even in theory, how do we
deal with this?" And I'd gotten the criticism
over the years that Dropbox is a commodity,
and investors in the early days would be like,
"Hey, this is kind a graveyard of a space,
and DOA." And I thought, "Well, how do other
companies deal with this kind of competition,
and commodities?" So there's a great book by AG
Lafley and Roger Martin called Playing to Win.
Roger's been on the podcast.
Yeah. I'm a huge fan of Roger's. And I was
like, "All right. Well, if we think we're
selling a commodity, try literally selling paper
towels." Which is what AG, and Procter & Gamble,
and a lot of CPG companies do. And AG was the CEO
of Procter & Gamble at the time. And basically,
he and Roger did this download of how they think
about competition, and markets, and advantage.
And a lot of it's thinking really critically
about where do you play, and how do you win?
So being very selective about the markets you're
in, and only being in markets where you can have
a leadership position. And then, being really
crisp about what is your leadership position? And
so that was a very timely thing to read in terms
of, "All right. Dropbox looks like one product,
but it's really participating in many different
markets. And our big risk might be that we're
the number two best thing in each of those
markets, which would be a bad situation."
Another really influential book was Only the
Paranoid Survive by Andy Grove, and I'd been
a big fan of Andy's. High Output Management
is another great book of his, which was my
introduction to management. At least, his theory
of management. So just loved that book. And then
Only the Paranoid Survive talks about Intel's
experience where they actually had something
like this happen that I wasn't aware of, and we
all know Intel as the microprocessor company,
Intel Inside. At least in the 80s, 90s.
But before, they were in microprocessors.
They sold memory, RAM. In the 70s, they were
running into a situation where they were really
high growth, successful business selling memory.
But then, they had these Japanese competitors that
were just building memory faster, better, cheaper.
Just on every dimension. And potentially, also,
things like anti-competitive things where
the government might be subsidizing these
manufacturers. This feeling not only
they might just be better at the game,
but there's also not a level playing field.
But meanwhile, you wouldn't see it in their
numbers. They're still growing. And just that
there were these weird dissonant experiences
where salespeople just suddenly have problems
selling into accounts that used to be a slam dunk,
or things that used to work just stop
working. And this happens. Blackberry's,
and Nokia's best sales years happened in the
years after launching the iPhone. So these
things don't actually change immediately. And so
Andy labeled these moments strategic inflection
points for a company, and I'm like, "Yeah. Then,
we're definitely in a strategic inflection point."
But they were dealing with, "Oka., our whole
business is memory. How do we deal with this
competition?" And there's this little vignette
where he and Gordon Moore, one of the other
co-founders of Intel, said, "Hey, let's pretend
we're consultants to ourselves. What would we
do?" And what they immediately decided was, "Oh,
well, we clearly get out of the memory business,
and put all of our chips on this sketchy little
microprocessor thing that was much smaller. But
very high growth, and potentially big market." And
then they're like, "Well, why don't we do that?"
Only problem with that is it's like Google saying,
"Yeah. Let's get out of search, and go all in on
Gmail, or something, or YouTube." So it just
seemed insane. Andy cautions in the book that,
"Look, most of the time CEOs want options. They
want to hedge their bets, but what you really
want to do in these strategic inflection points
is go all in one thing." Or as Mark Twain put it,
"Put all your eggs in one basket, and watch
that basket." And I was like, "All right. This
makes sense to me, but man, this is going to be
painful." So we go away for 4th of July. I'm with
my family in New Hampshire. I reread the book, I
come back. All right. I'm like, "Well, we really
got to do it." Then, I just killed Carousel,
killed Mailbox. Went all in on productivity...
Killed mailbox, went all in on productivity.
To some extent, that was a relatively easy
decision because most of our subscribers, 80% of
people paying for Dropbox were using it at work.
But that meant foreclosing on photo sharing and
consumer and storage and all these things that
Dropbox had become synonymous with and to this day
are some of the things that we're most recognized
for. And I wish I could say then everything
got better. It was the opposite, actually,
the narrative completely flipped on the company.
The press started, we killed these new products,
and then internally and externally, the narrative
became super negative. Articles would come out
every week or two, like, oh, Dropbox could be the
first dead deck of corn. And then sometimes we've
all seen this in tech companies get in this
washing machine of self-perpetuating negative
press. And if it goes deep enough, I mean, Uber
had this for a while later, Meta's had this over
their history, lots of companies where you
just can't get the monkey off your back.
And then because what the reporters end up doing
is they basically park their metaphorical van
behind your office. They interview all the people
that you just fired and then print everything that
they say anonymously as if it were facts. And
there's a lot of truth to what the press were
saying, so I can't really blame them or saying
they were being unfair, but it immediately put
recruiting into this deep freeze. You're just
in the situation. You've started this company,
it's been super successful, and then suddenly
your employees don't want to wear your T-shirt
anymore. And frankly, you don't even want
to wear your T-shirt anymore. It's just your
pride in your own company takes a big hit.
And meanwhile, I've talked mostly about the
external market competitive forces, but inside the
company was a mess too. The business's revenue had
scaled so much faster than our ability to hire
and build the right infrastructure and operations
internally. And so everybody's just panicking and
being like, "All right, well good, Drew, we're not
doing Carousel, we're not doing Mailbox. What are
we doing?" And the truth was like, if I knew the
answer to that, we would be doing it, but it's
just this is going to take some time to figure
out. So it was pretty tough when everybody's
looking to you as the founder and CEO looking for
quick fixes and answers, and also just wondering,
how the hell did you get us in this situation?
Wow. So we're going to talk about how you're
actually turning things around
and the work you're doing now,
learning from this experience. But I have a lot
of questions about this part of the journey.
Yeah, yeah.
Just to almost summarize the journey,
it's like launch, killing it, viral,
find all these opportunities, find all these
big markets. You start three different product
lines. There's the enterprise use case,
there's the consumer file storage use case,
there's photo sharing, there's productivity, and
then basically every big incumbent's like, okay,
great, we're going to come eat your lunch. And
you end up fighting wars on three or four fronts
against the big kahunas that have infinite cash
and can do whatever they want. It's interesting
the way you described the Apple launch of just
like it was this mushroom cloud you didn't quite
see for a while, but the Google Photos launch
was like, okay, that was more clear of like,
okay, this is bad news. I know it's
always easy in hindsight of like, oh,
I should have done something different
when Apple launched this thing. But is
there anything maybe you could have done, or
was it even possible to have adjusted course
at that point? Or was it like, okay, this
is tough and we need time to figure it out?
Well, we panicked about the Apple
thing too, because that also,
that created a much smaller version of the
tempest in a teapot that the Google Photos
did. It was just much less public. Or it was just
less obvious that we would be so out position.
And actually we were more surprised to the upside
when it's Google Drive launches, iCloud launches,
OneDrive launches. And even as they build version
two that we just didn't really notice that much of
a problem. And I also studied over the years
what happened in Netscape and companies like
[inaudible 00:31:27] MySpace or these other
cautionary tales. And interestingly, Internet
Explorer was a thing that eventually undermined
Netscape enough to permanently throw it into a
negative trajectory. But Internet Explorer 1.0,
2.0, even maybe 3.0 just weren't that good and
didn't really do anything but Internet Explorer
4.0, 5.0 and all the bundling, that really made
a big difference, or big negative difference.
And then another thing that was interesting was,
so there's a big time lag where between when
these products launch and when they actually
have an impact, because often it's not so much
the existence of the product or it's availability,
it's the constant bundling or the constant
iteration, or it's the boa constrictor,
in any given second, it's not much tighter, but
over the following day, you're in a bad place.
But another thing that was interesting
was one cool thing that we got to do
and moving to California is you get to actually
meet people who had been at these companies. And
one of those people was a guy named Bill Campbell
who was at Netscape during that whole period,
and I had asked him, I'm like, "Man, that's
really unfair. That sucks what happened with
Microsoft and bundling with Windows and all these
things and the antitrust and this and that." And
he's looked at me, he laughed at and snorted and
he's like, "Microsoft did not kill us. We killed
ourselves." And so that was the other half of
what was the problem within Dropbox was a lot
of our wounds were self-inflicted in that we were
struggling to keep scaling and launching all these
products. And the Dropbox products had stagnated.
And I started to learn the hard way that, okay,
yeah, I now understand what Bill is talking about,
because we were hiring all these smart people,
but the things we would do as a company would
seem really stupid. And then some of these things
were me personally, like yeah, I knew about
from reading all these different things, but
for whatever reason, I guess we just kept
going anyhow. We were just too confident
in our ability to respond, or we got lulled
into this complacency, we were like, " Oh,
well." Because it hasn't been a problem,
it won't be a problem in the future.
But I'd say there's something about the Google
Photos launch that just really set things off
kilter. And then also for me personally, I
think, I'd go from feeling good but stressed
out all the time to mostly feeling bad all
the time. And I just remember leaving, really
trying to get away from the office for a
little bit during this period, picked my
teeth up off the ground. And the good news, I
bought a place in Hawaii, so I was doing that
in Hawaii, but didn't feel very good in any way.
And then I learned. I had to really figure out
a lot of different things for myself to be the
leader that could get us through this. Because
mostly what I felt was like, man, I felt like
we'd been doing such a good job, but now, man,
if I really screw this up, or maybe I don't know
what I'm doing. And then I had to really reset
on a number of fronts. One is I just remember
thinking my 18-year-old self would be like,
what the hell are you complaining about? You did
it. This is so great, and yet I felt so bad about
things. And so I'm like, yeah, both of those
things are true. How do I navigate that? And
I think one part that was really helpful is
getting a sense of equanimity basically, and
doing a lot around mindfulness and meditation to
distance... One thing that happens when you're a
founder and your company succeeds is your identity
is fused with the company. And so it's easy to get
into a situation where you only feel good if the
company's... Or how you feel is how the company is
doing, and you need to separate that a little bit.
So what that looked like for me is recognizing,
yeah, there's really not an easy button that keeps
things up and to the right forever. And most of
the entrepreneurs that are my heroes had various
periods of wandering in the desert. Those things
instead of just being problems were probably the
crucible that forged the people that they became.
So the presence of badness is not necessarily
you are bad. And it's like, yeah, now you're
just getting your stripes as an entrepreneur.
And people were really helpful during that
period. So I mentioned Bill Campbell. He was
nice enough that we just stayed in touch and he
would take me out to dinner every now and then.
And I would be freaking out, but I was always
surprised he'd never seemed to be freaking out.
And mostly he'd just be saying like, all right,
he'd dust you off and smack you and say, get
your ass back out there. And he was literally
a coach of the Columbia football team in addition
to being a great technology executive and advisor
to many of the great founders that I looked up
to. He was really helpful because he helped me
believe in myself even when I wouldn't believe
in myself. And then people like Andy Grove who
had written all these books, I'm like, well, at
least I'm having this problem. But yeah, then that
raised a question for me. I'm like, okay, I've
been through this chapter one where everything's
up and to the right, but I ran out of merit badges
or Xbox achievements to collect. I was like,
we did it. We got the product to this many users,
we got it to where we got this valuation, or let
me back up. So my whole life, or it's common, I
think for a lot of founders, especially if you get
good grades and stuff, you follow pretty linear
path from childhood, from first get the right
test scores, then get into the right college, get
into the right college, take the right classes,
get the right internship, get the right job. And
early startup life is like that a lot. It's like,
okay, have an idea. Find a co-founder, get
into Y Combinator, get funding from Sequoia.
Watch an MVP just in 10 million, a
hundred million, billion valuation.
And I felt like we'd cleared all that. And
so actually one of the other problems was,
I don't even know what Dropbox needs to be and
I don't even know what I need that I want to
be in the world. And so part of this was also
reconnecting to some kind of sense of purpose,
because if I was really honest with myself,
I was like, well, I'm just checking boxes and
advancing and leveling up like a video game or
something, but now I'm here. I'm like, all right,
is it just big numbers bigger? It's also not that
fun to just launch something that you put your
soul into and then just have it get crushed with
these competitors. It's even worse when you're
bringing all these hundred other people who worked
on that thing through that meat grinder too.
So are we just inventing things 10 minutes
before Google and Apple do? If not,
what are we doing? And then if we're really,
really honest with ourselves, I think it's hard
to argue that no one would've invented cloud
photo gallery that wasn't constrained to your
local storage. So I had to really rethink what
does the company need to do. That actually took
a longer time to answer than I wanted, but then
also just what do I want to do? And I was like,
well, you know what? I'm going to do this.
What I ended up settling on was like, look,
coming back to my 18-year-old self, I was like,
all right, stop complaining. This is a pretty
good situation. You wanted something where the
learning curve would be steep. Here it is. You
get to do this really meaningful work to build
things for millions of people, work with awesome
teammates. There's always good things about it,
and you've chosen this life, so stop complaining
about the burdens because it's really dangerous if
you start to resent the job or feel like a victim
because that's just corrosive to everything
else that you can get in this spin cycle.
What helped you come to that place? Because
that sounds like a very hard place to get to
and a very important place. Was that Bill
Campbell advice? How long did it take you
to go from this is not going well and life
sucks to, okay, let's look at it this way?
I think there were a couple unlocks that were
pretty fast, but I think again, this was not like,
oh, then I felt better and we lived happily
ever after at all. There were some moments
of recognition where I was able to, I always try
to get away from the mayhem or the whirlwind and
recenter myself and do think weeks and things like
that. And so those were really helpful because
I felt when I diagnosed, well, when I'm on this
treadmill and just firefighting or how did I miss
this important thing? It's like, well, basically
the root causes of being on the treadmills,
I was too busy firing to aim, and then I
thought I would do my aiming on vacations and
things like that. But no, I need to get off the
treadmill every now and then and make the space
to really address some of these bigger questions.
Because it's not like I didn't forget about them.
They just were always below the fold on my to-do
list to deal with. And then until a few years go
by and you're like, wait. Yeah, we really were
just strategically out of position. The other
way I came to some of these conclusions is a
combination of things. So I think picking up
a meditation or mindfulness practice, having
therapists personally, having coaches, having
friends and mentors, other founder friends. And so
I wouldn't say it was any one thing, but I think
you have to build this whole ecosystem of support
around yourself and recognize no one's going to
do that for you. And it's super important.
And then to Bill's other point, he was like,
yeah, Microsoft wasn't killing us, we were
killing ourselves, I think having to ask some
hard questions to myself of, yeah, some of these
wounds were self-inflicted. As much as there might
be, I could look at this and say, oh, Microsoft
is mean, or Google was mean, or Apple was mean,
but I'm like, I drove the ship towards these
rocks. So that's one downside of being founder,
CEO. You can't blame the last guy. I think
one of the big questions every founder
has to figure out is not just, how do I have
equanimity? What's my purpose? But then also,
what am I doing that is destroying the company?
Because everybody's got strengths and weaknesses,
but as CEO, both your strengths and your
weaknesses are massively amplified and a lot
of blind spots in your personality can become
huge cultural dysfunctions in the company.
And so step one to dealing with that is building
awareness. And one thing that floated around the
company for a while was the Enneagram, which
on the surface is a personality typing thing
like Myers-Briggs. I often describe it as it's
like Myers-Briggs, but actually useful. The way
it works is it's a personality typing system.
You get a number from one through nine that's
your dominant... Or there's nine types that are
numbered. It's similar to Myers-Briggs in that
Myers-Briggs has 16 types of letters like ENFJ or
different things. But I find that Myers-Briggs is
more descriptive. So it tells you, okay, you're
an introvert, not an extrovert or vice versa.
You're judging instead of perceiving. But I could
never really work out what that meant. And so
it's descriptive versus predictive or causal.
Enneagram I find is the theory that is really
about your fundamental motivations. What are you
running towards and what are you running away
from? And the theory goes through some combination
of your wiring from your genetics and your early
childhood. Your autopilot is fixed after your
childhood in that you just have instinctive
responses to things. Now it's autopilot. It
doesn't mean it's your destiny. You could override
it, but it's super important to become aware of
what are you running from and towards. And the
Enneagram gives you a really good map to do that.
And so I'm reading this book and it starts by you
type yourself, and I'm rolling my eyes. I'm
like, okay, I'm a seven. What's a seven? And
then you read, each type has its own chapter and
you read the chapter and I was like, oh my God,
this completely describes who I am down to
my core. And I was almost looking over my
shoulder. Who the hell did this? I thought I was
a special snowflake, but apparently not. Okay,
I'm listening. And [inaudible 00:45:16] with a
lot of my early coaching experiences, which are,
you do a 360, your coach sits you down,
they're like, here are your strengths. In
my case, it would be things like, oh, you're
really creative and you like new ideas. That's
okay. And second, you really love people. You
build great relationships with people. I'm like,
okay. Uh-huh. Third, you're really comfortable
in chaos and resilient. I was like, this coaching
thing is great. See, yeah, that was my first
coach. And then you flip to your development
areas because no one calls them weaknesses.
It's like, all right, one is you're bored by
routine and really undisciplined. Second is
you're really conflict avoidant. And third is
you're intuitive, but you're also pretty chaotic
and don't create enough structure for people
so they're mostly confused. And when you pair
the two together, you're like, oh, wait. Yeah,
I'm creative and like new ideas, but I'm bored by
routine and I'm a bit of a space cadet. All right,
you love good relationships with people, but
you don't want to make them unhappy so you
don't tell them the truth basically about things
that are difficult to hear. And it's going to be
a similar map of things depending on your
personality type or circumstances. But the
Enneagram was that map for me to be like, okay,
I've got these things that are genuinely great,
but I need to address these downsides
of the company's conflict avoidant,
so we're not telling the truth and then making
a bunch of predictable mistakes, or I'm creating
this really chaotic environment where people
don't know what they're supposed to be doing.
That's a problem. My personality is quite
directly, I'm going to torpedo the company
unless I do something about it. The same is
true for any founder. And I'm a type seven,
it's the enthusiast. It's like, again, central
casting is like a lot of new things and creative
and love just interesting things. But then a
space cadet, FOMO, some of the shadow side of it,
and every type has a thing like that.
So really understanding, okay then,
I was also just frustrated in the day-to-day of my
work, I'm like, yeah, I'm not really getting to do
these creative things where I'm too busy firing to
aim. I'm missing these bigger picture things that
are really taking the ship way too close to the
rocks. Okay. Then I need to then understand what
those things are and either work on myself or hire
the right people who don't have those issues or
one way or another, just make it so the company
is not so exposed to my personal dysfunction.
And so yeah, it was a whole constellation of
things like that where it's like, all right,
we have to get... I mean, after this whole
tailspin, we got to work. I'm like, all right,
first business issues. The most urgent issues
were just blowing all this cash. We need to get
the P&L to look a lot better and get out of this
land grab mode or fighting with Google on giving
more free storage away or just being in these
fundamentally unprofitable things. And so we
did that. We cut the unprofitable parts of the
business. We turned cash flow positive in 2016,
maybe several months after this reckoning,
and that set the tracks for getting into a
billion run rate in 2017, going public in 2018.
We had to come up with a new vision and mission
for the company, which I'll maybe save
for chapter three. And then I was also
just trying to do things that helped sustain me
through the difficult things. I'm like, well,
I am an engineer. As a little kid, I was coding
since childhood. I knew I wanted be a founder.
I didn't know I wanted be a CEO, so I backed
into being a CEO. And then, so I'm like, man,
there's a lot of tedious things about being an
executive. So I was like, I'm going to find ways
to automate tedious parts of my job and learn
machine learning in 2016 and '17, and that ended
up being really important later on. But then also
it's just coming to terms with my job and what I
wanted to do from a personal perspective, which
included things like, oh, I'm lucky in that being
a CEO is, I always wanted a steep learning curve.
In a lot of professions like in sports or math or
chess or certain academic fields, you peak in your
twenties or thirties. CEO's not like that. You can
go your whole life and still not be a master. So
I'm like, for better or worse, it's pretty cool
that I can do this kind of work. And then I don't
really get that much out of just chasing bigger
numbers. The thing that is my favorite thing
about Dropbox is looking over someone's shoulder
in Starbucks and seeing if the little Dropbox icon
is there. Building something that becomes a verb,
taking some of the pain out of technology, things
like that. So really reorienting. Yeah, it's not
about just the external scoreboard just much.
It's more about the craft of being a great CEO
and building things I'm really proud of or really
making a difference. And so those kinds of things,
none of them all coalesce. It's like this lens
that slowly and stubbornly comes into focus,
but making the time to have some of
that reflection was super important.
So much of what you're describing makes me think
about founder mode in a lot of different ways. One
is your point about how you didn't have a lot of
time to think about where things might be going
and how the markets are shifting, and that has
to happen, basically, no one else is going to
do that if it's not you. Also, just this idea of
how much of the solution was you understanding
yourself better, reflecting on where you have
strengths and weaknesses. Also, I'll mention,
so before I had Brian Chesky on the podcast, I
asked you, "What should I ask Brian?" And you
asked me to ask him basically about founder mode,
which was the first time I think you talked about
it, and now it's like this whole thing. So you've
been in the middle of all that for a long time.
I guess just any thoughts on the importance of
that and how you think about that as a founder?
So founder mode means a lot of things to a lot
of people. So it's a bit of a Rorschach test,
but I think parts of it that really resonate
with me are, there's this evolution you go on
as a founder where you don't know what you're
doing and everything is new and unfamiliar. And
then you're also very involved in all the details
because there's no one else to be involved in the
details. It's not like someone else is coding
for you if you're just in your room at home.
But then over time, you have to, there's this, Ben
Horowitz calls it the Product-CEO Paradox, where
the first way that companies die is from founders
not letting go. And so you need to learn to scale
yourself and hand off your responsibilities
and operate at a higher level of abstraction.
But then the second way that companies kill
themselves is the founders get too far away.
And I felt like I had done that. That's a big part
of the problem that led to a lot of this chaos at
the end of chapter two, where I was like, oh, man,
I'm on this treadmill. I'm doing stuff, but I'm
clearly not setting the right direction. Or people
are confused or it's not working, and I was too
distant from the product. And then there's all
kinds of issues you can get into as you hire an
executive team and get that to function well. And
so I think there's a debate to what extent founder
mode is a mindset or a destination. To me, I think
the destination part is pretty important. I think
it's like after that learning journey, suddenly
you have this conviction from actually knowing,
from having lived experience and navigating a lot
of these things where suddenly it's a lot clearer.
You don't have the same kind of confusion or
learning curve problem. And then if you start
out being too far leaned in, then you lean out too
far. And I think a lot of that founder mode flip
is when you're like, hey, this is not the company
I want to be running. I need to be more involved.
I need to stop making excuses. And basically,
I also don't want to apologize or negotiate all
the time for the kind of company that I want to
be part of and run. So I had that too over time,
maybe more towards a chapter three, some of those
elements of... And I don't know if there's a way
to get to this destination without some level
of pain. Certainly the Elons and Steve Jobs
of the world had big spans of wandering in the
desert where they were not as cool as they are-
... spans of wandering in the desert where
they were not as cool as they are today. The
things they were doing weren't working, and
they managed things very differently in that
sort of post wandering phase. Suddenly had this
level of conviction, and intuition that they
might not have had before, or they sanded
down some of their more counterproductive
instincts. Again, there's a lot of surface area.
I don't know if anybody has a common definition
of founder mode, but certainly that evolution,
the way I think about is it is very difficult.
One of the hardest things when you're running a
company is that you're hiring all these execs who
the only thing you know is they know a lot more
about the subject matter than you do. What does
it even mean to bring someone in, bring an exec
who had managed a double-digit billion dollar
P&L at Google, and what am I supposed to tell him
how sales works or marketing? It's easy to be too
leaned out there where you're not really setting
a clear direction. Each founder is going to have
their own things that are easy, things that
are harder. Step one is being aware of them,
and then being intentional about, how do I
offset those things? Then you eventually get
to a point where the learning curve flattens
out. You actually do have some experience, and
you can have a lot more conviction about what the
company should do, and where you want it to go.
Awesome. The way you described it to
me, which has really stuck with me,
is as a founder, as you said, you're in there
leaning in, doing, on top of everything,
micromanaging. Then you lead out, and hire
execs that you think are smarter than you,
and delegate more. Then it's like, "Oh, things
aren't going great," and come right back into it.
Yeah. Specifically, it's often well-intended
or it's often even not conscious, but as you
hire these execs, and then you also build up an HR
function, you get coaches, and things like that,
and then the things are not going well, one
thing that can happen is you start collecting
all this feedback. People are like, "Wait,
if I can give Drew some negative feedback,
then maybe I can displace some of the ..." It's
sort of easy to get into a situation where you're
sort of being my to-do list of problems, just
weaknesses, and flaws I needed to work on was
super long, way longer than anyone else's. On the
one hand I'm like, "Yes, I am wholly accountable,
and responsible for everything in the company
as its CEO." That's not wrong. But you can end
up just carrying too much of the water, so a lot
of it ended up having to be this pushing back a
bit. Be like, "All right, yes, there are things
I need to work on, but that can't be an excuse
for my execs to somehow evade accountability."
There's these sorts of systemic things that can
creep in for sure. Then you get this feedback, and
you're like, "Now, I'm doing all this behavior,"
or, "Now, I'm behaving in ways that I don't think
are really right." Or I'm like, "Everything is
just negotiated compromise with everyone on
the roadmap or on how we behave or strategy."
At some point you end up blowing that up as a
founder, and that was certainly my experience.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta.
When it comes to ensuring your company
as top-notch security practices, things get
complicated fast. Now, you can assess risk,
secure the trust of your customers, and
automate compliance for SOC 2, ISO 27001,
HIPAA, and more. With a single platform, Vanta.
Vanta's market leading trust management platform
helps you continuously monitor
compliance alongside reporting,
and tracking risks. Plus, you can save hours by
completing security questionnaires with Vanta
AI. Join thousands of global companies that
use Vanta to automate evidence collection,
unify risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go to
vanta.com/lenny. That's V-A-N-T-A.com/lenny.
I think this is a great segue to get into
chapter three. Basically, what I understand
from what you're going through right now is
you're rebooting the team, you're rebooting the
core business, you're rebooting the product. I
think it might be good to start with the team. You
talked a few times about just how you feel like
you got to a point where the team wasn't shipping
as much as you thought you would, as much as you
think they should. Talk about maybe that part
of it, of just realizing, "Hey, this part of the
business needs to change. Then we can talk about
the product, and the direction you've discovered."
My playbook as an entrepreneur is to get
really frustrated by something, and then
try to solve that personally. I'll cover the team,
and what direction we ended up choosing together.
My first frustration was forgetting a thumb drive,
and then wanting to never have that problem again.
But my second big frustration was like, "Man,
this scaling this company was way harder than
it should have been." Thank God I had people like
Bill, Andy, friends, mentors to guide me along. A
lot of people don't have access to that. But I
feel like I could have written myself postcards
that would've made this a little bit
easier. Or, there are just some things
that don't make sense about how you scale
a company. There seem to be things that are
really broken about the way we work in general.
As I was piecing through a lot of the challenges,
I'm like, "All right, what should Dropbox do?" We
should probably not do things that would've been
invented by everybody else 10 minutes later. Where
are the problems that are not solving themselves?
One problem I felt like was not solving itself
was this problem of being just on this treadmill
where I'm like, "I'm working really hard. I'm in
meetings all day, emails all night. Is this it?"
First of all problem, no complaints. But I'm like,
"This is so weird. Yeah, I'm making huge strategic
mistakes, because I'm too busy firing the aim,
and I'm upset at myself about a lot of these
things." But then I look left, look right,
I'm like, "Wait, everybody is too busy firing
the aim." Everybody is on the same treadmill.
I'm like, "This is bizarre. Who's winning here?"
It's like if I was working hard, and the company
is benefiting, then no problem. But I'm very busy,
but I'm not really productive. I'm not putting
in a lot of creative input. Then the company's
not getting a lot of creative output. It
just seems like lose, lose, lose all around.
I'm like, "Why are we on this treadmill?" We know
from brain science that people are most happy,
most productive, fulfilled, engaged, kind of
everything you want, where we'd rattle off
the same list, like when people are focused, when
there's some kind of flow state, when they've had
enough sleep, when they have a sense of purpose.
We know all that. Yet we go to work, and it's
like this cage fight of who's busiest, who's
gotten the least sleep, who's most inbox zero.
Then you look at the environment on our screens,
now, especially after COVID, we live with that.
That's where we work. We don't work in an
office, no matter what flavor of hybrid you are,
you're working on a screen. COVID relocated us
from offices to screens. You look what's on that
screen, it's like, "Yeah, if you wanted to design
a working environment that made it impossible
to ever focus, ever get into a flow state,
bombard you with just constant interruptions,
distractions, and busy work, then
yeah, you can squint and see me even
before COVID, but definitely after.
But that people are like, "Yeah,
I'm really not feeling great." I'm not feeling
super engaged because half of my work is bullshit,
the other half I'm just distracted to death.
I'm like, "Why is this this? All right. Maybe
Dropbox doesn't have to exist. Maybe we did
the thing. Maybe I should go." Maybe I'm ready
for the tech bro ascendancy. Maybe I should
be flying cars, space, cancer, climate ...
Ayahuasca.
Yeah, right. But then I would talk to people
who were actually working on those things,
and they were on the same treadmill. I interviewed
this director of engineering at SpaceX. I was
like, "Oh my God, you're actually going to
Mars. This is so cool. How do you guys work
together? How are you going to get to Mars?" He's
like, "I don't really understand the question."
I'm like, "What tools do you use? How do you
work together? How are we going to get to
Mars?" The answer was basically, "We're going
to get to Mars through a lot of emails, and a
lot of files." I was like, "Oh, my God." Most of
the time, we correctly think about technology as
just like force multiplier, like the amplifier
of our abilities. But from another perspective,
we're only as good as organizations as our
tools, or tools can become the limiting
factor. It's really a problem when the mechanism
through which we were getting work done has gone
from being a force multiplier, and amplifier to a
suppressor. We are the frogs in the boiling water
where this kind happen one day at a time.
All the people working on those things,
and there are many others, they're all dealing
with the same issues of, "I can't focus my
tools. I'm fighting with my tools." Somehow
the tools went from helping us get the work
done to becoming the work, as we layer. It went
from 5 of them, to 10 of them, to 500 of them.
Yeah. I'm like, "All right. If Einstein were
alive today, what would his day be like?" He
would wake up. He'd have to delete a bunch of
LinkedIn notifications. He'd get down to work,
start writing equations, and then someone
would Slack him, and interrupt him. Then he'd
get back to work. Would we still understand
relativity if Einstein were living in that
kind of working environment? Probably not.
Even just visiting my dad at work when I was
a kid, a lot of things were the same. He had
a phone, a PC and an office, but he could turn
his phone off. He got 5 emails a day, not 500.
He would literally come home from work with a
briefcase, put it down, and stop thinking about
work. Then when he would be in the office, he
could close the door, and actually get stuff done.
I'm not saying we should go back to the early
90's, but I'm saying it wasn't always like
this. The whole frontier of productivity
at the time felt like it was just taking us
in the wrong direction. Things like Slack,
which are wonderful tools, also chop up your day
into little fragments, and make you cognitively
diabetic. There's a lot of empty carbs in our
collaboration, and our collaboration tools.
I'm like, "Okay, here is a problem
that's not solving itself. Actually,
none of our competitors even are framing the
problem correctly. What we should be recognizing
is that our ultimate non-renewable resource is
our time, our attention, mostly our brain power,
our creative energy. I think as a civilization,
we're going to, hopefully in 5 or 10 years be
like, "Man, we took this crazy detour where we
basically hooked up that brain power to this thing
that was just burning off half of it as friction
with our tools." That was dumb. Yet no company was
even talking about this, let alone fixing it.
Then we came up with a new Dropbox mission. It
became Dropbox is designing a more enlightened
way of working, because the way we were working
is unenlightened, unexamined. Meanwhile, we were
patient zero as the company. No one was doing a
lot of thinking. Everybody's kind of busy.
Everybody's bumping into each other. There
were a lot of cultural problems. Like that we
were faster. Your company grows, and rises,
the easier it is for new people in the company to
think they hit a home run instead of starting on
third base. A lot of complacency, entitlement,
and preoccupation with things other than our
customers or other than our products set in.
It wasn't all bad. I think there were a lot of
good things we had to pay attention to. We were
scaling up the business financially. We were
getting ready to go public. We had to mature a
lot of things, but we lost sight of the place that
money is coming from is from our customers, and
the thing they really want is a great experience.
We've been tackling this in a lot of different
ways. First is just things like after COVID hit,
suddenly the world is working in a completely
different way. We saw this as a big opportunity,
not just a crisis. Or once you got past the crisis
part of COVID, there was a big opportunity. COVID
kind of wrecked everything, but we didn't have to
put the floorboards back down in the same places.
I'm a big fan of people like Peter Drucker, and
lots of people who think about the nature of work,
and this idea of we're finally decoupling work
from our physical location. It's a big deal. It's
probably one of the biggest changes to knowledge
work in our lifetimes. Or even since Drucker
coined that term knowledge work in 1959.
It's like, "Cool. For the first time,
we can actually design how we work
in ways that our parents couldn't,
or the way that most of us just receive how
we work from our parents." But like, "Hey,
we can actually do things completely differently."
We came up with this whole virtual first model
where we're 90% remote, but then most importantly,
we're trying to rebuild the new product stack for
distributed work. I'll talk a little bit about
where the new things we're doing, and then I'll
come back to how we're rebooting some of the core.
But initially, after COVID, we studied a lot of
how other remote first companies had worked.
We synthesized with a lot of primary research
of other companies like GitLab, Automattic, and
others who had been doing this for a long time. We
collated all that, synthesized a common playbook,
open sourced it. If anybody's curious about this,
you could find Dropbox. We've open sourced our
virtual first toolkit. Then since COVID, designing
a working model very in line with our new mission
with a lot of benefits. It really works. The
employee retention, satisfaction, engagement
or offer separates all the things we care about
have been significantly up since COVID. There's
many factors to that, but there's a lot that's
working about the model. But really, we're
approaching it from a product standpoint.
In deciding to turn Dropbox into this lab
for distributed work, we're like, "Okay,
when you open up your laptop in 2025, 2030, what
do you see?" Hopefully, there's some new stuff
or some things that are different on there. What
are those things, and how do we bring them back?
One of the first things you lose when you
go distributed is context. We get a lot.
You get a lot for free from osmosis. Just, "Oh,
hey, how are you doing? How's this?" Or, "Oh,
do you have that thing?" But then when
you're remote, then a lot of that gets
replaced with endless video meetings, and lots
of Slack messages, which is super inefficient.
Also, one thing that was clear across the board
from all the successful remote first companies
was you have to be more documented, but then you
have a lot more documents. This started turning
up very obvious problems, which is like,
"Wait, why do I have 1 search box at home,
and 10 search boxes at work? Why is it easier to
search all of human knowledge than my company's
knowledge? Why is this problem getting worse
not better every year?" If you think about it,
we've got 10 search boxes that you search 10% of
our stuff. I'm like, "We should just fix this."
Again, even just as a frustrated user, maybe 2018,
2019, I'm having this problem myself. I'm like,
"It's really hard to find stuff." Plus
there's always cool vector search stuff,
and deep learning stuff happening. Even
for ChatGPT, I'm going to make a personal
search engine that takes us, so I shouldn't
have to, right? If I search for strategy,
and the title of the document is plan, it
should get it right, and the matching should
be fuzzy. Then I built something like this.
I'm like, "Oh my God, it completely works."
You built this yourself, you're saying?
Yeah, it went nowhere for a couple of years,
but then after COVID, and after we're dealing
with all these information problems, I'm like,
"Yeah, we should be the company that helps you
get the right information at the right
time to the right person." I built that
little hacked up search engine thing that
I made, might be an ingredient to this.
We bought a little company called Command E that
was doing universal search, and we created this
new product called Dropbox Dash. Basically, Dash
connects to all your different apps. It gives you
universal search. Then obviously after ChatGPT,
not only can you do conventional search, but you
can ask questions in natural language, and answer
a lot of the questions that ChatGPT can't because
it's not connected to your stuff. If you ask
ChatGPT like, "When does my lease expire? Where's
that slide from last year's product launch," can't
tell you because it's not personalized. Because
it's not connected to your information. We did all
of that for this whole connector platform where we
index the known universe of SaaS apps, have this
kind of intelligence engine that brings all of it
into a common representation, and lets you do
conventional search, natural language search.
Then more than that, we want to organize your
working life for you. Stepping back even further,
often it happens that a company likes to starts
solving a problem, and that problem is never
permanently solved. In a lot of ways, Dash is
the biggest, best embodiment of solving the same
kinds of problems I started Dropbox to begin
with. Because on the one hand, I was talking
about thumb drive, but I wasn't, really. If you
think about the higher level job to be done,
I was like, "No, the real issue is that it's
super hard to find my stuff, organize my stuff,
share my stuff, and secure my stuff."
In the beginning that was like my stuff
was my files, and the scattering was across
devices. Now, the stuff is tabs in my browser,
and cloud tools. But it's a lot of the same
problems. We've talked a lot about search,
but then organize is still a big problem. There's
no desktop folder or desktop as in the physical
realm, when you're in your browser. It's just this
ocean of content that washes by you. Then you get
tired. You nuke the whole environment. But there's
nothing to come back to. There's no collection
concept. Files have folders, songs have playlists,
links have ... If you're getting ready for board
meeting or remodeling a house, there's no common
container. If you have a Google doc, and a 10 gig,
4K video, and an air table, this is a new problem.
Dash also has this thing called Stacks,
and has basically smart collections that
helps make sharing a lot easier. But again,
a lot of this was an intersection of like,
"Yeah, how has work changed since COVID?
What crazy little science projects have I done?
Then how should one find, organize, and share
their information in the cloud era? If I were to
build Dropbox today, what would it look like?"
Dash is first part of the answer. We're super
excited. But we just launched it two months ago,
and signed up our first customers. Then I can come
back to just rebooting the core business too. I
think one of the big challenges or lessons from
this whole period is that one, is as part of the
problem we had with competition, and this chapter
two was external, but a lot of it was internal,
where we couldn't organize ourselves effectively.
The business has scaled so much faster than our
ability to manage it. First is to recognize
this is not an unusual problem. Many companies,
not all, but certainly many, and actually many in
SaaS productivity have this sophomore slump where
you have the super successful first product,
but then it's challenging to build the next
platinum album. Dropbox has fallen into that
category. You could say Zoom, Slack, others.
First, it's easy to feel bad about it yourself,
but no, you're not. This is actually a very
common problem. Then there's a lot of solutions.
People devise lots of solutions to this. Part of
it's structural. Your company has to go from
a pretty fun, and stable state of a functional
organization where you have engineering
in product design, there's one product,
and there's one customer. Everybody's working,
we are all in the same direction for the same
team to then when you have multiple products,
then you have all these conflicts. How much
should we invest in the core business versus
the new thing? Who should have authority in the
company? You try to build multiple products in a
functional org, but then you lose accountability.
People are like, "I'm spending a lot.
I'm trying to make Dropbox work. I'm
trying to make mailbox work. I'm trying
to make paperwork, and all these things."
Then you respond by breaking up into groups or
business units. We have a product business unit,
product GM structure. Then you have to refactor
things to have a common technical platform, and
all the GNA functions. There's this metamorphosis,
and maturation you need to go through that is mega
obvious to experienced people. That you're just
totally blindsided by this if you're solving it
by trial and error. There's a great book,
Zone to Win, that talks about some of this,
what needs to happen internally by Geoffrey Moore.
Then there's a lot of cultural problems that set
in. We just touched on some of them at a high
level. But whether you're in a company or an
empire, a civilization, what gets you to the
top turns out to be pretty similar things. You
have this outsider, challenger mentality
where you have to eat what you kill, and
the odds are against you. Through hard work,
learning, and grinding, you start moving up the
curve faster. But then once you're successful,
then there's a temptation to take the foot off
the gas or enjoy the finer things in life or just
focus on other things, be it other than what got
you there. I think what we experienced, many other
companies experienced, Bill Campbell experienced
in Netscape, the success plants, the seeds of
failure in terms of complacency, entitlements,
or taking your eye off of what got you to be
successful in the first place, yeah, I went from
earning a lot of the early stage startup founder
merit badges to earning the stagnation, and
irrelevance merit badge. Now, the turnaround merit
badge. Part of that is the turnaround playbook.
Okay, first, it's just getting out of this
delusional state where you think you're great,
just splashing cold water on everyone, and
be like, "Look, we haven't shipped any. Last
three years, the only thing our customers have
really meaningfully seen from our product is a
price increase. What the hell are we doing?"
A lot of it is getting back to like, "Hey,
we have to focus on craft. We have to embrace
a growth mindset and learning. We have to stop
blaming external factors or displacing blame.
We have to be a high agency culture." There's
a cultural transformation that you have
to personally embody, and be clear about.
Then in our case, we had to reboot the whole
exec team. We've had all the time getting
the right kind of leadership team in place for
the end of chapter two and three. Part of what
happens in conjunction with a lot of the cultural
stuff I just talked about, is also you can have
this as the talent flywheels flying forward, and
flies in reverse. You have a new set of issues
where you get all these amazing people in the
company, but they want to work for Facebook,
not MySpace. You start having retention problems
when the narrative goes negative. We start
bleeding talents, and then it's also really hard
to hire people for the same reasons. Especially,
as I think about where the big lessons from
chapter two that we've addressed in chapter three,
the seniority gap is something that can accumulate
because much of the talent can fly to the next
shiny thing. What you do in response typically
is, you promote a lot of people internally,
which is good for them. It seems good for them in
the short term, because they're just getting a lot
more authority, and responsibility quickly. People
like that on day one. But it's a problem because
suddenly people are solving problems through trial
and error. Things may be new to them that are not
new to the industry, and suddenly no knowns to the
industry are unknown and knowns to those leaders.
Then usually you can get around that by hiring
a layer of experienced execs or having enough of
them in the company. But in the talent wars of the
late teens, we were in the situation as were many
companies where, any exec you talked to with any
experience had five offers from fan companies for
three times the comp, and a third of the workload,
or 10 offers from pre-IPO startups, and C-level
roles. These are offers in hand. The only thing
that really worked to even just keep the lights on
was basically giving people double promotions so
that they could justify someone who's a director
at company X, making him a VP at Dropbox. Then
you had to do that because they literally had
offers in hand of many millions of dollars a year.
Otherwise, you'd just hire no one. That cooled off
a lot after the correction in SaaS, after we
got more of our vision straight, and certainly
after we've been working on things like Dash.
But that seniority gap is really rough. Where ...
Seniority gap is really rough where you need to
have enough experienced people in the company
who can then train your high potential
people. And again, that sounds obvious,
but it's very difficult to do that in an
environment where the talent flywheel is
going in your direction and then starts
flying away from you really quickly. And
then through the battlefield promotions
and these double promotions on hiring,
you can end up a situation where there's
a huge voltage drop in terms of people's
matching between what your company needs and what
they know how to do. And that also doesn't mean
hire only experienced people either because then
you're splicing in a lot of outside DNA into your
organism. But what you want is to keep it roughly
in balance. I mean 60-40, 40-60, 50-50, whatever.
But your high potential people also lose out if
they don't have experienced people learning from.
So that's a little bit, I think that it was a big
part of the stagnation. Again, it's not because
the people, but this was something that I was
doing to my team. So it's not them or certainly on
my watch, but I think it's a dynamic you have to
be careful of like do we have the right balance of
people who are super high potential and talented,
but doing their thing for the first time? Are
they paired with people who have been there, done
that, this is not the biggest job of their life,
and that they can help those people up the
learning curve faster such that the aggregate
learning curve or the aggregate learning
rate of your company is what it needs to be.
Man, I feel like there's a book
here of lessons for founders,
things that you never hear about until-
Mind the seniority gap.
That's one of so many. People think about
becoming founders, they start companies, "Oh, I'm
going to start a company, there we go." And then,
they think about that first part of the journey
that you talked about. And most people don't
even get that part. And the best case scenario
is you experience a ton of growth. And then,
the way you described it to me previously is
you hit the final bosses where showing all the
success and they're like, "Oh, I see there's a
big market here. Let's go after it." And you're
battling Apple and Google and Microsoft and Meta,
and a lot of people don't think about that
and how that's the future if you do well.
Yeah, every time you move up a league, your
reward is a stronger and better opponent and
potentially more unlevel playing field. And
that's just the way it is. You can't control
that. All you can control is how you respond. And
so, you want your company's response to embrace
that challenge and use it as a mechanism
to get stronger. Easy to say, hard to do.
Yeah. So maybe just to start reflecting
on some of the lessons from this journey,
because there's a lot here. One question people
may be wondering is, should I even be a founder?
Should I start a company? A lot of people, there's
a lot of pain that you've been sharing of the
challenge of starting companies. What do you tell
people that are asking you like, "Hey, should I
start a company? Am I right to be a founder?"
Is there any advice there that you could share?
I don't know what made me want to be a
founder. I just showed up that way. And so,
there's probably some chemical imbalance
of some form that causes people to do it,
but I had a lot of insecurity about should I
be a CEO? Because coming from the technical
side, because I was like, I can do the engineering
and technology, but all I know about being a CEO
is I do not know how to do all of those things
that CEOs do, and I do not look like that,
I do not talk like that, it's intimidating.
So I think first is it doesn't have to be an
all or nothing decision. I mean, obviously
it's all encompassing decision to become,
to start a company, but you'll have many points
along the way where you can keep calibrating.
And I think the biggest thing is, or advice I
got from one of the founders of a company where
I worked was I was like, oh, should I be CEO?
Should I not be CEO? Should I be CTO? He's like,
"Look, just try it, be CEO, see how it goes."
Initially, I thought I was like, all right,
well I'm going to get the company to 100 million
valuation and the trend will just be going faster,
faster and faster, faster. And instead of just
getting thrown off of it, I'll just hit stop
and retire. And I thought that sounded like a
great plan. But then, moving to the Bay Area, you
suddenly meet, you throw a rock and hit 10 people
who've done that. And what do you learn? This was
just shocking to me because I talked to one of the
advisors I mentioned earlier. He's like, "Yeah,
the day I sold my company was the saddest day
of my life." I'm like, "What?" As a 24-year-old,
and he's like, "Yeah. Well, I just felt like the
company had drifted away from what it was supposed
to be and I just didn't like it." I think they're
certain in the founder mode trough where you're
like, wait, things are screwed up and it's on
my watch, but I'm not really sure what happened
and what do I do about it? So I think burnout is
the biggest thing that will kill you. And so, I
think that's why these coping methods and getting
your own head is important, but if you do that,
then it's also this amazing experience. And then
often so many founders go back and start another
company and another company. And you don't
have to, but there's a reason that people do
that because there's just a lot of rewarding
aspects of it, building great things with
great people that impact huge populations.
What I found is that founders keep doing
this because they love it in some way, or at
least have a love-hate relationship with it or
can't imagine something else that they would
otherwise be doing and I'm probably the same
way. But I think to get through that, you have
to, Ben Horowitz also said the hardest thing
for a CEO is to manage your own psychology.
And we've talked a lot about, yeah, first you
have to be aware of what your psychology is, and
then how do you make sure you're not resenting
or hating your company or yourself and view...
I think the hardest thing for a founder, challenge
is not optional. You're going to be challenged,
but the suffering is optional. You don't actually
have to suffer. I mean, look, there's crunch
periods or times where it's taxing, but it
doesn't have to be this experience of suffering
all the way or burning out or being really angry
and sad all the time. Although certainly, in my
experience that I did get in periods where I was
just sad and angry all the time. So you need to
figure out how do you work your way out of that.
So along those lines, I'm curious, so you've
shared a few things that have helped you level
up as a leader and push through that.
You mentioned meditation, Bill Campbell,
a coach. You mentioned a few books. What
has helped you continue to level up and
stay ahead of where the company needs you?
Sometimes you fell behind, sometimes you're
ahead. What are some tips for founders that are
trying to stay ahead of where things are going?
Well, I think first thing is I think
a theme that's carried throughout a
lot of these different chapters is
you have to figure out what game
you're playing and what the rules
are when the game keeps changing.
So I like in addition to the Enneagram or coding,
I also like a long time video game player and
there's a great game called, everybody's familiar
with StarCraft. It's an awesome game. I think it
has many lessons and riddles for an aspiring
entrepreneur, many parallels with running
a company. I'll save that for another one.
But this idea, Mindshare is a big resource.
It's not actually how much money
or economy or land or whatever or-
Actions?
Military. Yeah, it's like you can only do so
much or think about so much, your attention,
but that's actually not the big lesson.
In StarCraft and other games, there's this
concept of there's a micro and macro, and I would
add to that, there's also the meta game. Okay,
so what's that? Micro in these games,
something like StarCraft is like, all right,
can you click really fast and move your people
and build things really quickly? And it's like
the mechanics. Every second, how many hundreds
of things are you doing per minute or how many
things are you doing per second? And that's like
a conditioning and practice and one kind of thing.
Then, there's the macro game. Well, could come
back to the micro, in a product context or in a
startup context, that might be things like, all
right, how do I, often the stuff around product
design and technology and distribution. So
early founders especially are going to be
totally fixated on here's how I make this great
design and here's how the engineering works and
here's how we get users and here's how our sales
motion works, or here's how our viral loop works
or things like that. And it's very in the details.
And then, there's the macro game. In StarCraft,
that might be things like, well, clicking a lot
is important, but overall you're really managing
your economy. So do you have more expansions
and resources than the other player? Are you
building up your military? Are you getting
your balance of the investment in economy and
military? Are you scouting? Do you know what
the other person's doing? It's more strategic
and conceptual. So things in the startup realm
that would feel more like that are more like,
all right, not just the mechanics of how does this
feature work, but more like, all right, what's
the business model? What's the market? Who are my
competitors? How do I differentiate myself? How's
this all going to evolve over time as the category
goes from super high growth to more mature,
things like that? And you respond, okay,
we got to go from one product to multiple
products, so then we have to reorganize the
company that way and we blah, blah, blah.
And then I'd say there's also this, the meta
game, which in gaming is a pretty specific
thing. It's like some combination of the game
itself gets updated so that as the creators,
they make this unit stronger and this area unit
is stronger, and this ground unit weaker and try
to keep this big system in balance. And then,
also as this community of players figures out
new strategies and this big repeated game of
rock paper, scissors, people figure out, okay,
this one strategy is now categorically better.
And it's always this adversarial thing that's
always shifting. And so, playing StarCraft in 2020
is pretty different from playing StarCraft in 2015
or 2010 because everything, both the players
are shifting and the game itself is shifting.
And the game, it's usually not shifting a lot.
So it's really more of an ecological effect.
So I think it's super important. And then, in
a startup context, what's the meta game? Well,
I'd say some of it is just business cycles.
So I think you'll have, as you see, there's
this boom in the late teens in SaaS and in tech.
There's a bit of an AI boom happening right now.
It's not that different from what, or parts of it
are not that different from what happened with the
dotcom era in '99, 2000 or the web 2.0 era in 2007
or others. And then, you have these bust times
like 2008 and 2000, 2001, et cetera. So there's
a market cycle thing that often creates similar
dynamics where it's like five years ago every tech
company was hiring the maximal number of people
that it could. And then, that created one talent
dynamic. Now, it's a lot of companies are keeping
high comp flat or negative, so that's just a very
different thing. But even those are cyclical.
Then, you want to identify how is this game
of business actually fundamentally permanently
changing? So for example, we launched Dash, we
usually do a press thing, conventional press, tech
press, we got almost no coverage for it. And yet
all the stuff we did on social or going direct was
way, way, way more impactful. And it's not just
Dropbox or in tech, but it's also presidential
election. All the candidates are on podcasts. Yes,
they're on CNN too, but not really. So that's just
a new thing. How do you manage the brand of your
company or launch products, things like that. The
nature of marketing is changing. And that changed
when, in 2007 too, instead of hiring PR firms
and buying AdWords and stuff, we were creating
these viral videos and we were using math from
epidemiology to create these viral loops. In a
lot of ways, Dropbox took that, transplanted that
consumer internet playbook into business software.
But the thing is you need to understand what game
you're playing and you need to get good at the
micro. It's not that the meta is more important
than the micro, it's like you need to do all
three at the same time. And so, that's really
the hard part. And then, when things are shifting.
And the way you know what game you're playing is
to be systematic about training yourself and
probably the single most useful, or at least
important to me piece of advice I could give is
you have to figure out how to keep your personal
growth curve ahead of the company's growth curve.
The single most important impactful thing for me
has been reading because talk about this micro,
macro, meta games or abstractions, this is the
kind of stuff you can learn from history.
Learning what happened in Netscape ended
up being pretty important to what happened
at Dropbox in 2014. Learning what happened
to Procter & Gamble and selling makeup ended up
actually being pretty relevant. So I think having
a broad information diet is really important. And
I've collated a list of books that were really
impactful to me. You can find a way to share
that. All right, I'd be happy to share that.
Absolutely.
But in a lot of ways, as a CEO, you have to
be right about a lot of things, especially
and including things you haven't done before.
And I think from that perspective at least,
I'd say there's things that are challenging for
your head and things that are challenging for
your heart. The head challenge is one that's more
like, all right, how do I cultivate wisdom really
quickly? And so, in addition to a lot of technical
books about here's how you do marketing or product
or management or things like that. So it could
be around higher level, almost philosophical when
it's things like Buffett or Munger or Bezos would
be more on that end of the spectrum. But it's not
just reading. I think having a community of people
that you can learn from is really important. And
I've also found it's interesting, you learn having
stable of people that are at the same stage as
you, couple people, a couple stages ahead, 2
years ahead, 5 years ahead, 20 years ahead.
And this is founders, other CEOs?
Other founders, founders and CEOs, exactly,
because you'll learn different things from
them. So first of all, when you're in the
early innings, you'll actually get more useful
advice often from your peers because they're
going through the same thing. So it's like,
how do I raise a seed round? You're going to get
a lot more out of someone who did that a year ago
or is doing that now. Then if I asked the doc,
"How do you raise a seed round?" He'd be like,
"I don't remember. Just build a good company."
And you'll see that as you talk to people
at different phases. I think again,
early stage it's more about the micro,
about the product and distribution, then there's
this continuum. So then it's about your business
model and monetization and the financials, then
it's about defensibility and maintaining that
advantage. And as you talk to, as I talked to my
peers would be more about the product. That was
the scaffold I would see over founders.
And then, people that were further out,
actually they still knew all the micro stuff
and had feelings about it, but they're almost
philosophical in nature like philosophers and
just very broad intellectually and drawing lots
of distinctions from lots of different things
and knew a lot about a lot. And I think most
of the tenured founders that I'm, most of
the founder CEOs who've been at it for 10,
20 years plus, I'm at 17, almost all of them read
voraciously. So I think combination of reading
and community are the most important things.
But then, the last thing is being systematic about
it. So in line with what does it mean to keep
your personal growth curve ahead of the company's
growth curve? I think one way to do that exercise
is think about is always be working back from,
in one year from now, what will I wish I had been
learning today? Two years, five years? And often,
those to-do lists are pretty different.
So in 2008, I would've been focused on
just getting users for Dropbox, but then looking
ahead to a year later, I would've been building
the first business functions in the company, and
then five years later, it would be thinking about
how do we fight with Google and Microsoft and all
these other things. And then, for my own skills,
it would be like 2008 where like how do I raise a
scale to venture round and what do all these terms
mean and things like that. But then, how do I be a
great leader, great manager, comfortable speaking
publicly, things like that. And the things that
are further out are often the most intimidating,
but you also have the most time to learn and you
often can psych yourself out in terms of like, oh,
this is just new and uncomfortable. And I did
say this is one of the hard challenges. You're
always going to have that feeling of discomfort.
And instinctively, what you're going to want to
do is run away from it because you're human.
It's uncomfortable to feel like to confront
these things that you're not good at or might be
embarrassing or threatening. And so, I think an
important part of being a founder is learning to
run towards that feeling not away from it. That's
a big part of your learning rate is the extent to
which you're pushing yourself beyond discomfort.
And so having that list of a year from now, two
years from now, five years from now, what can I
start learning today? And then, recognizing these
things, they're all trainable. So in five weeks
you're not going to be a great guitar player or
surgeon or manager, leader, but in five years you
can put a pretty big dent in those problems. And
people who enter college and leave college often
have a lot more relevant knowledge after those
four years. So just having that growth mindset.
And I'd say the last piece of it that is also
tricky in addition to going from a heart or
mindset perspective going towards discomfort
and in addition to a lot of the other stuff
we talked about being like how do you have a
sense of equanimity, you're not burning out
and finding a sustainable pace. I think the
other thing is often smart people have more
trouble learning than otherwise. And there's this
great article that I, it's probably my most handed
out articles probably from the '70s or '80s or
something called Teaching Smart People How to
Learn. Because what ends up happening is the
more book smart you are or the more you were
identified as gifted or intelligent as a kid,
the more not knowing something or being wrong,
it's not just not knowing something or being
wrong, it's like an assault on your identity.
And so, I found that one of the best predictors
of an exact continuity of this scale,
it's not just what they know or what they can
do, but the extent to which they can actually
be aware of their failures and not blame or
dismiss things because smart people have a really
fast rationalization hamster. They can convince
themselves that, well, here's how they were
technically right even though clearly they were
wrong or clearly the thing didn't work out and
they let themselves off the hook. And all of this
happens unconsciously as a protective mechanism.
So I think finding ways to take responsibility
or always have a mindset of what if I were a
hundred percent responsible for this? What if it
was no one else's fault? What if it's entirely
in my control? And those things are never true,
but that's always... Or with perfect hindsight,
what would I have done differently? And just
owning things ends up being more painful in the
short run, but then some painful hours can save
painful years. And there's a great book on that
mindset stuff, the 15 Principles of Conscious
Leadership, Diana Chapman and some co-authors,
and she's been a coach and friend of mine. She's
amazing and it has really helped me on that front.
But really, how do you train your head and train
your heart? There's different things you do for
each, but all in service of keeping your personal
growth curve ahead of the company's growth curve.
I love how tactically your advice is. There's
this piece of advice of think what do I need to
know a year from now, two years from now,
five years from now, this reading list,
this idea of having staggered staged founders
in a community to help you along this journey,
this article about how smart people learn and
how to get past this block. So I love just how
concrete a lot of this stuff is. So then, just
zooming out and maybe final reflections on this
journey, as you described this, it's basically
the epitome of the hero's journey that you've
been on here. Things are good, trouble appears,
you enter this other land of everyone coming at
you trying to squash you in every direction,
battling them, and then emerging now into
this new land with all the things you've learned,
coming back to the original idea of what Dropbox
could have been. So I think that's partly why
it's so interesting is it's the epitome of-
But we still got to make it fully out of the,
we're on our way up, we're
clawing our way back up.
The dragon's still out there.
The incumbents still exist.
And by the way, it will always be like
that. You're never done with that. It's
not like you reach the A-top or you
don't have to if you don't want it.
And it makes me think about, as you're
talking, people think about product
market fit and something, a lesson from
this journey is just like product market
fit is not a binary. You will have it now.
You've got it and you have it and will last
forever. It's constantly being broken
by other people or if there's something
you've discovered that is a big market. And
maybe final reflection on the story you've
shared things that might be helpful to people,
just the journey you've been on that might be
helpful to founders who are going through this
right now or will probably go through this.
I think it's important to remember we're all
really lucky to be able to do this kind of
work. And the things that I got out of... When I
was 18, the things I thought I would get out of
starting company would've been the things
you would think. It'd be like, oh, I'll be
really well-known or really rich or build these
awesome things. I think there's benefits to that,
but what I've grown to appreciate a lot more
is over time is this thing or the experience
and the journey of starting a company can
really be of forge for a better character
or there's transfer. A lot of what you learn
here is transferable in many different domains.
I just had a little kid, Charlie, he's
one-year-old, so I know we're both in
new dad mode, but I'm like, it's made me a
better husband, it'll make me a better father,
made me a better person. And then, I just say,
listen, there's no easy button where things are
just up to the right and so don't look for one
and don't feel bad if things are difficult. But
ultimately, one of the biggest surprises
about being able to spend time with all
these interesting people and founder CEOs who've
created these iconic companies is at the end of
the day, they do it because they love it.
And so, I think learning to decouple... That
doesn't mean they're always having a good time
at all. Most of them use metaphors like Jensen
or Eli, like chewing broken glass, staring into
the abyss, and yet for a lot of these people,
there's at the end of the day, nothing they'd
rather do. So I think finding the gun in that.
I'm very excited to follow the
next chapter of your journey.
I am really thankful that you shared these
stories. I think this is going to be helpful
to a lot of people. I think this is a story
that people study for a long time because
it's common and not talked about much. Drew,
thank you so much for being here. For folks
that want to maybe check out what you're building,
anything you want to share, where should they go?
I'm just Drew Houston on all the socials and
then we got our new product, Dropbox Dash,
dropbox.com/dash. Right now, it's for
companies. We'll have a downloadable
version. You could just get on your
phone or your computer soon. But Lenny,
this is awesome, super fun,
really big fan of what you do.
Awesome. Same. Drew, thank
you so much for being here.
Thanks.
Bye everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.