Let's paint a picture of just what it was like to
join Airbnb in your 50s. I was mentoring Brian,
but he was also my boss. I was 52. The average
age was 26. I had to be both wise and curious and
often the dumbest person in the room. So, it's
great to be in founder mode. It's not as great
to be working for someone in founder mode. Brian
assumed everybody else was going to work at the
same pace and duration. His point of view is like,
hey, we're having a meeting in the office tonight
at 10:00. You know, be there. Everyone's talking
about we got to make the product better. We got
to optimize this button and improve conversion.
Isn't the product the homes and the apartments?
Jobat said no product in the tech industry
is something different. I just said, listen,
let's get some older people who are hosts in here.
This whole story is a really good example of the
value of having folks that are older. When you
have older brains connecting the dots, younger
team members being really fast and focused, it's
brilliant. And people won't notice your wrinkles
as much as they'll notice your energy. The Airbnb
experience led you to starting something called
the modern elder academy. So if you think about
the caterpillar to butterfly journey, midlife is
the crystallis. Midlife is not crisis. I'm happier
today at 64 than I was at 47 when I was going
through my flatline experience. Well, let's back
up a little bit. This near-death experience today,
my guest is Chip Connelly. Chip is one of the
most extraordinary and interesting people that
you'll ever meet. He was a founding member of the
board of Burning Man. He was on the board of the
Eselin Institute in Big Su. At 26, he started a
hotel chain called Jadviv, which went on to become
the second largest boutique hotel chain in the US.
After selling it, Brian Chesy personally recruited
Chip to join Airbnb to help Brian and the company
transform from a fast growing startup to the
world's most valuable hospitality brand. After
leaving Airbnb, where he was known as the modern
elder, Chip started the Modern Elder Academy, now
known as MEA, the world's first midlife wisdom
school with large, sprawling, beautiful campuses
in Baja and Santa Fe. He's also written seven
books, given a TED talk, and is just a genuinely
interesting and amazing human and friend. In our
conversation, we explore how to be successful in
tech as you age. What he's learned working with
and for Brian Chesy, including a lot of real talk,
how to build a great culture at your company,
his near-death experience, and how it changed
the trajectory of his life, and so much more. If
you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe
and follow it in your favorite podcasting app or
YouTube. Also, if you become an annual subscriber
of my newsletter, you get a year free of a
bunch of incredible products, including Replet,
Lovable, Bolt, NAN, Linear, Superhum, Descript,
Whisper Flow, Gamar, Perplexity, Warp, Granola,
Magic Patterns, Raycast, JPRD, Mobin, and more.
Check it out at lennisnewsletter.com and click
bundle. With that, I bring you Chip Connelly.
This episode is brought to you by Great Question,
the all-in-one UX research platform loved by teams
at Brex, Canva, into it, and more. One of the
most common things I hear from PMs and founders
that I talk to is, "I know I should be speaking to
customers more, but I just don't have the time or
the tools." That's exactly the gap Great Question
fills. Great Question makes it easy for anyone
on your team, not just researchers, to recruit
participants, run interviews, send surveys, test
prototypes, and then share it all with powerful
video clips. It's everything you need to put your
customers at the center of your product decisions.
With a prompt as simple as, "Why did users choose
us over competitors?" Great question not only
reveals what your customers have already shared,
but it also makes it incredibly easy to ask them
in the moment for fresh insights from the right
segment. Picture this. Your roadmap's clear. Your
team's aligned. You're shipping with confidence,
and you're building exactly what your customers
need. Head to greatquest.com/lenny to get started.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta.
When it comes to ensuring your company has
top-notch security practices, things get
complicated fast. Now you can assess risk,
secure the trust of your customers, and automate
compliance for SOCK 2, ISO 27,01, HIPPA,
and more with a single platform, Vanta. Vanta's
marketleading trust management platform helps
you continuously monitor compliance alongside
reporting and tracking risk. Plus, you can
save hours by completing security questionnaires
with Vanta AI. Join thousands of global companies
that use Vanta to automate evidence collection,
unify risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go
to vanta.com/lenny. That's venta.com/lenny.
Chip, thank you so much for being here and welcome
to the podcast. Oh my god, Lenny. I I sort of feel
like I'm your father who's so proud of his son has
done. My son has done so well and I I like to talk
about tell all my friends about you. Wow. Uh I am
honored. Uh I'm happy that I'm making you proud,
Chip, and I feel I feel the same in reverse. Uh we
got to work together for many years at Airbnb. I
got to learn a ton from you. Uh I'm really excited
that more people are going to get to learn from
you from this conversation. I'm thinking that the
way that we break up this conversation is kind of
break it up into three parts which are kind of the
three arcs of your career and the three parts are
your uh early career building your time at Airbnb
where we got to work together and then talking
through what you're working on now the modern
elder academy I actually want to start with the
middle chapter I want to talk about Airbnb where
we got to work together let's paint a picture
of just what it was like for you to join Airbnb
in your 50s uh surround ed by a bunch of 20some
30somes reporting to Brian Jesy who is I don't
know in his 30s. What was that like? So yeah,
I I wasn't planning on doing this. I I got a call
uh from a woman named Natalie Tucci who worked at
Airbnb and said I we Brian Chesy and I have been
talking about having you come in and give a talk.
Are you open to that? And I was like well what
is Airbnb? This was uh 13 years ago. This was
I think it was the end of 2012 and then Brian
called me and said, "Listen, we really want
you to come in." And so I came in and gave a talk
about innovation and hospitality. And and I think
I I didn't realize it was sort of a a a dress
rehearsal for Brian to sort of see whether the
younger crowd there um I was 52, the average
age was 26 would, you know, feel good about,
you know, an old geyser like me with a bricks and
mortar boutique hotel background uh talking about
the industry that Airbnb was disrupting. Um, and
as it turns out, people liked me. And, um, so,
uh, Brian said, "I want you to come in for
and work 15 hours a week as a consultant. I
want you to be my in-house mentor for both me
and Joe and and Nate." And and I said, "Okay,
you know, 15 hours a week is great." And then,
uh, within three weeks, it was 15 hours a day.
And and Brian and I was saying to Brian, you
know, you're actually not paying me anything.
Um they he gave me uh a little bit of stock that
would would vest in six months and I said like I
don't know that this deal is working for me. Um
this is you you it seems like the company needs
me a little more than you said and and he said
yeah I got you. I just wanted you to get in here
and see like what you could do. And long story
short is I ended up going full-time and um it was
hard at first, Lenny, because I didn't understand
the tech lingo. I I didn't have any background.
I was 52. I'd never worked in a tech company
before. I was mentoring Brian on leadership,
but he was also my boss. I was the um head of
global hospitality and strategy. uh so which
mess meant initially I was in charge of all the
hosts in the world over time that like you know
that meant a lot more things too I I was involved
in mo many parts of the business definitely not
the technical parts but I think the hardest thing
for me is was just that initially when people were
talking about product and Joe said you know I'm
the chief product officer and I'm like well isn't
the product isn't the product the homes and the
apartments and Jobot said no product in the tech
industry is something different. And so I had to
be both wise and curious and often the dumbest
person in the room. And that was uh it required
me to have a certain amount of humility as well
as to be reporting to a guy 21 years younger
than me, Brian. That actually the point you're
making there about what is the product? I I
asked uh Laura Hughes, formerly Laura Modi,
what to talk to you about, who we got to work
together. She's the CEO of Bobby now. uh you work
closely with her at Airbnb and she said this was
the thing that stuck with her most about working
with you is coming in and and everyone's talking
about we got to make the product better. We got
to optimize this button and improve conversion
and product product and you're just like what is
like what is the product? I thought the product of
Airbnb was the hosts and the experiences and the
trips and I think that shows the value of someone
like you coming in with different experience and
also older and helping us communicate differently
to hosts who also don't understand. Well, there's
an interesting thing also, Lenny, and you you know
this, the difference in age between our hosts and
our guests was probably about 10 years maybe. And
over time, it actually got higher um because we
started actually reaching out more uh aggressively
to you know, boomers and and Gen Xers to be hosts.
And so you had I remember one point um and again,
let's get into product talk here. I remember one
point that there was a conversation that was going
on about taking Airbnb so it was mobile only. Um,
I mean, partly because back in the day, the two
sharing economy darlings were Uber and Airbnb. And
of course, Uber was pretty much a mobile only app.
And Airbnb started as non-mobile and then went
mobile. And then I was like, "Oh, wouldn't it be
interesting if everything was mobile?" And at some
point, I just said, "Listen, let's get some older
people who are hosts in here to see how well they
will be versed in in in managing their listing
purely on mobile." And so there were times where I
was a voice for older uh users in this case hosts
um that was helpful to you know guys and women in
their 20s who are the engineers and designers and
product managers and um I always liked working
with you. I want to just compliment Lenny um for
a minute. How sweet is that? because and we did a
lot, you know, we were we did a lot of different
things together. And what I appreciated was you
you had a humility to you that was different than
a lot of the other product managers. There's other
product managers, I'm not going to mention their
names, and there some of these some of these
product managers were very good. There were other
product managers though who I found it sometimes
hard to work with because they expected me to
know as much as they did. And you know, I guess
it would be the if the opposite side of that would
be um an older manager expecting a younger manager
to have as much emotional intelligence because
emotional intelligence on average is something
we get better at as we get older. So I think the
key for me to work in that environment and make
it work was to not pretend to know things I didn't
know. It was to have a sense of humor and humility
in how I operated. And it was to show respect
and hope that I got in return. And I don't know
if that you felt that way, Lenny. I, you know,
that's that's the try the kind of environment
I tried to to embody there. Absolutely. There's a
couple of threads there I want to follow. One is
just working for Brian. A lot of people talk about
founder mode and the power of founder mode. It's
so great. And guess who like you know populated
that recently? That was Brian. Exactly. Uh so it's
great to be in founder mode. It's not not as great
to be working for someone in founder mode. Often a
very challenging place to be. Yes. You reported
to Brian. Uh also you were just your own boss
basically your entire career. You never really had
to report to someone before. Also he was in his
30s, you're in your 50s. What was it like working
for Brian? Uh you know like the more real you can
be the better because a lot of people always talk
about here is like I was wonderful. I learned so
much. Just like what was that experience like?
What did you learn from working for someone like
Brian? Well, let's start with the fact that it
I would never have gone to work for Airbnb if
I didn't believe in Brian because quite frankly
when Brian approached me and we started talking
about I was like I wasn't sure I liked the the
business model all that well as a hotel year. So
I had to believe in something beyond the business
model because I wasn't sure that this the business
model would work. Although soon after joining I
saw the numbers I was like wow this is working
pretty well. But I believed in Brian because the
thing that Brian showed up with initially was
just a curiosity and an appetite for learning. You
know, I remember back in 2011 when the, you know,
the big debacle happened with um the the apartment
getting uh trashed by a guest and and so Brian
decided he was going to go to find, you know,
George Tennant, the the former head of the CIA.
And so like Jo Brian would go to experts and and
say to the expert, I don't know what the hell I'm
doing. And um he did that with me when it came to
hospitality. So I appreciated that a guy who had a
lot of hubris, and Brian definitely has a lot of
hubris, could also have the humility to to say,
I want to learn more about this. So it's sort of
a growth mindset. What was hard with Brian is I'd
say three things. Um, number one is Brian assumed
everybody else was going to work at the same pace
and duration, you know, and he still has this
issue. I mean, the beautiful thing about Brian
is he's been very honest in the last couple years
on podcasts about his workcoholism and about the
fact that the way he lives his life is not like
other people. But back when I joined, you know,
his point of view was like, hey, we're having a
meeting in the in the office tonight at 10:00,
you know, be there. It's like, really? No, I don't
I don't think so. But so so I think the the the
fact that Brian assumed everybody else was was as
one-dimensional in their focus as him was at times
a problem, especially for a guy like me who was
I was in a stage in my career where like I have
a lot of interests. Um, so that was one. Number
two is Brian admires and admired in back then
Steve Jobs so much that there was a sense that
as a guy who came from the product world uh from
the Rhode Island School of Design, he knew better
than anybody else. And so there was this you know
one of the challenges for a CEO sometimes and I
this was my experience in my 24 years of running
Viv, my boutique hotel company is it feels good
when you feel needed. Um, and to come into a room
and sort of see something and then point out the
things that are wrong makes you feel good. And
if you don't have emotional intelligence, you
can that process can really piss people off or
or demotiv demotivate people. And in Brian's
case, I didn't have to deal with that too much
because he didn't understand when I was starting.
It was really I was in charge of the hosts around
the world. And so quite frankly, the idea of
what's the psychology of the host? What's a host
entrepreneur like? I went on a world tour to 20
different cities and went and talked to hosts. And
I think I came back from that with a little bit of
credibility with Brian to say like, hey, you know,
yes, our data science team and the quality folks
were who are doing qualitative interviews, they're
getting something out of this, but I actually went
into the homes of these hosts in all around the
world. And and I think I I was lucky because Brian
did less of that than he did with other people.
But he for the for the product team, my god, I
mean, a product meeting with Brian would keep
people up the night before. uh not just because
they were actually working all night long to
get prepared, but also that they knew they would
work all night long because they probably wouldn't
sleep in anticipation for this. So that's that
was another issue for I'd say um I think the other
thing that you know that and and in each of these
cases I think Brian's getting better. So just
like Steve Jobs got better over time when he left
and then he came back, he was much better when he
came back from all the people I've talked with who
worked with him. I'd say the third thing for Brian
was the sense that adding a zero to something
in terms of expectations or thinking that you're
going to set a deadline that is unreasonable is
necessary because if you don't do that there's
an almost an underlying message that people won't
kick ass on their own. So there was a sense that
Brian had that he had to maybe create ridiculous
goals because even if we hit half of that goal,
it was very encouraging. What he missed in that
was the fact that when you miss a goal and when
you have someone who has power over you setting
the goal or encouraging a particular goal, you're
setting people up for, you know, a lot of stress.
And so at the end of the day, I think Brian is an,
you know, a generational leader for as a
millennial. Um, and I think he deserves a lot of
credit and Airbnb is as successful as it is partly
because of Brian's leadership and I would not have
been there without him. Having said that, I had
to hold my tongue in meetings sometimes uh when
I saw how he was operating because I wouldn't
have done it that way. And I think over time,
I hope I had a little bit of influence on him in
terms of how to apply some emotional intelligence
uh to leading people. For people in this position,
a lot of people work for founders, especially now
that founder mode is a thing. Every founder is
just like, I'm the founder. You got to do what
I tell you. It's founder mode. We're getting this
is how we win. We're in founder mode. You shared
really good insight of building credibility as
a really good lever to work better with someone
like that. Is there anything else you just think
as uh tactics to be effective with founders in
founder mode? So, if I knowing what I know now,
I would say Lenny, let's let's do a little pep
talk you and me before the meeting. I want you
to start the meeting with the following uh as as
you present and Brian's in the room. So, Brian,
let's talk about what we're trying to accomplish
here. Let's get really clear, and you probably
did this, but let's get really clear on what
um both what's the intention of this iteration
we're doing on the product, like what defines
success and what do I want to get accomplished in
this meeting? And you start with that because that
actually helps to make sure there's alignment. And
frankly, if there's not alignment, you might as
well not have the meeting. Let's spend the rest of
this meeting talking about alignment. That's what
I would do because that's something you can come
back to over and over again during the rest of the
meeting. When Brian or the founder, whomever it
is, is beating you up on something, saying like,
"Well, let me tell you why it looks like that
or why we're doing that." It goes back to that,
you know, the three principles or the three key
goals we're we're trying to do with this product
update. And um yeah, so so try to set alignment
on the front end. That's a that's an important
tip for anyone working with anyone even. So I love
I love just that that works especially well here.
And then just going back to the credibility piece,
I what you shared there is you went on this world
tour. Not something everyone can do, but just like
getting really close to your customers and using
that as a hey, I actually know what I'm talking
about. You actually should listen to me even
though you're the founder. Yeah. And don't and I
think the other thing is um PowerPoint or whatever
whatever tool you're using. I mean like just be
careful about being overly reliant upon it. It
just it's especially when you have a combustible
founder who may take you off path such that your
deck in its current order makes no sense at
all. So that I always wanted to really limit
the deck as much as possible because I didn't
know where the meeting was going to go and I
wanted the deck's helpful at the start at the very
start to just sort of set principles, set goals.
Um but yeah, so this whole story of you joining
Airbnb in your 50s is a really good example of of
uh c intergenerational collaboration, something
that you're big on just the value of having folks
that are older working at tech companies. Maybe
just talk about that broadly and then we segue
into other elements of your career. I wrote
a book called Wisdom at Work: The Making of
a Modern Elder after my Airbnb experience and um
I did a lot of research. I was like, "Wow, so why
do we have less intergenerational collaboration
in the workplace, especially in Silicon Valley,
than we could we could use?" And I started
interviewing people. Then I started talking to
brain scientists, neuroscientists, and realized
that a younger brain has fluid intelligence,
tends to be fast and focused, really good at
problem solving, uh, very good at linearity in
terms of looking at things. As you get older,
the brain shrinks a little bit and you have
crystallized intelligence. And in crystallized
intelligence, what's going on is your brain,
you're going from left brain to right brain more
adeptly. You're there's a little bit less focus, a
little more holistic thinking, systemic thinking,
connecting the dots. So you can imagine that on
a team in a you know when you have older brains
connecting the dots thinking broadly peripherally
younger team members being really fast and focused
and being able to think linearly how to get things
done. That combination can either be successful
or not. When it's successful it's brilliant. And
I think Laura, you know, Laura Modi, um, Laura
Hughes Modi, who was my director of hospitality,
but also we worked in so many different capacities
with her in the company. I loved working with her
because her brain worked different than my brain.
And um that's the opportunity is when you realize
that diversity on a team whether you know there's
lots of kinds of diversity but when it comes to
uh brain diversity not just with neurodeiverse
people but age diverse people you get a benefit
an effective benefit that is not as uh noticeable
quite frankly in some other diversities. Uh so I
found that over and over was really helpful. Part
of my job sometimes was to find the blind spot.
You know, again, if you are very focused, you
know, one of the things I said to Brian early on
um was, you know, I I've seen the business
plan now. I know the goals of how big we want
to be in three years. This was very early in my
tenure. I said, but what we really have done,
everything we're trying to do is to like have no
regulations and pay no occupancy tax. Now, hotels
pay a bed tax, occupancy tax. we're not paying it
and we're trying to do everything we can not to
pay it knowing that you know so for our listeners
and viewers to know this this is something that
a guest pays. It's not the host who pays it the
guest pays it. It's part of the bill. If you go
and stay in a hotel there's a big big tax part of
the bill. But it made us more affordable by not
having to pay tax have our guests pay taxes. Long
story short is I said to Brian if we're as big as
we're going to be three years from now I promise
you we're going to be regulated. I promise you,
we're gonna pay be paying occupancy taxes. So,
let's take some proactive steps toward building a
strategy for how we're going to be regulated. And
that's that has consistently been Airbnb's biggest
challenge is regulation in municipal markets
all around the world. If we'd started a little
earlier, maybe in New York, maybe in New York,
it wouldn't have gotten to the point where it
has been toxic in New York the whole for the last
dozen years um ever since I was there. And there's
a few other markets in the in the world where it
was like that. So, I would just say, you know,
um the value in in having some age diversity,
even when you have an older person reporting
to a younger person, is it can be collaborative.
There was a guy named John Q. Smith, uh, you know,
an engineer who you I think you probably remember
him, uh, uh, at at Airbnb. So, this is a guy who
looked younger than he was and was he was
a little bit nervous about PE like telling
people his age. But the thing that was great about
John is over time he was not necessarily going
to be the best coder uh, at Airbnb. There was a
whole new collection of coders coming in every,
you know, month. But he became a great manager.
And the beautiful thing about moving from the,
you know, individual contributor to the the
manager, the person who can actually bring
out the best in a bunch of younger people who may
be better technically than he or she is, but they
know how to elevate talent. I call this invisible
productivity. It's it's productivity in which you
make everybody else around you better. And that's
something I tried to do with my teams at Airbnb.
And ultimately I had six different teams, five
hospitality and five other teams reporting to
me. And I did my best to just be the kind of
person who wasn't solving all the problems,
but I was trying to elevate. There was a woman
named Lisa Deost who is at at Airbnb and she one
day I the HRE department was reporting to me at
one point and she was running HR. She was 25 and
had no background in HR at all. And one day she
came into me and she just said, "Chip, you are my
confidant." and Lisa Lisa has a French accent and
you know fluent in French and she said so she said
confidant in just the right way and and I said oh
well thank you Lisa but I said to her you haven't
given me any juicy details yet like a confidant
is someone who has the secrets and and she said
to me no in my in my part of France a confidant
is somebody who gives you confidence and it was
like oh well maybe that's what a mentor can be is
a confidant someone who gives gives you confidence
and helps by asking questions helps you as the
younger mentee find your road map to success.
So you're sharing a lot of really good examples
of the value of older folks being within tech
companies. So let me just ask you this. How how
real is agism in tech? And I ask because a lot of
people that are hiring are probably thinking,
"No, no, I'm not biased. I'm going to hire
the best person. If there's someone in their 50s,
I'll hire them. No problem." Doesn't feel like it
actually works out that way often. just how real
of a problem is this? What do you see? Yeah, it,
you know, it's clearly a problem. Um, I'd say it's
maybe a little bit less of a problem than it was a
dozen years ago because I think a dozen years ago
it was almost a blind spot. You know, in Airbnb,
we had a group called Wisdom at Airbnb. It was an
employee resource group for people 40 and older.
And so there are lots of these kinds of groups
that didn't exist a dozen years ago in all kinds
of tech companies, which is good because it
means that there's a there's a voice and a
way to congregate with a bunch of people who
are older. Ultimately, we had these senior we
had these senior nomads come in and be like the
voice of the customer for 10 weeks at Airbnb. And
it was the wisdom at Airbnb older employee group
that really actually pushed for this with Brian.
But the the challenge is in a world in which the
smartest new people especially when it comes to
technical skills and engineering are coming in
with a whole new you know uh set of skills that
an older person doesn't have. The the older person
is both expensive uh and may be perceived as slow.
So in the era of AI, it's a whole new ballgame and
the question I think will be if what AI cannot do
is the human wisdom piece, artificial intelligence
and and human wisdom might be the balance beams
here. Is it possible that older managers who
have a little more emotional intelligence, a
little more more pattern recognition, a little bit
more wisdom um can be a value to a company? And so
it's still the the jury still out. There's a New
York Times article that just came out about the
question of is AI going to wipe out older people's
jobs or younger people's jobs? And I think the
answer is both. But the the question is how much
how bad is it for both of them and um I think that
what I would say to an older person and when I say
older I mean what 45 or older if you've done well
financially and you're doing okay the question you
might ask yourself is are you open as I ultimately
was with Brian in my fourth year at Airbnb I took
a substantial pay cut like I think I went to down
to 40% or 50% time and my stock uh my you options
were dropped to that level. My salaries dropped to
that level because I didn't want to work full-time
anymore. And there are a lot of people who can be
valuable in a company who have some institutional
wisdom, some process knowledge of how to get
things done in this organization. And in tech
companies, that's really important. Um, Airbnb,
one of the biggest challenges at Airbnb has
always been how do I get [ __ ] done around here?
Um, and process knowledge allows you to understand
how do you how do you deal with an org chart and
get things done partly because you understand
the motivations of different groups and that
is something you build over time. So, long story
short is um I just think that uh you know older
people might look at their workload and say I'm
willing to take a 20% or a 40% pay cut to go to
80% or 60% time and the company is going to get
their money's worth in that. That's a really
interesting point that if you're older and you're
maybe less connected to the most cutting edge ways
of building and and coding, AI makes that a lot
easier in many ways where you start to just talk
to it. You don't even need to understand what's
happening underneath. Yeah. So, there's a lot of
listeners who are older in tech. There's a lot of
listeners who are approaching midlife, let's say,
worried about what happens to their career. When
you look at people you've worked with and had at
your academy, which we'll talk about, who continue
to thrive and continue to have a really healthy
career in tech, what do they do differently? What
do they do? What what do they have in common that
other folks you think should work on and focus
on? I think this this idea of being a mentor,
a mentor and an intern, this just the voracious
appetite for curiosity. When I talk to someone
who's in midlife and wants to be in the tech world
or already is, the thing I say is show up with
curiosity and a passionate engagement for what
you do. And people won't necessarily notice your
wrinkles as much as they'll notice your energy.
And energy has two parts to it. Uh energy is
they notice that you are not just sort of resting
on your laurels. You are you have like physical
you know energy in how you do your job. And when
people are like that, they are sort of timeless.
They are a they're age fluid, as I say. Um, we
talk about gender fluidity. Well, there could be
age fluidity. They they don't they're defined by
their age. But the other part of energies that's
important is being positive. You know, that's
sort of more energetic, like a little bit more
California energetic. There's a sense of like when
someone's got good energy, you're drawn to them.
So, it's about showing up with the kind of energy
of someone 10 or 20 years younger than you and
then showing up with positive energy. And I think
one of the things that I would say I did well at
I mean there's lots of things I didn't do well at
Airbnb, but in terms of what I did well is I was
very approachable. And over the course of time,
the number of mentees I had, the number of people
who just wanted to have coffee with me or tea,
the number of people who just said, "Thank you for
being in that meeting, you just sort of gave it
a positive feeling was really important." and and
um so my energy both the positive energy part and
then also the fact that yeah I I could work 60
and 70 hours a week and I could travel around
the world as the as the secretary of state of
the company which is what Brian called me a couple
times on the stage. The fact that I could do that
meant that no one was looking at me and saying
let's get rid of the old fogy. Uh well maybe some
people were but I wasn't aware of them. So, I just
think show up with that passionate engagement,
that curiosity, that energy, the ability to be
both the learner and the teacher with respect
for people that younger than you, and you're going
to probably do pretty well. That is really great
advice. Today's episode is brought to you by KOD.
I personally use KOD every single day to manage
my podcast and also to manage my community. It's
where I put the questions that I plan to ask every
guest that's coming on the podcast. It's where I
put my community resources. It's how I manage my
workflows. Here's how KOD can help you. Imagine
starting a project at work and your vision is
clear. You know exactly who's doing what and where
to find the data that you need to do your part.
In fact, you don't have to waste time searching
for anything because everything your team needs
from project trackers and OKRs to documents and
spreadsheets lives in one tab all in KOD. With
KOD's collaborative all-in-one workspace, you
get the flexibility of docs, the structure of
spreadsheets, the power of applications, and the
intelligence of AI, all in one easy to organize
tab. Like I mentioned earlier, I use KOD every
single day, and more than 50,000 teams trust KOD
to keep them more aligned and focused. If you're
a startup team looking to increase alignment and
agility, KOD can help you move from planning to
execution in record time. To try it for yourself,
go to kod.io/lenny. io/lenny today and get
6 months free of the team plan for startups.
That's cooda.io/lenny to get started for free and
get six months of the team plan. kod.io/lenny.
Interestingly, curiosity comes up a lot when
I ask AI forward people what are they focusing
on helping their kids learn most. Curiosity is the
most common way to describe. So, at every stage of
life, curiosity is uh some to cultivate. I want to
go to the flip side of companies looking to hire.
Feels like there's this uh untapped supply of
awesome people that companies with agism and tech
uh aren't finding and hiring. So to help hiring
managers and companies take advantage of this,
what's something you suggest they do? How do they
shift their mindset or maybe shift the way they
they hire that might help them find these people?
I think we're moving into there's a there's a book
that David Epste wrote called range and the whole
premise of range is that we are moving out of the
era of the specialists and into the era of the
generalists and I think AI is just accelerating
this um as we are more reliant upon AI and AI
can can be exceptional at technical skills and
solutions really expeditiously. I think
generalists, people who can think broadly
become all the more important. And I think that
what I would say to someone in HR or recruiting,
uh, is yet beyond what I already said before
is is the person passionate? Are they curious?
Are they a learner? Um, do they have good energy?
But I would also say, are they a generalist when
they're a problem solver? because I actually think
that's going to be an increasingly important part
of how effective companies think broadly. So I
think that's a key one. I think also this idea of
how do you create intergenerational collaboration
in the form of mutual mentorships. Um, one of the
things I I I loved at Airbnb with there were a
few people I did this with where I had something
to teach them and they had something to teach me.
So, um, good example, my iPhone. So, there's 97%
of the utility of my iPhone that I probably don't
use and don't know how to use. This is, you know,
back in, let's say, 2013, 2014. And so there
were people in who knew iPhone or Google suites
back then. I'd never used a Google doc back then
when I joined Airbnb. So there were people who
could teach me something technical and then they
wanted to learn something from me which would be
like how do you run a great meeting um or how
do you give a great employee review? you know,
there are a lot of managers who've never been
a manager before and and so how do you disperse
people like me in the organization so that you
don't you know there's usually not enough time
for these young managers to come to some training
session on how to do a good you know employee
review. So you sort of have to do it out there
in the field. It's like apprenticeship. You know,
back in the trades, you are you're an electrician
apprentice. Not because you're watching, you know,
some video on it. You're out there in the field
doing it. And and that's a huge value in a younger
company when you have some older people who
have not been vested with the responsibility
of managing those younger people because they may
have they may actually be reporting to someone
younger than them, but they're there to actually
be support. And um in some ways I think that was
part of the unexpected value that I was able to
offer to Airbnb and to Brian specifically because
there are a ton of people in Airbnb who were
not even in my departments who would come to me
and say I'm having a problem. How do I solve this?
Can we spend lunch together? And you know I almost
always said yes. I think the reason people did
that in many ways is you just have a very unique
aura of wisdom and it's hard to replicate that
chip. Yeah. I mean Yes. And it all comes back
to the curiosity. If I was just the older elder
dispensing wisdom, people would have gotten bored
very quickly. And I think the fact Yeah. Yeah.
I mean, I was on the board of Burning Man. Oh,
that's cool. And so there was a I I I I show up
as someone who feels younger than I am. I mean,
I'm turning 65 this year. So the bottom line is I
think people lost track of my age partly because I
lost track of my age. That's such a good such good
advice. So on the front end uh to be successful
as a person kind of getting older in tech is
curiosity, positive energy. the way you tal talked
about it passionate passionate uh engagement is
that the term? Yep. And then on the other side
is uh hired generalist. This actually comes up a
lot in in the AI conversation just exactly as you
said the power of generalist reminds me I'm I'm
going to this gym now and the lady there is just
like I love AI so much because I'm just such a big
picture person and I can so bad at just getting
thinking about the details and AI solves all that
for me. It's like here here's what I want to do.
I'll do this, move my house to here, here. And
it's like, here's what you need to do. Step one,
two, three, four, five. It is remarkable. I
mean, you know, since the time I've known you,
how fast it has become dominant in our lives. Uh,
but yeah, I think one of the last thing I'd say
is look, I'm privileged. So, for those of you who
are listening or watching this and you're saying,
well, you know, Chip, you were 52 years old and
they came to you. Like, that doesn't happen to
me. I'm not in that position. The thing I would
say is you're right. So I but I could have been
plucked and brought in and partly as as Brian's
boy, people would have like rejected me because
if I didn't show up the right way, it wouldn't
have worked well. Uh and there are lots of people
who Brian brought into the company who didn't work
well. So I think I think the key is how do you get
the foot in the door? And at the end of the day um
you know those second and third order of you know
uh degrees of separation um in terms of networking
is are still essential. But the most important
thing is to be able to articulate what you have
accomplished in a new way that a recruiter says
wow. And so I I really tell people like I
I would love to see a resume. First of all,
the question that uh I think it it was who was
someone asked it. I don't remember if it's Cheryl
Stanber or someone else asked her who said like
what's the biggest problem you're dealing with
here and how can I help you? Like that's a great
that's a great line. Number two is uh what I love
to see is not so much what roles you've had,
what bullet points do you have of your like
things you've learned. Give me in a paragraph a
a a thorny problem you faced. Um what what was
the problem and how you got how you what skills
you used to actually accomplish it and what was
the result of that. I would love to see a resume
like that. And the older you are, the more you
can actually have a resume like that. And then you
can use that as the conversation piece when you're
doing interview your interviews. So, I love that.
I love that we're getting into interview advice
and resume advice. Yes. Um, speaking of throwing
problems and also uh why Brian decided to reach
out to you, I want to go back to the beginning
of your career. Yes. So, you're good at this,
by the way. You're good at this. was thinking
ahead. Okay, so you're in business school. You
left business school. You decid you're like maybe
I should start a hotel. Uh something that rarely
works out usually probably leads to a lot of
money lost and a lot of frustration and just
like okay what have I done with my life worked
out for you? Ended up building the second largest
boutique hotel chain in the world. Uh beloved uh
I I I loved every single experience I've had at
when you sold it. I was like that is so sad. Talk
about just that that story. Uh, I know this could
go on for hours, but what's the Yeah, I'll be I'll
be brief. Yeah. 26 years old, couple years out of
Stanford Business School, working for commercial
real estate developer. I was bored silly. I wanted
to do something more creative. Bill Graham,
famous concert promoter, said to me, you know,
because I gotten to know him, what San Francisco
really needs is a rock and roll hotel. So, I
decided to start looking to to find a broken down
motel hotel that I could turn into a rock and roll
hotel. and I found something in the Tenderloin uh
and uh and turned it into the Phoenix which became
a famous rock and roll hotel that I have owned
for 39 years now. Um so long story short is that
was how I started in the company and we grew to 52
hotels around California became the second largest
as you said in the in the world uh in terms of the
number of hotels boutique hotels that we operated
and I loved it till I hated it in my late 40s.
I hated it. Didn't want to do it anymore. I was,
you know, the Great Recession came along and it
was just kicking my ass. And I really went through
a bit of a what I now call a midlife cryis, uh,
but a midlife crisis, um, where I just wanted to
change everything. And, um, I got through it. Uh,
I had an NDE, had a near-death experience where I
had an allergic reaction to an antibiotic
and I died. And from that point forward,
I realized every day is a a gift and a bonus.
and um uh you know I decided to sell my company
at the bottom of the great recession. So that's
so that was really how I created this space in
my life to be able to join Airbnb. Well, let's
back up a little bit. This near-death experience
uh share more there what happened there. Yeah,
I was uh so I write books. have written seven
or eight books and I had written a book called
Peak uh how great companies get their mojo from
Maslo and it was a book that Brian really liked
and part of the reason he he wanted to reach out
to me. Um I was on a book tour. I had a broken
ankle. Uh broke my ankle at a bachelor party
uh playing baseball and um I ended up with a cut
on my leg and um the cut on my leg had fertilizer
in it and went septic and so I was on a very
strong antibiotic and I died. I went flatline
from the allergic reaction to the antibiotic and
so I saw you know I it happened nine times over 90
minutes. I kept dying, kept flatlining and yeah,
ended up in the hospital for a couple three days
and they finally said, "Listen, it's an allergic
reaction. We believe they thought it was I thought
they thought it was a heart attack. Thought a
bunch of stuff, stroke, etc." No, it was the
allergic reaction. So, but you know, I saw birds.
I mean, I saw all this beautiful stuff. I We don't
have time to go into it. What? I did. You want to
hear this? Yeah. No, I saw this beautiful stuff.
the the best I think there's a hotel in San
Francisco called the Vitali that I built
um across the street from the ferry building and
it's still there but it's no longer called the
Vitali. Um in that hotel there were these slippers
in every guest room. One slipper said slow,
the other slipper said down. Um, and so I was
wearing these slippers in my flatline thing, uh,
flying in in the air in a 40 foot tall living room
in the Alps, surrounded by birds that were twer
tweeting and and chirping at me. And I understood
bird talk. I understand I understood exactly what
they were saying. And they kept telling me, "If
you slow down, you will see beauty and you will
see awe." And there was a bunch of other things,
but let me just limit it to that and just say,
and then the birds would like say, "It's time to
go." And the birds would go out the big window,
you know, into the mountains, and I would try
to follow them. And right as I would get to the
window, all of a sudden, I'd come back to life.
Holy [ __ ] Uh, I love that this was uh like
there was a message inside of this experience.
I don't know how many people experienced that.
Clearly, this led to a big life change. And it's
interesting that a lot of times you need something
like that. Like you've been doing this for how
many years at that point running? Uh, at that
point I've been running for 22 years and 22 years.
And it's interesting that you need something like
that a lot of times otherwise it just momentum
just keeps carrying you forward. Yep. within
two years I'd sold it and you know I had had
the chance to move on. So with building Juvary
something you've written about a number of times
is just the way you built it as a really unique
approach to building a business. Specifically
there's a huge focus on culture which also
came out at Airbnb. Talk about just why you see
culture as such an important part of how you build
a business like tangibly because a lot of people
talk about culture warm fuzzy stuff but you think
about it very tangibly. Culture is what happens
around here when the boss is not around. Um and
and the more distributed a company, the more
culture is important because the boss is around
in a traditional bricks and mortar workplace
where everybody shows up at 8 and leaves at 6
and we all see each other. But uh at in my company
in Aviv, we had 52 hotels and 25 restaurants and
four spas and it was distributed. So I couldn't
be in all those places all the time. And same
similarly with Airbnb. I mean Airbnb had offices
around the world and was it was a global company.
So the more distributed you are, of course, in the
remote work world we live in, the more culture is
important and more difficult because the when
you're remote, you know, there's these few
cues you have about how we do things around here
and they're usually in a digital virtual format,
which is why, you know, it's all the more
important for you to have in-person gatherings
of a team more often if you are virtual. So at the
end of the day, the reason culture is important is
because it actually helps it helps guide people
in terms of making decisions, but it's also a
magnet for the right kind of people. So Oracle
has a different, you know, culture than Apple,
which has a different culture than Facebook. And
so you can choose the place you're going to work
based upon the culture. And there are people who
can be very good at what they do, but if they're
in the wrong culture, they're in the wrong kind
of environment and they're not willing to shift
to fit that culture. And we saw it at Airbnb all
over and over again. Uh in in fact, Airbnb saw it,
I think, when with Amazon people. Um Apple
people have resonated pretty well at at at
Airbnb. Amazon people less so. And those are two
different cultures, Amazon and and Apple. And that
therefore understanding a culture before you even
actually take the job is one of the more important
decisions you need to make is like is this
culture a culture that I can live with? Um and
maybe influence. Um there's language about culture
fit. I like to say culture ad because culture fit
to me means can actually be quite negative toward
somebody who is the aberration. Um you have to fit
in and especially if this is like a demographic
thing, a person of color, a gay person, a you
know a person in a wheelchair. So you have to fit
in. But a culture ad suggests that actually having
some diversity on the team is helpful because it
actually adds to the culture. But that's still
h you still have to be able to get along in that
culture. So culture is an intangible. That's the
problem with it is it's hard to measure but you
see its value and you understand whether it's
working based upon p you know employee pulse
reports and things like that. You talk about
having to understand a culture is such a key part
of having success at a company. Do you have any
advice for just how to understand that culture
for someone interviewing? I don't know like you
know you came in you work part-time it's easier
to experience it all any tips there for like
okay this is for me this not for me when you're
interviewing you're you're also interviewing them
when you're interviewing it's not about you having
to prove yourself it's also for them to actually
prove themselves as a company and also try to
understand if there is um some alignment in the
company and so the kind of questions I would
ask as someone who's being interviewed would
be what are three to five adjectives that define
this culture. What's the biggest problem in this
culture in terms of something that's just endemic
or like baked in across the organization and is it
ever going to get fixed and how could I come in
and maybe help that? Uh which frankly at a very
junior level you're not going to be able to help
it. Uh except for in very minor ways. If you're
a senior person you might be able to help it. Um,
so those are those are the kind of questions I'd
want to know. And frankly, if I'm asking that same
question about what are the adjectives to multiple
people, am I hearing the same thing over and
over again? Um, and if I'm not, is that because
there's not alignment, is that because different
departments have different flavors? Um, because
you can have a culture within a department that's
very different than the overall corporate culture.
The corporate culture certainly has an enormous
oppressive uh influence, but uh you know you can
you can you can be in a culture uh a really great
culture of a team or a department in an overall
company culture that's not good. In the long run,
that oppressive company culture is either going to
have to evolve or your department may be you may
lose people. When I reflect back on one of the on
the impact you had at Airbnb, one of the funny
uh things I think about is uh triangles showing
up a lot on decks uh and specifically rooted in
Maslo's hierarchy. Just like everything's this
Maslo hierarchy metaphor. True. Um, and this one
uh I don't know specific piece of this is you have
this kind of model you think about for how to help
employees be successful at a company. It's kind of
rooted in your peak book uh philosophy. Maybe just
talk about that and then if there's anything else
you want to expand on with this power of thinking
through the Masow hierarchy. So you know Maslo's
hierarchy basically five levels. Later in life he
had a seven and an eight level model. But you know
uh at the base is you know physical uh you know
the kind of physical water, food, air and you move
up to self-actualization at the top. Um so to use
this model as a hierarchy of needs for employees,
customers and investors is what the peak model
is about. uh the the you know the peak uh my book
um the employee model is really simple. It's money
or compensation at the base um recognition in the
middle and meaning at the top. Now there are some
industries and some kinds of jobs in which money
is 90% of the pyramid. So just because it's at
the base doesn't mean it's not the dominant part
of the pyramid. But the differentiation often is
in recognition and meaning in nonprofits. It's
usually the money piece of it's rather thin and
the recognition's this and meaning is huge. So I
so understanding how do you create an organization
and and I gave a TED talk in 2010 about this topic
as well. Um how do you create a how do you
measure the intangibles uh of meaning and how
do you create an environment where people feel a
sense of meaning? Um the customer pyramid briefly,
I'll just say that one is meeting expectations
is the base, meeting desires is in the middle
and then meeting unrecognized needs. And I think
one of the things that we did at Airbnb about a
year after I joined and when Jonathan Mildenhal
was joining is we really tried to ask ourselves,
are we in the home sharing business or are we
in some kind of business that is even bigger and
broader than that? And ultimately we we came up
with the idea that we were in the belong anywhere
business. Airbnb was not in home sharing. We
were in belonging anywhere. So once you have that
uh down that was sort of the unrecognized need
at the top of the pyramid. Then that becomes an
organizing principle for how do you teach your
hosts to create a sense of belonging? um how do
our how does our marketing and advertising play up
the belonging piece especially and the everywhere
piece because hotels are not everywhere but
homes are and so I would just say that you
know this model the idea of hierarchies is I
think very helpful um and uh yeah my book peak
is has been out for 18 years but I still am asked
to give 20 or 30 speeches a year on it oh man this
uh this pyramid of comp recognition meaning is
really interesting Especially these days because
uh like with all this AI uh researcher poaching,
there's all this talk of just like it will people
just go work wherever the you know they get they
get the most money or is there a mission and and
meaning to the work they're doing that will keep
them not taking a hundred million dollar offer
and seems to be happening a lot of cases which
shows you the power of meaning. Yeah. I mean,
if you know you're working for a toxic company,
at some point your conscience kicks in. Whether
it's toxic in terms of the purpose of the company,
toxic in terms of the leadership or the culture.
Um, yeah. Life is too short. Okay. So, you've had
two major shifts in your career. You started the
hotel chain, you went to then you went to Airbnb.
Most recently, the Airbnb experience, I imagine,
led you to starting something in the called
the Modern Elder Academy. talk about what is
the modern elder academy. Yeah. What is going
on with that modern elder academy? The modern
elder academy. So there was a couple times where
I was called the modern elder at Airbnb. And then
I was told that a modern elder is someone who's as
curious as they are wise. So uh Jonathan Mildenhal
who was the chief marketing officer at at Airbnb
used to call me the modern elder as well. And when
he and he said like if you ever create a school
you you know modern modern elder would be a good
name. And so we talked about it and next thing
I knew I was like saying okay this is called the
modern elder academy. We now call it MEA because
elder is a fraught word on some level. It makes
you sound elderly. But um what I really wanted to
create was a place where people could come and do
a workshop. you you know they're fiveday workshops
um in Baja on the beach or in Santa Fe on a big
four square mile uh horse ranch and reimagine and
repurpose yourself and navigate transitions. We
go through so many transitions in the middle of
our life. Let's say between I I define midlife
as 35 to 75 guys. So like this is it's a very
it's a very long life stage. So we go through
a lot of transitions. We are constantly evolving
our purpose. We're building our wisdom. You know,
we have knowledge management tools out there, but
where are the wisdom management tools? Where are
the tools that help us to get wiser over time?
And then we need to reframe our relationship with
getting older because Becca Levy has shown at Yale
that when you shift your mindset on aging from a
negative to a positive, you get seven and a half
years of additional life, which is more life than
any other biohack that's being done right now.
So that's what we do. and we have 7,000 grads
from 60 countries and 56 regional chapters around
the world. So, it's a bit of a movement. And um I
teach I I teach some of the workshops and we have
all kinds of famous people who come and teach. And
for me, creating the world's first midlife wisdom
school just feels like the the natural next thing
for me to do. I I love hospitality so it's a
very upscale kind of experience, but we have
scholarships. I love um retreat centers. I was on
the board of the Eselin Institute in Big Surf for
10 years. I love wellness. I've owned the Kabuki
Springs and Spa for 28 years um which is the
largest spa in San Francisco. And I love education
and my book wisdom at work the making of a modern
elder gave me a curriculum in which we've expanded
quite a bit with uh Harvard, Yale, Stanford and UC
Berkeley professors helping us a great greater
curriculum around midlife. Um and so that's how
MEA came about. Uh to your point I forget who said
I think you said Jonathan has said this was the
natural next step for you. I completely agree.
It's like looking back this is the obvious thing
you should be doing right now. Yeah. Uh, also I'm
learning more things about you. I didn't know you
were involved with the Kabuki Spa. I think Esel
and I knew just keep getting more interested.
Thank you. There's a couple threads here I want
to actually follow. So this point you made about
shifting your mindset to aging is a positive
thing. Makes you helps you live longer. That's
such a powerful point. Can you just speak more
to that? Just what does that look like? Yeah,
there's a couple there's lots of data points.
I'm just I'll talk about two. One is this Becca
Levy study which has been going on for 15 to 20
years. If you sort of take buy into the agism of
American society or Hallmark cards when you get a
a a card at age 40, 50 or beyond, there's a belief
that life gets worse as you get older. And um and
if you can survive your midlife crisis, all you
have to look forward to is disease, decrepitude,
and death. And the bottom line is uh you know,
there's a lot of things that get better with age.
I wrote a book called Learning to Love Midlife.
The subtitle says it all. 12 reasons why life gets
better with age. And what I really wanted to do
with that book, which is really it it summarizes
the MEA curriculum. I wanted to write a book that
sort of helped people to see the upside of aging,
the unexpected pleasures of aging. Uh so they had
a pro-aging, not just an anti-aging point of view.
Because when you actually have a pro-agging point
of view, and you see the upside of aging, you take
better care of yourself, both your mind and your
body, you actually are willing to learn and try
new things. One of my favorite MEA questions is 10
years from now, what will you regret if you don't
learn it or do it now? It's a powerful question,
really important question as we get older. When
you're young, you know, you've got all, you know,
all of your life left ahead of you. But when
I moved to Baja part-time in Mexico at age 56,
um I had a mindset which was I'm too old to learn
Spanish. I'm too old to learn to surf. But when I
said 10 years from now, what will I regret if I
don't learn it or do it now? And I said, well,
10 years from now, I might still be living in
Baja, like I should learn this. I should learn
Spanish. I should learn how to surf because we're
right next to a surf break. And so I did. Um,
so what I believe is that anticipated regret
is a form of wisdom. And so and it's a catalyst
for taking action. So that's one data point. The
other data point is something called the U curve
of happiness and it's been around for 20 years and
it shows the following. It has changed in the last
couple years because young adults are h unhappy
like never before. So a 20 or a 22 year old really
unhappy, 24y old really unhappy. But historically
the way it was is you were happy from 18 to 23 or
24 and then around 23 24 you start to see a long
slow decline in life satisfaction that actually
uh bottoms out between 45 and 50. I'm sorry
to tell you that Lenny since you're 44. Um
but your mileage may vary. So you're saying
I'm the least happy I'll ever be. Like that's
only upside. That's great. Yeah. Well, here's
the part that's weird is that when before this
re research was done, and it's global research
across all demographics, what they found was
uh starting around age 50 or 52, you get happier.
So that you're happier in your 50s than your 40s,
60s 50s, 70s happier than 60s, and women
in their 80s happier than 70s. So, wow.
And it's partly because we are in around 45 to
50 doing this thing called the um the midlife
unraveling. What Bnee Brown calls the midlife
unraveling. You're unraveling your expectations,
your uh what you define as success. Uh your
definition of you what a beautiful body looks like
and you get some you're liberated into freedom in
your 50s and beyond. And uh I can say that yeah,
I'm happier today at 64 than I was at 47 when I
was going through my flatline experience and not
wanting to run my company anymore. You used this
term earlier, the midlife cryales. Was that what
it was? Or chrysalis. Crystis. Chrysalis. What is
that? Is that kind of along the same lines? So if
you think about the caterpillar to butterfly
journey, midlife is the chrysalis. It's that
cocoon in which all of the change is happening. at
the time, you know, when you're going through it,
it's like, oh [ __ ] my life my life is liquefying
in front of myself, but you know, on the other
side of it, there's a metamorphosis that happens.
And so uh I I like to use the language and in fact
I have a podcast called the midlife crystis
um because I want to help you know change the
dialogue around midlife so that the number one
word attached to midlife is not crisis um but in
fact it's maybe cryis and the idea that um life is
meant to be transformative uh during that era that
is actually very empowering I am sort of going
through that not necessarily in this intense way
yet but that might be You said there's a bunch
of upsides to being getting older. It might be
helpful just to share a couple of those things for
folks that are like, "Oh, wow. I didn't realize
that." Emotional intelligence grows with age. Um,
our wisdom can grow with age, although we know 70
year olds who are not as wise as 30-year-olds.
So, it's a matter of what you do with your
life experience. I define wisdom as metabolized
experience mindfully shared for the common good.
Uh, what else gets better with age? You learn how
to edit. you can't you you have no more Fs left
to give, no more effects left to give there. That
is absolutely true, especially for women as they
age. You are more spiritually curious. Uh you're
um I mean the list is long and and so there are
a lot of things that actually another one that
I don't love is you're not compartmentalized.
When you're younger, you're compartmentalized.
As you go grow older, you are growing whole.
And that means you're alchemizing curiosity and
wisdom, introvert, extrovert, masculine, feminine,
gravitas, depth and levity, lightness. And the
people who I really admire who are 85 years old,
they're so present and they are so whole. They
are like they are just who they are. There's
a quote I found from you along these lines. The
societal narrative on aging is just don't do it.
Yeah. there. I mean, we sort of say like we want
we don't want to age, but we do want to live. And
quite frankly, aging and living are the same thing
as are aging and growing. Coming back to MEA,
just for folks that are like interested, curious
about this, who's this for, would you say,
who should seriously look into this program? MEA
is really the people who tend to come to MA are in
a midst of a transition. It could be uh selling
their company, leaving a job, getting divorced,
um having kids, um becoming an empty neester,
taking care of parents till they're passing away,
having a health diagnosis. That's scary. So
average age is 54 and it's people of all walks
of life. Uh so it's not just the tech industry,
but a lot, you know, it's very popular in the
tech industry. Um it's people who are looking to
maybe do a reframe of their purpose uh and maybe
even a reinvention of their career and so yeah and
and the two campuses are just gorgeous. Uh they
it's been called the Four Seasons meets Blue Zones
meets the Elon Institute which I like. Um, and uh,
we don't we have online programs, too. And so you
don't have to come to either of our campuses in
Mexico or on the beach or in uh, New Mexico. Uh,
you can actually do it online. Those three. Yeah,
that's the tagline. That's your tagline right
there. Esselin meets Blue Zones meets what was
the first one? The Four Seasons. The Four Seasons.
Yeah. Nailed it. Okay, I'm going to zoom out and
take us to a recurring segment on this podcast. I
want to see if this goes anywhere. Uh AI corner.
And with AI Corner, ask guests just what's a way
that you've found AI useful in your work or in
your life. Any kind of trick you've learned, any
workflow, anything you found useful. Yeah, you
know, I I have a daily blog. It's called Wisdom
Well, and it's on the MBA website. And um when
I'm looking for inspiration, you know, AI does it
for me. And ultimately, it gives me a first draft.
And that's good enough for me then to say like,
okay, because there's times when I'm like missing
the inspiration. I tend to write really well in
the morning. If it's any other time of the day,
I do not like writing creatively. Um so if I have
a deadline for tomorrow and it's five o'clock in
the afternoon, it's like, "Okay, chat GBT. I'm on
my way to you." And I I tend to use chat GBT the
most because I don't know. I mean I like Claude as
well, but um yeah. Okay, awesome. I was going to
ask which tool you use uh and what's your workflow
there? Is it you use voice mode? Do you just kind
of type out here's what I'm thinking about? Write
me a little drop blog post. The good news is that
at this point, uh it knows me well enough and
my and my blogs and I've actually, you know,
it it it knows my my sort of weird sense of humor.
Uh so it's able to ape me pretty well. So, I'll
just say I need a 250word post on um like today,
you know, today's post was a post that chat GBT
helped me with it. I said, I believe that there's
a a a reframe that needs to happen with soul. We
tend to say like I have a soul or I don't have
a soul, but what if this my soul has me? um what
if in fact my job is just to be this vehicle for
my soul to go to the next lifetime and my so my
job is to be this steward of the soul and I said
write me something around that and so it's just a
weird idea and of course my not all my blog posts
are so new age and and uh like that I I I write a
lot on leadership but that was one that you know
within you know 30 seconds I had a 250word you
blog post that I then adapted. And there you
go. Amazing. Chip, we've covered a lot of
ground. We've gone through your entire life. Maybe
actually just the tip of the iceberg. With that,
we've reached our very exciting lightning round.
I've got five questions for you. Are you ready?
Yes. Let's do it. First question. What are two or
three books that you find yourself recommending
most to other people? My favorite book of all
time, Man's Search for Meaning, Victor Frankle, uh
in a concentration camp in World uh World War II.
when someone's going through a hard time in their
life, I say, "Read that book. You'll realize it's
not so bad what you're going through." Yeah. Um,
but it also really speaks to this idea of despair
equals suffering minus meaning. I wrote a book
uh called Emotional Equations that was a New York
Times bestseller that spoke to this idea that what
if you could take all of your emotions and turn
them into equations. Very engineering-minded of
me. Um, so that's one. Um I you know I love uh any
book by Liz Gilbert. Um sort of the opposite. So
Elizabeth Gilbert wrote E Pray Love. Her her book
she's a she's on faculty at MEA. She teaches here.
Um uh Big Magic is just a beautiful book about
sort of like how do you get in the flow to allow
the genie to come through you. um her TED talk in
2009 was about the fact that genius is not about
being the genius yourself. It's about being the
receptacle for the genie to come through you. I
want to come back to this uh equation you shared.
I was going to get to it but I didn't. So this is
a good opportunity to So there's a couple that
are really interesting to me. This is you wrote
about these in a book. You have a bunch of these
equations about living a happier life. So the one
you shared is despair equals suffering minus
meaning. Yes. And so the implication there is
if you want less despair increase the meaning.
That's right. So suffering suffering the sort of
Buddhist philosophy number the first noble truth
of Buddhism is that suffering is ever present.
And so if suffering is a constant and you have
two variables uh using some algebra I guess um
you know that uh if you have more meaning you
have less suffering. And so that's that one.
The other one that I love is anxiety equals
uncertainty times powerlessness. Maybe talk about
that one briefly. 98% of anxiety comes from two
sources. One is what you don't know and number two
is what you can't control or influence and based
upon social science. And so um you can create an
anxiety balance sheet and you know create four
columns. First column is what is it you do know
about this thing that's making you anxious? The
second column is what is it you don't know. The
third column is what is it you can control or
influence. And the fourth column is what is it you
can't control or influence. And when you take free
floating anxiety and put it into uh a an equation,
it actually makes it more tangible and you often
are less anxious as a result. Boom. Okay. So,
if you're feeling anxious right now, this is an
exercise you can do and you'll feel less anxious
in like five minutes is what I'm Okay. Excellent.
Very, very good nugget of advice. Okay. Let's keep
going with the lightning round. come back from our
tangent. Do you have a favorite recent movie or TV
show you've really enjoyed? I mean, Ted Lasso is
I'm like a sucker for for for that show. You know,
when it comes to movies, I'm a total movie buff.
I I we have an annual MEA film festival uh at our
Santa Fe campus. Um and I would say that the film
that I'm most excited about that is coming out
um that most people have never heard of is called
I'll Push You. And it's the story of two guys,
one of whom is uh in a degenerative health
condition and in a wheelchair and his best
friend pushes him the 500 miles of the Camino
de Santiago and it's the relationship they
build along that way. Amazing. Very deep cut.
Do you have a favorite product that you recently
discovered that you really love? Yes. Hair growing
material. No. Um, you know, uh, Viori shorts I I,
you know, I sound like Scott Galloway because
he t he advertises this, but Viori shorts are
like I just love them. You know, they're just
breathe and they're comfortable. I'm wearing the
Yori uh joggers right now. Uh, the one downside
of Yori, not to make anyone mad, is they're not
like very they're kind of plasticky if you look
at the material. So, I'm trying to like I don't
know. Yeah. But I do love There's nothing better.
That's the problem. I have done anything else like
this that isn't all cotton. Yeah. Yes. But I'm
a fan. I have many Vori. I don't know if they're
called chuggers. Just I don't know, weekenders
or something. Anyway, love you, Vori. Okay. Do
you have a favorite life motto that you often come
back to and find really useful in work or in life?
I imagine you have many, but is there one that
comes to mind? I mean, my favorite one right now
is your painful life lessons are the raw material
for your future wisdom. And the the premise of
that is that wisdom often comes through the school
of hard knocks. So when you're in the midst of
a really, you know, challenging time, you're
developing your future wisdom that's going to be
valuable to you. Okay. Final question. You were on
the board of Burning Man or you still are. Uh it
was for us. I I helped found the board of Burning
Man. Yeah. Okay. No big deal. So I don't know if
you know this. I got married at Burning Man. We
had a unofficial wedding there on bicycles. So,
it's really meaningful to us. I've been there
four or five times. Uh, what's something about
Biringham that maybe people don't know some
insight story or a really unexpected piece of
this the journey? I may imagine there's a lot, but
what comes to I would say the best not well-known
thing about Burning Man is that Burning Man owns
a place called Fly Ranch and Fly Ranch is about 10
miles from Burning Man. Now, if when you go to the
burn, uh the event in, you know, around Labor Day,
uh you cannot go over there, it's it's it's locked
off. It's 3,400 acres. But if you do, if you look
at Fly Ranch, um fly ranch.org, I think it might
even be or it's on the Burning Man site. Fly Ranch
is like the opposite of Burning Man. Burning Man
is this alkaline desert. Like there's no no living
life there at all. It's very masculine. Fly Ranch
is like porous and and like lots of like desert
grasses and hot springs and hot pools and it and
birds and wild horses and it's one of my favorite
hot springs places in the world. Um so just check
it out and you can go there when it's not during
the event and and it's it's quite beautiful. Feels
like it might have inspired uh MEA in many ways.
It didn't. Yes. Chip, two final questions. Where
can folks find you online and how can listeners be
useful to you? So online, meowisdom.com is the
website for MEA. My website's chipconley.com,
co- ny. And uh I'm on LinkedIn. That's
really from a social media perspective,
the thing that I do the most. I actually take
my daily blogs and put them on LinkedIn. So,
and then what the what the your community can do,
just Yeah. Come say hi. come uh check me out. And
if wisdom is interesting to you, and I think
wisdom should be interesting to everybody here,
um on the MEA website at the very bottom footer,
you will see a bunch of free resources. One of
them is called Why Successful Leaders Value
Wisdom. It is a free resource. Um and there
there's also a free resource down there called the
Anatomy of a Transition. Those two free resources,
understanding how to build your TQ, your
transitional intelligence and understanding
how to develop wisdom are two, to my mind, two
of the most important modern skills that we can
have. It's funny when you say you're on LinkedIn.
It feels doesn't resonate with me. You can chip
conly on LinkedIn posting on LinkedIn. So, I don't
know why because I'm a little too Burning Man.
You're just Yeah, exactly. It feels like that's
not your vibe. But I love that you do it because
that's where the people are. Oh, I I put wild
weird stuff up on LinkedIn and you know, thank
thank God somebody's doing that. I got for some
reason I don't see it. I need to fix that. Chip,
this was incredible. Everything I was hoping
it'd be, thank you so much for being here and
for sharing your wisdom. I am so proud as I go
back like I'm your proud papa who just loves to
see you in your element. And I just want to say
make sure everybody knows the following. Lenny
was so good to work with. I really when whenever
you were assigned to a pro uh project as a PM,
I appreciated it because I just knew that we were
gonna have great conversations and you're you're
just an interesting dude. Well, I appreciate
that, Chip. That's going to be the beginning
of this whole episode. We're just going to put
that up front. Just kidding. That was awesome,
Chip. Really appreciate it. Uh and thanks everyone
for listening. Bye, everyone. Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennispodcast.com. See you in the next episode.