I think you see in the team at Linear
that a lot of people don't see,
which is that there's not actually a
trade-off between speed and quality.
People talk about this as if there were a
trade-off because when they think about speed,
the thing they over-index on is rushing or being
sloppy. What they should be indexing on is being
really competent. If you look at people who
are at the pinnacle of their craft, you can
basically tell how good the output is going to be
of their work product by how fast they're going.
What does speed look like when you say
it can be done quickly and high quality?
What it really looks like is you have some
rough time budget for how long you think
something's going to take. By the time
10% of it has passed, after week one,
you have something that works that tests
some kind of key hypothesis internally.
I imagine a criticism you all get. Over time,
you'll probably become a bloated
piece of software as well.
When we examine this problem, we look at, "Well,
what feature requests can we debate and what kind
of feature requests do we absolutely have to say
no to?" The stuff that we absolutely have to say
no to is the exact kind of thing that leads to
this bloatedness that makes ICs hate their lives.
Something that your head of sales shared with
me is how impressed he is with the way you
ask questions on customer calls and just keep
digging and digging until you get to something.
My goal is to feel bad in the
same way that customers feel bad.
Today, my guest is Nan Yu. Nan is Head of Product
at Linear, which is one of the most beloved,
most beautifully designed, and also the fastest
growing B2B SaaS product out there today. You
rarely see the kind of love that people have for
Linear for any enterprise B2B SaaS product. So,
there is a lot that we can learn from how
Linear operates and how they build product.
In my conversation with Nan, he shares a system
that he uses for being creative and coming up with
non-obvious solutions to customer problems,
why it's a red flag to him when PMs tell him
there's a trade-off between speed and quality,
how he talks to customers in order to figure
out the emotion that they want to avoid and then
figure out the solution to avoiding that emotion,
plus some killer advice on how to land a job,
including how he landed his job at Linear and
his previous role at Mode, and so much more.
If you have a desire to build a company or a
product that's as beloved as Linear, this episode
will give you a ton of tactics and ways to change
how you and your team operate. If you enjoy
this podcast, don't forget to subscribe and
follow it in your favorite podcasting app or
YouTube. It's the best way to avoid missing
feature episodes, and it helps the podcast
tremendously. With that, I bring you Nan Yu.
This episode is brought to you by Sinch, the
Customer Communications Cloud. Here's the
thing about digital customer communications.
Whether you're sending marketing campaigns,
verification codes or account alerts, you need
them to reach users reliably. That's where Sinch
comes in. Over 150,000 businesses, including 8
of the top 10 largest tech companies globally
use Sinch's API to build messaging, email,
and calling into their products, and there's
something big happening in messaging that product
teams to know about, Rich Communication Services,
or RCS. Think of RCS as SMS 2.0. Instead
of getting texts from a random number,
your users will see your verified company name
and logo without needing to download anything
new. It's a more secure and branded experience.
Plus you get features like interactive carousels
and suggested replies, and here's why this
matters. US carriers are starting to adopt
RCS. Sinch is already helping major brands send
RCS messages around the world, and they're helping
Lenny's Podcast listeners get registered
first before the rush hits the US market.
Learn more and get started at sinch.com/lenny.
That's S-I-N-C-H.com/lenny. This episode is
brought to you by Paragon, the integration
infrastructure for B2B SaaS companies. Is
AI on your 2025 product roadmap? Whether you
need to enable RAG with your users' external
data like Google Drive files, Gong transcripts
or Jira tickets, or build AI agents that can
automate work across your users' other
tools. Integrations are the foundation,
but building all these integrations in-house will
cost you years of engineering, time you don't have
given the fast pace of AI. That's where Paragon's
all-in-one integration platform comes in. Build
scalable workflows to ingest all of your users'
external data into your RAG pipelines and leverage
ActionKit, their latest product, to instantly give
your AI agents access to over 100 integrations
and thousands of third party actions with a single
API call. Leading AI companies like AI21, You.com,
11x, and coffee.ai are already shipping new
integrations seven times faster with Paragon,
keeping their engineers focused on core product
development. Ready to accelerate your AI roadmap
this year? Visit useparagon.com/lenny to get
a free MVP of your next product integration.
Nan, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Thanks for having me. I'm a long-time listener
and reader, so it's really a treat to be here.
I want to share something with you to kick
off that I haven't shared with you yet,
that I haven't shared with anyone. These
results might have come out by the time
this podcast comes out, but I'm running
a survey right now that I'm calling,
"What's in your stack?" Where all my subscribers
are asked, "What tools do you use most day to
day? What tools do you love most? What tools do
you hate?" And one of the questions asked was,
what tool do you wish you could switch to
if your IT department allowed you to? The
number one answer by far is people
want to switch from Jira to Linear.
Wow. I mean, hopefully, that
means we're doing a good job.
I think that's exactly what that means. I'll
read a couple quotes to give you a sense of what
people are saying about Linear. I doubt these are
surprising to you, but this gives people a sense
of why you're here and why I'm excited to extract
as much wisdom as I can from you. So, a couple
quotes here. "Linear is a joy to use as I interact
with my engineering teams, and I find inspiration
in its design." "Linear is simple to use, yet
powerful." "Linear's design is obviously an
industry benchmark, but moreover, the performance
and speed is a massive productivity boost."
I mean, it's really good to hear that because
in a lot of ways, that's what we're trying to
do. If you think about the entire impetus
behind why Linear was started, it's because
Karri was sitting at Coinbase and Airbnb and
these places and just watching everyone around
him struggle using the tools that they had
available and always incumbent tools and just
seeing that it made people hate their day-to-day
a little bit, and we all got into technology and
design and engineering, all this kind of stuff
because it was fun. All of us started off building
stupid MySpace pages and all of these side
projects when we were young, and it started
off as this fun thing that we do, and we're like,
"Wow, we get to do this for a career," and then
to have all of this kind of stuff put these big
speed bumps into our day-to-day workflow, it just
was really sad. So, that's why we started
Linear. This really bust through all of that.
What I love about Linear, I feel like it's an
inspirational business because many people want
to, "I'm going to build just a much better version
of something," and often that doesn't actually
work out. Often nobody cares enough. There's all
these barriers and reasons. People don't switch to
something that's better, and Linear is an amazing
example of building an excellent product and
actually succeeding, and there's a lot more to it
maybe than just building an awesome product. So,
that's what I'm excited to dig into and understand
how you all operate, and I guess just based on
these results, to me, this is the ultimate
sign of product market fit. People being sad
they can't use a product in B2B enterprise
software especially, so let's get into it.
First question I want to get into is something
that I think you see and the team at Linear
sees that a lot of people don't see, which is
that there's not actually a trade-off between
speed and quality. I think a lot of people think
this is just an innate fact and something I've
heard you talk about is that's not actually
true. I actually saw Patrick Collison tweet
this exact point that I'll read after you...
I want to hear your thoughts, but talk about
what you've learned about how there's maybe not
actually this trade-off between speed and quality.
People talk about this as if there were
a trade-off almost in a naive way because
when they think about speed, the thing they
over index on is rushing or being sloppy,
and what they should be indexing on is being
really competent or being like an expert. So,
if you look at people who are at the pinnacle of
their craft, it could be anything. It could be
like a chef or a programmer or someone building
houses or something. You can basically tell how
good the output is going to be of their work
product by how fast they're going. If they're
going really fast, and they're obviously not being
sloppy and then leaving a mess all over the place,
it's like, "Yeah. Well, they got there because
this is just second nature to them," and they're
able to go at a really rapid pace and try stuff.
And when we're building software, that's such
a big component of how good the product is on
the other side of it, which is like, "How many
iterations were you able to do?" So, the only way
you're going to get a bunch of iterations done and
try different things and really feel out these
different variations is by just going very fast.
In terms of speed, is the speed there
moving quickly on each of iterations?
Like what does speed look like when you say,
"It can be done quickly and high
quality"? What does speed look like?
Speed... What it really looks like is you have
some rough time budget for how long you think
something's going to take, and by the time 10%
of it has passed, you have a workable solution.
It's not like, "Oh, at the halfway point, we have
something that is maybe a candidate that we can
play around with." It's like, no, no, no. After
week one you have something that works that tests
some kind of key hypothesis internally so that
you can feel like is this thing actually panning
out the way we expect it to or did we have some
crazy incorrect assumption? And you don't want
to wait until you're 80% done to be able to make
that kind of judgment because then it's just too
late. Then you're pushing deadlines out, and
you're making your marketing team very sad.
Amazing. Okay, so the way you think is,
"We're going to spend a month on this
feature. Let's get something workable.
We can start testing with potential
users even internally in the first few
days, essentially in the first week"?
Yes. Yeah.
Yeah. I guess how can you do that?
Because most teams can't do that.
Most teams need to research, design, build. "Okay,
cool. We have something," and once a
month later, what allows you to do that?
Yeah, I mean, there's a lot of components of it.
I think having really good talent really helps.
Having engineers who don't get blocked by every
single little design choice, they're happy to
just make something workable. Even if they don't
feel comfortable with that particular solution,
they'll just bust through it and make something
happen there. Part of it is intent. We don't have
any expectation that the first version of it is
going to be great. That is not in the cards. Look,
the first version of it is our best guess
in the general direction of what we want
to actually ship in the end, and sometimes
it works out. Sometimes, it's like, "Wow,
this first version was pretty good.
Let's make some minor adjustments,
and we're good to go," but there's no expectation
there. So, no one feels like they have to be a
perfectionist and get everything, like all
sanded down and really in tip-top shape.
It just has to work and get the job done and
validate or invalidate our major assumptions.
I'll read this quote from Patrick Collison.
He tweeted this today as I was preparing for
this interview, and he's the CEO and founder of
Stripe, if you're not familiar. His tweet is,
"I increasingly believe that 'good, cheap, fast
-- choose two' maxim is devious misinformation
spread by the slow. In my experience,
slow and expensive usually go together."
Yeah, exactly. I mean, use the contractor kind of
example. Like If someone's making modifications to
their house, and it's taking forever, one, you're
in a hotel and also the bills are adding up.
The other example you used when we were
chatting about this earlier is chess
players. I'm thinking of Magnus Carlsen,
watching him. I think he was number one
in speed chess in addition to just regular
chess and what a microcosm of this point.
Yeah, I think that's the case and
Magnus and Hikaru and all those
guys who are at the top of their game,
they can go unbelievably fast. In fact,
that's the usual... I mean, I don't want
to get too out of my depth with chess,
but the usual way you try to make the game
fair is you give them much, much less time
than someone who's not quite as strong of a
player, and they'll still win a lot of time, too.
So, maybe just to close out this point and give
someone something concrete they can do with this
information, say they want to start moving faster
while not cutting quality, what do you think they
can do? What's one thing they can start trying
to work on and improving in the way they operate?
I think it's really that sort of attitude
and point of view question to understand and
take the almost controlled risk that the first
version of this is not going to be perfect. So,
it actually makes it a lot cheaper in many ways.
It means you don't need a pixel perfect design.
It means you don't need to make sure that all
of the little UI bugs and stuff like that are
solved because none of that really matters.
What matters is you have working software
that you can interact with, and you can see
if it feels good. Does it actually solve the
core problem that is facing our users? You
can take it back to users. You can even let
them into an early beta or something like
that and get real validation there and to
really focus on getting the smallest, shippable
element, like not shippable in the sense of,
"I can actually put on the production," but in the
sense of like, "I can start learning from here."
Just a question I imagine is in everyone's
mind is what do you do with this first very
ugly V1... not ugly, not fully ready,
first version. Is this something you're
using internally to see if it's something? Is
it something you have beta design partners with?
We have a gradually increasing sort of circle
of users that use every single feature. So,
by the time it hits GA, by the time it gets
released, it's been used by a lot of different
users up to that point. So, the first circle is
just internal users. We use Linear every single
day to write software and do our own work, so we
have that kind of advantage and then once we feel
like it's good enough, we'll put it into some
beta customer group, and again, as early as we
can in the process. We have to make sure that
we don't end up corrupting people's data, and
it doesn't look hideous and that kind of stuff,
but as long as it reaches that level of quality,
we can release it to early access customers who
can give us good feedback and also just try to
solve their problems with it. If no one engages
with it, if no one's using it, then that's a good
signal that we didn't really hit the mark, and
then we have a couple of different beta audiences
that we grow and then the ultimate release
obviously is for GA where everyone gets it.
That's an amazing answer. Okay, so secret
number one to Linear success, I'm going to
take some notes here, is get new feature, product
ideas out to people as early as possible, say,
in the first 10% of the amount of time you've
allotted, and then release it increasingly to
more and more people to get feedback. I think
the implication here is just most wasted time
is on building things nobody actually ends up
wanting or using. So, the sooner you at least
get directional sense of are you heading
in a good direction, the faster it all go?
Yeah, totally.
I imagine a criticism you all get. People are
like, "Yes, Linear is so great, so beautiful,
so much better than what's been out there for
decades," but over time you'll probably become
a bloated piece of software as well. That's
just the fate of enterprise software. You
have to check all these checkboxes. IT teams need
all these features. So, there's always this like,
"Oh, yeah, sure, you guys can operate this way
for now. You have an amazing product for now,
but it'll get ugly and bloated." How do
you think about avoiding that? I know it's
something you spent a lot of time thinking
about. Maybe give us a glimpse into some of
the conversations you have internally when
there's these feature requests like, "Oh,
I need single sign-on with this thing and this
button here." How do you think about what to add,
what not to add, and how to add these
features to not make it bloated?
This question actually comes to us a lot from
candidates that are interviewing with us. When you
go like, "Hey, do you have any questions for us?"
This is the question that we're going to get. So,
we hear it quite a lot, and it's very sensible
for them to ask it because they see history being
littered with the corpses of startups trying
to compete in this space and not making it,
and I think when we examine this problem, we
look at, "Well, what kind of feature requests
can we debate and what kind of feature requests
do we absolutely have to say no to?" And the
stuff that we absolutely have to say no to is
also the exact kind of thing that leads to this
bloatedness that makes ICs hate their lives,
and it's very specific. It's customization
features requested by middle managers in
order to make reporting a little bit easier
at the cost of making IC workflows worse.
It's like if it fits that description,
we're just saying, "No." There's no debate
because we've already thought about it and
this is the thing that we can't take a single
step down this path. So, I think that's honestly
one of the core promises of Linear is that we
will not make this particular trade-off. So,
when you see people saying like, "Wow, Linear is
so much faster. It's so much easier to use and it
makes my work so much more enjoyable." This is
the reason because we have not taken a single step
in this direction. It's very easy for a PM to say
yes to this kind of request because often they're
talking with buyers. Any kind of B2B type of
space, they're talking with whoever the gatekeeper
is and sales is putting pressure on them, and
they're saying like, "Hey, we really want this one
feature. It's going to make our reporting nicer."
So, the director's going to be really excited by
this, and we'll definitely make a buying decision
based off of this, and we have to convince them
that this is a false trade-off. The whole premise
is wrong because the moment you start going down
this path, and you make the IC user experience
worse, they're just going to disengage. No one
has to do this. If I'm an engineer, I get paid to
write code. My performance review is based on my
code contribution. It's not based on like,
"Did I fill in all the tickets right?" So,
I'm just not going to do that part, or
I'm going to do it very sporadically,
and then I'm going to just focus on my actual job.
And then all your reporting is wrong because all
the data is wrong, and it's sparse, and you get
situations where people will... They'll say like,
"Well, here's a dropdown field that someone put
in here that's required." There's nine choices.
I don't know what any of them meet, so I'm just
going to pick one at random. I'm still going to
pick the first one. Also, I'm going to pray that
my boss is not actually using this data to do any
kind of reporting and that has consequence because
the data can't possibly be correct. So, I think
for us, it's a very easy decision when it comes
to that particular category of feature request.
I love how simple and clear that is. Basically,
you all have a policy. We'll prioritize ICs over
middle managers. Especially, like I love that it's
around reporting. Almost always it sounds
like, "I want to track what's happening."
Yeah, exactly. It's always, "I want
to track what's happening." Well,
what do you want to track? Well, I want
to track which version of the product
this thing's tied to based on some field
information. It's like, okay, how is the
person working on this supposed to even know that
information? Well, it takes like a five-minute
scavenger hunt every single time. It's like,
"I don't think they're going to do that, man."
What I imagine happens, and I think
why this is hard for most companies
is there's an implication that you're turning
down deals. You're not adding that one feature
that will close a massive million-dollar
sale, very difficult to do. I imagine it
helps a lot that... I imagine the COO is
very bought into this and there's this,
"We will win long-term holding
the line on this." Is that right?
So, it is, but I also think that there's not
as much pressure as you would expect to do
these kinds of things. There are basic scaling
things, like we had to make SAML and SCIM and
that kind of stuff. It's like, "Yeah, sure, we're
going to do those sorts of, like keep the lights
on type of work," but when it comes to work
that's related to the actual business logic of
the app's value proposition, what buyers
care about is, is this going to make their
team more effective? That's the reason that
they're making this buying decision in the
first place is that they're like, "Well,
the current situation we're in... " And
especially with large companies, right?
The current situation we're in is a mess,
and if we can convince them that these types of
things are actually the reason that it's a mess,
then we can really navigate them out
of wanting them in the first place.
Got it. So, there's an element
of you think you need this,
but it turns out you'll be more successful
and get everything you want, not getting this?
Yeah, and the thing is, it's not everything
you want, right? Because people come with a
laundry list, and it's like laundry list.
Here's 10 things I want. You're like,
"Do you want all of those 10 things equally?"
They're like, "No, actually I don't." The first
three are the things that really matter to us. If
we solve the first three, then the other stuff,
we can negotiate on. So, our job is to solve
the first three-way better than anybody else
that if they got through the first three through
some kind of visual programming, customization
type of thing, that it's never going
to get to the quality level and the
depth that we're able to offer by
offering those as native features.
It's interesting thinking back to that survey
I shared where the tool people want to switch
to if IT allowed them was Linear, and
on the one hand you could argue, "Well,
okay, IT is not letting them use Linear for all
these reasons. On the other hand, you guys are
growing really quickly within enterprise, like
you're a new business. You started, I think,
mid-market startups, and now you're working
way up. So, I think it's not fair to say it's
not going to work in enterprise. It's clearly
working really well. I don't know if there's
any stats you can share anything of that, but
it seems to be going well, expanding up market.
Yeah, I mean, growth has been good. Growth in
enterprise has been leading the other segments
because I think this year, especially we reached
a tipping point where I think with software,
so much of the buying decision is
based on almost like a brand thing,
like is this for us? A lot of times people
pick "enterprise software." It's like,
"Why? You know everyone doesn't want this,"
and they're like, "Yeah, but it's for us."
You won't get fired for
buying Microsoft or whatever.
Yeah, exactly, and I think that we're starting to
have enough brand penetration amongst enterprises
where people can have that feeling, right? They're
like, "Hey, Linear is for us. Who are we? Well,
we are a large company that wants
to act like a startup." It's like,
"Who doesn't want that? Who
doesn't want to go fast?"
Yeah. I had Jeffrey Moore on the podcast,
and this is exactly what crossing the chasm
looks like. He talked about basically you
need someone that's across the chasm like a
later adopter that isn't the person that's, "I
love new stuff, and I'm an early adopter kind
of evangelist." You need someone that's like
traditional old school, takes their time to
start to adopt it for you to be like, "Oh, okay.
Now, maybe I should really take it seriously."
I also think that with this particular category
of tool, and with a lot of other B2B software,
not... Like no means not now, right?
Not right now because it doesn't fit
our budget. It doesn't fit our
change management situation. "Oh,
we have this exec that's really wedded to this
other tool," but those things change, right? So,
we keep in contact with them. They're in our CRM
where we make sure we follow up, and we've had
a lot of these where we've been said no to,
like two years ago, and now we have some new
features, and then go like, "Oh, yeah, it seems
like you're ready for our scale," or whatever.
You mentioned that when you have these
debates and questions that come out,
you have features that a big company wants.
There's this category of, "We know we will
not build things for middle managers that want
reporting and custom stuff just to track what's
happening," versus something an IC wants to be
more productive and successful, Linear. Give us
a little sense of some of the more complicated
debates that aren't necessarily in that bucket.
I think the complicated debates are often
when we do add a new native feature,
do we extend an existing feature and make
it more powerful or do we add a new sort
of service? And a big part of that is trying
to figure out exactly who's going to use it,
what are the actual real life use cases that
we know about? Like that I know that Bob from
Company X has this workflow and this is
how it would work for him. Here are the
different variations where it would work. So,
tying it all the way back to real people is-
Like a specific person?
Yeah, specific person. Yeah. Yeah,
exactly. Not a hypothetical person.
Not one that you made up like Alice, Bob, or
whatever. It's like, "No, here's the first name,
last name. Here's their email. You can ask them,"
and I think that being able to tie it all the way
back to reality in that way is a big part of how
we really think about and discuss these things.
This connects the way I think about my
newsletter is I always try to answer
the question a very specific,
like a person actually asked,
not a general sense of something people may be
interested in, and that very specific question,
like it implies there's a need. Like not
implies, it proves there's at least one
person who needs this thing versus you have
this idea of somebody that may want this thing.
Yeah. I think a trap that a lot of times PMs
will fall into is they'll make something,
and they'll make some choices in it because maybe
it's beautiful or it's elegant, but they don't
go the step of like, "Is reality also beautiful
and elegant?" Because reality is ugly sometimes,
and if you have a beautiful and elegant
solution that doesn't match with reality,
it doesn't really matter. People can
look at it, and they can ooh and ah,
but if they don't use it to get their work done,
it's never going to have long-term staying power.
Do you have a heuristic of how often
you need to hear something for you to...
could be just convinced, this is worth
investing in? People may hear this, "Oh,
one Bob. Bob wants this featured."
That doesn't make sense. It's just
one guy. How do you know when it's like,
"Okay, we should really invest in this"?
Part of it is you hear something, and you're like,
"Gosh, that actually is... " Not only is that
true. It means that the way we thought about this
was a little bit wrong, and I call this process...
I don't know if it's the right way to describe
it. I call it a kneeling where you have a thing,
and it's not quite the right shape,
and you put it out into the wild. So,
this happens way in the first bit of the life
of a particular feature. You release a thing,
and then you start getting feedback about
it, about hey, it doesn't quite fit reality,
and then you ask yourself like, "Did we test that
aspect of it? Did we actually match that part to
reality?" And if you didn't, then it's like that's
the part where you don't actually need that many
pieces of feedback against it. It's not really
a volume thing. It's like, "Did we think about
this right or wrong?" That's one sort of category.
Another category is just you're getting a request
for maybe a very big feature or a feature set from
a lot of different people, but then you dig in,
and you try to say like, "Okay. Well, tell me
about how you're trying to use this," and there's
100 different use cases. So, you have choices
here. You can either build the big feature that
covers all the long tail of use cases or you
can try to see if there's really concentrated
pools of use cases for this that really make a
lot of sense to adopt as a first order type of
feature. So, I think those are the two sort of
strategies that we employ the most. It's like,
"Did we think about this wrong? And now we're
just learning something about how it matches
reality or for this big general feature that
people are asking for, are there actually more
specific use cases that we should be solving,
and we should be solving really, really well?"
A thread that's coming through so far across
a lot of these examples is getting to the
specific person using the thing and making them
happy and making sure the ask is going to solve
their actual problem. In the case of looking at
the IC versus the middle manager, in this case,
it's like, "Let's talk to the person actually
asking for this thing," not, "There's like 100
people generally asking for this thing and let's
build what we think is a general solution."
Yeah. I'll give you an example of all of
these things, which we just launched a
feature called Customer Requests, and basically
what this does, it adds a new concept of Linear,
which is a customer. For B2B companies, this
is very relevant, and the reason we did this
is because we kept getting this request for
fully customized fields, and we would be like,
"Well, what is it that you want with your custom
fields?" Because the problem is you add 100 custom
fields and all your ICs start hating it. So, we
don't want to go down that path, but what is it
actually you're trying to do? And 40% of them were
because, "Well, I have a customer," like Walmart
or whatever, right? Like, "Walmart asked for
this feature, and it's really important. I need
everyone to know that Walmart needs this. I need
to track it. I need to see how have we report... "
We can report on what have we done for Walmart
over the past year so that when my CSM has a
one-on-one conversation with a rep, they can have
some kind of evidence that we've been doing stuff
for them, like all this kind of stuff. We're
like, "Okay. Cool." That sounds like a very
useful and powerful thing you want to do. How
do you expect people to tag these things? Well,
manually, because that's how we did it in our
spreadsheets. It's like, "Okay, instead of that,
we're going to hook up with your customer support
tools. We're going to hook up with your CRNs.
We're going to automatically bring in feedback
from these companies. We're going to analyze the
emails where they're from, and then if someone
requests a feature that gets escalated into
engineering, it'll just be tagged with whoever
asked for it. You don't have to do anything,
but you will know, and you can still report
on this stuff, but there's nothing about
this that makes ICs lives harder.
In fact, it makes them feel more
confident because when they're building the
thing, they actually understand who's asking
for it and exactly what the email said. So,
when they're doing the design or the details,
they can actually see the real-life use cases
that are present and solve for those directly.
As I'm hearing this, it's like, "Okay, obviously,
this seems like an obvious solution. Of course,
40% of people telling me they have customers."
In reality, most of the time, if you hear from
a bunch of your customers, "Hey, I need this
custom field," and sometimes you hear one thing,
sometimes you hear another. Most of the
time you're going to build this custom
field. Something that your head of sales shared
with me is how impressed he is with the way you
ask questions on customer calls and just keep
digging and digging until you get to something
that is an insight for you, and then you start
to try to solve the problem for them and think
about what the product might be, and I think
this is such an important and underappreciated
skill for PMs. Is there any advice you
could share of just how you approach this,
how you ask questions, how you think about
these customer calls to get to, "Okay, now,
I see what we need to build versus let's
just build what they're asking for"?
It's funny because I think from the outside, I'm
on these sales calls and then the AE or someone's
watching me ask these questions, and I think
often they're like, "What are you doing? You're
just asking questions from angles that I don't
even know what your goal is here," and my goal
is to feel bad in the same way that customers feel
bad. They come to us with a request, "Hey, we want
X," and it's like there's something motivating it
and you can do the normal analytical thing and be
like, "Ask five whys," and try to figure out like,
"Well, what are your goals?" "And as a persona X,
I want to achieve this outcome." You can do it
that way, but you might miss the reason that they
actually feel bad for not having this thing like,
"I can't accomplish this goal. So what?" "So,
I'm not going to get promoted at work."
Okay, great. I understand the severity of
your problem at this point. What is the actual
emotional valence that is motivating whatever
you're telling me? And it takes a little while
to get there. You can ask people directly like,
"How do you feel?" And they're not necessarily
going to tell you, but if you have a long enough
and deep enough conversation with them, you
start to level with them, and you're starting
to see stuff from their perspective, and the
more you see it from their perspective and the
more they know that, the more they're willing
to open up to you and tell you like, "Okay,
honestly, I had this thing happen where
I marked the ship date of this project as
December 30th because it's a Q4 project,
and I wanted to put it at the very end,
and then my marketing team lost their mind
because they're like, 'We can't ship something
on December 30th. Everyone's on vacation,'"
and you're like... And then they're like,
"Yeah, this has made me feel really bad."
So, I don't ever want to put dates on things
ever again. So, like, "Okay, cool. We can help
you deal with that. If that's what you're feeling,
then I can start building stuff to make sure that
you never have to have that bad feeling again."
People talk about empathy like, "You need to
have empathy as a PM. You need to build empathy
the best product leaders, have empathy in this."
I think it's such a succinct and powerful way of
describing what empathy actually looks like as a
product leader, which is I want to feel as bad as
they feel in hearing the story they tell, and it
sounds like the way you do that is you keep asking
questions to understand the moment they felt
bad about something. In this case, the deadline.
And if you ask somebody in that last story, like
what kind of issue do you have? You're like,
"Oh, marketing and I would just never align on
anything." It's like that doesn't really tell
you what's going on. What it tells you is you had
this terrible moment of communication that it's
all miscommunicated, and you're like, "It's just
going to keep happening over and over again." So,
the thing that we did specifically to solve this
was on projects in Linear, you can just specify
a target date at whatever level of granularity
you want. You can say it's a December project.
You can say it's a Q4 project. You can say it's a
second half of 2024 project. Like whatever you're
happy promising, you can just put it on there and
that way you never feel like you have to give this
sense of false precision so that it ends up with
a whole bunch of miscommunication down the line.
I could see why people love Linear is it just
makes them feel less bad less often. There's
a lot of connection here. I know this idea
of emotions and feeling bad is a core part
of how you think about building product,
looking for moments. People feel bad. Is
there anything more you could share there
to share how you think about this idea of
emotional hooks, emotional moments,
and how you decide what to build?
So, to set the background of this, I've worked
in very, very competitive industries. I worked
at Everlane, which was a direct-to-consumer
clothing brand. I worked in Mode,
which is like BI tools and there's so many
BI tools out there, and then obviously,
Linear. We're project management. There's a
lot of project management tools, and I think
the more competitive your industry is, the
more the low-hanging goal-oriented stuff is
already picked because every PM from every one
of these companies has been asking like, "Well,
what's your goal? What is your job to be
done," and all this kind of stuff. So,
you have to look at things from an angle that
other people might not have seen and for me,
and for us, it's the angle of where are the
emotional hooks that you're experiencing as
you go through your work day, as you use our
product, as you use competitors' products?
I think it's probably underexplored because...
I don't know. I feel like PMs and engineers,
we're like very thinky people. We avoid the
touchy-feely stuff. So, I think that's the
opportunity. You can see where are you feeling bad
throughout your day where you don't even know? You
might think, "I hate Mondays." "Why do you hate
Mondays?" "Well, on Mondays, I have to go out
and gather a whole bunch of stuff to write this
report that it's really annoying." "Oh, so if I
gave you a button that made the report, would
that help?" It's like, "Oh, yeah, then I might
not hate Monday so much." So, I think Paul Graham
has a word for this. He calls it schlep blindness,
right? It's like I'm schlepping through life, and
I'm just completely blind to it, and it's true.
You have to have an outsider come in and see what
the rhythm of your feelings are throughout the
day, throughout the week, and you note the spots
where you could really use a lot of improvement.
Is there an example? I've shared a couple,
but just where you've noticed this in someone
using maybe a competitor or even Linear that
you solved. I know you gave an example of
the dates. I guess is there anything else?
A big feature that people love about Linear is
we have this thing called Triage Management,
and what it does is it systemizes this thing
where if I put an issue into a different team,
if I'm asking them to do something or I'm
reporting a bug to them, it sticks in a
special zone where it'll notify the right people.
They're on a rotation and people will be able to
respond to it in an organized manner, and I think
this kind of automation, this feature, it came
out of two different fields people were having.
One, people were trying to implement this stuff
by hand, and it was just a lot of touches, and
they were doing it, but they felt like, "Oh, I'm
totally underwater." "Why are you under water?"
"Well, I have to throw all these tickets around
and route them correctly and stuff like that," and
they didn't see this as an opportunity to have a
tool specialize in managing their triage queue.
Because they were managing by hand.... They
were on top of it, but it just felt really
bad because they just had to spend so much
attention doing this and then there's the folks
who didn't do that. The feeling was just like,
"Well, it's totally out of control. People
are just throwing tickets over the wall, and
I don't know what to do with them. I don't know
where they are. They end up in all these holes
and then the people on the other side are like,
"I throw tickets over the wall. I have no idea
what happens to them. I have no expectation that
people are ever going to respond to them." So,
there's all of these bad feelings that people
are having. They all have the same root cause,
which is like there wasn't a very automated
organized way to deal with your triage queue.
Marketers, I know that you love TLDRs. So, let
me get right to the point. Wix Studio gives you
everything you need to cater to any client at any
scale, all in one place. Here's how your workflow
could look. Scale content with dynamic pages
and reusable assets effortlessly. Fast-track
projects with built-in marketing integrations
like Meta, CAPI, Zapier, Google Ads, and more.
A-B test landing pages in days, not weeks with
intuitive design tools. Connect to tracking and
analytics tools like Google Analytics and Semrush,
and capture key business events without the hassle
of manual setup. Manage all your client's social
media and communications from a unified dashboard,
then create schedule and post content across all
their channels. If you're on content-rich sites,
Wix Studio's no-code CMS lets you build and
manage without touching the design. And when
you're ready for more, Wix Studio grows with you.
Add your own code, create custom integrations with
Wix-made APIs, or leverage robust native
business solutions. Drive real client
growth with Wix Studio. Go to wixstudio.com.
I'm going to try to summarize some of the secrets
of Linear's success so far. So, the first is
get something out as quickly as possible, say,
in the first 10% of the time that you have to
build this thing and get it out to internal users
and then maybe a growing list of beta users
and people that are aware of they're using
early stuff. Two is prioritize the IC and the
user, basically, versus the buyer or the middle
manager that wants reporting and all these custom
features. So, it's basically focused on the user,
which I think you hear a lot, but I love this very
specific example. Three is when you hear asks for
features and requests, get to the specific
person using the thing, not just general,
"Okay, cool. I've heard it 100 times." Find
the person that actually needs this thing and
understand what's going on, and then four is look
for people feeling bad in a moment working in the
product. Is there anything else that I'm missing
that's important or any nuance you want to add?
The part where you said, like focus on the user,
I think it's maybe a little bit more subtle than
that. There's a nuance which is find where the
incentives are really misaligned amongst your
user base. There's a middle manager that wants
really detailed reporting and there's a IC who
just really doesn't want to go through all those
extra steps, and the incentives for what they want
are just very... They're just very misaligned, and
you have to find those situations and be pretty
judicious about how you make those trade-offs and
where you can really find win-win outcomes there.
That's a really important nuance. Something else
that's come through a couple of times as you've
been talking is also something Patrick Collison
tweeted once that has stuck with me, which is
this idea of having a mental model in your head
of the user. So, the way he described it and the
way you've described it is oftentimes people are
like, "Cool. We're going to figure out what to
build. We're going to do a bunch of research,
talk to users. That'll inform what we build,
and we build it, versus what you've been saying
and what he said is you do a bunch of research,
look at data, talk to people. That informs
your mental model of what the customer needs
in their life, and then that informs what you
build. So, that anytime you do more research,
talk to customers, it's informing your view
of the person, and then you're like, "Oh,
this was different from what I imagined,"
or, "Oh wow. This is exactly what we've
been thinking and let's build that." Anything
along those lines that you might want to share?
Yeah, I mean, I can tell you a little bit about
how we manage our backlog, which I think actually
ties directly into this. At any given moment, we
have probably 20 or 30 opportunities that we could
possibly explore, just product opportunities, like
problems to solve, areas to improve for our users,
but they're not ready yet. We don't have enough
conviction around how we might approach it. So,
we just accumulate understanding of this stuff
and periodically, we accumulate some more stuff,
and then we reevaluate, "Okay, what is our current
understanding of how we might best approach this
thing?" And I think something that people struggle
with is that they might have this model in their
head. Like a PM might have this model in their
head about how a user behaves, but it's just very
hard to share that with someone else. You have to
telepathically throw it into their brain, which is
hard. So, what we try to do is identify areas that
we might attack with a product, but also keep an
up-to-date analysis of each of those areas so that
everyone can engage with it and also contribute.
Is there an example of something that's
sitting in your roadmap? I don't know
if you could share these sort of things
that's just sitting in the backlog of just
like, "We're not quite ready to tackle this
yet, but here's something we're inkling on."
Yeah, sure. Capacity planning is a thing that's
been sitting in our backlog, and it's something
that we see managers struggle with all the time,
which is like I have a limited amount of personnel
and resources, and I need to deploy them in such
a way where we can theoretically accomplish our
roadmap, but also we don't get blocked by some
bottleneck that we don't end up blocking all of
the projects because this one engineer is stuck
on some info thing, and that's a thing people
struggle with all the time. All the solutions
out there are bad. The best solution is a very,
very custom spreadsheet that someone
would make, and it's a lot of upkeep. So,
we have some ideas about how we might automate
this, how we might use existing data within
Linear to really help out with this problem,
but I don't think we've quite cracked it yet.
I think there's some nuances that we have
to really explore a little bit further. So,
we're continuously developing this, and as we
hear from hear from users that are struggling
with this problem, we will get on a call with
them and sit down with them and talk through it.
And the idea there is keep
informing this mental model,
keep informing what this could be
until you get to a place of like,
"Okay. Cool. I think we figured out what will
really solve this problem in an elegant way"?
Yeah, and I want to really stress a nuance
here, which is it's not that we want to solve
the entire problem. The entire problem is quite
big, but there's something that's really right for
Linear to do that would help people have a good
starting point for them to reason about it. So,
I think a lot of building conviction around
stuff is not even like do we have a workable
solution? It's like how much of the problem
should we actually take on? Because if we
take on too much of the problem, then we'll end up
overpromising and not being able to deliver on it.
I think what's also useful here is
you all keep your team very small
intentionally and being constrained
keeps you from taking on these things
too early because you don't have the
engineers to build their designers.
Yeah, that's true. I actually hadn't
really put that part together,
but I think some of the reason we've
done it this way is because we don't
have the bandwidth to action everything.
So, we have this backlog that we maintain
to make sure that when we do take it
on, we're pretty set up for success.
Yeah, it's interesting. I think a lot of companies
are starting to realize that they can build better
products and move faster with fewer teams. I want
to move in a different direction and talk a bit
about how you actually think about building
new products. Something that I've heard from
you is that you have a systemized way of being
creative, which I think is a dream for a lot of
people's. It's like how do I be more creative?
How do I think of new innovative concepts? You
have a really interesting process for
how you do this. Can you talk about it?
Yeah, totally. I think when people talk about
being creative, a lot of times what they have
a problem with is extrapolating. They can
see the stuff that's right in front of them,
but what about two or three steps down
the line? And then it's just like, "Well,
there's just so much possibility. I
don't know what direction to go." So,
the way that we try to do it is we ask a question
which is like, "Okay, how extreme can you take
it? You're designing a product. You're trying
to come up with a solution. What's the most
outrageous version of this along some trait?" I
don't know if you guys did this at Airbnb, but I
think Brian Chesky talks about like, "What's the
11-star experience?" Is that a thing you guys did?
It was a thing he talked about. Yeah,
there's always a push of what's
the 10X version of some idea.
When you think in that way, when you're saying
like, "Hey, what's the 11-star experience?" What
you're really asking is like, "Hey, what's the
most luxurious version of this hotel stay? Or
what's the most unforgettable kind of experience
we can give people?" And you throw away things,
I don't know, like cost. You throw away
things like practicality because that's
not what's interesting. What's interesting is I
want to actually explore the possibility space,
and I think this is really important to
do because the goal is to get you to see
beyond your defaults. We have all of these
constraints that we're operating under that we
psychically have in the back of our heads that
we just don't even realize we have them. So,
just break past all of them, and then you can
really see what your options are because we talk
about product decisions. It's like, "Oh, yeah, you
have these choices. What are you going to decide?"
There's all this decision-making kind of theory.
But the biggest risk is you didn't see the right
choice to begin with. You have these three choices
and none of them were right. It's this fourth one
that was over in this corner, but you didn't
look in that corner, so you never found it. So,
I think the whole goal of this is to try to expand
the search space of what you're trying to do.
So, what you're saying is people often don't
think out of the box enough by not thinking too
radically enough. So, the choices they're
deciding between are just meh options and
there's this process of breaking out of that, and
I think you could hear this and be like, "Yeah,
sure." I could spend 10 minutes being like, "Oh,
hey, what's the craziest [inaudible 00:47:35]- "
Yeah.
But you're saying that actually is what
you do and that actually works really well?
Yeah, and you actually build it. You can
think of a very extreme version of a product
and you can say, "Hey, let's actually...
" For the first version, we talked about,
like the first version, you know it's not really
the right answer. Sometimes, you know it's so hard
because you know this is the most extreme
version of the answer. So, let's build that
as fast as we can and see how it feels, and
then we're going to learn so much about what
the right actual answer is because we have seen
this area of the product space and really felt it.
Awesome. Let's talk about an example
of this because this feels awesome.
Yeah, I can talk to an example.
Actually, is it okay if I demo something?
Absolutely. Let's do it. Show and tell.
Yeah, let me do that right now.
Here we go. We're going to share screen.
All right. So, this is just like a demo space
instead of Linear. So, the feature where we did
this that I remember very clearly, because it was
recent, is we built this feature to save drafts
for your issues. So, Linear, as hard as an issue
tracker, if I make a new issue and let's say I'm
trying to report a bug or something, so it's like
I make a bug report, then I might start thinking
through like, "Okay, what are the repro steps?"
And then I start typing them, and this happens all
the time. When you're at work, you're doing this
and someone distracts you. If someone pings you on
Slack or you have to go to a meeting or something
like that, you're like, "I got to put this away
for a second. I'll come back to it later." Note to
self, figure out the actual repro steps and do it.
So, what can you do? Well, you want to
save it as a draft. So, we're like, "Okay,
this is the problem," and the first version
of this, we're like, "What do we want to do?
Linear is about being fast." So, we don't want
to get in your way. We want to say like, "What
is the fastest draft saving experience possible?"
So, if you save it as draft, you can save it as
draft. If you decide to not... you want to throw
it away, you don't want it, just hit the X button,
and it'll just throw it away. We're not going to
interrupt you with a popup that says like, "Do you
want to save your changes," or any of that kind of
stuff. We'll just absolutely get out of your way
fast as possible. So, we're like, "What's the
risk here?" Well, it might feel really unsafe.
If you close this, and we don't ask you if you
want to save change, you might feel like, "Oh,
I just lost my changes on accident." We
knew that going in. We built this anyway,
and it felt super unsafe. It turns out
that sort of inkling that we had was true,
and we really felt exactly how unsafe it was. So,
then we were like, "Okay, well, what's the safest
thing we could possibly do?" The safest thing is
just auto save everything. So, you start a new
issue, and then you start typing some stuff,
and it's just like auto saving as soon as you
type a single character and that did feel
quite safe. So, cool, but it also ended up
leaving behind a whole bunch of like a paper
trail of things you change your mind about.
You've probably had this happen in document
tools where you have a whole bunch of things
in your space called like Untitled Document or
New Document and stuff like that. It's just like-
So many untitled folders.
Yeah, so many untitled folders because the moment
you say new folder, it starts saving it, and then
you don't actually mean for that to happen. So, we
had those two sorts of variations that we built,
and we fell through and where we ended
up was a balance between those two. So,
what happens is if I'm creating a new issue, like
I am here, and I close it out, it'll interrupt me,
like we have to interrupt you, otherwise it
feels too unsafe. So, I can save the draft,
I can go to my drafts, and then if I'm in this
draft I've already made, and I go in there,
and I start to say, "Okay, I'm going to keep
working on it," but then I get interrupted again,
then I'm just going to auto-save it for you.
There's no point. I'm not going to ask you again.
I'm always going to auto save it because I'm
not going to create a new object. I'm just
making modifications in place. So, we made this
very specific choice of on a brand new issue,
we will interrupt you, and then on an existing
draft that you're messing around with,
we're just going to auto save everything
and someone doing a analysis. If they
did a detailed teardown of these decisions,
they might say like, "Wow, they made very
specific choices here," but the path to get
there is to do something totally extreme in
one direction and then totally extreme in another
direction and then find where they really meet up.
Such a good example, the way that you
described it is you went like here's
the safest route. Here's the fastest
version. Where did you come up with
these list of options? And for folks that
are trying to do this for their company,
are these like... Because these are
Linear principles, we're going to be very
fast. Is this the way you think most companies
should operate these sorts of attributes? Do you
think it's specific to what makes their
product different? How do you think about that?
I think for a lot of companies, you have to
ask, "What is the promise that your product
or your business is making people?" It might be
you always have a car available if you need it,
and if you do that, then maybe we're going to have
to implement search pricing to make that happen.
It's always going to be available. So, here's
the trade-off that we have to make. It's a very
extreme point of view to do that. Or you might say
the price is always predictable, but sometimes you
can't have a car in the first place. Those are
all choices that you get to make, and you have to
sort decide, like where in that spectrum does it
make sense based on the promise of your company?
A lot of people talk about this idea of
working backwards. Brian Chesky in Airbnb
has a big concept of working backwards from the
ideal. Let's design the best possible scenario
and work backwards. I love that this is even
more tactical, which is just pick the extreme
version of very specific attributes. Probably
not that ideal, but it'll give us insight into
a version of the ideal and an element that works
well and then what doesn't. Yeah, exactly. I did
this a lot actually at Airbnb, just like testing
the extreme. So, it super resonates, this idea,
and when you say test, so was it like you build
it and play with it? Do you roll it out to some
of these circles of users or is it often just
internal, and then you learn and then iterate?
Yeah, we rolled out some of
these versions to people.
Oh, wow. Okay.
So, the super-fast version that
was unsafe, that only went interna,
and everyone felt it was too unsafe, but then
we thought, "Okay, let's go to the super-safe
version," and then we rolled that out and
everyone started having a whole bunch of...
Like how many drafts are people making? I'm
like, "This is too many." The people are
leaving behind this crazy paper trail. Okay,
we got to figure out some difference here.
Awesome. So, this very much connects to your
first point of get things out really quick,
and in this case, it's like extreme versions.
You're probably not going to work
long term, but it will teach you.
Yeah, exactly.
Amazing. Okay, and seeing it in action, I'm like,
"Okay, obviously, this is the solution,"
and that's how the way this should feel,
and to your point, it was not an obvious
solution when you started thinking about it.
Yeah. I mean, the best solutions
are always obvious in hindsight,
and it's just like you have to develop a process
internally that to eventually find your way there.
Something else that you've mentioned when
we were chatting that connects to some of
the things we've been talking about is you have
this perspective that B2B software isn't just
solving people's problems, it's also teaching
them how to work, and it's this accumulation
of information. Can you talk about that?
Because I thought that was really fascinating.
If you think about how a lot of B2B software gets
created, it's because there was some person in the
middle of some giant company who implemented
some kind of process, and they're like, "Wow,
this process is really working for us. Maybe we
should make it easier," and they build a little
tool internally and then all of their colleagues
can now press on buttons and good things happen,
and then they turn that process and that
tool. They spin it off into a startup,
and they make a startup. This process repeats
thousands of times. So, when you adopt that tool,
you're not just adopting the actual software,
you're adopting the idea that this is a practice
that you ought to be doing in the first place. So,
if you're a marketing person, and you adopt some
marketing software, you're not just saying, "Okay,
now, I can write emails and send them to people."
There's all sorts of process around that. You're
organizing stuff into campaigns. You're measuring
click-through rates. You're calculating cost of
acquisition and all that stuff probably comes
equipped with a tool because those are the
right practices to do when you're doing this
sort of marketing exercise. And whether you knew
about it before or you learned it from the tool,
like as a buyer for this kind of product,
what I'm doing is I'm saying like, "Hey,
I'm going to bring in this baseline level of
marketing competency into my organization,
that this is the worst we can do
is whatever the tool defaults are."
Interesting. So, you're basically
buying into a way of working when
you're adopting a piece of software, not
just have this problem I need solved.
Yeah, exactly, and I think the most salient
example of this is if you've ever seen like a
company adopt an ERP product, it's the most
painful thing you can imagine. It's doing
deep surgery. They have to redo all of their
internal processes and the way they manage
inventory and all this kind of stuff, but they're
willing to do it because they know that this is
a battle-tested way of making sure that you're
actually doing good management of resources. So,
they're like, "We're growing up now. It's time
for us to adopt these best practices. In order to
do that, we have to adopt this tool, and we will
conform to whatever the tool is best is to do."
This connects to a couple things I know
about Linear, one is what you've shared
of just avoiding these customizations requests
from people. Do you have a very opinionated way
of here's how you should operate in order
to build a great functioning product, org,
and company in general? I'm just connecting
threads here. One is like we're going to avoid
letting people customize too much because we
know they'll have a bad time, and then two
is just this idea of we are opinionated
about the way you should work in Linear,
and it's like you have a Linear method,
I think it's called, of just like here's
how product team should operate based
on everything we've seen be successful.
Yeah. Yeah. It's definitely connected in a way,
and I think sometimes when people talk about...
You mentioned like being opinionated, and I
think sometimes when people talk about being
opinionated, it can feel like they're almost
saying like, "Hey, this is arbitrary," like
your opinion and my opinion, they're just too
opinions, man. Neither is right or wrong. What we
try to do is find where there's actual consensus
amongst a lot of different high performing teams,
and then we can take those practices and say
like, "Okay, for a team that isn't already
practicing this, can we give them a button
so that they can start practicing this?"
When we see companies doing a really
good job of managing their triage queue,
but it's very manual, we're like, "Okay,
can we automate this? And then for this
other company that really needs it that they
don't know this is what they need, can we just
give them a button to activate this?" And now
they have the practice within their org, too.
So, I think the takeaway here
is when you choose a tool,
recognize it's going to change the way
you operate and be thoughtful about is
this the way we want to work versus just
we just have a problem we want solved?
Yeah, exactly.
I want to come back to something, a thread
that's come up a couple of times in our chat
is the way you collaborate internally. It
feels like there's a pretty unique way.
You said you were on all the sales calls.
Is there anything that you can share about
how you collaborate internally, how the
different functions collaborate that may
be unlike how other companies operate that
might be helpful for them to learn from?
Yes. Something that's worked really, really
well for us is we think of product management
as partially like a go-to-market discipline
in the same way that sales and marketing are,
right? When you talk to people and like,
"Hey, tell me how product management works
in your company," they'll probably
say something about like, "Well,
there's engineering product and design. They work
in this triad, and here's how they interact and
collaborate," and we all understand why that's
useful, why that's helpful, but this other form
of collaboration between product management,
sales and marketing, I think it's something
that's probably really underexamined
and often I feel like in organizations,
you actually see some antagonism between product
and sales and marketing, and I think that's a
shame because when we come together, the
way we think about the way that we think
about selling is a matter of like... especially
because we sell to very expert practitioners,
and they have a very sensitive BS detector.
So, a big part of what we try to do is we try
to help our marketing team pick exactly
the right word and the right phrasing to
make us sound native to the language
that our customers speak and also-
You're talking about engineers is my sense, right?
Yeah. Engineers is a big one,
but even product managers, right?
Mm-hmm.
Like product managers know when...
They know what the job is like. So,
when you come in, you say the wrong
words, people give you stink eye.
Don't call them project managers.
Yeah, exactly, for example. So, I think
that's a big part of what we have to do. So,
on our PM team, we actually have a full-time
product marketer, and her job is to... Tactically,
it's like all the change logs come from her, all
the release notes, and also she's always crafting
the language for whatever upcoming release that
we're building and working directly with the teams
and trying to figure out how to talk about it,
and then once we go out and build the campaigns,
build assets and things like that, that's where
a lot of the language is coming from. It's coming
from the work that she's doing and then with
sales, they're validating all that message in
the field. They're saying the words to customers
directly and telling you if it's sticking or not,
and then you can have a really good feedback
cycle between those three disciplines.
What I've seen you refer to this way
of working as is a double triangle,
which is I think a complement to the PM, engineer,
designer. Talk about that and give
us a visual of what that looks like.
Yeah, I think PMs, like product managers, we
often have a tough time trying to explain like,
"What is your job?" It's a little bit of
everything. I think the job that I do that
we see it as is you're taking the building side
of the organization and the selling side of the
organization and bringing it together. You're
taking all of the commercial motivations and
goals of the company and making sure that what
you build actually solves for those goals,
and you're tempering that with what's
possible and where the opportunities
are to actually build stuff. So, to me, it's the
PM in the middle, and then you have engineering,
product design, and then sales, marketing,
product management on the other side.
PM is always in the middle-
Indeed.
... but I think that's true from the perspective
of PM, and I love this visual of just the PM is
connecting the builders to the sellers, and
you're involved in both worlds. This connects
very directly to Brian Chesky's whole thing
about how PMs should be doing marketing. So,
the way they changed it, every PM is also PMM,
and there's no more... They're product marketers
now. That's their title and that's like the
extreme version of what you're describing.
Yeah. Yeah, and I think Apple's been
doing that way for forever, too.
Got it. So, the advice here is
if you're a PM at a B2B business,
lean into the sales and marketing side
of it, lean into the go-to-market.
Yeah, and in fact, if you're leaving something
on the table in terms of the kind of impact that
you are having at your job, that's probably
the thing that you're leaving on the table.
You're probably already doing a good job of
collaborating with engineering and design. It's
probably the sort of sell side that there's
an opportunity for you to have more impact.
Just to make it even more concrete for PMs that
are like, "Okay, I want to do this. I want to
do what Linear's doing. I'm going to get more
salesy." What does it look like when someone
is more is in this double triangle working
more closely with sales? You talked about
being on sales calls. What else there can you
share of just like, "Here, try these things"?
I think originate the message
that you send to your audience.
There's a lot of things that marketing does,
which you are never going to necessarily touch.
There's always demand gen and figuring out
channel strategy and all this kind of stuff,
like sure. That's a peer marketing concern,
but actually picking the words and where the
emphasis is, like you should understand
the customer at a pretty deep level,
probably deeper than any other group at the
company because of the kinds of requirements
gathering, discovery that you're doing. So,
you're going to know the native language that
your customers speak a lot better and help
your marketing team originate those words.
Got it. So, basically be really
involved in the product marketing,
the writing, the emails,
the headlines, the website?
Yeah, yeah, exactly. I know the
word product marketing is also so
overloaded. They do so many different
things, but it's that sort of content
creation piece that you really have
an opportunity to contributes to.
Yeah, I love how concrete that is. It's
like don't think about this concept,
product marketing. Just think about the words that
your potential customers and customers see. Okay,
final area I want to spend a lot of time on is
totally different. It's around getting a job.
Oh, yeah. Okay.
You have a pretty unique approach to finding
a gig. I heard from the founder of Mode about
the very unique way you approached getting
a job there. I imagine Linear is a similar
boat. What advice can you share with
folks that are looking for a job,
maybe struggling, that work for you
when you were looking for your next gig?
Project management is a unique role. Because we
do just about everything, you don't really get
pigeonholed into being compared along a single
dimension with everyone else, and everyone who's
hiring PMs, just like when they're hiring execs,
they're hoping that they bring them on to solve
some burning problem that they have. So, it's your
job when you're in the interview process to figure
out what that burning problem is. So, put on your
discovery hat and go figure out what is the actual
job to be done of the hiring manager when they're
bringing on a new PM onto their team? And if you
can do that and then make a good case that you
are the person to solve that problem, then hiring
you becomes a binary choice between do I hire the
solution to my problem or do I hire someone else?
And I think what ends up happening a lot is when
you're in a interview process, you're just trying
to put your best foot forward, trying to say
that you're great at everything. You have very
few weaknesses. Maybe you tried too hard, like
whatever, but everyone's going to say that. So,
you're just one of end people, and you want to
make yourself a little bit of just you versus
the field. You're the solution to a problem and
then everyone else is like a roll of the dice.
So, the way you're describing it is the company
has a job to be done, say it's drive growth of
some feature. In this case, it's like for Linear,
just build a killer or successful B2B product. I
don't know. That's a broad one. Usually, you're
not interviewing for head of product role,
so that's maybe too broad. So, it's like what is
this PM role's job to be done at the company and
then help convince them you are the best person
to do that job and solve this problem for them.
Yeah, and a lot of times when you take that
approach, it'll feel like you already work there,
and the way that I did this, like I got advice
from a friend. He said like, "I was interviewing
for this job at Mode that you referenced." I'm
like, "How should I approach it?" He's like,
"Just act like you already worked there. What
would you do?" And then it's like, "Okay, I could
do that." So, then when you're in this interview
process and someone's asking you questions. He
goes, "Do you have any questions for me?" You can
ask them like, "What are your OKRs this quarter?
How can someone help you achieve those?" You
can be that specific about it, and they're like,
"Oh, yeah, sure. I can tell you about the
exact thing that I'm doing this quarter,
and then you'll have some level of intelligence
about what people are actually trying to solve
because I think often we just get stuck in these
very high level general types of questions like,
"What's the company goals sand all that kind
of stuff, and it's like, no, you can get really
specific. If you were collaborating with that
person in your job, what would you say to them?
I love how actionable this advice
is. There's obviously an element of
this takes work and time. A lot of people
are interviewing at a lot of companies,
trying to find a job, is part of
your advice. Pick the ones you're
most excited about and invest a lot
of time in this way of interviewing.
You can invest a lot in the ones where
you know that you're going to be able
to over deliver on. If you understand
what they're actually trying to solve,
then you know where you're going to have both
the highest chance of success of getting hired,
but also doing a really great
job on the other end of it.
And you talk about how you're like pretending
you have the job, pretending you actually have
this job as part of the interview process.
Oftentimes, as an outsider, you don't have
enough information to have a really good thought
on what the solution is, and maybe part of it
is going to be so wrong because you're like, "I
don't actually know. I don't have the data." Do
you actually try to reach out to the engineers
and designers on the team to try to understand
things? How far do you go to try to solve
these problems and show them what you can do?
Yeah, I mean, you're in the interview loop. These
are people that you're going to be working closely
with. So, start there. Do your discovery
questions, and if there's an area that you
think you want to dig, you can ask. There's no
harm asking, "Hey, can you put me in touch with
an engineering manager who's working on the
same problem?" And if no one else is asking,
again, you're going to have an extra piece
of feedback from that eng manager. So, yeah,
like this guy asks really good questions,
and it seems like they're really with it.
No one else is going to have that piece of
feedback. So, during the debrief process.
And just asking that question alone will show them
how deeply you're thinking about this already?
Yeah.
Amazing. Nan, is there anything else that we
have not covered that you want to touch on or
share or you think might be helpful to listeners
before we get to a very exciting lightning round?
I have a very specific point
of view on deadlines. I don't
know if that's [inaudible 01:09:34] you care.
Let's do it. Fire away.
I think what often happens is people get
depressed about deadlines. It's like, "Hey,
here's the ship date," and then you never make it.
I don't know if you've had this feeling before.
Absolutely, with some deadlines.
You were an engineer before too, right? So, it's
just like engineers is basically like, "Oh, yeah.
Yeah, deadlines, they're complete fabrications,"
and the only way to make deadlines real is to take
them so seriously that they are basically like a
P0 problem, and everything else has to not matter
in comparison to the deadline because that's the
only way you're going to be able to signal to the
team and also to all the stakeholders that you're
actually taking it seriously. So, my feeling on
deadlines is don't have too many of them, and when
you do, it's a P0. So, the engineer is working
on it. They don't get to work on anything else.
It's like, "Oh, I need them for this," like nope.
Nope. You're not pulling them off of anything.
We're doing this. As a PM, your job is to just
cut as much scope as possible to make it possible
to hit that deadline. Like what are the things
actually blocking us from doing it? Because what
you want to do is at the moment where you have
to make the go, no-go call on whether to ship,
you want to be able to actually have a product
that you can say yes to. It might not have all the
features you had wanted or whatever, and you can
say no. You can make that choice, but you want to
set yourself up to be in a position where you can
actually say yes or no to something, because what
often happens is like we want this thing. Well,
it's not even close to being done yet, so there's
no possible way we can say yes. I can't ship it.
It's half broken. It's like, "No, no, no. You want
to get to a point where it works. It might not be
the product that you want, but it is an actual
real product that you can conceivably ship."
So, you said that don't have too many deadlines,
but when you do, make sure you... Everyone
understands these are actual deadlines. When
do you decide it's worth having a deadline?
Is it like a marketing launch sort of thing?
What's worthy of a deadline in your experience?
Yeah, it's usually having to
do with some kind of external
marketing type of exercise that you're try to hit.
Got it.
And I think that that's the other thing that I
think. As builders, we can often look at launch
dates and stuff like that. It's like, "Oh, who
cares if it's a little bit later or we skip this
change log," or whatever it is, and I think that
that's really a... I don't know. It makes me go
crazy when I hear people say that in all honesty.
With marketing and communication with customers,
you basically have a limited amount of
opportunities to do so. A year is 365
days. There are 12 months. Each of those
months has about four weeks. There's some
rhythm where you get to have 50-ish weeks to
say something to your audience once a week,
or you get to have 12 months to say something
really big or four quarters to say something huge.
If you miss one of those opportunities,
you don't get it back again. You can't time
travel back and say like, "Okay, actually,
let's redo first quarter and say this message
that we wish we could have gotten into the field."
That is such a powerful point.
I could see the sales marketing,
go-to-market element of your job coming out there.
I imagine everyone that's in that field's like,
"Yes, this is exactly right." Maybe just
the last question along this line. So,
I love this idea of taking deadlines very
seriously when you commit to a deadline.
At the same time, as you pointed out, it
creates a lot of stress knowing there's a
deadline we have to hit. So, one lever you've
mentioned is cutting scope. Another is just
people spending more time estimating to have
more accurate deadlines. You invest in that.
How do you think about just for an engineering
team to come into a deadline, how much to spend
on de-risking and estimating versus just, "Let's
just do our best and then we'll cut and adjust"?
This might be my hot take, but we
do almost no estimating in order
to hit deadlines. What we do is we ship as
early as we can. The thing we talked about
earlier where if by the time that 10% of the
time has elapsed, you have a working thing,
you can now spend the rest of the time
deciding whether or not you want to do
another iteration or you want to polish that
thing and get it to be a shippable state. So,
you're setting up your future self to be able
to make that decision. So, none of this is...
You can't go into this at the very last moment and
say like, "Okay, now, we have to take the deadline
seriously." You have to do it from the beginning
and commit to the process of going very fast,
iterating early, and then putting yourself in a
position where you can say yes or no to a product.
So interesting and so different from
the way most companies operate. Nan,
this was everything I was hoping it'd be. I
think this is going to help a lot of people
build much better product, which would
be good for the world if more products
are like Linear. With that, we reached our
very exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
Yeah, let's do it.
Okay, let's do it. Okay, first question.
What are two or three books that
you have recommended most to other people?
I think the one book that I recommend
the most is The Design of Everyday Things
by Don Norman. I read it originally in
college for an HCI class I was taking,
and I think of everything I've ever read, it's
the thing that caused me to see the world from
the perspective of everything you interact
with as a product. Every pencil that you use,
every door that you open is a
product that somebody designed.
And is that the big takeaway from
that book? Because it comes up a lot,
and it's such an old book. So, I guess
for someone that hasn't read or maybe
doesn't have time to read, it is the
big takeaway for you. Someone designed
everything and there's a reason things
aren't great, and they can be improved.
Yeah. I mean, I saw this the other day.
I was at a café in my neighborhood,
and I saw a kid rip a handle off a door, like of
the café. He pulled it so hard, it came right off
because it was a push door, but it had a handle
that looked like you could pull it, and that's
one of the canonical examples of the book because
[inaudible 01:15:25] are just mysteries. Yeah.
Awesome. Next question. Do you have a favorite
recent movie or TV show you've really enjoyed?
I watched The Diplomat on Netflix. I
think it was terrific. It's really fun,
easy watch. It has some West Wing vibes
if you were into that back in the day.
Yeah, have you seen the second season?
Yeah, I finished the second season. Yeah.
I wasn't as excited about the second season,
just to put that out there. The first season was
really good and then just went off a little like,
"Okay. I guess it's cool," but stuff like that.
Yeah, it got a little like spy thrillery, I think.
Okay, cool, but still really
good and on Netflix. Okay,
cool. Do you have a favorite product you
recently discovered that you really like?
I didn't discover it, but I discovered a version
of it that was really interesting. There's a pen.
Actually, I have one on my desk. It's called the
Sakura Micron. I don't know if you use these. It's
like a felt tip pen. It's really great. It was
originally invented in Japan for artists to draw
comic books and stuff, and you can use it for
anything. I use it for journaling or whatever,
but I was on Amazon. I was trying to buy more,
and I found a package that said like, "Bible Study
Kit." I was like, "Why is this labeled Bible Study
Kit?" And it was literally just the pen in four
different colors, and it was because the thing
doesn't bleed through pages. So, if you have a
Bible, which they often have these really flimsy
newsprint pages. It's not going to bleed through.
And it's just really interesting to me that
someone marketed a normal package of these
pens as a Bible study kit and for people who were
looking for that keyword, and it was official,
too. It was not something hacked together. It
was actually an official packaging of this.
Amazing. What a unique pen choice. Two
more questions. Do you have a favorite
life motto that you often come back
to and find useful in work or in life?
The correct amount is too much minus one, and I
think this ties into the try the extreme version
of it of a thing where... I don't know, like a
stupid example, like how much pizza do you want to
eat? It's like, well, five slices was too many. I
feel bad. Then four was probably the right number,
and then if you want to find the right number,
sometimes you just have to really shoot for the
edge and then find out what's too much, and then
you'll find out exactly what the right amount is.
I love how tactical that is, makes
me think about Elon Musk's thing
about cutting things. Like one of his
formulas for just getting stuff done,
one of them is just cut stuff before
trying to optimize it and automate it,
and his advice is if you don't bring back 10%
of things, you cut, you're not cutting enough.
Yeah, exactly.
Final question. You worked at
Everlane for a number of years,
and you shared the rough idea of a story around
a shirt, maybe a bestseller that they have now,
and how you helped create a bestselling
women's shirt. Can you share that story?
Yeah. So, I mean, to be clear, I witnessed the
creation. I don't think I had a direct hand in it,
but yeah. So, I saw this advertisement the
other day on Instagram for... It's called the
Women's Box-Cut Tee, and it's a wide and short for
women, and I looked, and it had 20 colors of it,
and it sells super well, and I remember when
we created this thing, and it was because there
was a batch of defective men's t-shirts. They
all came in an inch and a half too short. So,
we couldn't sell them. You would have your belly
button sticking out. No one wants to wear of
that. So, what we did was like, well, we
have to salvage the inventory because we
were a very small company, and we had to make
cash flow, and we couldn't just damage it out.
So, the design team and the marketing team came
together, and they said, "Okay. Here's what we're
going to do. We're going to cut another two inches
off of this and make it really cropped and market
it towards women as like a cropped boxed-tee
silhouette, and we did that. We're like, "Okay,
hopefully, we can salvage this inventory and not
have to take a write-down." It sold out in a week,
and we're like, "Oh, okay. I guess we just made a
hit product," and it's one of these things where
it's very hard to know what this was. Was this a
marketing thing? Was this a design thing? I don't
know, but you just come together, and you find
the right product market fit in the weirdest way.
I love that it's still going.
Yeah, it's still going. Originally, it was
just white. Now, there's like 20 colors.
Oh, man. I love how many industries you
have worked in: fashion, data analytics,
project management. I don't know what's next.
There's more, I imagine. Nan, this was incredible.
I really appreciate making time for this. Like
I said, I think we're going to have helped a lot
of people build better products. Two final
questions, where can folks find you online
if they want to reach out and learn more?
And how can listeners be useful to you?
Yeah, I'm on X/Twitter as the
thenanyu. It's T-H-E and then my name,
and if they have any feedback about
Linear, we're very happy to take it,
especially for people who use it in their
day-to-day. We really want to hear from users.
What's the best way for them to
share that? Is it tweet at you?
Is it go to the website? What do you recommend?
Oh, yeah. You can tweet at us. You can DM me
on Twitter. My DMs are open, so it's all good.
Amazing. Nan, thank you so much for being here.
Yeah, of course. Thanks, Lenny.
Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.