The work that you guys do has had such
a tremendous impact on the way the world
works. I want to start with just giving people a
brief understanding of what is Community Notes.
Someone on X can see a post. If they think it's
misleading, they can propose a note that they
think other people might find informative.
Other people can then rate that note.
We actually look for agreement from
people who have disagreed in the past.
And what we see is when people actually
have that sort of surprising agreement,
that's what makes the notes so neutral and
accurate and well- written, really, overall.
There's many people that are very polarized.
How do you deal with people that
are super anti-vax, super Jan 6?
One philosophical thing that's important is
that we want all of humanity to participate
and sometimes people are surprised
by that. We have all of humanity.
We then have the data to understand what
notes will be helpful to actual humanity.
Every post is eligible for notes. We
shouldn't exempt Elon. We shouldn't
exempt government figures. We should be like
everyone... Even advertisers can get notes.
There have been external studies run by people
totally independent of us who have found that
if you take a post with or without a Community
Note, that actually people's agreement with the
core claims in the post does change if
they see it with a note versus without.
Is there anything else along
the lines of just working for
Elon within an org Elon runs
that might surprise people?
If I were to start a company in that company,
it would be even leaner than I would've made
it before. I've been amazed with just how much
the team is able to accomplish with a small
group and I think because of a small group-
Today, my guests are Keith Coleman, Product
Lead for Community Notes, and Jay Baxter,
Founding ML Engineer and Researcher for Community
Notes. This conversation may be my newest favorite
podcast episode so far. Community Notes is one
of the most impactful and clever and, also,
underappreciated products in the world right now.
If you ever use X/Twitter and you see a note
underneath a tweet correcting the misinformation
in that tweet, that is Community Notes.
I've never heard a deep dive into the story
behind the product and the team that built it
and I'm excited to bring you just that. We get
into the surprising origin story of the product,
how the algorithm actually works, how the
algorithm emerged out of an internal contest
within Twitter, the principles behind Community
Notes, and why staying true to them has been so
key to its success. Also, how it survived four
different leaders, including Elon and Jack,
and why it's now a big part of the solution to
solving misinformation on the internet. Including
recently being adopted by Meta as their main
fact-checking tool. This is an incredibly special
episode and I'm so excited to bring it to you.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. Also,
if you become a subscriber of my newsletter, you
now get a year free of Notion and Superhuman and
Granola and Linear and Perplexity Pro.
Check that out at lennysnewsletter.com.
With that, I bring you Keith Coleman and
Jay Baxter. This episode is brought to
you by WorkOS. If you're building a SaaS app, at
some point, your customers will start asking for
enterprise features like SAML Authentication and
SCIM Provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in,
making it fast and painless to add enterprise
features to your app. Their APIs are easy to
understand so that you can ship quickly
and get back to building other features.
Today, hundreds of companies are already powered
by WorkOS. Including ones you probably know like
Vercel, Webflow, and Loom. WorkOS also recently
acquired Warrant, the Fine Grain Authorization
service. Warrant's product is based on a
groundbreaking authorization system called
Zanzibar, which was originally designed for
Google to power Google Docs and YouTube. This
enables fast authorization checks at enormous
scale while maintaining a flexible model that
can be adapted to even the most complex use cases.
If you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features
like single sign-on, SCIM, or user management,
you should consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in
replacement for Auth0 and supports up to 1 million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
workos.com to learn more. That's workos.com.
This episode is brought to you by Productboard,
the leading product management platform for the
enterprise. For over 10 years, Productboard has
helped customer-centric organizations like Zoom,
Salesforce, and Autodesk build the right
products faster. And as an end- to-end platform,
Productboard seamlessly supports all stages of
the product development lifecycle from gathering
customer insights, to planning a roadmap, to
aligning stakeholders, to earning customer
buy-in, all with a single source of truth.
And now, product leaders can get even more
visibility into customer needs with Productboard
Pulse, a new voice of customer solution. Built-in
intelligence helps you analyze trends across all
of your feedback and then dive deeper by asking
AI your follow-up questions. See how Productboard
can help your team deliver higher-impact products
that solve real customer needs and advance your
business goals. For a special offer and free
15-day trial, visit productboard.com/lenny.
That's productboard.com/lenny.
Keith and Jay, thank you so much for
being here. Welcome to the podcast.
It's great to be here. [inaudible 00:05:25].
Thanks for having us on.
It's so my pleasure. I'm so thrilled to be
having this conversation. The work that you
guys do has had such a tremendous impact on
the way the world works. So many product teams
are always talking about driving impact and
want to drive impact. You guys have actually
built things that have changed the world
in meaningful ways and continue to do that.
And I've never really heard the backstory
of how Community Notes came to be and how
it works and all these things, so I'm really
appreciative of you guys making time to chat.
Yeah. First, thanks for saying that. That's
why we built this thing is to help people and
it's great to hear it. It's great to see
people enjoying it and finding it useful.
I want to start with just giving
people a brief understanding of
what is Community Notes. I think a
lot of people kind of heard about it,
kind of maybe see it on X. As they scroll
through, they see these notes but they're like,
"I don't actually know what this is." So can you
just briefly describe what is Community Notes?
Community Notes is a way for the people, like
the public, to add context to posts that might
be misleading. The basic way it works is that
someone on X can see a post. If they think it's
misleading, they can propose a note that they
think other people might find informative. Other
people can then rate that note. And if the note
is found helpful by people who normally disagree
with each other, indicating that it's probably
accurate, it's probably really neutrally-worded,
it's probably informative, then it will show to
everyone on X. The goal is just to get people
more information about what they're seeing so
they can make better decisions in their lives.
Amazing, and I think hearing this, it's
absurd that this works. I think when
people originally heard this idea like,
"No way this is going to work." And so, just
to dive a little bit deeper, can you give us
a deeper understanding of how it actually works?
Because I think it's the algorithm that you guys
designed that is so clever that allowed this to
work. So talk a little bit about that algorithm.
Yeah. So I think a key misunderstanding a lot
of people have if they haven't really dived
into details, they just think that maybe someone
can write a note and it appears immediately or
we're just taking a majority rules vote of
who thinks the note's good. I think both of
those approaches would probably lead to biased or
inaccurate notes. I think the key thing, really,
that we do is we actually look for agreement
from people who have disagreed in the past.
And what we see is when people actually
have that sort of surprising agreement,
that's what makes the notes so neutral and
accurate and well-written, really, overall.
It's just that people who are very polarized,
overall, often can't find agreement when things
aren't accurate, right? I think it also provides
some good anti-manipulation properties. I think
people are often... If you said... I think back
in 2020 before we started building anything here,
whether this could work at all, I think
a room of ML engineers would say, "Oh,
you have to keep it closed source. People
are going to be manipulating this all the
time. You have to use ground truth
labels from fact checkers. There's
no way that you could bootstrap the system without
external labels." But it turns out that you can
do that with this kind of bridging-based
agreement algorithm is what we call it.
Okay. So just to summarize and make it
super clear. It's basically people...
Someone writes a note. This information
is fault... What's a good example,
just as we talk about this,
like a classic example?
A really classic example is an AI generated
image or an out of context image like,
"Look what's happening here." But
it's actually from five years ago
in a different country and a
different topic or something-
Oh, man. I've seen this so many times
where it's like, "Look what's happening
in San Francisco," and I'm like, "No, this
is a whole different city and that's not-"
Totally. Yeah.
Yeah. Okay. So someone posts this
AI image. Someone writes a note,
"This is actually five years ago in
a different city," and this algorithm
helps understand if this note is true
and it's just regular people doing this.
Yep. Regular people who have signed up to be
Community Notes contributors. So there are
a few checks, like you do have to have a verified
phone number for instance. But yeah, at the end of
the day, these are regular people. Not necessarily
professional fact checkers or anything like that.
And yeah, that was really important to us
too. There was a question at the beginning,
to the point Jay was making of like, "Did
anyone think this was going to work?" Obviously,
it was a crazy idea. We didn't know if
regular people were going to be able to do
this task and certainly people had concerns
about whether they would do it effectively.
Initially, some people inside the
company were suggesting like, "Hey,
why don't you have journalists or some
select group be the first participants?"
But very specifically we were like, "No.
We're trying to move away from the idea
of curated editorial decisions being made
around this. This is supposed to be open
to everyone." So we very intentionally
try to allow all humans in. People are
randomly selected and that's important to it
feeling fair, feeling open, feeling trustable.
Yeah. And again, it's just like this sounds like
the holy grail of understanding what is true and
it actually works. And works so well that Meta
recently, as you all know, decided to adopt this
exact system for them instead of having tens
of thousands of fact checkers reviewing things.
One distinction that I would make, which maybe
can come off as nitpicky but I think is important,
is Community Notes adds additional context.
It's not fact-checking necessarily,
right? So there are cases where the post could
be true. But maybe, it's just misleading because
there there's no context or there's missing
context. We cover those cases and I think
that's an important distinction. We just have
the philosophy that users should be able to
make up their own minds, right? Like, "Here's
extra context, take it or leave it," right?
Yeah. What I think about, you shared this with
me, this example of a picture with a cat and
somebody's Community Note was just, "That's a
dog." Or is it the other way around or that's a-
Yeah. "A Palestinian boy shares his bread with
a dog," was the post and it's a picture of this
cat. So obviously, this particular note is
not super necessary because it just says,
"That's a cat," and links to a Wikipedia for cat.
It's a good example that the system is... This
is not something a professional fact-checker or
whatever or you think would need fact-checking.
But it's proof that the system is really
run by the users at the end of the day
and adds some comic relief, I
guess. And the note is correct.
Okay. It's important.
Yeah.
When does a post get triggered to even
be considered for Community Note? Is
there a threshold or is it just
you can write a Community Note on
anything and people decide what they
would vote on? How does that work?
So every post is eligible for notes and that
was, again, another really important principle.
It's like, "We shouldn't exempt Elon. We shouldn't
exempt government figures. We should..." Everyone,
even advertisers, can get notes. So any
posts on the platform can get a note.
And if you look in practice, you'll see notes
appearing on world leaders, on Elon, on ads,
on media organizations, and on, obviously, just
regular people using social media. But yeah,
the idea is really that it's an even
playing field. For a note to be proposed,
the person proposing it has to have earned
the ability to write notes. So there is that
aspect where you have to earn in to be able
to do this. And the way you earn that ability
is through your ratings by demonstrating the
ability to help identify notes that are found
helpful to a broad range of people. So basically,
if you have an ability to see and know, recognize
what's helpful with a lot of people, then you
have the ability to start proposing notes.
I actually signed up to be on... What
do you call these people? Note take-
Contributors.
Okay. Contributors. Yeah. So I've
been rating. I haven't achieved-
Nice.
I can't write notes yet.
Yeah. It's not super easy. It takes some effort.
Are there stats you can share about the
scale of Community Notes at this point,
especially things that might surprise people?
Yeah. I mean, the service is growing rapidly,
so there are hundreds of notes per day. And
to put that into context, I saw some stats
recently from someone at UC Berkeley saying
there was something like 10 traditional fact
checks a day. So in contrast, there's hundreds
of notes a day that are getting shown. They
span a huge range of topics from, obviously,
politics, news, out to entertainment, sports,
gaming. Just whatever is going on that day.
In addition to there being hundreds of these
individual notes, they can also be matched
to multiple posts. So if someone writes a note
on an image or a video, like let's say it's AI
generated or something like that, that note
will automatically be matched to all posts
that contain the same image. So you can have a
single note matching to thousands of posts. And
over let's say the last year, 2024, we had
something like 95,000 notes that were seen
about 30 billion times. That's more than double
the prior year. Prior year was something like
37K notes seen 14 billion times. So that rate is
increasing dramatically when you think about 30
billion views, that's a lot of information that
is getting out there that might not have been
out there otherwise, which is pretty cool.
And part of the reason it is expanding like
that is the contributor base is expanding.
There's something like 950,000 contributors
around the world. That's nearing a million
people making this happen which is amazing.
Wow. And I'm one of those,
right? I count as a contributor?
Yeah. Yep. No. If you're signed
up as a contributor, you count.
Okay. Cool.
Then, there's more people on the waitlist too.
So there's plenty of headroom for more growth.
Regarding the matching on media and URLs, I think
that's a huge way to get extra coverage. Also,
I do think we've been very careful to make sure
that those matches are precise. Because I think
one thing that people love about Community Notes
compared to other types of fact checking is that,
actually, the notes are custom written
for the particular claim you're seeing,
right? So often, a fact check warning
would just say something like,
"Get the facts here." And then, there's a link
to some generic page about voting information,
which is so not helpful to have the information
behind a click. So pulling the context up so
that you have zero clicks that you need to
make and keeping it specific is so important.
One feature I love that I imagine you
guys thought deeply about is if I liked
the post in the past, I get notified
later if a community note shows up,
so that I'm not remembering
this false information.
Yeah. I mean, we try to make notes as fast as
we can, so we want them to appear instantly if
possible. But inevitably, there's going to be
a time gap between when a post goes live and
when people figure out what's going on and
when they get the note out there. And so,
we send those notifications to
try to close that gap. And yeah,
we get a lot of love for that. We see people take
screenshots and share them. They're excited about
it. And it's also a pretty cool example
of something you can do on the internet,
in the social media world that was difficult
in a print or standard news world where you
would see maybe a correction the next day in a
corner of a paper that was hard to read. Here,
you're getting a ping about it if you've
engaged with a post and note shows up.
One user feedback point is I'd
love the push to just tell me,
"Here's what you got wrong." Because I find
that I actually have to go into it and read
it and I feel like the push could just be like,
"Here's more context to this thing." You're like-
Agreed.
We'll go take a look at that-
There we go. Live user feedback.
Nice.
Okay. I want to get into the origin story
of this whole thing. But two more questions,
because we're on this thread. One is
what's the the threshold for a note to
show up on a note? Is that information
you can share, just how does that work?
So just because of the details
of the way the algorithm works,
it uses this machine learning algorithm
called Matrix factorization where we fit
it with Gradient Descent and whatnot. The
threshold is it's 0.4 on this made up scale-
0.4. Great.
Yeah. I mean, in practice, what it means is
basically a majority of people... If there
is a polarized divide relevant to the notes.
Obviously, some notes are not about politics
or something polarizing. But if there is, then
a sizable majority of people on both sides would
generally need to find the note helpful. And
then, there are other rules that come into
play beyond that main one. So even if it's above
that threshold, it might get filtered out if...
There's a separate algorithm that's looking
at agreement between people's incorrect tags.
So like maybe people found the
note helpful but incorrect,
right? It happens. And in those cases, it doesn't
matter if it's above the helpfulness threshold.
This is probably the wrong way to think about it,
but is it 40% of people that
normally disagree, agree-
No.
Okay. It's-
It means nothing like that. It's
just like on some arbitrary scale-
Okay.
Yeah.
Yeah. If we change random other
things about the algorithm,
that number would also have to change to an
equally seemingly arbitrary number. We arrived at
some numbers like that by gauging user feedback.
So we could share a lot of notes with people,
get feedback on which ones are
helpful, and just a line emerged
about indicating where things go from
questionable to pretty clearly helpful.
Yeah. And it is set right now, by
the way, to be really conservative,
I think. We just are pretty particular about
quality and we really want note quality to
be really high. I think Keith and I both
believe that we live or die based on the
quality of the notes at the end of the day. So
we'd rather not show a note that maybe good,
but we didn't have enough signal
on than the other way around.
That makes so much sense. I've never seen a
Community Note that is wrong and breaking that
promise is a big deal. So I completely get
why you guys are super conservative there.
Okay. Two more questions [inaudible
00:19:53] because I'm just curious.
These weren't on my list of questions
to ask, but I feel like people wonder
this. How many notes are written versus
end up showing up and triggering on a-
We probably show about 8% of notes that
get proposed. It's been between, let's say,
7% and 10% or 11%, something like that over time.
The number can vary a little bit. And as Jay said,
there are undoubtedly... And you can see it,
there's clearly more good notes than we show,
but the goal is to hold a really high bar. We
want to show a note when it's going to be helpful,
when it's not going to appear biased and undermine
trust in the system. We want these to be neutral,
informative, helpful. And as Jay was saying, we
view the worst possible mistake as showing a bad
note because that's going to undermine trust
and the trust is why people like the product.
So yeah, the bar is there. And like I said,
there's clearly some in that remaining,
let's call it 90%, that are good. And
then, there's a lot that are just not
that great and there's some that are bad.
And if you write one of these ones that
are bad which bad being defined as people who
normally disagree find the note not helpful,
so it's like the inverse of the ones we show.
If you write one that people normally disagree,
find not helpful, you actually will ultimately
lose your ability to write and have to earn
it back. That other 90% is a mix. Sometimes
people look at the number, they're like, "Oh,
why don't you show more?" It's like, "Well,
you probably actually don't really want us
showing most of those." The gold here is that
the system is able to filter out the good ones.
That makes sense. Okay. One other question is
there's many people that are very polarized, like
very disagreeable with a lot of things. How do
they filter into this algorithm? How do you deal
with people that are super anti-vax, super Jan
6, like all these very extreme potential views?
If people really are so polarized that there isn't
agreement among people that typically disagree,
it's possible that this is one of those notes that
might be correct, but it wouldn't be helpful to
show as context. Maybe it's about a claim that
people have really entrenched opinions about and
they've read hundreds of things about it already.
Probably this is just not going to improve
people's understanding. It's just not going to be
a helpful user experience. So it might not be the
worst thing in those cases to not show the note.
People, a few years ago, were pretty pessimistic
that maybe fact-checking never changes people's
understandings about what's true. Actually,
there have been external studies run by people
totally independent of us who have found that if
you take a community note or posts with or
without a community note... That actually,
people's agreement with the core claims in
the post does change if they see it with
the note versus without. So we are having an
impact on this thing that people previously
thought was maybe not so easy to do.
And so, it's nice to focus on the cases
where there is the bridging agreement. I
would also say there is this reputation
component to the algorithm as well. So if
you consistently rate notes in a way that
is counter to the bridging-based consensus, then
we will stop counting your ratings. So if you're
the kind of person who constantly rates bad
notes as helpful, we do filter you out. So
there's a difference between those types of
people versus the good but polarized ones.
Yeah. I think one philosophical thing that's
important is that we want all of humanity to
participate. And sometimes, people are surprised
by that. They'll be like, "Oh, aren't there
people who shouldn't be doing this?", or like,
"Their thinking is so extreme or something,
maybe they shouldn't participate." But our view
is it's actually we want to have all of humanity
here. Because if we have all of humanity,
we then have the data to understand what
notes will be helpful to actual humanity.
We can better model that better or better
understand and better show those notes.
So it's advantageous to have people who have all
sorts of points of views and we don't expect that
every note will be loved by every single person.
That's an impossible bar. But we do intend to show
the notes that 80% of people are going to read and
say, "Wow. I'm glad I knew that." And so, in that
sense, it doesn't matter how maybe extreme someone
views a person's views as. It's still great to
have them in the program. So no matter what your
views are, please sign up and participate.
It helps identify what's really helpful.
Cool. And we'll link to people
if they want to actually sign up,
so they know how to do this. Something
we didn't actually specify, these are
all volunteers. No one's getting paid to
be doing these notes and voting, right?
Yeah. It's totally based on intrinsic motivation
and we think that's a great reason to be doing it.
When you talk to the most active contributors, a
lot of them, they want to have better information
out in the world and that's a great motivation.
So yeah, that's why they... If you think about,
like for these people, the impact they can have
is nuts. So when we first launched US-wide,
this was like in 2022, a note appeared on a
White House tweet and the White House deleted
the tweet and reissued an updated statement.
Imagine being the person who wrote that. You
probably have 12 followers. Your posts
probably get a couple likes. And here,
you just put a note on the White House and they
changed their public talking points based on what
you did. That is an incredible amount of impact.
So you could see why people are motivated to do
it when they care about what's going on
in the world. You don't have to be a big,
well-known person to shape the discourse and
information flow in a way that's helpful.
It's insane. There's so much to love about
this. One is just the meritocracy of this
whole operation of just anybody that
is true and correct can participate
and have impact. Also, it just shows you
how much information we get that is just
wrong. We had no idea how often we see
things that are wrong and now we do.
Working on this product has made
me realize just how many things
I used to trust by default, that
now I look at more skeptically.
Definitely mean these days. Okay. Before we
get to the origin story, is there anything else
along those lines you guys think might be really
important to share, that are really interesting?
Sure. I guess one other thing is that although
we don't actually use the fact that a post was
noted in the core ranking algorithm, which we
think is a nice property. There is a really big
impact just organically, meaning not from
the algorithm but just from user behavior,
where people will like and re-share
or quote posts way less when-
Quote. Posts way less when notes are applied. I
don't know, for people out there who typically
run A-B tests on big platforms, you may already be
familiar with this, but 1% is typically an awesome
effect size for any algorithm change. We saw more
like 30 to 40% engagement rate drops for likes and
reposts in A-B tests we were ran when showing a
post with or without a note, which is just crazy
big. That's just an A-B test on the engagement
rate, so that's not the network effect. If you
capture the overall network effect of how post
spread less by that person's repost, basically if
you look top line with a difference in differences
approach, multiple different external research
groups have both found consistently that there's
a 50 or 60% drop in total reposts, which is just
nuts after a note is applied. It's having a
really big impact on spread actually, too.
That's so great to hear. It's what I would want
to see and it's incredible impact. Basically, an
AI image of something false would just go crazy on
Twitter, and did before Community Notes came out,
and now what you're saying is just adding that
context, not actually... Like you're saying,
the algorithm doesn't demote it. If there's
something incorrect, it's just people are like,
"Okay, this is false, why would I want
to retweet this?" That makes sense.
Correct.
Right.
Yeah, the notes just totally take the wind out
these stories. The thing will be going viral,
note appears, resharing drops 50 to 60%,
and that's it. At 50 to 60% per generation,
the virality quickly goes to zero.
By the way, I have very mixed
feelings about this next one,
but authors become 80% more likely to decrease,
sorry, to delete their post after they get noted,
which okay, that's great, because less
misinfo out there, but I'm pan about,
because those are usually the best notes. If the
note was so just good that you had no other option
but to delete your post, those notes don't
get seen by other people, right? Because-
That's hard.
There's an argument, by the way, that
seeing... Just because you might see
the same misleading claim elsewhere off X,
or somewhere else on X, it might be good
to actually show... Better to have seen the
post with the note than not see it at all.
Yeah.
Unsure about that claim.
That is so interesting.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'd be so sad if I was that community note
writer and just... Man, it's so good. They just
can't even keep the post up. Okay. Coming back
from today's world, where this small amount of
code is changing the way people understand the
world and what they believe, and making the White
House rescind their announcements, zooming back to
the beginning of how this whole project started,
what I heard just briefly is, Keith, you were
just tired of managing PMs, you wanted to just
work on something yourself, you wanted to work
on something impactful away from corporate BS,
and you basically just started looking for
something that was impactful, important,
and you found this. Talk about just how it
all came to be at the beginnings of the story.
Yeah. I mean, for me, the beginnings
actually go back to why I joined,
it was then, Twitter in 2016. I had a startup
and we'd had some acquisition offers, and one of
them was from this company, Twitter. It was 2016,
it was the middle of the election between
Donald Trump and Hillary Clinton, and there were
something like three televised debates, but every
day, there was a debate happening on Twitter,
and it was very clear, this is where people
are talking about these things that matter,
where information is being shared, where ideas
are being formed. As a user, it was obvious that
I could get good information there, but it
was also obvious that there was questionable
information floating around. I remember just
looking, as an outsider, thinking like, "Wow,
this is a really hard problem and it also seems
really important," so we ended up going to Twitter
and the company was in a turnaround at that point.
My first three years was just helping to get the
company growing again, working on everything
that was the consumer product, getting user
growth going back and people wanting to work
there again, et cetera, but a few years in, I
was reflecting on what we had done. I think we had
done a lot of good work getting momentum going,
and people in the us and in the industry had
tried things to deal with misleading information,
but nothing was really working. It was obvious
nothing was working. Nothing could handle the
scale of the problem, nothing could handle the
speed, and a lot of people just didn't trust the
existing approaches. The existing approaches
were either fact-checkers or internal trust
and safety teams making decisions about what
was or was not misleading. A lot of people
just didn't want or trust that to be the way
this was decided, which is very reasonable.
I'm looking at that, I was still managing a
large PM team. That's a whole story in itself.
That job required a lot of energy in, and I didn't
feel like I always saw the output that I wanted
to see from it. I didn't see the change in the
product I wanted to see and I was contemplating,
"Should I go start a company? Should I do
something else?" And I kept coming back to this
problem. I'm like, "Man, how is the world going to
deal with this information quality issue of what
we get on social media?" Wherever get it. I'm at
this company where you can make a difference on
this problem, why not go and try some crazy ideas
and see if one of them might work? I had a kid,
I came back from paternity leave, I went to
my boss, Kayvon. I was like, "Hey, Kayvon.
How about I just stop doing my job and I go work
on this instead? 'This' being trying some crazy
ideas to see if we can deal with misleading info."
He was stoked, so I went off and started working
on that. It started with just reading any
research I could on the problem and existing
solutions. What was or was not working, what
were the issues, and then into prototyping.
Then it ultimately led to us building and
piloting this idea that became Community Notes.
Amazing. I have so many questions and we're
going to keep going through the story,
but when you joined Twitter, what was
the... It was called Twitter. At this point,
I'm going to try to call it X now, which I know
is important to your boss. What era of Twitter
was it at that point? It was Kayvon joined and
who was the CEO? Because there's been many.
Okay, yeah. I came in December 2016, so Jack
had relatively recently come back as CEO to
turn the company around, and just to give
you a sense of the state of the company,
something like a third of employees were
leaving every year. Just imagine a third
of your team gone every year. The stock was in
the toilet, the product was not really growing,
so Jack was working on a turnaround
and Kayvon was there already. Kayvon
was running Periscope with a bunch of video
stuff, and that group continued to... Jack was
there up through the start of the Community
Notes, then Birdwatch Project, and... Yeah.
Okay, and it was called Birdwatch. I
don't think we've used that term yet,
but that's an important point. It
was called Birdwatch initially.
Yeah. It was originally called Birdwatch
when we started the project, but obviously,
somewhat famously the name changed along the way.
Yeah, maybe let's just tell that story real
quick, and I know we're zooming it forward,
but just... I have this Twitter thread
that I saw between Jack and Elon when
they're debating what to call it, and
Elon's like, "Birdwatch sounds creepy,
I want to change it". Is there
anything there you can share?
Yeah, the story there... The story, that's funny.
Elon came in, acquired the company, and we had
just launched the product relatively recently
in the US. It had been in pilot for a year,
but we had just made it available US-wide, and I
guess he'd been seeing the notes. Soon after the
exhibition, he DM'd me and he was like, "Hey, this
Community Notes thing is awesome," and I was like,
"I'm glad you like it, let's talk," so we
talked the next day and he kept referring
to it as "This Community Notes thing." I was
like, "It's interesting you keep calling it that,
because that's actually the very first thing that
I called it." The very first figma mockup I made
depicting this thing was called "Community Notes."
I don't know why, it just felt really natural,
so that's the first prototype we had tested.
Later, the project changed the same to Birdwatch,
but Elon was like, "Hey, let's just call it
that." The next day, we just changed the name.
It's always notable for the team when you
change the name, but really, the team was
excited about it. I think it is a much more
understandable name. Jack has made fun of it,
calling it "The ultimate Facebook
name," or something like that.
The most boring Facebook
name [inaudible 00:36:44].
Boring name, which is funny, because they're
now launching Community Notes. I think it is
a very understandable, intuitive name,
and I think it has served the product
really well. There's a reason it was
the name in the very first mockup.
Yeah, I think descriptive names just
makes sense. This connection with Elon,
and I want to talk later about just how you've
dealt with so many strong personalities over and
kept this alive throughout so many changes, but
before we get to that, you did something that I
think a lot of product leaders, angel leaders,
just people that have managed people dream of
give up all this power, in air quotes, and
career trajectory and influence and just,
"Forget all that. I'm going to go back
to just building something awesome,
small team." Is there any advice there that
you could share from that experience that you
think might be helpful for other leaders to
share or to hear to help them maybe do that
same jump? Because that's really difficult
in practice. Easy to talk about, hard to do.
Yeah, I think it is a difficult jump. I've done
it a bunch of times in my career and I've always
been very happy with it, where I started with a
small team, that it grew into something bigger,
and then I was like, "We're dealing
with a lot of big production stuff,
team's really big. I want to go back to doing
something like crazy and new with a small team
again." I've done that sawtooth leap a bunch of
times, but it can be hard, because certainly,
the natural... The classic career path is, I don't
know, rewards or running a large organization or
being a manager, or things like that, but I
think, at the end of the day, you got to work
on stuff you love, you got to be having fun,
and I think people want to be having impact.
I think there's one myth that can get in people's
ways. The idea that the more people you manage or
the larger your scope is, the more impact you
have. I definitely do not think that is true.
I mean, look at Community Notes for example. If
I had stayed running a large consumer PM team,
what would I have produced? 16 more pages of
OKRs? I don't know, a bunch of documents? I
think building Community Notes has had way
bigger impact on the world. It's become the
industry standard for how to deal with this now,
which is super cool. People love it, it's the
first thing that is plausibly dealing with the
internet-scale issue of information quality. I
think it's unquestionably a bigger impact than
I would've had if I were just doing whatever,
doing some standard management track thing like
I was doing before. I think that's true of so
many other small companies and startups. Someone
screenshotted I think it's Blake Scholl's LinkedIn
the other day. He went from director of coupons
or something to building the first supersonic-
Yeah, from Groupon.
Those stories are everywhere when you look,
so I definitely have found that, for me,
I love building hands-on, I love trying crazy
new ideas. I love the zero-to-one experience.
It's fun to scale things up too, and it can
be fun to operate at scale, but this team is
a good example of one that operates at a very
large scale, but that is still very small.
Yeah, I think the way you guys operate is
what more and more companies are trying to do,
remove middle management layers, create small
teams that just execute and build impact,
just like Ics. Whenever I say IC, I
have a comment on YouTube, where like,
"What is IC?" I'm just going to
explain, individual contributor,
non-manager is when I say the word IC. Let me
follow this thread, and when I asked people about
how you set up the team to operate effectively
and protect it initially, there's this term,
"Thermal," that came up a lot. It was like a
thermal team, if that's how you describe it.
Yeah.
What is thermal?
Yeah, so anyone who's worked in a larger
company probably knows that things can get
bureaucratic or bogged-down, decision-making can
be slow. There's these large planning cycles,
people can try to take someone from
one team, move them to another at
random arbitrary times that can disrupt
a project, all sorts of things like that.
Our company, this is a number of years ago
when we started this project, we had a lot of
founders in the company. Kayvon is an example
of founder who is helping to run the company,
and he had this idea, "Hey, why don't
we create this program, call it Thermal,
where we could have teams that were somewhat
isolated from that." They could run through their
own process, they would have one clear owner.
The team would be entirely dedicated to that
project and we would just repeatedly make funding
decisions as to whether to continue the effort.
Why was it called Thermal, by
the way? What was the idea there?
I think it was an old bird analogy of thermals
lifting the bird on their wings. Twitter 1.0
obviously had a lot of bird analogies, bless its
heart, so that was one of them. I loved the idea,
as someone who liked the startup environment, so
when we were starting this project, I was like,
"Hey, Kayvon. Why don't we make this the
first Thermal project?" And he was like,
"Yeah, let's do it," so we started with that
way of operating and it gave us, from day one,
a lot of freedom and autonomy that I think
was really important to make the product work.
Just be very specific about it. What makes it a
Thermal project? How do you set that
up? This is asking from perspective,
if a company wants to build their own
something like this, what does that look like?
Yeah, I think there's a bunch of key attributes.
One key attribute is there's one clear driver of
the project, who's effectively a founder. I guess
maybe you could have two or something, but really
clear, there's driver of the project and also
there's one clear decision-maker that they go to.
Outside of the team?
Outside of the team. That was
true back when we started and
it is true now. If we need something
or have a question about something,
I talk to Elon. It was like that from
the beginning, it's like that now, and I
think that's a big reason we're able to make
decisions effectively, quickly, in a simple way.
It probably has to be someone very
senior, not [inaudible 00:43:05] manager.
Someone senior who can make the decisions you need
made, whatever they are. I think that's really
important, that clear decision-making structure.
Another was 100% focus, so everyone on the project
is expected to be totally focused on it. A lot
of companies, it can be easy to have people's
attention spread across a bunch of things, and
it makes it hard to get stuff done. You'll talk
to whoever that person is, you'll ask them for
help on something, and they'll be like, "Yeah,
I'll help you. I got to finish this thing, and
it'll take me a week or two and then I'll get
to it." A week or two delay totally changes the
momentum of a project. When we were 100% focused,
we talk in the morning, it's like, "Hey, Jay.
Why don't we try this thing in the algorithm?"
He's like, "Yeah." Then that afternoon or
the next day, we're looking at results.
Because of that total focus, the rate of
iteration goes way up. Then beyond that,
there was also just the ability to use
whatever our own decision-making process
was. We didn't need to write OKRs or...
For others standard practices. Obviously,
we had to make sure we were responsibly building
the product and everything, but we didn't need to
use the standard practices. I think that's another
great example, OKRs, I understand why they can be
helpful, but they can also be not necessarily the
right cadence at which to set goals. I think it's
really unclear that quarterly or annual goals
are actually the right pace. We would set the
goal for the next milestone that mattered, and
we would work on that. We reached that milestone,
we would have an idea of what was coming after,
and then when we hit that, we'd set the next
milestone. Whether that was two weeks, a month,
three months, whatever it was. We set our own pace
and goals at that pace, and that just I think is a
lot more natural for the development of something.
The whole OKR determination and
planning process took longer than
it would take us to pick a goal and
then execute on it and finish it.
How big was the team early on that
you set up? How many engineers?
It started with just me and then, when we
decided to build the thing, we figured we
needed about five. We wanted it to be as small as
we possibly could. It was clear we needed someone
on ML doing scoring, it was clear we needed
someone to do some client engineering work,
someone to do backend engineering work. There may
have been one or two other. We needed a designer
and a researcher to help us understand the
customer base and make sure we were building the
thing in a way that was actually going to resonate
with people. I think it was backend, frontend,
ML, design research. That was the
original team, from what I remember.
Amazing. Basically, one of each function.
A question I have for Jay, actually,
is there's all this talk of small teams
and moving fast, but sometimes you just
need more engineers to build the thing. Is there
anything you've learned about just how to keep a
team small while moving as fast as you are,
and not need or need to hire more engineers?
I think, in the beginning when we were iterating
on what should even the requirements be,
it was definitely good to just have one
ML engineer, but I think, at some point,
we got clear on what the goals of the algorithm
should really be and we tried... I think,
at the very beginning, it wasn't clear that we
needed to build this bridging-based algorithm.
The actual first algorithm that I put into
production was very focused on anti-manipulation.
It was this page rank variant, but
it didn't solve the problem of bias,
basically. If there are more users on one side,
a page rank type graph algorithm can actually
amplify those biases. I think, after building
that prototype and getting data from that,
it was clear that the bridging-based algorithm was
going to be the way that we needed to solve it,
and at that point, basically I set up a
bake-off. Kind of a Kaggle competition or
something. That was the key time where it was
really important to pull in other engineers.
That is such a cool story. I want to follow that
thread. Before we do that, you just mentioned you
guys yell "Thermal." What does that mean?
Is that YOLO, like a version of... Okay.
We're just going to ship,
because we're thermal project.
Ship it.
Okay. Marketers, I know that you love [inaudible
00:47:52], so let me get right to the point. Wix
Studio gives you everything you need to cater to
any client at any scale, all in one place. Here's
how your workflow could look. Scale content with
dynamic pages and reusable assets effortlessly,
fast-track projects with built-in
marketing integrations like Meta,
CAPI, Zapier, Google Ads, and more. A-B
test landing pages in days, not weeks,
with intuitive design tools, connected
tracking, and analytics tools, like Google
Analytics and Semrush. Encapture key business
events without the hassle of manual setup,
manage all your client's social media and
communications from a unified dashboard,
then create, schedule, and post content across all
their channels. If you're working on content-rich
sites, Wix Studio's No-Code CMS lets you build
and manage without touching the design. When
you're ready for more, Wix Studio grows with you.
Add your own code, create custom integrations
with Wix-made APIs, or leverage robust native
business solutions. Drive real client growth
with Wix Studio. Go to Wixstudio.com.
Okay, so coming back to this algorithm,
this is actually really interesting, because I've
never heard any of this. I was going to ask just
what inspired this actual algorithm, and you
basically did an internal competition amongst
ML engineers to see who had the most successful
algorithm. Netflix-contest style, Kaggle style.
Yeah, yeah. This particular idea of finding
content that is liked by people on opposite
sides of a polarized divider who typically
disagree, this was not an idea out of thin air.
I think Keith had found some of Chris Bale's
work, he had made this list of accounts that
were often liked by people who were on both
sides politically. There is other projects,
like polls out there that look for agreement among
people who typically disagree, but I think that
it wasn't obvious that our project definitely
needed to use that from the very beginning.
When you implement it and compare it against
these other type... PageRank seems, obviously,
it's designed to be manipulation-resistant.
Naturally, if you just have a voting ring
of people who all vote themselves up, then
PageRank can filter that out very well, but
that just wasn't the main attack vector, I guess.
We had to get some real data from the pilot to
realize that, "Okay, the real thing going
on here is people are polarized," so it
was only once we got that, the real data
from the pilot, that I think it was clear
that the bridging-based algorithm was
the direction we really needed to go.
I want to come back to the way you
operate the team. I hear that you
run the whole team off a single Google
Doc that's like a four-year-old doc
that you just keep adding goals
to, bullet points. Is that true?
There is a very long-running doc that has had to
be chopped and purged, because it was breaking
Google Docs in Chrome at various points in time.
It's like a note-taking doc. It's really where we
coordinate what we're doing. The team meets on
a daily basis, we spend whatever amount of time
we need to get on the same page about what we're
building. We might talk about anything from what's
most important right now to, "What should we work
on next?" To, "What are we trying to launch right
now, and why is it not launched? What's in the
way of launching it?" We might review new modeling
or scoring algorithm update and try to understand
what's working in it, what's not. We'll just cover
whatever we want or whatever feels most important.
As you said, we set our goals very dynamically,
so whatever seems like the most important thing
for us to work on now and next is what we spend
our time on. I think that's served the project
really well versus feeling attached to some
quarterly goals, or something. We'll look at,
"What is going to help people the most?" Or,
"What's the biggest problem right now?" What
are either one of those? And we will go tackle
it. We might change our roadmap multiple
times in two weeks based on what we see.
I'm hearing no Jira, no Asana, no Monday.com.
No.
Okay.
Yeah, I mean, we have to use Jira to coordinate
with some other teams. Sometimes when we file
a request, we have to make a Jira ticket.
But no, I am not a fan of heavyweight task
management. I love being on the same page,
being able to keep most things in my head,
and having a really light way to write down the
things that the team can't keep in its head.
We did use Asana briefly, but my memory
of it is that you spent more time in the
meeting grooming a backlog of
irrelevant stuff than actually
talking about the proper priorities. I
think it's nice in the Google Doc that,
if something becomes irrelevant, it can just fall
off without needing explicit backlog grooming.
Just to maybe summarize a little bit of how you
guys operate that might inspire other companies
to set teams up like this, so I'm going to
go through a few things you shared. One is
one person in charge of the team, like the
founder almost. They're basically the founder
of the team. They have one very senior,
essentially, sponsor/decision-maker that
they interface with. In your case, Elon, no big
deal. In other cases, it could be the CTO, CPO,
someone like that. The team is focused 100% on its
product and goal. You keep the team very small,
so you start with one person of each function. One
front-end engineer, back-end, ML person, designer,
researcher, PM, and then Google Docs is almost
basically for your project management. Yeah,
it's basically run with Google Docs,
stop, don't use big, complicated products.
I think that's a pretty good recipe. On
the Google Docs, people can do what they
want. If they want to use thumbnails, go for
it. I think those first ingredients, really,
are key structurally. Then beyond that, it's a
matter of having an ambitious goal that gets-
And then beyond that, it's a matter of having an
ambitious goal that gets people
fired up to go do great work.
Yeah. Awesome. I think there's
a lot there that a lot of people
think they should do when they set these
teams up, but they don't actually do,
and it feels like each of these is just a really
key ingredient to it to actually succeeding.
It definitely really helped us
succeed. I don't know that the
project would be here if it was
not for some of those elements.
That's a powerful statement. This thing that
has changed the way the world understands what
is true would not have existed if you
didn't set it up in this specific way.
Yeah. I don't know if I would've
begun the project had I not known.
We had that structure, that ability to
make decisions, the autonomy, the speed,
the ability to go fast. We started with that
in 1.0 and it's been continued and if anything,
furthered in X. X as a whole company operates
with a lot of those attributes, and I think it's
one of the reasons the product is successful.
I think those are big reasons why at least,
Jay can speak for himself, I have so much fun
working on this. I love working on it. It's
great to wake up every day and solve these
problems. We get to do them efficiently,
make decisions quickly, build stuff that
helps a lot of people. It's awesome.
This whether thermal or Elon way of operating
is definitely more fun and the fact that...
That combined with the awesome mission is super
important for internal recruiting. I remember
when I was first chatting to Keith about this
back in early 2020, I had another project. I
worked on a few, but one was like personalize
the number of push notifications that we send,
and it drove a lot of DAU without losing opt-outs
significantly. So that was setting me on track,
or if I had kept working on that, I could have
probably gotten a promotion from that with low
risk, or I could take this huge career...
It's not as big at a career risk as joining
or founding an actual external startup,
but there is still career risk, I guess,
in joining a team like this. I think all of
the same aspects of recruiting that apply to
external startups and apply internally, and if
you can have an exciting vision, that is key.
Related to that and your list, Lenny, one
thing we missed that's super important
is that on this project, and I think of
successful projects like it in startups,
is that people are self-selecting to join. We
did not assign anyone to this project. People
reached out to join or they applied to join the
job. I and the team interviewed every single
person that joined the team and we were like,
"We want that person on the team. They want to
be on the team." And so people are totally bought
in to the goal, mission, the way the team works,
the other people they're going to be working
with. And that makes a huge difference.
So a great time to do that is at the start of one
of these things. If you're going to try something
crazy, it's going to be tough if you're just
assigning random people to it. But if you let
people opt in and self-select much more likely to
be successful. And one thing that I have observed
at X, which really surprised me was that this
is also possible at a large scale. One of the
things that Elon did when he bought the company
was he basically asked people to self-select to
stay. You had to click the button. And he sent
an email out that was like, "Hey, Twitter 2.0."
Fork in the road. Right? [inaudible 00:57:46]
Fork in the road. Fork in the road.
Exactly. He's like, "Twitter 2.0,
now X, it's going to be hardcore. We're
going to do ambitious things. You're going
to work your butt off." And you had
to click on the form and say, "Yes,
I want to join." And I think that was really
important for the company because you want
people to opt into that. You want the people
to be saying, "Yeah, that's what I want to
do," and the company's going to be a lot
more successful. If people aren't sure,
it's better for them probably to go do something
else and where they're naturally more aligned and
happier. And I thought that was a great approach
to taking a large company and getting it down to
people who are really excited about working
together on a mission. So for us, we did it
from day one, which I think is an easy way to
do it, but it's possible to do it later as well.
I love that you described it as fun and I
think a lot of people when they see Elon
laying off a bunch of people, being very
hardcore himself, people don't imagine it
as a fun place to work. And it's clear
how much you guys love working on this,
how fun it is and how interesting it is. And
it's interesting to hear that 'cause I think a
lot of people don't feel that externally. Is there
anything else along the lines of just working for
Elon within an org Elon runs that might surprise
people about just the way of working that's
interesting or surprising or you think other
companies might want to think about adopting?
I've always liked lean teams, but my experience
at X has made me change the way I would think
about running a future org-... If I were to start
a company and had to change the way I think about
starting that company, I would be even leaner than
I would've made it before. I've been amazed with
just how much the team is able to accomplish
with a small group. And I think because of
a small group, shortly after the acquisition, we
had this product called Spaces. It had been in the
product before, but it was pretty small scale,
and Elon wanted to run these large spaces. I
forget who the first people he was going to bring
on were, but he was going to be there. Ultimately,
these things have gone on to host politicians
and things like that, and he's like, "Guys,
we got to scale this up." I forget the numbers.
He's like, "We need to be able to scale a million
people," or something like that. I'm getting
the numbers wrong. "You need to be able to scale
way up." This is the kind of thing at 1.0 That
would've taken a year if it had ever happened,
and the team did it in two or three weeks. And it
was really exciting and inspiring to see. I didn't
work on that, but I watched it from the outside.
I'm like, "Wow, with this tiny team motivated
behind a big goal that was like, 'Hey, guys,
it's not like, are we going to do this?' It's,
'We are going to do this.'" They got it done in
two or three weeks. That must've felt amazing
for them. It was certainly exciting to see.
But I've definitely come to appreciate just
how lean something can be and not just get by
but actually thrive because it's that lean.
I think the point you made about
people opting into that is important,
'cause I think a lot of people hearing
that would be like, "I would never want
to be asked to build something like that in
two weeks." And I think a lot of people do,
and we love that kind of experience, especially
working with the Elon, especially shipping
something at that scale. But I think there's
an important element there of just like,
"Okay, I don't want to do that. I have
other things to do in my life other than
ship spaces." So I think that's a key point
you've raised of just there's an opt-in step.
Totally. I think the opt in is important,
and it may even be that you want to opt in at
one point in your life, and maybe at another
point in your life something else is better.
I think whatever it is you're choosing to do,
it's nice to be opting in to feel like it's
aligned with how you want to spend your time.
Something on my mind, and I don't
know if you guys want to go here,
but it's something I think a lot of
people think about is when Elon came in,
he let go of 80% of folks. And everyone's just
like, "Twitter is dead. It's all going to fall
apart. There's no way they can run this thing
with that small of a staff," and clearly they
were wrong. Clearly, it's working great.
It's becoming a massive deal in the world
and continues to grow. Is there anything
about that that you were surprised by
or anything about just how it continues to
operate so well in spite of that big shift?
I think the leaner team, the reduced process in
bureaucracy is a big reason it does move as fast
as it does. It's easier to get stuff done faster
here. Yeah. I think that shrinking is actually a
big reason for the increased pace of launches, the
increased pace of experimentation. One thing that
I noticed a result of that is the people who are
here, they seem to all really feel like owners.
They take the sense of responsibility that an
owner takes in the product. They'll try to track
down what's wrong, fix whatever is needed, jump
in to help build or fix, improve any system that
needs help, even if it's outside of their space.
And there's the flip side of that too. For people
who've worked at big companies, they may have
experienced this thing where there's like ano-...
You want to change something in some other system
or product, and so you reach out to that team. And
maybe they're a little resistant, they'll maybe be
like, "Oh, we'll get to that next quarter or so-
They have their own goals to
hit. Yeah. [inaudible 01:03:08]
Yeah. Exactly. They don't really necessarily want
to help you or they're busy. Here, you're like,
"Hey, guys, we need to do this thing with that
other system you work on." And they're like,
"Great! Here's the code. Here are the docs.
Send us the fab if you have any questions,
and we'll get it in." And it's just the thing, you
can just jump in and get it done. And that kind
of collaborative effort, like the sense of shared
ownership, I think from my experience came from or
was a result of the shrinking of the team down to
people who wanted to be there and work together to
build this thing. So I think that's been a really
positive impact. It's not always easy. Certainly,
a lot of people have a lot of responsibilities,
but they're here because they're up for it.
Yeah. I think one other thing that's key is when
you are forced to have such a small team, well,
this is important anyways, but deleting code is
more important than writing it a lot of the time.
So I think so often maybe due to promotion
incentives or just regular human tendency,
engineers have a tendency to add these little
incremental wins that actually add more of
a long-term maintenance cost than is clear,
because you just run a little one month A-B test,
you see this significant win and you don't
realize the maintenance burden you just added
to your team for the rest of eternity until you
turn the thing off. So I think there's a lot
to be gained and you get forced to do this, by
the way, when you have such a small team. It's
just auditing parts of your system and deleting
the things where the maintenance cost is worse
than the gains. So I think we did have to do
this across the company after the big layoffs,
and systems are leaner now and they can
be worked on by fewer numbers of people.
That's an amazing point. I
remember Elon's being like,
"Here, we have to throw away the whole
thing. We have to re-architect everything.
It's stupid the way it's built." And
it sounds like that actually worked.
Yeah, so-
Well.
You don't have to rewrite everything
from scratch. Some things are good,
I guess, to rewrite. But just
even deleting the unnecessary
cruft and keeping the rest of
the core system, that's awesome.
I love that we're creating a formula to run
these sorts of companies and teams. There's
so much here. I want to go back to the building of
the original product. I took us on a long tangent
and an amazing tangent, but I heard a story
of when you launched Birdwatch at that point.
You specifically wanted to keep expectations
very low and there was a GIF in the thing,
and it just looked like clearly this is not ready
for prime time. Talk about just how you did that,
how you launched it in a way where people
weren't like, "It's never going to work."
We were very disciplined, I guess you could
say, about having the product prove itself
at every given point. When we built the first
mockups, these were just pictures of depicting
what community notes might look like. We showed
those to people across the political spectrum.
We saw, hey, people really like these.
Whether they're on the right or left,
they seem very open to reading these community
notes even when they're critical to people of
their own side. So we're like, "All right. That
gives us confidence that if we can build this,
if we can actually make this as a reality, it's
going to work." Then there's a question of can we
make it a reality? Will people in the real world
be able to write notes that are of this quality?
And so we had an internal pilot test version of
this where you could write notes. And we first
basically ran this through an Amazon MTurk type
of participant test just to see if you just put
some normal people in there, will they be able to
write these notes? All those notes weren't good,
but it was clear that there were people out there
who could write good notes. So then like, "Okay,
this is possible. What will happen if we
actually do this out in the real world?
And let's run a pilot and find out." And
so we took that pilot that we'd run the
MTurk of test on, and we released it to at
first 1000 people, totally out in public,
and we didn't know what was going to show up. You
could imagine the notes could have been terrible.
And so we were talking, "Well, what do we do?
We're going to put this out there. Everyone's
going to have all these questions. They're
probably going to be really skeptical, and
we know it might be a total dumpster fire. And so
what do we do to set expectations appropriately?"
We felt like we could probably get there in the
end, but we just didn't know what was going to
happen at first. We wanted to set expectations,
and so we're like, "Well, why don't we just
stick..." There's the page where you see a post
in the notes below. We're like, "Why don't we
just stick a dumpster fire GIF on that page?" And
you go there, you're like, "Hey, anything you see
below here might just be a total dumpster fire.
At least it would show we were aware of that as a
possible risk." In the end, we did not do that.
It cracked me up, but we thought it was like-
Oh, you didn't actually launch.
Okay. That was just a concept. Okay.
We had mockups of it, and every time
I looked at the mockup, I laughed,
but ultimately we had so much to explain on that
page, like, what is this thing and how does it
work? Ultimately, we're like, "Okay, this is
probably going to distract from the point."
So we pulled it. I wish maybe it had seen the
light of day at one point, but yeah, ultimately
we kept it simple and we focused that page on
explaining what was going on here. But again,
as has happened many times with the project, we
put the pilot out there and the notes were good.
They weren't all good. It was a mixed
bag, but there was gold in there. And
from the very early days with just
1000 contributors, it was obvious
that people could write notes that were
informative, that were neutral, that spoke
to controversial challenging topics, and that
if we could just identify those from the rest,
this was going to work. It was going to
work as well as the very first mockups we
had made. So that became the focus that is,
how do we sift out the gold from the rest?
I think you may have shared with this with me,
when someone noticed you guys were testing this
and they took screenshots and tweeted it,
and I think Elon replied, "This is cool."
Yeah. Yeah. So in the very early days
when it was just a Figma prototype,
we were running these usertesting.com on moderated
studies. I guess one of the participants sent
one to an NBC reporter who wrote a bunch of
stories on it. Anyway, that day, there was
a lot of chatter about it on the service, and
Elon... To put this back in time perspective,
this is, I think, 2020, so two years before any
acquisition stuff happened, Elon is just a Twitter
user building rockets and electric cars and other
cool stuff and stumbles on this thing that depicts
the prototype that we've been testing. And he
writes back, "Definitely worth trying, IMO."
And I remember thinking that was cool back then
and it's interesting to see, he's obviously had a
very consistent point on it. I think the idea was
appealing and he has obviously been a big fan of
it in the product and had been a big supporter
proponent. So yeah, it was cool that it came
from... that support has been from the very early
days before he was ever involved in the company.
I love that moment. That must have felt really
wild for Elon to be commenting on
this Figma prototype retesting.
It was cool. It was cool.
Oh, man. So when we were preparing for this
interview, I asked you guys what's the main
thing you want to make sure people get and
understand about why community notes has been
so effective? And Keith, you specifically said
that it was the principles behind how you wanted
to approach this and how you continue to stick
to this throughout. And we'll talk about how
you kept it alive throughout all these different
CO changes in leaders. But just talk about these
principles, what the actual principles are
and why that was so key to it working out.
There are a number of principles that I think
when we first shared them with people at the
company seemed maybe a little bit crazy. But
I think they are the reason the product works,
and I think they've been very important, and we
do. We come back to them regularly, today, all
the time. Probably the craziest one is just that
this thing is going to be the voice of the people.
It's going to represent the voice of people. It's
not going to represent the company's voice. So it
is not a tech company deciding what shows. It
is the people deciding what shows, and that
had a lot of implications on the design. First of
all, we don't have a button that will change the
status of a note. So if a note is showing because
the people have rated it and found it helpful,
it is going to show. We can't change that.
And that is the kind of thing that when we first
propose this, that's unsettling to people. They're
like, "Wait, so something can go up and the
company can't take it down, or can't change its
status, get it to stop showing." And we're like,
"Yeah, and it has to work that well. If it doesn't
work well enough to do that, then it doesn't
work." This is one of our key principles was,
if there's a problem with a note that's so bad,
you want to do something about it's a problem
with the system. We need to redesign the system
to be showing good notes. And so yeah, we had
to get everyone comfortable with the idea that
there was no button to change the status of a
note. Similarly, as we talked about earlier,
we wanted this to represent all of humanity.
And so we didn't want to be arbiters of who
can come in and be a contributor and who can't.
So we open it to everyone. You just have to meet a
really basic objective criteria. You have to have
a verified phone to help reduce the likelihood of
having bots or things like that participating.
But beyond that, it's random selection and it
still is that way today. And again, that people
took some time to get people comfortable with
it. But I think that the fact that this is the
voice of the people and reflects their output
through an open and transparent process is
so key to both why it is good, why it works,
but also why it's trusted. So that's
number one and I think will forever be
the heart of the product. Another one that
people thought was crazy was transparency.
The previous approaches to dealing with
misleading info, it felt to a lot of people,
like black box tech companies or media companies
or leads or whatever making decisions. We're like,
"People need to get comfortable with this. They
need to trust this. So the whole thing has to be
out in the open." The code that decides what notes
share has to be out in the open. All of the data
and ratings that make it happen have to be out
in the open. People should be able to take the
code and data and replicate the whole service
and that we have done exactly what we've said
we've done. And they should be able to audit
it. They should be able to go and look and say,
"Hey, I think this part could be better."
Or if they think we're biased, they should be able
to work with the data and point it out. And if
people have good observations, that should factor
back into the code. And this is, again, something
that's difficult to get people comfortable with,
that everything is out there, you can't cover
anything up. But I think that's so essential to
people trusting it. Yeah, we set these out on day
one. We go back to them constantly because we're
always evolving the product, and we're always
like got to make sure every new change is open.
Whenever we update the scoring system, there's an
update in GitHub when the data is published daily
so you can download it. And so yeah, I think those
have been really essential to the thing working.
And by the way, these do not come without a
cost. It's actually really hard from an end
perspective to actually open source the actual
algorithm that's running on the actual data.
Because the way large-scale services
like this are usually architected does
not naturally lend itself to being run as a
script by someone who's downloaded a TSV. So
we actually have to take weird architectural
decisions to make this possible in a way that
probably wouldn't have been if we didn't
start with this assumption from scratch.
We would've had to maybe rewrite
the system to make it like this.
What's an example of that?
For instance, there's a matrix
factorization that we train. Usually, you
would train a matrix factor... train your
ML model once and then serve it, I guess
with a separate service. But we didn't want to
have people externally spinning up services to
be able to replicate the system that we had.
So basically, I don't think it would've been
actually very cool if we had open sourced the code
in a way that wasn't actually runnable, I guess,
by someone just... At this point, you
can download Python code and run a
script. You do need a lot of RAM right
now, but you can do it on one machine.
Okay. How much RAM are we talking about?
Oh, only like 500 gigs.
Okay. Okay. That's reasonable.
It'll take a day if you don't do anything
special to speed it up. Good to know, but yeah.
Cool.
Possible is the key thing, and people have
done it. Vitalik Buterin had a blog post
where he talks about his explorations, making
sure the algorithm really does what it says
it does. And I think just the fact that a
handful of people have done this, there's
enough people who have done it that there's
someone you'd probably trust who's verified it.
And that's rolling out to Meta. No big deal.
I love just as you described these principles,
just I could imagine a PM at a company being like,
"Okay, guys. Here, I want to do this project."
There's so much idealism to it that rarely works
in real life; going to be open source. You're
going to give it to everyone. We don't have actual
control over what it's going to do, don't worry
about it. It's going to just change the way people
see this thing that we've been very careful about
and then it works. And I think that's very rare
and it's really impressive. And what I'm hearing
partly is that sticking to those principles was
actually really fundamental to it working and not
bending over when someone's like, "No, no, no,
we can't do this. What if we change this part?"
I think if we had broken with any of those
principles, if there was anything black box,
if there was whatever, the product would
be a lot harder to trust. And so I think
it's because we've just stuck to them so
cleanly simply that people can trust it.
You've talked about a few moments when it
was like, wow, the White House changed their
announcement because of the community note. We
talked about the dog is a cat. Are there any other
moments that after you launched of, "Holy shit,
this is working? This is going to actually work."
All along, we saw it working. We wanted to
be confident whenever we expanded it to new
audiences or new countries or whatever, we
wanted to be confident it was going to work.
So maybe held our breath a little bit just
to see that it would do what we expected,
but we always expected that. But
that said, there were definitely
stress cases. The one that comes to mind
is the start of the Israel Hamas conflict
in 2023 in October. That was probably the largest
deluge of misleading information I've ever seen
shared on the internet at one time. It was
overwhelming. A number of photos and videos
and whatever coming out related to that, it
was insane. And just to give you an example,
I think it was first three days or something
of that conflict, we had 500 notes covering
all sorts of different... out of context imagery.
Someone would say, "Hey, this is happening here."
It's actually from 2013 in Syria. There
were people making fake battle footage
in the video game simulator Arma
3. So there were notes explaining,
this stuff looked realistic. And unless you saw
the note, you wouldn't really know. There are all
sorts of claims about what was going on in the
ground, and that was definitely... The product
was still pretty new at that point. We'd expanded
in the U. S. less than a year before that. We had
been rolling out throughout the world that year
and then this large event happened. And I felt
like we were just enough prepared at the right
time for the system to be able to handle that.
Probably one of the most important things we did
right before that was launch the ability to write
notes on images and videos and have those matched
to other posts. I remember at that time thinking,
"Wow, I'm glad we launched that feature a few
months ago versus still had it on the shelf,"
because it was really important in that conflict.
And I think even it was just a few weeks before we
had launched a major speed up in notes too. When
we first built the product, the number one focus
was always quality. We knew that the product
would live and die by the quality of the notes.
That was the thing we could never give up on. We
also knew it needed to deliver speed and scale,
but we're like, "We will get the quality in the
right place, and we can speed it up and scale-
Get the quality in the right place and we can
speed it up and scale it out over time. And we
had actually just launched a speed-up that took
three hours off the time it needed to go live,
and it was I think a matter of weeks
before that conflict happened, so again,
super glad that was out there. In the first
few days of the conflict the median time
from a post going live to a note showing up
was five hours, which is like crazy fast.
Typical fact checking is like two to
four, at least it's really common to
see it take two to four days. These notes
were showing up in five hours and we're like,
we are so glad we got those things out before this
happened, it made the service a lot more helpful.
One other thing that was, I think, nice to see
working then was, one criticism of Community
Notes some people bring up is, well if you always
need agreement from people who typically disagree,
then in these super polarized settings,
that conflict being probably number one,
then you wouldn't see any notes. But actually
the reality was there were tons of notes about
that conflict. So I think there was this
kind of nice property where actually,
and maybe this is a surprising fact, that
there's more agreement out there across
polarized divides than maybe conventional wisdom
says, and the places where people agreed were
really objectively true and verifiable. I guess
maybe this is more true the more polarized the
setting is, but where the agreement actually
lends you, and basically notes that are very
neutrally written, very focused on the
facts and easy to verify information.
There's this talk for a while of just there's
no more facts, nobody believes there is a single
true fact anymore, everything is subjective, and
I think Community Notes proves the opposite. Facts
matter, there are facts that we can all agree
with even on the most controversial topics.
Yeah, we saw this really from day one, when
we would show those prototypes to people just
depicting the idea, it was really obvious that
people cared more about, or they cared a lot
about understanding reality and what was going on
and they were willing to disagree with their side,
so to speak, to recognize that. And I think
that's not always that obvious to people.
The world does feel really polarized,
but people definitely are willing to
cross partisan boundaries to get to accurate
information and that's why the product works.
It feels like as we rely more and more on what we
know and understand about the world is becoming
social media online and moving this quickly, it's
like I'm so thankful this exists because otherwise
it'd just be, what do we trust anymore? This being
out aligns with we need this thing to exist at the
same time. And it feels like at the same time
there's also people I just don't trust. I think
people have shifted from I trust what I read to,
okay, I shouldn't just believe everything I'm
reading. Is there anything there you're noticing
about just how people think about news they see
and their shift of just like, I'm not going to
believe everything. Is there anything that you've
noticed about just human behavior or just the
way we've shifted understanding what is true?
We haven't done any research to look broadly
at how people's perceptions are changing there,
but I certainly have found myself that
particularly seeing notes, I am more
skeptical about what I read at first, and I think
that's been helpful. And we hear that from people,
that they think about things a bit more, and I
think that's a good secondary effect and benefit
of something like this, which is the more you
see the patterns of how what you're reading can
be wrong, the more you can thoughtfully question
it and try to get a better understanding of what's
really going on. So historically I think this
was called media literacy, but basic idea of
can you understand the ways in which things
can go wrong and try to cut them yourself.
Another aspect I think we help with that is
discovery of the Community Notes. I think often
before Community Notes you could have just
been living in a little news filter bubble,
or maybe there were fact checks
out there that you should have
been reading but you weren't discovering
them. So the fact that the note applies,
it is directly attached to the post and
visible by anyone who sees the post helps
cross those filter bubbles and can kind of...
I think for some people it's the first time
they've actually seen counter arguments to
claims made in their own little echo chamber.
That's incredible, yeah. I love the point
you're making about how it actually teaches
people to be a little more skeptical of
the things they read. It's an education
system more than just, here, this
one thing is wrong. I love that.
Okay, just a few more questions. There
was an audience question asked on Twitter,
we all asked on Twitter, "What do people
want to know about Community Notes?" one
was actually why you guys switched to anonymous
contributors, what was the decision behind that?
Yeah, we had this pilot where we were
testing with a small number of contributors,
a few thousand contributors, and we learned a
lot through that pilot. Probably the biggest
thing we learned was related to anonymity
or pseudonymity of contributors. We had
originally assumed that it was important that
people contribute under their real handle,
or their real name, or whatever it was.
The first prototypes depicted that,
we kind of thought that would be important
for people trusting the note, and actually
it was totally wrong. The best option was
actually opposite of what we first tried.
We found a few things. One, people were hesitant
to write a note on a controversial topic because
they didn't want to get attacked or harassed
online. And so some people were comfortable
doing this but others were not, and so it
meant there was more potential good notes
to be written than were getting written, and
this was very clear feedback from the pilot.
Two, and this is super interesting, people are
actually more willing to cross partisan boundaries
when they are anonymous or pseudonymous
than when they are under their real name,
and it intuitively makes a lot of sense. If
you publicly are using your name, you feel
are affiliated with one side versus the other,
you might hesitate to be perceived as breaking
with that side. But you may actually, for example,
find a note helpful that's critical of that side,
and there's a bunch of studies that show when
people are anonymous, they're much more willing
to cross partisan boundaries and work with
the other side, agree with the other side,
and we saw that too. And so by allowing people
to be pseudonymous, you actually get more honest
answers about what they really think and
it helps find disagreement that really-
That's so counterintuitive.
Yes.
You never hear the opposite always, and
it's so interesting it's the opposite.
Yeah, yeah.
I think the same principle applies
to making the likes private.
I was just thinking that.
Yeah.
Yeah, I like a lot more stuff that's a little,
definitely, I wouldn't have liked, yeah.
It allows freedom for honesty, which is pretty
great. And one of the criticisms of pseudonymity
is it can generate, maybe people have reached
the quality threshold that they put out there,
but we have so many quality mechanisms
in the system that that wasn't an issue,
so we could keep quality high
while opening up for that honesty.
Another question, you touched on this a
little bit, which is around navigating
the existing trust and safety apparatus of
Twitter, which as you described, basically,
previously, it was like we make decisions on what
is true and not, and every company works this way,
you guys basically upended that like, here's a
completely different way, you have no control
over what we say is true or not. Talk about just
that experience of overcoming that, I imagine,
very difficult hurdle of like, okay, forget all
that, we're going to do it totally different.
Yeah, it was definitely, what we were
proposing was very different. I will
say that I think people were sort of
open-minded to it, generally speaking,
and I think everyone had a sense that what was
being done at the time wasn't really working
that well or solving the problem, and people were
open to new ideas, so that's a good foundation.
But I think one thing we did that was probably
very helpful in that is we wanted the product to
prove itself at any point. First it had to prove
that people could possibly find notes helpful,
then it had to prove that people could possibly
write these notes that would be good quality. And
so anytime that we were proposing doing something
with the product, like running some research test,
or running the pilot, or expanding the pilot,
we always had the data that had convinced us
that that was a good decision, like we were
stepping into the next phase of expansion that
made sense. And so I think we probably rarely
proposed anything that seemed unwise, because
we were holding such a high bar for quality
ourselves, and I suspect that went a long way.
So it's partly, what I'm hearing is, take it
step by step to prove this is actually working,
and partly be confident it is working to yourself
before you try to convince the trust
and safety team this is the way to go.
Exactly.
Was there a moment along that journey it
shifted from no way this is a thing to okay,
wow, let's actually consider this?
Or was it this very gradual process?
Whether other people were saying
no way to wow, let's actually-
Yeah, just internally of just like, okay,
we're going to actually stop this trust and
safety way of operating and instead rely on
Community Notes, was there a moment of like,
okay, let's actually make that switch, or was
that Elon actually, is that the big switch?
The biggest change there happened in X,
the biggest changes prior to that were
just the decision to put this out there
and have it be operating in public at
first US wide scale. But yeah, then the
bigger switches came in the X period.
I think even though there was original research
before Birdwatch had even started, or Community
Notes had even started, from external researchers
showing that crowdsourced fact-checkers,
laypeople can do about as well as fact-checkers
and actually the agreement rates were kind of
similar between the groups. I think even though
that research was out there, I think there were
definitely a lot of people who didn't really
believe it could work until it already worked.
Basically prove it, prove that it works. Yeah,
that makes sense, versus just a bunch of docs
and strategy and thinking, it's just like, look,
it's actually working, you can see for yourself.
Yeah.
Makes sense. Okay, possibly last question,
we'll see which fractals of questions you
guys bring up here. I referenced this a couple
times, this incredible achievement of keeping
a project alive through Jack and then, I have
this note, and Kayvon running the show then,
and then Parag running Twitter, and then Elon,
and then Linda taking over as CEO, quite rare,
especially something this visible, this impactful
to everything that X is. Any lessons or keys to
that actually working, of this project surviving
throughout so many work changes and leaders?
It definitely has been a crazy time to be building
something. It's been fun. The craziness has been
entertaining. I think one reason perhaps the
product has done so well and survived is the
nature of the product itself. It is designed
to produce information that is found helpful
by people who normally disagree. And so even
if you have CEOs or leaders who might disagree,
there's a good chance actually they'll find it
helpful, they'll be like, wow, this thing does
produce pretty useful output. So I think there's
something in the nature of the product itself,
that when people see it, whatever side they're
on, left, up, down, they're likely to find it
pretty helpful, so I do think that helps.
I also think the team executed really well.
We had ambitious goals that were exciting, they
solved a real problem. This is a real problem
that matters in the world. At every step, as we
talked about, the product needed to prove itself,
and we would make sure it proved itself and we
would bring the results that convinced us and we'd
share those with people. And so they would say,
oh yeah, I agree, it kind of proved itself, let's
take the next leap. And we've done that all along
the way and we continue to operate that way, and
I think that focus on the outcome and goal that
matters, and executing against it, really helped.
The team did not get distracted by much all
through the period during which the acquisition
happened. There was a lot of opportunity for
distraction. This team was shipping every week,
we were super focused on the goal, let's make
this thing work, let's get these notes out there,
and I think people saw that execution
and were excited to support it.
Yeah, like it's working, why would we
mess with that? And it's important,
and it keeps us from having to hire tens
of thousands of people to fact check.
The interesting thing about that is no one
ever asked us or brought up or seemed to
care about anything related to cost savings in
this process. And I think that's an assumption
people have outside the company, that this
must have been a reason there was interest
in it. But that was never a goal, it was not at
all why the project was started, it was not why
people were excited about the project. And
I think that's also, for people outside who
maybe don't see the conversations, it's kind of
a heartening thing to know, is that the focus was
always on solving the problem. The other approach
is even if you had 10,000 people doing it,
the real issue is that they don't work that well
because they're not trusted or they don't scale
or they're too slow. And so the goal was really
always just help people stay informed at scale.
Let's build an internet scale solution to
an internet scale problem that people like.
Something I heard about you, Keith, when I was
asking people about how this worked and why this
worked so well is that they describe you with
having a very low ego, and that allowed you to
give up this whole team and power and influence
and just the name, forget it, whatever you want,
we'll call it Community Notes, great. Is
there anything in there you can share of
just how you think about that and how important
that is as a product leader to have a low ego?
For me, this project, I feel like I
get to do community service with this
project. I see my work as in service
of the people and the community,
and that's what motivates me. The only thing
that I care about is delivering the outcome
that the world finds helpful. And so in some
ways the project has not been about ego,
it's about truth-seeking, let's find... Not
truth in the sense of what information is true,
but let's find out what's actually going to make
this work. How does it need to be structured,
what should it be called? Whatever is going to
produce the best outcome is what we should do. So
I think I feel more attached to the product being
helpful than to anything else, and so to whatever
degree it might seem like low ego is probably more
a result of wanting to actually solve the problem.
And I think partly what I'm hearing
is just if you win and succeed,
good things will happen, so focus on that.
Certainly satisfying things will happen, it's
very satisfying to have people appreciate it.
It's satisfying that people on the left and
right love it. It's satisfying that even
people who receive notes, love notes,
and reach out to them and post them,
that's amazing, it feels so good
to have helped give people that,
and yeah, it's very motivating. It's a
great reason to wake up in the morning.
It's absurd this has worked, but it's
also like of course this would work,
of course something like this should
work. It's like such interesting-
It's the internet, it's of the
internet, that's why it works.
Oh man. Where's Community Notes
going from here? What's happening,
where's it going, what's the future?
We're always working on basically more better
notes faster. So there's clearly an opportunity
to get more notes out there, we want them to stay
as good or better than they are, we want to get
them there faster, so we're always working on core
product changes to help deliver that. Recently,
for example, we just released an update to
what we call the Community Notes bat signal,
or the ability to request a Community Note. So
anyone on X can say, "Hey, I think this post
needs a Community Note," and now they can even add
a source explaining why so that when a prospective
writer sees that it's much easier for them to
write a note. So we're always working on core
things like that, core algorithm improvements.
I think there are also new frontiers that show a
lot of potential, AI and LLMs are one. It's easy
to imagine a lot of ways that AI could assist
the people in this task they're doing of trying
to get information out there quickly. And maybe
Jay should talk about the Supernotes work that
we've done with some folks outside the company.
Yeah, so one cool thing about having public
data and code is that external researchers can
collaborate with you, and in this case Supernotes
had this idea that we can basically take existing
notes as input, existing proposed notes that
maybe they have some problem, maybe they have
part of the story, maybe they're worded in kind of
a biased way. Basically take all these in, have an
LLM generate a ton of different variants, and then
basically make the simulated jury to basically get
a representative group of contributors for
community notes who would be rating the note
and try to predict based on their past ratings
how they would rate these LLM generated notes.
And so this way you can actually, rather than just
having an LLM write a note from scratch and hoping
it's good, you can simulate the entire community
notes rating process and explicitly create notes
that are likely to be rated helpful by people.
So I think ideas like that are very promising
for the future, and it's a nice way that LLMs
and humans can work together. Obviously agents
can browse the web too, and that's one way that
you could imagine agents assisting humans is maybe
checking whether a note is actually supported
by the source. Although then you get into things
like, well, are people going to actually be
as diligent? Right now I think raters are
very diligent because they know just some
Community Notes contributor wrote this like,
I better check this before I rate it helpful. But
hopefully we can design things in a way such that
people don't trust the output and actually verify
it themselves before issuing a helpful rating.
Yeah, that is such an interesting area to explore
where you want to avoid AI hallucinating slop
versus make it easier and scale it even
further. What an interesting challenge.
What's cool about this project, in addition
to the AI element, is that it's being done
outside the company. We talked earlier about the
open source transparency. The key reason we made
this all open source was so people could see
how it worked, but the dream is actually that,
it's not just that the contributions to
the notes and ratings are from the people,
but the dream is actually the product is built
by the people. What if the scoring algorithm
were significantly or entirely written by the
public? That would be incredible. And Supernotes
is probably the first very substantial potential
change in the algorithm of the way it works,
that was kind of coming from the outside
and plausibly could be part of the core,
so we'd love to see the product
go in that direction as well.
Sweet, go Supernotes. Well guys, the
work you're doing is tremendous. This
is every product person's dream, I think to
work, on something like this. Small team,
lots of support, lots of impact, just
innately interesting, and so I think
this is going to inspire a lot of people.
So let me just ask you, is there anything
else you wanted to share? Anything else you think
might be helpful for folks to leave them with?
Sure, I guess one thing that just I thought was
interesting over the course of working on this
product is just there's... I think in a similar
way to how retweets originally were not something
Jack came up with, I think users just started
doing it and then it became a core part of the
product. There's a huge way already in which
there's just a lot of surprising things that
people wanted to use Community Notes for
that I don't think we really expected,
and it's kind of cool to see
those user desires emerge.
I think one example, I guess we had always been
imagining political type of misinformation,
but for whatever reason there's a lot of people
who love debating whether Messi or Ronaldo got
more goals. I guess it's kind of a funny
one. There's a community moderation aspect,
so I think we also thought that this would be
specifically for adding context to misleading
or potentially misleading information, but what
you can see is that there are some notes that go
beyond that towards calling out content that
they think is spammy or something. So I think
that's just another dimension in which commuted
notes is a product that's driven by the people.
That's so beautiful, basically they're trying
to keep Twitter/X healthy and they're just like,
no, this should be taken down, this tweet of spam.
Yeah.
I love that. Is there an answer on the Messi
versus, who is the other soccer player?
Ronaldo.
Ronaldo, okay. Is there a definitive
fact there or is that just unknowable?
Yeah, I guess that's an interesting one because
it's a case where raters are actually very
polarized. I guess it actually kind of fits
into the core algorithm where there's some
people who are just diehard Messi fans or Ronaldo
fans, just like they could be on politics, so we
actually specifically modeled that topic, as well
as some other topics, so we can estimate people's
opinion on that particular debate. It's kind
of funny that something like that would emerge.
You're saying that's the most controversial
topic on X, Ronaldo versus Messi.
That's a controversial one.
Oh wow, who knew? Okay. Keith, is
there anything you wanted to add?
Yeah, community Notes is cool itself, but I think
what it points to about society is actually even
bigger. Society often feels really polarized,
you hear people talk about it all the time,
no one can ever agree on anything, but actually
Community Note shows you people really can agree
on quite a lot. Even on super controversial
topics related to politics and everything,
there's a lot of agreement, that's why notes work.
And I think that's a really big reason for
optimism about the world, is that while it
might feel polarized, there's probably like
an 80% set of people that agree on quite
a lot of things. And imagine if we could
use the same kind of approaches we use with
notes, but to find agreement on legislation,
or policies, or things like that that people
want the government or the world to do,
possibly we could get a lot more momentum
behind these ideas that the people really
want and everyone would be a lot happier. Maybe
10% of the people on the edges wouldn't be happy,
but I bet there's a lot of agreement that
we are not identifying, and if we did it,
we'd all be pretty happy. So I don't know, I
think it's easy for people to feel pessimistic
about the world, but I think this product is a
good reason to be optimistic about the future.
What an incredible way to end it. I can also see,
Keith, why people want to join you and
work with you and work on this team.
Appreciate it. If you do want to join,
we are hiring an ML engineer. You get to
work on these amazing problems with us and
have a lot of fun, so we're accepting
applications at x.com/communitynotes.
Okay, great, I'm glad you gave the URL.
Oh man, you're about to get flooded.
Guys, thank you so much for doing this. Is
there anywhere other than that place to go off,
join the team as an ML engineer, is there
any other place you want to point people to,
either your socials or anything else?
I'm KeithColeman on X, please reach out if
you have any feedback or want to help us out,
whether you may want to work here or want to do
something from the outside, we would love to talk.
Yeah, I'm @ _JayBaxter_ at X.
Yeah, I think in particular,
besides just using Community Notes, it would
be great to get more substantial contributions,
pull requests, collaborate
on projects like Supernotes,
I think that's the most exciting type of
stuff if people do want to contribute.
Ship some code guys. Amazing. Guys,
thank you so much for doing this.
Thanks for having us, Lenny.
Thank you, thank so much.
It's my pleasure. Bye everyone. Thank you so
much for listening. If you found this valuable,
you can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app. Also,
please consider giving us a rating or leaving a
review as that really helps other listeners find
the podcast. You can find all past episodes or
learn more about the show at LennysPodcast.com.
See you in the next episode.